<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41878892</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-8306</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>CPT: pharmacometrics &amp; systems pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>CPT Pharmacometrics Syst Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integration of Machine Learning With PBPK and QSAR Modeling Approaches to Facilitate Drug Discovery and Development.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70228</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70228</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/psp4.70228</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This review examines the application of machine learning (ML) in physiologically based pharmacokinetic (PBPK) modeling through improved prediction of input parameters, particularly via quantitative structure-activity relationship (QSAR) models, for absorption, distribution, metabolism, and excretion (ADME) properties across drug development phases. Traditional PBPK models, while mechanistically sound, face limitations in applicability domain when compound-specific physicochemical and biochemical parameters (e.g., partition coefficients, metabolic clearance rates, plasma protein binding) cannot be reliably determined or estimated for novel chemicals. ML-enhanced QSAR models address these input parameter limitations by predicting required parameters directly from chemical structure, thereby extending PBPK applicability to diverse chemical space without altering the mechanistic model framework itself. Recent advances in ML-powered QSAR methodology generate higher-quality predictions of partition coefficients, clearance rates, and binding parameters. When these ML-predicted parameters are integrated as inputs into conventional PBPK frameworks, the resulting simulations often demonstrate significantly improved predictive accuracy compared to PBPK models using conventional regression-based QSAR inputs. This workflow-wherein ML enhances QSAR prediction quality, which subsequently improves PBPK simulation reliability through better input parameters-facilitates critical drug discovery and development decisions, from early candidate selection to clinical translation and safety assessment, potentially reducing pharmacokinetic-related drug candidate failures. However, challenges remain, including limited chemical diversity in QSAR training data sets, model interpretability concerns, and evolving regulatory considerations for ML-derived parameters in PBPK submissions. Future developments point toward seamless integration of ML-enhanced QSAR predictions as validated inputs for mechanistic PBPK models through standardized validation approaches and collaboration among academia, industry, and regulatory bodies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). CPT: Pharmacometrics &amp; Systems Pharmacology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Society for Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xinyue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-5916-5375</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental and Global Health, College of Public Health and Health Professions, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Environmental and Human Toxicology, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Pharmacometrics and Systems Pharmacology, University of Florida, Orlando, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Zhoumeng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8731-8366</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental and Global Health, College of Public Health and Health Professions, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Environmental and Human Toxicology, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Pharmacometrics and Systems Pharmacology, University of Florida, Orlando, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>CPT Pharmacometrics Syst Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101580011</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2163-8306</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D021281" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quantitative Structure-Activity Relationship</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055808" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Discovery</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Development</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Biological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010599" MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacokinetics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug discovery and development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nanomedicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiologically based pharmacokinetic model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative structure&#x2013;activity relationship model</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41878892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/psp4.70228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>S. Ekins, C. L. Waller, P. W. Swaan, G. Cruciani, S. A. Wrighton, and J. H. Wikel, &#x201c;Progress in Predicting Human ADME Parameters in Silico,&#x201d; Journal of Pharmacological and Toxicological Methods 1 (2000): 251&#x2013;272, https://doi.org/10.1016/S1056&#x2010;8719(00)00109&#x2010;X.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. V. Singh, M. H. D. Ansari, D. Rosenkranz, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning in Computational Nanotoxicology: Unlocking and Empowering Nanomedicine,&#x201d; Advanced Healthcare Materials 9, no. 17 (2020): 1901862, https://doi.org/10.1002/adhm.201901862. English.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Kola and J. Landis, &#x201c;Can the Pharmaceutical Industry Reduce Attrition Rates?,&#x201d; Nature Reviews Drug Discovery 8, no. 8 (2004): 711&#x2013;716, https://doi.org/10.1038/nrd1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Sertkaya, T. Beleche, A. Jessup, and B. D. Sommers, &#x201c;Costs of Drug Development and Research and Development Intensity in the US, 2000&#x2010;2018,&#x201d; JAMA Network Open 7, no. 6 (2024): e2415445, https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.15445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Komura, R. Watanabe, and K. Mizuguchi, &#x201c;The Trends and Future Prospective of in Silico Models From the Viewpoint of ADME Evaluation in Drug Discovery,&#x201d; Pharmaceutics 15, no. 11 (2023): 2619, https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics15112619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Konig and A. Vellido, &#x201c;Understanding Predictions of Drug Profiles Using Explainable Machine Learning Models,&#x201d; Biodata Mining 17, no. 1 (2024): 25, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13040&#x2010;024&#x2010;00378&#x2010;w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wu, B. Ramsundar, E. N. Feinberg, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;MoleculeNet: A Benchmark for Molecular Machine Learning,&#x201d; Chemical Science 9, no. 2 (2018): 513&#x2013;530, https://doi.org/10.1039/c7sc02664a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Zheng, T. Fu, and Z. Liang, &#x201c;QCS&#x2010;ADME: Quantum Circuit Search for Drug Property Prediction with Imbalanced Data and Regression Adaptation,&#x201d; 2025, arXiv:2503.01927, https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2503.01927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Gawehn, N. Greene, F. Miljkovic, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Perspectives on the Use of Machine Learning for ADME Prediction at AstraZeneca,&#x201d; Xenobiotica 54, no. 7 (2024): 368&#x2013;378, https://doi.org/10.1080/00498254.2024.2352598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Di Lascio, G. Gerebtzoff, and R. Rodriguez&#x2010;Perez, &#x201c;Systematic Evaluation of Local and Global Machine Learning Models for the Prediction of ADME Properties,&#x201d; Molecular Pharmaceutics 20, no. 3 (2023): 1758&#x2013;1767, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.2c00962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Jones and K. Rowland&#x2010;Yeo, &#x201c;Basic Concepts in Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling in Drug Discovery and Development,&#x201d; CPT: Pharmacometrics &amp; Systems Pharmacology 8 (2013): e63, https://doi.org/10.1038/psp.2013.41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Tsamandouras, A. Rostami&#x2010;Hodjegan, and L. Aarons, &#x201c;Combining the &#x2018;bottom Up&#x2019; and &#x2018;top Down&#x2019; Approaches in Pharmacokinetic Modelling: Fitting PBPK Models to Observed Clinical Data,&#x201d; British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology 79, no. 1 (2015): 48&#x2013;55, https://doi.org/10.1111/bcp.12234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, Z. Wang, Y. Li, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Combination of Machine Learning and PBPK Modeling Approach for Pharmacokinetics Prediction of Small Molecules in Humans,&#x201d; Pharmaceutical Research 41, no. 7 (2024): 1369&#x2013;1379, https://doi.org/10.1007/s11095&#x2010;024&#x2010;03725&#x2010;y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Hartmanshenn, M. Scherholz, and I. P. Androulakis, &#x201c;Physiologically&#x2010;Based Pharmacokinetic Models: Approaches for Enabling Personalized Medicine,&#x201d; Journal of Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics 5, no. 5 (2016): 481&#x2013;504, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10928&#x2010;016&#x2010;9492&#x2010;y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Shebley, P. Sandhu, A. E. Riedmaier, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Model Qualification and Reporting Procedures for Regulatory Submissions: A Consortium Perspective,&#x201d; Clinical Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 104, no. 1 (2018): 88&#x2013;110, https://doi.org/10.1002/cpt.1013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, H. Yang, Z. Wu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;In Silico Prediction of Blood&#x2010;Brain Barrier Permeability of Compounds by Machine Learning and Resampling Methods,&#x201d; ChemMedChem 13, no. 20 (2018): 2189&#x2013;2201, https://doi.org/10.1002/cmdc.201800533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Khaouane, L. Khaouane, S. Ferhat, and S. Hanini, &#x201c;Deep Learning for Drug Development: Using CNNs in MIA&#x2010;QSAR to Predict Plasma Protein Binding of Drugs,&#x201d; AAPS PharmSciTech 24, no. 8 (2023): 232, https://doi.org/10.1208/s12249&#x2010;023&#x2010;02686&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Y. Chen and Z. M. Lin, &#x201c;A Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Model of an Oral Tyrosine Kinase 2 Inhibitor Deucravacitinib in Healthy Adults,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Pharmacology 65 (2025): 1011&#x2013;1025, https://doi.org/10.1002/jcph.70014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Lin, R. Gehring, J. P. Mochel, T. Lav&#xe9;, and J. E. Riviere, &#x201c;Mathematical Modeling and Simulation in Animal Health &#x2013; Part II: Principles, Methods, Applications, and Value of Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling in Veterinary Medicine and Food Safety Assessment,&#x201d; Journal of Veterinay Pharmacology and Therapeutics 5 (2016): 421&#x2013;438, https://doi.org/10.1111/jvp.12311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Mi, X. Wu, and Z. Lin, &#x201c;Chemical Risk Assessment in Food Animals via Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling &#x2212; Part I: Veterinary Drugs on Human Food Safety Assessment,&#x201d; Environment International 197 (2025): 109339, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2025.109339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Zhao, L. Zhang, J. A. Grillo, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Applications of Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic (PBPK) Modeling and Simulation During Regulatory Review,&#x201d; Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics 89, no. 2 (2011): 259&#x2013;267, https://doi.org/10.1038/clpt.2010.298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ahmad, X. Pepin, L. Aarons, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;IMI &#x2013; Oral Biopharmaceutics Tools Project &#x2013; Evaluation of Bottom&#x2010;Up PBPK Prediction Success Part 4: Prediction Accuracy and Software Comparisons With Improved Data and Modelling Strategies,&#x201d; European Journal of Pharmaceutics and Biopharmaceutics 156 (2020): 50&#x2013;63, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejpb.2020.08.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Gill, M. Moullet, A. Martinsson, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Comparing the Applications of Machine Learning, PBPK, and Population Pharmacokinetic Models in Pharmacokinetic Drug&#x2010;Drug Interaction Prediction,&#x201d; CPT: Pharmacometrics &amp; Systems Pharmacology 11, no. 12 (2022): 1560&#x2013;1568, https://doi.org/10.1002/psp4.12870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Walter, G. Aljayyoussi, B. Gerner, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Predicting Pharmacokinetics in Rats Using Machine Learning: A Comparative Study Between Empirical, Compartmental, and PBPK&#x2010;Based Approaches,&#x201d; Clinical and Translational Science 18, no. 3 (2025): e70150, https://doi.org/10.1111/cts.70150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. T. Saleem, M. H. Shoaib, R. I. Yousuf, and F. Siddiqui, &#x201c;RSM and AI Based Machine Learning for Quality by Design Development of Rivaroxaban Push&#x2010;Pull Osmotic Tablets and Its PBPK Modeling,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 15, no. 1 (2025): 7922, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;025&#x2010;91601&#x2010;z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Gulave, H. W. van den Maagdenberg, L. van Boven, G. J. P. van Westen, E. C. M. de Lange, and J. G. C. van Hasselt, &#x201c;Prediction of the Extent of Blood&#x2010;Brain Barrier Transport Using Machine Learning and Integration Into the LeiCNS&#x2010;PK3.0 Model,&#x201d; Pharmaceutical Research 42, no. 2 (2025): 281&#x2013;289, https://doi.org/10.1007/s11095&#x2010;025&#x2010;03828&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Isoherranen, &#x201c;Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling of Small Molecules: How Much Progress Have We Made?,&#x201d; Drug Metabolism and Disposition 53, no. 1 (2025): 100013, https://doi.org/10.1124/dmd.123.000960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Swierczek, D. Batko, and E. Wyska, &#x201c;The Role of Pharmacometrics in Advancing the Therapies for Autoimmune Diseases,&#x201d; Pharmaceutics 16, no. 12 (2024): 1559, https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics16121559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Arav, &#x201c;Advances in Modeling Approaches for Oral Drug Delivery: Artificial Intelligence, Physiologically&#x2010;Based Pharmacokinetics, and First&#x2010;Principles Models,&#x201d; Pharmaceutics 16, no. 8 (2024): 978, https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics16080978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Bassani, N. J. Parrott, N. Manevski, and J. D. Zhang, &#x201c;Another String to Your Bow: Machine Learning Prediction of the Pharmacokinetic Properties of Small Molecules,&#x201d; Expert Opinion on Drug Discovery 19, no. 6 (2024): 683&#x2013;698, https://doi.org/10.1080/17460441.2024.2348157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Fuhrer, A. Gruber, H. Diedam, A. H. Goller, S. Menz, and S. Schneckener, &#x201c;A Deep Neural Network: Mechanistic Hybrid Model to Predict Pharmacokinetics in Rat,&#x201d; Journal of Computer&#x2010;Aided Molecular Design 38, no. 1 (2024): 7, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10822&#x2010;023&#x2010;00547&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Andrews&#x2010;Morger, M. Reutlinger, N. Parrott, and A. Olivares&#x2010;Morales, &#x201c;A Machine Learning Framework to Improve Rat Clearance Predictions and Inform Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling,&#x201d; Molecular Pharmaceutics 20, no. 10 (2023): 5052&#x2013;5065, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.3c00374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. C. Chou and Z. Lin, &#x201c;Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence in Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling,&#x201d; Toxicological Sciences 31, no. 1 (2023): 1&#x2013;14, https://doi.org/10.1093/toxsci/kfac101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. C. Chou, Q. Chen, L. Yuan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;An Artificial Intelligence&#x2010;Assisted Physiologically&#x2010;Based Pharmacokinetic Model to Predict Nanoparticle Delivery to Tumors in Mice,&#x201d; Journal of Controlled Release 361 (2023): 53&#x2013;63, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jconrel.2023.07.040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Gruber, F. Fuhrer, S. Menz, H. Diedam, A. H. Goller, and S. Schneckener, &#x201c;Prediction of Human Pharmacokinetics From Chemical Structure: Combining Mechanistic Modeling With Machine Learning,&#x201d; Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences 113, no. 1 (2024): 55&#x2013;63, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xphs.2023.10.035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. K. Vora, A. D. Gholap, K. Jetha, R. R. S. Thakur, H. K. Solanki, and V. P. Chavda, &#x201c;Artificial Intelligence in Pharmaceutical Technology and Drug Delivery Design,&#x201d; Pharmaceutics 15, no. 7 (2023): 1916, https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics15071916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Deepika and V. Kumar, &#x201c;The Role of &#x2018;Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Model (PBPK)&#x2019; new Approach Methodology (NAM) in Pharmaceuticals and Environmental Chemical Risk Assessment,&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 20, no. 4 (2023): 16, https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph20043473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Lin, W. C. Chou, Y. H. Cheng, C. He, N. A. Monteiro&#x2010;Riviere, and J. E. Riviere, &#x201c;Predicting Nanoparticle Delivery to Tumors Using Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Approaches,&#x201d; International Journal of Nanomedicine 17 (2022): 1365&#x2013;1379, https://doi.org/10.2147/IJN.S344208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Parrott, N. Manevski, and A. Olivares&#x2010;Morales, &#x201c;Can we Predict Clinical Pharmacokinetics of Highly Lipophilic Compounds by Integration of Machine Learning or in Vitro Data Into Physiologically Based Models? A Feasibility Study Based on 12 Development Compounds,&#x201d; Molecular Pharmaceutics 19, no. 11 (2022): 3858&#x2013;3868, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.2c00350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Naga, N. Parrott, G. F. Ecker, and A. Olivares&#x2010;Morales, &#x201c;Evaluation of the Success of High&#x2010;Throughput Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic (HT&#x2010;PBPK) Modeling Predictions to Inform Early Drug Discovery,&#x201d; Molecular Pharmaceutics 19, no. 7 (2022): 2203&#x2013;2216, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.2c00040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Madla, F. K. H. Gavins, H. A. Merchant, M. Orlu, S. Murdan, and A. W. Basit, &#x201c;Let's Talk About Sex: Differences in Drug Therapy in Males and Females,&#x201d; Advanced Drug Delivery Reviews 175 (2021): 113804, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addr.2021.05.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Kulkarni, &#x201c;Prediction of Drug&#x2010;Induced Kidney Injury in Drug Discovery,&#x201d; Drug Metabolism Reviews 53, no. 2 (2021): 234&#x2013;244, https://doi.org/10.1080/03602532.2021.1922436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. Fagerholm, S. Hellberg, and O. Spjuth, &#x201c;Advances in Predictions of Oral Bioavailability of Candidate Drugs in Man With New Machine Learning Methodology,&#x201d; Molecules 26, no. 9 (2021): 2572, https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26092572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. P. Chen, R. W. Bondi, and P. J. Michalski, &#x201c;Model&#x2010;Based Target Pharmacology Assessment (mTPA): An Approach Using PBPK/PD Modeling and Machine Learning to Design Medicinal Chemistry and DMPK Strategies in Early Drug Discovery,&#x201d; Journal of Medicinal Chemistry 64, no. 6 (2021): 3185&#x2013;3196, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jmedchem.0c02033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Kamiya, K. Handa, T. Miura, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;In Silico Prediction of Input Parameters for Simplified Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Models for Estimating Plasma, Liver, and Kidney Exposures in Rats After Oral Doses of 246 Disparate Chemicals,&#x201d; Chemical Research in Toxicology 34, no. 2 (2021): 507&#x2013;513, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrestox.0c00336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Gao, W. Wang, J. Dong, Z. Ye, and D. Ouyang, &#x201c;An Integrated Computational Methodology With Data&#x2010;Driven Machine Learning, Molecular Modeling and PBPK Modeling to Accelerate Solid Dispersion Formulation Design,&#x201d; European Journal of Pharmaceutics and Biopharmaceutics 158 (2021): 336&#x2013;346, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejpb.2020.12.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Li, Y. Yu, X. Bian, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Prediction of Oral Hepatotoxic Dose of Natural Products Derived From Traditional Chinese Medicines Based on SVM Classifier and PBPK Modeling,&#x201d; Archives of Toxicology 95, no. 5 (2021): 1683&#x2013;1701, https://doi.org/10.1007/s00204&#x2010;021&#x2010;03023&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Maharao, V. Antontsev, M. Wright, and J. Varshney, &#x201c;Entering the Era of Computationally Driven Drug Development,&#x201d; Drug Metabolism Reviews 52, no. 2 (2020): 283&#x2013;298, https://doi.org/10.1080/03602532.2020.1726944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cheng, S. Wang, W. Lin, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Computational Systems Pharmacology&#x2010;Target Mapping for Fentanyl&#x2010;Laced Cocaine Overdose,&#x201d; ACS Chemical Neuroscience 10, no. 8 (2019): 3486&#x2013;3499, https://doi.org/10.1021/acschemneuro.9b00109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Docci, N. Parrott, S. Krahenbuhl, and S. Fowler, &#x201c;Application of New Cellular and Microphysiological Systems to Drug Metabolism Optimization and Their Positioning Respective to in Silico Tools,&#x201d; SLAS Discovery 24, no. 5 (2019): 523&#x2013;536, https://doi.org/10.1177/2472555219831407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Kuepfer and A. Schuppert, &#x201c;Systems Medicine in Pharmaceutical Research and Development,&#x201d; Methods in Molecular Biology 1386 (2016): 87&#x2013;104, https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;1&#x2010;4939&#x2010;3283&#x2010;2_6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lu, K. Deng, X. Zhang, G. Liu, and Y. Guan, &#x201c;Neural&#x2010;ODE for Pharmacokinetics Modeling and Its Advantage to Alternative Machine Learning Models in Predicting New Dosing Regimens,&#x201d; iScience 24, no. 7 (2021): 102804, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2021.102804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Daan, O. Rik, M. J. R. Ad, G. M. v R. Joost, and A. J. H. Mark, &#x201c;Separating Uncertainty and Physiological Variability in Human PBPK Modelling: The Example of 2&#x2010;Propanol and Its Metabolite Acetone,&#x201d; Toxiology Letters 214, no. 2 (2012): 154&#x2013;165, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.toxlet.2012.08.016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. R. Wedagedera, A. Afuape, S. K. Chirumamilla, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Population PBPK Modeling Using Parametric and Nonparametric Methods of the Simcyp Simulator, and Bayesian Samplers,&#x201d; CPT: Pharmacometrics &amp; Systems Pharmacology 11, no. 6 (2022): 755&#x2013;765, https://doi.org/10.1002/psp4.12787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Hines, J. Abedini, D. Allen, N. Kleinstreuer, and K. Mansouri, &#x201c;Integrating Parameter Uncertainty in PBPK Modeling. FutureTox V Meeting.&#x201d;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. B. Siramshetty, P. Shah, E. Kerns, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Retrospective Assessment of Rat Liver Microsomal Stability at NCATS: Data and QSAR Models,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 10, no. 1 (2020): 26, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;020&#x2010;77327&#x2010;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, Y. Xu, and Y. Yu, &#x201c;CRNNTL: Convolutional Recurrent Neural Network and Transfer Learning for QSAR Modeling in Organic Drug and Material Discovery,&#x201d; Molecules 26, no. 23 (2021): 7257, https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules26237257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Walter, J. M. Borghardt, L. Humbeck, and M. Skalic, &#x201c;Multi&#x2010;Task ADME/PK Prediction at Industrial Scale: Leveraging Large and Diverse Experimental Datasets,&#x201d; Molecular Informatics 43, no. 10 (2024): e202400079, https://doi.org/10.1002/minf.202400079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Heyndrickx, L. Mervin, T. Morawietz, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;MELLODDY: Cross&#x2010;Pharma Federated Learning at Unprecedented Scale Unlocks Benefits in QSAR Without Compromising Proprietary Information,&#x201d; Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling 64, no. 7 (2024): 2331&#x2013;2344, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c00799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Cozac, H. Hasic, J. J. Choong, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;kMoL: An Open&#x2010;Source Machine and Federated Learning Library for Drug Discovery,&#x201d; Journal of Cheminformatics 17, no. 1 (2025): 22, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13321&#x2010;025&#x2010;00967&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhou, S. Cahya, S. A. Combs, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Exploring Tunable Hyperparameters for Deep Neural Networks With Industrial ADME Data Sets,&#x201d; Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling 59, no. 3 (2019): 1005&#x2013;1016, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.8b00671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Sasahara, M. Shibata, H. Sasabe, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Feature Importance of Machine Learning Prediction Models Shows Structurally Active Part and Important Physicochemical Features in Drug Design,&#x201d; Drug Metabolism and Pharmacokinetics 39 (2021): 100401, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dmpk.2021.100401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Tao, P. Zhang, C. Qin, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Recent Progresses in the Exploration of Machine Learning Methods as In&#x2010;Silico ADME Prediction Tools,&#x201d; Advanced Drug Delivery Reviews 23 (2015): 83&#x2013;100, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addr.2015.03.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Banerjee and K. Roy, &#x201c;Machine&#x2010;Learning&#x2010;Based Similarity Meets Traditional QSAR: &#x2018;q&#x2010;RASAR&#x2019; for the Enhancement of the External Predictivity and Detection of Prediction Confidence Outliers in an hERG Toxicity Dataset,&#x201d; Chemometrics and Intelligent Laboratory Systems 15 (2023): 237, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemolab.2023.104829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Dasgupta, H. Barik, and S. Gayen, &#x201c;Modelling of Intrinsic Membrane Permeability of Drug Molecules by Explainable ML&#x2010;Based q&#x2010;RASPR Approach Towards Better Pharmacokinetics and Toxicokinetics Properties,&#x201d; SAR and QSAR in Environmental Research 36, no. 2 (2025): 127&#x2013;143, https://doi.org/10.1080/1062936X.2025.2478118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Fan, S. Shi, H. Xiang, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Predicting Elimination of Small&#x2010;Molecule Drug Half&#x2010;Life in Pharmacokinetics Using Ensemble and Consensus Machine Learning Methods,&#x201d; Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling 64, no. 8 (2024): 3080&#x2013;3092, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.3c02030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wu, P.&#x2010;Y. Wu, W.&#x2010;C. Chou, L. A. Tell, and Z. Lin, &#x201c;A Machine Learning&#x2010;Empowered Quantitative Structure&#x2010;Activity Relationship Model for Predicting the Plasma Half&#x2010;Life of Drugs in Dogs,&#x201d; AAPS Journal 28, no. 1 (2026): 22, https://doi.org/10.1208/s12248&#x2010;025&#x2010;01170&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yang, K. Yao, M. P. Repasky, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Efficient Exploration of Chemical Space With Docking and Deep Learning,&#x201d; Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 17, no. 11 (2021): 7106&#x2013;7119, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.1c00810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Satheeskumar, &#x201c;Enhancing Drug Discovery With AI: Predictive Modeling of Pharmacokinetics Using Graph Neural Networks and Ensemble Learning,&#x201d; Intelligent Pharmacy 3, no. 2 (2025): 127&#x2013;140, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ipha.2024.11.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. De Carlo, D. Ronchi, M. Piastra, E. M. Tosca, and P. Magni, &#x201c;Predicting ADMET Properties From Molecule SMILE: A Bottom&#x2010;Up Approach Using Attention&#x2010;Based Graph Neural Networks,&#x201d; Pharmaceutics 16, no. 6 (2024): 776, https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics16060776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. J. Bongers, I. J. Ap, and G. J. P. Van Westen, &#x201c;Proteochemometrics&#x2014;Recent Developments in Bioactivity and Selectivity Modeling,&#x201d; Drug Discovery Today: Technologies 32&#x2013;33 (2019): 89&#x2013;98, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ddtec.2020.08.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Fluetsch, E. Di Lascio, G. Gerebtzoff, and R. Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez, &#x201c;Adapting Deep Learning QSPR Models to Specific Drug Discovery Projects,&#x201d; Molecular Pharmaceutics 21, no. 4 (2024): 1817&#x2013;1826, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.3c01124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Peteani, M. T. D. Huynh, G. Gerebtzoff, and R. Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez, &#x201c;Application of Machine Learning Models for Property Prediction to Targeted Protein Degraders,&#x201d; Nature Communications 15, no. 1 (2024): 9, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467&#x2010;024&#x2010;49979&#x2010;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Handa, S. Yoshimura, M. Kageyama, and T. Iijima, &#x201c;Development of Novel Methods for QSAR Modeling by Machine Learning Repeatedly: A Case Study on Drug Distribution to Each Tissue,&#x201d; Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling 64, no. 9 (2024): 3662&#x2013;3669, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c00046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. R. Chen, L. Yuan, W. C. Chou, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Nanoparticle Distribution in Tumors and Major Organs in Tumor&#x2010;Bearing Mice,&#x201d; ACS Nano 17, no. 20 (2023): 19810&#x2013;19831, https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.3c04037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. H. Cheng, C. L. He, J. E. Riviere, N. A. Monteiro&#x2010;Riviere, and Z. M. Lin, &#x201c;Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Nanoparticle Delivery to Tumors Using a Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling and Simulation Approach,&#x201d; ACS Nano 14, no. 3 (2020): 3075&#x2013;3095, https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.9b08142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Mansouri, J. T. Moreira&#x2010;Filho, C. N. Lowe, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Free and Open&#x2010;Source QSAR&#x2010;Ready Workflow for Automated Standardization of Chemical Structures in Support of QSAR Modeling,&#x201d; Journal of Cheminformatics 16, no. 1 (2024): 19, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13321&#x2010;024&#x2010;00814&#x2010;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Faller, &#x201c;Artificial Membrane Assays to Assess Permeability,&#x201d; Current Drug Metabolism 9, no. 9 (2008): 886&#x2013;892, https://doi.org/10.2174/138920008786485227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Mansouri, A. L. Karmaus, J. Fitzpatrick, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;CATMoS: Collaborative Acute Toxicity Modeling Suite,&#x201d; Environmental Health Perspectives 129, no. 4 (2021): 047013, https://doi.org/10.1289/Ehp8495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Mansouri, N. Kleinstreuer, A. M. Abdelaziz, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;CoMPARA: Collaborative Modeling Project for Androgen Receptor Activity,&#x201d; Environmental Health Perspectives 128, no. 2 (2020): 027002, https://doi.org/10.1289/Ehp5580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Grulke, A. J. Williams, I. Thillanadarajah, and A. M. Richard, &#x201c;EPA'S DSSTox Database: History of Development of a Curated Chemistry Resource Supporting Computational Toxicology Research,&#x201d; Computational Toxicology 12 (2019): 100096, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comtox.2019.100096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. H. Asyali, &#x201c;Design of Optimal Sampling Times for Pharmacokinetic Trials via Spline Approximation,&#x201d; Turkish Journal of Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences 18 (2010): 1019&#x2013;1030, https://doi.org/10.3906/elk&#x2010;0911&#x2010;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Sharma and J. H. McNeill, &#x201c;To Scale or Not to Scale: The Principles of Dose Extrapolation,&#x201d; British Journal of Pharmacology 157, no. 6 (2009): 907&#x2013;921, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1476&#x2010;5381.2009.00267.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Kumagai, Y. Ando, A. Tanaka, K. Tsuda, Y. Katsura, and K. Kurosaki, &#x201c;Effects of Data Bias on Machine&#x2010;Learning&#x2013;Based Material Discovery Using Experimental Property Data,&#x201d; Science and Technology of Advanced Materials: Methods 2, no. 1 (2022): 302&#x2013;309, https://doi.org/10.1080/27660400.2022.2109447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Li, E. A. Stuart, and D. B. Allison, &#x201c;Multiple Imputation A Flexible Tool for Handling Missing Data,&#x201d; JAMA 314, no. 18 (2015): 1966&#x2013;1967, https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2015.15281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Y. Shams, Z. Tarek, and A. M. Elshewey, &#x201c;A Novel RFE&#x2010;GRU Model for Diabetes Classification Using PIMA Indian Dataset,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 15, no. 1 (2025): 982, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;024&#x2010;82420&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Antontsev, A. Jagarapu, Y. Bundey, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;A Hybrid Modeling Approach for Assessing Mechanistic Models of Small Molecule Partitioning in Vivo Using a Machine Learning&#x2010;Integrated Modeling Platform,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 11, no. 1 (2021): 11143, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598&#x2010;021&#x2010;90637&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Behdenna, M. Colange, J. Haziza, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;pyComBat, a Python Tool for Batch Effects Correction in High&#x2010;Throughput Molecular Data Using Empirical Bayes Methods,&#x201d; BMC Bioinformatics 24, no. 1 (2023): 459, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859&#x2010;023&#x2010;05578&#x2010;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. W. Zhao, M. del Cueto, and A. Troisi, &#x201c;Limitations of Machine Learning Models When Predicting Compounds With Completely New Chemistries: Possible Improvements Applied to the Discovery of New Non&#x2010;Fullerene Acceptors,&#x201d; Digital Discovery 1, no. 3 (2022): 266&#x2013;276, https://doi.org/10.1039/d2dd00004k.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Simm, L. Humbeck, A. Zalewski, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Splitting Chemical Structure Data Sets for Federated Privacy&#x2010;Preserving Machine Learning,&#x201d; Journal of Cheminformatics 13, no. 7 (2021): 96, https://doi.org/10.1186/s13321&#x2010;021&#x2010;00576&#x2010;2. English.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Mostafa, V. Howle, and M. J. Chen, &#x201c;Machine Learning to Predict Drug&#x2010;Induced Liver Injury and Its Validation on Failed Drug Candidates in Development,&#x201d; Toxics 12, no. 6 (2024): 385, https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12060385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Obrezanova, G. Cs&#xe1;nyi, J. M. R. Gola, and M. D. Segall, &#x201c;Gaussian Processes: A Method for Automatic QSAR Modeling of ADME Properties,&#x201d; Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling 47, no. 5 (2007): 1847&#x2013;1857, https://doi.org/10.1021/ci7000633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Y. Wu, W. C. Chou, X. Wu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Development of Machine Learning&#x2010;Based Quantitative Structure&#x2010;Activity Relationship Models for Predicting Plasma Half&#x2010;Lives of Drugs in Six Common Food Animal Species,&#x201d; Toxicological Sciences 203, no. 1 (2025): 52&#x2013;66, https://doi.org/10.1093/toxsci/kfae125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. C. Cai, M. Liu, Y. Hu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Identification of Adverse Drug&#x2010;Drug Interactions Through Causal Association Rule Discovery From Spontaneous Adverse Event Reports,&#x201d; Artificial Intelligence in Medicine 76 (2017): 7&#x2013;15, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.artmed.2017.01.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, Q. W. Xu, G. L. Jian, X. L. Zhang, and H. Wang, &#x201c;Improved and Interpretable Prediction of Cytochrome P450&#x2010;Mediated Metabolism by Molecule&#x2010;Level Graph Modeling and Subgraph Information Bottlenecks,&#x201d; Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling 64, no. 24 (2024): 9487&#x2013;9500, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jcim.4c01632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. M. Alves, S. J. Capuzzi, E. N. Muratov, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;QSAR Models of Human Data Can Enrich or Replace LLNA Testing for Human Skin Sensitization,&#x201d; Green Chemistry 18, no. 24 (2016): 6501&#x2013;6515, https://doi.org/10.1039/c6gc01836j.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Handa, S. Sakamoto, M. Kageyama, and T. Iijima, &#x201c;Development of a 2D&#x2010;QSAR Model for Tissue&#x2010;To&#x2010;Plasma Partition Coefficient Value With High Accuracy Using Machine Learning Method, Minimum Required Experimental Values, and Physicochemical Descriptors,&#x201d; European Journal of Drug Metabolism and Pharmacokinetics 48, no. 4 (2023): 341&#x2013;352, https://doi.org/10.1007/s13318&#x2010;023&#x2010;00832&#x2010;w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Kopac, &#x201c;Leveraging Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Characterizing Protein Corona, Nanobiological Interactions, and Advancing Drug Discovery,&#x201d; Journal of Drug Delivery Science and Technology 12, no. 3 (2025): 312, https://doi.org/10.3390/bioengineering12030312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services Food and Drug Administration, &#x201c;Nanotechnology Regulatory Science Research Plan 2018,&#x201d; 2013, https://www.fda.gov/science&#x2010;research/nanotechnology&#x2010;programs&#x2010;fda/2013&#x2010;nanotechnology&#x2010;regulatory&#x2010;science&#x2010;research&#x2010;plan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency (EMA), &#x201c;Reflection Paper on the Use of Artificial Intelligence (AI) in the Medicinal Product Lifecycle 2024,&#x201d; https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/scientific&#x2010;guideline/reflection&#x2010;paper&#x2010;use&#x2010;artificial&#x2010;intelligence&#x2010;ai&#x2010;medicinal&#x2010;product&#x2010;lifecycle_en.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services Food and Drug Administration, &#x201c;Considerations for the Use of Artificial Intelligence to Support Regulatory Decision&#x2010;Making for Drug and Biological Products, Guidance for Industry and Other Interested Parties &#x2010; DRAFT GUIDANCE 2025,&#x201d; https://www.fda.gov/media/184830/download.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency (EMA), US Department of Health and Human Services Food and Drug Administration, &#x201c;Guiding Principles of Good AI Practice in Drug Development 2026,&#x201d; https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/other/guiding&#x2010;principles&#x2010;good&#x2010;ai&#x2010;practice&#x2010;drug&#x2010;development_en.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services Food and Drug Administration, &#x201c;The Use of Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Analyses &#x2014; Biopharmaceutics Applications for Oral Drug Product Development, Manufacturing Changes, and Controls Guidance for Industry &#x2010; Draft Guidance 2020,&#x201d; https://www.fda.gov/media/142500/download.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency (EMA), &#x201c;Guideline on the reporting of physiologically based pharmacokinetic (PBPK) modelling and simulation 2018,&#x201d; https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/scientific&#x2010;guideline/guideline&#x2010;reporting&#x2010;physiologically&#x2010;based&#x2010;pharmacokinetic&#x2010;pbpk&#x2010;modelling&#x2010;and&#x2010;simulation_en.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. V. Nova, T. P. Lin, S. Shanehsazzadeh, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Nanomedicine Ex Machina: Between Model&#x2010;Informed Development and Artificial Intelligence,&#x201d; Frontiers in Digital Health 4, no. 18 (2022): 799341, https://doi.org/10.3389/fdgth.2022.799341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Chen, Z. Yaari, E. Apfelbaum, P. Grodzinski, Y. Shamay, and D. A. Heller, &#x201c;Merging Data Curation and Machine Learning to Improve Nanomedicines,&#x201d; Advanced Drug Delivery Reviews 183 (2022): 114172, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.addr.2022.114172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Maojo, M. Fritts, D. de la Iglesia, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Nanoinformatics: A New Area of Research in Nanomedicine,&#x201d; International Journal of Nanomedicine 7 (2012): 3867&#x2013;3890, https://doi.org/10.2147/Ijn.S24582.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>