<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41738620</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-9159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of surgery (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research trends of tumor-associated macrophages in colorectal cancer: a bibliometric analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JS9.0000000000004422</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Colorectal cancer (CRC) represents the third most prevalent malignancy worldwide and accounts for the second-highest cancer-related mortality rate. Accumulating evidence over the past decade has established the pivotal role of tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs) in CRC tumorigenesis and disease progression. This study employs bibliometric analysis to delineate the research landscape and emerging frontiers in CRC TAMs investigation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We systematically retrieved publications indexed in the Web of Science Core Collection from database inception through 14 April 2025, applying predefined inclusion and exclusion criteria. Using VOSviewer and CiteSpace, we conducted comprehensive visual analyses of the CRC TAMs research domain, including country contributions, institutional productivity, annual publication trends, and journal distributions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Our bibliometric analysis identified 2861 publications on CRC TAMs worldwide, with a consistent upward publication trend since 2018. Geospatial analysis revealed that China and the United States are the predominant contributing nations, with Sun Yat-sen University being the most productive institution. Keyword co-occurrence mapping identified five predominant research clusters: CRC biology, TAMs characterization, patient survival outcomes, disease progression mechanisms, and metastatic processes. Four key research directions emerged: (1) single-cell RNA sequencing for TAMs heterogeneity analysis, (2) PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint interactions with TAMs, (3) molecular mechanisms underlying macrophage polarization, and (4) chemotherapeutic modulation of TAMs functionality (particularly irinotecan). These advances provide mechanistic insights into CRC TAMs biology and may facilitate (1) the discovery of novel diagnostic biomarkers, (2) precision therapeutic strategies, and (3) personalized prognostic frameworks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Bibliometric analysis has highlighted the global landscape of research on CRC TAMs. Future research directions in CRC TAMs are likely to center on the integration of multi-omics, in-depth investigation of the tumor microenvironment, targeting TAMs, application of machine learning and artificial intelligence, and the development of personalized treatment strategies for CRC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Yuxin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Second Clinical Medical College, Shanxi University of Chinese Medicine, Xianyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Xijing Hospital, Air Force Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiangxu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Xijing Hospital, Air Force Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoting</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Xijing Hospital, Air Force Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Xijing Hospital, Air Force Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Shou</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Xijing Hospital, Air Force Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hongmei</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3991-3750</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Xijing Hospital, Air Force Military Medical University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101228232</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-9159</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CRC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TAMs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bibliometric</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">future trend</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">research topic</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41738620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JS9.0000000000004422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01279778-990000000-04706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Riaz AA, Ginimol M, Rasha R, et al. Transparency in the reporting of Artificial Intelligence &#x2013; the TITAN Guideline [J]. Prem J Sci 2025;10:100082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhanani O, Ben-Uri R, Keren L. Spatial profiling technologies illuminate the tumor microenvironment [J]. Cancer Cell 2023;41:404&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassetta L, Pollard JW. Targeting macrophages: therapeutic approaches in cancer [J]. Nat Rev Drug Discov 2018;17:887&#x2013;904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Wang X, Zhang X, et al. The promising role of tumor-associated macrophages in the treatment of cancer [J]. Drug Resist Updat 2024;73:101041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson NR, Minutolo NG, Gill S, et al. Macrophage-based approaches for cancer immunotherapy [J]. Cancer Res 2021;81:1201&#x2013;08.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers KV, Amend SR, Pienta KJ. Targeting Tyro3, Axl and MerTK (TAM receptors): implications for macrophages in the tumor microenvironment [J]. Mol Cancer 2019;18:94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C, Jeong H, Bae Y, et al. Targeting of M2-like tumor-associated macrophages with a melittin-based pro-apoptotic peptide [J]. J Immunother Cancer 2019;7:147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Yang Y, Deng Y, et al. Delivery of CD47 blocker SIRP&#x3b1;-Fc by CAR-T cells enhances antitumor efficacy [J]. J Immunother Cancer 2022;10:e003737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo P, Lepland A, Scodeller P, et al. Peptide-guided resiquimod-loaded lignin nanoparticles convert tumor-associated macrophages from M2 to M1 phenotype for enhanced chemotherapy [J]. Acta Biomater 2021;133:231&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hourani T, Holden JA, Li W, et al. Tumor associated macrophages: origin, recruitment, phenotypic diversity, and targeting [J]. Front Oncol 2021;11:788365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Dong T, Li X, et al. Global biomarker trends in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease research: a bibliometric analysis [J]. Heliyon 2024;10:e27437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh K, Stadler ZK, Cercek A, et al. Immunotherapy in colorectal cancer: rationale, challenges and potential [J]. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2019;16:361&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cercek A, Lumish M, Sinopoli J, et al. PD-1 blockade in mismatch repair-deficient, locally advanced rectal cancer [J]. N Engl J Med 2022;386:2363&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9; T, Lonardi S, Wong KYM, et al. Nivolumab plus low-dose ipilimumab in previously treated patients with microsatellite instability-high/mismatch repair-deficient metastatic colorectal cancer: 4-year follow-up from CheckMate 142 [J]. Ann Oncol 2022;33:1052&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani A, Marchesi F, Malesci A, et al. Tumour-associated macrophages as treatment targets in oncology [J]. Nat Rev Clin Oncol 2017;14:399&#x2013;416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeNardo DG, Ruffell B. Macrophages as regulators of tumour immunity and immunotherapy [J]. Nat Rev Immunol 2019;19:369&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daldrup-Link HE, Golovko D, Ruffell B, et al. MRI of tumor-associated macrophages with clinically applicable iron oxide nanoparticles [J]. Clin Cancer Res 2011;17:5695&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etzerodt A, Tsalkitzi K, Maniecki M, et al. Specific targeting of CD163(+) TAMs mobilizes inflammatory monocytes and promotes T cell-mediated tumor regression [J]. J Exp Med 2019;216:2394&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toledo B, Zhu Chen L, Paniagua-Sancho M, et al. Deciphering the performance of macrophages in tumour microenvironment: a call for precision immunotherapy [J]. J Hematol Oncol 2024;17:44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Li Z, Skrzypczynska KM, et al. Single-cell analyses inform mechanisms of myeloid-targeted therapies in colon cancer [J]. Cell 2020;181:442&#x2013;59.e29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginhoux F, Schultze JL, Murray PJ, et al. New insights into the multidimensional concept of macrophage ontogeny, activation and function [J]. Nat Immunol 2016;17:34&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenes M, Shang M, Di Matteo M, et al. Macrophage metabolism controls tumor blood vessel morphogenesis and metastasis [J]. Cell Metab 2016;24:701&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulder K, Patel AA, Kong WT, et al. Cross-tissue single-cell landscape of human monocytes and macrophages in health and disease [J]. Immunity 2021;54:1883&#x2013;900.e5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Liu Y, Wang X, et al. Integration of single-cell RNA sequencing and bulk RNA transcriptome sequencing reveals a heterogeneous immune landscape and pivotal cell subpopulations associated with colorectal cancer prognosis [J]. Front Immunol 2023;14:1184167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelands J, van der Ploeg M, Ijsselsteijn ME, et al. Transcriptomic and immunophenotypic profiling reveals molecular and immunological hallmarks of colorectal cancer tumourigenesis [J]. Gut 2023;72:1326&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Peng W, Wang H, et al. C1q(+) tumor-associated macrophages contribute to immunosuppression through fatty acid metabolic reprogramming in malignant pleural effusion. J Immunother Cancer 2023;11:e007441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries [J]. CA Cancer J Clin 2021;71:209&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, et al. Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries [J]. CA Cancer J Clin 2018;68:394&#x2013;424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekker E, Tanis PJ, Vleugels JLA, et al. Colorectal cancer [J]. Lancet 2019;394:1467&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2020 [J]. CA Cancer J Clin 2020;70:7&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biller LH, Schrag D. Diagnosis and treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer: a review [J]. Jama 2021;325:669&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei C, Yang C, Wang S, et al. Crosstalk between cancer cells and tumor associated macrophages is required for mesenchymal circulating tumor cell-mediated colorectal cancer metastasis [J]. Mol Cancer 2019;18:64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo C, Xia J, Xu Y, et al. stClinic dissects clinically relevant niches by integrating spatial multi-slice multi-omics data in dynamic graphs [J]. Nat Commun 2025;16:5317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma RY, Black A, Qian BZ. Macrophage diversity in cancer revisited in the era of single-cell omics [J]. Trends Immunol 2022;43:546&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chen Z, Han J, et al. Functional and therapeutic significance of tumor-associated macrophages in colorectal cancer [J]. Front Oncol 2022;12:781233.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>