<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41345631</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1747-5341</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Philosophy, ethics, and humanities in medicine : PEHM</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Philos Ethics Humanit Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Understanding and addressing intimate partner violence: a comprehensive review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43</StartPage><MedlinePgn>43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">43</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13010-025-00175-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Intimate Partner Violence (IPV) remains a pervasive and distressing societal issue with far-reaching physical, emotional, and psychological consequences. This paper delves into the complex dynamics of IPV, aiming to enhance the comprehension of its root causes, contributing factors, and various manifestations. By synthesizing multidisciplinary research, it highlights the role of societal norms, cultural influences, and individual psychological traits in perpetuating such violence. Moreover, the paper elucidates the impact of IPV on survivors, children, families, and communities, emphasizing the urgent need for comprehensive intervention strategies. Drawing upon psychological, sociological, and criminological perspectives, the outlines existing theoretical frameworks that seek to explain the underlying mechanisms of IPV. It explores the cyclical nature of violence, power and control dynamics, as well as the intersectionality of factors such as gender, socioeconomic status, and race. By examining the various forms of IPV, including physical, emotional, sexual, and financial abuse, the paper underscores the importance of recognizing the subtler, non-physical forms of violence. In addressing IPV, evaluate the effectiveness of prevention and intervention programs across different contexts. It emphasizes the significance of early education, awareness campaigns, and policy initiatives in reshaping societal attitudes and dismantling cycles of violence. Additionally, the paper examines support systems for survivors, from crisis intervention and shelters to counseling and legal assistance, while considering the unique needs of marginalized and vulnerable populations.Ultimately, this paper underscores the urgent necessity for a holistic and collaborative approach to eradicating IPV. By understanding its intricate underpinnings and consequences, society can work collectively to challenge ingrained norms, promote healthy relationships, and provide survivors with the resources they need to rebuild their lives. Through a comprehensive exploration of IPV, this paper contributes to the ongoing discourse surrounding this critical issue and advocates for a future free from the shackles of intimate partner violence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Asmatullah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Eastern Medicine, University of Poonch, Azad Jammu and Kashmir, Rawalakot, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akram</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Eastern Medicine, Government College University Faisalabad, Faisalabad, Pakistan. makram_0451@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Philos Ethics Humanit Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101258058</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1747-5341</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000066511" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intimate Partner Violence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Awareness campaigns</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Criminological perspectives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emotional abuse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Financial abuse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intimate partner violence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical harm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Policy initiatives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevention and intervention programs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological effects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sexual abuse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sociological effects</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Informed consent: Not applicable. Consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: All authors are agreed for Publication. Competing interests: There is no conflict of interest among authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41345631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12676874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13010-025-00175-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13010-025-00175-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Hajj S, Moustafa M, Hechi ME, Chahrour MA, Nasrallah AA, Kaafarani H. (2021). Physical Injuries and Burns among Refugees in Lebanon: Implications for Programs and Policies. medRxiv. 2009;2027:21264058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10518957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37749592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alejo K. Long-term physical and mental health effects of domestic violence. Themis: Res J Justice Stud Forensic Sci. 2014;2(1):5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31979/THEMIS.2014.0205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson EJ, Krause KC, Krause M, Welter C, McClelland A, Garcia DJ, D. O., et al. Web-based and mHealth interventions for intimate partner violence victimization prevention: a systematic review. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2021;22(4):870&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524838019888889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31742475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Band-Winterstein T, Goldblatt H, Lev S, Harel D. Forms of sexual assault against older women in the context of acquaintance relationships: an intersectional perspective. Health Soc Care Commun. 2022;30(5):e2330&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hsc.13672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34850479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates EA. Walking on egg shells: A qualitative examination of Men&#x2019;s experiences of intimate partner violence. Psychol Men Masculinities. 2020;21(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/men0000203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boateng JD, Tenkorang EY. A qualitative inquiry of the causes of economic abuse among women in intimate relationships in Ghana. J Family Violence. 2023;38(5):919&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10896-022-00435-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38470542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks C, Martin S, Broda L, Poudrier J. How many silences are there? Men&#x2019;s experience of victimization in intimate partner relationships. J Interpers Violence. 2020;35(23&#x2013;24):5390&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260517719905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullock HE, Reppond HA, Truong SV, Singh MR. An intersectional analysis of the feminization of homelessness and mothers&#x2019; housing precarity. J Soc Issues. 2020;76(4):835&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/josi.12406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullough A, Guelich U, Manolova TS, Schjoedt L. Women&#x2019;s entrepreneurship and culture: gender role expectations and identities, societal culture, and the entrepreneurial environment. Small Bus Econ. 2022;58(2):985&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11187-020-00429-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7794635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38624690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrow SJ. Gender violence: resistance, resilience, and autonomy. Rowman &amp; Littlefield; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzi RS, Smith PB, Kozinetz CA, Wiemann CM. Pregnant adolescents as perpetrators and victims of intimate partner violence. J Interpers Violence. 2020;35(13&#x2013;14):2492&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260517704228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calati R, Ferrari C, Brittner M, Oasi O, Oli&#xe9; E, Carvalho AF, et al. Suicidal thoughts and behaviors and social isolation: A narrative review of the literature. J Affect Disord. 2019;245:653&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2018.11.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30445391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capaldi DM, Knoble NB, Shortt JW, Kim HK. A systematic review of risk factors for intimate partner violence. Partn Abuse. 2012;3(2):231&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/1946-6560.3.2.231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22754606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carnes PJ. (2018). Betrayal bond, revised: breaking free of exploitive relationships.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellanos S, Cooke A, Koenders S, Joshi N, Miaskowski C, Kushel M, et al. Accounting for the interplay of interpersonal and structural trauma in the treatment of chronic non-cancer pain, opioid use disorder, and mental health in urban safety-net primary care clinics. SSM-Mental Health. 2023;4:100243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssmmh.2023.100243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10923552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38464953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connell RW. Masculinities. Routledge; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtois CA, Ford JD. Treatment of complex trauma: A sequenced, relationship-based approach. Guilford Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deuba K, Shrestha R, Koju R, Jha VK, Lamichhane A, Mehra D, Ekstr&#xf6;m AM. Assessing the Nepalese health system&#x2019;s readiness to manage gender-based violence and deliver psychosocial counselling. Health Policy Plann. 2024;39(2):198&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czae003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10883662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38300229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duron JF, Johnson L, Hoge GL, Postmus JL. Observing coercive control beyond intimate partner violence: examining the perceptions of professionals about common tactics used in victimization. Psychol Violence. 2021;11(2):144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/vio0000354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis J, Johnson Q, Moxley A. (2023). Everlasting Pain: The Long-Term Effects of Physical and Emotional Abuse. Human Trafficking: A Global Health Emergency: Perspectives from Nursing, Criminal Justice, and the Social Sciences, 289&#x2013;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel B. The emotionally abusive relationship: how to stop being abused and how to stop abusing. Wiley; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favazza AR. Bodies under siege: Self-mutilation, nonsuicidal self-injury, and body modification in culture and psychiatry. JHU; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fegert JM, Vitiello B, Plener PL, Clemens V. Challenges and burden of the coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic for child and adolescent mental health: a narrative review to highlight clinical and research needs in the acute phase and the long return to normality. Child Adolesc Psychiatry Mental Health. 2020;14:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13034-020-00329-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7216870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32419840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foy T, Dwyer RJ, Nafarrete R, Hammoud MSS, Rockett P. Managing job performance, social support and work-life conflict to reduce workplace stress. Int J Productivity Perform Manage. 2019;68(6):1018&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJPPM-03-2017-0061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman AR. Rape and domestic violence: the experience of refugee women. In: Cole E, Espin OM, Rothblum ED, editors. Refugee women and their mental health. Routledge. 2013; pp. 65&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gezinski LB, Gonzalez-Pons KM, Rogers MM. Substance use as a coping mechanism for survivors of intimate partner violence: implications for safety and service accessibility. Violence against Women. 2021;27(2):108&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077801219882496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31662096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorman L. Rape as torture: application of the US torture statute to the physical and. Psychological Consequences of Rape and Sexual Violence on Victims; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grace KT, Anderson JC. Reproductive coercion: a systematic review. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2018;19(4):371&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524838016663935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5577387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray JS, LaBore KB, Carter P. Protecting the sacred tree: conceptualizing spiritual abuse against native American elders. Psychol Relig Spiritual. 2021;13(2):204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/rel0000195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene K, Bogo M. The different faces of intimate violence: implications for assessment and treatment. J Marital Fam Ther. 2002;28(4):455&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1752-0606.2002.tb00370.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12382554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greig A, Flood M. Work with men and boys for gender equality: A review of field formation, the evidence base and future directions. New York: UN Women; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamberger LK, Larsen SE, Lehrner A. Coercive control in intimate partner violence. Aggress Violent Beh. 2017;37:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.avb.2017.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammock GS, Richardson DS, Lamm KB, Taylor E, Verlaque L. The effect of gender of perpetrator and victim on perceptions of psychological and physical intimate partner aggression. J Family Violence. 2017;32:357&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10896-016-9850-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hine B, Bates EA, Wallace S. I have guys call me and say &#x2018;I can&#x2019;t be the victim of domestic abuse&#x2019;: exploring the experiences of telephone support providers for male victims of domestic violence and abuse. J Interpers Violence. 2022;37(7&#x2013;8):NP5594&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260520944551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8980445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32727270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulley J, Bailey L, Kirkman G, Gibbs GR, Gomersall T, Latif A, et al. Intimate partner violence and barriers to help-seeking among black, Asian, minority ethnic and immigrant women: A qualitative metasynthesis of global research. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2023;24(2):1001&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15248380211050590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10012394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35107333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson A, Rogerson M, Le Grande M, Thompson D, Ski C, Alvarenga M et al. Protocol for the development and validation of a measure of persistent psychological and emotional distress in cardiac patients: the cardiac distress inventory. BMJ Open. 2020;10(6):e034946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7295398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32532770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaukinen C. When stay-at-home orders leave victims unsafe at home: exploring the risk and consequences of intimate partner violence during the COVID-19 pandemic. Am J Criminal Justice. 2020;45:668&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12103-020-09533-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7274936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32837152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobe R. From the heart. Richmond Kobe; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohtala S, Jaffe PG, Chiodo D, Dawson M, Straatman A-L. Barriers to safety planning for female victims of domestic violence in Canadian rural, remote, and Northern communities. J Family Violence. 2023;40(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubicek K, McNeeley M, Collins S. Young men who have sex with Men&#x2019;s experiences with intimate partner violence. J Adolesc Res. 2016;31(2):143&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0743558415584011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacey KK, Shahid HR, Jeremiah RD. Intimate partner violence and the role of child maltreatment and neighborhood violence: A retrospective study of African American and US Caribbean black women. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18052245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7956464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33668319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leach J. Psychological factors in exceptional, extreme and torturous environments. Extrem Physiol Med. 2016;5:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13728-016-0048-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4890253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27257476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerner AB. From the ashes of history: collective trauma and the making of international politics. Oxford University Press; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litz BT, Kerig PK. Introduction to the special issue on moral injury: conceptual challenges, methodological issues, and clinical applications. J Trauma Stress. 2019;32(3):341&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jts.22405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31162737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovallo WR, Dickensheets SL, Myers DA, Thomas TL, Nixon SJ. Blunted stress cortisol response in abstinent alcoholic and polysubstance-abusing men. Alcoholism: Clin Experimental Res. 2000;24(5):651&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10832906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lux G, Gill S. Identifying coercive control in Canadian family law: A required analysis in determining the best interests of the child. Family Court Rev. 2021;59(4):810&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/fcre.12540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutwak N. The psychology of health and illness: the mental health and physiological effects of intimate partner violence on women. In: Rokach A, editor. The psychology of health and illness. Routledge; 2024. pp. 105&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30089083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons M, Brewer G. Experiences of intimate partner violence during lockdown and the COVID-19 pandemic. J Family Violence. 2021;37(6):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7908951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33654343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machawira P, Castle C, Herat J. (2020). Progress and challenges with comprehensive sexuality education: What does this mean for HIV prevention in the ESA region? <i>Preventing HIV Among Young People in Southern and Eastern Africa</i>, 261&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheson FI, Daoud N, Hamilton-Wright S, Borenstein H, Pedersen C, O&#x2019;Campo P. Where did she go? The transformation of self-esteem, self-identity, and mental well-being among women who have experienced intimate partner violence. Women&#x2019;s Health Issues. 2015;25(5):561&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.whi.2015.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26116987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza M, Marano G, Del Castillo AG, Chieffo D, Monti L, Janiri D, et al. Intimate partner violence: a loop of abuse, depression and victimization. World J Psychiatry. 2021;11(6):215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v11.i6.215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8209536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messing J, Bagwell-Gray M, Brown ML, Kappas A, Durfee A. Intersections of stalking and technology-based abuse: emerging definitions, conceptualization, and measurement. J Family Violence. 2020;35(7):693&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10896-019-00114-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motz A. Toxic couples: the psychology of domestic violence. Routledge; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanasi N. Disarming domestic abusers. Harv L Pol&#x2019;y Rev. 2019;14:559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguefack-Tsague G, Amani A, Dadjie VD, Koyalta D, Carole DN, Dissak-Delon FN, Chichom-Mefire A. Gender-based violence and its health risks on women in Yaound&#xe9;, Cameroon. Archives Public Health. 2024;82(1):90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-024-01308-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11184865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38886777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nnawulezi N, Engleton J, Jumarali S, Royson S, Murphy C. Isn&#x2019;t there any other way than calling the cops?? How differences in initiation of Police intervention influence survivor safety. J Interpers Violence. 2022;37(23&#x2013;24):NP21953&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08862605211064287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34933576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Malley RL. Short-term and long-term impacts of financial sextortion on victim&#x2019;s mental well-being. J Interpers Violence. 2023;38(13&#x2013;14):8563&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08862605231156416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36866591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyeaka H, Anumudu CK, Al-Sharify ZT, Egele-Godswill E, Mbaegbu P. COVID-19 pandemic: A review of the global lockdown and its far-reaching effects. Sci Prog. 2021;104(2):00368504211019854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00368504211019854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10454957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34061685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. COVID-19 and violence against women: what the health sector/system can do, 7 April 2020. World Health Organization; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SY. (2022). Sharing my story has been part of my healing process: how Native women survivors heal from IPV. <i>medRxiv</i>, 2022.2012. 2006.22283188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotta G. The concept of altered perception in body dysmorphic disorder: the subtle border between the abuse of selfies in social networks and cosmetic surgery, between socially accepted dysfunctionality and the pathological condition. J Neurol Neurol Sci Disord. 2020;6(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17352/jnnsd.000036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perumal J, Moyo Z. Disadvantaged school contexts and female school leadership in Zimbabwe. Int J Afr Renaiss Stud. 2019;14(1):83&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh B, Becker P. Exploring definitions and prevalence of verbal sexual coercion and its relationship to consent to unwanted sex: implications for affirmative consent standards on college campuses. Behav Sci. 2018;8(8):69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs8080069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6115968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30072605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn Z. Crash override: how Gamergate (nearly) destroyed my life, and how we can win the fight against online hate. Hachette UK; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regehr K, Birze A, Regehr C. Technology facilitated re-victimization: how video evidence of sexual violence contributes to mediated cycles of abuse. Crime Media Cult. 2022;18(4):597&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17416590211050333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reshi IA, Sudha T. ECONOMIC EMPOWERMENT OF WOMEN: A REVIEW OF CURRENT RESEARCH. Int J Educational Rev Law Social Sci (IJERLAS). 2023;3(2):601&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggs SA. Childhood emotional abuse and the attachment system across the life cycle: what theory and research tell Us. In: Reyome N, editor. The effect of childhood emotional maltreatment on later intimate relationships. Routledge; 2019. pp. 5&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rippon TJ. Aggression and violence in health care professions. J Adv Nurs. 2000;31(2):452&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2648.2000.01284.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10672105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberton T, Daffern M, Bucks RS. Emotion regulation and aggression. Aggress Violent Beh. 2012;17(1):72&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.avb.2011.09.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson SR, Ravi K, Voth Schrag RJ. A systematic review of barriers to formal help seeking for adult survivors of IPV in the united States, 2005&#x2013;2019. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2021;22(5):1279&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524838020916254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32266870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers A, Pilgrim D. (2021). A Sociology of Mental Health and Illness 6e. McGraw-Hill Education (UK).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruork AK, McLean CL, Fruzzetti AE. It happened matters more than what happened: associations between intimate partner violence abuse type, emotion regulation, and post-traumatic stress symptoms. Violence against Women. 2022;28(5):1158&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10778012211013895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34057860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanghera J. Unpacking the trafficking discourse. In: Kamala K, Pattanaik B, editors. Trafficking and prostitution reconsidered. Routledge; 2017. pp. 3&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sereno M, Catagnus R, Griffith A, Eilers H. A systematic review of empirical studies measuring training effects on biases evidenced by professionals toward intimate partner violence. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2023;25(2):1053&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37177989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyfi S, Hall CM, Vo-Thanh T. The gendered effects of statecraft on women in tourism: economic sanctions, women&#x2019;s disempowerment and sustainability? J Sustainable Tourism. 2022;30(7):1736&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09669582.2020.1850749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel DJ, Gottman M. (2015). An interpersonal neurobiology approach to developmental trauma. Mindfulness-oriented Interventions Trauma: Integrating Contemplative Practices, 1:210&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toccalino D, Haag H, Nalder E, Chan V, Moore A, Colantonio A, Wickens CM. (2024). A whole ball of all-togetherness: the interwoven experiences of intimate partner violence, brain injury, and mental health. PLoS ONE, 19(8), e0306599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11343459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toccalino D, Haag HL, Estrella MJ, Cowle S, Fuselli P, Ellis MJ, et al. Addressing the shadow pandemic: COVID-19 related impacts, barriers, needs, and priorities to health care and support for women survivors of intimate partner violence and brain injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;103(7):1466&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2021.12.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8776331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35007550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd CL, Byrd JE, Baldwin L. Intimate partner cyber abuse viewed through the lens of criminology. In: Lutwak N, editor. Research anthology on child and domestic abuse and its prevention, volumn 2. IGI Global; 2022. pp. 522&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace WC. (2022). Introduction to Guns, Gun Violence and Gun Homicides: Perspectives from the Caribbean, Global South and Beyond. Guns, Gun Violence and Gun Homicides: Perspectives from the Caribbean, Global South and Beyond, 1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehlan C. Proventing intimate partner Violence-Related attitudes through Arts-Based peace education. A Sequential Explanatory Study of Dancing Classrooms Alumni; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson E. Living in the world of the domestic violence perpetrator: negotiating the unreality of coercive control. Violence against Women. 2010;16(12):1412&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077801210389162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21164217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>