<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41792189</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural fatigue failure analysis and lifetime reliability monitoring strategy of the lattice jib in all-terrain cranes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42707-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>During lifting operations, the boom of large-tonnage all-terrain cranes bears quasi-static loads imposed by the structure weight and wind forces, and alternating cyclic loads caused by the departure, rotation, and landing of cargo. These factors give rise to localized fatigue failure of welded joints, thereby triggering engineering accidents. Current fatigue monitoring strategies mainly rely on historical data and simplified load spectra, which are insufficient to accurately capture the randomness and complexity in crane operations. This study proposes a new fatigue monitoring strategy that integrates real-time operational data with finite element (FE) modeling. The fatigue failure of the lattice jib section (LJS) of an all-terrain crane was investigated through bench testing and FE analysis to establish a fatigue lifetime reliability monitoring strategy for the lattice jib of all-terrain cranes. First, the static loading strain at specific positions, fatigue failure positions, fatigue life and characteristics of the fracture surface were obtained through the implementation of full-scale static load tests, fatigue tests, and fractographic investigation. Then, a refined solid element FE model of the LJS containing weld elements was established, and the hot spot stresses along the wall thickness direction at the weld toes were extracted for fatigue failure analysis. At last, by utilizing the Internet of Things crane operation data and simplified FE model of the entire crane, the fatigue load spectra for components were established, enabling the prediction of cumulative damage rate and potential fatigue failure locations in the crane lattice jib. The simulation method and lifetime monitoring strategy developed in this study can serve as a valuable reference for reliability assessment of crane.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Automotive Engineering, Suzhou University of Technology, Changshu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Yuqin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xuzhou Heavy Machinery Co., Ltd., Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Changqing</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xuzhou Heavy Machinery Co., Ltd., Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Liwei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Wuhe</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Automotive Engineering, Suzhou University of Technology, Changshu, China. jiangw@szut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>XCMG Environment Technology Co., Ltd., Xuzhou, China. jiangw@szut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">All-terrain crane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue failure prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Finite element simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lattice jib section</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lifetime reliability strategy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41792189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42707-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42707-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;tz, W. A history of fatigue. Eng. Fract. Mech. 54, 263&#x2013;300 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C., Qi, Q., Dong, Q., Yu, Y. &amp; Fan, Y. Research on fatigue remaining life of structures for a dynamic lifting process of a bridge crane. J. Mech. Sci. Technol. 37, 1789&#x2013;1801. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12206-023-0319-7 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, L. et al. Investigation of the fatigue crack growth behavior of S355 steel weldments of motor hangers of high-speed trains. Eng. Fail. Anal. 140, 106425. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engfailanal.2022.106425 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan, K. et al. Multi-objective optimization design for anti-fatigue lightweight of dump truck carriage combined with machine learning. Adv. Mech. Eng. 16 (9), 1&#x2013;18. 10.11716878132241269244 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, J. et al. Buckling failure analysis of all-terrain crane telescopic boom section. Eng. Fail. Anal. 57, 105&#x2013;117. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engfailanal.2015.07.038 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. et al. Fatigue life optimization and lightweight design of wheel based on entropy weight grey relation analysis and modified NSGA-II. Adv. Mech. Eng. 15 (1&#x2013;20). https://doi.org/10.1177/16878132231189119 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, P., Hong, J. K., Osage, D. A., Dewees, D. J. &amp; Prager, M. The master SN curve method an implementation for fatigue evaluation of welded components in the ASME B&amp;PV code. Section VIII, Division 2 and API 579-1/ASME FFS-1. Welding Res. Council Bulletin 523 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin, W., Chang, K. &amp; Muzaffer, S. Fatigue analysis of cruciform welded joint with weld penetration defects. Eng. Fail. Anal. 120, 105111. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engfailanal.2020.105111 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frendo, F. Analysis of the catastrophic failure of a dockside crane Jib. Eng Fail. Analysis, 31394&#x2013;31411 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Standard Institution. BS7608:2014&#x2009;+&#x2009;A1:2015: Fatigue Design and Assessment of Steel Structures. (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Standard. Eurocode 3: design of steel structures - part 1&#x2013;1: general rules and rules for buildings. (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobbacher, A. F. Recommendations for Fatigue Design of Welded Joints and Components - IIW-Document IIW-2259-15 ex XIII-2460-13/xv-1440-13 (Switzerland, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, P. Residual stresses and distortions in welded structures: a perspective for engineering applications. Sci. Technol. Weld. Join. 10 (4), 389&#x2013;398. https://doi.org/10.1179/174329305X29465 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P., Pei, X., Dong, P. &amp; Song, S. Traction structural stress analysis of fatigue behaviors of rib-to deck joints in orthotropic bridge deck. Int. J. Fatigue. 125, 11&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2019.03.038 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, P., Hong, J. K. &amp; Jesus, A. M. P. D. Analysis of recent fatigue data using the structural stress procedure in ASME div 2 rewrite. Press. Vessel Technol. 129 (3), 355&#x2013;362 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hectors, K., Chaudhuri, S. &amp; Waele, W. D. Fracture mechanics and hot spot stress-based fatigue life calculation: Case study for a crane runway girder. Fatigue Fract. Eng. Mater. Struct. 45 (9), 2662&#x2013;2675. https://doi.org/10.1111/ffe.13729 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Fatigue tests and design of welded hollow spherical joints in grid structures. Struct 65, 106590. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.istruc.2024.106590 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, S. et al. Unified method for predicting the fatigue life of pipe-sphere joints in grid structures. Thin-walled Struct. 203,112209 (2024). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tws.2024.112209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, S. et al. Estimating load spectra probability distributions of train bogie frames by the diffusion-based kernel density method. Int. J. Fatigue. 132, 105352 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez, M. Fatigue of offshore structures: A review of statistical fatigue damage assessment for stochastic loadings. Int. J. Fatigue. 132, 105327 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B. J. et al. Improving the fatigue reliability of metro vehicle bogie frame based on load spectrum. Int. J. Fatigue. 132, 105389 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, F. et al. Digital Twin-driven framework for fatigue life prediction of steel bridges using a probabilistic multiscale model: Application to segmental orthotropic steel deck specimen. Eng. Struct. 241, 112461 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shittu, A. et al. Comparative study between S-N and fracture mechanics approach on reliability assessment of offshore wind turbine jacket foundations. Reliab. Eng. Syst. Saf. 215, 107838. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ress.2021.107838 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Q. et al. Real-time prediction method of fatigue life of bridge crane structure based on digital twin. Fatigue Fract. Eng. Mater. Struct. 442280&#x2013;442306. https://doi.org/10.1111/ffe.13489 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, J. et al. Failure analysis of torsional buckling of all-terrain crane telescopic boom section. Eng. Fail. Anal. 73, 72&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engfailanal.2016.12.006 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, W. et al. Simulation analysis and prevention strategies for fatigue fracture of the swivel shaft in concrete pump trucks. Eng Fail. Analysis 163 Part. B. 108557. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108557 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. Beijing,. Crane design manual, 2nd. 64&#x2013;65 (in Chinese). (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlie, R. B. &amp; Ashok, C. Failure Analysis of Engineering MaterialsNew York, (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hershko, E. et al. Assessment of fatigue striation counting accuracy using high resolution scanning electron microscope. Eng. Fail. Anal. 15, 20&#x2013;27 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster, R. J. et al. Development of a novel methodology to study fatigue properties using the small punch test. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 748, 21&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2019.01.074 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HBM. Calculation of stresses from solid elements. Design Life Theory Guide 294&#x2013;300 (2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>