<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41553156</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1753-8165</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Informatics for health &amp; social care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Inform Health Soc Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A chronic kidney disease prediction system based on Internet of Things using walrus optimized deep learning technique.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>21</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-21</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/17538157.2025.2610695</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Internet of Things (IoT) and cloud computing (CC) concepts are commonly incorporated in healthcare applications. In the healthcare industry, a huge quantity of patient data is generated by IoT devices. The integral storage of mobile devices and processing power is used to analyze the stored data in the cloud. The Internet of Medical Things (IoMT) combines health monitoring mechanisms with medical equipment and sensors to monitor patient records and offer extra smart and experienced healthcare services. This paper proposes an effective and walrus-optimized deep learning (DL) technique for chronic kidney disease (CKD) prediction in IoT. To begin, the data are collected from the CKD dataset, and the preprocessing procedures, such as missing value imputation, numerical conversion, and normalization, are performed to improve the quality of the dataset. Then, dataset balancing is done using the k-means (KM) clustering algorithm to prevent the model from making inaccurate predictions. After that, enhanced residual network 50 (EResNet50) is utilized to extract more discriminative features from the dataset. From that, the optimal features are selected via elite opposition and the Cauchy distribution-based walrus optimization algorithm (ECWOA). Finally, the classification uses the walrus-optimized bidirectional long short-term memory (WOBLSTM). The simulation outcomes demonstrated the effectiveness of our method over existing techniques, with a higher sensitivity of 99.89% for CKD prediction.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M</LastName><ForeName>Sakthimohan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics Engineering (VLSI Design and Technology), Dr. Mahalingam College of Engineering and Technology, Pollachi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M</LastName><ForeName>Thenmozhi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Artificial Intelligence and Data Science, Sri Eshwar College of Engineering, Coimbatore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth Rani</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering (Cyber Security), Dr. Mahalingam College of Engineering and Technology, Pollachi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M</LastName><ForeName>Arun</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, KGiSL Institute of Technology, Coimbatore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Inform Health Soc Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101475011</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1753-8157</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dataset balancing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">internet of medical things</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pre-trained CNN</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41553156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17538157.2025.2610695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>