<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41849402</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>123</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nonmonotonic rate-dependent adhesion of hydrogels.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2536311123</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2536311123</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2536311123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2536311123</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hydrogel adhesion underlies a wide range of biological and engineering functions, yet its rate dependence remains poorly understood. Classical adhesive systems exhibit a monotonic increase in adhesion strength with separation rate, a behavior attributed to bond stress relaxation. Here, we show that hydrogels fundamentally deviate from this paradigm. Using atomic force microscopy-based indentation over six orders of magnitude in retraction rate, we find that the pull-off force first decreases and then increases, revealing a distinctly nonmonotonic rate dependence in hydrogels. To explain this behavior, we develop a quantitative model that couples the deformation of the hydrogel with a rate-dependent traction carried by interfacial bonds with distinct association and dissociation kinetics. The model reproduces the full pull-off force spectrum exhibiting the nonmonotonic behavior and predicts the evolution of the contact radius during detachment. In situ confocal microscopy measurements of contact-area dynamics confirm these predictions, providing independent validation of the kinetic mechanism. Together, the experiments and theory reveal that hydrogel adhesion is governed by a competition between time-dependent bond formation, which strengthens adhesion at slow rates, and limited bond relaxation, which enhances traction at fast rates. This interplay produces a broad intermediate regime in which reduced contact time suppresses bond buildup and weakens adhesion. Our findings identify a previously unrecognized adhesion regime in polymeric materials and provide a unified framework for understanding and designing hydrogel interfaces whose performance depends sensitively on rate, contact history, and interfacial bonding kinetics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Dongjing</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1034-4256</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>George W. Woodruff School of Mechanical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA 30332.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Jiahe</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7301-3652</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA 30332.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yuhang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2274-4903</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>George W. Woodruff School of Mechanical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA 30332.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA 30332.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>N00014-23-1-2754</GrantID><Agency>DOD | USN | Office of Naval Research (ONR)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dynamic bonding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrogel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rate-dependent adhesion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41849402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13011931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2536311123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Burla F., Mulla Y., Vos B. E., Aufderhorst-Roberts A., Koenderink G. H., From mechanical resilience to active material properties in biopolymer networks. Nat. Rev. Phys. 1, 249&#x2013;263 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoh J. H., Schoenenberger C. A., Surface morphology and mechanical properties of MDCK monolayers by atomic force microscopy. J. Cell Sci. 107, 1105&#x2013;1114 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7929621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling E. M., Zauscher S., Guilak F., Viscoelastic properties of zonal articular chondrocytes measured by atomic force microscopy. Osteoarthr. Cartil. 14, 571&#x2013;579 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16478668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S., Costa K. D., Ateshian G. A., Microscale frictional response of bovine articular cartilage from atomic force microscopy. J. Biomech. 37, 1679&#x2013;1687 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15388310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., et al. , Biomechanical properties of murine meniscus surface via AFM-based nanoindentation. J. Biomech. 48, 1364&#x2013;1370 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25817332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Last J. A., Liliensiek S. J., Nealey P. F., Murphy C. J., Determining the mechanical properties of human corneal basement membranes with atomic force microscopy. J. Struct. Biol. 167, 19&#x2013;24 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2747323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19341800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahlsten A., et al. , On the compressibility and poroelasticity of human and murine skin. Biomech. Model. Mechanobiol. 18, 1079&#x2013;1093 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30806838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsimantov J., et al. , Poroelastic characterization and modeling of subcutaneous tissue under confined compression. Ann. Biomed. Eng. 52, 1638&#x2013;1652 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38472602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budday S., et al. , Mechanical properties of gray and white matter brain tissue by indentation. J. Mech. Behav. Biomed. Mater. 46, 318&#x2013;330 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4395547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25819199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller K., Chinzei K., Orssengo G., Bednarz P., Mechanical properties of brain tissue in-vivo: Experiment and computer simulation. J. Biomech. 33, 1369&#x2013;1376 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10940395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L., Myers K., A finite porous-viscoelastic model capturing mechanical behavior of human cervix under multi-step spherical indentation. J. Mech. Behav. Biomed. Mater. 143, 105875 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10330483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37187153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seliktar D., Designing cell-compatible hydrogels for biomedical applications. Science 336, 1124&#x2013;1128 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22654050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malu D., He D., Shi W., Finn M. G., Hu Y., Statistical chain-based model for predicting drug release from degradable hydrogels. Eur. J. Mech. 113, 105699 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T. T., Malu D., He D., Hu Y., Kim J., Development of bioorthogonally degradable tough hydrogels using enamine N -oxide based crosslinkers. Adv. Mater. 37, 2414692 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11962699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40018818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W., et al. , Injectable hydrogels for programmable nanoparticle release. Adv. Funct. Mater. 35, 2409796 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12525862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41104373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K. Y., Mooney D. J., Hydrogels for tissue engineering. Chem. Rev. 101, 1869&#x2013;1880 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11710233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanikawa S., et al. , Engineering of an electrically charged hydrogel implanted into a traumatic brain injury model for stepwise neuronal tissue reconstruction. Sci. Rep. 13, 2233 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9929269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36788295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy A., et al. , Self-assembling peptides with insulin-like growth factor mimicry. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 16, 364&#x2013;375 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11678780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38145951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen M. E., et al. , Biomimetic behaviors in hydrogel artificial cells through embedded organelles. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 120, e2307772120 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10466294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37603747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noor N., et al. , 3D printing of personalized thick and perfusable cardiac patches and hearts. Adv. Sci. 6, 1900344 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6548966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31179230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessier A., Zhuo S., Kabiri Ameri S., Ultrasoft long-lasting reusable hydrogel-based sensor patch for biosignal recording. Biosensors 14, 405 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11352425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39194634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni C., et al. , High speed underwater hydrogel robots with programmable motions powered by light. Nat. Commun. 14, 7672 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10667353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37996451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eddington D. T., Beebe D. J., Flow control with hydrogels. Adv. Drug Deliv. Rev. 56, 199&#x2013;210 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14741116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S., et al. , Stretchable hydrogel electronics and devices. Adv. Mater. 28, 4497&#x2013;4505 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4896855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26639322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ban S., et al. , Recent advances in implantable sensors and electronics using printable materials for advanced healthcare. Biosens. Bioelectron. 257, 116302 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38648705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park K., et al. , Reciprocal discoidin domain receptor signaling strengthens integrin adhesion to connect adjacent tissues. Elife 12, RP87037 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10328527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37405383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S. J., Guillon E., Holley S. A., The roles of inter-tissue adhesion in development and morphological evolution. J. Cell Sci. 135, jcs259579 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9264361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z., Xu W., Zhang T., Luo L., Mechanisms of tendon-bone interface healing: Biomechanics, cell mechanics, and tissue engineering approaches. J. Orthop. Surg. Res. 19, 817 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11613615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39623392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L., et al. , Bioadhesive nanoparticles for local drug delivery. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 23, 2370 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8874699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35216484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H., Li J., Hydrogel adhesives for tissue recovery. Adv. Colloid Interface Sci. 341, 103496 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40168713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J., et al. , Adhesive anti-fibrotic interfaces on diverse organs. Nature 630, 360&#x2013;367 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11168934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38778109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., et al. , Catechol-functionalized hydrogels: Biomimetic design, adhesion mechanism, and biomedical applications. Chem. Soc. Rev. 49, 433&#x2013;464 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7208057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31939475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bovone G., Dudaryeva O. Y., Marco-Dufort B., Tibbitt M. W., Engineering hydrogel adhesion for biomedical applications via chemical design of the junction. ACS Biomater. Sci. Eng. 7, 4048&#x2013;4076 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cond&#xf2; I., Giannitelli S. M., Lo Presti D., Cortese B., Ursini O., Overview of dynamic bond based hydrogels for reversible adhesion processes. Gels 10, 442 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11275299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39057465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., et al. , Programming hydrogel adhesion with engineered polymer network topology. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 120, e2307816120 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10523657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37725650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H., Qu X., Wang Q., Guo Y., Dong X., Dynamic regulation of interfacial adhesion in biomedical hydrogels. Chem. Soc. Rev. 55, 469&#x2013;503 (2026), 10.1039/D5CS00403A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5CS00403A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41327540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Z., et al. , Adhesion mechanism and application progress of hydrogels. Eur. Polym. J. 173, 111277 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., et al. , Bioadhesive chitosan hydrogel with dynamic covalent bonds and sustained kartogenin release for endogenous cartilage regeneration. Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol. 13, 1606726 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12339519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40799372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu K., Li Q., Ji X., Polymer entanglement-induced hydrogel adhesion. Gels 10, 822 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11675780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39727580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai Y., Hu Y., The relation between adhesion properties and network properties of hydrogels: A study based on an indentation adhesion method. Mech. Mater. 159, 103877 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macron J., Bresson B., Tran Y., Hourdet D., Creton C., Equilibrium and out-of-equilibrium adherence of hydrogels against polymer brushes. Macromolecules 51, 7556&#x2013;7566 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuk H., Zhang T., Lin S., Parada G. A., Zhao X., Tough bonding of hydrogels to diverse non-porous surfaces. Nat. Mater. 15, 190&#x2013;196 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4762474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26552058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai Y., He D., Hu Y., Indentation adhesion of hydrogels over a wide range of length and time scales. Extreme Mech. Lett. 31, 100540 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He D., Malu D., Hu Y., A comprehensive review of indentation of gels and soft biological materials. Appl. Mech. Rev. 76, 050802 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Ma Z., Liu S., Li J., Tissue adhesion with tough hydrogels: Experiments and modeling. Mech. Mater. 157, 103800 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee W., Eriten M., Poroviscoelastic relaxations and rate-dependent adhesion in gelatin. Soft Matter 20, 4583&#x2013;4590 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38742525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee W., Eriten M., A note on transients in rate-dependent adhesion of gelatin. Tribol. Lett. 73, 141 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghihnejad A., Zeng H., Hydrophobic interactions between polymer surfaces: Using polystyrene as a model system. Soft Matter 8, 2746 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato N., Aoyama Y., Yamanaka J., Toyotama A., Okuzono T., Particle adsorption on hydrogel surfaces in aqueous media due to van der Waals attraction. Sci. Rep. 7, 6099 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5522479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28733639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X., Cappa T., Kuhlenschmidt T., Kuhlenschmidt M., Saif T., &#x201c;Specific and non-specific adhesion in cancer cells with various metastatic potentials&#x201d; in Mechanobiology of Cell-Cell and Cell-Matrix Interactions, Wagoner Johnson A., Harley B. A. C., Eds. (Springer US, 2011), pp. 105&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boddupalli B., Mohammed Z., Nath R., Banji D., Mucoadhesive drug delivery system: An overview. J. Adv. Pharm. Technol. Res. 1, 381 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22247877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., et al. , Untethered small-scale machines for microrobotic manipulation: From individual and multiple to collective machines. ACS Nano 17, 13081&#x2013;13109 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37440200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derjaguin B., Muller V., Toporov Y., Effect of contact deformation on the adhesion of elastic solids. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 53, 314&#x2013;326 (1975).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K. L., Kendall K., Roberts A. D., Surface energy and the contact of elastic solids. Proc. R. Soc. A Math. Phys. Eng. Sci. 324, 301&#x2013;313 (1971).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maugis D., Adhesion of spheres: The JKR-DMT transition using a dugdale model. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 150, 243&#x2013;269 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciccotti M., Giorgini B., Barquins M., Stick-slip in the peeling of an adhesive tape: Evolution of theoretical model. Int. J. Adhes. Adhes. 18, 35&#x2013;40 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gent A. N., Petrich R. P., Adhesion of viscoelastic materials to rigid substrates. Proc. R. Soc. Lond. A. Math. Phys. Sci. 310, 433&#x2013;448 (1969).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creton C., Ciccotti M., Fracture and adhesion of soft materials: A review. Rep. Prog. Phys. 79, 46601 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27007412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavoie S. R., Long R., Tang T., Rate dependent fracture of a double cantilever beam with combined bulk and interfacial dissipation. Int. J. Solids Struct. 75&#x2013;76, 277&#x2013;286 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Style R. W., Hyland C., Boltyanskiy R., Wettlaufer J. S., Dufresne E. R., Surface tension and contact with soft elastic solids. Nat. Commun. 4, 2728 (2013), 10.1038/ncomms3728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms3728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24201430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X., Jagota A., Hui C. Y., Effects of surface tension on the adhesive contact of a rigid sphere to a compliant substrate. Soft Matter 10, 4625&#x2013;4632 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z., Stevens M. J., Dobrynin A. V., Adhesion and wetting of nanoparticles on soft surfaces. Macromolecules 47, 3203&#x2013;3209 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui C. Y., Liu T., Salez T., Raphael E., Jagota A., Indentation of a rigid sphere into an elastic substrate with surface tension and adhesion. Proc. A 471, 2175 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4353052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25792953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q., et al. , Direct measurement of strain-dependent solid surface stress. Nat. Commun. 8, 1&#x2013;6 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5601460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., et al. , Effects of strain-dependent surface stress on the adhesive contact of a rigid sphere to a compliant substrate. Soft Matter 15, 2223&#x2013;2231 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30758375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T., Jagota A., Hui C., Effect of surface tension on the adhesion between a rigid flat punch and a semi-infinite neo-Hookean half-space. Extrem. Mech. Lett. 9, 310&#x2013;316 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barthel E., On the description of the adhesive contact of spheres with arbitrary interaction potentials. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 200, 7&#x2013;18 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K. L., Contact Mechanics (Cambridge University Press, 1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell G. I., Models for the specific adhesion of cells to cells. Science 200, 618&#x2013;627 (1978).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">347575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans E., Ritchie K., Dynamic strength of molecular adhesion bonds. Biophys. J. 72, 1541&#x2013;1555 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1184350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9083660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J., Wang J., Gao H., Lifetime and strength of adhesive molecular bond clusters between elastic media. Langmuir 24, 1262&#x2013;1270 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18179265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freund L. B., Characterizing the resistance generated by a molecular bond as it is forcibly separated. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 106, 8818&#x2013;8823 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2674939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19416901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhury M. K., Rate-dependent fracture at adhesive interface. J. Phys. Chem. B 103, 6562&#x2013;6566 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T., Yang X., Huang R., Liechti K. M., Rate-dependent traction-separation relations for a silicon/epoxy interface informed by experiments and bond rupture kinetics. J. Mech. Phys. Solids 131, 1&#x2013;19 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y., Zhao X., Vlassak J. J., Suo Z., Using indentation to characterize the poroelasticity of gels. Appl. Phys. Lett. 96, 121904 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier Y. A., Zhang K., Spencer N. D., Simic R., Linking friction and surface properties of hydrogels molded against materials of different surface energies. Langmuir 35, 15805&#x2013;15812 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6899455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31369280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plamper F. A., Richtering W., Functional microgels and microgel systems. Acc. Chem. Res. 50, 131&#x2013;140 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28186408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiyama R., et al. , Nanoscale TEM imaging of hydrogel network architecture. Adv. Mater. 35, 2208902 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36349878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubinstein M., Colby R. H., Polymer Physics (Oxford University Press, New York, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israelachvili J. N., Intermolecular and Surface Forces (Elsevier, ed. 3, 2011), p. 161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>She H., Malotky D., Chaudhury M. K., Estimation of adhesion hysteresis at polymer/oxide interfaces using rolling contact mechanics. Langmuir 14, 3090&#x2013;3100 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cholewinski A., Yang F. K., Zhao B., Underwater contact behavior of alginate and catechol-conjugated alginate hydrogel beads. Langmuir 33, 8353&#x2013;8361 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28787168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghatak A., Vorvolakos K., She H., Malotky D. L., Chaudhury M. K., Interfacial rate processes in adhesion and friction. J. Phys. Chem. B 104, 4018&#x2013;4030 (2000).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>