<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41900604</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Freckle Defects on Hot Deformation Behavior and Dynamic Recrystallization Structure Inheritance of an Iron-Nickel-Based Superalloy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1113</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19061113</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To study the influence of freckle defects on the hot deformation behavior and the inheritance of dynamic recrystallization (DRX) structure in GH4706 alloy, the microstructures of specimens with and without freckles and the evolution laws of hot-processing parameters were compared. Hot compression experiments were conducted on a thermal simulation testing machine at 950-1150 &#xb0;C, strain rates of 0.001-1 s<sup>-1</sup>, and 55% deformation. Freckle-containing specimens were tested under DRX critical conditions. The flow stresses of both specimens increase with strain rate or with decreasing temperature. The power dissipation coefficient (&#x3b7;) and instability value (&#x3be;) follow complex laws. Electron back-scattering diffraction (EBSD) was used to analyze DRX microstructures and nucleation mechanisms. The DRX degree of freckle-containing specimens is lower, with a larger average grain size. The DRX mechanism initiates preferentially in freckle-containing specimens, and its volume fraction changes in a complex manner. Grain coarsening occurs in freckle-containing specimens at high temperatures and low strain rates. Freckle defects lead to significant differences in the DRX mechanism of GH4706 alloy. Freckle-containing specimens exhibit both discontinuous dynamic recrystallization (DDRX) and continuous dynamic recrystallization (CDRX), whereas freckle-free specimens primarily display DDRX and second-phase particle-stimulated nucleation (PSN). The presence of MC carbides and Laves phases within freckle defects provides nucleation sites, further supporting a typical second-phase particle-stimulated nucleation mechanism.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lianjie</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gaona Aero Material Co., Ltd., Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Key Laboratory for Anisotropy and Texture of Materials (Ministry of Education), School of Materials Science and Engineering, Northeastern University, Shenyang 110819, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yuhan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Key Laboratory for Anisotropy and Texture of Materials (Ministry of Education), School of Materials Science and Engineering, Northeastern University, Shenyang 110819, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Key Laboratory for Anisotropy and Texture of Materials (Ministry of Education), School of Materials Science and Engineering, Northeastern University, Shenyang 110819, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gaona Aero Material Co., Ltd., Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shuo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gaona Aero Material Co., Ltd., Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Guohua</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gaona Aero Material Co., Ltd., Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Key Laboratory for Anisotropy and Texture of Materials (Ministry of Education), School of Materials Science and Engineering, Northeastern University, Shenyang 110819, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52371096</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022YFB3705101</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022YFB3705102</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GH4706 alloy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dynamic recrystallization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">freckle defects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hot processing map</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermal deformation behavior</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Lianjie Zhang, Ran Duan, Shuo Huang, and Guohua Xu were employed by the company &#x201c;Gaona Aero Material Co., Ltd.&#x201d; The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41900604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13027906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19061113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19061113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bae J., Kim Y., Kim J., Kim S. Fractographic analysis on fatigue crack propagation behavior of Inconel 706 at 25, 450 and 650 &#xb0;C. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2024;33:5384&#x2013;5396. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.10.194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.10.194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schilke P., Schwant R. Alloy 706 use, process optimization, and future directions for GE gas turbine rotor materials; Proceedings of the 5th International Symposium on Superalloys 718, 625, 706 and Various Derivatives; Pittsburgh, PA, USA. 17&#x2013;20 June 2001; pp. 25&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma P., Chakradhar D., Narendranath S. Effect of wire diameter on surface integrity of wire electrical discharge machined Inconel 706 for gas turbine application. J. Manuf. Process. 2016;24:170&#x2013;178. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2016.09.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2016.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maharaj C., Morris A., Dear J. Modelling of creep in Inconel 706 turbine disc fir-tree. Mater. Sci. Eng. A-Struct. Mater. Prop. Microstruct. Process. 2012;558:412&#x2013;421. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2012.08.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2012.08.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit P., Fesland J. Manufacturing of large in 706 and in 718 forging parts; Proceedings of the International Symposium on Superalloys 718, 625, 706 and Various Derivatives; Pittsburgh, PA, USA. 15&#x2013;18 June 1997; pp. 153&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kindrachuk V., Wanderka N., Banhart J., Mukherji D., Del Genovese D., R&#xf6;sler J. Effect of rhenium addition on the microstructure of the superalloy Inconel 706. Acta Mater. 2008;56:1609&#x2013;1618. doi: 10.1016/j.actamat.2007.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2007.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S., Zhang B., Zhang W., Zhao G., Qi Z. The Abnormal Dynamic Recrystallization Behavior of a Large Alloy 706 Disc; Proceedings of the 9th International Symposium on Superalloy 718 and Derivatives&#x2014;Energy, Aerospace, and Industrial Applications; Champion, PA, USA. 17&#x2013;21 September 2000; pp. 1013&#x2013;1031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider M., Gu J., Beckermann C., Boettinger W., Kattner U. Modeling of micro-and macrosegregation and freckle formation in single-crystal nickel-base superalloy directional solidification. Metall. Mater. Trans. A. 1997;28:1517&#x2013;1531. doi: 10.1007/s11661-997-0214-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11661-997-0214-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J.X., Zhang M.C., Zeng Y.P. Microstructure behavior and freckle characteristics for GH706 superalloy. Rare Met. Mater. Eng. 2006;35:176&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Li D., Zhou Q., Jiang F., Song Y., Liang W., Liu M., Shen X., Wang H. Quantitative Characterization of Elemental Segregation in Inconel 718 Superalloy by Micro-Beam X-ray Fluorescence Spectroscopy and Its Correlation Study. Materials. 2023;16:7163. doi: 10.3390/ma16227163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16227163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10672502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38005090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Gong X., Chou K. Review on powder-bed laser additive manufacturing of Inconel 718 parts. Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. Part B-J. Eng. Manuf. 2017;231:1890&#x2013;1903. doi: 10.1177/0954405415619883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0954405415619883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad K., Obana M., Ito A., Torizuka S. Synchrotron diffraction characterization of dislocation density in additively manufactured IN 718 superalloy. Mater. Charact. 2021;179:10. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2021.111379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2021.111379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koul S., Zhou L., Ahmed O., Sohn Y., Jiang T., Kushima A. In situ TEM Characterization of Microstructure Evolution and Mechanical Behavior of the 3D-Printed Inconel 718 Exposed to High Temperature. Microsc. Microanal. 2021;27:250&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1017/S1431927621000052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1431927621000052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33588959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan C., Zeng Q., Khanlari K., Zhu X., Wang Z. Characterization of microstructure, grain distribution, and tribocorrosion properties of NiTi-based alloy. J. Mater. Sci. 2022;57:21237&#x2013;21250. doi: 10.1007/s10853-022-07927-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-022-07927-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren N., Panwisawas C., Li J., Xia M., Dong H., Li J. Solute enrichment induced dendritic fragmentation in directional solidification of nickel-based superalloys. Acta Mater. 2021;215:13. doi: 10.1016/j.actamat.2021.117043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2021.117043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma D., Li L., Zhao Y., Deng Y., Cheng B., Xu F. Experimental Investigation on Quasi-Freckle Phenomenon in Single-Crystal-Blade Castings of Superalloys. Metals. 2024;14:1129. doi: 10.3390/met14101129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met14101129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Zhao Y., Xiong W., Ma D., Ludwig A., Kharicha A., Wu M. Modelling freckles and spurious grain formation in directionally solidified superalloy castings. Commun. Mater. 2024;5:232. doi: 10.1038/s43246-024-00672-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43246-024-00672-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11489085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39430063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopper N., Luther F., Koll T. Formation Mechanism of Freckles on Zn-Al-Mg Coatings and their Influence on Processing Properties. Corros. Sci. Technol. 2024;23:393&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng N., Horke K., Meyer A., Gotterbarm M.R., Rettig R., Singer R.F. Surface recrystallization and its effect on oxidation of superalloy C263. Corros. Sci. 2017;128:186&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/j.corsci.2017.09.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2017.09.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapelle P., No&#xeb;l C., Risacher A., Jourdan J., Jardy A. Characterization of the behaviour of the electric arc during VAR of a Ti alloy; Proceedings of the International Symposium on Liquid Metal Processing and Casting (LMPC); Leoben, Austria. 20&#x2013;24 September 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez F., Beaman J., Williamson R., Evans D. Controlling pool depth during VAR of Alloy 718; Proceedings of the International Symposium on Liquid Metal Processing and Casting (LMPC); Leoben, Austria. 20&#x2013;24 September 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel A., Fiore D. On the Modeling of Vacuum Arc Remelting Process in Titanium Alloys. IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2016;143:012017. doi: 10.1088/1757-899X/143/1/012017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1757-899X/143/1/012017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tin S., Lee P., Kermanpur A., Rist M., McLean M. Integrated modeling for the manufacture of Ni-based superalloy discs from solidification to final heat treatment. Metall. Mater. Trans. A-Phys. Metall. Mater. Sci. 2005;36A:2493&#x2013;2504. doi: 10.1007/s11661-005-0123-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11661-005-0123-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Jia Y., Wang Y., Zhang Y., Ma L., Cheng F., Zeng Y., Shen X., Du Y., Ge B. New vision of convection induced freckle formation theory in nickel-based superalloys by electron microscopy. Microstructures. 2024;4:2024006. doi: 10.20517/microstructures.2023.47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20517/microstructures.2023.47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Liu Z., Duan Y., Liu C., Li B. Multi-physics coupling model&#x2013;based numerical analysis of the effect of the electric current path on electroslag remelting. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2022;20:3843&#x2013;3859. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.08.135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.08.135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kajikawa K., Sato T., Yamada H. Freckle Formation in Ni-base Superalloys. Tetsu Hagane-J. Iron Steel Inst. Jpn. 2009;95:613&#x2013;619. doi: 10.2355/tetsutohagane.95.613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2355/tetsutohagane.95.613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Practice for Compression Tests of Metallic Materials at Elevated Temperatures with Conventional or Rapid Heating Rates and Strain Rates. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long F., Yoo Y., Jo C., Seo S.M., Jeong H., Song Y., Jin T., Hu Z.Q. Phase transformation of &#x3b7; and &#x3c3; phases in an experimental nickel-based superalloy. J. Alloys Compd. 2009;478:181&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2008.11.121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2008.11.121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonov S., Huo J., Feng Q., Isheim D., Seidman D.N., Helmink R.C., Sun E., Tin S. &#x3c3; and &#x3b7; Phase formation in advanced polycrystalline Ni-base superalloys. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2017;687:232&#x2013;240. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2017.01.064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2017.01.064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schirra J.J., Caless R.H., Hatala R.W. The effect of Laves phase on the mechanical properties. Miner. Met. Mater. Society. 1991:375&#x2013;388. doi: 10.7449/1991/SUPERALLOYS_1991_375_388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7449/1991/SUPERALLOYS_1991_375_388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthymiou E. Numerical and experimental investigation of a reference aluminium bolted joint.  [(accessed on 1 January 2026)];Jordan J. Civ. Eng. 2008 2:4. Available online:  https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:41596742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang L.X., Luo R., Gui Y.W., Cao Y., Chen L.L., Cui Y.J., Bian H.K., Aoyagi K., Yamanaka K., Chiba A. Hot deformation characteristics and dynamic recrystallization mechanisms of a Co-Ni-based superalloy. Mater. Sci. Eng. A-Struct. Mater. Prop. Microstruct. Process. 2020;788:139638. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2020.139638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2020.139638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Zhang W., Xin X., Wang L., Zhu C., Zhu X., Sun W. Microstructure evolution and dynamic recrystallisation behaviour in hot deformation of Haynes 214 superalloy. J. Alloys Compd. 2022;919:165755. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2022.165755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2022.165755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Liu X., Zhang W., Liu P., Guo S., Qin H., Tian Q. Microstructure evolution and dynamic recrystallization mechanism during thermal deformation of GH4698 superalloy. J. Mater. Sci. 2022;57:2969&#x2013;2987. doi: 10.1007/s10853-021-06699-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-021-06699-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S., Sun R., Wang L., Dong D., Duan R., Song X., Liu Y. Microstructure evolution and fracture mechanism of a Fe-Ni-Cr superalloy during various strain rates tensile deformation at elevated temperatures. J. Mater. Sci. 2023;58:5901&#x2013;5920. doi: 10.1007/s10853-023-08368-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-023-08368-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Wu X., Cao L., Liao B., Wang Y., Liu Q. Hot deformation and dynamic recrystallization in Al-Mg-Si alloy. Mater. Charact. 2021;173:110976. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2021.110976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2021.110976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S., Wang L., Lian X.T., Zhang B.J., Zhao G.P. Development of Constitutive Equation and Processing Maps for IN706 Alloy. Acta Metall. Sin. Engl. Lett. 2014;27:198&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1007/s40195-014-0037-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40195-014-0037-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang Q., Yu H., Lee Y.-S., Kim M.-S., Kim H.-W. Hot deformation behavior and microstructure evolution of annealed Al-7.9Zn-2.7Mg-2.0Cu (wt%) alloy. J. Alloys Compd. 2018;763:25&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2018.05.307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2018.05.307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Ye X., Wu T., Yin W., Chen H., Xu J., Zhou X. Effects of Nb addition on the carbides, grain boundary characteristics and tensile properties of a Ni-26W-6Cr-based superalloy. Mater. Sci. Eng. A-Struct. Mater. Prop. Microstruct. Process. 2024;894:11. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2024.146176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2024.146176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Luo H., Wei M., Xiang W., Cui M., Xie J., Guo S., Huang L. Research on hot workability and deformation mechanism of as-extruded Ti-6554 alloy over a broad temperature range. J. Alloys Compd. 2025;1010:177055. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Detrois M., Antonov S., Tin S., Jablonski P.D., Hawk J.A. Hot deformation behavior and flow stress modeling of a Ni-based superalloy. Mater. Charact. 2019;157:109915. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2019.109915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2019.109915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z., Shu X., Xu H., Wang G., Tong F., Li Z., Chen K., Li G., Li B. Hot compression deformation behavior and microstructure evolution of Al-0.5Mg-0.4Si alloy. J. Alloys Compd. 2024;1002:175282. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty A., Roy S. Shear localization and shear banding: A review about the complex interplay between material, microstructural and process variables. Mater. Charact. 2024;218:19. doi: 10.1016/j.matchar.2024.114501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2024.114501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medeiros S., Prasad Y., Frazier W., Srinivasan R. Microstructural modeling of metadynamic recrystallization in hot working of IN 718 superalloy. Mater. Sci. Eng. A-Struct. Mater. Prop. Microstruct. Process. 2000;293:198&#x2013;207. doi: 10.1016/S0921-5093(00)01053-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0921-5093(00)01053-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang K., Log&#xe9; R. A review of dynamic recrystallization phenomena in metallic materials. Mater. Des. 2016;111:548&#x2013;574. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2016.09.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2016.09.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao G., Zang X., Jing Y., Lu N., Wu J. Role of carbides on hot deformation behavior and dynamic recrystallization of hard-deformed superalloy U720Li. Mater. Sci. Eng. A-Struct. Mater. Prop. Microstruct. Process. 2021;815:9. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2021.141293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2021.141293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu T., Liu X., Zhang W., Tian Q. Microstructure evolution and fracture characteristics of GH4079 superalloy during high-temperature tensile process. Mater. Sci. Eng. A-Struct. Mater. Prop. Microstruct. Process. 2024;918:14. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2024.147450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2024.147450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K., Rui S., Wang F., Dong J., Yao Z. Microstructure and homogenization process of as-cast GH4169D alloy for novel turbine disk. Int. J. Miner. Metall. Mater. 2019;26:889&#x2013;900. doi: 10.1007/s12613-019-1802-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12613-019-1802-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Z.J., Shan A.D., Wu Y., Lu J., Xu W., Song H.W. Quantitative analysis of homogenization treatment of INCONEL718 superalloy. Trans. Nonferrous Met. Soc. China. 2011;21:1009&#x2013;1017. doi: 10.1016/S1003-6326(11)60814-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1003-6326(11)60814-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Z.J., Shan A.D., Lu J., Song H.W. Segregation and diffusion characterization in two-stage homogenisation of conventional superalloy. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2011;27:1551. doi: 10.1179/026708310X12815992418139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/026708310X12815992418139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emdadi A., Yang Y., Bolz S., Stryzhyboroda O., Tovar M., Gein S., Hecht U., Wei S. Mechanisms of necklace recrystallization in a BCC Fe-Al-Ta alloy with strengthening Laves phase precipitates. Scr. Mater. 2023;237:6. doi: 10.1016/j.scriptamat.2023.115705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scriptamat.2023.115705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du J., Bi Z., Qu J. Recent Development of Triple Melt GH4169 Alloy. Acta Metall. Sin. 2023;59:1159&#x2013;1172. doi: 10.11900/0412.1961.2023.00144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11900/0412.1961.2023.00144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allain-Bonasso N., Wagner F., Berbenni S., Field D. A study of the heterogeneity of plastic deformation in IF steel by EBSD. Mater. Sci. Eng. A-Struct. Mater. Prop. Microstruct. Process. 2012;548:56&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2012.03.068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2012.03.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan C., Feng A., Qu S., Cao G., Sun J., Shen J., Chen D. Dynamic recrystallization of titanium: Effect of pre-activated twinning at cryogenic temperature. Acta Mater. 2018;154:311&#x2013;324. doi: 10.1016/j.actamat.2018.05.057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2018.05.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irukuvarghula S., Hassanin H., Cayron C., Attallah M., Stewart D., Preuss M. Evolution of grain boundary network topology in 316L austenitic stainless steel during powder hot isostatic pressing. Acta Mater. 2017;133:269&#x2013;281. doi: 10.1016/j.actamat.2017.04.068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2017.04.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L., Xu P., Wang P., Guo Y., Li Y., Ren J., Zhou L., Liang Y., Liang Y. Dissolution of &#x3b7; phase and evolution of dynamically recrystallized grains in ATI 718Plus superalloy during hot compressive deformation. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2024;30:4612&#x2013;4624. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.04.172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.04.172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S., Wang L., Zhang B., Zhang W., Zhao G. Dynamic recrystallization and grain control of GH4706 alloy. Chin. J. Mater. Res. 2014;28:362&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>