<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41444821</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Two secure authentication protocols for mitigating vulnerabilities in IoD.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3132</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3132</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3132</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-33020-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Internet of Drones (IoD) is a network layer control system that manages the communication of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs). Drones have emerged as a novel approach to addressing everyday human challenges and are now used in a variety of domains, such as personal activities (e.g., photography and videography), urban applications (e.g., traffic monitoring and structural inspection), commercial operations (e.g., power line and tower inspection), agriculture, and military operations. Given the rapid growth of UAVs and their expanding applications, interconnecting drones to form an IoD is a desirable trend for enhancing flight safety and quality. However, challenges related to security, privacy, and inter-drone communication remain significant obstacles. Numerous authentication protocols have been developed to address these concerns. Recently, Zhang et al. proposed a PUF-based authentication scheme that uses unique identifiers and hash functions to secure authentication in the IoD environment. However, in this paper, we demonstrate that Zhang et al.'s scheme is vulnerable to several attacks, including secret value disclosure, integrity violation, key extraction, traceability, and anonymity violation. The presented attacks are shown to have a success probability of one. We also introduce two enhanced protocols that, through both informal and formal security proofs using the Scyther tool, demonstrate that they do not suffer from the vulnerabilities found in the earlier protocol. The communication costs of the proposed protocols (a) and (b) have increased by [Formula: see text] and [Formula: see text], respectively, compared to the previous protocol. The computational costs for the proposed protocols (a) and (b) have also increased by [Formula: see text] and [Formula: see text], respectively, while the storage costs in both proposed protocols remain unchanged compared to the previous protocol. It is true that the costs in the proposed protocols have risen; however, the previous design was vulnerable to various attacks, whereas the proposed protocols have demonstrated better security and have successfully achieved all their security objectives.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Safkhani</LastName><ForeName>Masoumeh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Shahid Rajaee Teacher Training University, Tehran, 16788-15811, Iran. Safkhani@sru.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Institute for Research in Fundamental Sciences (IPM), Tehran, Iran. Safkhani@sru.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghorbani Fard</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Shahid Rajaee Teacher Training University, Tehran, 16788-15811, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>1404/385773</GrantID><Agency>Shahid Rajaee Teacher Training University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anonymity violation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Authentication protocol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Integrity contradiction attack</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IoD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scyther</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Session key disclosure attack</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflicts of interest: The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest. The founding sponsors had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analysis, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the manuscript, and in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41444821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12830610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-33020-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-33020-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kumar, V., Ahmad, M. &amp; Kumari, A. A secure elliptic curve cryptography based mutual authentication protocol for cloud-assisted TMIS. <i>Telemat. Inform.</i><b>38</b>, 100&#x2013;117 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tele.2018.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, N. &amp; Dhiman, P. A survey on IoT security: Challenges and their solutions using machine learning and blockchain technology. <i>Clust. Comput.</i><b>28</b>, 313 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10586-025-05208-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, N. &amp; Dhiman, P. A secure addressing mutual authentication scheme for smart IoT home network. <i>Multimed. Tools Appl.</i><b>84</b>, 25111&#x2013;25143 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-024-19898-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, N. &amp; Dhiman, P. Lightweight privacy preserving scheme for IoT based smart home. <i>Recent. Adv. Electr. Electron. Eng. (Former. Recent. Pat. Electr. Electron. Eng.)</i><b>17</b>, 763&#x2013;777 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, N. &amp; Dhiman, P. Design of secure and unique addressing with mutual authentication scheme in IoT networks. <i>Peer-To-Peer Netw. Appl.</i><b>18</b>, 50 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12083-024-01882-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharibi, M., Boutaba, R. &amp; Waslander, S. L. Internet of drones. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>4</b>, 1148&#x2013;1162 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2016.2537208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derhab, A. et al. Internet of drones security: Taxonomies, open issues, and future directions. <i>Veh. Commun.</i><b>39</b>, 100552 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svaigen, A. R., Boukerche, A., Ruiz, L. B. &amp; Loureiro, A. A. Design guidelines of the internet of drones location privacy protocols. <i>IEEE Internet Things Mag.</i><b>5</b>, 175&#x2013;180 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/IOTM.008.2100131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. PRLAP-IoD: A PUF-based robust and lightweight authentication protocol for internet of drones. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>238</b>, 110118 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2023.110118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanveer, M., Alasmary, H., Kumar, N. &amp; Nayak, A. SAAF-IoD: Secure and anonymous authentication framework for the internet of drones. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>73</b>(1), 232&#x2013;244 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2023.3306813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irshad, A. et al. SUSIC: A secure user access control mechanism for SDN-enabled IIoT and cyber-physical systems. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>10</b>, 16504&#x2013;16515 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2023.3268474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmood, K. et al. A security enhanced chaotic-map based authentication protocol for internet of drones. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>11</b>(12), 22301&#x2013;22309 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3379930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivas, J., Das, A. K., Wazid, M. &amp; Vasilakos, A. V. Designing secure user authentication protocol for big data collection in IoT-based intelligent transportation system. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>8</b>, 7727&#x2013;7744 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2020.3040938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkanovi&#x107;, M., Brumen, B. &amp; H&#xf6;lbl, M. A novel user authentication and key agreement scheme for heterogeneous ad hoc wireless sensor networks, based on the internet of things notion. <i>Ad Hoc Netw.</i><b>20</b>, 96&#x2013;112 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.adhoc.2014.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porambage, P., Schmitt, C., Kumar, P., Gurtov, A. &amp; Ylianttila, M. Two-phase authentication protocol for wireless sensor networks in distributed IoT applications. In <i>2014 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC)</i>, 2728&#x2013;2733 (IEEE, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzahrani, B. A., Barnawi, A. &amp; Chaudhry, S. A. A resource-friendly authentication protocol for UAV-based massive crowd management systems. <i>Secur. Commun. Netw.</i><b>2021</b>, 3437373 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/3437373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivas, J., Das, A. K., Kumar, N. &amp; Rodrigues, J. J. TCALAS: Temporal credential-based anonymous lightweight authentication scheme for internet of drones environment. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>68</b>, 6903&#x2013;6916 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2019.2911672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Liu, T., Tang, F. &amp; Tinashe, M. An unlinkable authentication scheme for distributed IoT application. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>7</b>, 14757&#x2013;14766 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2893918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wazid, M., Das, A. K., Kumar, N., Vasilakos, A. V. &amp; Rodrigues, J. J. Design and analysis of secure lightweight remote user authentication and key agreement scheme in internet of drones deployment. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>6</b>, 3572&#x2013;3584 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2018.2888821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanveer, M. et al. PAF-IoD: PUF-enabled authentication framework for the internet of drones. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>73</b>(7), 9560&#x2013;9574 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2024.3365992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. &amp; Preneel, B. AEGIS: a fast authenticated encryption algorithm. In <i>Selected Areas in Cryptography&#x2013;SAC 2013: 20th International Conference, Burnaby, BC, Canada, August 14-16, 2013, Revised Selected Papers 20</i>, 185&#x2013;201 (Springer, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., He, D., Li, L. &amp; Chen, B. A lightweight authentication and key agreement scheme for internet of drones. <i>Comput. Commun.</i><b>154</b>, 455&#x2013;464 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comcom.2020.02.067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, A., Tripathi, M., Shaikh, T. J. &amp; Sharma, A. A lightweight anonymous user authentication and key establishment scheme for wearable devices. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>149</b>, 29&#x2013;42 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2018.11.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, J., Son, S., Kwon, D. &amp; Park, Y. A PUF-based secure authentication and key agreement scheme for the internet of drones. <i>Sensors</i><b>25</b>, 982 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25030982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11820592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39943621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, M., Narwal, B., Anand, R., Mohapatra, A. K. &amp; Yadav, R. PSECAS: A physical unclonable function based secure authentication scheme for internet of drones. <i>Comput. Electr. Eng.</i><b>108</b>, 108662 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2023.108662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modarres, A. M. A. &amp; Sarbishaei, G. Enhancing internet of drones security: A robust multi-factor authentication and key establishment protocol. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i>10.1109/TVT.2025.3591497 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2025.3591497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyangaresi, V. O., Ahmad, M., Maghrabi, L. A. &amp; Althaqafi, T. Cost-effective PUF and ECC based authentication protocol for secure internet of drones communication. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>12</b>, 33844&#x2013;33857 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3576313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang, K.-H. et al. A physically unclonable function using soft oxide breakdown featuring 0% native ber and 51.8 fj/bit in 40-nm cmos. <i>IEEE J. Solid-State Circuits</i><b>54</b>, 2765&#x2013;2776 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSSC.2019.2920714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolev, D. &amp; Yao, A. On the security of public key protocols. <i>IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory</i><b>29</b>, 198&#x2013;208 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIT.1983.1056650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan, R.C.-W. Cryptanalysis of a new ultralightweight RFID authentication protocol&#x2013;SASI. <i>IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput.</i><b>6</b>, 316&#x2013;320 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2008.33</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreitzer, R., Moonsamy, V., Korak, T. &amp; Mangard, S. Systematic classification of side-channel attacks: A case study for mobile devices. <i>IEEE Commun. Surv. &amp; Tutor.</i><b>20</b>, 465&#x2013;488 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/COMST.2017.2779824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messerges, T. S., Dabbish, E. A. &amp; Sloan, R. H. Examining smart-card security under the threat of power analysis attacks. <i>IEEE Trans. Comput.</i><b>51</b>, 541&#x2013;552 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TC.2002.1004593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Mulder, E. <i>et al.</i> Electromagnetic analysis attack on an FPGA implementation of an elliptic curve cryptosystem. In <i>EUROCON 2005-The International Conference on &#x201c;Computer as a Tool&#x201d;</i>, vol.&#xa0;<b>2</b>, 1879&#x2013;1882 (IEEE, 2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gope, P. PMAKE: Privacy-aware multi-factor authenticated key establishment scheme for advance metering infrastructure in smart grid. <i>Comput. Commun.</i><b>152</b>, 338&#x2013;344 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comcom.2019.12.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahavori, M. &amp; Moazami, F. Lightweight and secure PUF-based authenticated key agreement scheme for smart grid. <i>Peer-to-Peer Netw. Appl.</i><b>13</b>, 1616&#x2013;1628 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12083-020-00911-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>