<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41395833</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3732</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of craniofacial surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Craniofac Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prediction Model of Prolonged Length of Stay in Orthognathic Surgery: A Retrospective Cohort Study Under ERAS Pathways.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SCS.0000000000012258</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to identify the factors influencing prolonged hospital stay in patients undergoing orthognathic surgery (OS) and to construct a predictive model aligned with the Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) protocol. The goal was to facilitate the development of personalized rehabilitation plans and optimize medical resource allocation. This was a retrospective study. Clinical data from OS patients treated between July 2018 and December 2023 were retrospectively reviewed. Demographic characteristics, surgical details, and postoperative recovery parameters were analyzed. The data set was randomly partitioned into a training set and a validation set at a 7:3 ratio. Potential predictors were first screened using univariate analysis, and those with statistical significance were subsequently included in a multivariate logistic regression analysis to construct the predictive model. The model's discriminative ability was assessed using the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve, while its calibration was evaluated with the Hosmer-Lemeshow test. Independent predictive factors for prolonged hospital stay in OS patients included age, surgical duration, time to first oral intake, time to first ambulation, and other factors (n=7). The area under the ROC curve (AUC) was 0.790, corresponding to a sensitivity of 60.9%, a specificity of 84.7%, and a Youden index of 0.456, indicating a fair to good predictive ability. The Hosmer-Lemeshow test indicated good calibration (P=0.215). The predictive model established in this study demonstrated fair to good predictive power for prolonged hospital stay following OS. It shows potential in identifying high-risk patients early in the postoperative period, enabling targeted interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by Mutaz B. Habal, MD.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jiayu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, State Key Laboratory of Oral and Maxillofacial Reconstruction and Regeneration and National Clinical Research Center for Oral Diseases and Shaanxi Engineering Research, Center for Dental Materials and Advanced Manufacture, School of Stomatology, The Fourth Military Medical University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yufei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Fan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Tiantian</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Craniofac Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9010410</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1049-2275</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enhanced recovery after surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hospital length of stay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthognathic surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perioperative management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">predictive model</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41395833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SCS.0000000000012258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001665-990000000-03517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Weiss RO, Ong AA, Reddy LV, et al. Orthognathic surgery-LeFort I Osteotomy. Facial Plast Surg 2021;37:703&#x2013;708</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly JF, Helfrick JF, Smith DW, et al. A survey of oral and maxillofacial surgeons concerning their knowledge, beliefs, attitudes, and behavior relative to parameters of care. J Oral Maxillofac Surg 1992;50:50&#x2013;58</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uribe FA, Farrell B. Surgery-first approach in the orthognathic patient. Oral Maxillofac Surg Clin North Am 2020;32:89&#x2013;103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loureiro RM, Collin J, Sumi DV, et al. Postoperative CT findings of orthognathic surgery and its complications: a guide for radiologists. J Neuroradiol 2022;49:17&#x2013;32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydil BA, Akba&#x15f; M, Ayhan M, et al. Retrospective examination of complications observed in orthognathic surgery in 85 patients. Ulus Travma Acil Cerrahi Derg 2022;28:698&#x2013;702</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaroni FM, Cavalcante RC, Jo&#xe3;o da Costa D, et al. Complications associated with orthognathic surgery: a retrospective study of 485 cases. J Craniomaxillofac Surg 2019;47:1855&#x2013;1860</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JY, Jiao YQ. Application of enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) concept in the anesthesia recovery period of orthognathic surgery. Practical Clin Med 2018;2018:91&#x2013;93; 98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Medical Association, Surgical Branch, Chinese Medical Association, Anesthesiology Branch. Expert consensus on enhanced recovery after surgery in China and pathway management guidelines (2018). Chin J Anesthesiol 2018;38:8&#x2013;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao H, Chen YJ, Gu XP, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for enhanced recovery after surgery in China (2021 version). Chin J Pract Surg 2021;41:961&#x2013;992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ljungqvist O, Scott M, Fearon KC. Enhanced recovery after surgery: a review. JAMA Surg 2017;152:292&#x2013;298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson UO, Scott MJ, Schwenk W, et al. ERAS: A consensus review of the evidence for enhanced recovery after surgery in colorectal surgery. World J Surg 2019;43:568&#x2013;583</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ljungqvist O, Young-Fadok T, Demartines N. The history of enhanced recovery after surgery and the ERAS society. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech A 2017;27:860&#x2013;862</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He DY, Fan Z, Wu YF, et al. The impact of enhanced recovery after surgery clinical pathways on the outcomes of orthognathic surgery patients: a retrospective study. J Air Force Med Univ 2023;44:819&#x2013;825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang HC, Xu YN. What still needs to be done by today&#x2019;s surgeons for ERAS development? Chin J Surg 2021;59:2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venugoplan SR, Nanda V, Turkistani K, et al. Discharge patterns of orthognathic surgeries in the United States. J Oral Maxillofac Surg 2012;70:e77&#x2013;e86</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song GD, Yang P, Hu J, et al. The effect of tranexamic acid on blood loss in orthognathic surgery: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol 2013;115:595&#x2013;600</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowe CM, Gurney B, Sloane J, et al. Operative time, length of stay, and reoperation rates for orthognathic surgery. Br J Oral Maxillofac Surg 2021;59:163&#x2013;167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H. Sample size determination and power analysis using the G*Power software. J Educ Eval Health Prof 2021;18:17; Epub 2021 Jul 30. PMID: 34325496; PMCID: PMC8441096</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Chen YJ, Dong HL, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery: China expert consensus and pathway management guidelines (2018 version). Chin J Pract Surg 2018;38:1&#x2013;20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xun ZM, Shang HT, Li XY, et al. Promoting the practice of ERAS in orthognathic surgery. Chin Health Qual Manag 2020;27:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma JC, Shang LP, Li SH, et al. Meta-analysis of risk factors for prolonged hospital stay in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. J PLA Nurs 2022;39:60&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peacock ZS, Lee CCY, Klein KP, et al. Orthognathic surgery in patients over 40 years of age: indications and special considerations. J Oral Maxillofac Surg 2014;72:1995&#x2013;2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huaman ET, Juvet LM, Nastri A, et al. Changing patterns of hospital length of stay after orthognathic surgery. J Oral Maxillofac Surg 2008;66:492&#x2013;497</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarab F, Omar E, Bhayat A, et al. Duration of hospital stay following orthognathic surgery at the Jordan University Hospital. J Maxillofac Oral Surg 2012;11:314&#x2013;318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen K, Thastum M, N&#xf8;rholt SE, et al. Relative blood loss and operative time can predict length of stay following orthognathic surgery. Int J Oral Maxillofac Surg 2016;45:1209&#x2013;1212</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Han D, Hu X, et al. Perioperative liberal drinking management promotes postoperative gastrointestinal function recovery after gynecological laparoscopic surgery: A randomized controlled trial. J Clin Anesth 2024;97:111539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Jiang Z, Xu R, et al. Application and Effect Evaluation of Precision Nursing Care of Enhanced Rehabilitation After Surgery in the Perioperative Period of Colorectal Cancer. Journal of Sichuan University (Medical Science Edition) 2023;54:746&#x2013;751</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Ji G, Tao K, et al. Application of laparoscopic and open gastrectomy in enhanced recovery after surgery for gastric cancer: analysis of data from multiple centers in China. Nan Fang yi ke da xue xue bao. Journal of Southern Medical University 2021;41:1828&#x2013;1834</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai L, Wang XY, Su X, et al. Research progress on early out-of-bed activity after vertebroplasty under the concept of enhanced recovery after surgery. Nursing Sci 2023;12:980&#x2013;987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagenson AM, Gleeson EM, Lau KKN, et al. Early drain removal after hepatectomy: an underutilized management strategy. HPB 2020;22:1463&#x2013;1470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Chen X, Fang L, et al. Study on the indwelling time of urinary catheter after laparoscopic ureteral repair: a single-center retrospective study of 100 cases. Clin Urol J 2023;38:99&#x2013;102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown L, Gray M, Griffiths B, et al. A multicentre, prospective, observational cohort study of variation in practice in perioperative analgesia strategies in elective laparoscopic colorectal surgery (the LapCoGesic study). Ann R Coll Surg Engl 2020;102:28&#x2013;35</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirz S, Seidensticker S, Shtrichman R, et al. Patient-Controlled Analgesia (PCA): Intravenous Administration (IV-PCA) versus Oral Administration (Oral-PCA) by Using a Novel Device (PCoA&#xae; Acute) for Hospitalized Patients with Acute Postoperative Pain&#x2014;A Comparative Retrospective Study. Pain Res Manag 2021;2021:2542010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JD, Hu QF, Zheng PY, et al. Effect of intelligent patient-controlled intravenous analgesia in elderly patients after laparoscopic radical resection of colorectal cancer. J Clin Anesthesiol 2022;38:341&#x2013;345</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>