<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41755222</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Young White Pine Detection Using UAV Imagery and Deep Learning Object Detection Models.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1284</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26041284</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study demonstrates the power of combining unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) imagery and deep learning (DL) for monitoring forest regeneration, specifically focusing on young white pine (<i>Pinus strobus</i>). Using high-resolution three-band RGB and five-band multispectral orthomosaics derived from UAV flights, 20 DL object-detection models were evaluated within ArcGIS Pro 3.4 software (Esri Inc., Redlands, CA, USA). The models were tested across study sites in St. Lawrence County, NY, to assess performance on three distinct size classes of white pine, each stratified into low, medium, and high density areas. The Faster R-CNN (F-RCNN) model, particularly when trained with image rotation and no augmentation, significantly outperformed others, achieving an average precision of 0.88 across both imagery types. Subsequent confusion matrix analysis yielded 91% and 90% overall accuracy in medium and high-density white pine blocks, respectively. These findings validate the use of UAV-DL systems as an accurate and efficient tool for operational white pine regeneration assessment, reducing the need for labor-intensive fieldwork.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poudel</LastName><ForeName>Abishek</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3105-5285</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sustainable Resources Management, State University of New York College of Environmental Science and Forestry, Syracuse, NY 13210, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bevilacqua</LastName><ForeName>Eddie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0194-0531</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sustainable Resources Management, State University of New York College of Environmental Science and Forestry, Syracuse, NY 13210, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">F-RCNN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">confusion matrix</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forest monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">regeneration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41755222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12944172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26041284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26041284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chadwick A.J., Goodbody T.R.H., Coops N.C., Hervieux A., Bater C.W., Martens L.A., White B., R&#xf6;eser D. Automatic Delineation and Height Measurement of Regenerating Conifer Crowns under Leaf-Off Conditions Using UAV Imagery. Remote Sens. 2020;12:4104. doi: 10.3390/rs12244104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12244104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadwick A.J., Coops N.C., Johnson K.M., Bater C.W., Martens L.A., R&#xf6;eser D., White B. A Remote Sensing Methodology for Sub-Stand Growth and Yield Projection of Post-Harvest Forest Regeneration. For. Int. J. For. Res. 2025;98:454&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1093/forestry/cpae051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/forestry/cpae051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozderya M.A. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. The State University of New York College of Environmental Science and Forestry; New York, NY, USA: 2020. Evaluation of Unmanned Aerial Systems (UAS) Imagery for Forest Regeneration Surveys.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Carrasco M., Karelovic B., Molina R., Saavedra R., Cerulo P., Cabrera-Vives G. Precision Silviculture: Use of UAVs and Comparison of Deep Learning Models for the Identification and Segmentation of Tree Crowns in Pine Crops. Int. J. Digit. Earth. 2022;15:2223&#x2013;2238. doi: 10.1080/17538947.2022.2152882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17538947.2022.2152882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J., Yuan S., Li W., Fu H., Yu L., Huang J. A Review of Individual Tree Crown Detection and Delineation From Optical Remote Sensing Images: Current Progress and Future. IEEE Geosci. Remote Sens. Mag. 2025;13:209&#x2013;236. doi: 10.1109/MGRS.2024.3479871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MGRS.2024.3479871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodbody T.R.H., Coops N.C., Hermosilla T., Tompalski P., Crawford P. Assessing the Status of Forest Regeneration Using Digital Aerial Photo Grammetry and Unmanned Aerial Systems. Int. J. Remote Sens. 2017;39:5246&#x2013;5264. doi: 10.1080/01431161.2017.1402387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2017.1402387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green P.C., Burkhart H.E. Plantation Loblolly Pine Seedling Counts with Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Imagery: A Case Study. J. For. 2020;118:487&#x2013;500. doi: 10.1093/jofore/fvaa020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jofore/fvaa020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan M., Leite R.V., Broadbent E.N., Wan Mohd Jaafar W.S., Srinivasan S., Bajaj S., Dalla Corte A.P., Do Amaral C.H., Gopan G., Saad S.N.M., et al. Individual Tree Detection Using UAV-Lidar and UAV-SfM Data: A Tutorial for Beginners. Open Geosci. 2021;13:1028&#x2013;1039. doi: 10.1515/geo-2020-0290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/geo-2020-0290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fromm M., Schubert M., Castilla G., Linke J., McDermid G.J. Automated Detection of Conifer Seedlings in Drone Imagery Using Convolutional Neural Networks. Remote Sens. 2019;11:2585. doi: 10.3390/rs11212585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs11212585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Z., Lin L., Post C.J., Jiang Y., Li M., Wei N., Yu K., Liu J. Assessing Tree Height and Density of a Young Forest Using a Consumer Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) New For. 2021;52:843&#x2013;862. doi: 10.1007/s11056-020-09827-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11056-020-09827-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan M., Silva C., Klauberg C., Jat P., Catts G., Cardil A., Hudak A., Dia M. Individual Tree Detection from Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) Derived Canopy Height Model in an Open Canopy Mixed Conifer Forest. Forests. 2017;8:340. doi: 10.3390/f8090340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f8090340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Y., Zhang W., Quackenbush L.J. Active Contour and Hill Climbing for Tree Crown Detection and Delineation. Photogramm. Eng. Remote Sens. 2010;76:1169&#x2013;1181. doi: 10.14358/PERS.76.10.1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14358/PERS.76.10.1169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Y., Quackenbush L.J. A Review of Methods for Automatic Individual Tree-Crown Detection and Delineation from Passive Remote Sensing. Int. J. Remote Sens. 2011;32:4725&#x2013;4747. doi: 10.1080/01431161.2010.494184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2010.494184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhen Z., Quackenbush L.J., Zhang L. Trends in Automatic Individual Tree Crown Detection and Delineation&#x2014;Evolution of LiDAR Data. Remote Sens. 2016;8:333. doi: 10.3390/rs8040333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs8040333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diez Y., Kentsch S., Fukuda M., Caceres M.L.L., Moritake K., Cabezas M. Deep Learning in Forestry Using UAV-Acquired RGB Data: A Practical Review. Remote Sens. 2021;13:2837. doi: 10.3390/rs13142837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13142837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kattenborn T., Leitloff J., Schiefer F., Hinz S. Review on Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) in Vegetation Remote Sensing. ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens. 2021;173:24&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2020.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2020.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulido D., Salas J., R&#xf6;s M., Puettmann K., Karaman S. Assessment of Tree Detection Methods in Multispectral Aerial Images. Remote Sens. 2020;12:2379. doi: 10.3390/rs12152379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12152379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou X., Huang Y., Fang L., Huang S., Gao H., Yang L., Weng Y., Hung I.-K. uai Measuring Loblolly Pine Crowns with Drone Imagery through Deep Learning. J. For. Res. 2022;33:227&#x2013;238. doi: 10.1007/s11676-021-01328-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11676-021-01328-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopatin E., Poikonen P. Cost-Effective Aerial Inventory of Spruce Seedlings Using Consumer Drones and Deep Learning Techniques with Two-Stage UAV Flight Patterns. Forests. 2023;14:973. doi: 10.3390/f14050973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14050973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braga J.R.G., Peripato V., Dalagnol R., Ferreira M.P., Tarabalka Y., Arag&#xe3;o L.E.O.C., Velho H.F.d.C., Shiguemori E.H., Wagner F.H. Tree Crown Delineation Algorithm Based on a Convolutional Neural Network. Remote Sens. 2020;12:1288. doi: 10.3390/rs12081288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12081288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Z., Lin L., Post C.J., Mikhailova E.A., Li M., Chen Y., Yu K., Liu J. Automated Tree-Crown and Height Detection in a Young Forest Plantation Using Mask Region-Based Convolutional Neural Network (Mask R-CNN) ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens. 2021;178:112&#x2013;123. doi: 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2021.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2021.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moharram D., Yuan X., Li D. Tree Seedlings Detection and Counting Using a Deep Learning Algorithm. Appl. Sci. 2023;13:895. doi: 10.3390/app13020895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13020895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein B.G., Marconi S., Bohlman S., Zare A., White E. Individual Tree-Crown Detection in RGB Imagery Using Semi-Supervised Deep Learning Neural Networks. Remote Sens. 2019;11:1309. doi: 10.3390/rs11111309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs11111309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu K., Hao Z., Post C.J., Mikhailova E.A., Lin L., Zhao G., Tian S., Liu J. Comparison of Classical Methods and Mask R-CNN for Automatic Tree Detection and Mapping Using UAV Imagery. Remote Sens. 2022;14:295. doi: 10.3390/rs14020295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14020295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang W., Ho H.W., Zhou Y., Suandi S.A., Ismail F. A Comprehensive Review on Tree Detection Methods Using Point Cloud and Aerial Imagery from Unmanned Aerial Vehicles. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2024;227:109476. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2024.109476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2024.109476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadwick A., Coops N.C., Bater C.W., Martens L.A., White B.C. Species Classification of Automatically Delineated Regenerating Conifer Crowns Using RGB and Near-Infrared UAV Imagery. IEEE Geosci. Remote Sens. Lett. 2022;19:2502205. doi: 10.1109/LGRS.2021.3123552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LGRS.2021.3123552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Pu Z., Luo L., Wang L., Gao J. A Study on Tree Species Recognition in UAV Remote Sensing Imagery Based on an Improved YOLOv11 Model. Appl. Sci. 2025;15:8779. doi: 10.3390/app15168779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15168779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasana C., Pasini S., Milani F., Fraternali P. Weakly Supervised Object Detection for Remote Sensing Images: A Survey. Remote Sens. 2022;14:5362. doi: 10.3390/rs14215362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14215362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finn A., Kumar P., Peters S., O&#x2019;Hehir J. Unsupervised Spectral-Spatial Processing of Drone Imagery for Identification of Pine Seedlings. ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens. 2022;183:363&#x2013;388. doi: 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2021.11.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2021.11.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayathunga S., Pearse G.D., Watt M.S. Unsupervised Methodology for Large-Scale Tree Seedling Mapping in Diverse Forestry Settings Using UAV-Based RGB Imagery. Remote Sens. 2023;15:5276. doi: 10.3390/rs15225276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15225276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailly A., Blanc C., Francis &#xc9;., Guillotin T., Jamal F., Wakim B., Roy P. Effects of Dataset Size and Interactions on the Prediction Performance of Logistic Regression and Deep Learning Models. Comput. Methods Programs Biomed. 2022;213:106504. doi: 10.1016/j.cmpb.2021.106504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2021.106504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34798408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoph B., Cubuk E.D., Ghiasi G., Lin T.-Y., Shlens J., Le Q.V. Learning Data Augmentation Strategies for Object Detection. In: Vedaldi A., Bischof H., Brox T., Frahm J.-M., editors. Computer Vision&#x2014;ECCV 2020. Volume 12372. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2020. pp. 566&#x2013;583. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ESRI Export Training Data For Deep Learning (Image Analyst)&#x2014;ArcGIS Pro|Documentation.  [(accessed on 16 March 2025)].  Available online:  https://pro.arcgis.com/en/pro-app/latest/tool-reference/image-analyst/export-training-data-for-deep-learning.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T.-Y., Goyal P., Girshick R., He K., Dollar P. Focal Loss for Dense Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision; Venice, Italy. 22&#x2013;29 October 2017; pp. 2980&#x2013;2988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S., He K., Girshick R., Sun J. Proceedings of the Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems. Volume 28 Curran Associates, Inc.; Red Hook, NY, USA: 2015. Faster R-CNN: Towards Real-Time Object Detection with Region Proposal Networks.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang J., Chen K., Shi J., Feng H., Ouyang W., Lin D. Libra R-Cnn: Towards Balanced Learning for Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Long Beach, CA, USA. 15&#x2013;20 June 2019; pp. 821&#x2013;830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z., Vasconcelos N. Cascade R-Cnn: Delving into High Quality Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;23 June 2018; pp. 6154&#x2013;6162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmon J., Farhadi A. Yolov3: An Incremental Improvement. arXiv. 2018 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767.1804.02767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Z., Shen C., Chen H., He T. Fcos: Fully Convolutional One-Stage Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision; Seoul, Republic of Korea. 27 October&#x2013;2 November 2019; pp. 9627&#x2013;9636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong T., Sun F., Liu H., Jiang Y., Li L., Shi J. Foveabox: Beyound Anchor-Based Object Detection. IEEE Trans. Image Process. 2020;29:7389&#x2013;7398. doi: 10.1109/TIP.2020.3002345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2020.3002345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Wang Y., Dayoub F., Sunderhauf N. Varifocalnet: An Iou-Aware Dense Object Detector; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Nashville, TN, USA. 20&#x2013;25 June 2021; pp. 8514&#x2013;8523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C., He Y., Savvides M. Feature Selective Anchor-Free Module for Single-Shot Object Detection; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Long Beach, CA, USA. 15&#x2013;20 June 2019; pp. 840&#x2013;849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Chang H., Ma B., Wang N., Chen X. Dynamic R-CNN: Towards High Quality Object Detection via Dynamic Training. In: Vedaldi A., Bischof H., Brox T., Frahm J.-M., editors. Proceedings of the Computer Vision&#x2014;ECCV 2020. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2020. pp. 260&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Qi L., Qin H., Shi J., Jia J. Path Aggregation Network for Instance Segmentation; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;23 June 2018; pp. 8759&#x2013;8768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao S.-H., Cheng M.-M., Zhao K., Zhang X.-Y., Yang M.-H., Torr P. Res2net: A New Multi-Scale Backbone Architecture. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2019;43:652&#x2013;662. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2019.2938758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2019.2938758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31484108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai J., Qi H., Xiong Y., Li Y., Zhang G., Hu H., Wei Y. Deformable Convolutional Networks; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision; Venice, Italy. 22&#x2013;29 October 2017; pp. 764&#x2013;773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Chen K., Xu R., Liu Z., Loy C.C., Lin D. Carafe: Content-Aware Reassembly of Features; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision; Seoul, Republic of Korea. 27 October&#x2013;2 November 2019; pp. 3007&#x2013;3016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Liu Y., Wang X. Gradient Harmonized Single-Stage Detector; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Honolulu, HI, USA. 27 January&#x2013;1 February 2019; pp. 8577&#x2013;8584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu T., Jang H., Pham T.X., Yoo C.D. Cascade RPN: Delving into High-Quality Region Proposal Network with Adaptive Convolution. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2019;32 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1909.06720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1909.06720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Zhang W., Cao Y., Chen K., Pang J., Gong T., Shi J., Loy C.C., Lin D. Side-Aware Boundary Localization for More Precise Object Detection. In: Vedaldi A., Bischof H., Brox T., Frahm J.-M., editors. Computer Vision&#x2014;ECCV 2020. Volume 12349. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2020. pp. 403&#x2013;419. (Lecture Notes in Computer Science).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esri Deep Learning Frameworks. GitHub Repository.  [(accessed on 8 February 2026)].  Available online:  https://github.com/Esri/deep-learning-frameworks.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Chi C., Yao Y., Lei Z., Li S.Z. Bridging the Gap between Anchor-Based and Anchor-Free Detection via Adaptive Training Sample Selection; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Seattle, WA, USA. 13&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 9759&#x2013;9768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B., Gao Z., Gao Y., Zhu Y. Rapid Detection and Counting of Wheat Ears in the Field Using YOLOv4 with Attention Module. Agronomy. 2021;11:1202. doi: 10.3390/agronomy11061202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy11061202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Z., Lin L., Post C.J., Mikhailova E.A., Yu K., Fang H., Liu J. The Co-Effect of Image Resolution and Crown Size on Deep Learning for Individual Tree Detection and Delineation. Int. J. Digit. Earth. 2023;16:3753&#x2013;3771. doi: 10.1080/17538947.2023.2257636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17538947.2023.2257636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstein B.G., Marconi S., Bohlman S.A., Zare A., White E.P. Cross-Site Learning in Deep Learning RGB Tree Crown Detection. Ecol. Inform. 2020;56:101061. doi: 10.1016/j.ecoinf.2020.101061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2020.101061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo Y., Qian X., Li C., Wang W. Multiple Instance Complementary Detection and Difficulty Evaluation for Weakly Supervised Object Detection in Remote Sensing Images. IEEE Geosci. Remote Sens. Lett. 2023;20:6006505. doi: 10.1109/LGRS.2023.3283403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LGRS.2023.3283403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Han C., Huang L., Nie T., Liu X., Liu H., Li M. AG-Yolo: Attention-Guided Yolo for Efficient Remote Sensing Oriented Object Detection. Remote Sens. 2025;17:1027. doi: 10.3390/rs17061027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs17061027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxwell A.E., Warner T.A., Guill&#xe9;n L.A. Accuracy Assessment in Convolutional Neural Network-Based Deep Learning Remote Sensing Studies&#x2014;Part 2: Recommendations and Best Practices. Remote Sens. 2021;13:2591. doi: 10.3390/rs13132591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13132591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stehman S.V. A Critical Evaluation of the Normalized Error Matrix in Map Accuracy Assessment. Photogramm. Eng. Remote Sens. 2004;70:743&#x2013;751. doi: 10.14358/PERS.70.6.743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14358/PERS.70.6.743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stehman S.V., Foody G.M. Key Issues in Rigorous Accuracy Assessment of Land Cover Products. Remote Sens. Environ. 2019;231:111199. doi: 10.1016/j.rse.2019.05.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2019.05.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>