<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41902495</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-4610</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Headache</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Headache</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/head.70048</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES/BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This review summarizes current insights into Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome (RCVS) diagnosis, management, and outcomes. RCVS is a cerebrovascular disorder characterized by recurrent thunderclap headaches and transient segmental vasoconstriction of cerebral arteries, typically resolving within 3 months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive database search was performed across MEDLINE (via PubMed), Embase, Scopus, and the Cochrane Library.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Although often self-limiting, RCVS may cause complications such as subarachnoid hemorrhage, ischemic stroke, and cerebral edema. Triggers include vasoactive substances, pregnancy, postpartum state, and physical or emotional stress. Differentiating RCVS from conditions like primary angiitis of the central nervous system, aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage, and cerebral venous thrombosis is essential because clinical and imaging features may overlap, whereas treatments differ. Advances in neuroimaging, especially magnetic resonance angiography and vessel wall imaging, have enhanced diagnostic accuracy. Management focuses on eliminating triggers and symptomatic support. Calcium channel blockers are frequently used, although their impact on disease evolution remains uncertain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although most patients recover without major sequelae, chronic symptoms such as long-term headaches and neuropsychological symptoms, including cognitive impairment, underscore the need for ongoing follow-up and suggest a post-RCVS syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Headache: The Journal of Head and Face Pain published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Headache Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Sousa</LastName><ForeName>&#xcd;caro Ara&#xfa;jo</ForeName><Initials>&#xcd;A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9452-1207</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Behavior Sciences, Medical School of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Machado</LastName><ForeName>Abner da Silva</ForeName><Initials>ADS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Behavior Sciences, Medical School of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veras</LastName><ForeName>Arthur de Oliveira</ForeName><Initials>AO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Behavior Sciences, Medical School of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goulart</LastName><ForeName>Thiago Oscar</ForeName><Initials>TO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Behavior Sciences, Medical School of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tatsuta</LastName><ForeName>Sarah Galassi</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Faculty of Philosophy, Sciences and Letters, Medical School of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gon&#xe7;alves</LastName><ForeName>Trajano Aguiar Pires</ForeName><Initials>TAP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Behavior Sciences, Medical School of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocha</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Depatment of Neurology and Neurosurgery, Federal University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pontes-Neto</LastName><ForeName>Oct&#xe1;vio Marques</ForeName><Initials>OM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0317-843X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Behavior Sciences, Medical School of Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, Ribeir&#xe3;o Preto, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Agency>Coordena&#xe7;&#xe3;o de Aperfei&#xe7;oamento de Pessoal de N&#xed;vel Superior (CAPES)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Headache</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985091R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0017-8748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome (RCVS) causes sudden, severe &#x201c;thunderclap&#x201d; headaches due to temporary narrowing of brain arteries that typically resolves within 3 months, although serious complications like stroke can occur. This review examines the historical understanding of RCVS, its common triggers (including stress, physical exertion, certain medications, and pregnancy), and current approaches to diagnosis using advanced brain imaging techniques. A sudden, explosive headache requires immediate medical attention, and even after recovery, some patients experience ongoing headaches or cognitive changes that may indicate a &#x201c;post&#x2010;RCVS&#x201d; syndrome.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Headache: The Journal of Head and Face Pain published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Headache Society.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive impairment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intracranial hemorrhage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thunderclap headache</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vasoconstriction</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.70048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a review of pathogenesis, clinical presentation, and treatment. Int J Stroke. 2023;18:1151&#x2010;1160. doi:10.1177/17474930231181250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese LH, Dodick DW, Schwedt TJ, Singhal AB. Narrative review: reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes. Ann Intern Med. 2007;146:34&#x2010;44. doi:10.7326/0003-4819-146-1-200701020-00007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB, Caviness VS, Begleiter AF, Mark EJ, Rordorf G, Koroshetz WJ. Cerebral vasoconstriction and stroke after use of serotonergic drugs. Neurology. 2002;58:130&#x2010;133. doi:10.1212/WNL.58.1.130</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckle RM, Boulay GD, Smith B. Death due to cerebral vasospasm. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1964;27:440&#x2010;444. doi:10.1136/jnnp.27.5.440</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis MT, Newton TH. Methamphetamine (&#x201c;speed&#x201d;) arteritis. Neuroradiology. 1971;2:179&#x2010;182. doi:10.1007/BF00335049</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder BD, McClelland RR. Isolated benign cerebral vasculitis. Arch Neurol. 1978;35:612&#x2010;614. doi:10.1001/archneur.1978.00500330060012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseaux M, Bernard JF, Guyot BS. [Acute benign cerebral angiopathy. 6 cases]. [Article in French]. Presse Med. 1983;12:2163&#x2010;2168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serdaru M, Chiras J, Cujas M, Lhermitte F. Isolated benign cerebral vasculitis or migrainous vasospasm? J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1984;47:73&#x2010;76. doi:10.1136/jnnp.47.1.73</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day JW, Raskin NH. Thunderclap headache: symptom of unruptured cerebral aneurysm. Lancet. 1986;2(8518):1247&#x2010;1248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaye BR, Fainstat M. Cerebral vasculitis associated with cocaine abuse. JAMA. 1987;258(15):2104&#x2010;2106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Call GK, Fleming MC, Sealfon S, Levine H, Kistler JP, Fisher CM. Reversible cerebral segmental vasoconstriction. Stroke. 1988;19:1159&#x2010;1170. doi:10.1161/01.STR.19.9.1159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogousslavsky J, Despland PA, Regli F, Dubuis PY. Postpartum cerebral angiopathy: reversible vasoconstriction assessed by transcranial Doppler ultrasounds. Eur Neurol. 1989;29:102&#x2010;105. doi:10.1159/000116388</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barinagarrementeria F, Cant&#xfa; C, Balderrama J. Postpartum cerebral angiopathy with cerebral infarction due to ergonovine use. Stroke. 1992;23:1364&#x2010;1366. doi:10.1161/01.STR.23.9.1364</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson M, Lennox G, Jaspan T, Jefferson D. Migraine Angiitis precipitated by sex headache and leading to watershed infarction. Cephalalgia. 1993;13:427&#x2010;430. doi:10.1046/j.1468-2982.1993.1306427.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese LH, Gragg LA, Furlan AJ. Benign angiopathy: a distinct subset of angiographically defined primary angiitis of the central nervous system. J Rheumatol. 1993;20:2046&#x2010;2050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin K, Rogers T, Kavanaugh A. Central nervous system angiopathy associated with cocaine abuse. J Rheumatol. 1995;22:780&#x2010;782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodick DW, Brown RD, Britton JW, Huston J III. Nonaneurysmal thunderclap headache with diffuse, multifocal, segmental, and reversible vasospasm. Cephalalgia. 1999;19:118&#x2010;123. doi:10.1046/j.1468-2982.1999.019002118.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razavi M, Bendixen B, Maley JE, et&#xa0;al. CNS pseudovasculitis in a patient with pheochromocytoma. Neurology. 1999;52:1088. doi:10.1212/WNL.52.5.1088</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducros A, Boukobza M, Porcher R, Sarov M, Valade D, Bousser M&#x2010;G. The clinical and radiological spectrum of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. A prospective series of 67 patients. Brain. 2007;130:3091&#x2010;3101. doi:10.1093/brain/awm256</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducros A. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Lancet Neurol. 2012;11:906&#x2010;917. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(12)70135-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soo Y, Singhal AB, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome with posterior leucoencephalopathy after oral contraceptive pills. Cephalalgia. 2010;30:42&#x2010;45. doi:10.1111/j.1468-2982.2009.01868.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topcuoglu MA, Chan S, Silva GS, Smith EE, Kwong KK, Singhal AB. Cerebral vasomotor reactivity in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Cephalalgia. 2017;37:541&#x2010;547. doi:10.1177/0333102416650706</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa &#xcd;A, Pontes&#x2010;Neto OM. Neuropsychological aspects of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: preliminary findings on an unexplored topic in RCVS. 1st ed. Eliva Press; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magid&#x2010;Bernstein J, Omran SS, Parikh NS, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neurology. 2021;97:e248&#x2010;e253. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000012223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SD, Oliver FO, Elmashad A, et&#xa0;al. Outcomes among patients with primary angiitis of the CNS: a nationwide United States analysis. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2022;31:106747. doi:10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2022.106747</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MJ, Choi HA, Choi H, Chung CS. Serial testing of the ICHD&#x2010;3 beta diagnostic criteria for probable reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a prospective validation study. Cephalalgia. 2018;38:1665&#x2010;1671. doi:10.1177/0333102417744361</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Fuh J, Wang S, et&#xa0;al. Magnetic resonance angiography in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes. Ann Neurol. 2010;67:648&#x2010;656. doi:10.1002/ana.21951</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducros A, Fiedler U, Porcher R, Boukobza M, Stapf C, Bousser M&#x2010;G. Hemorrhagic manifestations of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Stroke. 2010;41:2505&#x2010;2511. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.109.572313</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes. Arch Neurol. 2011;68:1005. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2011.68</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez&#x2010;Montanez A, Morana G, Mancardi MM, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction mimicking posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome in an infant with end&#x2010;stage renal disease. Cephalalgia. 2015;35:1031&#x2010;1033. doi:10.1177/0333102414566197</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topcuoglu MA, McKee KE, Singhal AB. Gender and hormonal influences in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Eur Stroke J. 2016;1:199&#x2010;204. doi:10.1177/2396987316656981</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacheco K, Ortiz JF, Parwani J, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in the postpartum period: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Neurol Int. 2022;14:488&#x2010;496. doi:10.3390/neurolint14020040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffino SW, Fryer RH. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in pediatrics: a case series and review. J Child Neurol. 2017;32:614&#x2010;623. doi:10.1177/0883073817696817</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado&#x2010;Soto AR, Fryer RH. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in children: an update. Semin Pediatr Neurol. 2021;40:100936. doi:10.1016/j.spen.2021.100936</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange KS, Wang S&#x2010;J, Pezzini A, et&#xa0;al. Regional differences in presentation, cause, and outcome of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Stroke. 2025;56:2516&#x2010;2526. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.125.051733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha EA, Topcuoglu MA, Silva GS, et&#xa0;al. RCVS 2 score and diagnostic approach for reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neurology. 2019;92:e639&#x2010;e647. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000006917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sequeiros JM, Roa JA, Sabotin RP, et&#xa0;al. Quantifying intra&#x2010;arterial verapamil response as a diagnostic tool for reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Am J Neuroradiol. 2020;41:1869&#x2010;1875. doi:10.3174/ajnr.A6772</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrigan MT, Biller J. Intracranial arteriopathies and RCVS. Neurology. 2019;92:309&#x2010;310. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000006907</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducros A, Wolff V. The typical thunderclap headache of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome and its various triggers. Headache. 2016;56:657&#x2010;673. doi:10.1111/head.12797</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramineni KK, Jakkani RK, Girgani S, Balani A, Satyanarayan S. Triptan&#x2010;induced reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome presenting with thunderclap headache and paraparesis. Neurologist. 2018;23:160&#x2010;162. doi:10.1097/NRL.0000000000000193</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John S, Donnelly M, Uchino K. Catastrophic reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome associated with serotonin syndrome. Headache. 2013;53:1482&#x2010;1487. doi:10.1111/head.12202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB. Postpartum angiopathy with reversible posterior leukoencephalopathy. Arch Neurol. 2004;61:411. doi:10.1001/archneur.61.3.411</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asawavichienjinda T, Jittapiromsak N, Blumenfeld A. Cerebral artery vasoconstriction after galcanezumab loading dose for migraine prevention: a case report. Pain Ther. 2024;13:1705&#x2010;1712. doi:10.1007/s40122-024-00665-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short K, Emsley HCA. Illicit drugs and reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neurohospitalist. 2021;11:40&#x2010;44. doi:10.1177/1941874420953051</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veras AO, Micelli Noleto F, Zonkowski Ribas M, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome associated with probable drug poisoning. Radiol Case Rep. 2023;18:844&#x2010;849. doi:10.1016/j.radcr.2022.11.044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugate JE. Fulminant postpartum cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Arch Neurol. 2012;69:111. doi:10.1001/archneurol.2011.811</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher JJ, Kramer AH, Bleck TP, Solenski NJ. Overlapping features of eclampsia and postpartum angiopathy. Neurocrit Care. 2009;11:199&#x2010;209. doi:10.1007/s12028-009-9221-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brewer J, Owens MY, Wallace K, et&#xa0;al. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome in 46 of 47 patients with eclampsia. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2013;208:468.e1&#x2010;468.e6. doi:10.1016/j.ajog.2013.02.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;Mart&#xed;nez MM, Fern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Travieso J, G&#xf3;mez Mu&#xf1;oz N, Varela Mezquita B, Almarcha&#x2010;Menargues ML, Miralles Mart&#xed;nez A. Cerebral hemodynamics and vasoconstriction in preeclampsia: from diagnosis to resolution. Pregnancy Hypertens. 2021;26:42&#x2010;47. doi:10.1016/j.preghy.2021.08.114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB, Kimberly WT, Schaefer PW, Hedley&#x2010;Whyte ET. Case records of the Massachusetts General Hospital. Case 8&#x2010;2009. A 36&#x2010;year&#x2010;old woman with headache, hypertension, and seizure 2&#x2009;weeks post partum. N Engl J Med. 2009;360:1126&#x2010;1137. doi:10.1056/NEJMcpc0809063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott M, Miller EC, Rundek T, Hurn PD, Bushnell CD. Preeclampsia: association with posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome and stroke. Stroke. 2018;49:524&#x2010;530. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.117.018416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz BS, Fugate JE, Ameriso SF, et&#xa0;al. Clinical worsening in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71:68. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.4639</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao P, McCullough MF, Stevens J, Edwardson MA. Grief&#x2010;induced reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome (RCVS). BMJ Case Rep. 2020;13:e232204. doi:10.1136/bcr-2019-232204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Y&#x2010;C, Fuh J&#x2010;L, Lirng J&#x2010;F, Lu S&#x2010;R, Wu Z&#x2010;A, Wang S&#x2010;J. Bathing headache: a variant of idiopathic thunderclap headache. Cephalalgia. 2003;23:854&#x2010;859. doi:10.1046/j.1468-2982.2003.00603.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh Y&#x2010;C, Fuh J&#x2010;L, Chen S&#x2010;P, Wang S&#x2010;J. Clinical features, imaging findings and outcomes of headache associated with sexual activity. Cephalalgia. 2010;30:1329&#x2010;1335. doi:10.1177/0333102410364675</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdices M, Herkes G. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neuropsychol Rehabil. 2018;28:223&#x2010;233. doi:10.1080/09602011.2016.1257434</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verillaud B, Ducros A, Massiou H, Huy PT, Bousser MG, Herman P. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in two patients with a carotid glomus tumour. Cephalalgia. 2010;30:1271&#x2010;1275. doi:10.1177/0333102410365107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos Neto EP, de Sousa &#xcd;A, Ricarte F I, Pontes&#x2010;Neto OM. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome and fibromuscular dysplasia: an epiphenomenon or a causal relationship? Acta Neurol Taiwanica. 2024;33:122&#x2010;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa &#xcd;A, Dos Santos EP, Corr&#xea;a MR, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome related to extracranial dissection associated with COVID&#x2010;19: an immunological trigger? Einstein (S&#xe3;o Paulo). 2023;21:eAI0445. doi:10.31744/einstein_journal/2023AI0445</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa IA, dos Santos Neto EP, Ferreira Ricarte I, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome associated with chikungunya infection. BMJ Case Rep. 2023;16:e254729. doi:10.1136/bcr-2023-254729</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache Society (IHS). The International Classification of Headache Disorders, 3rd edition (beta version). Cephalalgia. 2013;33:629&#x2010;808. doi:10.1177/0333102413485658</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S&#x2010;P, Fuh J&#x2010;L, Lirng J&#x2010;F, et&#xa0;al. Recurrent primary thunderclap headache and benign CNS angiopathy. Neurology. 2006;67:2164&#x2010;2169. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000249115.63436.6d</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boitet R, Gaillard N, Bendiab E, et&#xa0;al. Concomitant reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome and transient global amnesia. J Neurol. 2020;267:390&#x2010;394. doi:10.1007/s00415-019-09594-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isahaya K, Shinohara K, Akamatu M, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome presenting with transient global amnesia. Intern Med. 2017;56:1569&#x2010;1573. doi:10.2169/internalmedicine.56.7460</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinette P. What does transient global amnesia really mean? Review of the literature and thorough study of 142 cases. Brain. 2006;129:1640&#x2010;1658. doi:10.1093/brain/awl105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canaple S, Fournier A, Bugnicourt J&#x2010;M, Deramond H, Lamy C, Godefroy O. Syndrome de vasoconstriction c&#xe9;r&#xe9;brale r&#xe9;versible et cardiomyopathie de Tako&#x2010;Tsubo: une association fortuite? Pratique Neurologique &#x2010; FMC. 2014;5:223&#x2010;228. doi:10.1016/j.praneu.2014.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fugate JE, Rabinstein AA. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome: clinical and radiological manifestations, pathophysiology, and outstanding questions. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:914&#x2010;925. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(15)00111-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann J, Buecke P, Meinel T, et&#xa0;al. Frequency of ischaemic stroke and intracranial haemorrhage in patients with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome (RCVS) and posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome (PRES) &#x2013; a systematic review. Eur J Neurol. 2024;31:e16246. doi:10.1111/ene.16246</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeanneret V, Jillella DV, Rangaraju S, et&#xa0;al. PRES and RCVS: two distinct entities or a Spectrum of the same disease? J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2022;31:106472. doi:10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2022.106472</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilato F, Distefano M, Calandrelli R. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome and reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: clinical and radiological considerations. Front Neurol. 2020;11:34. doi:10.3389/fneur.2020.00034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling Y&#x2010;H, Chi N&#x2010;F, Pan L&#x2010;LH, et&#xa0;al. Association between impaired dynamic cerebral autoregulation and BBB disruption in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. J Headache Pain. 2023;24:170. doi:10.1186/s10194-023-01694-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S&#x2010;P, Wang S&#x2010;J. Pathophysiology of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. J Biomed Sci. 2022;29:72. doi:10.1186/s12929-022-00857-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB. Posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome and reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome as syndromes of cerebrovascular dysregulation. Continuum. 2021;27:1301&#x2010;1320. doi:10.1212/CON.0000000000001037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamel E. Perivascular nerves and the regulation of cerebrovascular tone. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:1059&#x2010;1064. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00954.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi HA, Lee MJ, Chung C&#x2010;S. Cerebral endothelial dysfunction in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a case&#x2010;control study. J Headache Pain. 2017;18:29. doi:10.1186/s10194-017-0738-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andresen J, Shafi NI, Bryan RM. Endothelial influences on cerebrovascular tone. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:318&#x2010;327. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.00937.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraci FM. Reactive oxygen species: influence on cerebral vascular tone. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:739&#x2010;743. doi:10.1152/japplphysiol.01044.2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S&#x2010;P, Chung Y&#x2010;T, Liu T&#x2010;Y, Wang YF, Fuh JL, Wang SJ. Oxidative stress and increased formation of vasoconstricting F2&#x2010;isoprostanes in patients with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Free Radic Biol Med. 2013;61:243&#x2010;248. doi:10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2013.04.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu W&#x2010;H, Wang S&#x2010;J, Chao Y&#x2010;M, et&#xa0;al. Urine metabolomics signatures in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Cephalalgia. 2020;40:735&#x2010;747. doi:10.1177/0333102419897621</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MJ, Cha J, Choi HA, et&#xa0;al. Blood&#x2013;brain barrier breakdown in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: implications for pathophysiology and diagnosis. Ann Neurol. 2017;81:454&#x2010;466. doi:10.1002/ana.24891</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Chang Y, Chou C, et&#xa0;al. Circulating microRNAs associated with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Ann Neurol. 2021;89:459&#x2010;473. doi:10.1002/ana.25965</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontaine D, Almairac F, Santucci S, et&#xa0;al. Dural and pial pain&#x2010;sensitive structures in humans: new inputs from awake craniotomies. Brain. 2018;141:1040&#x2010;1048. doi:10.1093/brain/awy005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akazawa Y, Inaba Y, Hachiya A, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome and posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome in a boy with Loeys&#x2010;Dietz syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2015;167:2435&#x2010;2439. doi:10.1002/ajmg.a.37202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moussavi M, Korya D, Panezai S, Peeraully T, Gizzi M, Kirmani JF. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in a 35&#x2010;year&#x2010;old woman following hysterectomy and bilateral salpingo&#x2010;oophorectomy. J Neurointerv Surg. 2012;4:e35. doi:10.1136/neurintsurg-2011-010122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun RL, Chhabra A, Patel A, Shaltoni H. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome after levonorgestrel&#x2010;releasing intrauterine device placement&#x2014;case report. Headache. 2023;63:700&#x2010;704. doi:10.1111/head.14515</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freilinger T, Schmidt C, Duering M, Linn J, Straube A, Peters N. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome associated with hormone therapy for intrauterine insemination. Cephalalgia. 2010;30:1127&#x2010;1132. doi:10.1177/0333102409360675</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alcorn SR, Sorel M&#x2010;A, Auerbach S, Shaffer K. Ehlers&#x2010;Danlos syndrome presenting as severe headache in a young adult. Radiol Case Rep. 2008;3:172. doi:10.2484/rcr.v3i2.172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S&#x2010;P, Yang AC, Fuh J&#x2010;L, Wang SJ. Autonomic dysfunction in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes. J Headache Pain. 2013;14:94. doi:10.1186/1129-2377-14-94</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S&#x2010;P, Fuh J&#x2010;L, Wang S&#x2010;J, Tsai SJ, Hong CJ, Yang AC. Brain&#x2010;derived neurotrophic factor gene Val66Met polymorphism modulates reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes. PLoS One. 2011;6:e18024. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0018024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohyama&#x2010;Tamagake A, Kaneko K, Itami R, et&#xa0;al. Adult&#x2010;onset Leigh syndrome with a m.9176T&gt;C mutation manifested as reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Intern Med. 2023;62:1995&#x2010;1998. doi:10.2169/internalmedicine.0773-22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constant dit Beaufils P, Guillon B, Chabriat H, et&#xa0;al. Familial reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: insights from two families. Case Rep Neurol Med. 2025;2025:3126513. doi:10.1155/crnm/3126513</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Cho YH, Oh MJ, et&#xa0;al. No association of RNF213 polymorphism with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. J Clin Neurol. 2020;16:330&#x2010;332. doi:10.3988/jcn.2020.16.2.330</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh HU, Mathew PG. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: updates and new perspectives. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2014;18:414. doi:10.1007/s11916-014-0414-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrigan MT, Heran MKS, Shewchuk JR. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: an important and common cause of thunderclap and recurrent headaches. Clin Radiol. 2018;73:417&#x2010;427. doi:10.1016/j.crad.2017.11.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadaro A, Scott KR, Koyfman A, Long B. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a narrative review for emergency clinicians. Am J Emerg Med. 2021;50:765&#x2010;772. doi:10.1016/j.ajem.2021.09.072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodick DW. Thunderclap headache. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2002;72:6&#x2010;11. doi:10.1136/jnnp.72.1.6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senno R, Schonfeld E, Nagar C. OnabotulinumtoxinA injections: treatment of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome chronic daily headaches. BMJ Case Rep. 2019;12:e228562. doi:10.1136/bcr-2018-228562</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff V, Ducros A. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome without typical thunderclap headache. Headache. 2016;56:674&#x2010;687. doi:10.1111/head.12794</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Fuh J, Chang F, Lirng JF, Shia BC, Wang SJ. Transcranial color Doppler study for reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes. Ann Neurol. 2008;63:751&#x2010;757. doi:10.1002/ana.21384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abkur TM, Saeed M, Alfaki NO, O'Connor M. Idiopathic reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome (RCVS). BMJ Case Rep. 2014;2014:bcr2014206913. doi:10.1136/bcr-2014-206913</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi HA, Lee MJ, Choi H, Chung CS. Characteristics and demographics of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a large prospective series of Korean patients. Cephalalgia. 2018;38:765&#x2010;775. doi:10.1177/0333102417715223</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yancy H, Lee&#x2010;Iannotti JK, Schwedt TJ, Dodick DW. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Headache. 2013;53:570&#x2010;576. doi:10.1111/head.12040</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caria F, Zedde M, Gamba M, et&#xa0;al. The clinical spectrum of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: the Italian project on stroke at young age (IPSYS). Cephalalgia. 2019;39:1267&#x2010;1276. doi:10.1177/0333102419849013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bain J, Segal D, Amin R, Monoky D, Thompson SJ. Call&#x2010;Fleming syndrome: headache in a 16&#x2010;year&#x2010;old girl. Pediatr Neurol. 2013;49:130&#x2010;133.e1. doi:10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2013.05.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noskin O, Jafarimojarrad E, Libman RB, Nelson JL. Diffuse cerebral vasoconstriction (Call&#x2013;Fleming syndrome) and stroke associated with antidepressants. Neurology. 2006;67:159&#x2010;160. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000223648.76430.27</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marder CP, Donohue MM, Weinstein JR, Fink KR. Multimodal imaging of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a series of 6 cases. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2012;33:1403&#x2010;1411. doi:10.3174/ajnr.A2964</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia&#x2010;Mendoza M, Ram&#xed;rez&#x2010;Rodr&#xed;guez N, Vargas&#x2010;Avila N, et&#xa0;al. Fatal reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a systematic review of case series and case reports. J Clin Neurosci. 2019;70:183&#x2010;188. doi:10.1016/j.jocn.2019.08.014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB, Topcuoglu MA, Fok JW, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndromes and primary angiitis of the central nervous system: clinical, imaging, and angiographic comparison. Ann Neurol. 2016;79:882&#x2010;894. doi:10.1002/ana.24652</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh RD, Floyd JP, Eidelman BH, Barrett KM. B&#xe1;lint syndrome and visual allochiria in a patient with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. J Neuroophthalmol. 2012;32:302&#x2010;306. doi:10.1097/WNO.0b013e3182359f4a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arif HE, Masoom A, Hakim Mohammed AR, Mogri I, Thacker I, Shamim S. Spinal cord reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Baylor Univ Med Cent Proc. 2025;38:751&#x2010;754. doi:10.1080/08998280.2025.2473815</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim B&#x2010;S, Kim S, Kim E, et&#xa0;al. Concurrent extracerebral vasoconstriction in patients with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. J Clin Med. 2025;14:4402. doi:10.3390/jcm14134402</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa &#xcd;A, de Azevedo AF, Veras AO, et&#xa0;al. Neuropsychological aspects of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Dement Neuropsychol. 2024;18:225&#x2010;233. doi:10.1590/1980-5764-dn-2023-0117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perillo T, Paolella C, Perrotta G, Serino A, Caranci F, Manto A. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: review of neuroimaging findings. Radiol Med. 2022;127:981&#x2010;990. doi:10.1007/s11547-022-01532-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsutake A, Mano T, Kawai M, et&#xa0;al. Hyperdense vessel sign in brain computed tomography as an early indication of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Intern Med. 2025;64:1404&#x2010;1407. doi:10.2169/internalmedicine.4350-24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SD, Topiwala K, Saini V, et&#xa0;al. Hemorrhagic reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a retrospective observational study. J Neurol. 2021;268:632&#x2010;639. doi:10.1007/s00415-020-10193-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton TM, Bushnell CD. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Stroke. 2019;50:2253&#x2010;2258. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.119.024416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topcuoglu MA, Singhal AB. Hemorrhagic reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Stroke. 2016;47:1742&#x2010;1747. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.116.013136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf R, Akhtar M, Akhtar S, Manzoor I. Diagnostic accuracy of flair in detection of acute subarachnoid hemorrhage in patients presenting with severe headache. J Neuroradiol. 2019;46:294&#x2010;298. doi:10.1016/j.neurad.2018.07.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S&#x2010;P, Fuh J&#x2010;L, Lirng J&#x2010;F, Wang S&#x2010;J. Hyperintense vessels on flair imaging in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Cephalalgia. 2012;32:271&#x2010;278. doi:10.1177/0333102412437387</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C&#x2010;Y, Chen S&#x2010;P, Fuh J&#x2010;L, et&#xa0;al. Vascular wall imaging in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome &#x2013; a 3&#x2010;T contrast&#x2010;enhanced MRI study. J Headache Pain. 2018;19:74. doi:10.1186/s10194-018-0906-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimoda M, Oda S, Shigematsu H, et&#xa0;al. Clinical significance of centripetal propagation of vasoconstriction in patients with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a retrospective case&#x2010;control study. Cephalalgia. 2018;38:1864&#x2010;1875. doi:10.1177/0333102418762471</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducros A, Bousser M&#x2010;G. Reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Pract Neurol. 2009;9:256&#x2010;267. doi:10.1136/jnnp.2009.187856</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard M, Verreault S, Gari&#xe9;py J, Dupr&#xe9; N. Intra&#x2010;arterial milrinone for reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Headache. 2009;49:142&#x2010;145. doi:10.1111/j.1526-4610.2008.01211.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boysson H, Parienti J&#x2010;J, Mawet J, et&#xa0;al. Primary angiitis of the CNS and reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neurology. 2018;91:e1468&#x2010;e1478. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000006367</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandell DM, Matouk CC, Farb RI, et&#xa0;al. Vessel wall MRI to differentiate between reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome and central nervous system vasculitis. Stroke. 2012;43:860&#x2010;862. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.111.626184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haller S, Zaharchuk G, Thomas DL, Lovblad KO, Barkhof F, Golay X. Arterial spin labeling perfusion of the brain: emerging clinical applications. Radiology. 2016;281:337&#x2010;356. doi:10.1148/radiol.2016150789</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu T, Kimura T, Yagishita A, Takahashi K, Koide R. A case of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome presenting with recurrent neurological deficits: evaluation using noninvasive arterial spin labeling MRI. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2014;126:96&#x2010;98. doi:10.1016/j.clineuro.2014.08.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kano Y, Inui S, Uchida Y, et&#xa0;al. Quantitative arterial spin labeling magnetic resonance imaging analysis of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a case series. Headache. 2021;61:687&#x2010;693. doi:10.1111/head.14094</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S, Lee MJ, Gil YE, Chung CS. RCVS&#x2013;TCH score can predict reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in patients with thunderclap headache. Sci Rep. 2021;11:7750. doi:10.1038/s41598-021-87412-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlak MHM, Algra A, Brandenburg R, Rinkel GJ. Prevalence of unruptured intracranial aneurysms, with emphasis on sex, age, comorbidity, country, and time period: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Lancet Neurol. 2011;10:626&#x2010;636. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(11)70109-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muehlschlegel S, Kursun O, Topcuoglu MA, et&#xa0;al. Differentiating reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome with subarachnoid hemorrhage from other causes of subarachnoid hemorrhage. JAMA Neurol. 2013;70:1254&#x2010;1260. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2013.3484</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Goddeau RP, Selim MH, et&#xa0;al. Atraumatic convexal subarachnoid hemorrhage. Neurology. 2010;74:893&#x2010;899. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181d55efa</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel SD, Topiwala K, Otite Oliver F, et&#xa0;al. Outcomes among patients with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a nationwide United States analysis. Stroke. 2021;52:3970&#x2010;3977. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.121.034424</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermann P, Zerr I. Rapidly progressive dementias &#x2014; aetiologies, diagnosis and management. Nat Rev Neurol. 2022;18:363&#x2010;376. doi:10.1038/s41582-022-00659-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junek M, Perera KS, Kiczek M, Hajj&#x2010;Ali RA. Current and future advances in practice: a practical approach to the diagnosis and management of primary central nervous system vasculitis. Rheumatol Adv Pract. 2023;7:rkad080. doi:10.1093/rap/rkad080</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al&#x2010;Mufti F, Dodson V, Wajswol E, et&#xa0;al. Chemical angioplasty for medically refractory reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Br J Neurosurg. 2018;32:431&#x2010;435. doi:10.1080/02688697.2018.1479512</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bress AP, Anderson TS, Flack JM, et&#xa0;al. The management of elevated blood pressure in the acute care setting: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Hypertension. 2024;81:e94&#x2010;e106. doi:10.1161/HYP.0000000000000238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S, Seong M, Lee MJ. Early nimodipine treatment in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome: a serial transcranial Doppler study. Headache. 2025;65:1617&#x2010;1625. doi:10.1111/head.14999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muehlschlegel S, Rordorf G, Bodock M, Sims JR. Dantrolene mediates vasorelaxation in cerebral vasoconstriction: a case series. Neurocrit Care. 2009;10:116&#x2010;121. doi:10.1007/s12028-008-9132-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijalski C, Dakay K, Miller&#x2010;Patterson C, et&#xa0;al. Magnesium for treatment of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neurohospitalist. 2016;6:111&#x2010;113. doi:10.1177/1941874415613834</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal AB, Topcuoglu MA. Glucocorticoid&#x2010;associated worsening in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neurology. 2017;88:228&#x2010;236. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000003510</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringer AJ, Qureshi AI, Kim SH, Fessler RD, Guterman LR, Hopkins LN. Angioplasty for cerebral vasospasm from eclampsia. Surg Neurol. 2001;56:373&#x2010;378. doi:10.1016/S0090-3019(01)00635-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song JK, Fisher S, Seifert TD, et&#xa0;al. Postpartum cerebral angiopathy: atypical features and treatment with intracranial balloon angioplasty. Neuroradiology. 2004;46:1022&#x2010;1026. doi:10.1007/s00234-003-1129-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girfanova M, Martinez&#x2010;Majander N, Mannism&#xe4;ki L, Sibolt G, Tiainen M, Curtze S. Retrospective analysis of 80 patients diagnosed with reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome in the Helsinki metropolitan area. Eur J Neurol. 2025;32:e16564. doi:10.1111/ene.16564</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John S, Singhal AB, Calabrese L, et&#xa0;al. Long&#x2010;term outcomes after reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Cephalalgia. 2016;36:387&#x2010;394. doi:10.1177/0333102415591507</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Kumar S, Rocha E, Lioutas VA. Vasoconstriction and long&#x2010;term headache in reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. J Neurol. 2023;270:1647&#x2010;1653. doi:10.1007/s00415-022-11511-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boitet R, de Gaalon S, Duflos C, et&#xa0;al. Long&#x2010;term outcomes after reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Stroke. 2020;51:670&#x2010;673. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.119.027703</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S&#x2010;P, Fuh J&#x2010;L, Lirng J&#x2010;F, Wang Y&#x2010;F, Wang S&#x2010;J. Recurrence of reversible cerebral vasoconstriction syndrome. Neurology. 2015;84:1552&#x2010;1558. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000001473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange KS, Choi SY, Ling Y&#x2010;H, et&#xa0;al. Reversible cerebral Vasoconstriction syndrome intERnational CollaborativE (REVERCE) network: study protocol and rationale of a multicentre research collaboration. Eur Stroke J. 2023;8:1107&#x2010;1113. doi:10.1177/23969873231182207</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>