<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41564637</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1361-8423</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>109</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical image analysis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Image Anal</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advances in automated fetal brain MRI segmentation and biometry: Insights from the FeTA 2024 challenge.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103941</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103941</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.media.2026.103941</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1361-8415(26)00010-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate fetal brain tissue segmentation and biometric measurement are essential for monitoring neurodevelopment and detecting abnormalities in utero. The Fetal Tissue Annotation (FeTA) Challenges have established robust multi-center benchmarks for evaluating state-of-the-art segmentation methods. This paper presents the results of the 2024 challenge edition, which introduced three key innovations. First, we introduced a topology-aware metric based on the Euler characteristic difference (ED) to overcome the performance plateau observed with traditional metrics like Dice or Hausdorff distance (HD), as the performance of the best models in segmentation surpassed the inter-rater variability. While the best teams reached similar scores in Dice (0.81-0.82) and HD95 (2.1-2.3&#x202f;mm), ED provided greater discriminative power: the winning method achieved an ED of 20.9, representing roughly a 50% improvement over the second- and third-ranked teams despite comparable Dice scores. Second, we introduced a new 0.55T low-field MRI test set, which, when paired with high-quality super-resolution reconstruction, achieved the highest segmentation performance across all test cohorts (Dice=0.86, HD95=1.69, ED=6.26). This provides the first quantitative evidence that low-cost, low-field MRI can match or surpass high-field systems in automated fetal brain segmentation. Third, the new biometry estimation task exposed a clear performance gap: although the best model reached a mean average percentage error (MAPE) of 7.72%, most submissions failed to outperform a simple gestational-age-based linear regression model (MAPE=9.56%), and all remained above inter-rater variability with a MAPE of 5.38%. Finally, by analyzing the top-performing models from FeTA 2024 alongside those from previous challenge editions, we identify ensembles of 3D nnU-Net trained on both real and synthetic data with both image- and anatomy-level augmentations as the most effective approaches for fetal brain segmentation. Our quantitative analysis reveals that acquisition site, super-resolution strategy, and image quality are the primary sources of domain shift, informing recommendations to enhance the robustness and generalizability of automated fetal brain analysis methods.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zalevskyi</LastName><ForeName>Vladyslav</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Lausanne University Hospital and University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland; CIBM Center for Biomedical Imaging, Lausanne, Switzerland. Electronic address: vladyslav.zalevskyi@unil.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanchez</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Lausanne University Hospital and University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland; CIBM Center for Biomedical Imaging, Lausanne, Switzerland. Electronic address: thomas.sanchez@unil.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaandorp</LastName><ForeName>Misha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland; University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: misha.kaandorp@kispi.uzh.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roulet</LastName><ForeName>Margaux</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Lausanne University Hospital and University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland; CIBM Center for Biomedical Imaging, Lausanne, Switzerland. Electronic address: margaux.roulet@unil.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fajardo-Rojas</LastName><ForeName>Diego</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Early Life Imaging, School of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Imaging Sciences, King's College London, London, UK. Electronic address: diego.fajardo_rojas@kcl.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Liu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart &amp; Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK. Electronic address: liu.li20@imperial.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hutter</LastName><ForeName>Jana</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Early Life Imaging, School of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Imaging Sciences, King's College London, London, UK; Smart Imaging Lab, University Hospital Erlangen, Erlangen, Germany. Electronic address: jana.hutter@kcl.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hongwei Bran</ForeName><Initials>HB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Quantitative Biomedicine, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland; Department of Informatics, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany. Electronic address: holi2@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barkovich</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California San Francisco, UCSF Benioff Children's Hospital, San Francisco, California, USA. Electronic address: matthew.barkovich@ucsf.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland; Neuroscience Center Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: hiu.ji@kispi.uzh.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilhelmi</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: luca.wilhelmi@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#xe4;ndliker</LastName><ForeName>Aline</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: aline.daendliker@kispi.uzh.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steger</LastName><ForeName>C&#xe9;line</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland; Neuroscience Center Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: celine.n.steger@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koob</LastName><ForeName>M&#xe9;riam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Lausanne University Hospital and University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland. Electronic address: meriam.koob@chuv.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gomez</LastName><ForeName>Yvan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sagol Brain Institute, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center and Faculty of Medicine and Sagol School of Neuroscience, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel; Department Woman-Mother-Child, CHUV, Lausanne, Switzerland; BCNatal Fetal Medicine Research Center (Hospital Cl&#xed;nic and Hospital Sant Joan de D&#xe9;u), Universitat de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain. Electronic address: yvan.gomez1@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jakov&#x10d;i&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Anton</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Croatian Institute for Brain Research, School of Medicine, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: anton.jakovcic97@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klai&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Melita</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Croatian Institute for Brain Research, School of Medicine, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: melita.klaic@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ad&#x17e;i&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Croatian Institute for Brain Research, School of Medicine, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: anaa.adzic@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Markovi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Pavel</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Croatian Institute for Brain Research, School of Medicine, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: pavelm990@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grabari&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Gracia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Croatian Institute for Brain Research, School of Medicine, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: grabaricgracia@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rados</LastName><ForeName>Milan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Croatian Institute for Brain Research, School of Medicine, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia; Department of Biomedical Engineering, School of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Imaging Sciences, King's College, London, UK. Electronic address: mrados3@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aviles Verdera</LastName><ForeName>Jordina</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Early Life Imaging, School of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Imaging Sciences, King's College London, London, UK; Smart Imaging Lab, University Hospital Erlangen, Erlangen, Germany. Electronic address: jordina.aviles_verdera@kcl.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasprian</LastName><ForeName>Gregor</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Imaging and Image-Guided Therapy, Division of Neuroradiology and Musculoskeletal Radiology, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria. Electronic address: gregor.kasprian@meduniwien.ac.at.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dovjak</LastName><ForeName>Gregor</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Imaging and Image-Guided Therapy, Division of Neuroradiology and Musculoskeletal Radiology, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria. Electronic address: gregor.dovjak@gmx.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaubert-Rachm&#xfc;hl</LastName><ForeName>Raphael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: rgaubertrachmuhl@clipper.ens.psl.eu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aschwanden</LastName><ForeName>Maurice</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: maurice.d.aschwanden@bluewin.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. Electronic address: qi.zeng@childrens.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karimi</LastName><ForeName>Davood</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. Electronic address: davood.karimi@childrens.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peruzzo</LastName><ForeName>Denis</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Unit, Scientific Institute IRCCS E. Medea, Bosisio Parini, Italy. Electronic address: denis.peruzzo@lanostrafamiglia.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciceri</LastName><ForeName>Tommaso</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Unit, Scientific Institute IRCCS E. Medea, Bosisio Parini, Italy; University Research Priority Project Adaptive Brain Circuits in Development and Learning (AdaBD), University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland; Sagol Brain Institute, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center and School of EE, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel; Department of Medical Imaging Sciences, The Faculty of Social Welfare and Health Sciences, University of Haifa, Haifa, Israel. Electronic address: tommaso.ciceri@lanostrafamiglia.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longari</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Informatics, Systems and Communication, University of Milano Bicocca, Milan, Italy. Electronic address: giorgio.longari@unimib.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamadache</LastName><ForeName>Rachika E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Computer Vision and Robotics (ViCOROB), Universitat de Girona, Girona, Spain. Electronic address: rachikaelhassna.hamadache@udg.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouzid</LastName><ForeName>Amina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Computer Vision and Robotics (ViCOROB), Universitat de Girona, Girona, Spain. Electronic address: aminabouzid01@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Llad&#xf3;</LastName><ForeName>Xavier</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Computer Vision and Robotics (ViCOROB), Universitat de Girona, Girona, Spain. Electronic address: xavier.llado@udg.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiarella</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe0; di Bologna, Bologna, Italy. Electronic address: simone.chiarella@studio.unibo.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;-Juan</LastName><ForeName>Gerard</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BCN MedTech, Department of Engineering, Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona, Spain. Electronic address: gerard.marti@upf.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonz&#xe1;lez Ballester</LastName><ForeName>Miguel &#xc1;ngel</ForeName><Initials>M&#xc1;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BCN MedTech, Department of Engineering, Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona, Spain; ICREA, Barcelona, Spain. Electronic address: ma.gonzalez@upf.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castellaro</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Engineering, University of Padova, Padova, Italy. Electronic address: marco.castellaro@unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinamonti</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Engineering, University of Padova, Padova, Italy. Electronic address: marco.pinamonti.1@phd.unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Visani</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Engineering, University of Padova, Padova, Italy. Electronic address: valentina.visani@studenti.unipd.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cremese</LastName><ForeName>Robin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Pasteur, Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, CNRS UMR 3571, Decision and Bayesian Computation, Paris, France. Electronic address: robin.cremese@pasteur.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sam</LastName><ForeName>Ke&#xef;n</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut Pasteur, Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, CNRS UMR 3571, Decision and Bayesian Computation, Paris, France. Electronic address: kein.sam@etu.u-paris.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaudfernau</LastName><ForeName>Fleur</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inria, HeKA, PariSant&#xe9;Campus, Paris, France. Electronic address: fleur.gaudfernau@orange.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahir</LastName><ForeName>Param</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>L. D. College of Engineering, Gujarat, India. Electronic address: ahirparam@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parikh</LastName><ForeName>Mehul</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>L. D. College of Engineering, Gujarat, India. Electronic address: mehulcparikh@ldce.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zenk</LastName><ForeName>Maximilian</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Faculty Heidelberg, Heidelberg University, Pattern Analysis and Learning Group, Department of Radiation Oncology, Heidelberg University Hospital, Heidelberg, Germany; German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) Heidelberg, Division of Medical Image Computing, Heidelberg, Germany. Electronic address: m.zenk@dkfz-heidelberg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baumgartner</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Faculty Heidelberg, Heidelberg University, Pattern Analysis and Learning Group, Department of Radiation Oncology, Heidelberg University Hospital, Heidelberg, Germany; German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) Heidelberg, Division of Medical Image Computing, Heidelberg, Germany. Electronic address: m.baumgartner@dkfz-heidelberg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maier-Hein</LastName><ForeName>Klaus</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Faculty Heidelberg, Heidelberg University, Pattern Analysis and Learning Group, Department of Radiation Oncology, Heidelberg University Hospital, Heidelberg, Germany; German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) Heidelberg, Division of Medical Image Computing, Heidelberg, Germany; Pattern Analysis and Learning Group, Department of Radiation Oncology, Heidelberg University Hospital, Heidelberg, Germany; Helmholtz Imaging, German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ), Heidelberg, Germany; Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science, Heidelberg University, Heidelberg, Germany. Electronic address: k.maier-hein@dkfz-heidelberg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tianhong</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canon Medical Systems (China) Co., Ltd, China. Electronic address: tianhong1.li@cn.medical.canon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canon Medical Systems (China) Co., Ltd, China. Electronic address: hong2.yang@cn.medical.canon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longfei</LastName><ForeName>Zhao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canon Medical Systems (China) Co., Ltd, China. Electronic address: longfei1.zhao@cn.medical.canon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Preloznik</LastName><ForeName>Domen</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electrical Engineering, University of Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia. Electronic address: domen.preloznik@fe.uni-lj.si.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x160;piclin</LastName><ForeName>&#x17d;iga</ForeName><Initials>&#x17d;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electrical Engineering, University of Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia. Electronic address: ziga.spiclin@fe.uni-lj.si.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Won Choi</LastName><ForeName>Jae</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, South Korea. Electronic address: djc0105@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Muyang</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, China. Electronic address: 18190351554@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, China. Electronic address: jia.fu@std.uestc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Guotai</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, China. Electronic address: guotai.wang@uestc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Jingwen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China. Electronic address: williamsriver@whu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tong</LastName><ForeName>Lyuyang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China. Electronic address: lyuyangtong@whu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China. Electronic address: dubo@whu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gondova</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fetal Neonatal Neuroimaging and Developmental Science Center, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA; Division of Newborn Medicine, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. Electronic address: andrea.gondova@childrens.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>You</LastName><ForeName>Sungmin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fetal Neonatal Neuroimaging and Developmental Science Center, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA; Division of Newborn Medicine, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. Electronic address: sungmin.you@childrens.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Im</LastName><ForeName>Kiho</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fetal Neonatal Neuroimaging and Developmental Science Center, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA; Division of Newborn Medicine, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA; Department of Radiology, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA. Electronic address: kiho.im@childrens.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qayyum</LastName><ForeName>Abdul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart &amp; Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK. Electronic address: a.qayyum@imperial.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazher</LastName><ForeName>Moona</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hawkes Institute, Department of Computer Science, University College London, London, UK. Electronic address: moona.mazher@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niederer</LastName><ForeName>Steven A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart &amp; Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK. Electronic address: s.niederer@imperial.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jakab</LastName><ForeName>Andras</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland; University Research Priority Project Adaptive Brain Circuits in Development and Learning (AdaBD), University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: andras.jakab@kispi.uzh.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Licandro</LastName><ForeName>Roxane</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Computational Neuroimaging, Athinoula A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Massachusetts General Hospital/Harvard Medical School, Charlestown, Massachusetts, USA; Department of Biomedical Imaging and Image-guided Therapy, Computational Imaging Research Lab (CIR), Early Life Image Analysis Group, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria. Electronic address: roxane.licandro@meduniwien.ac.at.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Payette</LastName><ForeName>Kelly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Early Life Imaging, School of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Imaging Sciences, King's College London, London, UK; Center for MR-Research, University Children's Hospital Zurich, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: kelly.payette@kispi.uzh.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bach Cuadra</LastName><ForeName>Meritxell</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Lausanne University Hospital and University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland; CIBM Center for Biomedical Imaging, Lausanne, Switzerland. Electronic address: meritxell.bachcuadra@unil.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Med Image Anal</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9713490</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-8415</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000196" MajorTopicYN="N">embryology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="Y">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001699" MajorTopicYN="N">Biometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007090" MajorTopicYN="Y">Image Interpretation, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007091" MajorTopicYN="Y">Image Processing, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005333" MajorTopicYN="N">Fetus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Challenge results</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Domain shift</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fetal brain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Low-field</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Segmentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Topology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper. The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Vladyslav Zalevskyi reports financial support was provided by NVIDIA Ltd. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper. During the preparation of this work, the authors used Grammarly and ChatGPT (GPT 4o) to assist with spell checking, grammar refinement, and language clarity improvements. After using this tool/service, the authors reviewed and edited the content as needed and take full responsibility for the content of the publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41564637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2026.103941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1361-8415(26)00010-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>