<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41696322</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synergistic Low-Carbon Economic Dispatch of a Virtual Power Plant with Microencapsulated Carbon Capture and Demand Response.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8431</StartPage><EndPage>8441</EndPage><MedlinePgn>8431-8441</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c11262</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Building power systems dominated by renewable energy is an inevitable trend under carbon neutrality goals. However, the large-scale integration of intermittent and volatile renewables poses significant challenges to the grid and coal-fired power systems concerning low-carbon operation and flexible peak-shaving and frequency regulation. Conventional carbon capture (CC) technologies and the flexibility of thermal power plants can no longer meet these demands. Microencapsulated carbon capture (MECC) offers a promising alternative with higher specific surface area, stability, and capture rates 3-5 times that of amine-based methods. This paper proposes a virtual power plant (VPP) model integrating MECC and demand response (DR) to evaluate its dispatch performance. Using a self-developed microcapsule material, the model leverages electrothermal complementarity and integrated DR to optimize flexible resources. Under a carbon trading mechanism, simulations in MATLAB/YALMIP with GUROBI show that MECC reduces energy consumption by 20.45% and improves generation efficiency. DR enhances renewable integration, increasing wind and photovoltaic utilization by 2.17% and 1.60%, respectively, while reducing curtailment costs by 3.45%. This study provides theoretical and operational references for MECC application in power systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Huachen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Energy Carbon Neutrality, School of Electrical Engineering, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830047, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">47907</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-2427-4558</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Energy Carbon Neutrality, School of Electrical Engineering, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830047, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">47907</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Northwest Energy Carbon Neutrality, Ministry of Education, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830047, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41696322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12902956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c11262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Liu P., Li Z.. Low carbon transition pathway of power sector with high penetration of renewable energy. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 2020;130:109985. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2020.109985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2020.109985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Cheng B., Ren Y.. et al. Flexible resource dynamic aggregation regulation method of virtual power plant to ensure more renewable energy generation. Process Safety and Environmental Protection. 2023;180:339&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2023.09.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2023.09.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju L., Lv S. S., Zhang Z.. et al. Data-driven two-stage robust optimization dispatching model and benefit allocation strategy for a novel virtual power plant considering carbon-green certificate equivalence conversion mechanism. Applied Energy. 2024;362:122974. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.122974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.122974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., He X., Niu W.. et al. Analysis of the joint trading of local green power certificates, carbon emissions rights, and electricity considering demand flexibility. International Journal of Electrical Power &amp; Energy Systems. 2024;155:109653. doi: 10.1016/j.ijepes.2023.109653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2023.109653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, M. , Kang, L. , Wu, J. , et al. Optimal Scheduling of VPP with Carbon Capture and P2G Considering Demand Response//International Conference on Wireless Power Transfer; Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore, 2023; pp 128&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochedi F. O., Yu J., Yu H.. et al. Carbon dioxide capture using liquid absorption methods: a review. Environmental Chemistry Letters. 2021;19(1):77&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1007/s10311-020-01093-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10311-020-01093-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safaei S. H., Young S.. Advancements in the Treatment of Amine-rich Wastewater from Amine-based Post-combustion Carbon Capture: A Review. Carbon Capture Science &amp; Technology. 2025;16:100475. doi: 10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Q., Zhang X., Wang T.. et al. Technical perspective of carbon capture, utilization, and storage. Engineering. 2022;14:27&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/j.eng.2021.12.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eng.2021.12.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos A. I., Tzirakis F., Tsivintzelis I.. et al. Phase-change solvents and processes for postcombustion CO2 capture: a detailed review. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019;58(13):5088&#x2013;5111. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.8b06279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.8b06279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y., Gao L., He S.. Analysis of the mechanism of energy consumption for CO2 capture in a power system. Energy. 2023;262:125103. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2022.125103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2022.125103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muntaha N., Rain M. I., Goni L K M O.. et al. A review on carbon dioxide minimization in biogas upgradation technology by chemical absorption processes. ACS omega. 2022;7(38):33680&#x2013;33698. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.2c03514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.2c03514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9520701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolaroff J. K., Ye C., Oakdale J. S.. et al. Microencapsulation of advanced solvents for carbon capture. Faraday Discuss. 2016;192:271&#x2013;281. doi: 10.1039/C6FD00049E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6FD00049E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27504736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Zhao W., Lu H., Meng H.. Encapsulated Ionic Liquids with MOF-Driven CO2 Channels: Overcoming Kinetic Limits for Rapid Carbon Capture. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2025;17(36):50713. doi: 10.1021/acsami.5c10814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.5c10814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40862453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P., Wang Z., Wang J.. et al. Two-stage optimal operation of integrated energy system considering multiple uncertainties and integrated demand response. Energy. 2021;225:120256. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2021.120256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2021.120256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strbac G.. Demand side management: Benefits and challenges. Energy policy. 2008;36(12):4419&#x2013;4426. doi: 10.1016/j.enpol.2008.09.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enpol.2008.09.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M., Lu H., Chang X.. et al. An optimization on an integrated energy system of combined heat and power, carbon capture system and power to gas by considering flexible load. Energy. 2023;273:127203. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.127203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W., Zhang N., Kang C., Li M., Huo M.. From demand response to integrated demand response: Review and prospect of research and application. Protection and Control of Modern Power Systems. 2019;4:12. doi: 10.1186/s41601-019-0126-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41601-019-0126-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connell N., Pinson P., Madsen H., O'Malley M.. Benefits and challenges of electrical demand response: A critical review. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 2014;39:686&#x2013;699. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2014.07.098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2014.07.098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Jiang Y., Chong Z.. Optimal scheduling of electro-thermal system considering refined demand response and source-load-storage cooperative hydrogen production. Renewable Energy. 2023;215:118845. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2023.05.103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2023.05.103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Ma Y., Song F.. et al. Economic and efficient multi-objective operation optimization of integrated energy system considering electro-thermal demand response. Energy. 2020;205:118022. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2020.118022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.118022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z., Zhang R., Wang L.. et al. Optimal operation of regional integrated energy system considering demand response. Applied Thermal Engineering. 2021;191:116860. doi: 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2021.116860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2021.116860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochedi F. O., Yu J., Yu H.. et al. Carbon dioxide capture using liquid absorption methods: a review. Environmental Chemistry Letters. 2021;19(1):77&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1007/s10311-020-01093-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10311-020-01093-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yew M., Ren Y., Koh K. S.. et al. Synthesis of microcapsules for carbon capture via needle-based droplet microfluidics. Energy Procedia. 2019;160:443&#x2013;450. doi: 10.1016/j.egypro.2019.02.179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egypro.2019.02.179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu W., Wang T., Park A H A.. et al. Toward sustainable energy and materials: CO2 capture using microencapsulated sorbents. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2020;59(21):9746&#x2013;9759. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.0c01065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.0c01065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galogahi F. M., An H., Zhu Y.. et al. Thermal and mechanical stabilities of Core-shell microparticles containing a liquid core. J. Mol. Liq. 2021;344:117726. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang B., Mu M., Zhou Y., Zhang J., Li W.. Nanoparticle-Empowered Core&#x2013;Shell Microcapsules: From Architecture Design to Fabrication and Functions. Small. 2024;20(33):2311897. doi: 10.1002/smll.202470245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202470245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38456762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Sun L., Shi L.. et al. Fabrication of natural microcapsule with intrinsic core&#x2013;shell structure as building blocks for achieving source control of obesity. Chemical Engineering Journal. 2024;493:152585. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.152585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.152585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang F., Wang X., Wu D.. Design and synthesis of magnetic microcapsules based on n-eicosane core and Fe3O4/SiO2 hybrid shell for dual-functional phase change materials. Applied Energy. 2014;134:456&#x2013;468. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2014.08.061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2014.08.061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J., Li H., Zhang Z.. Review of Virtual Power Plant Response Capability Assessment and Optimization Dispatch. Technologies. 2025;13(6):216. doi: 10.3390/technologies13060216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/technologies13060216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai C., Cao Z., Wang Y.. et al. A reverse incentive-based demand response strategy for shared energy storage in industrial microgrids: Optimization, scheduling, and investment analysis. Energy. 2025;330:136882. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2025.136882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2025.136882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y., Jia H., Wang X.. et al. Review of operations for multi-energy coupled virtual power plants participating in electricity market. Energy Reports. 2023;9:992&#x2013;999. doi: 10.1016/j.egyr.2023.04.149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2023.04.149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sgouridis S., Carbajales-Dale M., Csala D.. et al. Comparative net energy analysis of renewable electricity and carbon capture and storage. Nature Energy. 2019;4(6):456&#x2013;465. doi: 10.1038/s41560-019-0365-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-019-0365-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Li Z., Li G.. Grandfather-based or benchmark-based: Strategy choice for carbon quota allocation methods in the carbon neutrality era. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 2024;192:114195. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2023.114195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2023.114195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>