<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41929641</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-3121</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SAGE open medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SAGE Open Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hand anthropometry, grip strength, and manual dexterity: A correlational study among dental students.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20503121261428206</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20503121261428206</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20503121261428206</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20503121261428206</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Hand anthropometry, grip strength, and manual dexterity are fundamental to the safe and the effective performance of dental procedures. While these factors are individually important, their interrelationships in dental students remain insufficiently explored. This study aimed to examine the correlation of hand anthropometric dimensions with grip strength, and manual dexterity among dental students, and to evaluate their potential implications for dental education and ergonomic instrument design.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This cross-sectional study included 100 dental students. Thirty hand anthropometric dimensions were measured using a digital caliper and measuring tape. Power grip strength was assessed using a Jamar hydraulic dynamometer, and fine grip strength (tip pinch and key pinch) using a hydraulic pinch gauge. Manual dexterity was evaluated with the Roeder Hand Aptitude Test. Descriptive statistics, independent <i>t</i>-tests, and Pearson correlation analyses were performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">All hand anthropometric dimensions showed significant positive correlations with power and fine grip strength, with the strongest associations observed for palm width and hand length. Male students demonstrated significantly higher grip strength than female students across all grip types (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). No significant sex-based differences were observed in manual dexterity. Most anthropometric dimensions were not significantly associated with manual dexterity, except for width-related measures (palm width, width across four fingers, and wrist width) in the more complex washer-and-nut task.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Hand anthropometric dimensions are strong predictors of grip strength but have limited influence on manual dexterity. These findings suggest that while grip strength is largely determined by physical characteristics, manual dexterity is more dependent on motor coordination and practice. The results support the importance of ergonomics-based dental education and the consideration of hand-size variability in the design of dental instruments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rastgoo Balov</LastName><ForeName>Leila</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Health, School of Health, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, West Azerbaijan Province, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allahyari</LastName><ForeName>Teimour</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6701-5050</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Health, School of Health, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, West Azerbaijan Province, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jafari</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Medicine, School of Dentistry, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hajaghazadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Health, School of Health, Urmia University of Medical Sciences, West Azerbaijan Province, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>SAGE Open Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101624744</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-3121</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Roeder hand aptitude test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dentistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">grip strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand anthropometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">manual dexterity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41929641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13039577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121261428206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20503121261428206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chenna D, Pentapati KC, Kumar M, et al. (2022). Prevalence of musculoskeletal disorders among dental healthcare providers: A systematic review and meta-analysis. F1000Research,2022; 11: 1062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9709350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36505095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meenakshi S, Raghunath N, Nandlal MN. Work related musculoskeletal disorders among general dental practitioners of Mysore district, Karnataka-A questionnaire survey. Int J Health Sci Res 2014; 4(10): 131&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anton D, Rosecrance J, Merlino L, et al. Prevalence of musculoskeletal symptoms and carpal tunnel syndrome among dental hygienists. Am J Indus Med 2022; 42(3): 248&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12210693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn J. An approach for designing dental tools. Auburn University, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta M, Saini A, Dabas H, et al. Human factors engineering in dentistry. Adv Sports Sci Technol 2025; 8: 812&#x2013;819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iordache C, F&#x103;tu AM, Chirieac R, et al. Work-related hand pathology among dentists: a pilot study. Pathology, 2016; 9(10): 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevala N, Sormunen E, Remes J, et al. Evaluation of ergonomics and efficacy of instruments in dentistry. Ergon Open J 2013; 6: 6&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayez ES. Neck pain and hand grip strength in dentists of Saudi Arabia. Int J Innov Appl Stud 2014; 9(2): 655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Counts BR, Barnett BE, et al. Associations between handgrip strength and ultrasound-measured muscle thickness of the hand and forearm in young men and women. Ultrasound Med Biol 2015; 41(8): 2125&#x2013;2130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25959055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel DPK. Ergonomics and dentistry: a brief review. MAR Dent Sci 2021; 2(3): 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salam FA, Chinnakalai T. Relationship of grip and pinch strength to body mass index among dental professionals-cross sectional study. Int J Curr Res Rev 2016; 8(21): 29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angst F, Drerup S, Werle S, et al. Prediction of grip and key pinch strength in 978 healthy subjects. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2010; 11(1): 94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2882344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20482832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kishawi M, Khalaf K, Winning T. How to improve fine motor skill learning in dentistry. Int J Dentist 2021; 2021(1): 6674213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7884127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33628248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genaro LE, Da Costa Neves T, Pazos JM, et al. Effectiveness of manual dexterity assessment methods for preclinical training in dentistry. PLoS One 2024; 19(12): e0311973. 10.1371/journal.pone.0311973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0311973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11616867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39630647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkan NF, Gokalp-Yavuz F. Effects of dexterity level and hand anthropometric dimensions on smartphone users&#x2019; satisfaction. Mobile Inform Syst 2015; 2015(1): 649374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallahi AA, Jadidian AA. The effect of hand dimensions, hand shape and some anthropometric characteristics on handgrip strength in male grip athletes and non-athletes. J Hum kineti 2011; 29: 151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3588620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23486361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akba&#x15f; A. Hand-focused strength and proprioceptive training for improving grip strength and manual dexterity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Med 2025; 14(19): 6882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12524766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41095962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fess EE. Grip strength. In: Solomon G, MacDermid J, Valdes K. (eds) Clinical assessment recommendations. ASHT, 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISO 7250. Basic human body measurements for technological design. International Standard, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathiowetz V, Kashman N, Volland G, et al. Grip and pinch strength: normative data for adults. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 1985; 66(2): 69&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3970660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roader WS. Roader manipulative aptitude test. Model 32026. Instruction Manual, 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;ak&#x131;t E, Durgun B, Cetik O. Assessing the relationship between hand dimensions and manual dexterity performance for Turkish dental students. In: Advances in physical ergonomics and human factors: Proceedings of the AHFE 2016 international conference on physical ergonomics and human factors, 27&#x2013;31 July 2016, Walt Disney World&#xae;, FL, USA. Springer International Publishing, pp. 469&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer PE, Shiri R, Kryger AI, et al. Associations of work activities requiring pinch or hand grip or exposure to hand-arm vibration with finger and wrist osteoarthritis: a meta-analysis. Scand J Work Environ Health 2014; 40(2): 133&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24310528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valachi B, Valachi K. Mechanisms of MSDs in dentistry. J Am Dent Assoc 2003; 134(10): 1344&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14620013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandoval-Alarc&#xf3;n S, B&#xe4;umle R, Castellucci HI. Impact of ergonomic interventions on musculoskeletal health and work performance in dentists and dental students: a scoping review. Appl Ergon 2025; 129: 104602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40700983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>