<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600524</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SADQN-Based Residual Energy-Aware Beamforming for LoRa-Enabled RF Energy Harvesting for Disaster-Tolerant Underground Mining Networks.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">730</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020730</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The end-to-end efficiency of radio-frequency (RF)-powered wireless communication networks (WPCNs) in post-disaster underground mine environments can be enhanced through adaptive beamforming. The primary challenges in such scenarios include (i) identifying the most energy-constrained nodes, i.e., nodes with the lowest residual energy to prevent the loss of tracking and localization functionality; (ii) avoiding reliance on the computationally intensive channel state information (CSI) acquisition process; and (iii) ensuring long-range RF wireless power transfer (LoRa-RFWPT). To address these issues, this paper introduces an adaptive and safety-aware deep reinforcement learning (DRL) framework for energy beamforming in LoRa-enabled underground disaster networks. Specifically, we develop a Safe Adaptive Deep Q-Network (SADQN) that incorporates residual energy awareness to enhance energy harvesting under mobility, while also formulating a SADQN approach with dual-variable updates to mitigate constraint violations associated with fairness, minimum energy thresholds, duty cycle, and uplink utilization. A mathematical model is proposed to capture the dynamics of post-disaster underground mine environments, and the problem is formulated as a constrained Markov decision process (CMDP). To address the inherent NP hardness of this constrained reinforcement learning (CRL) formulation, we employ a Lagrangian relaxation technique to reduce complexity and derive near-optimal solutions. Comprehensive simulation results demonstrate that SADQN significantly outperforms all baseline algorithms: increasing cumulative harvested energy by approximately 11% versus DQN, 15% versus Safe-DQN, and 40% versus PSO, and achieving substantial gains over random beamforming and non-beamforming approaches. The proposed SADQN framework maintains fairness indices above 0.90, converges 27% faster than Safe-DQN and 43% faster than standard DQN in terms of episodes, and demonstrates superior stability, with 33% lower performance variance than Safe-DQN and 66% lower than DQN after convergence, making it particularly suitable for safety-critical underground mining disaster scenarios where reliable energy delivery and operational stability are paramount.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anabi</LastName><ForeName>Hilary Kelechi</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-6049-2479</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining and Explosives Engineering, Missouri University of Science and Technology, Rolla, MO 65409, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frimpong</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8300-6824</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining and Explosives Engineering, Missouri University of Science and Technology, Rolla, MO 65409, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Madria</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Missouri University of Science and Technology, Rolla, MO 65409, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NOT GIVEN</GrantID><Acronym>CC</Acronym><Agency>CDC HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long Range (LoRa)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safe Deep Q-Network (Safe-DQN)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adaptive beamforming</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy beamforming (EB)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy harvesting (EH)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reinforcement learning (RL)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wireless power transfer (WPT)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest. The funders had no role in the design of this study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the manuscript; or in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12846087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stafford A., Requist K.W.B., Lopez S.L., Gordon J., Momayez M., Lutz E. Underground mining self-escape and mine rescue practices: An overview of current and historical trends. Min. Metall. Explor. 2023;40:2243&#x2013;2253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anabi H.K., Frimpong S., Madria S. Energy-Harvesting Concurrent LoRa Mesh with Timing Offsets for Underground Mine Emergency Communications. Information. 2025;16:984. doi: 10.3390/info16110984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info16110984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelechi A.H., Samuel F. Empirical Study of Far-Field Radio Frequency Wireless Power Transfer Testbed for Underground Mines Based on 1.8 GHz. IEEE Access. 2025;13:7923&#x2013;7938. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3525068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3525068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerguizian C., Despins C.L., Affes S., Djadel M. Radio-channel characterization of an underground mine at 2.4 GHz. IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun. 2005;4:2441&#x2013;2453. doi: 10.1109/twc.2005.853899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/twc.2005.853899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez O.L., Alves H., Souza R.D., Montejo-S&#xe1;nchez S., Fern&#xe1;ndez E.M.G., Latva-Aho M. Massive wireless energy transfer: Enabling sustainable IoT toward 6G era. IEEE Internet Things J. 2021;8:8816&#x2013;8835. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2021.3050612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2021.3050612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clerckx B., Zhang R., Schober R., Ng D.W.K., Kim D.I., Poor H.V. Fundamentals of wireless information and power transfer: From RF energy harvester models to signal and system designs. IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun. 2018;37:4&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1109/JSAC.2018.2872615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSAC.2018.2872615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y., Clerckx B., Zhang R. Communications and signals design for wireless power transmission. IEEE Trans. Commun. 2017;65:2264&#x2013;2290. doi: 10.1109/TCOMM.2017.2676103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2017.2676103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen S., Clerckx B. Joint waveform and beamforming optimization for MIMO wireless power transfer. IEEE Trans. Commun. 2021;69:5441&#x2013;5455. doi: 10.1109/TCOMM.2021.3075236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2021.3075236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mismar F.B., Evans B.L., Alkhateeb A. Deep reinforcement learning for 5G networks: Joint beamforming, power control, and interference coordination. IEEE Trans. Commun. 2019;68:1581&#x2013;1592. doi: 10.1109/tcomm.2019.2961332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tcomm.2019.2961332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Ni W., Tian H., Hua M. Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference Workshops (WCNCW), Nanjing, China, 29 March 2021. IEEE; New York City, NY, USA: 2021. Deep reinforcement learning for energy-efficient beamforming design in cell-free networks; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing Y., Young R., Nguyen G., Lefebvre M., Zhao T., Pan H., Dong L. Optimal path planning for wireless power transfer robot using area division deep reinforcement learning. Wirel. Power Transf. 2022;9:1885. doi: 10.1155/2022/9921885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/9921885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoudia F.A., Gautier M., Berder O. RLMan: An energy manager based on reinforcement learning for energy harvesting wireless sensor networks. IEEE Trans. Green Commun. Netw. 2018;2:408&#x2013;417. doi: 10.1109/TGCN.2018.2801725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGCN.2018.2801725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhuheir M., Erbad A., Al-Fuqaha A., Seid A.M. Meta reinforcement learning for UAV-assisted energy harvesting IoT devices in disaster-affected areas. IEEE Open J. Commun. Soc. 2024;5:2145&#x2013;2163. doi: 10.1109/OJCOMS.2024.3377706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/OJCOMS.2024.3377706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masadeh A., Wang Z., Kamal A.E. Proceedings of the 2018 IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC), Kansas City, MO, USA, 20&#x2013;24 May 2018. IEEE; New York City, NY, USA: 2018. Reinforcement learning exploration algorithms for energy harvesting communications systems; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psomas C., Krikidis I. Energy beamforming in wireless powered mmWave sensor networks. IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun. 2018;37:424&#x2013;438. doi: 10.1109/jsac.2018.2872381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jsac.2018.2872381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Fang Y., Ren Z., Qiu L., Xu J. Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC), Dubai, United Arab Emirates, 21&#x2013;24 April 2024. IEEE; New York City, NY, USA: 2024. Training-free energy beamforming assisted by wireless sensing; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q., Zhang H., Wang B. Beamforming design for integrated sensing and wireless power transfer systems. IEEE Commun. Lett. 2022;27:600&#x2013;604. doi: 10.1109/lcomm.2022.3216950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/lcomm.2022.3216950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmanuel A.L. Ph.D. Thesis. Toronto Metropolitan University; Toronto, ON, Canada: 2023. IioT Wireless Network Design Algorithms for Smart Mines and Tunnels.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiou O., Psomas C., Demarchou E., Krikidis I. Proceedings of the ICC 2021-IEEE International Conference on Communications, Montreal, QC, Canada, 14&#x2013;23 June 2021. IEEE; New York City, NY, USA: 2021. Lora network performance under ambient energy harvesting and random transmission schemes; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarbahram A., L&#xf3;pez O.L., Souza R.D., Zhang R., Latva-Aho M. Energy beamforming for RF wireless power transfer with dynamic metasurface antennas. IEEE Wirel. Commun. Lett. 2023;13:781&#x2013;785. doi: 10.1109/lwc.2023.3343563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/lwc.2023.3343563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muy S., Lee J.-R. Joint optimization of trajectory, beamforming, and power allocation in UAV-enabled WPT networks using DRL combined with water-filling algorithm. Veh. Commun. 2023;43:100632. doi: 10.1016/j.vehcom.2023.100632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vehcom.2023.100632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narengerile, Thompson J., Patras P., Ratnarajah T. Deep reinforcement learning-based beam training with energy and spectral efficiency maximisation for millimetre-wave channels. EURASIP J. Wirel. Commun. Netw. 2022;2022:110. doi: 10.1186/s13638-022-02191-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13638-022-02191-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Zhang X., Chen C., Niu Y., Han Z., Wang H., Sun C., Ai B., Wang Y. Deep reinforcement learning coordinated receiver beamforming for millimeter-wave train-ground communications. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2022;71:5156&#x2013;5171. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2022.3153928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3153928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge J., Liang Y.-C., Joung J., Sun S. Deep reinforcement learning for distributed dynamic MISO downlink-beamforming coordination. IEEE Trans. Commun. 2020;68:6070&#x2013;6085. doi: 10.1109/TCOMM.2020.3004524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2020.3004524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantas Y., Iturria-Rivera P.E., Zhou H., Bavand M., Elsayed M., Gaigalas R., Erol-Kantarci M. Proceedings of the ICC 2023-IEEE International Conference on Communications, Rome, Italy, 28 May 2023&#x2013;1 June 2023. IEEE; New York City, NY, USA: 2023. Beam selection for energy-efficient mmwave network using advantage actor critic learning; pp. 5285&#x2013;5290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Xiong K., Guo W., Yang X., Fan P., Letaief K.B. Q-learning-based adaptive power control in wireless RF energy harvesting heterogeneous networks. IEEE Syst. J. 2020;15:1861&#x2013;1872. doi: 10.1109/JSYST.2020.3015386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSYST.2020.3015386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao B., Tang F., Yuichi K., Kato N. AI based service management for 6G green communications. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2101.01588.2101.01588</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2101.01588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Liu H., Xiong H., Xu T., Wang F., Xin H., Wu H. RLCharge: Imitative multi-agent spatiotemporal reinforcement learning for electric vehicle charging station recommendation. IEEE Trans. Knowl. Data Eng. 2022;35:6290&#x2013;6304. doi: 10.1109/tkde.2022.3178819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tkde.2022.3178819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P.P., Paul P.S., Ananda M. Development of LoRa communication system for effective transmission of data from underground coal mines. Processes. 2023;11:1691. doi: 10.3390/pr11061691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11061691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forooshani A.E., Bashir S., Michelson D.G., Noghanian S. A survey of wireless communications and propagation modeling in underground mines. IEEE Commun. Surv. Tutor. 2013;15:1524&#x2013;1545. doi: 10.1109/SURV.2013.031413.00130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/SURV.2013.031413.00130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieters M., Wiering M.A. Proceedings of the 2016 IEEE Symposium Series on Computational Intelligence (SSCI), Athens, Greece, 6&#x2013;9 December 2016. IEEE; New York City, NY, USA: 2016. Q-learning with experience replay in a dynamic environment; pp. 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finn C., Abbeel P., Levine S. Proceedings of the 34th International Conference on Machine Learning, Sydney, Australia, 6&#x2013;11 August 2017. PMLR; New York City, NY, USA: 2017. Model-agnostic meta-learning for fast adaptation of deep networks; pp. 1126&#x2013;1135.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>