<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41413522</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Artificial intelligence (AI) for social innovation in health education: promoting health literacy through personalized ai-driven learning tools - a systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>123</StartPage><MedlinePgn>123</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12909-025-08462-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Artificial Intelligence (AI) is transforming health education by enabling personalized, adaptive, and scalable approaches that may enhance aspects of health literacy. Despite rapid adoption, comprehensive synthesis of AI tools' impact on health literacy as social innovation is limited. Understanding these effects guides educators, developers, and policymakers in designing potentially effective, inclusive, and ethical AI interventions. This review examines generative AI models, chatbots, and adaptive learning systems in supporting health literacy globally.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic review was conducted following PRISMA guidelines. Literature was identified primarily through PubMed/Medline, Scopus, and ScienceDirect. Connectedpapers.com was used exclusively as a citation chasing tool, performing both backward and forward reference searches to identify thematically linked studies not captured by database searches. All records retrieved via Connected Papers were subjected to the same eligibility criteria as database-sourced studies, covering publications from 2000-2025. A total of 75 peer-reviewed empirical and theoretical studies focusing on AI tools for health literacy and social innovation were included. Titles, abstracts, keywords, and full texts were screened using predefined criteria. Data were managed and de-duplicated using Zotero. Screening and eligibility decisions were recorded in Excel spreadsheets. Thematic synthesis was conducted manually. PRISMA 2020 and PRISMA-S checklists were used to ensure transparent reporting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">AI research in health education was minimal until 2020 but rose sharply from 2021, peaking in 2023-2024 with generative AI (e.g., ChatGPT). Of the 75 included studies, 68 (90.7%) were co-authored by two or more researchers, 54 (72.0%) were published as Open Access, and review articles dominated with 41 studies (54.7%), while empirical research was limited, highlighting moderate to weak evidence. Research focused on personalized AI tools and learning effectiveness, with limited exploration of ethics, technical barriers, or social innovation. Findings suggest that AI interventions may improve readability, metacognitive engagement, cultural accessibility, and learner autonomy in the short term, particularly when multifaceted. However, evidence for long-term behavior change and real-world impact is sparse, indicating caution in generalizing results. Challenges include algorithmic bias, digital inequity, and lack of transparency, emphasizing the need for inclusive, equity-driven AI strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">AI-powered tools have potential to support health literacy and learner-centered innovation, while contributing to social impact. Multifaceted, adaptive interventions may offer greater benefits than single-tool approaches. Findings provide preliminary guidance for standardized training, AI literacy integration, and policy frameworks, while acknowledging the current limitations in evidence, generalizability, and long-term outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tbaishat</LastName><ForeName>Dina Mansour</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8029-9716</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Technological Innovation, Zayed University, Dubai, United Arab Emirates. dina.tbaishat@zu.ac.ae.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Educational Sciences, University of Jordan, Amman, Jordan. dina.tbaishat@zu.ac.ae.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elfadel</LastName><ForeName>Maha Waleed</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1346-8051</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Educational Sciences, University of Jordan, Amman, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Social Innovation Award [12096].</GrantID><Agency>Zayed University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088679</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6920</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Literacy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006266" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Education</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence (AI)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health literacy promotion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Personalized learning tools</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic literature review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not Applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41413522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12825272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-08462-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12909-025-08462-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ali O, Abdelbaki W, Shrestha A, Elbasi E, Alryalat MAA, Dwivedi YK. A systematic literature review of artificial intelligence in the healthcare sector: Benefits, challenges, methodologies, and functionalities. J Innov Knowl. 2023;8(1):100333. 10.1016/j.jik.2023.100333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jik.2023.100333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haleem A, Javaid M. Medical 4.0 and its role in healthcare during COVID-19 pandemic: a review. J Ind Integr Manag. 2020;5(4):531&#x2013;45. 10.1142/S2424862220300045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S2424862220300045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chattu VK. A review of artificial intelligence, big data, and blockchain technology applications in medicine and global health. Big Data Cogn Comput. 2021;5(3):41. 10.3390/bdcc5030041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bdcc5030041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M, Shiwlani A, Qayyum MU, Sherani AMK, Hussain HK. AI-powered healthcare revolution: an extensive examination of innovative methods in cancer treatment. BULLET J Multidiscip Ilma. 2024;3(1):87&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasool S, Ali M, Shahroz HM, Hussain HK, Gill AY. Innovations in AI-powered healthcare: transforming cancer treatment with innovative methods. BULLET J Multidisiplin Ilmu. 2024;3(1):118&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klumpp M, Hintze M, Immonen M, R&#xf3;denas-Rigla F, Pilati F, Aparicio-Mart&#xed;nez F, et al. Artificial intelligence for hospital health care: application cases and answers to challenges in European hospitals. Healthcare. 2021;9(8):961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare9080961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8393951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34442098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vo V, Chen G, Aquino YSJ, Carter SM, Do QN, Woode ME. Multi-stakeholder preferences for the use of artificial intelligence in healthcare: A systematic review and thematic analysis. Soc Sci Med. 2023;338:116357. 10.1016/j.socscimed.2023.116357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2023.116357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37949020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeilzadeh P. Challenges and strategies for wide-scale artificial intelligence (AI) deployment in healthcare practices: A perspective for healthcare organizations. Artif Intell Med. 2024;151:102861. 10.1016/j.artmed.2024.102861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.artmed.2024.102861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38555850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richie C. Environmentally sustainable development and use of artificial intelligence in health care. Bioethics. 2022;36(5):547&#x2013;55. 10.1111/bioe.13018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bioe.13018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9311654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35290675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzano AN, Mantsios A, Mattei N, Kosorok MR, Culotta A. AI can be a powerful social innovation for public health if community engagement is at the core. J Med Internet Res. 2025;27:e68198. 10.2196/68198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/68198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11799803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39841529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo VS, Cano CAG. Health education and technological innovation: an unpostponable relationship. Health Leadersh Qual Life. 2024;3(436):1. 10.56294/hl2024.436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56294/hl2024.436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangsa K, Karim S, Gide E, Elkhodr M. A systematic review and comprehensive analysis of pioneering AI chatbot models from education to healthcare. Future Internet. 2024;16(7):219. 10.3390/fi16070219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fi16070219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radanliev P, De Roure D, Maple C, Santos O. Forecasts on future evolution of artificial intelligence and intelligent systems. IEEE Access. 2022;10:45280&#x2013;8. 10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3169580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3169580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straw I. The automation of bias in medical artificial intelligence (AI): decoding the past to create a better future. Artif Intell Med. 2020;110:101965. 10.1016/j.artmed.2020.101965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.artmed.2020.101965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortune Business Insights. Artificial intelligence in healthcare market. 2022. Available from: https://www.fortunebusinessinsights.com/industry-reports/artificial-intelligence-in-healthcare-market-100534. Cited 2024 Dec 23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Schaar M, Alaa AM, Floto A, Gimson A, Scholtes S, Wood A, et al. How artificial intelligence and machine learning can help healthcare systems respond to COVID-19. Mach Learn. 2021;110:1&#x2013;14. 10.1007/s10994-020-05928-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10994-020-05928-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33318723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shringare Y, Sarnayak A, Deshmukh R. Face mask detection-based entry control using XAI and IoT. Explainable AI: foundations, methodologies and applications. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2023. pp. 211&#x2013;24. 10.1007/978-3-031-12807-3_10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajja R, Sermet Y, Cikmaz M, Cwiertny D, Demir I. Artificial intelligence-enabled intelligent assistant for personalized and adaptive learning in higher education. Information. 2024;15(10):596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info15100596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montelaghi A, Ciorciari A, Roklicer R, Jurak G, Carraro A. AI in motion: a systematic review of artificial intelligence-driven virtual assistants for physical activity promotion and their comparison with traditional strategies. Artif Intell Rev. 2025;58(12):367. 10.1007/s10462-025-11361-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-025-11361-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Zhang R, Lee YC, Kraut RE, Mohr DC. Systematic review and meta-analysis of AI-based conversational agents for promoting mental health and well-being. NPJ Digit Med. 2023;6(1):236. 10.1038/s41746-023-00979-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-023-00979-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10730549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38114588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Fraidan A. AI language and emotional support as a physician assistant in hypertension management: an N-of-1 case study on virtual encouragement and blood pressure control. Humanit Soc Sci Commun. 2025;12(1):1&#x2013;11. 10.1057/s41599-025-05635-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/s41599-025-05635-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#xe9;gent J, Chung VH, El Adib I, D&#xe9;silets M, Hudon A. Applications of artificial intelligence in psychiatry and psychology education: scoping review. JMIR Med Educ. 2025;11:e75238. 10.2196/75238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/75238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12340458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40720804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallam M. ChatGPT utility in healthcare education, research, and practice: systematic review on the promising perspectives and valid concerns. Healthcare. 2023;11(6):887. 10.3390/healthcare11060887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11060887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10048148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36981544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peres F. Health literacy in chatgpt: exploring the potential of the use of artificial intelligence to produce academic text. Cien Saude Colet. 2024;29(1):1&#x2013;13. 10.1590/1413-81232024291.02412023EN.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1413-81232024291.02412023EN</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38198321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albahri AS, Duhaim AM, Fadhel MA, Alnoor A, Baqer NS, Alzubaidi L, et al. A systematic review of trustworthy and explainable artificial intelligence in healthcare: assessment of quality, bias risk, and data fusion. Inf Fusion. 2023;96:156&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.inffus.2023.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2023.03.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan X, Chao D, Zhang Z, Wang D, Li X, Tian F. Utilization of self-diagnosis health chatbots in real-world settings: case study. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23(1):e19928. 10.2196/19928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7817366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33404508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang EYN, Chen DR, Chen YY. Associations between literacy and attitudes toward artificial intelligence&#x2013;assisted medical consultations: the mediating role of perceived distrust and efficiency of artificial intelligence. Computers Hum Behav. 2023;139:107529. 10.1016/j.chb.2022.107529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2022.107529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan WN. Ethical challenges of AI in education: balancing innovation with data privacy. AI EDIFY J. 2024;1(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzo RR. Bridging the digital divide: AI solutions for health literacy in underserved populations. Modern management science practices in the age of AI. IGI Global; 2024:151&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apio AL, Kissi J, Achampong EK. A systematic review of artificial intelligence-based methods in healthcare. Int J Public Health Sci. 2023;12(3):1259&#x2013;69. 10.11591/ijphs.v12i3.22298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11591/ijphs.v12i3.22298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. Updating guidance for reporting systematic reviews: development of the PRISMA 2020 statement. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;134:103&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2021.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behera RK, Bala PK, Dhir A. The emerging role of cognitive computing in healthcare: a systematic literature review. Int J Med Inform. 2019;129:154&#x2013;66. 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2019.04.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2019.04.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31445250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pranckut&#x117; R. Web of science (WoS) and scopus: the titans of bibliographic information in today&#x2019;s academic world. Publications. 2021;9(1):12. 10.3390/publications9010012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/publications9010012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Wu T. Evolution of artificial intelligence in medical education from 2000 to 2024: bibliometric analysis. Interact J Med Res. 2025;14(1):e63775. 10.2196/63775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/63775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11826936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39883926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Love AS, Niu C, Labay-Marquez J. Artificial intelligence in public health education: navigating ethical challenges and empowering the next generation of professionals. Health Promot Pract. 2025;15248399251320989. 10.1177/15248399251320989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40017174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun J, Kim J, Kim H, Lee G, Cho S, Kim C, et al. A comparative analysis of on-device AI-driven, self-regulated learning and traditional pedagogy in university health sciences education. Appl Sci. 2025;15(4):1815. 10.3390/app15041815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15041815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzangare G, Gulu TA. Adopting artificial intelligence for health information literacy: a literature review. Inf Dev. 2025. 10.1177/02666669251314839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02666669251314839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick PJ. Improving health literacy using the power of digital communications to achieve better health outcomes for patients and practitioners. Front Digit Health. 2023;5:1264780. 10.3389/fdgth.2023.1264780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2023.1264780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10693297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38046643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tranfield D, Denyer D, Smart P. Towards a methodology for developing evidence-informed management knowledge by means of systematic review. Br J Manag. 2003;14(3):207&#x2013;22. 10.1111/1467-8551.00375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-8551.00375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Hashish EA, Alnajjar H. Digital proficiency: assessing knowledge, attitudes, and skills in digital transformation, health literacy, and artificial intelligence among university nursing students. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24(1):2&#x2013;11. 10.1186/s12909-024-05482-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-05482-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11077799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38715005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adegboye M. Impact of artificial intelligence on health information literacy: guidance for healthcare professionals. Libr Hi Tech News. 2024;41(7):1&#x2013;5. 10.1108/lhtn-03-2024-0048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/lhtn-03-2024-0048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajalo E, Mukunya D, Nantale R, Kayemba F, Pangholi K, Babuya J, et al. Widespread use of ChatGPT and other artificial intelligence tools among medical students in uganda: a cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2025;20(1):e0313776. 10.1371/journal.pone.0313776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0313776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11717177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39787055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhaaldi SMI, Kassab CH, Dimassi Z, Oyoun Alsoud L, Al Fahim M, Al Hageh C, et al. Medical student experiences and perceptions of ChatGPT and artificial intelligence: cross-sectional study. JMIR Med Educ. 2023;9:e51302. 10.2196/51302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/51302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10770787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38133911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almarzouki AF, Alem A, Shrourou F, Kaki S, Khushi M, Mutawakkil A, et al. Assessing the disconnect between student interest and education in artificial intelligence in medicine in Saudi Arabia. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):150. 10.1186/s12909-024-06446-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-06446-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11780997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39881303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aloi MA, Caldwell PHY, Taba M, Kang M, Skinner SR, Bray L, et al. Co-designing an online educational resource to help adolescents improve their digital health literacy. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):1870. 10.1186/s12889-025-22949-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-22949-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12093690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40399824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlZaabi A, Masters K. Assessing medical students&#x2019; readiness for artificial intelligence after pre-clinical training. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):824. 10.1186/s12909-025-07008-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-07008-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12131332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40457325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asiksoy G. Nurses&#x2019; assessment of artificial intelligence chatbots for health literacy education. J Educ Health Promot. 2025;14(1):128. 10.4103/jehp.jehp_1195_24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_1195_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12017437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40271238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au J, Falloon C, Ravi A, Ha P, Le S. A beta-prototype chatbot for increasing health literacy of patients with decompensated cirrhosis: usability study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2023;10:e42506. 10.2196/42506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/42506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10466144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37581920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayd&#x131;nlar A, Mavi A, K&#xfc;t&#xfc;k&#xe7;&#xfc; E, K&#x131;r&#x131;ml&#x131; EE, Al&#x131;&#x15f; D, Ak&#x131;n A, et al. Awareness and level of digital literacy among students receiving health-based education. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24(1):38. 10.1186/s12909-024-05025-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-05025-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10773083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38191385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayre J, Mac O, McCaffery K, McKay BR, Liu M, Shi Y, et al. New frontiers in health literacy: using ChatGPT to simplify health information for people in the community. J Gen Intern Med. 2024;39(4):573&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s11606-023-08469-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-023-08469-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10973278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37940756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumg&#xe4;rtner K, Byczkowski M, Schmid T, Muschko M, Woessner P, Gerlach A, et al. Effectiveness of the medical chatbot PROSCA to inform patients about prostate cancer: results of a randomized controlled trial. Eur Urol Open Sci. 2024;69:80&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.euros.2024.08.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euros.2024.08.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11424957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39329071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscardin CK, Gin B, Golde PB, Hauer KE. ChatGPT and generative artificial intelligence for medical education: potential impact and opportunity. Acad Med. 2024;99(1):22&#x2013;7. 10.1097/ACM.0000000000005439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0000000000005439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37651677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukar UA, Sayeed MS, Abdul Razak SF, Yogarayan S, Sneesl R. Decision-making framework for the utilization of generative artificial intelligence in education: a case study of ChatGPT. IEEE Access. 2024;12:95368&#x2013;89. 10.1109/access.2024.3425172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2024.3425172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns C, Bakaj A, Berishaj A, Hristidis V, Deak P, Equils O. Use of generative AI for improving health literacy in reproductive health: case study. JMIR Form Res. 2024;8:e59434. 10.2196/59434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/59434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11336497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38986153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charow R, Jeyakumar T, Younus S, Dolatabadi E, Salhia M, Al-Mouaswas D, Anderson M, Balakumar S, Clare M, Dhalla A, Gillan C, Haghzare S, Jackson E, Lalani N, Mattson J, Peteanu W, Tripp T, Waldorf J, Williams S, Wiljer D. Artificial intelligence education programs for health care professionals: scoping review. JMIR Med Educ. 2021;7(4):e31043. 10.2196/31043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/31043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8713099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34898458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S-Y, Kuo HY, Chang S-H. Perceptions of ChatGPT in healthcare: usefulness, trust, and risk. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1457131. 10.3389/fpubh.2024.1457131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1457131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39346584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu Y-T, Huang R-Y, Chen TT-W, Lin W-H, Tang JT, Lin C-W, et al. Effect of health literacy and shared decision-making on choice of weight-loss plan among overweight or obese participants receiving a prototype artificial intelligence robot intervention facilitating weight-loss management decisions. Digit Health. 2022;8:205520762211363. 10.1177/20552076221136372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076221136372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9638535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36353693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun J, Kim J, Kim H, Lee G, Cho S, Kim C, et al. A comparative analysis of on-device AI-driven, self-regulated learning and traditional pedagogy in university health sciences education. Appl Sci. 2025;15(4):1815. 10.3390/app15041815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15041815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dave M, Patel N. Artificial intelligence in healthcare and education. Br Dent J. 2023;234(10):761&#x2013;4. 10.1038/s41415-023-5845-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41415-023-5845-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10219811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37237212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duran S, Gonzalez AM, Nguyen K, Nguyen J, Zinn Z. Enhancing Spanish patient education materials: comparing the readability of artificial intelligence-generated Spanish patient education materials to the society of pediatric dermatology Spanish patient brochures. Pediatr Dermatol. 2025;42(1):106&#x2013;8. 10.1111/pde.15805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pde.15805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39533849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigerlova E, Hani H, Hothersall-Davies E. A systematic review of the impact of artificial intelligence on educational outcomes in health professions education. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):129. 10.1186/s12909-025-06719-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-06719-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11773843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39871336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzek S, Choi K-EA. Shaping future practices: German-speaking medical and dental students&#x2019; perceptions of artificial intelligence in healthcare. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24(1):844. 10.1186/s12909-024-05826-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-05826-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11304766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39107732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Periaysamy GA, Satapathy P, Neyazi A, Padhi BK. ChatGPT: roles and boundaries of the new artificial intelligence tool in medical education and health research &#x2013; correspondence. Ann Med Surg. 2023;85(4):1317&#x2013;8. 10.1097/ms9.0000000000000371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ms9.0000000000000371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10129198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia Valencia OA, Thongprayoon C, Miao J, Suppadungsuk S, Krisanapan P, Craici IM, Jadlowiec CC, Mao SA, Mao MA, Leeaphorn N, Budhiraja P, Cheungpasitporn W. Empowering inclusivity: improving readability of living kidney donation information with ChatGPT. Front Digit Health. 2024;6:1366967. 10.3389/fdgth.2024.1366967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2024.1366967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11039889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38659656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez M, Joga Fuentefria I, P&#xe9;rez Asenjo J, L&#xf3;pez Martin S, Arruti E. IA model for the creation of automatic and personalized health literacy plans for home care services and protocol for its validation. Int J Integr Care. 2023;23(S1):746. 10.5334/ijic.icic23620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.icic23620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson D, Jackson S, Shanmugasundaram R, Seth I, Siu A, Ahmadi N, et al. Evaluating the efficacy of ChatGPT as a patient education tool in prostate cancer: multimetric assessment. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e55939. 10.2196/55939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/55939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11358656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39141904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griewing S, Knitza J, Gremke N, Wallwiener M, Wagner U, Lingenfelder M, et al. Awareness and intention-to-use of digital health applications, artificial intelligence and blockchain technology in breast cancer care. Front Med. 2024;11:1380940. 10.3389/fmed.2024.1380940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2024.1380940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11177209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38882671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halawani A, Almehmadi SG, Alhubaishy BA, Alnefaie ZA, Hasan MN. Empowering patients: how accurate and readable are large language models in renal cancer education. Front Oncol. 2024;14:1457516. 10.3389/fonc.2024.1457516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2024.1457516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11464325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39391252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoelscher SH, Pugh A. N.U.R.S.E.S. embracing artificial intelligence: a guide to artificial intelligence literacy for the nursing profession. Nurs Outlook. 2025;73(4):102466. 10.1016/j.outlook.2025.102466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.outlook.2025.102466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40561583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen NH, Aaby A, Ryom K, Maindal HT. A CHAT about health literacy &#x2013; a qualitative feasibility study of the conversational health literacy assessment tool (CHAT) in a Danish municipal healthcare centre. Scand J Caring Sci. 2021;35(4):1250&#x2013;8. 10.1111/scs.12943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/scs.12943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9290499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33314213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha N, Shankar PR, Al-Betar MA, Mukhia R, Hada K, Palaian S. Undergraduate medical students&#x2019; and interns&#x2019; knowledge and perception of artificial intelligence in medicine. Adv Med Educ Pract. 2022;13:927&#x2013;37. 10.2147/amep.s368519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/amep.s368519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9419901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36039185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph TS, Gowrie S, Montalbano MJ, Bandelow S, Clunes M, Dumont AS, et al. The roles of artificial intelligence in teaching anatomy: a systematic review. Clin Anat. 2025;38(5):552&#x2013;67. 10.1002/ca.24272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ca.24272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12163106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40269576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch R, Steffen MT, Wetzel AJ, Preiser C, Klemmt M, Ehni HJ, et al. Exploring laypersons&#x2019; experiences with a mobile symptom checker app as an interface between eHealth literacy, health literacy, and health-related behavior: qualitative interview study. JMIR Form Res. 2025;9:e60647. 10.2196/60647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/60647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11971579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40117573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurniawan MH, Handiyani H, Nuraini T, Hariyati RTS, Sutrisno S. A systematic review of artificial intelligence-powered (AI-powered) chatbot intervention for managing chronic illness. Ann Med. 2024;56(1):2302980. 10.1080/07853890.2024.2302980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2024.2302980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10930147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38466897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau PL, Nandy M, Chakraborty S. Accelerating UN sustainable development goals with AI-driven technologies: a systematic literature review of women&#x2019;s healthcare. Healthcare. 2023;11(3):401. 10.3390/healthcare11030401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11030401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9914215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36766976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence K, Levine DL. The digital determinants of health: a guide for competency development in digital care delivery for health professions trainees. JMIR Med Educ. 2024;10:e54173. 10.2196/54173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/54173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11376139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39207389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Ruijs N, Lu Y. Ethics &amp; AI: a systematic review on ethical concerns and related strategies for designing with AI in healthcare. AI. 2022;4(1):28&#x2013;53. 10.3390/ai4010003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ai4010003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek M, Nitsche J, Dinand C, Ehlers J, Lissek V, B&#xf6;hm P, et al. Interprofessional needs analysis and user-centred prototype evaluation as a foundation for building individualized digital education in dementia healthcare supported by artificial intelligence: A study protocol. Healthcare. 2023;11(10):1508. 10.3390/healthcare11101508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11101508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10217875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maqbool T, Ishaq H, Shakeel S, Zaib Un Nisa A, Rehman H, Kashif S, et al. Future pharmacy practitioners&#x2019; insights towards integration of artificial intelligence in healthcare education: preliminary findings from Karachi, Pakistan. PLoS One. 2025;20(2):e0314045. 10.1371/journal.pone.0314045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0314045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11819520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39937780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertala P, Fagerlund J, Calderon O. Finnish 5th and 6th grade students&#x2019; pre-instructional conceptions of artificial intelligence (AI) and their implications for AI literacy education. Computers and Education: Artificial Intelligence. 2022;3:100095. 10.1016/j.caeai.2022.100095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.caeai.2022.100095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mheidly N. Unleashing the power of AI: assessing the reliability of ChatGPT in disseminating breast cancer awareness. J Educ Health Promot. 2024;13(1):172. 10.4103/jehp.jehp_1033_23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_1033_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11392253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39268446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milne-Ives M, De Cock C, Lim E, Shehadeh MH, De Pennington N, Mole G, et al. The effectiveness of artificial intelligence conversational agents in health care: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22(10):e20346. 10.2196/20346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/20346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7644372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33090118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal U, Sai S, Chamola V, Sangwan D. A comprehensive review on generative AI for education. IEEE Access. 2024;12:142733&#x2013;59. 10.1109/access.2024.3468368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2024.3468368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed M, Kumar N, Zawiah M, Al-Ashwal FY, Bala AA, Lawal BK, et al. Psychometric properties and assessment of knowledge, attitude, and practice towards ChatGPT in pharmacy practice and education: A study protocol. J Racial Ethn Health Disparities. 2024;11(4):2284&#x2013;93. 10.1007/s40615-023-01696-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-023-01696-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37428357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Will J, Gupta M, Zaretsky J, Dowlath A, Testa P, Feldman J. Enhancing the readability of online patient education materials using large language models: cross-sectional study. J Med Internet Res. 2025;27:e69955. 10.2196/69955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/69955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12177420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40465378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi Baigi SF, Sarbaz M, Ghaddaripouri K, Ghaddaripouri M, Mousavi AS, Kimiafar K. Attitudes, knowledge, and skills towards artificial intelligence among healthcare students: a systematic review. Health Sci Rep. 2023;6(3):e1138. 10.1002/hsr2.1138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.1138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10009305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36923372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naamati-Schneider L. Enhancing AI competence in health management: students&#x2019; experiences with ChatGPT as a learning tool. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24(1):598. 10.1186/s12909-024-05595-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-05595-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11140890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38816721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naseer MA, Saeed S, Afzal A, Ali S, Malik MGR. Navigating the integration of artificial intelligence in the medical education curriculum: a mixed-methods study exploring the perspectives of medical students and faculty in Pakistan. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):273. 10.1186/s12909-024-06552-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-06552-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11844081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39979912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng DTK, Luo W, Chan HMY, Chu SKW. Using digital story writing as a pedagogy to develop AI literacy among primary students. Computers and Education: Artificial Intelligence. 2022;3:100054. 10.1016/j.caeai.2022.100054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.caeai.2022.100054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xe4;del-Ablass K, Schliz K, Schlick C, et al. Teaching opportunities for anamnesis interviews through AI based teaching role plays: a survey with online learning students from health study programs. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):259. 10.1186/s12909-025-06756-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-06756-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11834289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39966894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinc&#xf3;n EHH, Jimenez D, Aguilar LAC, et al. Mapping the use of artificial intelligence in medical education: a scoping review. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):526. 10.1186/s12909-025-07089-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-07089-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11993958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40221725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodger D, Mann SP, Earp B, et al. Generative artificial intelligence in healthcare education: how AI literacy gaps could compromise learning and patient safety. Nurse Educ Pract. 2025;104461. 10.1016/j.nepr.2025.104461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40633198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez C, Gismero Rodr&#xed;guez J, Garcia Ruiz AJ, et al. Can generative AI contribute to health literacy? A study in the field of ophthalmology. Multimodal Technol Interact. 2024;8(9):79. 10.3390/mti8090079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mti8090079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saig&#xed;-Rubi&#xf3; F, Romeu T, Hern&#xe1;ndez Encuentra E, et al. Design, implementation, and analysis of an assessment and accreditation model to evaluate a digital competence framework for health professionals: mixed methods study. JMIR Med Educ. 2024;10:e53462. 10.2196/53462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/53462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11528169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39418092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallam M, Salim N, Barakat M, Al-Tammemi A. ChatGPT applications in medical, dental, pharmacy, and public health education: a descriptive study highlighting the advantages and limitations. Narra J. 2023;3(1):e103. 10.52225/narra.v3i1.103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52225/narra.v3i1.103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10914078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38450035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapci AH, Sapci HA. Artificial intelligence education and tools for medical and health informatics students: systematic review. JMIR Med Educ. 2020;6(1):e19285. 10.2196/19285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/19285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32602844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secinaro S, Calandra D, Secinaro A, Muthurangu V, Biancone P. The role of artificial intelligence in healthcare: a structured literature review. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2021;21(1):1&#x2013;23. 10.1186/s12911-021-01488-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-021-01488-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8035061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singla R, Pupic N, Ghaffarizadeh S-A, Kim C, Hu R, Forster BB, et al. Developing a Canadian artificial intelligence medical curriculum using a Delphi study. NPJ Digit Med. 2024;7(1):323. 10.1038/s41746-024-01307-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-024-01307-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11574260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39557985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skryd A, Lawrence K. ChatGPT as a tool for medical education and clinical decision-making on the wards: case study. JMIR Form Res. 2024;8:e51346. 10.2196/51346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/51346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11112466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38717811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares S, Hoffmeister LV, Fernandes MDF, Henriques A, Costa A. The use of digital technologies in the promotion of health literacy and empowerment of informal caregivers: scoping review. JMIR Aging. 2024;7:e54913. 10.2196/54913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/54913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11091806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38683655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridharan K, Sequeira RP. Artificial intelligence and medical education: application in classroom instruction and student assessment using a pharmacology &amp; therapeutics case study. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24(1):431. 10.1186/s12909-024-05365-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-024-05365-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11034110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38649959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumner B, Martin R, Gladman T, Wilkinson TJ, Grainger R. Understanding the gap: a balanced multi-perspective approach to defining essential digital health competencies for medical graduates. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25(1):1&#x2013;11. 10.1186/s12909-025-07194-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-07194-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12065156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40346629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng M, Singla R, Yau O, Lamoureux D, Gupta A, Hu Z, et al. Health care students&#x2019; perspectives on artificial intelligence: countrywide survey in Canada. JMIR Med Educ. 2022;8(1):e33390. 10.2196/33390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/33390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8845000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35099397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldock WJ, Zhang J, Guni A, Nabeel A, Darzi A, Ashrafian H. The accuracy and capability of artificial intelligence solutions in health care examinations and certificates: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e56532. 10.2196/56532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/56532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11576595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39499913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li J. Artificial intelligence empowering public health education: prospects and challenges. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1389026. 10.3389/fpubh.2024.1389026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1389026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11252473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39022411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wubineh BZ, Deriba FG, Woldeyohannis MM. Exploring the opportunities and challenges of implementing artificial intelligence in healthcare: a systematic literature review. Urol Oncol Semin Orig Investig. 2024;42(3):48&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.urolonc.2023.11.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.urolonc.2023.11.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38101991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Zhang Y, Sun D, He W, Wei Y. Navigating the landscape of AI literacy education: insights from a decade of research (2014&#x2013;2024). Humanit Soc Sci Commun. 2025;12(1):1&#x2013;12. 10.1057/s41599-025-04583-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/s41599-025-04583-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahlan A, Ranjan RP, Hayes D. Artificial intelligence innovation in healthcare: literature review, exploratory analysis, and future research. Technology Soc. 2023;74:102321. 10.1016/j.techsoc.2023.102321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techsoc.2023.102321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasra M, Jaffri R, Pavlin-Premrl D, Kok HK, Khabaza A, Barras C, et al. Can artificial intelligence improve patient educational material readability? A systematic review and narrative synthesis. Intern Med J. 2025;55(1):20&#x2013;34. 10.1111/imj.16607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/imj.16607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39720869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeidnia HR, Hashemi Fotami SG, Lund B, Ghiasi N. Ethical considerations in artificial intelligence interventions for mental health and well-being: ensuring responsible implementation and impact. Soc Sci. 2024;13(7):381. 10.3390/socsci13070381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/socsci13070381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeidnia HR, Nilashi M. From MYCIN to MedGemma: a historical and comparative analysis of healthcare AI evolution. InfoScience Trends. 2025;2(6):18&#x2013;28. 10.61186/ist.202502.06.02.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshavarz H, Ausloos M, Elango B, Givi MR, Khodashenas Z, Kiani BM, Panahi P. Using social media for health purposes: positive associations with health literacy and information behavior of students. Infosci Trends. 2025;2(1):26&#x2013;43. 10.61186/ist.202502.01.03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61186/ist.202502.01.03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>