<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41783785</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2624-9367</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in sports and active living</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Sports Act Living</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Achilles tendon ultrasound-derived properties of the dominant and non-dominant jumping leg of university basketball athletes: relation with performance, range of motion, and injury.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1753505</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1753505</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1753505</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fspor.2026.1753505</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The Achilles tendon (AT) plays a crucial role in force transmission and movement efficiency, and greater tendon stiffness may enhance elastic energy storage and improve performance in explosive movements. Shear-wave elastography (SWE) enables reliable, non-invasive assessment of tendon stiffness, yet its associations with other ultrasound (US)-derived properties and functional outcomes remain insufficiently defined in athletes. Limited normative data exists for university-level basketball players, despite the relevance of tendon adaptations and asymmetries in this population. Therefore, this study aimed to examine AT stiffness, thickness, echo intensity (EI), and fibrillar pattern in male and female university basketball athletes, and to explore their associations with ROM, injury history, and performance measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Thirty-one university basketball athletes participated in this cross-sectional study. US imaging and SWE measured AT stiffness, thickness, and EI in both the dominant jumping leg (DJL) and the non-dominant jumping leg (NDJL). Functional assessments included a single-leg vertical jump, heel raise (HR) test, and ankle dorsiflexion ROM. Participants also provided demographic information and injury history data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Female players had lower AT thickness compared to males and showed a trend toward lower stiffness. No significant differences in stiffness, thickness, or EI were observed between the dominant and non-dominant jumping legs. Male players with a prior lower-body injury exhibited lower AT stiffness. Correlation analyses revealed no consistent associations between AT properties and performance or ROM, although a strong negative correlation between AT thickness and EI emerged in both sexes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Considering sex and injury history when interpreting tendon properties is crucial, and future larger-scale, longitudinal studies are needed to better understand how tendon characteristics evolve and inform training and injury prevention strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Soontjens, Busner and Fortin.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soontjens</LastName><ForeName>Owen</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Kinesiology and Applied Physiology, Concordia University, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Busner</LastName><ForeName>Jordan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Kinesiology and Applied Physiology, Concordia University, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fortin</LastName><ForeName>Maryse</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Kinesiology and Applied Physiology, Concordia University, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health, Concordia University, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Sports Act Living</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101765780</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2624-9367</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">achilles tendon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">basketball</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shear wave elasotography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasound</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41783785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12956306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2026.1753505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pierre-Jerome C, Moncayo V, Terk MR. MRI Of the Achilles tendon: a comprehensive review of the anatomy, biomechanics, and imaging of overuse tendinopathies. Acta Radiol Stockh Swed 1987. (2010) 51(4):438&#x2013;54. 10.3109/02841851003627809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02841851003627809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20380605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohm S, Mersmann F, Marzilger R, Schroll A, Arampatzis A. Asymmetry of A chilles tendon mechanical and morphological properties between both legs. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2015) 25(1):e124&#x2013;32. 10.1111/sms.12242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24798645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazier J, Maloney S, Bishop C, Read PJ, Turner AN. Lower extremity stiffness: considerations for testing, performance enhancement, and injury risk. J Strength Cond Res. (2019) 33(4):1156&#x2013;66. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29112054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWall RJ, Slane LC, Lee KS, Thelen DG. Spatial variations in Achilles tendon shear wave speed. J Biomech. (2014) 47(11):2685&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2014.05.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2014.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4125528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24933528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien M. The anatomy of the Achilles tendon. Foot Ankle Clin. (2005) 10(2):225&#x2013;38. 10.1016/j.fcl.2005.01.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fcl.2005.01.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15922915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selcuk Can T, Ozdemir S, Yilmaz BK. Shear-Wave elastography of patellar ligament and Achilles tendon in semiprofessional athletes: comparing with nonexercising individuals. J Ultrasound Med. (2022) 41(9):2237&#x2013;46. 10.1002/jum.15908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jum.15908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34862639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas H, Noort W, Baan GC, Finni T. Non-uniformity of displacement and strain within the Achilles tendon is affected by joint angle configuration and differential muscle loading. J Biomech. (2020) 101:109634. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2020.109634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2020.109634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31983404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloney SJ, Fletcher IM. Lower limb stiffness testing in athletic performance: a critical review. Sports Biomech. (2021) 20(1):109&#x2013;30. 10.1080/14763141.2018.1460395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2018.1460395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29768094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirrichs T, Schrading S, Gatz M, Tingart M, Kuhl CK, Quack V. Shear wave elastography (SWE) of asymptomatic Achilles tendons: a comparison between semiprofessional athletes and the nonathletic general population. Acad Radiol. (2019) 26(10):1345&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.acra.2018.12.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acra.2018.12.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30655054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Althoff AD, Vance K, Plain M, Reeves RA, Pierce J, Gwathmey FW, et al. Evaluation of Achilles tendon stiffness as measured by shear wave elastography in female college athletes compared with nonathletes. Sports Health. (2023) 16(1):12&#x2013;8. 10.1177/19417381231153657</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381231153657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10732119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36856196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;mer C, Zessin E, Czupajllo J, Fischer T, Wolfarth B, Lerchbaumer MH. Effect of anthropometric parameters on Achilles tendon stiffness of professional athletes measured by shear wave elastography. J Clin Med. (2023) 12(8):2963. 10.3390/jcm12082963</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12082963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10145458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37109299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez FM, Gleason CA, Lee KS, Labid SA, Nazarian LN, Morrison WB, et al. Shear wave elastography assessment and comparison study of the Achilles tendons in optimally conditioned asymptomatic young collegiate athletes. Skeletal Radiol. (2021) 50(12):2381&#x2013;92. 10.1007/s00256-021-03798-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00256-021-03798-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33963895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez FM, Gleason CN, Tran A, Wasyliw C, Risk BB, Faulkner ES, et al. Differences in Achilles tendon mechanical properties between professional ballet dancers and collegiate athletes utilizing shear wave elastography. Skeletal Radiol. (2024) 53(7):1381&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s00256-024-04564-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00256-024-04564-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38277027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maciejewska-Skrendo A, Le&#x17a;nicka K, Leo&#x144;ska-Duniec A, Wilk M, Filip A, Ci&#x119;szczyk P, et al. Genetics of muscle stiffness, muscle elasticity and explosive strength. J Hum Kinet. (2020) 74:143&#x2013;59. 10.2478/hukin-2020-0027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2020-0027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7706646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ, McMahon J. Lower limb mechanical properties. Sports Med. (2012) 42(11):929&#x2013;40. 10.1007/BF03262304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03262304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23009192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passini FS, Jaeger PK, Saab AS, Hanlon S, Chittim NA, Arlt MJ, et al. Shear-stress sensing by PIEZO1 regulates tendon stiffness in rodents and influences jumping performance in humans. Nat Biomed Eng. (2021) 5(12):1457&#x2013;71. 10.1038/s41551-021-00716-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41551-021-00716-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34031557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujala UM, Sarna S, Kaprio J. Cumulative incidence of Achilles tendon rupture and tendinopathy in male former elite athletes. Clin J Sport Med. (2005) 15(3):133&#x2013;5. 10.1097/01.jsm.0000165347.55638.23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.jsm.0000165347.55638.23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15867554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang TT, Li Z, Zhu YC, Wang XQ, Zhang ZJ. Effects of self-myofascial release using a foam roller on the stiffness of the gastrocnemius-Achilles tendon Complex and ankle dorsiflexion range of motion. Front Physiol. (2021) 12:718827. 10.3389/fphys.2021.718827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.718827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8484700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes J, Neto T, Vaz JR, Schoenfeld BJ, Freitas SR. Is there a relationship between back squat depth, ankle flexibility, and Achilles tendon stiffness? Sports Biomech. (2022) 21(7):782&#x2013;95. 10.1080/14763141.2019.1690569</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2019.1690569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32022631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carcia CR, Martin RL, Wukich DK. Achilles pain, stiffness, and muscle power deficits: Achilles tendinitis: clinical practice guidelines linked to the international classification of functioning, disability, and health from the orthopaedic section of the American physical therapy association. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. (2010) 40(9):A1&#x2013;A26. 10.2519/jospt.2010.0305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2010.0305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20805627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama T, Kameda M, Kageyama M, Kiba K, Kanehisa H, Maeda A. Asymmetry between the dominant and non-dominant legs in the kinematics of the lower extremities during a running single leg jump in collegiate basketball players. J Sports Sci Med. (2014) 13(4):951&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25435790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne C, Watt P, Webborn N. Shear wave elastography measures of the Achilles tendon: influence of time of day, leg dominance and the impact of an acute 30-Minute bout of running. Appl Sci. (2018) 8(7):1170. 10.3390/app8071170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app8071170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sconfienza LM, Silvestri E, Cimmino MA. Sonoelastography in the evaluation of painful Achilles tendon in amateur athletes. Clin Exp Rheumatol. (2010) 28(3):373&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20525445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docking SI, Cook J. Pathological tendons maintain sufficient aligned fibrillar structure on ultrasound tissue characterization (UTC). Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2016) 26(6):675&#x2013;83. 10.1111/sms.12491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26059532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De-la-Cruz-Torres B, Barrera-Garc&#xed;a-Mart&#xed;n I, Almaz&#xe1;n-Polo J, Ja&#xe9;n-Crespo G, Romero-Morales C. Ultrasound imaging evaluation of structural and textural features in asymptomatic Achilles tendons in pre-professional dancers: a cross-sectional study. Phys Ther Sport. (2020) 44:85&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.05.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taljanovic MS, Gimber LH, Becker GW, Latt LD, Klauser AS, Melville DM, et al. Shear-Wave elastography: basic physics and musculoskeletal applications. Radiographics. (2017) 37(3):855&#x2013;70. 10.1148/rg.2017160116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/rg.2017160116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5452887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28493799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis LC, Baumer TG, Bey MJ, van Holsbeeck M. Clinical utilization of shear wave elastography in the musculoskeletal system. Ultrasonography. (2019) 38(1):2&#x2013;12. 10.14366/usg.18039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14366/usg.18039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30343557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford SK, Thelen D, Yakey JM, Heiderscheit BC, Wilson JJ, Lee KS. Regional shear wave elastography of Achilles tendinopathy in symptomatic versus contralateral Achilles tendons. Eur Radiol. (2023) 33(1):720&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00330-022-08957-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-022-08957-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9771859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne C, Watt P, Cercignani M, Webborn N. Reproducibility of shear wave elastography measuresof the Achilles tendon. Skeletal Radiol. (2018) 47(6):779&#x2013;84. 10.1007/s00256-017-2846-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00256-017-2846-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29260258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennisson JL, Deffieux T, Fink M, Tanter M. Ultrasound elastography: principles and techniques. Diagn Interv Imaging. (2013) 94(5):487&#x2013;95. 10.1016/j.diii.2013.01.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diii.2013.01.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23619292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfuraih AM, O&#x2019;Connor P, Hensor E, Tan AL, Emery P, Wakefield RJ. The effect of unit, depth, and probe load on the reliability of muscle shear wave elastography: variables affecting reliability of SWE. J Clin Ultrasound. (2018) 46(2):108&#x2013;15. 10.1002/jcu.22534</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcu.22534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28990683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatta T, Giambini H, Uehara K, Okamoto S, Chen S, Sperling JW, et al. Quantitative assessment of rotator cuff muscle elasticity: reliability and feasibility of shear wave elastography. J Biomech. (2015) 48(14):3853&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2015.09.038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2015.09.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4655159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26472309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraioli G, Barr RG, Farrokh A, Radzina M, Cui XW, Dong Y, et al. How to perform shear wave elastography. Part I. Med Ultrason. (2022) 24(1):95. 10.11152/mu-3217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11152/mu-3217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33945590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taljanovic MS, Melville DM, Klauser AS, Latt LD, Arif-Tiwari H, Gao L, et al. Advances in lower extremity ultrasound. Curr Radiol Rep. (2015) 3(6):1&#x2013;12. 10.1007/s40134-015-0100-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40134-015-0100-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraioli G, Barr RG, Farrokh A, Radzina M, Cui XW, Dong Y, et al. How to perform shear wave elastography. Part II. Med Ultrason. (2022) 24(2):196&#x2013;210. 10.11152/mu-3342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11152/mu-3342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34379714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifsud T, Gatt A, Micallef-Stafrace K, Chockalingam N, Padhiar N. Elastography in the assessment of the Achilles tendon: a systematic review of measurement properties. J Foot Ankle Res. (2023) 16(1):23. 10.1186/s13047-023-00623-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13047-023-00623-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37101290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmer M, Kleiser B, Marquetand J, Ate&#x15f; F. Shear wave elastography characterizes passive and active mechanical properties of biceps brachii muscle <i>in vivo</i>. J Mech Behav Biomed Mater. (2023) 137:105543. 10.1016/j.jmbbm.2022.105543
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmbbm.2022.105543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36371993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berrigan WA, Wickstrom J, Farrell M, Alter K. Hip position influences shear wave elastography measurements of the hamstring muscles in healthy subjects. J Biomech. (2020) 109:109930. 10.1016/j.jbiomech.2020.109930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbiomech.2020.109930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32807303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roots J, Trajano GS, Drovandi C, Fontanarosa D. Variability of Biceps muscle stiffness measured using shear wave elastography at different anatomical locations with different ultrasound machines. Ultrasound Med Biol. (2023) 49(1):398&#x2013;409. 10.1016/j.ultrasmedbio.2022.09.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultrasmedbio.2022.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36266142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhu J, Gao J, Hu Y, Liu Y, Li W, et al. 
Assessment of ultrasound shear wave elastography within muscles using different region of interest sizes, manufacturers, probes and acquisition angles: an <i>ex vivo</i> study. Quant Imaging Med Surg. (2022) 12(6):3227&#x2013;37. 10.21037/qims-21-1072
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/qims-21-1072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9131342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35655847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernabei M, Lee SSM, Perreault EJ, Sandercock TG. Shear wave velocity is sensitive to changes in muscle stiffness that occur independently from changes in force. J Appl Physiol. (2020) 128(1):8&#x2013;16. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00112.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00112.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6985815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31556833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitta N, Yamakawa M, Hachiya H, Shiina T. A review of physical and engineering factors potentially affecting shear wave elastography. J Med Ultrason. (2021) 48(4):403&#x2013;14. 10.1007/s10396-021-01127-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10396-021-01127-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8578095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34453649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuschieri S. The STROBE guidelines. Saudi J Anaesth. (2019) 13(Suppl 1):S31&#x2013;4. 10.4103/sja.SJA_543_18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/sja.SJA_543_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6398292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iversen JV, Bartels EM, Langberg H. The victorian institute of sports assessment&#x2014;Achilles questionnaire (visa-a)&#x2014;a reliable tool for measuring Achilles tendinopathy. Int J Sports Phys Ther. (2012) 7(1):76&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3273883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22319681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamber J, Cosgrove D, Dietrich CF, Fromageau J, Bojunga J, Calliada F, et al. EFSUMB Guidelines and recommendations on the clinical use of ultrasound elastography. Part 1: basic principles and technology. Ultraschall Med Stuttg Ger 1980. (2013) 34(2):169&#x2013;84. 10.1055/s-0033-1335205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0033-1335205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23558397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove D, Piscaglia F, Bamber J, Bojunga J, Correas J-M, Gilja O, et al. EFSUMB Guidelines and recommendations on the clinical use of ultrasound elastography. Part 2: clinical applications. Ultraschall Med Stuttg Ger 1980. (2013) 34(3):238&#x2013;53. 10.1055/s-0033-1335375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0033-1335375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23605169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraioli G, Filice C, Castera L, Choi BI, Sporea I, Wilson SR, et al. WFUMB Guidelines and recommendations for clinical use of ultrasound elastography: part 3: liver. Ultrasound Med Biol. (2015) 41(5):1161&#x2013;79. 10.1016/j.ultrasmedbio.2015.03.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultrasmedbio.2015.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25800942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillander B, Gauffin H, Lyth J, Knutsson A, Timpka T. Symptomatic Achilles tendons are thicker than asymptomatic tendons on ultrasound examination in recreational long-distance runners. Sports. (2019) 7(12):245. 10.3390/sports7120245</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7120245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6955697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Deng L, Xiao S, Li L, Fu W. Sex differences in the morphological and mechanical properties of the Achilles Tendon. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2021) 18(17):8974. 10.3390/ijerph18178974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18178974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8430544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneebeli A, Del Grande F, Vincenzo G, Cescon C, Barbero M. Test-retest reliability of echo intensity parameters in healthy Achilles tendons using a semi-automatic tracing procedure. Skeletal Radiol. (2017) 46(11):1553&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s00256-017-2748-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00256-017-2748-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28828624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker-Petersen C, Juul-Kristensen B, Antflick J, Aagaard H, Myers C, Boesen AP, et al. Six weeks of intensive rehearsals for the Swan lake ballet shows ultrasound tissue characterization changes of the Achilles tendons in dancers. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2021) 31(11):2133&#x2013;43. 10.1111/sms.14034</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34407248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maulder P, Cronin J. Horizontal and vertical jump assessment: reliability, symmetry, discriminative and predictive ability. Phys Ther Sport. (2005) 6(2):74&#x2013;82. 10.1016/j.ptsp.2005.01.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2005.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fradkin AJ, Zazryn TR, Smoliga JM. Effects of warming-up on physical performance: a systematic review with meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. (2010) 24(1):140&#x2013;8. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c643a0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c643a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorborg K, Krommes KK, Esteve E, Clausen MB, Bartels EM, Rathleff MS. Effect of specific exercise-based football injury prevention programmes on the overall injury rate in football: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the FIFA 11 and 11+ programmes. Br J Sports Med. (2017) 51(7):562&#x2013;71. 10.1136/bjsports-2016-097066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28087568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohannon RW. The heel-raise test for ankle plantarflexor strength: a scoping review and meta-analysis of studies providing norms. J Phys Ther Sci. (2022) 34(7):528&#x2013;31. 10.1589/jpts.34.528</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.34.528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9246404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35784604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silbernagel KG, Nilsson-Helander K, Thome&#xe9; R, Eriksson BI, Karlsson J. A new measurement of heel-rise endurance with the ability to detect functional deficits in patients with Achilles tendon rupture. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. (2010) 18(2):258&#x2013;64. 10.1007/s00167-009-0889-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-009-0889-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19690833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sman AD, Hiller CE, Imer A, Ocsing A, Burns J, Refshauge KM. Design and reliability of a novel heel rise test measuring device for plantarflexion endurance. BioMed Res Int. (2014) 2014:391646. 10.1155/2014/391646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/391646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4022004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24877089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez MR, Athens J, Balsalobre-Fernandez C, Kubo M, H&#xe9;bert-Losier K. Concurrent validity and reliability of a mobile iOS application used to assess calf raise test kinematics. Musculoskelet Sci Pract. (2023) 63:102711. 10.1016/j.msksp.2022.102711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msksp.2022.102711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36604270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konor MM, Morton S, Eckerson JM, Grindstaff TL. Reliability of three measures of ankle dorsiflexion range of motion. Int J Sports Phys Ther. (2012) 7(3):279&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3362988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22666642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. New York: Routledge; (2013). 10.4324/9780203771587</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9780203771587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intziegianni K, Cassel M, Hain G, Mayer F. Gender differences of Achilles tendon cross-sectional area during loading. Sports Med Int Open. (2017) 1(04):E135&#x2013;40. 10.1055/s-0043-113814</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-113814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6226073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30539098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gianakos AL, Hartman H, Kerkhoffs GMMJ, Calder J, Kennedy JG. Sex differences in biomechanical properties of the Achilles tendon may predispose men to higher risk of injury: a systematic review. J ISAKOS. (2024) 9(2):184&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.jisako.2023.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jisako.2023.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37967617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arda K, Ciledag N, Aktas E, Ar&#x131;bas BK, K&#xf6;se K. Quantitative assessment of normal soft-tissue elasticity using shear-wave ultrasound elastography. Am J Roentgenol. (2011) 197(3):532&#x2013;6. 10.2214/AJR.10.5449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2214/AJR.10.5449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson SP, Hansen P, Kj&#xe6;r M. Tendon properties in relation to muscular activity and physical training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2003) 13(4):211&#x2013;23. 10.1034/j.1600-0838.2003.00308.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1600-0838.2003.00308.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12859603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK, Angadi SS, Bhargava A, Harper J, Hirschberg AL, Levine BD, et al. The biological basis of sex differences in athletic performance: consensus statement for the American college of sports medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2023) 55(12):2328&#x2013;60. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000003300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37772882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell DR, Blackburn JT, Norcorss MF, Ondrak KS, Hudson JD, Hackney AC, et al. Estrogen and muscle stiffness have a negative relationship in females. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. (2012) 20(2):361&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s00167-011-1577-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-011-1577-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21695466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobolewski&#x2d9; E, Crow J, Murr S, Hutchi&#x2d9;Son R. Physiological performance characteristics of male and female division I cross-country runners. Int J Sport Exerc Train Sci. (2021) 7:84&#x2013;75. 10.18826/useeabd.943976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18826/useeabd.943976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu TC, Ngo HC, Lau LW, Leung KW, Lo MH, Yu HF, et al. An investigation of the immediate effect of static stretching on the morphology and stiffness of Achilles tendon in dominant and non-dominant legs. PLoS One. (2016) 11(4):e0154443. 10.1371/journal.pone.0154443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0154443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4847758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27120097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanac G, Lemac D, Kosovic V, Bojanic K, Cengic T, Dumic-Cule I, et al. Importance of shear-wave elastography in prediction of Achilles tendon rupture. Int Orthop. (2021) 45(4):1043&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s00264-020-04670-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-020-04670-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya S, Kulig K. Tendinopathy alters mechanical and material properties of the Achilles tendon. J Appl Physiol. (2010) 108(3):670&#x2013;5. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00259.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00259.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19892931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Schie HT, de Vos RJ, de Jonge S, Bakker EM, Heijboer MP, Verhaar JA, et al. Ultrasonographic tissue characterisation of human Achilles tendons: quantification of tendon structure through a novel non-invasive approach. Br J Sports Med. (2010) 44(16):1153&#x2013;9. 10.1136/bjsm.2009.061010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2009.061010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19666626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docking SI, Rosengarten SD, Cook J. Achilles tendon structure improves on UTC imaging over a 5-month pre-season in elite Australian football players. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2016) 26(5):557&#x2013;63. 10.1111/sms.12469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malliaras P, Voss C, Garau G, Richards P, Maffulli N. Achilles tendon shape and echogenicity on ultrasound among active badminton players. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2012) 22(2):149&#x2013;55. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01156.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01156.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20561268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno T, Yoshiko A, Yamashita N, Harada K, Takeuchi K, Matsuo S, et al. Determinants of maximal dorsiflexion range of motion: multi-perspective comparison using mechanical, neural, morphological, and muscle quality factors. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. (2024) 9(4):257. 10.3390/jfmk9040257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk9040257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11679652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39728241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denegar CR, Hertel J, Fonseca J. The effect of lateral ankle sprain on dorsiflexion range of motion, posterior talar glide, and joint laxity. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. (2002) 32(4):166&#x2013;73. 10.2519/jospt.2002.32.4.166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2002.32.4.166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11949665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudel J, Turner &#xc9;, Cl&#xe9;ment J. Intraday variation of ankle dorsiflexion in short-track speed skaters. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. (2024) 19(8):833&#x2013;5. 10.1123/ijspp.2023-0423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2023-0423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38906530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez FM, Gleason CN, Reiter DA, Dunham J, Sayyid SK, Labib SA. <i>In vivo</i> sonographic characterization of the Achilles tendons in healthy young collegiate athletes as a function of ankle position. J Foot Ankle Surg. (2020) 59(5):898&#x2013;902. 10.1053/j.jfas.2020.01.009
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jfas.2020.01.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32624409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. Influence of elastic properties of tendon structures on jump performance in humans. J Appl Physiol. (1999) 87(6):2090&#x2013;6. 10.1152/jappl.1999.87.6.2090</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1999.87.6.2090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelsattar M, Konrad A, Tilp M. Relationship between Achilles tendon stiffness and ground contact time during drop jumps. J Sports Sci Med. (2018) 17(2):223&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5950739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29769823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods MA, Watsford ML, Cavanagh BP, Pruyn EC. Factors affecting jump performance in professional Australian rules footballers. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. (2015) 55(10):1114&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26129913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Pe&#xf1;a E, Formiglio E, Gervasi M, Benelli P, Bertuccioli A, Russo G, et al. The impact of track and field training on dynapenia: gender differences in age-related decline of vertical jump performance among older adults. Front Aging. (2024) 5:1504789. 10.3389/fragi.2024.1504789</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fragi.2024.1504789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11672781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39735687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Correa-Bautista JE, Lobelo F, Cadore EL, Alonso-Martinez AM, Izquierdo M. Vertical jump and leg power normative data for Colombian schoolchildren aged 9&#x2013;17.9 years: the FUPRECOL study. J Strength Cond Res. (2017) 31(4):990&#x2013;8. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28328716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty HJ, Weiss LW, Paquette MR, Powell DW, Allison LE. Potential predictors of vertical jump performance: lower extremity dimensions and alignment, relative body fat, and kinetic variables. J Strength Cond Res. (2021) 35(3):616&#x2013;25. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt M, Simonsen EB, Dyhre-Poulsen P, Klausen K. Mechanical and muscular factors influencing the performance in maximal vertical jumping after different prestretch loads. J Biomech. (1995) 28(3):293&#x2013;307. 10.1016/0021-9290(94)00062-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0021-9290(94)00062-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7730388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H-K, Lin K-H, Su S-C, Shih TT-F, Huang Y-C. Effects of tendon viscoelasticity in A chilles tendinosis on explosive performance and clinical severity in athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2012) 22(6):e147&#x2013;55. 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2012.01511.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2012.01511.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22830527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaara JP, Kyr&#xf6;l&#xe4;inen H, Niemi J, Ohrank&#xe4;mmen O, H&#xe4;kkinen A, Kocay S, et al. Associations of maximal strength and muscular endurance test scores with cardiorespiratory fitness and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. (2012) 26(8):2078&#x2013;86. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823b06ff</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823b06ff</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21997456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtara M, Chaouachi A, Levin GT, Chamari K, Amri M, Laursen PB. Effect of concurrent endurance and circuit resistance training sequence on muscular strength and power development. J Strength Cond Res. (2008) 22(4):1037&#x2013;45. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a4419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a4419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel TJ, Nimphius S, Bellon CR, Stone MH. The importance of muscular strength: training considerations. Sports Med. (2018) 48(4):765&#x2013;85. 10.1007/s40279-018-0862-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0862-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appel M, Zentgraf K, Kr&#xfc;ger K, Alack K. Effects of genetic variation on endurance performance, muscle strength, and injury susceptibility in sports: a systematic review. Front Physiol. (2021) 12:694411. 10.3389/fphys.2021.694411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.694411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8334364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34366884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie K, Kenny IC, Lyons M, Carson BP. The effect of strength training on performance in endurance athletes. Sports Med. (2014) 44(6):845&#x2013;65. 10.1007/s40279-014-0157-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0157-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24532151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;mer C, Legerlotz K, Czupajllo J, Fischer T, Wolfarth B, Lerchbaumer MH. Acute effects of running on shear wave elastography measures of the Achilles tendon and calf muscles in professional female handball and volleyball players. Diagnostics. (2023) 13(18):2957. 10.3390/diagnostics13182957</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13182957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10530130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37761324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>