<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41495748</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of PAPE induced by different squat loads on jump performance in collegiate female basketball players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>58</StartPage><MedlinePgn>58</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">58</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01508-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Post-activation performance enhancement (PAPE) effectively augments explosive performance, especially in jumping. As female athletes have distinct neuromuscular and biomechanical traits that may affect the PAPE response, the optimal squat load and recovery duration for collegiate female basketball players remains unclear. This study aimed to investigate how different back-squat conditioning loads influence subsequent jump performance and to identify the optimal load-recovery combination for enhancing jumping ability in this population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Twenty-eight collegiate women&#x2019;s basketball athletes(age 20.39&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.4 years, height 167.50&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.22&#xa0;cm, body mass 57.75&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.98&#xa0;kg, training age 6.49&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.63 years)were randomly allocated to 90%, 80%, or 70% of one-repetition maximum (1RM) back-squat groups, or a control group. Athletes completed 3&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;3 parallel back squats, after which countermovement jump (CMJ), single-leg and double-leg approach-jump heights were assessed at baseline and 4, 8, and 12&#xa0;min. CMJ kinetics&#x2014;peak power output, vertical ground-reaction force, and flight time&#x2014;and lower-limb surface EMG were recorded concurrently.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Loads&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;80%1RM reliably elicited PAPE, with improvements demonstrating clear load-dependence and time specificity. Double-leg approach-jump height peaked at 8&#xa0;min in the 90%1RM group (40.50&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.73&#xa0;cm). Single-leg approach-jump height was maximized at 8&#xa0;min in the 80%1RM group (40.00&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.82&#xa0;cm), exceeding the control condition. Kinetic and EMG analyses indicated that 90%1RM produced a delayed rectus femoris activation peak (8&#xa0;min) and a later CMJ power peak (12&#xa0;min), whereas 80%1RM facilitated earlier gastrocnemius activation (4&#xa0;min) with a stable output profile; performance benefits with 70%1RM were minimal.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">For collegiate female basketball players, using a parallel back-squat load of 80%1RM followed by an 8&#x2013;12-minute recovery period can effectively improve jump performance during pre-competition activation. Coaches and trainers should be aware that responses may differ between individuals, and testing this protocol beforehand is recommended to optimize its use for specific athletes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">Chinese Clinical Trial Registry ChiCTR2500112937; Registration date: 21/11/2025; Retrospectively registered.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-025-01508-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Si</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yu Hang</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Education, Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xin Ru</ForeName><Initials>XR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shanxi University, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ning</LastName><ForeName>Shao Jie</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Qing Bo</ForeName><Initials>QB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Tianjin University of Sport, Tianjin, China. lqb_tjus@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Female basketball players</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parallel squat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-activation performance enhancement (PAPE)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee of Tianjin University of Sport (Approval No.: Tjus2025-103) and conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Informed consent was obtained from all participants. Consent for publication: Not applicable. The manuscript does not include the participant&#x2019;s identification image or other personal or clinical details. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41495748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12870403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01508-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01508-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, LI F, Jiao J, et al. Effects of different training methods on Open-Skill and Closed-Skill agility in basketball players: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis [J]. Sports Med Open. 2025;11(1):50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00842-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12058619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40332702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sansone P, Fortes L S, Caparros T, et al. Breaking Down the 3 &#xd7; 3 Basketball Game: How Tournament Phase, Game Outcome, and Final Score Margin Impact Physiological, Perceptual, and Mental Demands [J]. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2025;20(6):834&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2024-0516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40268277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu T, Tsuchiya Y, Ueda H, et al. Eight-Week flywheel training enhances jump performance and Stretch-Shortening cycle function in collegiate basketball players. Eur J Sport Sci. 2025;25(2):e12257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejsc.12257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11774620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39875211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro-rom&#xe1;n V, Siquier-coll J, Grijota FJ, et al. Selenium concentrations in soccer players during a sports season: sex differences. Nutrients. 2025;17(14):2257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12298705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40732882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlie J, Krassowski V. Effects of menstrual cycle phases on athletic performance and related physiological outcomes: a systematic review of studies using high methodological standards [J]. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2025;139(3):650&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00223.2025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40695607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins HA, Barbosa JG, Seffrin A, et al. Sex differences in maximal oxygen uptake adjusted for skeletal muscle mass in amateur endurance athletes: a cross sectional study. Healthc (Basel). 2023;11(10):1502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10218102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RE, Paquette MR, Harry JR, et al. Footwear and sex differences in performance and joint kinetics during maximal vertical jumping [J]. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(6):1634&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29979276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louder T, Thompson BJ, Woster A, et al. Kinetics of depth jumps performed by female and male national collegiate athletics association basketball athletes and young adults. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2023;8(3):108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10443298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37606403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart A, Vetrovsky T, Cochrane-snyman K C, et al. Investigating the consistency in countermovement jump performance after High-Velocity and High-Force PAPE: A multiday analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2025;39(7):e843&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40267397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu K, Blazevich A J, Boullosa D, et al. Response to comment on optimizing Post-Activation performance enhancement in athletic tasks: A systematic review with Meta-Analysis for prescription variables and research methods . Sports Med. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40946130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim TM, Gurgel AV Faleirov, et al. Impacts of traditional warm-up and post-activation potentiation on muscle endurance during the back squat: response of blood lactate, perceived effort, and time under tension. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2025;10(2):188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12194115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40566438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ler I, Yilmaz C, Soylu H H, et al. Inspiratory muscle training in natural bodybuilders: adaptations in diaphragm muscle thickness and maximal strength. Front Physiol. 2025;16:1628146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1628146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12358352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40832136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terbalyan A, Skotniczny K, Krzysztofik M, et al. Effect of post-activation performance enhancement in combat sports: a systematic review and meta-analysis-part I: general performance indicators. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2025;10(1):88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11943059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40137340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarosz J, Gawel D, Grycmann P, et al. How repeatable is PAPE effect: the impact of in-season isometric squat activation on countermovement jump performance enhancement in National level soccer players [J]. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2025;17(1):115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01148-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12051318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40325482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Lim J, Thapa RK. Effects of deadlift vs. back squat as post-activation performance enhancement protocols on vertical jump performance of competitive male basketball players. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2025;7:399&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42978-024-00290-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tutar M, Gen&#xe7; S, &#xc7;a&#x11f;layan A, et al. Acute sprint performance responses to velocity-based versus traditional post activation performance enhancement interventions [J]. PLoS ONE. 2025;20(9):e0332479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0332479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12435655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40953043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-sanchez J, Rodr&#xed;guez-fern&#xe1;ndez A. Strength-dependent differences in the magnitude and time course of post-activation performance enhancement in high jump athletes. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2025;10(3):333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12452759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40981032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota G R. Comment on optimizing Post&#x2013;Activation performance enhancement in athletic tasks: A systematic review with Meta&#x2013;analysis for prescription variables and research methods. Sports Med. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40946130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D, Feng S, Zhou A, et al. Heavy load chain squats: a promising method for enhancing lower extremity explosive strength via post-activation performance enhancement [J]. Front Physiol. 2025;16:1596200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2025.1596200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12213354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40606228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esformes J I, Bampouras TM. Effect of back squat depth on lower-body postactivation potentiation. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(11):2997&#x2013;3000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828d4465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B J, Contreras B, Willardson JM, et al. Muscle activation during low- versus high-load resistance training in well-trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(12):2491&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-014-2976-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez S C, Coons J M, Mehls KD. Effect of external load on muscle activation during the barbell back squat. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23(6):975&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2022.2081093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houlton L J, Moody J A, Bampouras T M, et al. Acute effects of intracontrast rest after back squats on vertical jump performance during complex training. J Strength Cond Res. 2024;38(11):e645&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39016263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witmer C A, Davis S E, Moir G L. The acute effects of back squats on vertical jump performance in men and women. J Sports Sci Med. 2010;9(2):206&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makaraci Y, Ruiz-c&#xe1;rdenas J D, Pamuk &#xd6;, et al. Kinesio taping does not enhance jump performance and muscle activity in female athletes. Int J Sports Med. 2025;46(4):271&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2491-1988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39603263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mckay A K A, Stellingwerff T, Smith E S, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: A participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34965513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff Seitzlb. Factors modulating Post-Activation potentiation of Jump, Sprint, Throw, and Upper-Body ballistic performances: A systematic review with Meta-Analysis [J]. Sports Med. 2016;46(2):231&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0415-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26508319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JM, Duncan N M Marinpj, et al. Meta-analysis of postactivation potentiation and power: effects of conditioning activity, volume, gender, rest periods, and training status. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(3):854&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825c2bdb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22580978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouv&#xea;a A L, Fernandes I A, C&#xe9;sar E P, et al. The effects of rest intervals on jumping performance: a meta-analysis on post-activation potentiation studies. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(5):459&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.738924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23140550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chtourou H, Souissi N. The effect of training at a specific time of day: a review. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(7):1984&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31825770a7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22531613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccann M R, Flanagan S P. The effects of exercise selection and rest interval on postactivation potentiation of vertical jump performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(5):1285&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d6867c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20393352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercer R A J, Russell J L, Mcguigan L C, et al. Finding the signal in the Noise-Interday reliability and seasonal sensitivity of 84 countermovement jump variables in professional basketball players [J]. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(2):394&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36696261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-klug, C, et al. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10(5):361&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1050-6411(00)00027-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11018445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mark burden A, Lewis S E Willcoxe. The effect of manipulating root mean square window length and overlap on reliability, inter-individual variability, statistical significance and clinical relevance of electromyograms [J]. Man Ther. 2014;19(6):595&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.math.2014.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24985956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112(1):155&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.112.1.155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich A J Babaultn. Post-activation potentiation versus Post-activation performance enhancement in humans: historical Perspective, underlying Mechanisms, and current issues. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.01359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31736781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel T J Nimphiuss, Bellon C R, et al. The importance of muscular strength: training considerations. Sports Med. 2018;48(4):765&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-0862-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevan H R, Cunningham D J, Tooley E P, et al. Influence of postactivation potentiation on sprinting performance in professional rugby players. J Strength Cond Res. 2010;24(3):701&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c7b68a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20145565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crewther B T, Kilduff L P, Cook C J, et al. The acute potentiating effects of back squats on athlete performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(12):3319&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318215f560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22076086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott D J, Ditroilo M. Effect of accommodating resistance on the postactivation potentiation response in rugby league players. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2018;32(9):2510&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29401203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sygulla K S, Fountaine CJ. Acute Post-Activation potentiation effects in NCAA division II female athletes. Int J Exerc Sci. 2014;7(3):212&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/ZBEL2600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4831861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27182405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makaruk H, Winchester J B, Sadowski J, et al. Effects of unilateral and bilateral plyometric training on power and jumping ability in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(12):3311&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318215fa33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22076090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riches C J Rogersons, Jennings C, et al. The effect of five weeks of tribulus terrestris supplementation on muscle strength and body composition during preseason training in elite rugby league players [J]. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(2):348&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boullosa D. Post-activation performance enhancement strategies in sport: a brief review for practitioners. Hum Mov. 2021;22(3):101&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/hm.2021.103280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tillin NA. Factors modulating post-activation potentiation and its effect on performance of subsequent explosive activities. Sports Med. 2009;39(2):147&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200939020-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19203135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappelt L, Held S, Wiedenmann T, et al. Post-activation performance enhancement (PAPE) protocols do not further increase jumping performance beyond warm-up effects: findings from three acute randomized crossover trials. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1447421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1447421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11350113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39206386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormie P, Mcguigan M R. Newton R U. Developing maximal neuromuscular power: part 2 - training considerations for improving maximal power production. Sports Med. 2011;41(2):125&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11538500-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21244105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villalon-gasch L, Penichet-tomas A, Sebastia-amat S, et al. Postactivation performance enhancement (PAPE) increases vertical jump in elite female volleyball players [J]. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(1):462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19010462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8744649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donahue PT, McInnis AK, Williams MK, et al. Examination of countermovement jump performance changes in collegiate female volleyball in fatigued conditions [J]. J Funct Morphology Kinesiol. 2023;8(3):137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk8030137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10532426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37754970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comyns T M, HsrrisonA J, Hennessy LK, et al. The optimal complex training rest interval for athletes from anaerobic sports [J]. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(3):471&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuzzo JL. Narrative review of sex differences in muscle strength, Endurance, Activation, Size, fiber Type, and strength training participation Rates, Preferences, Motivations, Injuries, and neuromuscular adaptations [J]. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37(2):494&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36696264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada T, Kimura T, Moritani T. Selective fatigue of fast motor units after electrically elicited muscle contractions [J]. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2004;14(5):531&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2004.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15301772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caterisano A, Moss RF, Pellinger TK, et al. The effect of back squat depth on the EMG activity of 4 superficial hip and thigh muscles [J]. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16(3):428&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12173958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K, Leicht AS, Boullosa D, et al. Lunge exercises with blood-flow restriction induces post-activation potentiation and improves vertical jump performance [J]. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120(3):687&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-020-04308-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32006099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>