<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41822751</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1303-6092</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Turkish journal of biology = Turk biyoloji dergisi</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Turk J Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structure-activity modeling and hybrid machine learning-based prediction of bioactivity in pyrazole derivatives for drug discovery applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37</StartPage><EndPage>61</EndPage><MedlinePgn>37-61</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.55730/1300-0152.2789</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pyrazole derivatives are of growing interest due to their diverse pharmacological activities. However, their biological activity is often highly sensitive to subtle structural modifications. Existing quantitative structure-activity relationships (QSAR) approaches frequently fail to capture the conformational flexibility and nonlinear structure-activity relationships (SAR) of such heterocyclic scaffolds, creating a gap in the accurate prediction of their biological profiles. Therefore, there is a strong need for more robust and predictive computational frameworks. This study addresses this gap by integrating four-dimensional (4D)-QSAR descriptors with hybrid machine learning (ML) techniques to improve predictive accuracy and provide a more reliable tool for structure-based drug design. In this work, it was aimed to investigate the SAR of a series of pyrazole-based compounds using this advanced integrative computational strategy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The dataset consisted of 54 pyrazole derivatives, of which 50 compounds were used for model construction and 4 compounds were reserved as a test set for validation. Although the test set was limited in size, the selected compounds were structurally representative of the training set, sharing the same core scaffold while covering different substitution patterns and biological activity values. The 4D-QSAR approach included multiple conformations of each compound and utilized matrix-based representations of geometric and electronic properties to capture dynamic molecular behavior. A pharmacophore model was generated using EMRE software based on the spatial and electronic features of used compounds. EMRE is an in-house software developed by our research group. It has been employed in several previously published 4D-QSAR studies for electron-conformational matrix of contiguity construction, pharmacophore modeling, descriptor matrix generation, and activity prediction. EMRE operates on standard geometric and electronic descriptors derived from quantum-chemical calculations, ensuring methodological transparency and reproducibility despite its proprietary implementation. Comparable performance trends obtained with EMRE-based 4D-QSAR models have been reported in previous studies, supporting the validity of the software for pharmacophore-driven QSAR analysis (&#x15e;ahin et al., 2011; Sahin and Saripinar, 2020; Sahin et al., 2021).Using this framework, a total of 204 molecular descriptors were computed using Spartan 07. To reduce redundancy and prevent overfitting, descriptor selection was optimized through a genetic algorithm (GA)-based procedure (Fernandez et al., 2011), and only statistically significant descriptors with low intercorrelation were retained for model construction. Subsequently, multiple ML algorithms, including artificial neural network, decision tree, and hybrid models, were evaluated to enhance prediction accuracy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among all the tested models, the gradient boosting machine and random forest (GBM+RF) hybrid algorithm yielded the highest predictive performance, with an R<sup>2</sup> value of 0.99978. To assess the robustness of the ML models, the training and validation procedures were repeated using different random seed initializations. The resulting performance metrics showed only minor variations across runs, indicating that the predictive performance of the GBM, RF, and GBM+RF hybrid models was not sensitive to random seed selection. The overall dataset comprised 54 pyrazole derivatives, with 50 molecules used for model construction and 4 reserved for validation. Although the high R<sup>2</sup> value indicates strong internal consistency, it should be interpreted with caution due to the relatively small sample sizes for the construction of the model and the test subset. Overall, the integration of 4D-QSAR and ML approaches demonstrated strong predictive capability and effectively captured the key geometric and electronic features associated with biological activity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The electron conformational-GA computational strategy provides a robust framework for the rational design and virtual screening of pyrazole derivatives, leveraging multi-conformer modeling and a diverse set of molecular descriptors to identify potentially active compounds. The study was limited by the small size of the training and test set and the absence of experimental validation, which may constrain the generalizability of the findings. Future work could address these limitations by applying the model to larger and more diverse ligand dataset, performing virtual screening of compound libraries to discover novel hits, and validating promising candidates through in vitro assays. Overall, these findings support the potential of this scaffold for drug discovery, while further experimental studies are warranted to confirm the predicted activities and refine the predictive power of the model.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; T&#xdc;B&#x130;TAK.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x15e;ahin</LastName><ForeName>Kader</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9056-9000</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biochemistry, School of Medicine, Band&#x131;rma Onyedi Eyl&#xfc;l University, Bal&#x131;kesir, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Biology and Molecular Simulations Laboratory, Department of Biophysics, School of Medicine, Bah&#xe7;e&#x15f;ehir University, &#x130;stanbul, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kili&#xe7;arslan</LastName><ForeName>Serhat</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9483-4425</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Software Engineering, Faculty of Engineering and Natural Sciences, Band&#x131;rma Onyedi Eylul University, Bal&#x131;kesir, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durda&#x11f;i</LastName><ForeName>Serdar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0426-0905</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Therapy Lab, Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, School of Pharmacy, Bah&#xe7;e&#x15f;ehir University, &#x130;stanbul, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computational Biology and Molecular Simulations Laboratory, Department of Biophysics, School of Medicine, Bah&#xe7;e&#x15f;ehir University, &#x130;stanbul, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Innovative Drugs (Lab4IND), Computational Drug Design Center (H&#x130;TMER), Bah&#xe7;e&#x15f;ehir University, &#x130;stanbul, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Systems Biology Lab, Biruni University Scientific Research Center, Biruni University, Istanbul, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saripinar</LastName><ForeName>Emin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0116-0239</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, Erciyes University, Kayseri, Turkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Turkey</Country><MedlineTA>Turk J Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9434434</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1300-0152</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">4D-QSAR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GBM+RF hybrid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pyrazole derivatives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacophore modeling</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41822751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12978768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55730/1300-0152.2789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">tjb-50-01-37</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmed AHH, Mohamed MFA, Beshr EMA. A mini review on some biological activities of pyrazole derivatives. International Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences and Drug Analysis. 2024;4(2):34&#x2013;40. doi: 10.22271/27889246.2024.v4.i2a.99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22271/27889246.2024.v4.i2a.99</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altun A, Golcuk K, Kumru M, Jalbout AF. Electron-conformational study for the structure-hallucinogenic activity relationships of phenylalkylamines. Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry. 2003;11(18):3861&#x2013;3868. doi: 10.1016/S0968-0896(03)00437-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0968-0896(03)00437-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12927846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade CH, Pasqualoto KFM, Ferreira EI, Hopfinger AJ. 4D-QSAR: Perspectives in Drug Design. Molecules. 2010;15(5):3281&#x2013;3294. doi: 10.3390/molecules15053281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules15053281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6263259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20657478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker OM, Levy Y, Ravitz O. Flexibility, conformation spaces, and bioactivity. The Journal of Physical Chemistry B. 2000;104(9):2123&#x2013;2135. doi: 10.1021/jp992268m.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp992268m</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernazzani L, Duce C, Micheli A, Mollica V, Sperduti A, et al. Predicting physical-chemical properties of compounds from molecular structures by recursive neural networks. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. 2006;46(5):2030&#x2013;2042. doi: 10.1021/ci060104e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci060104e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16995734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersuker IB. Pharmacophore identification and quantitative bioactivity prediction using the electron-conformational method. Current Pharmaceutical Design. 2003;9(20):1575&#x2013;1606. doi: 10.2174/1381612033454586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1381612033454586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12871060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersuker IB. QSAR without arbitrary descriptors: the electron-conformational method. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design. 2008;22(6&#x2013;7):423&#x2013;430. doi: 10.1007/s10822-008-9191-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10822-008-9191-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18283420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersuker IB, Bahceci S, Boggs JE, Pearlman RS. A novel electron-conformational approach to molecular modeling for QSAR by identification of pharmacophore and anti-pharmacophore shielding. SAR and QSAR in Environmental Research. 1999a;10(2&#x2013;3):157&#x2013;173. doi: 10.1080/10629369908039174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10629369908039174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22091549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersuker IB, Bahceci S, Boggs JE, Pearlman RS. An electron-conformational method of identification of pharmacophore and anti-pharmacophore shielding: application to rice blast activity. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design. 1999b;13(4):419&#x2013;434. doi: 10.1023/A:1008052914704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1008052914704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10425606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman L. Random forests. Machine Learning. 2001;45:5&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1023/A:1010933404324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1010933404324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalkha M, Akhazzane M, Moussaid FZ, Daoui O, Nakkabi A, et al. Design, synthesis, molecular docking, 3D-QSAR and ADME-Tox of pyrazole derivatives. New Journal of Chemistry. 2022;46:2747&#x2013;2760. doi: 10.1039/D1NJ05621B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1NJ05621B</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Lin Y, Yan X, Ni H, Chen F, et al. 3D-QSAR studies on the structure&#x2013;bitterness analysis of citrus flavonoids. Food &amp; Function. 2023a;14(10):4921&#x2013;4930. doi: 10.1039/D3FO00601H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3FO00601H</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37158134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XD, Li J, Wang X, Liu R, Liu X, et al. 3D-QSAR, docking and MD of pyrazole derivatives as MALT1 inhibitors. New Journal of Chemistry. 2023b;47:19596&#x2013;19607. doi: 10.1039/D3NJ03490A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3NJ03490A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consonni V, Ballabio D, Todeschini R. Comments on the definition of the Q2 parameter for QSAR validation. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. 2009;49(7):1669&#x2013;1678. doi: 10.1021/ci900115y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci900115y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19527034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer RD, Patterson DE, Bunce JD. Comparative molecular field analysis (CoMFA). 1. Effect of shape on binding of steroids to carrier proteins. Journal of the American Chemical Society. 1988;110(18):5959&#x2013;5967. doi: 10.1021/ja00226a005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja00226a005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22148765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devi RV, Siva Sathya S, Coumar MS. Multi-objective genetic algorithm for de novo drug design (MoGADdrug) Current Computer-Aided Drug Design. 2021;17(3):445&#x2013;457. doi: 10.2174/1573409916666200620194143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1573409916666200620194143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimoglo AS, Vlad PF, Shvets NM, Coltsa MN, G&#xfc;zel Y, et al. Electronic-topological investigations of the relationship between chemical structure and ambergris odor. New Journal of Chemistry. 1995;19(12):1217&#x2013;1226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimoglo AS, Shvets NM, Tetko IV, Livingstone DJ. Electronic-topological investigation of the structure-acetylcholinesterase inhibitor activity relationship in the series of N-benzylpiperidine derivatives. Quantitative Structure-Activity Relationships. 2001;20(1):31&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1002/1521-3838(200105)20:1&lt;31::AID-QSAR31&gt;3.0.CO;2-S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1521-3838(200105)20:1&lt;31::AID-QSAR31&gt;3.0.CO;2-S</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duca JS, Hopfinger AJ. Estimation of molecular similarity based on 4D-QSAR analysis: formalism and validation. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 2001;41(5):1367&#x2013;1387. doi: 10.1021/ci0100090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci0100090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11604039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez M, Caballero J, Fernandez L, Sarai A. Genetic algorithm optimization in drug design QSAR: Bayesian-regularized genetic neural networks (BRGNN) and genetic algorithm-optimized support vector machines (GA-SVM) Molecular Diversity. 2011;15(1):269&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1007/s11030-010-9234-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11030-010-9234-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20306130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox T, Kriegl JM. Machine learning techniques for in silico modeling of drug metabolism. Current Topics in Medicinal Chemistry. 2006;6(15):1579&#x2013;1591. doi: 10.2174/156802606778108915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/156802606778108915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16918470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman JH. Greedy function approximation: A gradient boosting machine. Annals of Statistics. 2001;29(5):1189&#x2013;1232. doi: 10.1214/aos/1013203451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1214/aos/1013203451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillet VJ, Khatib W, Willett P, Fleming PJ, Green DVS. Combinatorial library design using a multiobjective genetic algorithm. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 2002;42(2):375&#x2013;385. doi: 10.1021/ci010375j.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci010375j</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11911707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giuliani A. The application of principal component analysis to drug discovery and biomedical data. Drug Discovery Today. 2017;22(7):1069&#x2013;1076. doi: 10.1016/j.drudis.2017.01.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2017.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28111329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golbraikh A, Tropsha A. Beware of q2! Journal of Molecular Graphics and Modeling. 2002;20(4):269&#x2013;276. doi: 10.1016/S1093-3263(01)00123-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1093-3263(01)00123-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11858635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein H, Poole CP, Safko JL. Classical Mechanics. 3rd ed. Pearson; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gramatica P, Pilutti P, Papa E. Validated QSAR prediction of OH tropospheric degradability of volatile organic compounds: Splitting into training&#x2013;test sets and consensus modeling. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 2004;44(5):1794&#x2013;1802. doi: 10.1021/ci049923u.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci049923u</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15446838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guha R, Jurs PC. Development of linear, ensemble, and nonlinear models for the prediction and interpretation of the biological activity of a set of PDGFR inhibitors. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 2004;44(6):2179&#x2013;2189. doi: 10.1021/ci049849f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci049849f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15554688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanachi R, Ben Said R, Allal H, Rahali S, Alkhalifah MAM, et al. Structural, QSAR, machine learning and molecular docking studies of 5-thiophen-2-yl pyrazole derivatives as potent and selective cannabinoid-1 receptor antagonists. New Journal of Chemistry. 2021;45:17796&#x2013;17807. doi: 10.1039/D1NJ02261J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1NJ02261J</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hehre WJ. Molecular Mechanics &amp; Quantum Calculations. Wavefunction Inc. 2003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herv&#xe1;s C, Silva M, Serrano JM, Orejuela E. Heuristic extraction of rules in pruned artificial neural networks models used for quantifying highly overlapping chromatographic peaks. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 2004;44(5):1576&#x2013;1584. doi: 10.1021/ci049948t.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci049948t</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15446815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong X, Hopfinger AJ. 3D-pharmacophores of flavonoid binding at the benzodiazepine GABA(A) receptor site using 4D-QSAR analysis. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 2003;43(1):324&#x2013;336. doi: 10.1021/ci0200321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci0200321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12546568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karali N, G&#xfc;rsoy A, Kandemirli F, Shvets N, Kaynak FB, et al. Synthesis and structure-antituberculosis activity relationship of 1H-indole-2,3-dione derivatives. Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry. 2007;15(17):5888&#x2013;5904. doi: 10.1016/j.bmc.2007.05.063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmc.2007.05.063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17561405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karrouchi K, Radi S, Ramli Y, Taoufik J, Mabkhot YN, et al. Synthesis and pharmacological activities of pyrazole derivatives: A review. Molecules. 2018;23(1):134. doi: 10.3390/molecules23010134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules23010134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6017056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29329257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Jeong JH. Structure-activity relationship studies based on 3D-QSAR CoMFA/CoMSIA for thieno-pyrimidine derivatives as triple negative breast cancer inhibitors. Molecules. 2022;27(22):7974. doi: 10.3390/molecules27227974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27227974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9698756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36432075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koirala M, Yan L, Mohamed Z, DiPaola M. AI-integrated QSAR modeling for enhanced drug discovery: From classical approaches to deep learning and structural insight. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 2025;26(19):9384. doi: 10.3390/ijms26199384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms26199384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12525248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41096653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krasowski MD, Hong X, Hopfinger AJ, Harrison NL. 4D-QSAR analysis of a set of propofol analogues: Mapping binding sites for an anesthetic phenol on the GABA(A) receptor. Journal of Medicinal Chemistry. 2002;45(15):3210&#x2013;3221. doi: 10.1021/jm010461a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jm010461a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2864546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12109905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Cheng Y, Han C, Song C, Huang N, et al. Pyrazole-containing pharmaceuticals: target, pharmacological activity, and their SAR studies. RSC Medicinal Chemistry. 2022;13:1300&#x2013;1321. doi: 10.1039/D2MD00206J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2MD00206J</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9667768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36439976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Zhao T, Yang Q, Du S, Xu L. A review of quantitative structure-activity relationship: the development and current status of data sets, molecular descriptors and mathematical models. Chemometrics and Intelligent Laboratory Systems. 2025;256:105278. doi: 10.1016/j.chemolab.2024.105278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemolab.2024.105278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang W, Ma S, Zhang Q, Zhu T. Integrative sparse partial least squares. Statistics in Medicine. 2021;40(9):2239&#x2013;2256. doi: 10.1002/sim.8900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.8900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33559203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Librando V, Alparone A. The role of electronic properties to the mutagenic activity of 1,6- and 3,6-dinitrobenzo[a]pyrene isomers. Journal of Hazardous Materials. 2009;161(2&#x2013;3):1338&#x2013;1346. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2008.04.095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2008.04.095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18571843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J, Zou H, Guo Y, Tong T, Ye L, et al. SRC kinase-mediated signaling pathways and targeted therapies in breast cancer. Breast Cancer Research. 2022;24(1):99. doi: 10.1186/s13058-022-01596-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13058-022-01596-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9798727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36581908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maattallaoui I, Sakho M, Maatallaoui A, Catal&#xe1;n EB, El Aouad N. Development of QSAR models and web applications for predicting hDHFR inhibitor bioactivity using machine learning. Molecules. 2025;30(23):4618. doi: 10.3390/molecules30234618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules30234618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12693464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41375213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makkouk AH, Bersuker IB, Boggs JE. Quantitative Drug Activity Prediction for Inhibitors of Human Breast Carcinoma. International Journal of Pharmaceutical Medicine. 2004;18(2):81&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marenich AV, Yong PH, Bersuker IB, Boggs JE. Quantitative antidiabetic activity prediction for the class of guanidino- and aminoguanidinopropionic acid analogs based on electron-conformational studies. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. 2008;48(3):556&#x2013;568. doi: 10.1021/ci700401p.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci700401p</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18278893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins JP, Barbosa EG, Pasqualoto KFM, Ferreira MMC. LQTA-QSAR: A new 4D-QSAR methodology. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. 2009;49(6):1428&#x2013;1436. doi: 10.1021/ci900014f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci900014f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19422246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Melagraki G, Afantitis A, Makridima K, Sarimveis H, Igglessi-Markopoulou O.

Prediction of toxicity using a novel RBF neural network training methodology. 







Journal of Molecular Modeling. 2006;12(3):297&#x2013;305. 
 https://doi:10.1007/s00894-005-0032-8
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00894-005-0032-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16283121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed HHM, Hussien ABWEM, Saeed AEM. QSAR and docking studies of pyrazole analogs as antiproliferative against human colorectal adenocarcinoma cell line HT-29. European Journal of Chemistry. 2022;13(3):319&#x2013;326. doi: 10.5155/eurjchem.13.3.319-326.2259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5155/eurjchem.13.3.319-326.2259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muratov EN, Bajorath J, Sheridan RP, Tetko IV, Filimonov D, et al. QSAR without borders. Chemical Society Reviews. 2020;49(11):3525&#x2013;3564. doi: 10.1039/D0CS00098A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0CS00098A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32356548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niazi SK, Mariam Z. Recent advances in machine-learning-based chemoinformatics: A comprehensive review. International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 2023;24(14):11488. doi: 10.3390/ijms241411488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms241411488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10380192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37511247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noronha G, Barrett K, Boccia A, Brodhag T, Cao J, et al. Discovery of [7-(2,6-dichlorophenyl)-5-methylbenzo[1,2,4]triazin-3-yl]-[4-(2-pyrrolidin-1-ylethoxy)phenyl]amine &#x2014; a potent, orally active Src kinase inhibitor with anti-tumor activity in preclinical assays. Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry Letters. 2007;17(3):602&#x2013;608. doi: 10.1016/j.bmcl.2006.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmcl.2006.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17113292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oprea TI, Waller CL, Marshall GR. Three-dimensional quantitative structure-activity relationship of human immunodeficiency virus (I) protease inhibitors. 2. Predictive power using limited exploration of alternate binding modes. Journal of Medicinal Chemistry. 1994;37(14):2206&#x2013;2215. doi: 10.1021/jm00040a013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jm00040a013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8035428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padmanabhan J, Parthasarathi R, Elango M, Subramanian V, Krishnamoorthy BS, et al. Multiphilic descriptor for chemical reactivity and selectivity. Journal of Physical Chemistry A. 2007;111(37):9130&#x2013;9138. doi: 10.1021/jp0718909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp0718909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17715901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel PK, Bhatt HG. Improved 3D-QSAR prediction by multiple conformational alignments and molecular docking studies to design and discover HIV-1 protease inhibitors. Current HIV Research. 2021;19(2):154&#x2013;171. doi: 10.2174/1570162X18666201119143457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570162X18666201119143457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33213349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlov T, Todorov M, Stoyanova G, Schmieder P, Aladjov H, et al. Conformational coverage by a genetic algorithm: Saturation of conformational space. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. 2007;47(3):851&#x2013;863. doi: 10.1021/ci700014h.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci700014h</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17465523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revard BC, Tipton WW, Hennig RG. Structure and stability prediction of compounds with evolutionary algorithms. Topics in Current Chemistry. 2014;345:181&#x2013;222. doi: 10.1007/128_2013_489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/128_2013_489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24515753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-P&#xe9;rez R, Miljkovi&#x107; F, Bajorath J. Machine learning in chemoinformatics and medicinal chemistry. Annual Review of Biomedical Data Science. 2022;5:43&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1146/annurev-biodatasci-122120-124216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-biodatasci-122120-124216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35440144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romeiro NC, Albuquerque MG, de Alencastro RB, Ravi M, Hopfinger AJ. Construction of 4D-QSAR models for use in the design of novel p38-MAPK inhibitors. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design. 2005;19(6):385&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1007/s10822-005-7927-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10822-005-7927-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16231199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosines E, Bersuker IB, Boggs JE. Pharmacophore Identification and Bioactivity Prediction for Group I Metabotropic Glutamate Receptor Agonists by the Electron-Conformational QSAR Method. Quantitative Structure-Activity Relationships. 2001;20(4):327&#x2013;334. doi: 10.1002/1521-3838(200111)20:4&lt;327::AID-QSAR327&gt;3.0.CO;2-Q.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1521-3838(200111)20:4&lt;327::AID-QSAR327&gt;3.0.CO;2-Q</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ahin K, Saripinar E, Yanmaz E, Ge&#xe7;en N. Quantitative bioactivity prediction and pharmacophore identification for benzotriazine derivatives using the electron conformational-genetic algorithm in QSAR. SAR and QSAR in Environmental Research. 2011;22(3&#x2013;4):217&#x2013;238. doi: 10.1080/1062936X.2010.548341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1062936X.2010.548341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21391137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin K, Saripinar E. A novel hybrid method named electron conformational genetic algorithm as a 4D-QSAR investigation to calculate the biological activity of the tetrahydrodibenzazosines. Journal of Computational Chemistry. 2020;41:1091&#x2013;1104. doi: 10.1002/jcc.26154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.26154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin K, Saripinar E, Durdagi S. Combined 4D-QSAR and target-based approaches for the determination of bioactive Isatin derivatives. SAR and QSAR in Environmental Research. 2021;32(10):769&#x2013;792. doi: 10.1080/1062936X.2021.1971760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1062936X.2021.1971760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34530651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Filho OA, Hopfinger AJ. Structure-based QSAR analysis of a set of 4-hydroxy-5,6-dihydropyrones as inhibitors of HIV-1 protease: an application of the receptor-dependent (RD) 4D-QSAR formalism. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. 2006;46(1):345&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1021/ci050326x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci050326x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16426069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saripinar E, G&#xfc;zel Y, Patat S, Yildirim I, Ak&#xe7;amur Y, et al. Electron-topological investigation of the structure-antitubercular activity relationship of thiosemicarbazone derivatives. Arzneimittel-Forschung/Drug Research. 1996;46(8):824&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9125287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;&#xfc;rmann G, Ebert RU, Chen J, Wang B, K&#xfc;hne R. External validation and prediction employing the predictive squared correlation coefficient &#x2014; test set activity mean vs training set activity mean. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling. 2008;48(11):2140&#x2013;2145. doi: 10.1021/ci800253u.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci800253u</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18954136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidel T, Wieder O, Garon A, Langer T. Applications of the Pharmacophore Concept in Natural Product inspired Drug Design. Molecular Informatics. 2020;39(11):e2000059. doi: 10.1002/minf.202000059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/minf.202000059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32578959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son WJ, Jang S, Shin S. Simulated Q-annealing: Conformational search with an effective potential. Journal of Molecular Modeling. 2012;18(1):213&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1007/s00894-011-1072-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00894-011-1072-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21523533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao ZF, Li G, Tong Y, Stewart KD, Chen Z, et al. Discovery of 4&#x2032;-(1,4-dihydro-indeno[1,2-c]pyrazol-3-yl)-benzonitriles and 4&#x2032;-(1,4-dihydro-indeno[1,2-c]pyrazol-3-yl)-pyridine-2&#x2032;-carbonitriles as potent checkpoint kinase 1 (Chk1 inhibitors. Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry Letters. 2007;17(21):5944&#x2013;5951. doi: 10.1016/j.bmcl.2007.07.102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmcl.2007.07.102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17827013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todeschini R, Consonni V. Handbook of Molecular Descriptors. Weinheim: Wiley-VCH; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokarski JS, Hopfinger AJ. Prediction of ligand-receptor binding thermodynamics by free energy force field (FEFF) 3D-QSAR analysis: application to a set of peptidomimetic renin inhibitors. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 1997;37(4):792&#x2013;811. doi: 10.1021/ci970006g.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci970006g</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9254912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Damme S, Bultinck P. A new computer program for QSAR-analysis: ARTE-QSAR. Journal of Computational Chemistry. 2007;28(11):1924&#x2013;1928. doi: 10.1002/jcc.20664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.20664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17394240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatraman V, Dalby AR, Yang ZR. Evaluation of mutual information and genetic programming for feature selection in QSAR. Journal of Chemical Information and Computer Sciences. 2004;44(5):1686&#x2013;1692. doi: 10.1021/ci049933v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci049933v</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15446827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Yao H, Lin K. An overview of neural networks for drug discovery and the inputs used. Expert Opinion on Drug Discovery. 2018;13(12):1091&#x2013;1102. doi: 10.1080/17460441.2018.1547278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17460441.2018.1547278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30449189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai Y, Yang J, Zhang J, Yang J, Li Q, et al. Src-family protein tyrosine kinases: A promising target for treating cardiovascular diseases. International Journal of Medical Sciences. 2021;18(5):1216&#x2013;1224. doi: 10.7150/ijms.49241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.49241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7847615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33526983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Kilburg D, Eastman P, Pande VS, Gallicchio E. Efficient Gaussian density formulation of volume and surface areas of macromolecules on graphical processing units. Journal of Computational Chemistry. 2017;38(10):740&#x2013;752. doi: 10.1002/jcc.24745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.24745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28160511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>