<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41860927</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on epilepsy detection and recognition based on the combination of time frequency transform and deep learning model.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0336764</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0336764</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0336764</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0336764</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To improve the detection performance of epileptic electroencephalogram (EEG) signals and address their non-stationary characteristics,this paper compares the combined effects of continuous wavelet transform (CWT) and short-time Fourier transform (STFT) with three neural network models-EEGNet,AlexNet,and Shallow ConvNet-and incorporates targeted optimization designs. Specifically,Focal Loss,dynamic data augmentation,and an early stopping mechanism are introduced in the training phase to enhance model robustness. For EEGNet,optimizations are implemented by integrating a Squeeze-and-Excitation (SE) attention module,improving depthwise separable convolution,and dynamically adapting dimensions to reduce classification errors. For Shallow ConvNet,improvements include layered convolution for extracting "time-frequency" features and average pooling to adapt to long-duration data blocks. Experiments are conducted based on subject-independent validation,and the results show that the CWT-based feature extraction method outperforms STFT comprehensively. Among all combinations,the CWT+Shallow ConvNet pair exhibits the optimal overall performance,while the CWT+EEGNet combination follows closely with excellent precision. These findings verify the effectiveness of combining precise time-frequency features (extracted by CWT) with optimized neural network models,providing reliable technical support for clinical epileptic EEG signal detection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Wang et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Canhui</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Information Technology, Yunnan Minzu University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Key Laboratory of Unmanned Autonomous System, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Cyber-Physical Power System of Yunnan Colleges and Universities, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-8630-1833</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Information Technology, Yunnan Minzu University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Key Laboratory of Unmanned Autonomous System, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Cyber-Physical Power System of Yunnan Colleges and Universities, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Haoran</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Tianqi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Information Technology, Yunnan Minzu University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Key Laboratory of Unmanned Autonomous System, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Cyber-Physical Power System of Yunnan Colleges and Universities, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Zongfang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004827" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epilepsy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077321" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deep Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005583" MajorTopicYN="N">Fourier Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058067" MajorTopicYN="N">Wavelet Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012815" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Processing, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41860927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13004368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0336764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-58659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Biswas S, Hairston WD, Metcalfe JS, et al. EEG based BCI for autonomous control: a review. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2025;33(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin N, Gao W, Li L, Chen J, Liang Z, Yuan G, et al. vEpiNet: a multimodal interictal epileptiform discharge detection method based on video and electroencephalogram data. Neural Netw. 2024;175:106319. doi: 10.1016/j.neunet.2024.106319</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neunet.2024.106319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38640698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li Y, Wang H, et al. An autoencoder model based on 1D convolutional neural network for epileptic seizure detection. J South Med Univ. 2024;44(9):1320&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11744082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39505348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Chen J, Liu Z. A review of EEG data analysis technology based on deep learning. J Zhejiang Univ (Eng Sci). 2024;58(5):910&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong T, Liu S, Yu S. MCAN: a cross-domain hybrid self-supervised attention network for intelligent and efficient epileptic detection. Knowl Based Syst. 2025;298:114199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Wu J, Ren Z. CSBrain: a cross-scale spatiotemporal brain foundation model for EEG decoding. NeurIPS. 2025;38:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, et al. A method for epileptic EEG recognition based on semi-supervised deep convolutional channel attention single-class network. Chinese Patent CN114366124B. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei F, Kahane P, Chauvel P. Stereoelectroencephalography (SEEG) in the presurgical evaluation of epilepsy: methodology and results in 500 patients. Neurophysiol Clin. 2011;41(3):179&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppenheim AV, Willsky AS, Nawab SH. Signals and systems. 2nd ed. Upper Saddle River (NJ): Prentice-Hall; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawhern VJ, Solon AJ, Waytowich NR, Gordon SM, Hung CP, Lance BJ. EEGNet: a compact convolutional neural network for EEG-based brain-computer interfaces. J Neural Eng. 2018;15(5):056013. doi: 10.1088/1741-2552/aace8c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2552/aace8c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29932424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schirrmeister RT, Springenberg JT, Fiederer LDJ, Glasstetter M, Eggensperger K, Tangermann M, et al. Deep learning with convolutional neural networks for EEG decoding and visualization. Hum Brain Mapp. 2017;38(11):5391&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1002/hbm.23730</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.23730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5655781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28782865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Haan GJ, van Rijen PC, Majoie CB, et al. Ambulatory EEG and automated seizure detection: impact on pediatric epilepsy management and quality of life. Epilepsia. 2023;64(8):1987&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ech-Choudany Y, Scida D, Assarar M, Landr&#xe9; J, Bellach B, Morain-Nicolier F. Dissimilarity-based time&#x2013;frequency distributions as features for epileptic EEG signal classification. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2021;64:102268. doi: 10.1016/j.bspc.2020.102268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2020.102268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xydeas C, Angelov P, Chiao S-Y, Reoullas M. Advances in classification of EEG signals via evolving fuzzy classifiers and dependant multiple HMMs. Comput Biol Med. 2006;36(10):1064&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2005.09.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2005.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16298357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makumbura RK, Mampitiya L, Rathnayake N, Meddage DPP, Henna S, Dang TL, et al. Advancing water quality assessment and prediction using machine learning models, coupled with explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) techniques like shapley additive explanations (SHAP) for interpreting the black-box nature. Results Eng. 2024;23:102831. doi: 10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102831</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarenko I, Sitnikova E. A novel ANN-based classification of spike-wave activity in 24-hour EEG recordings in rats using spectrograms: Spike-Wave Discharge Artificial Neural Network (SWAN). J Neurosci Methods. 2025;423:110555. doi: 10.1016/j.jneumeth.2025.110555</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneumeth.2025.110555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40818779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarei A, Asl BM. Automatic seizure detection using orthogonal matching pursuit, discrete wavelet transform, and entropy based features of EEG signals. Comput Biol Med. 2021;131:104250. doi: 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33578071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tara K, Wang R, Matsuda Y, Goto S, Mitsudo T, Yamasaki T, et al. EEG-based cerebral pattern analysis for neurological disorder detection via hybrid machine and deep learning approaches. J Neurosci Methods. 2025;423:110551. doi: 10.1016/j.jneumeth.2025.110551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneumeth.2025.110551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40816535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malakouti SM. Enhanced epilepsy detection using discrete wavelet transform and bandpass filtering on EEG data: integration of ART-based and LVQ models. Clin eHealth. 2025;8:134&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1016/j.ceh.2025.07.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceh.2025.07.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C, Liu S, Chen H, Dama&#x161;evi&#x10d;ius R, Al-qaness MAA. Advanced epilepsy detection model using electroencephalography signals based on S-transform and ConvNeXt neural network. Meas. 2025;256(Part E):118517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Liu G, Wu S, Tin C. Phase spectrogram of EEG from S-transform Enhances epileptic seizure detection. Expert Syst Appl. 2025;262:125621. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2024.125621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.125621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulwahhab AH, Abdulaal AH, Thary Al-Ghrairi AH, Mohammed AA, Valizadeh M. Detection of epileptic seizure using EEG signals analysis based on deep learning techniques. Chaos Soliton Fract. 2024;181:114700. doi: 10.1016/j.chaos.2024.114700</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chaos.2024.114700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam T, Basak M, Islam R, Roy AD. Investigating population-specific epilepsy detection from noisy EEG signals using deep-learning models. Heliyon. 2023;9(12):e22208. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e22208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e22208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10730439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38125491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeli H, Ghosh-Dastidar S, Dadmehr N. A wavelet-chaos methodology for analysis of EEGs and EEG subbands to detect seizure and epilepsy. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 2007;54(2):205&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1109/TBME.2006.886855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2006.886855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17278577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiymik MK, G&#xfc;ler I, Dizib&#xfc;y&#xfc;k A, Akin M. Comparison of STFT and wavelet transform methods in determining epileptic seizure activity in EEG signals for real-time application. Comput Biol Med. 2005;35(7):603&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2004.05.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2004.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15809098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akay M. Wavelet transform applications in biomedical engineering. IEEE Eng Med Biol Mag. 1997;16(2):116&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin Q, Hu S, Liu S, Zhao L, Zhang Y-D. An attention-based wavelet convolution neural network for epilepsy EEG classification. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2022;30:957&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1109/TNSRE.2022.3166181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSRE.2022.3166181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35404819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Zhu B, Hu M, Deng Z, Zhang J. Revised tunable Q-factor wavelet transform for EEG-based epileptic seizure detection. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2023;31:1707&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1109/TNSRE.2023.3257306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSRE.2023.3257306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37028382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya UR, Faust O, Kannathal N, Chua KS, Laxminarayan S. Wavelet analysis of electroencephalogram signals. Comput Biol Med. 2008;38(2):187&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioffe S, Szegedy C. Batch normalization: accelerating deep network training. Proceedings of the 32nd International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML); 2015. p. 448&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie T, Tibshirani R, Friedman JH. The elements of statistical learning. New York: Springer; 2009:410&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T-Y, Goyal P, Girshick R, He K, Dollar P. Focal loss for dense object detection. 2017 IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV); 2017. p. 2999&#x2013;3007. doi: 10.1109/iccv.2017.324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iccv.2017.324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin T-Y, Goyal P, Girshick R, He K, Dollar P. Focal loss for dense object detection. IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell. 2020;42(2):318&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2018.2858826</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2018.2858826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30040631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wang X, Li J. Imbalanced epileptic seizure detection via focal loss and multi-scale feature fusion. Comput Biol Med. 2021;134:104568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers DM. Evaluation: from precision, recall and F - measure to ROC, informedness, markedness &amp; correlation. J Mach Learn Technol. 2011;2(1):37&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng H, Wang S, Lv H, Nie C, Feng W, Peng H, et al. Cross-subject seizure detection with vision transformer and unsupervised domain adaptation. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2026;111:108341. doi: 10.1016/j.bspc.2025.108341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2025.108341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X, He L, Li H, Liu Z, Shang W, Zhou W. Deep learning based automatic seizure prediction with EEG time-frequency representation. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2024;95:106447. doi: 10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2024.106447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung YG, Cho A, Kim H, Kim KJ. Single-channel seizure detection with clinical confirmation of seizure locations using CHB-MIT dataset. Front Neurol. 2024;15:1389731. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2024.1389731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2024.1389731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11148866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38836000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimr D, Fujita H, Tomaskova H, Cimler R, Selamat A. Automatic seizure detection by convolutional neural networks with computational complexity analysis. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2023;229:107277. doi: 10.1016/j.cmpb.2022.107277</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2022.107277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36463672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>