<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41459648</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-084X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>eLife</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Elife</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biophysical basis for brain folding and misfolding patterns in ferrets and humans.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">RP107141</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7554/eLife.107141</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A mechanistic understanding of neurodevelopment requires us to follow the multiscale processes that connect molecular genetic processes to macroscopic cerebral cortical formations and thence to neurological function. Using MRI of the brain of the ferret, a model organism for studying cortical morphogenesis, we create in vitro physical gel models and in silico numerical simulations of normal brain gyrification. Using observations of genetically manipulated animal models, we identify cerebral cortical thickness and cortical expansion rate as the primary drivers of dysmorphogenesis and demonstrate that in silico models allow us to examine the causes of aberrations in morphology and developmental processes at various stages of cortical ontogenesis. Finally, we explain analogous cortical malformations in human brains, with comparisons with human phenotypes induced by the same genetic defects, providing a unified perspective on brain morphogenesis that is driven proximally by genetic causes and affected mechanically via variations in the geometry of the brain and differential growth of the cortex.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025, Choi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Gary P T</ForeName><Initials>GPT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5407-9111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chunzi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Sifan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0296-3981</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe9;journ&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Gabrielle</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology, Duke University, Durham, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Richard S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walsh</LastName><ForeName>Christopher A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Genetics and Genomics, Manton Center for Orphan Disease, and Howard Hughes Medical Institute, Chevy Chase, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston Children's Hospital, Boston, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahadevan</LastName><ForeName>L</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5114-0519</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Organismic and Evolutionary Biology, Harvard University, Cambridge, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, Harvard University, Cambridge, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS032457</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R37NS035129</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS140046</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R37 NS035129</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01NS032457</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R00 NS112604</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1764269</GrantID><Agency>Harvard Quantitative Biology Initiative and the NSF-Simons Center for Mathematical and Statistical Analysis of Biology at Harvard</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R00NS112604</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 GM145449</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62587</GrantID><Agency>John Templeton Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01NS140046</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>4053650</GrantID><Agency>CUHK Faculty of Science Direct Grant for Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Elife</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101579614</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-084X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>bioRxiv. 2025 Mar 06:2025.03.05.641682. doi: 10.1101/2025.03.05.641682.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">40093050</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ferrets</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002540" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cerebral Cortex</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>The wrinkled and folded surface of the human brain is both iconic and familiar. These folds allow a large cortical surface area to fit inside the skull and are essential for healthy brain function. The folds form during development when the brain&#x2019;s outer layer &#x2013; the cerebral cortex &#x2013; grows faster than the tissue beneath it, causing the surface to buckle. When this process is disrupted, the brain can develop abnormal folding patterns known as malformations of cortical development. In humans, these conditions are associated with epilepsy, intellectual disability and developmental delay. Studying how such malformations arise is challenging because human brain folding occurs before birth. To address this, researchers use animal models. The ferret is particularly valuable because its brain develops folds similar to those in humans, and many genes linked to human cortical malformations produce comparable folding defects in ferrets. Choi et al. wanted to find out whether the wide range of brain folding abnormalities seen in ferrets and their homologs in humans could be explained by changes in just a few physical properties of the developing brain. Specifically, they tested whether mutations linked to human cortical malformations alter the thickness or growth rate of the cortex. This question is important because different genetic syndromes often result in surprisingly similar brain shapes. By combining brain imaging, computer simulations, and physical gel models of brains that fold when their surfaces absorb solvents and swell (similar to how fingertips swell and wrinkle when wetted for a while), Choi et al. showed that normal brain folding in ferrets can be explained by mechanical forces generated during cortical growth. Both physical experiments with gels and computer simulations of brains with varying cortical thickness or growth rates reproduced folding patterns seen in both healthy and genetically altered ferret brains and their human homologs. Local thinning of the cortex generated many small, tightly packed folds, resembling polymicrogyria, a condition linked to mutations such as those affecting the gene <i>SCN3A</i>, which encodes instructions to form a sodium channel. Reducing overall growth produced smaller, less folded brains similar to microcephaly, which is associated with genes such as <i>ASPM</i>. In contrast, weaker folding with shallow grooves &#x2013; characteristic of lissencephaly &#x2013; emerged when growth was reduced and cortical thickness increased, as seen with disruptions to genes such as <i>TMEM161B</i>. These results suggest that diverse human genetic disorders converge on common physical mechanisms that shape the brain. The work of c provides a unifying framework linking specific genes to brain shape through physical growth processes. The ferret provides a useful model organism with direct implications for human brain development and misfolding. In the future, it could help researchers interpret human brain scans and understand why different genetic disorders lead to similar malformations. However, before such insights can inform clinical practice, the models will need to incorporate additional biological detail and examine how altered folding affects brain function. More broadly, the paper also raises the question of how variations in brain folding patterns arise in non-human brains, which is the subject of a related study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025, Choi et al.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">developmental biology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ferret</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroscience</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>GC, CL, SY, GS, RS, CW, LM No competing interests declared</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41459648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12747519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.107141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">107141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abraham A, Pedregosa F, Eickenberg M, Gervais P, Mueller A, Kossaifi J, Gramfort A, Thirion B, Varoquaux G. Machine learning for neuroimaging with scikit-learn. Frontiers in Neuroinformatics. 2014;8:14. doi: 10.3389/fninf.2014.00014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fninf.2014.00014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3930868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24600388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akula SK, Exposito-Alonso D, Walsh CA. Shaping the brain: The emergence of cortical structure and folding. Developmental Cell. 2023a;58:2836&#x2013;2849. doi: 10.1016/j.devcel.2023.11.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.devcel.2023.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10793202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38113850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akula SK, Marciano JH, Lim Y, Exposito-Alonso D, Hylton NK, Hwang GH, Neil JE, Dominado N, Bunton-Stasyshyn RK, Song JHT, Talukdar M, Schmid A, Teboul L, Mo A, Shin T, Finander B, Beck SG, Yeh RC, Otani A, Qian X, DeGennaro EM, Alkuraya FS, Maddirevula S, Cascino GD, Giannini C, Burrage LC, Rosenfield JA, Ketkar S, Clark GD, Bacino C, Lewis RA, Segal RA, Bazan JF, Smith KA, Golden JA, Cho G, Walsh CA, Adams DR, Aday A, Alejandro ME, Allard P, Ashley EA, Azamian MS, Bacino CA, Baker E, Balasubramanyam A, Barseghyan H, Batzli GF, Beggs AH, Behnam B, Bellen HJ, Bernstein JA, Berry GT, Bican A, Bick DP, Birch CL, Bonner D, Boone BE, Bostwick BL, Briere LC, Brokamp E, Brown DM, Brush M, Burke EA, Burrage LC, Butte MJ, Chen S, Clark GD, Coakley TR, Cobban LA, Cogan JD, Colley HA, Cooper CM, Cope H, Craigen WJ, D&#x2019;Souza P, Davids M, Davidson JM, Dayal JG, Dell&#x2019;Angelica EC, Dhar SU, Dipple KM, Dorrani N, Dorset DC, Douglas J, Douine ED, Draper DD, Dries AM, Eckstein DJ, Emrick LT, Eng CM, Enns GM, Eskin A, Esteves C, Estwick T, Fernandez L, Ferreira C, Fieg EL, Fisher PG, Fogel BL, Friedman ND, Gahl WA, Godfrey RA, Goldman AM, Goldstein DB, Gould SE, Gourdine JPF, Groden CA, Gropman AL, Haendel M, Hamid R, Hanchard NA, High F, Holm IA, Hom J, Howerton EM, Huang Y, Jamal F, Jiang Y, Johnston JM, Jones AL, Karaviti L, Kelley E, Koeller DM, Kohane IS, Kohler JN, Korrick S, Kozuira M, Krasnewich DM, Krier JB, Kyle JE, Lalani SR, Lau CC, Lazar J, LeBlanc K, Lee BH, Lee H, Levy SE, Lewis RA, Loo SK, Loscalzo J, Maas RL, Macnamara EF, MacRae CA, Maduro VV, Majcherska MM, Malicdan MCV, Mamounas LA, Manolio TA, Markello TC, Marom R, Martin MG, Mart&#xed;nez-Agosto JA, Marwaha S, May T, McConkie-Rosell A, McCormack CE, McCray AT, Merker JD, Metz TO, Might M, Mochida G, Moretti PM, Morimoto M, Mulvihill JJ, Murdock DR, Murphy JL, Muzny DM, Nehrebecky ME, Nelson SF, Newberry JS, Newman JH, Nicholas SK, Novacic D, Orange JS, Orengo JP, Pallais JC, Palmer CGS, Papp JC, Parker NH, Pena LDM, Phillips JA, III, Posey JE, Postlethwait JH, Potocki L, Pusey BN, Renteria G, Reuter CM, Rives L, Robertson AK, Rodan LH, Rosenfeld JA, Sampson JB, Samson SL, Schoch K, Scott DA, Shakachite L, Sharma P, Shashi V, Signer R, Silverman EK, Sinsheimer JS, Smith KS, Spillmann RC, Stoler JM, Stong N, Sullivan JA, Sweetser DA, Tan QKG, Tan WH, Tifft CJ, Toro C, Tran AA, Urv TK, Vilain E, Vogel TP, Waggott DM, Wahl CE, Walker M, Walley NM, Wan J, Wangler MF, Ward PA, Waters KM, Webb-Robertson BJM, Westerfield M, Wheeler MT, Wise AL, Wolfe LA, Worthey EA, Yamamoto S, Yang Y, Yang J, Yoon AJ, Yu G, Zastrow DB, Zhao C, Zheng A, Undiagnosed Diseases Network TMEM161B regulates cerebral cortical gyration, Sonic Hedgehog signaling, and ciliary structure in the developing central nervous system. PNAS. 2023b;120:e2209964120. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2209964120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2209964120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9942790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36669111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo FAC, Carvalho LRB, Grinberg LT, Farfel JM, Ferretti REL, Leite REP, Jacob Filho W, Lent R, Herculano-Houzel S. Equal numbers of neuronal and nonneuronal cells make the human brain an isometrically scaled-up primate brain. The Journal of Comparative Neurology. 2009;513:532&#x2013;541. doi: 10.1002/cne.21974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.21974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19226510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayly PV, Okamoto RJ, Xu G, Shi Y, Taber LA. A cortical folding model incorporating stress-dependent growth explains gyral wavelengths and stress patterns in the developing brain. Physical Biology. 2013;10:016005. doi: 10.1088/1478-3975/10/1/016005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1478-3975/10/1/016005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3616769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23357794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonet J, Burton AJ. A simple average nodal pressure tetrahedral element for incompressible and nearly incompressible dynamic explicit applications. Communications in Numerical Methods in Engineering. 1998;14:437&#x2013;449. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1099-0887(199805)14:5&lt;437::AID-CNM162&gt;3.0.CO;2-W.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1099-0887(199805)14:5&lt;437::AID-CNM162&gt;3.0.CO;2-W</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrell V. How cells fold the cerebral cortex. The Journal of Neuroscience. 2018;38:776&#x2013;783. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1106-17.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1106-17.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6596235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29367288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brechb&#xfc;hler C, Gerig G, K&#xfc;bler O. Parametrization of closed surfaces for 3-D shape description. Computer Vision and Image Understanding. 1995;61:154&#x2013;170. doi: 10.1006/cviu.1995.1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/cviu.1995.1013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budday S, Raybaud C, Kuhl E. A mechanical model predicts morphological abnormalities in the developing human brain. Scientific Reports. 2014;4:5644. doi: 10.1038/srep05644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep05644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4090617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25008163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi PT, Lam KC, Lui LM. FLASH: fast landmark aligned spherical harmonic parameterization for genus-0 closed brain surfaces. SIAM Journal on Imaging Sciences. 2015;8:67&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1137/130950008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1137/130950008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi GPT. Ferret-brain-morphogenesis. swh:1:rev:7e7564e7ec4019806bf94238d43ab305cb4ba689Software Heritage. 2025 https://archive.softwareheritage.org/swh:1:dir:26e6f8fade1e5ff9c3e262da2d47932b4a21014f;origin=https://github.com/garyptchoi/ferret-brain-morphogenesis;visit=swh:1:snp:25c72d627b70a9dba94a58272b1a1487ede99174;anchor=swh:1:rev:7e7564e7ec4019806bf94238d43ab305cb4ba689</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del-Valle-Anton L, Borrell V. Folding brains: from development to disease modeling. Physiological Reviews. 2022;102:511&#x2013;550. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00016.2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00016.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desikan RS, Barkovich AJ. Malformations of cortical development. Annals of Neurology. 2016;80:797&#x2013;810. doi: 10.1002/ana.24793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5177533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27862206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ericson C. Real-Time Collision Detection. CRC Press; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fietz SA, Kelava I, Vogt J, Wilsch-Br&#xe4;uninger M, Stenzel D, Fish JL, Corbeil D, Riehn A, Distler W, Nitsch R, Huttner WB. OSVZ progenitors of human and ferret neocortex are epithelial-like and expand by integrin signaling. Nature Neuroscience. 2010;13:690&#x2013;699. doi: 10.1038/nn.2553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.2553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia KE, Wang X, Kroenke CD. A model of tension-induced fiber growth predicts white matter organization during brain folding. Nature Communications. 2021;12:6681. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-26971-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26971-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8602459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34795256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geschwind DH, Rakic P. Cortical evolution: judge the brain by its cover. Neuron. 2013;80:633&#x2013;647. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2013.10.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2013.10.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3922239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24183016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilardi C, Kalebic N. The ferret as a model system for neocortex development and evolution. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology. 2021;9:661759. doi: 10.3389/fcell.2021.661759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.661759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8118648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33996819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen DV, Lui JH, Parker PRL, Kriegstein AR. Neurogenic radial glia in the outer subventricular zone of human neocortex. Nature. 2010;464:554&#x2013;561. doi: 10.1038/nature08845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature08845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20154730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herculano-Houzel S. The human brain in numbers: a linearly scaled-up primate brain. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience. 2009;3:31. doi: 10.3389/neuro.09.031.2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/neuro.09.031.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2776484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19915731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heuer K, Traut N, de Sousa AA, Valk SL, Clavel J, Toro R. Diversity and evolution of cerebellar folding in mammals. eLife. 2023;12:e85907. doi: 10.7554/eLife.85907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.85907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10617990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37737580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>His W. Untersuchungen &#xdc;ber Die Erste Anlage Des Wirbelthierleibes: Die Erste Entwickelung Des H&#xfc;hnchens Im Ei. FCW Vogel; 1868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohlfeld E, Mahadevan L. Unfolding the sulcus. Physical Review Letters. 2011;106:105702. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.106.105702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.106.105702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21469809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton C, Draganski B, Ashburner J, Weiskopf N. A comparison between voxel-based cortical thickness and voxel-based morphometry in normal aging. NeuroImage. 2009;48:371&#x2013;380. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2009.06.043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2009.06.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2741580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19559801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MB, Sun X, Kodani A, Borges-Monroy R, Girskis KM, Ryu SC, Wang PP, Patel K, Gonzalez DM, Woo YM, Yan Z, Liang B, Smith RS, Chatterjee M, Coman D, Papademetris X, Staib LH, Hyder F, Mandeville JB, Grant PE, Im K, Kwak H, Engelhardt JF, Walsh CA, Bae B-I. Aspm knockout ferret reveals an evolutionary mechanism governing cerebral cortical size. Nature. 2018;556:370&#x2013;375. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0035-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-018-0035-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6095461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29643508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalebic N, Gilardi C, Albert M, Namba T, Long KR, Kostic M, Langen B, Huttner WB. Human-specific ARHGAP11B induces hallmarks of neocortical expansion in developing ferret neocortex. eLife. 2018;7:e41241. doi: 10.7554/eLife.41241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.41241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6303107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30484771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenderink JJ, van Doorn AJ. Surface shape and curvature scales. Image and Vision Computing. 1992;10:557&#x2013;564. doi: 10.1016/0262-8856(92)90076-F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0262-8856(92)90076-F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke CD, Bayly PV. How forces fold the cerebral cortex. The Journal of Neuroscience. 2018;38:767&#x2013;775. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1105-17.2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1105-17.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5783962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29367287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui JH, Hansen DV, Kriegstein AR. Development and evolution of the human neocortex. Cell. 2011;146:18&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2011.06.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2011.06.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3610574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21729779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda K, Toda T, Shinmyo Y, Ebisu H, Hoshiba Y, Wakimoto M, Ichikawa Y, Kawasaki H. Pathophysiological analyses of cortical malformation using gyrencephalic mammals. Scientific Reports. 2015;5:15370. doi: 10.1038/srep15370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep15370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4613358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26482531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moln&#xe1;r Z, Clowry GJ, &#x160;estan N, Alzu&#x2019;bi A, Bakken T, Hevner RF, H&#xfc;ppi PS, Kostovi&#x107; I, Rakic P, Anton ES, Edwards D, Garcez P, Hoerder-Suabedissen A, Kriegstein A. New insights into the development of the human cerebral cortex. Journal of Anatomy. 2019;235:432&#x2013;451. doi: 10.1111/joa.13055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joa.13055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6704245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31373394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller C. Spherical Harmonics. Springer; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neal J, Takahashi M, Silva M, Tiao G, Walsh CA, Sheen VL. Insights into the gyrification of developing ferret brain by magnetic resonance imaging. Journal of Anatomy. 2007;210:66&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-7580.2006.00674.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7580.2006.00674.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2100265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NGSolve Team  NetGen. 2019.  [June 22, 2022]. https://ngsolve.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie J, Guo L, Li G, Faraco C, Stephen Miller L, Liu T. A computational model of cerebral cortex folding. Journal of Theoretical Biology. 2010;264:467&#x2013;478. doi: 10.1016/j.jtbi.2010.02.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtbi.2010.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20167224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang JC, Aquino KM, Oldehinkel M, Robinson PA, Fulcher BD, Breakspear M, Fornito A. Geometric constraints on human brain function. Nature. 2023;618:566&#x2013;574. doi: 10.1038/s41586-023-06098-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-023-06098-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10266981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37258669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richman DP, Stewart RM, Hutchinson JW, Caviness VS. Mechanical model of brain convolutional development. Science. 1975;189:18&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1126/science.1135626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1135626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1135626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada K, Watanabe M. Development of cerebral sulci and gyri in ferrets (Mustela putorius) Congenital Anomalies. 2012;52:168&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1111/j.1741-4520.2012.00372.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1741-4520.2012.00372.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22925218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz E, Nenning KH, Heuer K, Jeffery N, Bertrand OC, Toro R, Kasprian G, Prayer D, Langs G. Evolution of cortical geometry and its link to function, behaviour and ecology. Nature Communications. 2023;14:2252. doi: 10.1038/s41467-023-37574-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-37574-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10119184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37080952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinmyo Y, Terashita Y, Dinh Duong TA, Horiike T, Kawasumi M, Hosomichi K, Tajima A, Kawasaki H. Folding of the cerebral cortex requires Cdk5 in upper-layer neurons in gyrencephalic mammals. Cell Reports. 2017;20:2131&#x2013;2143. doi: 10.1016/j.celrep.2017.08.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2017.08.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28854363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RS, Kenny CJ, Ganesh V, Jang A, Borges-Monroy R, Partlow JN, Hill RS, Shin T, Chen AY, Doan RN, Anttonen AK, Ignatius J, Medne L, B&#xf6;nnemann CG, Hecht JL, Salonen O, Barkovich AJ, Poduri A, Wilke M, de Wit MCY, Mancini GMS, Sztriha L, Im K, Amrom D, Andermann E, Paetau R, Lehesjoki AE, Walsh CA, Lehtinen MK. Sodium channel SCN3A (NaV1.3) regulation of human cerebral cortical folding and oral motor development. Neuron. 2018;99:905&#x2013;913. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2018.07.052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2018.07.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6226006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30146301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RS, Walsh CA. Ion channel functions in early brain development. Trends in Neurosciences. 2020;43:103&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1016/j.tins.2019.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tins.2019.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31959360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RS, Florio M, Akula SK, Neil JE, Wang Y, Hill RS, Goldman M, Mullally CD, Reed N, Bello-Espinosa L. Early role for a Na+, K+-ATPase (ATP1A3) in brain development. PNAS. 2021;118:e2023333118. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2023333118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2023333118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8237684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34161264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stomakhin A, Howes R, Schroeder C, Teran JM. Energetically consistent invertible elasticity. Proceedings of the 11th ACM SIGGRAPH/Eurographics conference on Computer Animation; 2012. pp. 25&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabata H, Nakajima K. Efficient in utero gene transfer system to the developing mouse brain using electroporation: visualization of neuronal migration in the developing cortex. Neuroscience. 2001;103:865&#x2013;872. doi: 10.1016/s0306-4522(01)00016-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0306-4522(01)00016-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11301197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallinen T, Biggins JS, Mahadevan L. Surface sulci in squeezed soft solids. Physical Review Letters. 2013;110:024302. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.110.024302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.110.024302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23383906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallinen T, Chung JY, Biggins JS, Mahadevan L. Gyrification from constrained cortical expansion. PNAS. 2014;111:12667&#x2013;12672. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1406015111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1406015111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4156754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25136099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallinen T, Biggins JS. Mechanics of invagination and folding: Hybridized instabilities when one soft tissue grows on another. Physical Review E. 2015;92:022720. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevE.92.022720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.92.022720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26382445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallinen T, Chung JY, Rousseau F, Girard N, Lef&#xe8;vre J, Mahadevan L. On the growth and form of cortical convolutions. Nature Physics. 2016;12:588&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1038/nphys3632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nphys3632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro R, Burnod Y. A morphogenetic model for the development of cortical convolutions. Cerebral Cortex. 2005;15:1900&#x2013;1913. doi: 10.1093/cercor/bhi068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhi068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15758198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro R, Perron M, Pike B, Richer L, Veillette S, Pausova Z, Paus T. Brain size and folding of the human cerebral cortex. Cerebral Cortex. 2008;18:2352&#x2013;2357. doi: 10.1093/cercor/bhm261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhm261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18267953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro R. BrainBox github repository. b45ab79Github. 2017 https://github.com/r03ert0/BrainBox</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro R, Bakker R, Delzescaux T, Evans A, Tiesinga P. FIIND: ferret interactive integrated neurodevelopment atlas. Research Ideas and Outcomes. 2018a;4:e25312. doi: 10.3897/rio.4.e25312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3897/rio.4.e25312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro R, Tiesinga P, Delzescaux T, Evans A. FIIND: ferret interactive integrated neuro development atlas. Neuroanatomie appliqu&#xe9;e et th&#xe9;orique. 2018b https://neuroanatomy.github.io/fiind</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Essen DC. Biomechanical models and mechanisms of cellular morphogenesis and cerebral cortical expansion and folding. Seminars in Cell &amp; Developmental Biology. 2023;140:90&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.semcdb.2022.06.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semcdb.2022.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9942585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35840524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welker W. In: Cerebral Cortex. Jones EG, Peters A, editors. New York, NY: Plenum Press; 1990. Why does the cortex fissure and fold: a review of determinants of gyri and sulci; pp. 3&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4615-3824-0_1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin S, Liu C, Choi GP, Jung Y, Heuer K, Toro R, Mahadevan L. Morphogenesis and morphometry of brain folding patterns across species. eLife. 2025;14:RP107138. doi: 10.7554/eLife.107138.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.107138.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12747518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41459643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>