<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41927828</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study of sand particle motion characteristics and distribution patterns in a helical-blade multiphase pump.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-45521-1</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xuhui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lanzhou Petrochemical University of Vocational Technology, Lanzhou, 730060, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Guangtai</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Fluid and Power Machinery (Xihua University), Ministry of Education, Chengdu, 610039, China. zhangyanping314@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Zonghui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dalian Leo Huaneng Pump Industry Co., Ltd, Dalian, 116049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yanping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Fluid and Power Machinery (Xihua University), Ministry of Education, Chengdu, 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024NSFJQ0012</GrantID><Agency>Sichuan Natural Science Foundation Outstanding Youth Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U23A20669</GrantID><Agency>Key project of Regional Innovation and Development Joint Fund of National Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Distribution characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Momentum analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiphase pump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sand particle motion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41927828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-45521-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-45521-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q. Q. Global oil market development trends and China&#x2019;s oil security strategy research. China Pet. Chem. Stand. Qual. 44(16), 154&#x2013;158 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, X. M. et al. Effect of clearance volume on the internal flow characteristics and output performance of oil-gas multiphase reciprocating pump. Sci. Rep. 14(1), 23580 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. J. et al. Progress and direction of oil and gas exploration in Daqing Oilfield. Daqing Petroleum Geol. Dev. 43(03), 26&#x2013;37 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, G. Chin National Petroleum Corporation Xinjiang Oilfield Company has achieved a major breakthrough in natural gas exploration in the Junggar Basin. Nat. Gas Ind. 39(08), 49 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Editorial Department of the Journal. China&#x2019;s largest integrated heavy oil field&#x2014;Fengcheng ultra-heavy oil reservoir in Xinjiang Karamay Oilfield to undergo large-scale development. Xinjiang Pet. Geol. 32(02), 136 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, Z. K. et al. Influence factors and prediction model of enstrophy dissipation from the tip leakage vortex in a multiphase pump. Sci. Rep. 12(1), 16032 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, J. Q. et al. Numerical simulation of sand-laden heavy oil horizontal separator&#xa0;. Petroleum Mach. 50(03), 57&#x2013;64 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harel, E. et al. Multiphase imaging of gas flow in a nanoporous material using remote-detection NMR. Nat. Mater. 5(4), 321&#x2013;327 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. L. et al. Study of sand particle transport characteristics and different critical velocities in sand-producing wells via indoor experiments. Sci. Rep. (1), 9707 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. L. et al. Analysis of the migration patterns of sand particles below the screw pump in wells based on experiments and numerical simulations. Sci. Rep. (1), 22161 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, L. et al. Dual-modality UDV-PIV system for measurement of solid-liquid flow in sewage facilities. Flow Meas. Instrum. 1&#x2013;11 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajkumar, Y., Shirazi, S. A. &amp; Karimi, S. Effect of pipe size on erosion measurements and predictions in liquid-dominated multiphase flows for the elbows. Wear 1&#x2013;13 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othayq, M. M. et al. Experimental and numerical assessments on solid particle erosion in upward vertical-horizontal and horizontal-vertical downward elbows for multiphase and gas-sand flows. Wear 1&#x2013;17 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinoza-Jara, A. et al. Erosion by turbulence: Discovering the counter-wise vortex events and their effect on wear. Wear 530&#x2013;531, 1&#x2013;12 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, B. C. et al. Liquid/solid flow field in a centrifugal pump with different impeller blade types by PIV. Meas. Control. (7&#x2013;8), 1219&#x2013;1233 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, C. et al. Deposition of solid particles exposed to the suction of dual pumps in the tank of a pumping station. Powder Technol. 727&#x2013;738 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K. et al. Research on the deposition characteristics of integrated prefabricated pumping station. Symmetry-Basel 12(5), 1&#x2013;24 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P., Zhu, X. Y. &amp; Li, Y. Analysis of flow and wear characteristics of solid-liquid two-phase flow in rotating flow channel. Processes 8(11), 1&#x2013;17 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. X. et al. Effect of particle motion on the hydraulic collection of coarse spherical particles. Acta Mech. Sin. 36(1), 72&#x2013;81 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Q. et al. CFD-DEM simulation of backflow blockage of deep-sea multistage pump. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 9(9), 1&#x2013;19 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderon-Hernandez, J. W. et al. Hydraulic convey of iron ore slurry: Pipeline wear and ore particle degradation in function of pumping time. Wear 450&#x2013;451, 1&#x2013;13 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wydrych, J. Comparative analysis of the methods of simulation of flow in boiler dust systems. Chem. Process Eng. 31(4), 603&#x2013;623 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukreev, F. et al. Simulation of adsorption processes on moving particles based on an Euler-Euler description using a lattice Boltzmann discretization. Chem. Eng. Sci. 270, 1&#x2013;11 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarodiya, R. &amp; Gandhi, B. Numerical simulation of a centrifugal slurry pump handling solid-liquid mixture: Effect of solids on flow field and performance. Adv. Powder Technol. 30(10), 2225&#x2013;2239 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, G. J. et al. Solid-liquid two-phase flow and wear analysis in a large-scale centrifugal slurry pump. Eng. Fail. Anal. 114, 1&#x2013;11 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. Y. &amp; Xiao, Y. H. Research of the gas-solid flow character based on the DEM method. J. Therm. Sci. 20(6), 521&#x2013;526 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng, F. et al. Numerical investigation of dust dispersion in a coal roadway with hybrid ventilation system. Powder Technol. 313, 260&#x2013;271 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y., Huang, F. &amp; Kang, S. Mechanism of penetration rate improvement in hot dry rock under the coupling of impact load and confining pressure release. Reserv. Sci. 2(1), 52&#x2013;64 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir, M. U. &amp; Guo, S. Preliminary investigation of fracture behavior during carbon dioxide fracturing of natural hydrogen reservoir with hard-core imperfections. Reserv. Sci. 2(1), 34&#x2013;51 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, N. &amp; Wang, Y. Effect of nanomaterials on improving the apparent viscosity of heavy oil and the environmental evaluation of reservoir environment. Reserv. Sci. 2(1), 1&#x2013;15 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, B., Prajapati, Y. K. &amp; Sheth, P. N. CFD analysis of the downdraft gasifier using species-transport and discrete phase model. Fuel 328, 1&#x2013;15 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. Numerical research on the particle transport and deposition in the impingement-film cooling passage. Phys. Fluids 35(5), 1&#x2013;21 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, W. L. et al. Investigation of particle size impact on dense particulate flows in a vertical pipe. Phys. Fluids 35(7), 1&#x2013;23 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, S. J. &amp; Hu, X. Z. Influence of different particle parameters and operating conditions on flow characteristics and performance of deep-sea mining pump. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 10(3), 1&#x2013;28 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, X. J. et al. Numerical simulation prediction of erosion characteristics in a double-suction centrifugal pump. Processes 9(9), 1&#x2013;16 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, H. et al. Investigation of energy dissipation mechanisms and unsteady flow characteristics of a cooling pump based on sweeping jet inflow. Energy Convers. Manag. 351, 120959 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, H. et al. Role of wall roughness on energy dissipation and vortex dynamics in self-priming centrifugal pump: A study via entropy generation and Liutex vortex identification. Energy https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.138733 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, H. et al. Efficiency optimization of energy storage centrifugal pump by using energy balance equation and non-dominated sorting genetic algorithms-II. J. Energy Storage 114, 115817 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morsi, S. A. &amp; Alexander, A. J. An investigation of particle trajectories in two-phase flow systems. J. Fluid Mech. 55, 193&#x2013;208 (1972).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider, A. &amp; Levenspiel, O. Drag coefficient and terminal velocity of spherical and nonspherical particles. Powder Technol. 58(1), 63&#x2013;70 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Y. et al. Numerical simulation of internal flow in centrifugal pump based on OpenFOAM. J. Basic. Sci. Eng. 20(6), 1048&#x2013;1056 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akimov, S. V. &amp; Borisov, D. V. Centrifugal pump modeling in FlowVision CFD software. Comput. Res. Model. 15(4), 907&#x2013;919 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>