<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41658410</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Engineering the electronic structure towards enhanced performances of CO<sub>2</sub> adsorption and conversion of a Ti-doped MoS<sub>2</sub> monolayer: a DFT study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7447</StartPage><EndPage>7458</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7447-7458</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5ra08046k</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The active site of MoS<sub>2</sub>, predominantly located at the crystalline edge, limits selectivity for the CO<sub>2</sub> reduction reaction (CO<sub>2</sub>RR). Single-Atom Catalysts (SACs), have emerged as a promising avenue to enhance the catalytic performance of MoS<sub>2</sub>, owing to their high catalytic selectivity on the basal plane and tunable activity in various chemical reactions. In this regard, transition metals from the 8B and 1B groups (Cr, Cu, Sc, Ti, V, and Ni) were investigated as dopants on the basal plane for the first time, employing first-principles calculations based on a 4 &#xd7; 4 &#xd7; 1 supercell of the MoS<sub>2</sub> monolayer. The Ti/MoS<sub>2</sub> catalyst was identified as the most stable among the SACs, attributed to its optimal formation energy. Various Ti-doped models were analyzed, encompassing energy band structure, density of states, charge differential density, Bader charge, and Gibbs free energy. Our findings indicate that Ti induces diminished electron binding, thereby weakening C[double bond, length as m-dash]O with lower energy, consequently enhancing the availability of surface sites and facilitating catalytic reactions. In our investigation of possible reaction pathways, the preferred CO<sub>2</sub>RR pathway was identified as the reverse water gas conversion (RWGS), with the rate-limiting step being CO<sub>2</sub> hydrogenation into carboxyl (*COOH). The Ti modification model on the MoS<sub>2</sub> basal surface demonstrated exceptional catalytic performance, reducing the rate-limiting step to 0.177 eV, which is 17 times lower than that of pure MoS<sub>2</sub>. These calculational results provide valuable theoretical insights for designing highly efficient SACs on MoS<sub>2</sub>-based functional materials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Junbo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foshan Power Supply Bureau of Guangdong Power Grid Foshan 528000 China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qiankai</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-6209-1889</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Science and Education Development, Xi'an Jiaotong University 28 Xianning West Road Xi'an 710049 China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foshan Power Supply Bureau of Guangdong Power Grid Foshan 528000 China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foshan Power Supply Bureau of Guangdong Power Grid Foshan 528000 China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5729-7261</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Science and Education Development, Xi'an Jiaotong University 28 Xianning West Road Xi'an 710049 China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Information, Xi'an Polytechnic University 19 Jinhua South Road Xi'an 710048 China wangyang@xpu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Science and Education Development, Xi'an Jiaotong University 28 Xianning West Road Xi'an 710049 China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41658410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12875378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ra08046k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5ra08046k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asadi M. Kumar B. Behranginia A. Rosen B. A. Baskin A. Repnin N. Pisasale D. Phillips P. Zhu W. Haasch R. et al., Robust carbon dioxide reduction on molybdenum disulphide edges. Nat. Commun. 2014;5:4470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25073814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budinis S. Krevor S. Dowell N. M. Brandon N. Hawkes A. An assessment of CCS costs, barriers and potential. Energy Strategy Rev. 2018;22:61&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L. Wang M. Cui Y. Chen Z. Wu J. Cao Y. et al., Surface iron species in palladium-iron intermetallic nanocrystals that promote and stabilize CO2 methanation. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2020;59:14434&#x2013;14442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32259391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y. Liu J. Liu F. Wu D. Reaction mechanism of CO2 methanation over Rh/TiO2 catalyst. Fuel. 2020;276:118093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu M. Tao H. Li Y. Li Y. Ding K. Huang X. et al., Toward improving CO2 dissociation and conversion to methanol via CO-hydrogenation on Cu (100) surface by introducing embedded Co nanoclusters as promoters: a DFT study. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2018;427:837&#x2013;847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z. Y. Ma T. Tao H. C. Fan Q. Han B. X. Fundamentals and challenges of electrochemical CO2 reduction using two-dimensional materials. Chem. 2017;3:560&#x2013;587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhowalla M. Shin H. S. Eda G. Li L. J. Loh K. P. Zhang H. The chemistry of two-dimensional layered transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets. Nat. Chem. 2013;5:263&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23511414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia X. Adriano A. Lazar P. Sofer Z. Luxa J. Pumera M. Layered platinum dichalcogenides (PtS2, PtSe2, and PtTe2) electrocatalysis: monotonic dependence on the chalcogen size. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2016;26:4306&#x2013;4318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H. Tsai C. Koh A. L. Cai L. Contryman A. W. Fragapane A. H. Zhao J. Han H. S. Manoharan H. C. Abild-Pedersen F. Norskov J. K. Zheng X. Activating and optimizing MoS2 basal planes for hydrogen evolution through the formation of strained sulphur vacancies. Nat. Mater. 2016;15:48&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26552057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J. Liang T. X. Tu R. Lai W. S. Liu Y. J. Redistribution of &#x3c0; and &#x3c3; electrons in boron-doped graphene from DFT investigation. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2019;481:344&#x2013;352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu N. Wang L. Li M. Sun X. Hou T. Li Y. Molybdenum disulfide as a highly efficient adsorbent for non-polar gases. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2015;17:11700&#x2013;11704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25865455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao X. Wang L. Xu Y. Li Y. Modulating the MoS2 edge structures by doping transition metals for electrocatalytic CO2 reduction. J. Phys. Chem. C. 2020;124:10523&#x2013;10529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z. Y. Zhou D. A. Xiangke J. Highly selective adsorption on monolayer MoS2 doped with Pt, Ag, Au and Pd and effect of strain engineering: A DFT study. Sens. Actuators, A. 2021;332:113176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J. Q. Li X. Liu W. Sun Y. Ju Z. Yao T. Wang C. Ju H. Zhu J. Wei S. et al., Carbon dioxide electroreduction into syngas boosted by a partially delocalized charge in molybdenum sulfide selenide alloy monolayers. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2017;56:9121&#x2013;9125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28621043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S. Park J. Abroshan H. Zhang L. Kim J. K. Zhang J. M. Guo J. H. Siahrostami S. Zheng X. L. Enhancing catalytic activity of MoS2 basal plane S-vacancy by Co cluster addition. ACS Energy Lett. 2018;3:2685&#x2013;2693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi G. D. Yu L. Ba X. Zhang X. S. Zhou J. Q. Yu Y. Copper nanoparticle interspersed MoS2 nanoflowers with enhanced efficiency for CO2 electrochemical reduction to fuel. Dalton Trans. 2017;46:10569&#x2013;10577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28106214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C. C. Yang W. J. Wang J. Y. Kannaiyan R. Gates I. D. CO2 adsorption and dissociation on single and double iron atomic molybdenum disulfide catalysts: A DFT study. Fuel. 2021;305:121547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Q. Theoretical studies of non-noble metal single-atom catalyst Ni1/MoS2: Electronic structure and electrocatalytic CO2 reduction. Sci. China Mater. 2022;66:1079&#x2013;1088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss B. Wang Q. Butle K. T. et al., Linking in situ charge accumulation to electronic structure in doped SrTiO3 reveals design principles for hydrogen-evolving photocatalysts. Nat. Mater. 2021;20:511&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33432143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaiss V. S. Costa L. T. Theoretical Systematic Investigation as a Strategic Tool for the Design of More Efficient Pure and Doped MoS2 Catalysts for CO2 Electroreduction. Chem. Phys. 2025;591:112597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv K. L. Suo W. Q. Shao M. D. Zhu Y. Wang X. P. Feng J. J. Fang M. W. Zhu Y. Nitrogen doped MoS2 and nitrogen doped carbon dots composite catalyst for electroreduction CO2 to CO with high Faradaic efficiency. Nano Energy. 2019;63:103834.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi P. Asadi M. Liu C. Sharifi-Asl S. Sayahpour B. Behranginia A. Zapol P. Shahbazian-Yassar R. Curtiss L. A. Salehi-Khojin A. Tailoring the edge structure of molybdenum disulfide toward electrocatalytic reduction of carbon dioxide. ACS Nano. 2017;11:453&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27991762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J. W. Jia W. M. Liu C. Lv S. S. Wang J. T. Li Z. C. Static and dynamic evolution of CO adsorption on &#x3b3;-U (1 0 0) surface with different levels of Mo doping using DFT and AIMD calculations. Nucl. Sci. Tech. 2023;34:142&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S. L. Wang X. T. Lei G. Xu H. X. Wang Z. Xiong J. Gu H. S. A DFT study on the outstanding hydrogen storage performance of the Ti-decorated MoS2 monolayer. Surf. Interfaces. 2021;26:101329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y. L. Li X. Wang Y. Li B. W. Yang L. Zhao N. Liu M. F. Wang X. Z. Yu Y. Liu J. M. Reaction mechanisms for reduction of CO2 to CO on monolayer MoS2. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2020;499:143964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Y. P. Bao H. W. Fan W. Li Y. Ma F. The adsorption behaviors of pristine MoS2 and N-MoS2 monolayer: A first-principles calculation. Surf. Interfaces. 2021;27:101580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark S. J. Segall M. D. Pickard C. J. Hasnip P. J. Probert M. J. Refson K. Payne M. C. First principles methods using CASTEP. Z. Kristallogr. 2005;220:567&#x2013;570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdew J. P. Burke K. Ernzerhof M. Generalized gradient approximation made simple. Phys. Rev. Lett. 1996;77:3865&#x2013;3868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10062328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H. Jia P. F. Doping effect of small Rhn (n = 1&#x2013;4) clusters on the geometric and electronic behaviors of MoS2 monolayer: A first-principles study. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2020;526:146659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huelmo C. P. Menezes M. G. Capaz R. B. Denis P. A. Structural and magnetic properties of a defective graphene buffer layer grown on SiC(0001): a DFT study. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2020;22:19963&#x2013;19972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32638763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimme S. Semiempirical GGA-type density functional constructed with a long-range dispersion correction. J. Comput. Chem. 2006;27:1787&#x2013;1799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16955487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. Li J. B. Wu F. M. Li S. S. Xia J. B. Wang L. W. High capacity hydrogen storage in Ca decorated graphyne: A first-principles study. J. Phys. Chem. C. 2011;115:23221&#x2013;23225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freysoldt C. Grabowski B. Hickel T. et al., First-principles calculations for point defects in solids. Rev. Mod. Phys. 2014;86:253&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He C. Z. Wang R. Xiang D. Li X. Y. Fu L. Jian Z. Y. Huo J. R. Li S. Charge-regulated CO2 capture capacity of metal atom embedded graphyne: a first-principles study. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2020;515:145392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan H. P. Du A. J. Shi Q. B. Zhou Y. F. Zhang Y. P. Tang Y. H. Adsorption behavior of CO2 on pristine and doped phosphorenes: A dispersion corrected DFT study. J. CO2 Util. 2018;24:463&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh K. Mridha N. K. Khan A. A. Baildya N. Dutta T. Biswas K. CO2 activation on transition metal decorated graphene quantum dots: An insight from first principles. Phys. E. 2022;135:114993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M. Y. Wang W. Ji M. Cheng X. L. Adsorption of phenol and hydrazine upon pristine and X-decorated (X = Sc, Ti, Cr and Mn) MoS2 monolayer. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2018;439:350&#x2013;363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ataca C. Ciraci S. Functionalization of single-layer MoS2 honeycomb structures. J. Phys. Chem. C. 2011;115:13303&#x2013;13311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi A. Abdelrasoul A. Sardroodi J. J. Adsorption of CO and NO molecules on Al, P and Si embedded MoS2 nanosheets investigated by DFT calculations. Adsorption. 2019;25:1493&#x2013;1506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi A. Sardroodi J. J. Theoretical study of the adsorption of NOx on TiO2/MoS2 nanocomposites: a comparison between undoped and N-doped nanocomposites. J. Nanostruct. Chem. 2016;6:309&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R. Y. Fu D. Ni J. M. Sun C. B. Song S. X. Adsorption for SO2 gas molecules on B, N, P and Al doped MoS2: the DFT study. Chem. Phys. Lett. 2018;712:51&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W. Da H. Liang G. Thermoelectric performance of MX2 (M=Mo, W; X=S, Se) monolayers. J. Appl. Phys. 2013;113:104304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szary M. J. Adsorption of ethylene oxide on doped monolayers of MoS2: A DFT study. Mater. Sci. Eng., B. 2021;272:115341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulliken R. S. Electronic population analysis on LCAO&#x2013;MO molecular wave functions. II. Overlap populations, bond orders, and covalent bond energies. J. Chem. Phys. 1955;23:1841&#x2013;1846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Y. Wang L. Liu H. Song L. Ab initio study of the elastic and mechanical properties of B19TiAl. Crystals. 2017;7:39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M. L. Khan M. Al Asad M. A. Rahaman M. Z. Hasan M. Chowdhury M. Hossain M. K. Modak J. K. Ezzine S. Amami M. Highly efficient and stable lead-free cesium copper halide perovskites for optoelectronic applications: A DFT based study. Heliyon. 2023;9:e18816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10415883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37576266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y. Wang R. Zhu G. Li G. Cao Y. A DFT study on the effect of lattice defects on the electronic structures and floatability of spodumene. Phys. B. 2024;676:415657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barman P. Rahman M. F. Islam M. R. Hasan M. Chowdhury M. Hossain M. K. Modak J. K. Ezzine S. Amami M. Lead-free novel perovskite Ba3AsI3: First-principles insights into its electrical, optical, and mechanical properties. Heliyon. 2023;9:e21675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10661203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38027926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X. Liu W. Duan H. Wang B. Han C. Wei D. The adsorption mechanism of calcium ion on quartz (101) surface: A DFT study. Powder Technol. 2018;329:158&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W. W. Xue Y. S. Luo X. M. Xu Y. A rare three-dimensional POM-based inorganic metal polymer bonded by CO2 with high catalytic performance for CO2 cycloaddition. Chem. Commun. 2018;54:1185&#x2013;1188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30288506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y. Xie Y. Zhou J. Li Y. Yu Y. Ren Z. Robust and Selective Electrochemical Reduction of CO2: The Case of Integrated 3D TiO2@MoS2 Architectures and Ti&#x2013;S Bonding Effects. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2018;6:4706&#x2013;4713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishnan J. Biswas K. Facile Synthesis of Ti Doped MoS2 and Its Superior Adsorption Properties. Mater. Lett. 2020;280:128522.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>