<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41699005</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Data-driven combination of METAR observations and CAMS reanalysis aerosols to enhance satellite retrieval of surface solar irradiance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6716</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6716</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6716</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39971-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate solar irradiance forecasts are vital for photovoltaic (PV) power prediction, especially in tropical and subtropical regions affected by dust, wildfire smoke, and pollution. Yet, aerosol detection from satellites is often obstructed by clouds, AErosol RObotic NETwork (AERONET) stations are sparsely distributed, and climatological datasets cannot capture intra-day variability. Global products such as the Copernicus Atmosphere Monitoring Service (CAMS) provide broad coverage but miss local events due to coarse resolution and uncertainties in the underlying emission database. In this study, atmospheric parameters from automated METeorological aerodrome report (METAR) observations and CAMS aerosol products are used as inputs to data-driven models trained on normalized pseudo global horizontal clear sky irradiance ([Formula: see text]) targets from one site. Models tested include gradient boosting methods, Random Forests, neural networks, and a quantum variational circuit. Results have been obtained using only openly available data from seven test sites with significant aerosol loads, for the period spanning 2015&#x2013;2024. The predicted global horizontal clear sky irradiance ([Formula: see text]) is then used in the Heliosat-3 method, which uses satellite-derived cloud index (CI) to estimate the all-sky global horizontal irradiance (GHI), for benchmarking against the all-sky GHI output of Heliosat-3 coupled with [Formula: see text] from the physics-based McClear model. Categorical boosting (CatBoost) shows the highest positive root mean squared error (RMSE) skill score (SS) of 4.2% over the entire test dataset, compared to the reference McClear. A consistent positive RMSE SS from 1&#x2013;5% is observed for the 6&#x2013;8&#xa0;km visibility range for all models. During dust and sand events, the Light Gradient-Boosting Machine (LightGBM) shows a 21% positive RMSE SS. These findings demonstrate the value of [Formula: see text] based machine learning approach for improving solar irradiance estimates in aerosol-rich environments.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Arindam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Aerospace Center (DLR), Institute of Networked Energy Systems, Energy System Analysis, Oldenburg, Germany. arindam.roy@uni-oldenburg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heinemann</LastName><ForeName>Detlev</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Oldenburg, Institute of Physics, Oldenburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schroedter-Homscheidt</LastName><ForeName>Marion</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Aerospace Center (DLR), Institute of Networked Energy Systems, Energy System Analysis, Oldenburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lezaca Galeano</LastName><ForeName>Jorge Enrique</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Aerospace Center (DLR), Institute of Networked Energy Systems, Energy System Analysis, Oldenburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerosol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CAMS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Classical and quantum learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">METAR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">McClear</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Satellite-estimated solar irradiance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41699005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12914021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39971-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39971-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Al-Dahidi, S., Ayadi, O., Alrbai, M. &amp; Adeeb, J. Ensemble approach of optimized artificial neural networks for solar photovoltaic power prediction. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>7</b>, 81741&#x2013;81758 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2923905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodayar, M., Mohammadi, S., Khodayar, M. E., Wang, J. &amp; Liu, G. Convolutional graph Autoencoder: A generative deep neural network for probabilistic spatio-temporal solar irradiance forecasting. <i>IEEE Trans. Sustain. Energy</i><b>11</b>, 571&#x2013;583 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSTE.2019.2897688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najdawi, F. Z. &amp; Villarreal, R. Utilizing the Vector autoregression model (VAR) for short-term solar irradiance forecasting. <i>EPE</i><b>15</b>, 353&#x2013;362 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/epe.2023.1511020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edoli, E., Fiorenzani, S. &amp; Vargiolu, T. <i>Optimization Methods for Gas and Power Markets</i> (Palgrave Macmillan, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunlop, E. D., Wald, L. &amp; Suri, M. <i>Solar Energy Resource Management for Electricity Generation from Local Level to Global Scale</i> (Nova Science Publishers Inc, 2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamasoe, M. A., do Ros&#xe1;rio, N. M. E. &amp; Barros, K. M. Downward solar global irradiance at the surface in S&#xe3;o Paulo city&#x2014;The climatological effects of aerosol and clouds. <i>JGR Atmos.</i><b>122</b>, 391&#x2013;404 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2016JD025585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmopoulos, P. G. et al. Dust impact on surface solar irradiance assessed with model simulations, satellite observations and ground-based measurements. <i>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</i><b>10</b>, 2435&#x2013;2453 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/amt-10-2435-2017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schafer, J. S. et al. Observed reductions of total solar irradiance by biomass-burning aerosols in the Brazilian Amazon and Zambian Savanna. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>29</b>, 1&#x2013;4 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2001GL014309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa, R. S., Martins, F. R. &amp; Pereira, E. B. Atmospheric aerosol influence on the Brazilian solar energy assessment: Experiments with different horizontal visibility bases in radiative transfer model. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>90</b>, 120&#x2013;135 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2015.12.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husar, R. B., Husar, J. D. &amp; Martin, L. Distribution of continental surface aerosol extinction based on visual range data. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>34</b>, 5067&#x2013;5078 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1352-2310(00)00324-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tantiwechwuttikul, R., Yarime, M. &amp; Ito, K. <i>Technologies and Eco-innovation towards Sustainability II</i> (Springer, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermann, M. et al<i>.</i> Meridional distributions of aerosol particle number concentrations in the upper troposphere and lower stratosphere obtained by civil aircraft for regular investigation of the atmosphere based on an instrument container (CARIBIC) flights. <i>J. Geophys. Res.</i><b>108</b> (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, X. et al. Worldwide performance assessment of 95 direct and diffuse clear-sky irradiance models using principal component analysis. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>135</b>, 110087 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2020.110087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamath, H. G. &amp; Srinivasan, J. Validation of global irradiance derived from INSAT-3D over India. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>202</b>, 45&#x2013;54 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2020.03.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gueymard, C. A., Habte, A. &amp; Sengupta, M. Reducing uncertainties in large-scale solar resource data: The impact of aerosols. <i>IEEE J. Photovolt.</i><b>8</b>, 1732&#x2013;1737 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPHOTOV.2018.2869554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foyo-Moreno, I. et al. Estimating aerosol characteristics from solar irradiance measurements at an urban location in southeastern Spain. <i>JGR Atmos.</i><b>119</b>, 1845&#x2013;1859 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2013JD020599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houborg, R., Soegaard, H., Emmerich, W. &amp; Moran, S. Inferences of all-sky solar irradiance using Terra and Aqua MODIS satellite data. <i>Int. J. Remote Sens.</i><b>28</b>, 4509&#x2013;4535 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431160701241902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remund, J., Wald, L., Lef&#xe8;vre, M., Ranchin, T. &amp; Page, J. H. <i>Proceedings of ISES Solar World Congress 2003</i> pp. 13 (International Solar Energy Society (ISES), 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, M., Levy, R. C., Remer, L. A., Mattoo, S. &amp; Gupta, P. Parameterizing spectral surface reflectance relationships for the dark target aerosol algorithm applied to a geostationary imager. <i>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</i><b>17</b>, 1913&#x2013;1939 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/amt-17-1913-2024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutgens, N. A. J. Site representativity of AERONET and GAW remotely sensed aerosol optical thickness and absorbing aerosol optical thickness observations. <i>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</i><b>20</b>, 7473&#x2013;7488 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/acp-20-7473-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, K.-H., Yoo, J.-M. &amp; Wong, M.-S. in <i>2020 IEEE International Geoscience &amp; Remote Sensing Symposium</i> pp. 5600&#x2013;5603. (IEEE, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lef&#xe8;vre, M. et al. McClear: a new model estimating downwelling solar radiation at ground level in clear-sky conditions. <i>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</i><b>6</b>, 2403&#x2013;2418 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/amt-6-2403-2013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gueymard, C. A. &amp; Yang, D. Worldwide validation of CAMS and MERRA-2 reanalysis aerosol optical depth products using 15 years of AERONET observations. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>225</b>, 117216 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2019.117216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaza, A., Kay, M., Evans, J. P., Bremner, S. &amp; Prasad, A. Validation of Australian atmospheric aerosols from reanalysis data and CMIP6 simulations. <i>Atmos. Res.</i><b>264</b>, 105856 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosres.2021.105856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari, K. &amp; Ramachandran, S. Optical and physical characteristics of aerosols over Asia: AERONET, MERRA-2 and CAMS. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>326</b>, 120470 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2024.120470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witthuhn, J., H&#xfc;nerbein, A. &amp; Deneke, H. Evaluation of satellite-based aerosol datasets and the CAMS reanalysis over ocean utilizing shipborne reference observations. <i>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</i><b>13</b>, 1387&#x2013;1412 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/amt-13-1387-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfa;nior, A. L. P. et al. Evaluation of aerosol optical depth (Aod) estimated by copernicus atmosphere monitoring service (Cams) in Brazil. <i>Theor. Appl. Climatol.</i><b>156</b>, 116 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00704-024-05335-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuna Tuygun, G. &amp; Elbir, T. Comparative analysis of CAMS aerosol optical depth data and AERONET observations in the Eastern Mediterranean over 19 years. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i><b>31</b>, 27069&#x2013;27084 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-024-32950-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11052789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38503950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koschmieder, H. Theorie der horizontalen sichtweite, Beitrage zur Physik der Freien Atmosphare. <i>Meteorol. Z.</i><b>12</b>, 3353 (1924).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath, H. On the applicability of the koschmieder visibility formula. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>1967</b>(5), 177&#x2013;184 (1971).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0004-6981(71)90081-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkaynak, H., Schatz, A. D., Thurston, G. D., Isaacs, R. G. &amp; Husar, R. B. Relationships between aerosol extinction coefficients derived from airport visual range observations and alternative measures of airborne particle mass. <i>J. Air Pollut. Control Assoc.</i><b>35</b>, 1176&#x2013;1185 (1985).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00022470.1985.10466020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedlander, S. K. <i>Smoke, Dust and Haze</i> (Oxford University Press, 2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson, J. T. &amp; Fee, C. J. Visibility-atmospheric turbidity dependence at Raleigh, North Carolina. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>1967</b>(15), 2561&#x2013;2563 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0004-6981(81)90072-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elterman, L. Relationships between vertical attenuation and surface meteorological range. <i>Appl. Opt.</i><b>9</b>, 1804&#x2013;1810 (1970).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1364/AO.9.001804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20094141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S., Wu, J., Fan, W., Yang, Q. &amp; Zhao, D. Review of aerosol optical depth retrieval using visibility data. <i>Earth-Sci. Rev.</i><b>200</b>, 102986 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2019.102986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, J. &amp; Lin, Y. A parameterization model of aerosol optical depths in China. <i>Acta Meteorol. Sin.</i><b>59</b>, 368&#x2013;372 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J. et al. Improvement of aerosol optical depth retrieval using visibility data in China during the past 50 years. <i>JGR Atmos.</i><b>119</b>, 13&#x2013;370 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. Aerosol optical depth retrieval from visibility in China during 1973&#x2013;2014. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>171</b>, 38&#x2013;48 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2017.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, F. et al. An improved method for retrieving aerosol optical depth using the ground-level meteorological data over the South-central Plain of Hebei Province, China. <i>Atmos. Pollut. Res.</i><b>13</b>, 101334 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apr.2022.101334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J. et al. Using particle swarm optimization to improve visibility-aerosol optical depth retrieval method. <i>NPJ Clim. Atmos. Sci.</i><b>4</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41612-021-00207-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Meteorological Organization. Manual on Codes: International Codes Volume I.1, Annex II to the WMO Technical Regulations, Part A &#x2010; Alphanumeric Codes. Technical Manual. World Meteorological Organization, 2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Civil Aviation Organization. Annex 3 to the Convention on International Civil Aviation: Meteorological Service for International Air Navigation. Standard. International Civil Aviation Organization, (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, H., Wang, K., Zhao, C., Wu, G. &amp; Li, J. Visibility-derived aerosol optical depth over global land from 1959 to 2021. <i>Earth Syst. Sci. Data</i><b>16</b>, 3233&#x2013;3260 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-16-3233-2024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar, K. et al. Solar radiometer sensing of multi-year aerosol features over a tropical urban station: direct-Sun and inversion products. <i>Atmos. Meas. Tech.</i><b>13</b>, 5569&#x2013;5593 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/amt-13-5569-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ineichen, P. &amp; Perez, R. Aerosol quantification based on global irradiance. <i>Solar Paces 2010 proceedings</i> (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sequeira, R. &amp; Lai, K.-H. The effect of meteorological parameters and aerosol constituents on visibility in urban Hong Kong. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>32</b>, 2865&#x2013;2871 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1352-2310(97)00494-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, C.-C. &amp; Yeh, H.-H. Comparative influences of airborne pollutants and meteorological parameters on atmospheric visibility and turbidity. <i>Atmos. Res.</i><b>96</b>, 496&#x2013;509 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosres.2009.12.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, Y. et al. Improved method of visibility parameterization focusing on high humidity and aerosol concentrations during fog&#x2013;haze events: Application in the GRAPES_CAUCE model in Jing-Jin-Ji, China. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>222</b>, 117139 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2019.117139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goudie, A. S. &amp; Middleton, N. J. The changing frequency of dust storms through time. <i>Clim. Change</i><b>20</b>, 197&#x2013;225 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00139839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahowald, N. M., Ballantine, J. A., Feddema, J. &amp; Ramankutty, N. Global trends in visibility: implications for dust sources. <i>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</i><b>7</b>, 3309&#x2013;3339 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/acp-7-3309-2007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavartkiladze, K. A. &amp; Amiranashvili, A. G. <i>Nucleation and Atmospheric Aerosols</i> (Springer, 2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, R. T., Milton, E. J. &amp; Nield, J. M. Are visibility-derived AOT estimates suitable for parameterizing satellite data atmospheric correction algorithms?. <i>Int. J. Remote Sens.</i><b>36</b>, 1675&#x2013;1688 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2015.1023558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbois, H., Rusydi, A. &amp; Thiery, A. Probabilistic forecasting of day-ahead solar irradiance using quantile gradient boosting. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>173</b>, 313&#x2013;327 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2018.07.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi, S. O., Haimberger, L., Abbasi, R. &amp; Samimi, C. Prediction of aerosol optical depth in West Asia using deterministic models and machine learning algorithms. <i>Aeolian Res.</i><b>35</b>, 69&#x2013;84 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aeolia.2018.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmopoulos, P. <i>Planning and Management of Solar Power from Space</i> (Academic Press, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neher, I., Buchmann, T., Crewell, S., Pospichal, B. &amp; Meilinger, S. Impact of atmospheric aerosols on solar power. <i>Meteorol. Z.</i><b>28</b>, 305&#x2013;321 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1127/metz/2019/0969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bent&#xe9;jac, C., Cs&#xf6;rg&#x151;, A. &amp; Mart&#xed;nez-Mu&#xf1;oz, G. A comparative analysis of gradient boosting algorithms. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>54</b>, 1937&#x2013;1967 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-020-09896-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Mucs, D., Norinder, U. &amp; Svensson, F. LightGBM: An effective and scalable algorithm for prediction of chemical toxicity-application to the Tox21 and mutagenicity data sets. <i>J. Chem. Inf. Model.</i><b>59</b>, 4150&#x2013;4158 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.9b00633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31560206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock, J. T. &amp; Khoshgoftaar, T. M. CatBoost for big data: an interdisciplinary review. <i>J. Big Data</i><b>7</b>, 94 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-020-00369-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33169094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geurts, P., Ernst, D. &amp; Wehenkel, L. Extremely randomized trees. <i>Mach. Learn.</i><b>63</b>, 3&#x2013;42 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10994-006-6226-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Car, Z., Baressi &#x160;egota, S., An&#x111;eli&#x107;, N., Lorencin, I. &amp; Mrzljak, V. Modeling the spread of COVID-19 infection using a multilayer perceptron. <i>Comput. Math. Methods Med.</i><b>2020</b>, 5714714 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/5714714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32565882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti, M., Lloyd, E., Sack, S. &amp; Fiorentini, M. Parameterized quantum circuits as machine learning models. <i>Quantum Sci. Technol.</i><b>4</b>, 43001 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2058-9565/ab4eb5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuld, M., Sinayskiy, I. &amp; Petruccione, F. An introduction to quantum machine learning. <i>Contemp. Phys.</i><b>56</b>, 172&#x2013;185 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00107514.2014.964942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanc, P., Jolivet, R., M&#xe9;nard, L. &amp; Saint-Drenan, Y.-M. Data sharing of in-situ measurements following GEO and FAIR principles in the solar energy sector. <i>Centre O.I.E. MINES Paris, Working document</i> (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driemel, A. et al. Baseline surface radiation network (BSRN): structure and data description (1992&#x2013;2017). <i>Earth Syst. Sci. Data</i><b>10</b>, 1491&#x2013;1501 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-10-1491-2018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolivet, R. &amp; Saint-Drenan, Y. M. <i>libinsitu: A library to transform solar in situ data into a standard NetCDF format</i>https://git.sophia.minesparis.psl.eu/oie/libinsitu. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El&#x2010;Metwally, M., Alfaro, S. C., Abdel Wahab, M. &amp; Chatenet, B. Aerosol characteristics over urban Cairo: Seasonal variations as retrieved from Sun photometer measurements. <i>JGR Atmospheres</i><b>113</b> (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Askary, H. &amp; Kafatos, M. Dust storm and black cloud influence on aerosol optical properties over Cairo and the Greater Delta region, Egypt. <i>Int. J. Remote Sens.</i><b>29</b>, 7199&#x2013;7211 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431160802144179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christodoulou, A. et al. <i>Submicron Aerosol Pollution in Greater Cairo (Egypt): A New Type of Urban Haze?</i> (Copernicus GmbH, 2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38626495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalchandani, V. et al. Effect of biomass burning on PM 2.5 composition and secondary aerosol formation during post-monsoon and winter haze episodes in Delhi. <i>JGR Atmosph.</i><b>127</b>, e2021JD035232 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2021JD035232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhowmik, H. S. et al. Contribution of fossil and biomass-derived secondary organic carbon to winter water-soluble organic aerosols in Delhi. <i>India. Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>912</b>, 168655 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.168655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37992837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, S., Sharma, S. K., Vijayan, N. &amp; Mandal, T. K. Seasonal characteristics of aerosols (PM2.5 and PM10) and their source apportionment using PMF: A four year study over Delhi India. <i>Environ. Pollut. (Barking, Essex: 1987)</i><b>262</b>, 114337 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2020.114337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32193082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, M., Kaskaoutis, D. G., Singh, R. P. &amp; Singh, S. Seasonal variability of atmospheric aerosol parameters over greater noida using ground sunphotometer observations. <i>Aerosol. Air Qual. Res.</i><b>14</b>, 608&#x2013;622 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4209/aaqr.2013.06.0219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, L. &amp; Liu, X. Seasonal variation of atmospheric aerosol and its relation to cloud faction over Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. <i>Chin. Res. Environ. Sci</i><b>22</b>, 924&#x2013;931 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B. G., Ran, Y. &amp; Tao, S. Seasonal variation and spatial distribution of atmospheric aerosols in Beijing. <i>Acta Sci. Circumstant.</i><b>28</b>, 1425&#x2013;1429 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takegawa, N. et al. Seasonal and diurnal variations of submicron organic aerosol in Tokyo observed using the Aerodyne aerosol mass spectrometer. <i>JGR Atmospheres</i><b>111</b> (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iijima, A. et al. Regional and seasonal characteristics of emission sources of fine airborne particulate matter collected in the center and suburbs of Tokyo, Japan as determined by multielement analysis and source receptor models. <i>J. Environ. Monit.</i><b>10</b>, 1025&#x2013;1032 (2008).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/b806483k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18728894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan, N.-T. &amp; Dinh-Tri, C. Assessment of air pollutant emissions from rice straw open burning in Hoa Vang district, Da Nang city, Vietnam. <i>UD-JST,</i> 25&#x2013;32 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham, T. T. K., Le, S. H., Nguyen, T., Balasubramanian, R. &amp; Tran, P. T. M. Characteristics of airborne particles in stone quarrying areas: Human exposure assessment and mitigation. <i>Environ. Res.</i><b>245</b>, 118087 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2023.118087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38159664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins, G. S. &amp; Gueye, M. WRF 1960&#x2013;2014 winter season simulations of particulate matter in the sahel: implications for air quality and respiratory health. <i>GeoHealth</i><b>2</b>, 248&#x2013;260 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2018GH000132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7007090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marif, Y. et al. Estimation of atmospheric turbidity over Adrar city in Algeria. <i>J. King Saud Univ. Sci.</i><b>31</b>, 143&#x2013;149 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2017.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djafer, D. &amp; Irbah, A. Estimation of atmospheric turbidity over Gharda&#xef;a city. <i>Atmos. Res.</i><b>128</b>, 76&#x2013;84 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosres.2013.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, Z., Djelloul, D. &amp; Fatima, C. Classification of aerosol types over Ghardaia, Algeria, based on MODIS data. <i>IJESD</i><b>7</b>, 745 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18178/ijesd.2016.7.10.873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howlett-Downing, C., Boman, J., Moln&#xe1;r, P., Shirinde, J. &amp; Wichmann, J. PM2.5 chemical composition and geographical origin of air masses in Pretoria, South Africa. <i>Water Air Soil Pollut.</i><b>233</b>, 271 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11270-022-05746-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesina, A. J., Kumar, K. R., Sivakumar, V. &amp; Griffith, D. Direct radiative forcing of urban aerosols over Pretoria (25.75&#xb0;S, 28.28&#xb0;E) using AERONET Sunphotometer data: first scientific results and environmental impact. <i>J. Environ. Sci.</i><b>26</b>, 2459&#x2013;2474 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jes.2014.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25499494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeifroth, U. et al.<i> Surface Radiation Data Set - Heliosat (SARAH) - Edition 3</i> (Satellite Application Facility on Climate Monitoring (CM SAF), 2023), https://wui.cmsaf.eu/safira/action/viewDetails?acronym=SARAH_V003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer, A. et al. Solar energy assessment using remote sensing technologies. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>86</b>, 423&#x2013;432 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0034-4257(03)00083-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cano, D. et al. A method for the determination of the global solar radiation from meteorological satellite data. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>37</b>, 31&#x2013;39 (1986).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0038-092X(86)90104-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigollier, C., Lef&#xe8;vre, M. &amp; Wald, L. The method Heliosat-2 for deriving shortwave solar radiation from satellite images. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>77</b>, 159&#x2013;169 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2004.04.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betcke, J. et al. Energy-specific solar radiation data from meteosat second generation (MSG): The Heliosat-3 Project. Final Report, (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer, A., K&#xfc;hnert, J., Weinreich, K. &amp; Lorenz, E. Short-term forecasting of surface solar irradiance based on meteosat-SEVIRI data using a nighttime cloud index. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>7</b>, 9070&#x2013;9090 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs70709070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solar API and Weather Forecasting Tool | Solcast&#x2122;. https://solcast.com/ (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bright, J. M. Solcast: Validation of a satellite-derived solar irradiance dataset. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>189</b>, 435&#x2013;449 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2019.07.086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bright, J. M., Killinger, S., Lingfors, D. &amp; Engerer, N. A. Integration of distributed solar forecasting with distribution network operations in Australia. <i>ISES Sol. World Congr. 2015, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, Oct. 29-Novemb. 2</i> (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ECMWF. CAMS solar radiation time-series: data documentation. Copernicus Knowledge Base - ECMWF Confluence Wiki. https://confluence.ecmwf.int/display/CKB/CAMS+solar+radiation+time-series%3A+data+documentation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inness, A. et al. The CAMS reanalysis of atmospheric composition. <i>Atmos. Chem. Phys.</i><b>19</b>, 3515&#x2013;3556 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/acp-19-3515-2019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ICAO. Annex 3 to the Convention on International Civil Aviation&#x2014;Meteorological Service for International Air Navigation (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzmann, D., Arritt, R. &amp; Todey, D. Iowa environmental mesonet. <i>mesonet. agron. iastate. edu/request/coop/fe. phtml (verified 27 Sept. 2005). Iowa State Univ., Dep. of Agron., Ames, IA</i> (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, P. W. A test of visibility sensors at Hong Kong international airport. <i>Weather</i><b>71</b>, 241&#x2013;246 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wea.2772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilbao, J., Rom&#xe1;n, R., Yousif, C., Mateos, D. &amp; de Miguel, A. Total ozone column, water vapour and aerosol effects on erythemal and global solar irradiance in Marsaxlokk. <i>Malta. Atmos. Environ.</i><b>99</b>, 508&#x2013;518 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2014.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bright, J. M. et al. Bright-Sun: A globally applicable 1-min irradiance clear-sky detection model. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>121</b>, 109706 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2020.109706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alia-Martinez, M., Antonanzas, J., Urraca, R., Martinez-de-Pison, F. J. &amp; Antonanzas-Torres, F. Benchmark of algorithms for solar clear-sky detection. <i>J. Renew. Sustain. Energy</i><b>8</b> (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis, B. H., Deceglie, M. &amp; Jain, A. Automatic detection of clear-sky periods from irradiance data. <i>IEEE J. Photovolt.</i><b>9</b>, 998&#x2013;1005 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPHOTOV.2019.2914444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, A. et al. Parallax and cloud shadow correction in satellite-based solar irradiance estimation: A study in tropical environments. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>399</b>, 126457 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelenka, A., Perez, R., Seals, R. &amp; Renn&#xe9;, D. Effective accuracy of satellite-derived hourly irradiances. <i>Theor. Appl. Climatol.</i><b>62</b>, 199&#x2013;207 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s007040050084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. &amp; Guestrin, C. <i>Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</i> pp. 785&#x2013;794. (Association for Computing Machinery, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y., Ke, G., Chen, Z., Zheng, S. &amp; Liu, T.-Y. <i>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</i> (Curran Associates Inc, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prokhorenkova, L., Gusev, G., Vorobev, A., Dorogush, A. V. &amp; Gulin, A. CatBoost: unbiased boosting with categorical features. <i>Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst.</i><b>31</b> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin, E. K. Comparative analysis of gradient boosting algorithms for landslide susceptibility mapping. <i>Geocarto Int.</i><b>37</b>, 2441&#x2013;2465 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10106049.2020.1831623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scornet, E. Random forests and kernel methods. <i>IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory</i><b>62</b>, 1485&#x2013;1500 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIT.2016.2514489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehenkel, L., Ernst, D. &amp; Geurts, P. <i>Robust methods for power system state estimation and load forecasting</i> (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paszke, A. <i>et al.</i> PyTorch: An Imperative style, high-performance deep learning library. <i>Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst.</i><b>32</b> (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovalle-Magallanes, E., Alvarado-Carrillo, D. E., Avina-Cervantes, J. G., Cruz-Aceves, I. &amp; Ruiz-Pinales, J. Quantum angle encoding with learnable rotation applied to quantum&#x2013;classical convolutional neural networks. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>141</b>, 110307 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2023.110307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. et al. Contrasting characteristics of the surface energy balance between the urban and rural areas of Beijing. <i>Adv. Atmos. Sci.</i><b>32</b>, 505&#x2013;514 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00376-014-3222-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R., Gao, W. &amp; Peng, W. Spatial downscaling method for air temperature through the correlation between land use/land cover and microclimate: A case study of the Greater Tokyo Area, Japan. <i>Urban Clim.</i><b>40</b>, 101003 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.uclim.2021.101003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanari, N. et al. Dioxin-like compounds in pine needles around Tokyo Bay, Japan in 1999. <i>J. Environ. Monit.</i><b>6</b>, 305&#x2013;312 (2004).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/b311176h</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15054539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation><i>Manual on Codes, International Codes, vol. I. 1 (Annex II to WMO Technical Regulations), part A, Alphanumeric Codes</i> (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. &amp; Li, T. <i>Fourth Seminar on Novel Optoelectronic Detection Technology and Application</i> pp. 165&#x2013;171. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janicka, L., Stachlewska, I. S., Veselovskii, I. &amp; Baars, H. Temporal variations in optical and microphysical properties of mineral dust and biomass burning aerosol derived from daytime Raman lidar observations over Warsaw, Poland. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>169</b>, 162&#x2013;174 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2017.09.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, B. et al. Temporal and spatial variations of haze and fog and the characteristics of PM2.5 during heavy pollution episodes in China from 2013 to 2018. <i>Atmos. Pollut. Res.</i><b>11</b>, 1847&#x2013;1856 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apr.2020.07.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. Y., Wong, M. S. &amp; Lee, K. H. Evaluation of the representativeness of ground-based visibility for analysing the spatial and temporal variability of aerosol optical thickness in China. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>147</b>, 31&#x2013;45 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2016.09.060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam, K., Trautmann, T., Blaschke, T. &amp; Subhan, F. Changes in aerosol optical properties due to dust storms in the Middle East and Southwest Asia. <i>Remote Sens. Environ.</i><b>143</b>, 216&#x2013;227 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2013.12.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>