<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41830156</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1557-0703</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2026</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Occupational therapy international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Occup Ther Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Digital Cognitive-Motor Occupational Training with QEEG Monitoring in Schizophrenia Rehabilitation: An Exploratory Neurofunctional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1389594</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e1389594</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/oti/1389594</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Current occupational therapy assessments for schizophrenia rely primarily on behavioral observation, with limited access to objective neurofunctional indicators of cognitive-motor engagement. Digital tools combined with neurophysiological monitoring offer new opportunities to address this gap. This study examined a digital cognitive-motor occupational training application paired with quantitative electroencephalography (QEEG) to explore neurofunctional engagement during task performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty individuals with schizophrenia completed structured occupational tasks under two conditions: with and without QEEG-based Brain Mapping Performance (BMP). Task engagement was characterized using participant-prioritized daily activities grouped into dopaminergic, serotonergic, oxytocinergic, and endorphin-related behavioral domains, conceptualized as theoretical behavioral associations rather than direct neurochemical measures. QEEG indices included theta relative power, beta relative power, and theta/beta ratio recorded from six frontal and temporal scalp sites.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Theta relative power was higher at frontal and central sites (Fz and Cz) during BMP-monitored conditions, reflecting executive and motor planning demands. Beta relative power varied across memory- and emotion-related task phases, indicating task-dependent modulation of cognitive effort. Engagement Intensity Scores were consistently higher in the unmonitored condition, while BMP monitoring was associated with longer task completion times and increased neurofunctional engagement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">QEEG-guided occupational task performance reveals distinct, task-dependent neurofunctional patterns in schizophrenia rehabilitation. The integration of digital task-based assessment with neurophysiological monitoring provides exploratory neurofunctional indicators that may support individualized, functionally informed occupational therapy interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Supalak Khemthong et al. Occupational Therapy International published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khemthong</LastName><ForeName>Supalak</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1974-3862</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Occupational Therapy, Faculty of Physical Therapy, Mahidol University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand, mahidol.ac.th.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rueankam</LastName><ForeName>Maliwan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4720-9795</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Occupational Therapy, Faculty of Physical Therapy, Mahidol University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand, mahidol.ac.th.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chatthong</LastName><ForeName>Winai</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5845-940X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Occupational Therapy, Faculty of Physical Therapy, Mahidol University, Nakhon Pathom, Thailand, mahidol.ac.th.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Electricity Generating Authority of Thailand</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Occup Ther Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9433361</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0966-7903</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schizophrenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Occupational Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001931" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Mapping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013647" MajorTopicYN="N">Task Performance and Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive-motor training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor relearning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occupational therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative electroencephalography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41830156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/oti/1389594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Harvey P. D., Assessment of Everyday Functioning in Schizophrenia, Innovations in Clinical Neuroscience. (2011) 8, no. 5, 21&#x2013;24, https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov21686144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su C.-Y., Tsai P.-C., Su W.-L., Tang T.-C., and Tsai Y.-J., Cognitive Profile Difference Between Allen Cognitive Levels 4 and 5 in Schizophrenia, American Journal of Occupational Therapy. (2011) 65, no. 4, 453&#x2013;461, https://doi.org/10.5014/ajot.2011.000711, 2-s2.0-79960370353, 21834461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21834461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieve J., Neuropsychology for Occupational Therapists: Assessment of Perception and Cognition, 1999, 2nd edition, Wiley.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemphill-PearsonB. J. and ReynoldsF., Assessments in Occupational Therapy Mental Health: An Integrative Approach, 2008, Thorofare, NJ.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khemthong S., Rueankam M., and Chatthong W., Brainy2Blessly: An Artificial Intelligence-Driven Digital Occupational Therapy System for Behavioral Monitoring in Schizophrenia Rehabilitation, 2025, Research Square, https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-7780966/v1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatthong W., Khemthong S., and Wongsawat Y., Brain Mapping Performance as an Occupational Therapy Assessment Aid in Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder, American Journal of Occupational Therapy. (2020) 74, no. 2, 7402205070p1&#x2013;7402205070p7, https://doi.org/10.5014/ajot.2020.035477, 32204785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32204785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer M., Glenn T., Geddes J., Gitlin M., Grof P., Kessing L. V., Monteith S., Faurholt-Jepsen M., Severus E., and Whybrow P. C., Smartphones in Mental Health: A Critical Review of Background Issues, Current Status and Future Concerns, International Journal of Bipolar Disorders. (2020) 8, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/s40345-019-0164-x, 31919635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31919635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatthong W., Khemthong S., and Wongsawat Y., A Design Thinking Model Based on Quantitative Electroencephalography in Social Emotional Learning for Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder, Mind, Brain, and Education. (2020) 14, no. 2, 104&#x2013;113, https://doi.org/10.1111/mbe.12235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi W. and Chamari K., The Algorithmic Athlete: A Call to Standardize Assessment of Sensor Technologies and Artificial Intelligence, International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance. (2026) 1&#x2013;2, https://doi.org/10.1123/ijspp.2025-0547, 41493778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41493778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souaifi M., Dhahbi W., Jebabli N., Ceylan H. &#x130;., Boujabli M., Muntean R. I., and Dergaa I., Artificial Intelligence in Sports Biomechanics: A Scoping Review on Wearable Technology, Motion Analysis, and Injury Prevention, Bioengineering. (2025) 12, no. 8, https://doi.org/10.3390/bioengineering12080887, 40868401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40868401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inhelder B., Sinclair H., and Bovet M., Learning and the Development of Cognition, 2014, Taylor &amp; Francis, https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315770932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khemthong S., Routine Task Inventory&#x2013;Expanded (RTI-E), Thai Version Jerusalem: School of Occupational Therapy, 2019, Faculty of Physical Therapy, Mahidol University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter J., Watson G., and Capra S., Food Skills Assessment Tools for People with a Mental Illness, Australian Occupational Therapy Journal. (1998) 45, no. 2, 65&#x2013;71, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440-1630.1998.tb00784.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Synovec C. E., Implementing Recovery Model Principles as Part of Occupational Therapy in Inpatient Psychiatric Settings, Occupational Therapy in Mental Health. (2015) 31, no. 1, 50&#x2013;61, https://doi.org/10.1080/0164212X.2014.1001014, 2-s2.0-84954200675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Public Health and Department of Mental Health, Annual Report: Department of Mental Health, Fiscal Year 2019, 2019, Nonthaburi, https://dmh-elibrary.org/items/show/189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada T., Nishi A., Yoshida T., Tanaka S., and Kobayashi M., Development of an Individualized Occupational Therapy Programme and Its Effects on the Neurocognition, Symptoms and Social Functioning of Patients with Schizophrenia, Occupational Therapy International. (2016) 23, no. 4, 425&#x2013;435, https://doi.org/10.1002/oti.1445, 2-s2.0-84994868544, 27748565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27748565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breuning L. G., Habits of a Happy Brain: Retrain Your Brain to Boost Your Serotonin, Dopamine, Oxytocin, and Endorphin Levels, 2015, Adams Media.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilchaikovit T., Uneanong S., Kessawai D., and Thomyangkoon P., The Thai Version of the Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale (PANSS) for Schizophrenia: Criterion Validity and Interrater Reliability, Journal of the Medical Association of Thailand. (2000) 83, no. 6, 646&#x2013;651, https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10932491/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahidol University, Faculty of Physical Therapy, Thai Physical Activity Guideline (TPAG). accessed April 1, 2020, https://pt.mahidol.ac.th/tpag/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X. L., Ranganath C., Hsieh L. T., Hurtado M., Niendam T. A., Lesh T. A., Carter C. S., and Ragland J. D., Task-Specific Disruptions in Theta Oscillations during Working Memory for Temporal Order in People with Schizophrenia, Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience. (2020) 32, no. 11, 2117&#x2013;2130, https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn_a_01598, 32573383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32573383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluwe-Schiavon B., Sanvicente-Vieira B., Kristensen C. H., and Grassi-Oliveira R., Executive Functions Rehabilitation for Schizophrenia: A Critical Systematic Review, Journal of Psychiatric Research. (2013) 47, no. 1, 91&#x2013;104, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2012.10.001, 2-s2.0-84869876763, 23122645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23122645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jebabli N., Boujabli M., Khlifi M., Ouerghi N., Bouassida A. N., Abderrahman A., Dhahbi W., and van den Tillaar R., Beta Frequency Binaural Beats Combined with Preferred Music Enhance Combat Performance and Recovery Responses in Amateur Kickboxers: A Randomized Crossover Trial, Frontiers in Psychology. (2025) 16, 1636856, https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1636856, 41035452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41035452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>