<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41685664</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2770</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of community psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Community Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Auto-photovoice: A reflexive extension of photovoice methodology and its practice in a COVID-quarantined community psychology course.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajcp.70053</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This article introduces "auto-photovoice," a novel self-reflexive extension of photovoice methodology where participant-researchers turn the camera on themselves to explore their personal experiences and observations of a phenomenon. In our exemplar project, students and faculty codesigned and implemented auto-photovoice methodology during a 10-week online community psychology graduate seminar during the COVID-19 pandemic quarantine. Our photos addressed the prompt, "What inequities do we experience and witness in well-being related to COVID-19?" The initial analysis of weekly discussions of the photos identified 24 themes regarding COVID-19 impacts, which we later synthesized into four more general themes: (1) systemic social injustices, (2) abuses of power, (3) inequitable access, and (4) differential experiences among workers. As participant-researchers practicing auto-photovoice, we created a sense of community and an empowering pedagogy in our first remote online class during the initial weeks of the COVID-19 pandemic. As a methodology rooted in epistemologies that value reflexive and participatory knowledge creation, auto-photovoice facilitates us working empathically and authentically with communities in projects characterized by epistemic respect and justice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Society for Community Research and Action.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mankowski</LastName><ForeName>Eric S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1640-8102</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bernard</LastName><ForeName>Liana</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3130-2741</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brott</LastName><ForeName>Holly</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8374-7649</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology Science, Central Connecticut State University, New Britain, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hachem</LastName><ForeName>Zeinab A</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9182-0992</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lipman</LastName><ForeName>Aliza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petit</LastName><ForeName>Brielle</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Snoeyink</LastName><ForeName>Megan J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6445-4533</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Community Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0364535</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0091-0562</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID&#x2010;19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">auto&#x2010;photovoice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community psychology education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">online education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reflexivity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41685664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajcp.70053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ali, S. H., Tozan, Y., Jones, A. M., Foreman, J., Capasso, A., &amp; DiClemente, R. J. (2021). Regional and socioeconomic predictors of perceived ability to access coronavirus testing in the United States: Results from a nationwide online COVID&#x2010;19 survey. Annals of Epidemiology, 58, 7&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.annepidem.2021.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augsberger, A., Toraif, N., Young, A., Dimitri, N. C., Bautista, R., Pierre, J., Le, C., Idahor, O., Jusme, C., &amp; Gergen Barnett, K. A. (2022). COVID&#x2010;19 shines a light on health inequities in communities of color: A youth&#x2010;driven photovoice inquiry. Journal of Community Psychology, 50(8), 3700&#x2013;3715. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.22866</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balcazar, F. E., Taylor, R. R., Keilhorner, G. W., Tamley, K., Benziger, T., Carlin, N., &amp; Johnson, S. (2004). Participatory action research: General principles and a study with a chronic health condition. In L. A. Jason, C. B. Keys, Y. S. Suarez&#x2010;Balcazar, R. R. Taylor, &amp; M. I. Davis (Eds.), Participatory community research: Theories and methods in action (pp. 17&#x2013;35). American Psychological Association.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barman&#x2010;Adhikari, A., DeChants, J. P., M. Brydon, D., Portillo, A., &amp; Bender, K. (2019). On the fringes: How youth experiencing homelessness conceptualize social and economic inequality&#x2014;A photovoice study. Journal of Community Psychology, 47(4), 924&#x2013;942. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.22164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard, L., Fox, S., Kulason, K., Phanphackdy, A., Kahle, X., Martinez, L., Praslova, L., &amp; Smith, N. A. (2023). Not your &#x201c;typical&#x201d; research: Inclusion ethics in neurodiversity scholarship. Industrial and Organizational Psychology, 16(1), 50&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1017/iop.2022.100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun, V., &amp; Clarke, V. (2006). Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qualitative Research in Psychology, 3(2), 77&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronfenbrenner, U. (1979). The ecology of human development: Experiments by nature and design. Harvard University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, R. (2002). Emotionally involved: The impact of researching rape (1st ed.). Routledge. https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203613511</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, R., &amp; Wasco, S. M. (2000). Feminist approaches to social science: Epistemological and methodological tenets. American Journal of Community Psychology, 28(6), 773&#x2013;791. https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1005159716099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio, V. C., &amp; Fandt, P. M. (2007). Photovoice in the diversity classroom: Engagement, voice, and the &#x201c;eye/I&#x201d; of the camera. Journal of Management Education, 31(4), 484&#x2013;504. https://doi.org/10.1177/1052562906288124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christi&#xe1;n, L., Erd&#x151;s, &#xc1;., &amp; H&#xe1;l&#xf3;, G. (2022). The background and repercussions of the George Floyd case. Cogent Social Sciences, 8(1), 2082094. https://doi.org/10.1080/23311886.2022.2082094</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins, K. (2016). Addressing the community psychology competency dialectic through participatory pedagogy. Global Journal of Community Psychology Practice, 7(4), 1&#x2013;71. Retrieved February 5, 2026, from http://www.gjcpp.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compare, C., Prati, G., Guarino, A., Gatti, F., Procentese, F., Fedi, A., Aresi, G. U., Gattino, S., Marzana, D., Tzankova, I., &amp; Albanesi, C. (2021). Predictors of prosocial behavior during the COVID&#x2010;19 national lockdown in Italy: Testing the role of psychological sense of community and other community assets. Community Psychology in Global Perspective, 7(2), 22&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.1285/i24212113v7i2p22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove, L., &amp; McHugh, M. C. (2000). Speaking for ourselves: Feminist methods and community psychology. American Journal of Community Psychology, 28(6), 815&#x2013;838. https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1005163817007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do, P. L., Goldingay, S., &amp; Dew, A. (2025). Using online photovoice to facilitate participation of autistic adolescents in research. Disability &amp; Society, 40(8), 2178&#x2013;2203. https://doi.org/10.1080/09687599.2024.2427695</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake, E., Jeffrey, G., &amp; Duckett, P. (2022). Colonised minds and community psychology in the academy: Collaborative autoethnographic reflections. American Journal of Community Psychology, 69(3&#x2013;4), 415&#x2013;425. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajcp.12574</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duijs, S. E., Abma, T., Schrijver, J., Bourik, Z., Abena&#x2010;Jaspers, Y., Jhingoeri, U., Plak, O., Senoussi, N., &amp; Verdonk, P. (2022). Navigating voice, vocabulary and silence: Developing critical consciousness in a photovoice project with (un) paid care workers in long&#x2010;term care. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 19(9), 5570. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19095570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, M., Perry, B., Janzen, K., &amp; Menzies, C. (2012). Using the artistic pedagogical technology of photovoice to promote interaction in the online post&#x2010;secondary classroom: The students' perspective. Electronic Journal of E&#x2010;learning, 10(1), 32&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichstaedt, J. C., Sherman, G. T., Giorgi, S., Roberts, S. O., Reynolds, M. E., Ungar, L. H., &amp; Guntuku, S. C. (2021). The emotional and mental health impact of the murder of George Floyd on the US population. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 118(39), e2109139118. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2109139118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster&#x2010;Fishman, P. G., Law, K. M., Lichty, L. F., &amp; Aoun, C. (2010). Youth ReACT for social change: A method for youth participatory action research. American Journal of Community Psychology, 46 (1), 67&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10464&#x2010;010&#x2010;9316&#x2010;y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gattino, S., Rizzo, M., Gatti, F., Compare, C., Procentese, F., Guarino, A., Di Napoli, I., Barbieri, I., Fedi, A., Aresi, G., Marta, E., Marzana, D., Prati, G., Rochira, A., Tzankova, I., &amp; Albanesi, C. (2022). COVID&#x2010;19 in our lives: Sense of community, sense of community responsibility, and reflexivity in present concerns and perception of the future. Journal of Community Psychology, 50(5), 2344&#x2013;2365. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.22780</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez, K. A. C., Chang, H., &amp; Ngunjiri, F. W. (2017). Collaborative autoethnography as multivocal, relational, and democratic research: Opportunities, challenges, and aspirations. a/b: Auto/Biography Studies, 32(2), 251&#x2013;254. https://doi.org/10.1080/08989575.2017.1288892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hershberg, R. M., Andringa, O., Camm, K., Hill, H., Little, J., Smith, R., &amp; Wilkinson, S. (2019). Learning through doing: Reflections on the use of photovoice in an undergraduate community psychology classroom. Global Journal of Community Psychology Practice, 10(2), 1&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.17161/gjcpp.v10i2.20700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesen, R., Wals, A. E. J., &amp; Tauritz, R. L. (2022). Creating a sense of community and space for subjectification in an online course on sustainability education during times of physical distancing. International Journal of Sustainability in Higher Education, 23(8), 85&#x2013;104. https://doi.org/10.1108/IJSHE&#x2010;07&#x2010;2021&#x2010;0270</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly, J. G. (2006). Becoming ecological: An expedition into community psychology. Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohfeldt, D., Chhun, L., Grace, S., &amp; Langhout, R. D. (2011). Youth empowerment in context: Exploring tensions in school&#x2010;based yPAR. American Journal of Community Psychology, 47(1&#x2013;2), 28&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10464&#x2010;010&#x2010;9376&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langhout, R. D. (2024). Teaching community psychology from an entanglement framework. In C. C. Sonn, J. S. Fern&#xe1;ndez, J. F. Moura, M. E. Madyaningrum, &amp; N. Malherbe (Eds.), Handbook of decolonial community psychology (pp. 113&#x2013;125). Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;3&#x2010;031&#x2010;67035&#x2010;0_6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichty, L., Kornbluh, M., Mortensen, J., &amp; Foster&#x2010;Fishman, P. (2019). Claiming online space for empowering methods: Taking photovoice to scale online. Global Journal of Community Psychology Practice, 10(3), 1&#x2013;26. https://doi.org/10.17161/gjcpp.v10i3.20692</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichty, L. F. (2013). Photovoice as a pedagogical tool in the community psychology classroom. Journal of Prevention &amp; Intervention in the Community, 41(2), 89&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1080/10852352.2013.757984</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannarini, T., Rizzo, M., Brodsky, A., Buckingham, S., Zhao, J., Rochira, A., &amp; Fedi, A. (2022). The potential of psychological connectedness: Mitigating the impacts of COVID&#x2010;19 through sense of community and community resilience. Journal of Community Psychology, 50(5), 2273&#x2013;2289. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.22775</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero, M. (2002). On the construction of reality and truth. Towards an epistemology of community social psychology. American Journal of Community Psychology, 30(4), 571&#x2013;584. https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1015864103005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulder, C., &amp; Dull, A. (2014). Facilitating self&#x2010;reflection: The integration of photovoice in graduate social work education. Social Work Education, 33(8), 1017&#x2013;1036. https://doi.org/10.1080/02615479.2014.937416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliffe, J. L., Gao, N., Kelly, M. T., Fernandez, C. C., Salavati, H., Sha, M., Seidler, Z. E., &amp; Rice, S. M. (2023). The case for and against doing virtual photovoice. International Journal of Qualitative Methods, 22, 1&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1177/16094069231190564</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oregon Executive Order No. 20&#x2010;12. (2020). Stay home, save lives: Ordering Oregonians to stay at home, closing specified retail businesses, requiring social distancing measures for other public and private facilities, and imposing requirements for outdoor areas and licensed child care facilities. 1&#x2013;12. https://www.oregon.gov/gov/eo/eo_20&#x2010;12.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry, B. (2006). Using photographic images as an interactive online teaching strategy. Internet and Higher Education, 9 (3), 229&#x2013;240. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.iheduc.2006.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulos, C. N. (2021). Conceptual foundations of autoethnography. In C. N. Poulos (Ed.), Essentials of autoethnography (pp. 3&#x2013;17). American Psychological Association. https://doi.org/10.1037/0000222&#x2010;001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruitt, A. S., Barile, J. P., Ogawa, T. Y., Peralta, N., Bugg, R., Lau, J., Lamberton, T., Hall, C., &amp; Mori, V. (2018). Housing first and photovoice: Transforming lives, communities, and systems. American Journal of Community Psychology, 61 (1&#x2013;2), 104&#x2013;117. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajcp.12226</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappaport, J. (1977). Community psychology: Values, research, and action. Harcourt School.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzo, M., Fedi, A., Brodsky, A. E., Rochira, A., Zhao, J., &amp; Mannarini, T. (2024). Mitigating the effect of COVID&#x2010;19 in a postemergency phase: The role of sense of community and individual resilience. Journal of Community Psychology, 52(8), 1138&#x2013;1149. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.23138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronzi, S., Pope, D., Orton, L., &amp; Bruce, N. (2016). Using photovoice methods to explore older people's perceptions of respect and social inclusion in cities: Opportunities, challenges and solutions. SSM&#x2010;Population Health, 2, 732&#x2013;745. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssmph.2016.09.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamrova, D. P., &amp; Cummings, C. E. (2017). Participatory action research (PAR) with children and youth: An integrative review of methodology and PAR outcomes for participants, organizations, and communities. Children and Youth Services Review, 81, 400&#x2013;412. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.childyouth.2017.08.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, C. H., &amp; Mankowski, E. S. (2004). Asking, witnessing, interpreting, knowing: Conducting qualitative research in community psychology. American Journal of Community Psychology, 33(1&#x2013;2), 21&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1023/B:AJCP.0000014316.27091.e8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suffla, S., Seedat, M., &amp; Bawa, U. (2015). Reflexivity as enactment of critical community psychologies: Dilemmas of voice and positionality in a multi&#x2010;country photovoice study. Journal of Community Psychology, 43(1), 9&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.21691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, S., &amp; Sarkisian, GV. (2011). Community psychology values&#x2010;driven pedagogy: The foundation for empowering educational settings. Global Journal ofCommunity Psychology Practice, 2(2), 19&#x2013;30. Retrieved February 5, 2026, from http://www.gjcpp.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, E., &amp; Mulvey, A. (2008). Using the arts in teaching and learning: Building student capacity for community&#x2010;based work in health psychology. Journal of Health Psychology, 13 (2), 239&#x2013;250. https://doi.org/10.1177/1359105307086703</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C., &amp; Burris, M. A. (1997). Photovoice: Concept, methodology, and use for participatory needs assessment. Health Education &amp; Behavior: The Official Publication of the Society for Public Health Education, 24(3), 369&#x2013;387. https://doi.org/10.1177/109019819702400309</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. C., Yi, W. K., Tao, Z. W., &amp; Carovano, K. (1998). Photovoice as a participatory health promotion strategy. Health Promotion International, 13(1), 75&#x2013;86. https://doi.org/10.1093/heapro/13.1.75</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (April 27, 2020). WHO timeline&#x2014;COVID&#x2010;19. https://www.who.int/news/item/29&#x2010;06&#x2010;2020&#x2010;covidtimeline</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>