<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41868354</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2469-7311</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>IEEE transactions on radiation and plasma medical sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>IEEE Trans Radiat Plasma Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ZS4D: Zero-Shot Self-Similarity-Steered Denoiser for Volumetric Photon-Counting CT.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>359</StartPage><EndPage>370</EndPage><MedlinePgn>359-370</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1109/trpms.2025.3593080</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Photon-counting computed tomography (PCCT) has emerged as a transformative imaging modality, enabling enhanced spatial resolution, and multi-energy acquisition with energy-discriminating detectors of significantly smaller detector elements. However, both energy discriminating power and reduced detector pixel size result in fewer detected photons per measurement, inherently increasing noise in reconstructed images. In this study, we propose ZS4D, a zero-shot self-similarity-steered denoiser for PCCT reconstruction. Specifically, a self-similarity denoiser is pre-trained in a self-supervised manner by leveraging spectral correlations through multi-energy extraction and capturing volumetric context via the complementary synergy of axial and sagittal planes. The pre-trained denoiser is then integrated as a prior into an iterative reconstruction framework, enabling effective noise suppression and structural preservation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that ZS4D adapts well to varying noise levels and significantly enhances image quality in both simulated and pre-clinical PCCT datasets. Also, ZS4D demonstrates effectiveness in deblurring tasks. Furthermore, our denoiser pretrained on clinical PCCT data is shown to enhance the spatial resolution of conventional CT images.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Yongyi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY 12180 USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Chuang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY 12180 USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Wenjun</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY 12180 USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Yuxuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY 12180 USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GE HealthCare Technology &amp; Innovation Center (HTIC), Niskayuna, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Man</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GE HealthCare Technology &amp; Innovation Center (HTIC), Niskayuna, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ge</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Imaging Center, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY 12180. and Department of Radiology, Wake Forest University, Winston-Salem, SC 27109 USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL151561</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>IEEE Trans Radiat Plasma Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101705223</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2469-7303</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zero-shot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">denoising and deblurring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-similarity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">volumetric photon-counting CT</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41868354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2153979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13004115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/trpms.2025.3593080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rajendran K, Petersilka M, Henning A, Shanblatt ER, Schmidt B, Flohr TG, et al. , &#x201c;First clinical photon-counting detector CT system: technical evaluation,&#x201d; Radiology, vol. 303, no. 1, pp. 130&#x2013;138, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8940675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34904876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douek PC, Boccalini S, Oei EH, Cormode DP, Pourmorteza A, Boussel L, et al. , &#x201c;Clinical applications of photon-counting CT: a review of pioneer studies and a glimpse into the future,&#x201d; Radiology, vol. 309, no. 1, p. e222432, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10623209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37787672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma SP, Lemmens MJD, Smulders MW, et al. , &#x201c;Photon-counting detector computed tomography in cardiac imaging&#x201d;. Netherlands Heart Journal, vol. 32 pp. 405&#x2013;416, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11502613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39356451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf6;nberg F, Lundberg J, Sj&#xf6;lin M, Persson M, Bujila R,Bornefalk H, et al. , &#x201c;Feasibility of unconstrained three-material decomposition: imaging an excised human heart using a prototype silicon photon-counting CT detector,&#x201d;European radiology,vol. 30, pp. 5904&#x2013;5912, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7554013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32588212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toia GV, Mileto A, Borhani AA, Chen GH, Ren L, Uyeda JW, et al. , &#x201c;Approaches, advantages, and challenges to photon counting detector and multi-energy CT,&#x201d; Abdominal Radiology, vol. 49, no. 9, pp. 3251&#x2013;3260, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38744702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng S, Yu L, Wang J, Fletcher JG, Mistretta CA, McCollough CH, &#x201c;Noise reduction in spectral CT: Reducing dose and breaking the trade-off between image noise and energy bin selection,&#x201d; Medical physics, vol. 38, no. 9, pp. 4946&#x2013;4957, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21978039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh SS, &#x201c;Coincidence counters for charge sharing compensation in spectroscopic photon counting detectors,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on medical imaging, vol. 39, no. 3, pp. 678&#x2013;687, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31398114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman B, Callahan MJ, &#x201c;ALARA (as low as reasonably achievable) CT 2011&#x2014;executive summary,&#x201d; Pediatric radiology, vol. 41, pp. 453&#x2013;455, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21847721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q, Yu H, Bennett J, He P, Zainon R, Doesburg et R. al, &#x201c;Image reconstruction for hybrid true-color micro-CT,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering, vol. 59, no. 6, pp. 1711&#x2013;1719, 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3773953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22481806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B, Ding H, Lu Y, Wang G, Zhao J, Molloi S, &#x201c;Dual-dictionary learning-based iterative image reconstruction for spectral computed tomography application,&#x201d; Physics in Medicine &amp; Biology, vol. 57, no. 24, pp. 8217&#x2013;8229, 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4511115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K, Ye JC, Worstell W, Ouyang J, Rakvongthai Y, El Fakhri G et al. , &#x201c;Sparse-view spectral CT reconstruction using spectral patch-based low-rank penalty,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 34, no. 3, pp. 748&#x2013;760, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25532170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu S, Yu G, Ma J, Wang J, &#x201c;Nonlocal low-rank and sparse matrix decomposition for spectral CT reconstruction,&#x201d; Inverse Problems, vol. 34, no. 2, p. 024003, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6168215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30294061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Mou X, Wang G, Yu H, &#x201c;Tensor-based dictionary learning for spectral CT reconstruction,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 36, no. 1, pp. 142&#x2013;154, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27541628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W, Liu F, Zhang Y, Wang Q, Yu H, &#x201c;Non-local Low-rank Cube-based Tensor Factorization for Spectral CT Reconstruction,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 38, no. 4, pp. 1079&#x2013;1093, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6536296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia W, Wu W, Niu S, Liu F, Zhou J, Yu H, et al. , &#x201c;Spectral CT reconstruction&#x2014;ASSIST: Aided by self-similarity in image-spectral tensors,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging, vol. 5, no. 3, pp. 420&#x2013;436, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao H, Yu H, Osher S, Wang G, &#x201c;Multi-energy CT based on a prior rank, intensity and sparsity model (PRISM),&#x201d; Inverse Problems, vol. 27, no. 11, p. 115012, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3249839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22223929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Chen Z, Wang G, Chu J, Gao H, &#x201c;A tensor PRISM algorithm for multi-energy CT reconstruction and comparative studies,&#x201d; Journal of X-ray Science and Technology, vol. 22, no. 2, pp. 147&#x2013;163, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24699344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z, Quan G, Qu H, Du Y, Zhao J, &#x201c;LOQUAT: Low-Rank Quaternion Reconstruction for Photon-Counting CT,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 44, no. 2, pp. 668&#x2013;684, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu J, Cong W, Li L, Wang G, &#x201c;Combination of current integrating/photon-counting detector modules for spectral CT,&#x201d; Physics in Medicine &amp; Biology, vol. 58, no. 19, pp. 7009&#x2013;7024, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24043342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Gao Y, Zhang Y, Sun J, Mou X, Liang Z, &#x201c;Spectral CT reconstruction via low-rank representation and region-specific texture preserving Markov random field regularization,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 39, no. 10, pp. 2996&#x2013;3007, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Gao Y, Xu Q, Li Y, Mou X, Liang Z, &#x201c;Learned tensor neural network texture prior for photon-counting CT reconstruction,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 43, no. 11, pp. 3830&#x2013;3842, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12169345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38753483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang E, Min J, Ye JC, &#x201c;A deep convolutional neural network using directional wavelets for low-dose X-ray CT reconstruction,&#x201d; Medical physics, vol. 44, no. 10, pp. e360&#x2013;e375, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29027238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D, Kim K, El Fakhri G, Li Q, &#x201c;Iterative low-dose CT reconstruction with priors trained by artificial neural network,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on medical imaging, vol. 36, no. 12, pp.2479&#x2013;2486, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5897914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28922116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Yan P, Zhang Y, Yu H, Shi Y, Mou X, et al. , &#x201c;Low-dose CT image denoising using a generative adversarial network with Wasserstein distance and perceptual loss,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on medical imaging, vol. 37, no. 6, pp. 1348&#x2013;57, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6021013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29870364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Yang Y, Wang Y, Zeng D, Bian Z, Zhang H, et al. , &#x201c;Optimizing a parameterized plug-and-play ADMM for iterative low-dose CT reconstruction,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on medical imaging, vol. 38, no. 2, pp.371&#x2013;382. 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30106717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G, Jacob M, Mou X, Shi Y, Eldar YC, &#x201c;Deep tomographic image reconstruction: yesterday, today, and tomorrow&#x2014;editorial for the 2nd special issue &#x201c;Machine Learning for Image Reconstruction&#x201d;,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on medical imaging, vol. 40, no. 11, pp.2956&#x2013;2964, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y, Niu C, Zhang J, Wang G, Shan H, &#x201c;CT image denoising and deblurring with deep learning: current status and perspectives,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Radiation and Plasma Medical Sciences, vol. 8, no. 2, pp.153&#x2013;172, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang B, Lu S, Zhang L, Lin B, Wu W, Liu Q, &#x201c;One-sample diffusion modeling in projection domain for low-dose CT imaging,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Radiation and Plasma Medical Sciences, vol. 8, no. 8, pp. 902&#x2013;915, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z, Gao Q, Wang T, Yang Z, Wang Z, Yu H, et al. , &#x201c;PrideDiff: Physics-Regularized Generalized Diffusion Model for CT Reconstruction,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Radiation and Plasma Medical Sciences, vol. 8, no. 2, pp. 157&#x2013;168, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousse A, Kandarpa V, Rit S, Perelli A, Li M, Wang G, et al. , &#x201c;Systematic review on learning-based spectral CT,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Radiation and Plasma Medical Sciences, vol. 8, no. 2, pp.113&#x2013;137, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10927029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38476981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Bousse A, Vermet F, Froment J, Vedel B, Perelli A, et al. , &#x201c;Uconnect: Synergistic spectral CT reconstruction with U-Nets connecting the energy bins,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Radiation and Plasma Medical Sciences, vol. 8, no. 2, pp. 222&#x2013;233, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang S, Zhang C, Mou X, Xu Q, He L, Chen X, &#x201c;A Parametric Physical Model Based X-ray Spectrum Estimation Approach for CT Imaging,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Radiation and Plasma Medical Sciences, vol. 8, no. 5, pp. 532&#x2013;539, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu C, Li M, Fan F, Wu W, Guo X, Lyu Q, et al. , &#x201c;Noise suppression with similarity-based self-supervised deep learning,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on medical imaging, vol. 42, no. 6, pp.1590&#x2013;1602, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Li Y, Chang D, He P, Feng P, Yu H, et al. , &#x201c;Spectral2Spectral: Image-spectral similarity assisted deep spectral CT reconstruction without reference,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging. Vol. 9, pp. 1031&#x2013;1042, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Zhang C, Bai T, Chang S, &#x201c;Improving Spectral CT Image Quality Based on Channel Correlation and Self-Supervised Learning,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Computational Imaging, vol. 9, pp. 1084&#x2013;1097, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Yang Y, Stevens GM, Yin Z, Wang AS, &#x201c;Emulating Low-Dose PCCT Image Pairs with Independent Noise for Self-Supervised Spectral Image Denoising,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging, vol. 44, no. 1, pp. 530&#x2013;542, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39196747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Zuo W, Chen Y, Meng D, Zhang L, &#x201c;Beyond a gaussian denoiser: Residual learning of deep CNN for image denoising,&#x201d; IEEE transactions on image processing, vol. 26, no. 7, pp.3142&#x2013;3155, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28166495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isensee F, Jaeger PF, Kohl SA, Petersen J, Maier-Hein KH, &#x201c;nnU-Net: a self-configuring method for deep learning-based biomedical image segmentation,&#x201d; Nature methods, vol. 18, no. 2, pp.203&#x2013;211, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33288961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Klasky M, McCann MT, Hu J, Fessler JA, &#x201c;Swap-Net: A Memory-Efficient 2.5 D Network for Sparse-View 3D Cone Beam CT Reconstruction,&#x201d; arXiv preprint arXiv:2410.10836, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HS, Kim K, Jeon K, &#x201c;Low-dose CT image reconstruction with a deep learning prior,&#x201d; IEEE Access, vol. 8, pp.158647&#x2013;158655, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano Y, Elad M, Milanfar P, &#x201c;The little engine that could: Regularization by denoising (RED),&#x201d; SIAM Journal on Imaging Sciences, vol. 10, no. 4, pp.1804&#x2013;1844, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mataev G, Milanfar P, Elad M, &#x201c;DeepRED: Deep image prior powered by RED,&#x201d; In Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision Workshops, pp. 0&#x2013;0, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ameen Z, Sulong G, Gapar MD, Johar MD, &#x201c;Reducing the Gaussian blur artifact from CT medical images by employing a combination of sharpening filters and iterative deblurring algorithms,&#x201d; Journal of Theoretical and Applied Information Technology, vol. 46, no. 1, pp. 31&#x2013;36, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielyan A, Katkovnik V, Egiazarian K, &#x201c;BM3D frames and variational image deblurring,&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on image processing, vol. 21, no. 4, pp.1715&#x2013;1728, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22128008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ameen Z, Sulong G, Johar MGM, &#x201c;Fast deblurring method for computed tomography medical images using a novel kernels set,&#x201d; International Journal of Bio-Science and Bio-Technology, vol. 4, no. 3, pp.9&#x2013;20, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen AH, Kak AC, &#x201c;Simultaneous algebraic reconstruction technique (SART): a superior implementation of the ART algorithm,&#x201d; Ultrasonic imaging, vol. 6, no. 1, pp.81&#x2013;94, 1984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6548059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong W, Xi Y, De Man B, Wang G, &#x201c;Monochromatic image reconstruction via machine learning,&#x201d; Machine learning: science and technology, vol. 2, no. 2, p. 025032, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9673989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36406260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao S, Zhou H, Gao Y, Zhuang X, &#x201c;BayeSeg: Bayesian modeling for medical image segmentation with interpretable generalizability,&#x201d; Medical Image Analysis, vol. 89, p.102889, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willemink MJ, Persson M, Pourmorteza A, Pelc NJ, Fleischmann D, &#x201c;Photon-counting CT: technical principles and clinical prospects,&#x201d; Radiology, vol. 289, no. 2, pp.293&#x2013;312, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30179101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>