<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41446570</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2835-8279</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PRX life</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PRX Life</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Energy injection in an epithelial cell monolayer indicated by negative viscosity.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1103/9lnm-gm3j</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Epithelial tissues are driven out of thermodynamic equilibrium by internally generated forces, causing complex patterns of motion. Even when both the forces and motion are measurable, it is not yet possible to relate the two, because the sources of energy injection and dissipation are often unclear. Here, we study how energy is transferred by developing a method to measure the effective viscosity from the shear stresses and strain rates within an epithelial cell monolayer. Interestingly, there emerged multicellular regions in which the relationship between shear stress and shear strain rate was negatively proportional, indicating a negative effective viscosity. The negative effective viscosity occurred in regions wherein cell stresses were less efficient at producing tissue deformations compared to regions of positive effective viscosity. Regions of negative effective viscosity consistently exhibited greater cell speed and vorticity, and the cells had elevated metabolic activity, reflecting an increased energy demand in these cells. Our study shows that negative effective viscosity is a useful means of quantifying the flow of energy in living matter.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCord</LastName><ForeName>Molly</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biophysics Program, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Notbohm</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biophysics Program, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R35 GM151171</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PRX Life</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918697474106676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2835-8279</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>ArXiv. 2025 Jan 6:arXiv:2501.03401v1.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">39867429</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><CoiStatement>Ethics declarations The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41446570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2127667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12724540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/9lnm-gm3j</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Poujade M, Grasland-Mongrain E, Hertzog A, Jouanneau J, Chavrier P, Ladoux B, Buguin A, and Silberzan P Collective migration of an epithelial monolayer in response to a model wound. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 104(41):15988&#x2013;15993, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vedula SRK, Leong MC, Lai TL, Hersen P, Kabla AJ, Lim CT, and Ladoux B Emerging modes of collective cell migration induced by geometrical constraints. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 109(32):12974&#x2013;12979, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alert R, Casademunt J, and Joanny J-F Active turbulence. Annu Rev Condens Matter Phys, 13(10.1146):143&#x2013;170, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trepat X, Wasserman MR, Angelini TE, Millet E, Weitz DA, Butler JP, and Fredberg JJ Physical forces during collective cell migration. Nat Phys, 5(6):426&#x2013;430, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tambe DT, Hardin CC, Angelini TE, Rajendran K, Park CY, Serra-Picamal X, Zhou EH, Zaman MH, Butler JP, Weitz DA, Fredberg JJ, and Trepat X Collective cell guidance by cooperative intercellular forces. Nat Mater, 10(6):469&#x2013;475, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3135682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21602808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Serra-Picamal X, Tambe DT, Zhou EH, Park CY, Sadati M, Park J-A, Krishnan R, Gweon B, Millet E, Butler JP, Trepat X, and Fredberg JJ Propulsion and navigation within the advancing monolayer sheet. Nat Mater, 12(9):856&#x2013;863, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23793160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bera PK, McCord M, Zhang J, and Notbohm J Traction and stress control formation and motion of+ 1/2 topological defects in epithelial cell monolayers. Newton, 1(8), 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchetti MC, Joanny J-F, Ramaswamy S, Liverpool TB, Prost J, Rao M, and Simha RA Hydrodynamics of soft active matter. Rev Mod Phys, 85(3):1143, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alert R and Trepat X Physical models of collective cell migration. Annu Rev Condens Matter Phys, 11(1):77&#x2013;101, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclos G, Erlenk&#xe4;mper C, Joanny J-F, and Silberzan P Topological defects in confined populations of spindle-shaped cells. Nat Phys, 13(1):58&#x2013;62, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez C, Alert R, Blanch-Mercader C, G&#xf3;mez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Kolodziej T, Bazellieres E, Casademunt J, and Trepat X Active wetting of epithelial tissues. Nat Phys, 15(1):79&#x2013;88, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6753015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmottant P, Mgharbel A, K&#xe4;fer J, Audren B, Rieu J-P, Vial J-C, van der Sanden B, Mar&#xe9;e AFM, Graner F, and Delano&#xeb;-Ayari H The role of fluctuations and stress on the effective viscosity of cell aggregates. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 106(41):17271&#x2013;17275, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guevorkian K, Colbert M-J, Durth M, Dufour S, and Brochard-Wyart F Aspiration of biological viscoelastic drops. Phys Rev Lett, 104(21):218101, 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20867138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanch-Mercader C, Vincent R, Bazelli&#xe8;res E, Serra-Picamal X, Trepat X, and Casademunt J Effective viscosity and dynamics of spreading epithelia: a solvable model. Soft Matter, 13(6):1235&#x2013;1243, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28098306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notbohm J, Banerjee S, Utuje KJ, Gweon B, Jang H, Park Y, Shin J, Butler JP, Fredberg JJ, and Marchetti MC Cellular contraction and polarization drive collective cellular motion. Biophys J, 110(12):2729&#x2013;2738, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4919426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27332131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathibhatla A and Notbohm J Tractions and stress fibers control cell shape and rearrangements in collective cell migration. Phys Rev X, 10(1):011016, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tambe DT, Croutelle U, Trepat X, Park CY, Kim JH, Millet E, Butler JP, and Fredberg JJ Monolayer stress microscopy: limitations, artifacts, and accuracy of recovered intercellular stresses. Plos One, 8(2):e55172, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3585344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathibhatla A, Galles EE, and Notbohm J Spatiotemporal force and motion in collective cell migration. Sci Data, 7(1):197, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32581285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatwalne Y, Ramaswamy S, Rao M, and Simha RA Rheology of active-particle suspensions. Phys Rev Lett, 92(11):118101, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15089176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cates M, Fielding S, Marenduzzo D, Orlandini E, and Yeomans J Shearing active gels close to the isotropic-nematic transition. Phys Rev Lett, 101(6):068102, 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18764508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sokolov A and Aranson IS Reduction of viscosity in suspension of swimming bacteria. Phys Rev Lett, 103(14):148101, 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19905604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gachelin J, Mino G, Berthet H, Lindner A, Rousselet A, and Cl&#xe9;ment &#xc9; Non-newtonian viscosity of escherichia coli suspensions. Phys Rev Lett, 110(26):268103, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23848926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez HM, Gachelin J, Douarche C, Auradou H, and Cl&#xe9;ment E Turning bacteria suspensions into superfluids. Phys Rev Lett, 115(2):028301, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26207507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orihara H, Harada Y, Kobayashi F, Sasaki Y, Fujii S, Satou Y, Goto Y, and Nagaya T Negative viscosity of a liquid crystal in the presence of turbulence. Phys Rev E, 99(1):012701, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30780349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chui JY, Douarche C, Auradou H, and Juanes R Rheology of bacterial superfluids in viscous environments. Soft Matter, 17(29):7004&#x2013;7013, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34240724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCord M and Notbohm J Measurement of tissue viscosity to relate force and motion in collective cell migration. arXiv preprint arXiv:2508.11518, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saintillan D Rheology of active fluids. Annu Rev Fluid Mech, 50(1):563&#x2013;592, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nejad MR, Ruske LJ, McCord M, Zhang J, Zhang G, Notbohm J, and Yeomans JM Stress-shape misalignment in confluent cell layers. Nat Commun, 15(1):3628, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11059169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38684651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee P and Wolgemuth C Advent of complex flows in epithelial tissues. Phys Rev E, 83(6):061920, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochet-Escartin O, Ranft J, Silberzan P, and Marcq P Border forces and friction control epithelial closure dynamics. Biophys J, 106(1):65&#x2013;73, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3907253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24411238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez K, Saraswathibhatla A, and Notbohm J Effect of substrate stiffness on friction in collective cell migration. Sci Rep, 12(1):2436, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35136184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S-Z, Zhang W-Y, Bi D, Li B, and Feng X-Q Energetics of mesoscale cell turbulence in two-dimensional monolayers. Commun Phys, 4(1):21, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaduto RC and Grotyohann LW Measurement of Mitochondrial Membrane Potential Using Fluorescent Rhodamine Derivatives. Biophys J, 76(1):469&#x2013;477, 1999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1302536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9876159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou C, Wang Y, and Shen Z 2-NBDG as a fluorescent indicator for direct glucose uptake measurement. J Biochem Bioph Meth, 64(3):207&#x2013;215, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeCamp SJ, Tsuda VMK, Ferruzzi J, Koehler SA, Giblin JT, Roblyer D, Zaman MH, Weiss ST, K&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7; A, De Marzio M, Park CY, Ogassavara NC, Mitchel JA, Butler JP, and Fredberg JJ Epithelial layer unjamming shifts energy metabolism toward glycolysis. Sci Rep, 10(1):18302, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7591531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33110128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron S, Caplanusi A, van de Ven M, Radu M, Despa S, Lambrichts I, Ameloot M, Steels P, and Smets I Role of mitochondrial na+ concentration, measured by CoroNa red, in the protection of metabolically inhibited MDCK cells. J Am Soc Nephrol, 16(12):3490, 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16221870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh AJ, Mueller K, Tweed K, Jones I, Walsh CM, Piscopo N, Niemi NM, Pagliarini DJ, Saha K, and Skala MC Classification of T-cell activation via autofluorescence lifetime imaging. Nature biomedical engineering, 5(1):77&#x2013;88, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filon MJ, Gillette AA, Yang B, Khemees TA, Skala MC, and Jarrard DF Prostate cancer cells demonstrate unique metabolism and substrate adaptability acutely after androgen deprivation therapy. 82(16):1547&#x2013;1557, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathibhatla A, Henkes S, Galles EE, Sknepnek R, and Notbohm J Coordinated tractions increase the size of a collectively moving pack in a cell monolayer. Extreme Mech Lett, 48:101438, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakes R and Drugan W Dramatically stiffer elastic composite materials due to a negative stiffness phase? J Mech Phys Solids, 50(5):979&#x2013;1009, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaglinski T, Kochmann D, Stone D, and Lakes RS Composite materials with viscoelastic stiffness greater than diamond. Science, 315(5812):620&#x2013;622, 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17272714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wensink HH, Dunkel J, Heidenreich S, Drescher K, Goldstein RE, L&#xf6;wen H, and Yeomans JM Meso-scale turbulence in living fluids. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 109(36):14308&#x2013;14313, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossen NS, Tarp JM, Mathiesen J, Jensen MH, and Oddershede LB Long-range ordered vorticity patterns in living tissue induced by cell division. Nat Commun, 5(1):5720, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4268690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25483750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart AG, Amaral LA, and Ottino JM Cascading failure and robustness in metabolic networks. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 105(36):13223&#x2013;13228, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelling J, Sauer U, Szallasi Z, Doyle FJ, and Doyle J Robustness of cellular functions. Cell, 118(6):675&#x2013;685, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15369668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitacre JM Biological robustness: paradigms, mechanisms, and systems principles. Front Genet, 3:67, 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3350086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22593762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBerardinis RJ and Chandel NS Fundamentals of cancer metabolism. Sci Adv, 2(5):e1600200, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4928883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27386546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergers G and Fendt S-M The metabolism of cancer cells during metastasis. Nat Rev Cancer, 21(3):162&#x2013;180, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8733955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Zhao F, Xu C, Zhang Q, Ren H, Huang X, He C, Ma J, and Wang Z Metabolic reprogramming in skin wound healing. Burns &amp; Trauma, 12:tkad047, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10762507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38179472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwata R and Vanderhaeghen P Metabolic mechanisms of species-specific developmental tempo. Dev Cell, 59(13):1628&#x2013;1639, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11266843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38906137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Kochba E, Toyjanova J, Andrews E, Kim K-S, and Franck C A fast iterative digital volume correlation algorithm for large deformations. Exp Mech, 55(1):261&#x2013;274, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler JP, Tolic-Norrelykke IM, Fabry B, and Fredberg JJ Traction fields, moments, and strain energy that cells exert on their surroundings. Am J Physiol Cell Ph, 282(3):C595&#x2013;C605, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Alamo JC, Meili R, Alonso-Latorre B, Rodriguez-Rodriguez J, Aliseda A, Firtel RA, and Lasheras JC Spatio-temporal analysis of eukaryotic cell motility by improved force cytometry. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 104(33):13343&#x2013;13348, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J.Vromans A and Giomi L. Orientational properties of nematic disclinations. Soft Matter, 12(30):6490&#x2013;6495, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27418339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smets I, Caplanusi A, Despa S, Molnar Z, Radu M, vandeVen M, Ameloot M, and Steels P
Ca<sup>2+</sup> uptake in mitochondria occurs via the reverse action of the Na<sup>2+</sup>/Ca<sup>2+</sup> exchanger in metabolically inhibited MDCK cells. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol, 286(4):F784&#x2013;F794, 2003.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14665432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi D, Yang X, Marchetti MC, and Manning ML Motility-driven glass and jamming transitions in biological tissues. Phys Rev X, 6(2):021011, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5619672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28966874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>