<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41632795</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Path planning for UAVs in complex terrain based on the PGD model: Algorithmic improvements combining feature extraction and reinforcement learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0340394</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0340394</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0340394</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0340394</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper proposes the PGD model for UAV path planning in complex terrain, addressing key challenges such as high-dimensional state processing, blind path exploration, and poor cross-scene adaptability. The PGD model integrates Transformer, GAN, and DDPG, forming a "compression-generation-optimization" closed-loop system. The Transformer module compresses high-dimensional terrain data, alleviating training bottlenecks, while the GAN module generates high-quality candidate paths, reducing ineffective exploration. DDPG then optimizes the path planning strategy efficiently. Experimental results demonstrate the superior performance of PGD on the UAVDT (suburban) and AirSim (canyon) datasets. In terms of path length (Pl), PGD achieves 20.0m/22.0m, compared to baseline models such as PPO-DRL (23.8m) and Soft Actor-Critic (24.0m). PGD also outperforms in collision rate (Cr) with 2.5%/3.0% and computational efficiency (Tc) with 13.5s/16.0s, respectively. The PGD model shows significant improvements in path planning efficiency and adaptability, particularly in high-complexity terrains. Compared to traditional models, PGD's multi-module synergy enhances feature correlation and physical path constraints, offering a novel framework for intelligent planning in complex environments. Future work will focus on enhancing model adaptability to extreme weather and multi-agent collaborative scenarios.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Liu et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Liangshuai</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-9458-0582</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Hebei Electric Power Research Institute, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaofeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Hebei Electric Power Research Institute, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Lingming</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Hebei Electric Power Research Institute, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yuntao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Hebei Electric Power Research Institute, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Yaya</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Hebei Electric Power Research Institute, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000088722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Unmanned Aerial Devices</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Theoretical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41632795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12867270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0340394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-45573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma Z, Chen J. Adaptive path planning method for UAVs in complex environments. Int J Appl Earth Observ Geoinform. 2022;115:103133. doi: 10.1016/j.jag.2022.103133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jag.2022.103133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Li J, Yang H, Feng X, Sun G. Complex environment path planning for unmanned aerial vehicles. Sensors (Basel). 2021;21(15):5250. doi: 10.3390/s21155250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21155250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8347258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xuzhao C, Zhishuai Z, Junming X, Li Y, Boyang Q, Pengwei E, et al. Multi-strategy fusion differential evolution algorithm for UAV path planning in complex environment. Aerosp Sci Technol. 2022;121:107287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Chen J, Lv L, Yu Z, Yao W, Cheng H, et al. Design and verification of a wearable microcapacitance test system for POC biosensing. IEEE Trans Instrum Meas. 2025;74:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1109/tim.2025.3555726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tim.2025.3555726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi H, Hu Z, Yang Z, Zhang J, Wu JJ, Cheng C, et al. Capacitive aptasensor coupled with microfluidic enrichment for real-time detection of trace SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid protein. Anal Chem. 2022;94(6):2812&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1021/acs.analchem.1c04296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.analchem.1c04296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34982528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing X, Wang B, Ning X, Wang G, Tiwari P. Short-term OD flow prediction for urban rail transit control: A multi-graph spatiotemporal fusion approach. Inform Fusion. 2025;118:102950. doi: 10.1016/j.inffus.2025.102950</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2025.102950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y. Multi-UAV search and rescue with enhanced A* algorithm path planning in 3D environment. Int J Aerospace Eng. 2023;2023(1):8614117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li Y, Li R, Chen H, Chu K. Trajectory planning for UAV navigation in dynamic environments with matrix alignment Dijkstra. Soft Comput. 2022;26(22):12599&#x2013;610. doi: 10.1007/s00500-022-07224-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00500-022-07224-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad NL, Ramkumar B. 3-D deployment and trajectory planning for relay based UAV assisted cooperative communication for emergency scenarios using Dijkstra&#x2019;s algorithm. IEEE Trans Veh Technol. 2023;72(4):5049&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1109/tvt.2022.3224304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tvt.2022.3224304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shynar Y, Seitenov A, Kenzhegarina A, Kenzhetayev A, Kemel A, Ualiyev N, et al. Comprehensive analysis of blockchain technology in the healthcare sector and its security implications. Int J E-Health Med Commun. 2025;16(1):1&#x2013;45. doi: 10.4018/ijehmc.372423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/ijehmc.372423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodipalli A, Fernandes SL, Dasar SK, Ismail T. Computational framework of inverted fuzzy C-means and quantum convolutional neural network towards accurate detection of ovarian tumors. Int J E-Health Med Commun. 2023;14(1):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.4018/ijehmc.321149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/ijehmc.321149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Liu Z, Cui H, Ma N, Wang H, Zhang C, et al. An electrified railway catenary component anomaly detection frame based on invariant normal region prototype with segment anything model. IEEE Trans Transp Electrific. 2025:1&#x2013;1. doi: 10.1109/tte.2025.3628607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tte.2025.3628607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Liu X, Liu X, Yang Y, Zhang W. FC-RRT*: An improved path planning algorithm for UAV in 3D complex environment. IJGI. 2022;11(2):112. doi: 10.3390/ijgi11020112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijgi11020112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, An Y, Cao J, Ouyang S, Wang L. UAV trajectory planning for complex open storage environments based on an improved RRT algorithm. IEEE Access. 2023;11:23189&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1109/access.2023.3252018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2023.3252018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Song Y, Yang H, Liu Z. Generalized koopman neural operator for data-driven modeling of electric railway pantograph&#x2013;catenary systems. IEEE Trans Transp Electrific. 2025;11(6):14100&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1109/tte.2025.3609347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tte.2025.3609347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Hu J, Zhang B, Ning X, Wu L. Dynamic personalized federated learning for cross-spectral palmprint recognition. IEEE Trans Image Process. 2025;34:4885&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1109/TIP.2025.3592508</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2025.3592508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40737152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao M, Gu Y, Dong K, Tiwari P, Lv X, Ning X. A prompt regularization approach to enhance few-shot class-incremental learning with Two-Stage Classifier. Neural Netw. 2025;188:107453. doi: 10.1016/j.neunet.2025.107453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neunet.2025.107453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40220563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao J, Ning X, Hong S, Wang L, Liu B. Secure and efficient authentication protocol for supply chain systems in artificial-intelligence-based internet of things. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12(19):39532&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2025.3592401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2025.3592401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshad MA, Khan SH, Qamar S, Khan MW, Murtza I, Gwak J, et al. Drone navigation using region and edge exploitation-based deep CNN. IEEE Access. 2022;10:95441&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1109/access.2022.3204876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2022.3204876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Z, Fengpu L, Bin L. A heuristic tomato-bunch harvest manipulator path planning method based on a 3D-CNN-based position posture map and rapidly-exploring random tree. Comput Electron Agric. 2023;213:108183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying L, Xiaodan W, Yang Y, Man D, Shaochun Q, Yanfang F. LSTM-DQN-APF path planning algorithm empowered by twins in complex scenarios. Appl Sci. 2025;15(8):4565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Qi N, Li X, Xiao M, Boulogeorgos AA-A, Tsiftsis TT, et al. Distributed multi-UAV trajectory planning for downlink transmission: A GNN-enhanced DRL approach. IEEE Wireless Commun Lett. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuhao P, Xiucheng W, Zhiyao X, Nan C, Wenchao X, Jun-Jie Z. GNN-empowered effective partial observation MARL method for AoI management in multi-UAV network. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shasha T, Yuanxiang L, Xiao Z, Lu Z, Linhui C, Wei S, et al. Fast UAV path planning in urban environments based on three-step experience buffer sampling DDPG. Digit Commun Netw. 2024;10(4):813&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruichang W, Weijun H, Xianlong M. Research on the method of trajectory planning for unmanned aerial vehicles in complex terrains based on reinforcement learning. In: Int Conf Intell Robotics Appl., Springer; 2024. p. 287&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai R, Bai B. The impact of labor productivity and social production scale on profit-induced demand: Function and analysis from the perspective of Marx&#x2019;s economic theory. J Xi&#x2019;an Univ Finance Econ. 2024;37(5):3&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMatteo C, Jakubowski J, Stazyk K, Randall S, Perrotta S, Zhang R. The headaches of developing a concussion app for youth. Int J E-Health Med Commun. 2024;15(1):1&#x2013;20. doi: 10.4018/ijehmc.352514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/ijehmc.352514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C-H, Tsai J, Chang Y-T. Intelligent path planning for UAV patrolling in dynamic environments based on the transformer architecture. Electronics. 2024;13(23):4716. doi: 10.3390/electronics13234716</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics13234716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almayyan WI, AlGhannam BA. Detection of kidney diseases: Importance of feature selection and classifiers. IJEHMC. 2024;15(1):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z, Xiong J, Gong H, Wang X. Mission planning of UAVs and CAVs based on graph neural networks transformer model. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskandari Mohsen, Savkin AndreyV. GANs the UAV path planner: UAV-based RIS-assisted wireless communication for Internet of Autonomous Vehicles. In: 2024 IEEE 19th Conf Ind Electron Appl (ICIEA); 2024. p. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zan L, Xiaomin L, Jia S, Li L, Pei X. MD-GAN-based UAV trajectory and power optimization for cognitive covert communications. IEEE Internet Things J. 2021;9(12):10187&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng W, Prabhash R, Vougioukas SG, Kong Z. Vision-based navigation of unmanned aerial vehicles in orchards: An imitation learning approach. Comput Electron Agric. 2025;238:110802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elizabeth B, Debadeepta D, Ashish K, Jim P, Shital S, Fei F, et al. Airsim-w: A simulation environment for wildlife conservation with uavs. In: Proc 1st ACM SIGCAS Conf Comput Sustain Soc.; 2018. p. 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawei D, Yuankai Q, Hongyang Y, Yifan Y, Kaiwen D, Guorong L, et al. The unmanned aerial vehicle benchmark: Object detection and tracking. In: Proc Eur Conf Comput Vis (ECCV); 2018. p. 370&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu B, Bedeer E, Nguyen HH, Barton R, Gao Z. UAV trajectory planning for AoI-minimal data collection in UAV-aided IoT networks by transformer. IEEE Trans Wireless Commun. 2022;22(2):1343&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1109/TWC.2022.3141234</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TWC.2022.3141234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonado-Romo J, Aldape-P&#xe9;rez M, Rodr&#xed;guez-Molina A. Path planning generator with metadata through a domain change by GAN between physical and virtual environments. Sensors (Basel). 2021;21(22):7667. doi: 10.3390/s21227667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21227667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8623835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34833741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Peng J, Yi W, Lin H, Lei L, Song X. A state-decomposition DDPG algorithm for UAV autonomous navigation in 3-D complex environments. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;11(6):10778&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2023.3327753</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2023.3327753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jinyan Y, Yongbai S, Yanli C, Guoqing Z, Xinyu H, Guiqiang B, et al. IHSSAO: An improved hybrid salp swarm algorithm and aquila optimizer for UAV path planning in complex terrain. Appl Sci. 2022;12(11):5634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feiyu Z, Dayan L, Zhengxu W, Jianlin M, Niya W. Autonomous localized path planning algorithm for UAVs based on TD3 strategy. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):763. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-51349-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-51349-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10774288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38191590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvirianti, Narottama B, Shin SY. UAV coverage path planning with quantum-based recurrent deep deterministic policy gradient. IEEE Trans Veh Technol. 2024;73(5):7424&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1109/tvt.2023.3347219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tvt.2023.3347219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Runjia W, Fangqing G, Hai-lin L, Hongjian S. UAV path planning based on multicritic-delayed deep deterministic policy gradient. Wirel Commun Mobile Comput. 2022 ;2022:9017079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirco T, Harald B, Marco C, Sangiovanni-Vincentelli AL. Learning to recharge: UAV coverage path planning through deep reinforcement learning. arXiv preprint arXiv:2309.03157. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonny A, Yeduri SR, Cenkeramaddi LR. Autonomous UAV path planning using modified PSO for UAV-assisted wireless networks. IEEE Access. 2023;11:70353&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1109/access.2023.3293203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2023.3293203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhuheir MA, Baccour E, Erbad A, Al-Obaidi SS, Hamdi M. Deep reinforcement learning for trajectory path planning and distributed inference in resource-constrained UAV swarms. IEEE Internet Things J. 2023;10(9):8185&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2022.3231341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2022.3231341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Gursoy MC, Erpek T, Sagduyu YE. Learning-based UAV path planning for data collection with integrated collision avoidance. IEEE Internet Things J. 2022;9(17):16663&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2022.3153585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2022.3153585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Liu G, Zhou Z, Wang J. Partially observable mean field multi-agent reinforcement learning based on graph attention network for UAV swarms. Drones. 2023;7(7):476. doi: 10.3390/drones7070476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones7070476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonas W, Julius R, Marija P. Multi-UAV adaptive path planning using deep reinforcement learning. In: 2023 IEEE/RSJ Int Conf Intell Robots Syst (IROS); 2023. p. 649&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiaping X, Wen TC, Yuhang Z, Mir F. FM-planner: Foundation model guided path planning for autonomous drone navigation. arXiv preprint arXiv:2505.20783. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahya R, Hamed H, Holger V, et al. UAV path planning employing MPC-reinforcement learning method considering collision avoidance. arXiv preprint arXiv:2302.10669. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Z, Liu Z, Li Z, Wang K, Vong C-M. Lightweight fault diagnosis via Siamese network for few-shot EHA circuit analysis. IEEE Trans Aerosp Electron Syst. 2025;61(6):15585&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1109/taes.2025.3589534</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/taes.2025.3589534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren X, Wang S, Zhao W, Kong X, Fan M, Shao H, et al. Universal federated domain adaptation for gearbox fault diagnosis: A robust framework for credible pseudo-label generation. Adv Eng Inform. 2025;65:103233. doi: 10.1016/j.aei.2025.103233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aei.2025.103233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>