<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41865224</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A predictive model for PICC-related thrombosis in sepsis patients using XGBoost algorithm.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-44999-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Percutaneous insertion of central venous catheters (PICC) is critical for the management of sepsis patients requiring prolonged intravenous therapy; however, it poses significant complications, including thrombosis. Identifying risk factors for PICC-related thrombosis can enhance clinical management and patient outcomes. This study aimed to develop a predictive model for PICC-related thrombosis in sepsis patients using the XGBoost algorithm. We analyzed data from 8,128 ICU patients diagnosed with sepsis and using PICC from the Medical Information Mart for Intensive Care IV version 3.1 (MIMIC-IV 3.1) database. Patients were divided into a training set (70%, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;5690) and a validation set (30%, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2438). Variables included demographic, laboratory, and clinical factors potentially associated with PICC-related thrombosis. An XGBoost model was developed and validated, with performance assessed using the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC) and SHAP analysis for interpretability. Decision curve analysis confirmed the clinical utility of the model. The XGBoost model achieved an AUC of 0.761 (95% CI 0.734-0.787) in the training set and 0.766 (95% CI 0.731-0.801) in the validation set. The calibration curve demonstrated good calibration of the model, indicating that predicted probabilities of thrombosis closely aligned with observed outcome. Decision curve analysis confirmed clinical utility, yielding a net benefit of 0.31 at 20% risk threshold, outperforming treat-all/none strategies. Key predictors, including white blood cell count, platelet count, history of myocardial infarction, hemoglobin levels, creatinine levels, PICC indwelling time, age, presence of mild liver disease and prothrombin time (PT), and diabetes without chronic complications, were identified using SHAP analysis in the XGBoost predictive model for PICC-related thrombosis, with the top ten predictors significantly contributing to the model's performance. The XGBoost model is an effective predictor of PICC-related thrombosis among sepsis patients, indicating its potential role in guiding clinical decision-making for the management of high-risk patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hao</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intensive Care Unit, National Cancer Center/National Clinical Research Center for Cancer/Cancer Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, 100021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>She</LastName><ForeName>Tian-Yu</ForeName><Initials>TY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging Function, Xi'an Electric Power Central Hospital, Xi'an, 710032, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Zhen-Nan</ForeName><Initials>ZN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Intensive Care Unit, National Cancer Center/National Clinical Research Center for Cancer/Cancer Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, 100021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Li-Na</ForeName><Initials>LN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, The Second Hospital of Hebei Medical University, Shijiazhuang, 050000, Hebei, China. LiulinaHB2H@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Hui-Ling</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, The Affiliated Hospital of Youjiang Medical University for Nationalities, Baise, 533000, Guangxi, China. fuguiqq@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Research and Development on Clinical Molecular Diagnosis for High-Incidence Diseases of Baise, Baise, 533000, Guangxi, China. fuguiqq@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PICC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sepsis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thrombosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XGBoost</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The data in this study is based solely on publicly available, de-identified data from MIMIC-IV. After completing Collaborative Institutional Training Initiative (CITI program: 68902439), we got permission to access the database. This study involves no direct human participation occurred and that IRB exemption was granted due to the nature of the dataset.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41865224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-44999-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-44999-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wheeler, D. S. Oxidative stress in critically ill children with sepsis. Open Inflamm. J. 4(s1), 74&#x2013;81 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad, R. A. Use of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients with severe sepsis or septic shock. Am. J. Health-Syst. Pharm. 67(15), 1238&#x2013;1245 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camara, D. Minimizing risks associated with peripherally inserted central catheters in the NICU. MCN Am. J. Matern. Child Nurs. 26(1), 17&#x2013;21 (2001) (quiz 22).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuliffe, E., O&#x2019;Shea, S. &amp; Khan, M. I. PO-02 - Retrospective audit of the peripherally inserted central catheter (PICC) associated thrombosis in patients with haematological malignancies at Cork University Hospital. Thromb. Res. 140(Suppl 1), S176 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Peripherally inserted central catheter thrombosis incidence and risk factors in cancer patients: A double-center prospective investigation. Ther. Clin. Risk Manag. 11, 153&#x2013;160 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zochios, V., Umar, I., Simpson, N. &amp; Jones, N. Peripherally inserted central catheter (PICC)-related thrombosis in critically ill patients. J. Vasc. Access 15(5), 329&#x2013;337 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, N. et al. Nomogram predicted risk of peripherally inserted central catheter related thrombosis. Sci. Rep. 7(1), 6344 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, L., Zhao, Q. &amp; Yang, X. Risk factors for venous thrombosis associated with peripherally inserted central venous catheters. Int. J. Clin. Exp. Med. 7(12), 5814&#x2013;5819 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares, F. M. et al. Design, construction, and validation of obstetric risk classification systems to predict intensive care unit admission. Int. J. Gynaecol. Obstet. 167(3), 1243&#x2013;1254 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabbad, D. A. et al. Machine learning model for predicting the length of stay in the intensive care unit for Covid-19 patients in the eastern province of Saudi Arabia. Inform. Med. Unlocked 30, 100937 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso, M. M. A. et al. Application of natural language processing to predict final recommendation of Brazilian health technology assessment reports. Int. J. Technol. Assess. Health Care 40(1), e19 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, L., Alhulwah, K. H., Hanif, M. F., Siddiqui, M. K. &amp; Ikram, A. S. On QSPR analysis of glaucoma drugs using machine learning with XGBoost and regression models. Comput. Biol. Med. 187, 109731 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, G., Liu, W., Da, X., Li, Z. &amp; Pu, J. The natural flavonoid pinocembrin shows antithrombotic activity and suppresses septic thrombosis. Int. Immunopharmacol. 142(Pt B), 113237 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhodes, A. et al. Surviving Sepsis Campaign: International Guidelines for Management of Sepsis and Septic Shock: 2016. Intensive Care Med 43(3), 304&#x2013;377 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L., Lu, Y., Wang, L., Pan, Y. &amp; Zhou, X. Construction of a nomogram risk prediction model for PICC-related venous thrombosis and its application. Asian J. Surg. 47(1), 107&#x2013;111 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, D. W. &amp; Ly, S. Y. Diagnostic recognition of Escherichia coli septicemia in in vivo vascular blood. Med. Chem. 11(6), 590&#x2013;594 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X. et al. Behcet&#x2019;s disease complicated with thrombosis: A report of 93 Chinese cases. Medicine (Baltimore) 93(28), e263 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D. et al. Incidence of thrombosis at different sites during the follow-up period in essential thrombocythemia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin. Appl. Thromb. Hemost. 29, 10760296231181117 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez-Larran, A. et al. Application of IPSET-thrombosis in 1366 patients prospectively followed from the Spanish Registry of Essential Thrombocythemia. Hemasphere 7(8), e936 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, C. Y. et al. Prediction models for COVID-19 disease outcomes. Emerg. Microbes Infect. 13(1), 2361791 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calzadilla-Bertot, L. et al. Predicting liver-related events in NAFLD: A predictive model. Hepatology 78(4), 1240&#x2013;1251 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. et al. aCCI-HBV-ACLF: A novel predictive model for Hepatitis B virus-related acute-on-chronic liver failure. Aliment. Pharmacol. Ther. 61(2), 286&#x2013;298 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal, A. et al. Hypercoagulability in end-stage liver disease: Prevalence and its correlation with severity of liver disease and portal vein thrombosis. Clin. Appl. Thromb. Hemost. 18(6), 594&#x2013;598 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Ghumlas, A. K. &amp; AbdelGader, A. G. The liver and the haemeostatic system. Saudi J. Gastroenterol. 9(2), 59&#x2013;68 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peck-Radosavljevic, M. Review article: Coagulation disorders in chronic liver disease. Aliment. Pharmacol. Ther. 26(Suppl 1), 21&#x2013;28 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez-Mon, M. et al. A predictive model and risk factors for case fatality of COVID-19. J. Pers. Med. https://doi.org/10.3390/jpm11010036 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadani, A., Wang, T., van Zon, K. &amp; Celi, L. A. VAP risk index: Early prediction and hospital phenotyping of ventilator-associated pneumonia using machine learning. Artif. Intell. Med. 146, 102715 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Y. et al. Development and validation of a predictive model for acute kidney injury in patients with ureterolithiasis. Ren. Fail. 46(2), 2394634 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, S. C. et al. Comparison of sepsis definitions as automated criteria. Crit. Care Med. 49(4), e433&#x2013;e443 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, D. et al. Correlation of clinical sepsis definitions with microbiological characteristics in patients admitted through a sepsis alert system; A prospective cohort study. Ann. Clin. Microbiol. Antimicrob. 21(1), 7 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lengquist, M. et al. Sepsis mimics among presumed sepsis patients at intensive care admission: A retrospective observational study. Infection 52(3), 1041&#x2013;1053 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nifong, T. P. &amp; McDevitt, T. J. The effect of catheter to vein ratio on blood flow rates in a simulated model of peripherally inserted central venous catheters. Chest 140(1), 48&#x2013;53 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns, K. E. &amp; McLaren, A. Catheter-related right atrial thrombus and pulmonary embolism: A case report and systematic review of the literature. Can. Respir. J. 16(5), 163&#x2013;165 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P., Wang, C. &amp; Pang, S. The diagnostic accuracy of mid-regional pro-adrenomedullin for sepsis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Minerva Anestesiol. 87(10), 1117&#x2013;1127 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, K. &amp; Cao, T. Automated HIV Case Identification from the MIMIC-IV Database. AMIA Jt Summits Transl Sci Proc 2024, 555&#x2013;564 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. Identification of clinical subphenotypes of sepsis after laparoscopic surgery. Laparosc. Endosc. Robot. Surg. 7(1), 16&#x2013;26 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. A comprehensive step-by-step approach for the implementation of target trial emulation: Evaluating fluid resuscitation strategies in post-laparoscopic septic shock as an example. Laparosc. Endosc. Robot. Surg. 8(1), 28&#x2013;44 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>