<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41895634</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-6424</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>397</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental pollution (Barking, Essex : 1987)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Pollut</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Salinity modulates the toxicity of benzotriazole UV stabilizer in sediment to gut microbiota of Corbicula fluminea.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>128023</StartPage><MedlinePgn>128023</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.envpol.2026.128023</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0269-7491(26)00393-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Benzotriazole ultraviolet stabilizers (BUVSs) are widespread emerging pollutants in sediments. However, studies on the effects of BUVSs on benthic gut microbiota, particularly under co-exposure with salinity fluctuations, remain underexplored. This is significant as salinity is a contributing factor to saline intrusion attributed to climate change. Therefore, this research was conducted to investigate the combined effects of benzotriazole ultraviolet stabilizer-329 (UV-329) and salinity on the gut microbiota of Corbicula fluminea in sediments. The metabolic function of gut microbiota evaluated by Biolog ECO microplates showed that co-exposure to UV-329 and salt stress reduced microbial metabolic activity (from 0.731 to 0.192, average well color development). Self-organizing map algorithm further revealed shifts in carbon sources utilization, with salt stress exerting a greater metabolic influence compared to UV-329. Compared to UV-329, co-exposure was more conducive to the survival of pathogens (e.g., Mycoplasma). Molecular docking demonstrated that UV-329-Na complexes had a stronger binding affinity for diamine oxidase than UV-329 alone, suggesting a mechanistic basis for enhanced intestinal inflammation under combined stress. Microbial source tracking indicated an increased proportion of gut bacteria originating from sediments (from 16.2% to 26.4%) under UV-329 and salt stress. Neutral community model and null model analyses revealed that stochastic processes dominated gut microbial assembly, and co-exposure reduced bacterial immigration rate compared to UV-329 exposure. These results highlight that salinity modulates the toxicity of UV-329 by exacerbating gut microbiota dysbiosis, impairing intestinal barrier function, and altering the probability of bacterial dispersal.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Ecology and Environment, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou, 450046, China; Key Laboratory of Integrated Regulation and Resources Development on Shallow Lakes of Ministry of Education, College of Environment, Hohai University, Nanjing, 210098, China; Yellow River Laboratory (Henan), Zhengzhou, 450046, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Peifang</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Integrated Regulation and Resources Development on Shallow Lakes of Ministry of Education, College of Environment, Hohai University, Nanjing, 210098, China; Collaborative Innovation Center for Efficient Utilization of Water Resources, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou, 450046, China; Yellow River Laboratory (Henan), Zhengzhou, 450046, China. Electronic address: pfwang2005@hhu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Integrated Regulation and Resources Development on Shallow Lakes of Ministry of Education, College of Environment, Hohai University, Nanjing, 210098, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Qiutong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Integrated Regulation and Resources Development on Shallow Lakes of Ministry of Education, College of Environment, Hohai University, Nanjing, 210098, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Haihua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Ecology and Environment, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou, 450046, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Pollut</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804476</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0269-7491</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-exposure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gut microbiota</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Salt stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UV-329</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41895634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2026.128023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0269-7491(26)00393-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>