<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41449205</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing healthcare classification with hybrid multimedia data processing and deep learning TNBO FCNN approach in IoT-enabled environments.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3286</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3286</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3286</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-33141-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid expansion of IoT-based healthcare systems has led to an explosion of multimodal patient data (e.g., voice, images, signals), raising concerns about accurate classification, real-time processing, and data security. Existing machine learning approaches often suffer from limited feature extraction, high computational demands, and inadequate privacy protection, particularly in decentralised and resource-constrained environments. Furthermore, the lack of robust routing and data integrity mechanisms hinders their deployment in real-world healthcare applications. To address these challenges, we propose a hybrid deep learning framework that integrates Tunable Nonlinear Bayesian Optimisation (TNBO) for efficient routing and hyper-parameter tuning with a Fully Connected Neural Network (FCNN) for robust classification of multimodal healthcare data. Additionally, we embed blockchain technology to ensure the security, transparency, and immutability of patient data across decentralised IoT environments. Our method demonstrates superior performance in terms of accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity when compared to traditional models such as RTS-DELM and SCA_WKNN. We optimise the proposed architecture for energy efficiency, scalability, and real-time healthcare monitoring, positioning it for deployment in telemedicine and smart healthcare systems. Experimental validation on benchmark datasets confirms the efficacy of our model, while ethical implications and future research directions are also discussed to support broader applicability. The performance of the proposed model was evaluated against existing state-of-the-art techniques, including Hybrid Multimedia Data Processing, RTS-DELM, Multimedia Data Sharing Systems, and SCA_WKNN. The results indicated that the TNBO&#x2009;+&#x2009;FCNN model achieved an accuracy of 0.924, a sensitivity of 0.921, and a specificity of 0.926. Furthermore, the model outperformed comparative approaches by significant margins, achieving an F1-score of 0.915 and an area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC-ROC) of 0.950. These findings validate the proposed model's effectiveness in enhancing healthcare data classification, making it a promising solution for real-time monitoring and decision-making in healthcare systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chourasiya</LastName><ForeName>Leeladhar</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Acropolis Institute of Technology and Research, Indore, MP, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lillohre</LastName><ForeName>Umesh Kumar</ForeName><Initials>UK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computing Science and Engineering, Galgotias University, Greater Noida, UP, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandey</LastName><ForeName>Abhishek Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computing Science and Engineering, Galgotias University, Greater Noida, UP, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simaiya</LastName><ForeName>Sarita</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Applications &amp; Technology, Galgotias University, Greater Noida, UP, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussien</LastName><ForeName>Shimaa A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering, Princess Nourah Bint Abdulrahman University, P.O. Box 84428, 11671, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghith</LastName><ForeName>Ehab Seif</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechatronics, Faculty of Engineering, Ain Shams University, Cairo, 11566, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Monish</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arba Minch University, Arba Minch, Ethiopia. drkumacse@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077321" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deep Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multimedia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000080487" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internet of Things</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="N">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016494" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Security</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FCNN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid multimedia data processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IoT-enabled healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TNBO</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41449205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12835001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-33141-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-33141-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shammi, S. A. et al. Advances in artificial intelligence and block chain technologies for early detection of human diseases.&#xa0;<i>IEEE Trans. Comput. Soc. Syst.</i> (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taloba, A. I. et al. A block chain-based hybrid platform for multimedia data processing in IoT healthcare. <i>Alexandria Eng. J.</i><b>65</b>, 263&#x2013;274 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2022.09.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehman, A. et al. A secure healthcare 5.0 system based on block chain technology entangled with federated learning technique. <i>Comput. Biol. Med.</i><b>150</b>, 106019 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2022.106019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36162198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, Y. et al. Integration of artificial intelligence, block chain, and wearable technology for chronic disease management: A new paradigm in smart healthcare. <i>Curr. Med. Sci.</i><b>41</b>, 1123&#x2013;1133 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11596-021-2485-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8702375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34950987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi, P., Zhang, X., Wang, L., Liu, W. &amp; Peng, S. A review of block chain-based secure sharing of healthcare data. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 7912. 10.3390/app12157912 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12157912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanova, H., Tufail, M., Baek, U. J., Park, J. T. &amp; Kim, M. S. A novel block chain-enabled heart disease prediction mechanism using machine learning. <i>Comput. Electr. Eng.</i><b>101</b>, 108086 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2022.108086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanwar, S., Parekh, K. &amp; Evans, R. Block chain-based electronic healthcare record system for healthcare 4.0 applications. <i>J Inf.</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, V., Gupta, A., Hasan, U. N., Shabaz, M. &amp; Ofori, I. Block chain in secure healthcare systems: state of the art, limitations, and future directions. <i>Secur. Communication Networks</i>. 10.1155/2023/9827513 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/9827513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Aguiar, E. J. &amp; Fai&#xe7;al, S. B. A survey of block chain-based strategies for healthcare.&#xa0;<i>ACM Comput. Surv.</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel, A. &amp; Neduncheliyan, S. An intelligent block chain strategy for decentralized healthcare framework. <i>Peer-to-Peer Netw. Appl.</i><b>16</b>, 846&#x2013;857. 10.1007/s12083-022-01429-x (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12083-022-01429-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9847450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36687767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahardoli, M., Eraghi, N. O. &amp; Nazari, S. Namib beetle optimization algorithm: A new meta-heuristic method for feature selection and dimension reduction. <i>Concurr. Comput.: Pract. Exp.</i><b>34</b>(1), e6524 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpe.6524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Movassagh, A. A. et al. Artificial neural networks training algorithm integrating invasive weed optimization with differential evolutionary model. <i>J. Ambient Intell. Humaniz. Comput.</i>10.1007/s12652-020-02623-6 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12652-020-02623-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakrashi, A. &amp; Chaudhuri, B. B. A Kalman filtering-induced heuristic optimization-based partitional data clustering. <i>Inf. Sci.</i><b>369</b>, 704&#x2013;717 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ins.2016.07.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faragallah, O. S. Robust noise MKMFCC&#x2013;SVM automatic speaker identification. <i>Int. J. Speech Technol.</i><b>21</b>, 185&#x2013;192 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10772-018-9494-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maria, A. &amp; Jeyaseelan, A. S. Development of optimal feature selection and deep learning toward hungry stomach detection using audio signals. <i>J. Control Autom. Electr. Syst.</i><b>32</b> (4), 853&#x2013;874 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40313-021-00727-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheshan, C. M. &amp; Prasanna Kumar, H. Performance of image pre-processing filters for noise removal in transformer oil images at different temperatures. <i>SN Appl. Sci.</i><b>2</b>, 1&#x2013;7 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-019-1800-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guermoui, M. &amp; Mekhalfi, M. L. A sparse representation of complete local binary pattern histogram for human face recognition. <i>ArXiv Preprint arXiv</i> :160509584 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bay, H., Ess, A., Tuytelaars, T. &amp; Van Gool, L. Speeded-up robust features (SURF). <i>Comput. Vis. Image Underst.</i><b>110</b> (3), 346&#x2013;359 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cviu.2007.09.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani, P., Kaur, P., Jain, V., Shokeen, J. &amp; Nain, S. Block chain-based IoT-enabled health monitoring system. <i>J. Supercomputing</i>. <b>78</b> (15), 17284&#x2013;17308 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-022-04584-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, R., Wang, N., Liu, Z., Chen, P. &amp; Sheng, X. Intrusion detection system in the advanced metering infrastructure: A cross-layer feature-fusion CNN-LSTM-based approach. <i>Sensors</i><b>21</b> (2), 626 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21020626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7830526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33477451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soenksen, L. R. et al. Integrated multimodal artificial intelligence framework for healthcare applications. <i>NPJ Digit. Med.</i><b>5</b> (1), 149 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-022-00689-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9489871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36127417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazir, S., Kaleem, M., Hamdoun, H., Alzubi, J. &amp; Hua, T. Block chain of things for healthcare asset management. <i>IET Appl.</i>, 181&#x2013;198 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzubi, O. A., Alzubi, J. A., Shankar, K. &amp; Gupta, D. Blockchain and artificial intelligence enabled privacy-preserving medical data transmission in Internet of Things. <i>Trans. Emerg. Telecommun. Technol.</i><b>32</b>(12), e4360 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ett.4360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seh, A. H. et al. Healthcare data breaches: insights and implications. <i>Healthcare</i><b>8</b> (2), 133 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare8020133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32414183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzubi, J. A. Block chain-based Lamport Merkle digital signature: authentication tool in IoT healthcare. <i>Comput. Commun.</i><b>170</b>, 200&#x2013;208 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comcom.2021.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, K. Advancing hospital healthcare: achieving IoT-based secure health monitoring through multilayer machine learning. <i>J. Big Data</i>. <b>12</b> (1), 1 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-024-01038-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J., Feng, G. &amp; Wang, Y. Optimal deployment mechanism of block chain in resource-constrained IoT systems. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>9</b> (11), 8168&#x2013;8177 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2021.3106355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khairandish, M. O., Sharma, M., Jain, V., Chatterjee, J. M. &amp; Jhanjhi, N. Z. A hybrid CNN-SVM threshold segmentation approach for tumor detection and classification of MRI brain images. <i>IRBM</i><b>43</b> (4), 290&#x2013;299 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.irbm.2021.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishwakarma, V. P. &amp; Yadav, A. K. MKD-Net: A novel neuro-evolutionary approach for block chain-based secure medical image classification using multi-kernel DLM.&#xa0;<i>IEEE Access</i>&#xa0;(2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey, B. et al. Design and build block chain-based privacy preservation and disease prediction using CNN model. In <i>2024 International Conference on Advances in Computing Research on Science Engineering and Technology (ACROSET)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahal, H. R., Slatnia, S., Kazar, O., Barka, E. &amp; Harous, S. Block chain-based multi-diagnosis deep learning application for various diseases classification. <i>Int. J. Inf. Secur.</i><b>23</b> (1), 15&#x2013;30 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10207-023-00733-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lilhore, U., Kumar &amp; Simaiya, S. Integrating Multimodal Data Fusion for Advanced Biomedical Analysis: A Comprehensive Review. In <i>Multimodal Data Fusion for Bioinformatics Artificial Intelligence,</i>&#xa0;127&#x2013;145 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khekare, G. et al. Identification of Brain Tumors in MRI Images Using Artificial Intelligence of Things. In <i>Artificial Intelligence of Things Applications</i> 93&#x2013;104 (CRC, 2025). 10.1201/9781003469896-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wajgi, R. et al. Optimized tuberculosis classification system for chest X-ray images: Fusing hyperparameter tuning with transfer learning approaches. <i>Eng. Rep.</i>10.1002/eng2.12906 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eng2.12906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yenurkar, G. K. et al. DeepLeuk: A convolutional neural network pre-trained model for microscopic cell images-based leukemia cancer analysis. <i>Multimed.Tools Appl.</i>10.1007/s11042-024-19544-7 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-024-19544-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lilhore, U. et al. An Attention-Driven hybrid deep neural network for enhanced heart disease classification. <i>Expert Syst.</i><b>42</b> (2), e13791 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exsy.13791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yenurkar, G. K. et al. Multifactor data analysis to forecast an individual&#x2019;s severity over novel COVID-19 pandemic using extreme gradient boosting and random forest classifier algorithms. <i>Eng. Rep.</i>10.1002/eng2.12678 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eng2.12678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yenurkar, G. &amp; Mal, S. Future forecasting prediction of COVID-19 using hybrid deep learning algorithm. Multimedia tools and applications. <i>Springer Nat.</i>10.1007/s11042-022-14219-7 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-022-14219-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9672606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36415331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yenurkar, G. K. et al. Future prediction for precautionary measures associated with heart-related issues based on IoT prototype. <i>Multimed. Tools Appl.</i>10.1007/s11042-024-19135-6 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-024-19135-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makade, J., Bankar, N., Kumar, A., Bandre, G. &amp; Yenurkar, G. Artificial intelligence in health care: A review of uses, challenges and potential uses. <i>AIP Conf. Proc.</i><b>3188</b>, 080032. 10.1063/5.0240230 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0240230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>