<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41514333</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association between obsessive-compulsive symptoms and job performance among hospital nurses: a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>129</StartPage><MedlinePgn>129</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">129</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-026-04302-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Obsessive-compulsive (OC) symptoms may influence occupational functioning, particularly in demanding healthcare environments. Understanding the extent to which these symptoms are associated with job performance is essential for supporting the well-being and productivity of hospital nurses. This study aimed to investigate the association between OC symptoms and their subdimensions with job performance among hospital nurses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This descriptive-analytical cross-sectional study was conducted in 2024 among 340 nurses working in public hospitals in southern Iran. Participants were selected using stratified random sampling. Data were collected using a validated 39-item OC Symptom Scale and the 15-item Job Performance Questionnaire. Pearson correlation and multiple linear regression analyses were performed to assess the relationships and associative strength of OC symptoms in relation to job performance. Demographic variables were also analyzed using t-tests, ANOVA, and Pearson&#x2019;s r.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The mean total score of OC symptoms was 84.36 (SD&#x2009;=&#x2009;15.72), indicating a moderate level. The mean job performance score was 27.84 (SD&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.26), also within the moderate range. Pearson correlation analysis revealed a significant negative correlation between total OC symptoms and job performance (<i>r</i> = -0.42, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). All eight subdimensions of OC symptoms showed significant negative correlations with job performance. A multiple linear regression analysis, adjusted for age, experience, education level, and employment type, indicated that OC symptoms were significantly associated with job performance (F(12, 327)&#x2009;=&#x2009;12.09, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), explaining 30.7% of the variance (Adjusted R&#xb2; = 0.307), which represents a moderate explanatory power. The effect size, calculated using Cohen&#x2019;s f&#xb2;, was 0.44, indicating a large effect. The most influential symptom domains showing significant negative associations were checking compulsions (&#x3b2; = -0.22, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), impulsive thoughts of harm (&#x3b2; = -0.19, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), and ordering compulsions (&#x3b2; = -0.17, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001). Age, experience, gender, education level, and type of employment also showed significant associations with the main variables (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">OC symptoms are significantly associated with reduced nurses&#x2019; job performance, highlighting the importance of mental health screening and targeted interventions within healthcare settings. Addressing these symptoms through preventive strategies and supportive policies may be linked to improved nurse performance and, in turn, patient care quality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kavosi</LastName><ForeName>Zahra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Human Resources Research Center, School of Health Management and Information Sciences, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keshavarz</LastName><ForeName>Khosro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Human Resources Research Center, School of Health Management and Information Sciences, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bahmaei</LastName><ForeName>Jamshid</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Behbahan Faculty of Medical Sciences, Behbahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yusefi</LastName><ForeName>Ali Reza</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Sirjan School of Medical Sciences, Sirjan, Iran. alirezayusefi67@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Sirjan School of Medical Sciences, Sirjan, Iran. alirezayusefi67@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nurses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obsessive-compulsive disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Regression analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Work performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study is approved by the Shiraz University of Medical Sciences Ethics Committee under ID number IR.SUMS.REC.1398.636. This study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. All methods were carried out in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations. Written informed consent was obtained from all subjects and/or their legal guardians. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41514333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12882169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-026-04302-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-026-04302-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bordbar S, Bahmaei J, Rad HF, Yusefi AR. Investigate the state of critical thinking and its impact on moral courage and moral sensitivity; evidence from nurses&#x2019; perspective. BMC Nurs. 2024;23(1):825. 10.1186/s12912-024-02496-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-024-02496-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11558967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39533267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Lin B, Liang H, Deng Y, Zhang L. Mediating role of psychological flexibility in the effect of obsessive-compulsive symptoms on sleep quality among nurses during the COVID-19 pandemic. Curr Psychol. 2024;43(18):16871&#x2013;80. 10.1007/s12144-023-04546-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-023-04546-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10097520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37359595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sayed MM, Elhay ES, Hawash MM, Sonbol HM, Taha SM. A closer look: obsessive-compulsive symptoms among intern nurses amidst COVID-19 pandemic. BMC Nurs. 2024;23(1):214. 10.1186/s12912-024-01872-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-024-01872-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10976757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38549136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zsoy T, Balaban &#xd6;. Obsessive-compulsive disorder and its association with work addiction and job stress. Work. 2025;80(1):461&#x2013;70. 10.3233/wor-230639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/wor-230639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39213119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein DJ, Ruscio AM, Altwaijri Y, Chiu WT, Sampson NA, Aguilar-Gaxiola S, et al. Obsessive-compulsive disorder in the world mental health surveys. BMC Med. 2025;23(1):416. 10.1186/s12916-025-04209-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-025-04209-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12239380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40629326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzu Durmaz A, &#xc7;i&#xe7;eko&#x11f;lu &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk P, &#xc7;evik, Durmaz Y. Work stress and obsessive-compulsive symptoms in nurses and office workers: a comparative study. Int J Occup Saf Ergon. 2024;30(3):711-6. 10.1080/10803548.2024.2335029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38628026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen T, Dittrich WH. Cognitive performance in a subclinical obsessive-compulsive sample 1: cognitive functions. Psychiatry J. 2013;2013(1):565191. 10.1155/2013/565191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/565191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3820080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24236282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uyar B, Donmezdil S. Comparison of healthcare workers and non-healthcare workers in terms of obsessive-compulsive and depressive symptoms during COVID-19 pandemic: a longitudinal case-controlled study. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1283317. 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1283317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1283317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10751325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38152663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saidin K, Wan P, Halim WA, Solihah WF. A synthesis towards the construct of job performance: dimensions and theoretical approaches. Pakistan J Life Social Sci. 2024;22(2):300&#x2013;12. 10.57239/pjlss-2024-22.2.0022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.57239/pjlss-2024-22.2.0022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almarwani AM, Alzahrani NS. Factors affecting the development of clinical nurses&#x2019; competency: A systematic review. Nurse Educ Pract. 2023;73:103826. 10.1016/j.nepr.2023.103826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nepr.2023.103826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37951064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennekam S, Richard S, Grima F. Coping with mental health conditions at work and its impact on self-perceived job performance. Empl Relations: Int J. 2020;42(3):626&#x2013;45. 10.1108/er-05-2019-0211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/er-05-2019-0211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tisu L, Lup&#x219;a D, V&#xee;rg&#x103; D, Rusu A. Personality characteristics, job performance and mental health: the mediating role of work engagement. Pers Indiv Differ. 2020;153:109644. 10.1016/j.paid.2019.109644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2019.109644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karada&#x11f; S, &#xc7;i&#xe7;ek B. Anxiety, depression and burnout levels of nurses working in COVID-19 intensive care units. OMEGA-Journal Death Dying. 2025;91(3):1406&#x2013;21. 10.1177/00302228231156313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00302228231156313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9904990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36747313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto A, Teller J, Wheaton MG. Obsessive-compulsive personality disorder: a review of symptomatology, impact on functioning, and treatment. Focus. 2022;20(4):389&#x2013;96. 10.1176/appi.focus.20220058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.focus.20220058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10187387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37200888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusefi AR, Daneshi S, Davarani ER, Nikmanesh P, Mehralian G, Bastani P. Resilience level and its relationship with hypochondriasis in nurses working in COVID-19 reference hospitals. BMC Nurs. 2021;20(1):219. 10.1186/s12912-021-00730-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-021-00730-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8561347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34727947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulin S, Ellbin S, Jonsdottir IH, Lindqvist Bagge AS. Is obsessive&#x2013;compulsive personality disorder related to stress-related exhaustion? Brain Behav. 2021;11(6):e02171. 10.1002/brb3.2171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.2171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33969937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alayoubi MM, Arekat ZM, Al Shobaki MJ, Abu-Naser SS. The impact of work stress on job performance among nursing staff in Al-Awda hospital. Found Manage. 2022;14(1):89&#x2013;110. 10.2478/fman-2022-0006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/fman-2022-0006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalanthroff E, Wheaton MG. An integrative model for Understanding obsessive-compulsive disorder: merging cognitive behavioral theory with insights from clinical neuroscience. J Clin Med. 2022;11(24):7379. 10.3390/jcm11247379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm11247379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9784452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36555995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X. Obsessive-Compulsive Personality. In: The ECPH encyclopedia of psychology. Singapore: Springer Nature Singapore;2024. p.1021. 10.1007/978-981-97-7874-4_86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakker AB, Demerouti E. Job demands&#x2013;resources theory: taking stock and looking forward. J Occup Health Psychol. 2017;22(3):273. 10.1037/ocp0000056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/ocp0000056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27732008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taris TW, Schaufeli WB. The job demands-resources model. In: Clarke S, Probst TM, Guldenmund F, Passmore J, editors. The Wiley Blackwell handbook of the psychology of occupational safety and workplace health. Oxford: Wiley Blackwell; 2015. p. 157&#x2013;80. 10.1002/9781118979013.ch8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams G, Kaviani H, Torkanbori YE, Ebrahimkhani N, Manesh AA. A study of validity and reliability of the Persian version of the Padua Inventory-Washington state university revision (PI-WSUR) in a sample of healthy Iranian students. Adv Cogn Sci. 2010;12(1):1&#x2013;16. http://icssjournal.ir/article-1-77-en.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanbari S, Hemati M. The study of relationship between social capitals with job performances of Bu-Ali Sina university employees. High Educ Letter. 2016;9(35):115&#x2013;33. https://journal.sanjesh.org/article_24504.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamloo MB, Kalani L, Ramezanpour E, Khaneghah ZN, Rashidi N. Frequency of Obsessive-Compulsive symptoms related to anxiety in nurses care for COVID-19 patients: A cross-sectional study. Iran J Psychiatry Behav Sci. 2022;16(4):e127173. 10.5812/ijpbs-127173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/ijpbs-127173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi Y, Baghaei R, Hosseingholipour K, Mollazadeh F. Challenges experienced by ICU nurses throughout the provision of care for COVID-19 patients: A qualitative study. J Nurs Adm Manag. 2021;29(5):1159&#x2013;68. 10.1111/jonm.13254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jonm.13254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33480145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheraghi R, Parizad N, Alinejad V, Piran M, Almasi L. The effect of emotional intelligence on nurses&#x2019; job performance: the mediating role of moral intelligence and occupational stress. BMC Nurs. 2025;24(1):130. 10.1186/s12912-025-02744-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-02744-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11796207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39905367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ergenc H, Ergenc Z, Usanmaz M, Tor IH, Usanmaz H, Akcay EU. Investigating Anxiety, depression and Obsessive-Compulsive disorders (OCD) among healthcare workers in COVID-19 unit and the control group. Medicine. 2020;9(4):1072&#x2013;5. 10.5455/medscience.2020.07.132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/medscience.2020.07.132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsayed MM, Ghazi GA. Fear of COVID-19 Pandemic, Obsessive-Compulsive traits and sleep quality among first academic year nursing Students, Alexandria University, Egypt. Egypt J Health Care. 2021;12(2):224&#x2013;41. 10.21608/ejhc.2021.150261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejhc.2021.150261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bragdon LB, Gibb BE, Coles ME. Does neuropsychological performance in OCD relate to different symptoms? A meta-analysis comparing the symmetry and obsessing dimensions. Depress Anxiety. 2018;35(8):761&#x2013;74. 10.1002/da.22785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29920848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancebo MC, Greenberg B, Grant JE, Pinto A, Eisen JL, Dyck I, Rasmussen SA. Correlates of occupational disability in a clinical sample of obsessive-compulsive disorder. Compr Psychiatr. 2008;49(1):43&#x2013;50. 10.1016/j.comppsych.2007.05.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comppsych.2007.05.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2211449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18063040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Beniwal RP, Bhatia T, Deshpande SN. Schizophrenia with and without obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a comparative analysis of performance on trail making test and disability on WHODAS. Gen Psychiatr. 2020;33(6):e100237. 10.1136/gpsych-2020-100237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gpsych-2020-100237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33195988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pajouhinia Sh, Abavisani Y, Rezazadeh Z. Explaining the Obsessive-compulsive symptoms based on cognitive flexibility and social cognition. J Pract Clin Psychol. 2020;8(3):233&#x2013;42. 10.32598/jpcp.8.3.10.717.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32598/jpcp.8.3.10.717.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontis D, Theochari E, Nikolakopoulou M, Andreopoulou A, Vassos D, Grigoriou V, et al. Obsessive compulsive symptoms are associated with better functioning independently of cognition in schizophrenia. Compr Psychiatr. 2016;70:32&#x2013;40. 10.1016/j.comppsych.2016.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comppsych.2016.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27624421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschtritt ME, Bloch MH, Mathews CA. Obsessive-compulsive disorder: advances in diagnosis and treatment. JAMA. 2017;317(13):1358&#x2013;67. 10.1001/jama.2017.2200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.2200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frydman I, Mattos P, de Oliveira-Souza R, Y&#xfc;cel M, Chamberlain SR, Moll J, Fontenelle LF. Self-reported and neurocognitive impulsivity in obsessive-compulsive disorder. Compr Psychiatr. 2020;97:152155. 10.1016/j.comppsych.2019.152155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comppsych.2019.152155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31864219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Putter LM, Koster EH. Can selective attention and Inhibition (interactively) predict future obsessive compulsive symptoms? A prospective study. J Behav Ther Exp Psychiatry. 2018;61:150&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.jbtep.2018.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbtep.2018.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30081256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stasik SM, Naragon-Gainey K, Chmielewski M, Watson D. Core OCD symptoms: exploration of specificity and relations with psychopathology. J Anxiety Disord. 2012;26(8):859&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.janxdis.2012.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.janxdis.2012.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23026094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulding R, Coles ME, Abramowitz JS, Alcolado GM, Alonso P, Belloch A, et al. Part 2. they scare because we care: the relationship between obsessive intrusive thoughts and appraisals and control strategies across 15 cities. J obsessive-compulsive Relat Disorders. 2014;3(3):280&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.jocrd.2014.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocrd.2014.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusefi AR, Faryabi R, Bordbar S, Daneshi S, Nikmanesh P. Job burnout status Andand its relationship with resilience level of healthcare workers during Covid-19 pandemic: a case of Southern Iran. Iran J Health Sci. 2021;9(3):1&#x2013;11. 10.18502/jhs.v9i3.7305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/jhs.v9i3.7305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obeng AF, Zhu Y, Azinga SA, Quansah PE. Organizational climate and job performance: investigating the mediating role of harmonious work passion and the moderating role of leader&#x2013;member exchange and coaching. Sage Open. 2021;11(2):21582440211008456. 10.1177/21582440211008456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21582440211008456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagci ZG, Ozcan GG, Yagci T, Ceylan D. Comparison of frontline healthcare professionals and other healthcare professionals in terms of Depression, Anxiety, Stress, Obsessive-Compulsive symptoms and quality of life in the COVID-19 pandemic. Eurasian J Med Invest. 2022;6(3):318&#x2013;25. 10.14744/ejmi.2022.11975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14744/ejmi.2022.11975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi M, Smilansky H, Porth R, Myers N, Geller D, Small BJ, McGuire JF, Wilhelm S, Storch EA. The moderating effect of age on the associations of cognitive and metacognitive beliefs with pediatric OCD symptoms. Cogn Behav Ther. 2021;50(2):104&#x2013;20. 10.1080/16506073.2020.1819866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2020.1819866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7897238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33073722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunawan J, Aungsuroch Y, Fisher ML, Marzilli C, Liu Y. Factors related to the clinical competence of registered nurses: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2020;52(6):623&#x2013;33. 10.1111/jnu.12594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnu.12594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32862486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areshtanab HN, Moonaghi HK, Jouybari L, Zamanzadeh V, Ebrahimi H. Adapting life to the reality of diabetes. East Mediterr Health J. 2018;24(8):729&#x2013;35. 10.26719/2018.24.8.729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26719/2018.24.8.729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30328603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibuea ZM, Sulastiana M, Fitriana E. Factor affecting the quality of work life among nurses: A systematic review. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2024;17:491&#x2013;503. 10.2147/jmdh.s446459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/jmdh.s446459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10849054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38328635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hult M, Halminen O, Mattila-Holappa P, Kangasniemi M. Health and work well-being associated with employment precariousness among permanent and temporary nurses: a cross-sectional survey. Nordic J Nurs Res. 2022;42(3):140&#x2013;6. 10.1177/20571585211070376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20571585211070376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>