<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41474365</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-1167</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Epilepsia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Epilepsia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>L-Relationship between uncertainty and average seizure frequency in clinical trials of antiseizure medications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/epi.70080</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Antiseizure medications are approved based on clinical trials that demonstrate their efficacy as measured by reductions in seizure frequency (SF). When designing these trials, trialists must select inclusion criteria where SF can be reliably measured to maintain statistical power. Statistical power is based on the magnitude and uncertainty of the difference between active treatment and placebo. To inform choices about how minimum, maximum, and individual participant SF impacts the statistical power of trials, we evaluated how the uncertainty in SF was associated with average SF within multiple clinical trials.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using data from 11 double-blind placebo-controlled trials of antiseizure medications for either focal or generalized onset epilepsy, we used log-log multivariable regression to associate the SD of SF in maintenance with the average SF in baseline and maintenance. We also evaluated whether capturing more seizures in people with high average SF offset the increased uncertainty in SF and asked whether these associations persisted when time to event designs were used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The uncertainty (SD) of maintenance SF was proportional to baseline average SF (daily diaries: slope of log-log association = .575, 95% confidence interval [CI] = .556-.593; fortnightly diaries: .657, 95% CI = .0642-.0671). Increased uncertainty for high SF was offset by counting more seizures. These relationships were maintained with a time to event design.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study validates the foundational L-relationship between average and SD of SF in which the uncertainty of seizure counts increased proportional to the number of seizures counted. When used for efficacy outcomes of trials, the statistical benefit of counting more seizures in participants with high SF was much greater than the increased challenge from higher uncertainty seizure counts. These results provide quantitative insights for SF-based inclusion criteria and statistical power calculations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Epilepsia published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of International League Against Epilepsy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerr</LastName><ForeName>Wesley T</ForeName><Initials>WT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5546-5951</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Informatics, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kok</LastName><ForeName>Neo</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-0505-6084</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McFarlane</LastName><ForeName>Katherine N</ForeName><Initials>KN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-0365-813X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reddy</LastName><ForeName>Advith S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-9831-0275</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biju</LastName><ForeName>Lavanya</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>French</LastName><ForeName>Jacqueline A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2242-8027</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comprehensive Epilepsy Center, New York University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldenholz</LastName><ForeName>Daniel M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8370-2758</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Epilepsy, Beth Israel Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Susan S. Spencer Clinical Research Training Scholalarship</GrantID><Agency>American Academy of Neurology</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 NS124656</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U24NS107158</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R25NS089450</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23NS135134</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23NS124656</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Epilepsia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2983306R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0013-9580</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">L&#x2010;relationship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antiepileptic drugs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epilepsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">time to event</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41474365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epi.70080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Brodie MJ, Liew D, Kwan P. Treatment outcomes in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy treated with established and new antiepileptic drugs: a 30&#x2010;year longitudinal cohort study. JAMA Neurol. 2018;75(3):279&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan P, Arzimanoglou A, Berg AT, Brodie MJ, Allen Hauser W, Mathern G, et&#xa0;al. Definition of drug resistant epilepsy: consensus proposal by the ad hoc task force of the ILAE commission on therapeutic strategies. Epilepsia. 2010;51(6):1069&#x2013;1077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr WT, Auvin S, van der Geyten S, Kenney C, Novak G, Fountain NB, et&#xa0;al. Time&#x2010;to&#x2010;event clinical trial designs: existing evidence and remaining concerns. Epilepsia. 2023;64(7):1699&#x2013;1708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr WT, Reddy AS, Seo SH, Kok N, Stacey WC, Stern JM, et&#xa0;al. Increasing challenges to trial recruitment and conduct over time. Epilepsia. 2023;64(10):2625&#x2013;2634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terman SW, Kirkpatrick L, Kerr WT, et&#xa0;al. Challenges and directions in epilepsy diagnostics and therapeutics: Proceedings of the 17th Epilepsy Therapies and Diagnostics Development conference. Epilepsia. 2023;65:846&#x2013;860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero J, Goldenholz DM. Statistical efficiency of patient data in randomized clinical trials of epilepsy treatments adds value. Epilepsia. 2020;61(10):2323&#x2013;2324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karoly PJ, Romero J, Cook MJ, Freestone DR, Goldenholz DM. When can we trust responders? Serious concerns when using 50% response rate to assess clinical trials. Epilepsia. 2019;60(9):e99&#x2013;e103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr WT, Chen H, Figuera Losada M, Cheng C, Liu T, French J. Reasons for ineligibility for clinical trials of patients with medication resistant epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2023;64(6):e56&#x2013;e60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Tharayil J, Moss R, Myers E, Theodore WH. Monte Carlo simulations of randomized clinical trials in epilepsy. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2017;4(8):544&#x2013;552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Goldenholz EB, Kaptchuk TJ. Quantifying and controlling the impact of regression to the mean on randomized controlled trials in epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2023;64(10):2635&#x2013;2643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biton V, Montouris GD, Ritter F, Riviello JJ, Reife R, Lim P, et&#xa0;al. A randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled study of topiramate in primary generalized tonic&#x2010;clonic seizures. Topiramate YTC study group. Neurology. 1999;52(7):1330&#x2013;1337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkovic SF, Knowlton RC, Leroy RF, Schiemann J, Falter U. Placebo&#x2010;controlled study of levetiracetam in idiopathic generalized epilepsy. Neurology. 2007;69(18):1751&#x2013;1760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr WT, Kok N, Reddy AS, McFarlane KN, Stern JM, Pennell PB, et&#xa0;al. Demonstration of group&#x2010;level and individual&#x2010;level efficacy using time&#x2010;to&#x2010;event designs for clinical trials of antiseizure medications. Neurology. 2024;103(4):e209713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattanzi S, Cagnetti C, Foschi N, Provinciali L, Silvestrini M. Brivaracetam add&#x2010;on for refractory focal epilepsy: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Neurology. 2016;86(14):1344&#x2013;1352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryvlin P, Cucherat M, Rheims S. Risk of sudden unexpected death in epilepsy in patients given adjunctive antiepileptic treatment for refractory seizures: a meta&#x2010;analysis of placebo&#x2010;controlled randomised trials. Lancet Neurol. 2011;10(11):961&#x2013;968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Westover MB. Flexible realistic simulation of seizure occurrence recapitulating statistical properties of seizure diaries. Epilepsia. 2023;64(2):396&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero J, Larimer P, Chang B, Goldenholz SR, Goldenholz DM. Natural variability in seizure frequency: implications for trials and placebo. Epilepsy Res. 2020;162:106306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Goldenholz SR, Moss R, French J, Lowenstein D, Kuzniecky R, et&#xa0;al. Is seizure frequency variance a predictable quantity? Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2018;5(2):201&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Goldenholz SR, Moss R, French J, Lowenstein D, Kuzniecky R, et&#xa0;al. Does accounting for seizure frequency variability increase clinical trial power? Epilepsy Res. 2017;137:145&#x2013;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Strashny A, Cook M, Moss R, Theodore WH. A multi&#x2010;dataset time&#x2010;reversal approach to clinical trial placebo response and the relationship to natural variability in epilepsy. Seizure. 2017;53:31&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Chen WV, Regalia G, Goldenholz DM, Picard RW. Statistical characteristics of large&#x2010;scale objective tonic&#x2010;clonic seizure records from medical smartwatches used in daily life. Epilepsia. 2024;65(11):3255&#x2013;3264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein P, Schiemann J, Sperling MR, Whitesides J, Liang W, Stalvey T, et&#xa0;al. A randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled, multicenter, parallel&#x2010;group study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of adjunctive brivaracetam in adult patients with uncontrolled partial&#x2010;onset seizures. Epilepsia. 2015;56(12):1890&#x2013;1898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan P, Trinka E, van Paesschen W, Rektor I, Johnson ME, Lu S. Adjunctive brivaracetam for uncontrolled focal and generalized epilepsies: results of a phase III, double&#x2010;blind, randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled, flexible&#x2010;dose trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55(1):38&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryvlin P, Werhahn KJ, Blaszczyk B, Johnson ME, Lu S. Adjunctive brivaracetam in adults with uncontrolled focal epilepsy: results from a double&#x2010;blind, randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55(1):47&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biton V, Berkovic SF, Abou&#x2010;Khalil B, Sperling MR, Johnson ME, Lu S. Brivaracetam as adjunctive treatment for uncontrolled partial epilepsy in adults: a phase III randomized, double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55(1):57&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halasz P, K&#xe4;lvi&#xe4;inen R, Mazurkiewicz&#x2010;Beldzi&#x144;ska M, Rosenow F, Doty P, Hebert D, et&#xa0;al. Adjunctive lacosamide for partial&#x2010;onset seizures: efficacy and safety results from a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2009;50(3):443&#x2013;453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung S, Sperling MR, Biton V, Krauss G, Hebert D, Rudd GD, et&#xa0;al. Lacosamide as adjunctive therapy for partial&#x2010;onset seizures: a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2010;51(6):958&#x2013;967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naritoku DK, Warnock CR, Messenheimer JA, Borgohain R, Evers S, Guekht AB, et&#xa0;al. Lamotrigine extended&#x2010;release as adjunctive therapy for partial seizures. Neurology. 2007;69(16):1610&#x2013;1618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biton V, di Memmo J, Shukla R, Lee YY, Poverennova I, Demchenko V, et&#xa0;al. Adjunctive lamotrigine XR for primary generalized tonic&#x2010;clonic seizures in a randomized, placebo&#x2010;controlled study. Epilepsy Behav. 2010;19(3):352&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biton V, Sackellares JC, Vuong A, Hammer AE, Barrett PS, Messenheimer JA. Double&#x2010;blind, placebo&#x2010;controlled study of lamotrigine in primary generalized tonic&#x2010;clonic seizures. Neurology. 2005;65(11):1737&#x2013;1743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulm K. A simple method to calculate the confidence interval of a standardized mortality ratio (SMR). Am J Epidemiol. 1990;131(2):373&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang S, Haut SR, Ferastraoaru V, Rao VR, Baud MO, Theodore WH, et&#xa0;al. Individualizing the definition of seizure clusters based on temporal clustering analysis. Epilepsy Res. 2020;163:106330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang S, Vannucci M, Goldenholz DM, Moss R, Stern JM. Epilepsy as a dynamic disease: a Bayesian model for differentiating seizure risk from natural variability. Epilepsia Open. 2018;3(2):236&#x2013;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tharayil JJ, Chiang S, Moss R, Stern JM, Theodore WH, Goldenholz DM. A big data approach to the development of mixed&#x2010;effects models for seizure count data. Epilepsia. 2017;58(5):835&#x2013;844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tingley D et&#xa0;al. Mediation: R package for causal mediation analysis. J Stat Softw. 2014;59(5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>French JA, Gil&#x2010;Nagel A, Malerba S, Kramer L, Kumar D, Bagiella E. Time to prerandomization monthly seizure count in perampanel trials: a novel epilepsy endpoint. Neurology. 2015;84(20):2014&#x2013;2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Guindani M, Grieco SF, Chen L, Holmes TC, Xu X. Beyond t test and ANOVA: applications of mixed&#x2010;effects models for more rigorous statistical analysis in neuroscience research. Neuron. 2022;110(1):21&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaha O, Esserman D, Li F. Design and analysis of cluster randomized trials with time&#x2010;to&#x2010;event outcomes under the additive hazards mixed model. Stat Med. 2022;41(24):4860&#x2013;4885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stram DO. Meta&#x2010;analysis of published data using a linear mixed&#x2010;effects model. Biometrics. 1996;52(2):536&#x2013;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath L, Fekete K, M&#xe1;rton S, Fekete I. Correlation between prescribed daily dose, seizure freedom and defined daily dose in antiepileptic drug treatment. Int J Clin Pharmacol. 2017;39(2):459&#x2013;467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Goldenholz SR. Placebo in epilepsy. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2020;153:231&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenholz DM, Tharayil JJ, Kuzniecky R, Karoly P, Theodore WH, Cook MJ. Simulating clinical trials with and without intracranial EEG data. Epilepsia Open. 2017;2(2):156&#x2013;161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson ME, McClung C, Bozorg AM. Analyses of seizure responses supportive of a novel trial design to assess efficacy of antiepileptic drugs in infants and young children with epilepsy: post hoc analyses of pediatric levetiracetam and lacosamide trials. Epilepsia Open. 2021;6(2):359&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auvin S, French J, Dlugos D, Knupp KG, Perucca E, Arzimanoglou A, et&#xa0;al. Novel study design to assess the efficacy and tolerability of antiseizure medications for focal&#x2010;onset seizures in infants and young children: a consensus document from the regulatory task force and the pediatric commission of the international league against epilepsy (ILAE), in collaboration with the pediatric epilepsy research consortium (PERC). Epilepsia Open. 2019;4(4):537&#x2013;543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira A, Romero JM, Goldenholz DM. Comparing the efficacy, exposure, and cost of clinical trial analysis methods. Epilepsia. 2019;60(12):e128&#x2013;e132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha A, Oh C, Hesdorffer D, Diehl B, Devore S, Brodie MJ, et&#xa0;al. Sudden unexpected death in epilepsy: a personalized prediction tool. Neurology. 2021;96(21):e2627&#x2013;e2638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak JL, Miller PR, Markovic D, Meymandi SK, DeGiorgio CM. Risk assessment for sudden death in epilepsy: the SUDEP&#x2010;7 inventory. Front Neurol. 2015;6:252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibue&#x2010;Adjei M, Kamp MA, Vonck K. 30&#x2009;years of vagus nerve stimulation trials in epilepsy: do we need neuromodulation&#x2010;specific trial designs? Epilepsy Res. 2019;153:71&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vossler DG, Rosenfeld WE, Stern S, Wade CT, Ferrari L, Kerr WT, et&#xa0;al. Sustainability of seizure reduction and seizure control with adjunctive cenobamate: post hoc analysis of a phase 3, open&#x2010;label study. Epilepsia. 2023;64(10):2644&#x2013;2652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenfeld WE, Ferrari L, Kerr WT, Sperling MR. Sudden unexpected death in epilepsy during cenobamate clinical development. Epilepsia. 2023;64:2108&#x2013;2115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>French JA, Porter RJ, Perucca E, Brodie MJ, Rogawski MA, Harden C, et&#xa0;al. Interim analysis of the long&#x2010;term efficacy and safety of azetukalner in an ongoing open&#x2010;label extension study following a phase 2b clinical trial (X&#x2010;TOLE) in adults with focal epilepsy. Epilepsia Open. 2025;10(2):539&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auvin S, Nortvedt C, Fuller DS, Sahebkar F. Seizure&#x2010;free days as a novel outcome in patients with Lennox&#x2010;Gastaut syndrome: post hoc analysis of patients receiving cannabidiol in two randomized controlled trials. Epilepsia. 2023;64(7):1812&#x2013;1820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan J, Specchio N, Devinsky O, Auvin S, Perry MS, Strzelczyk A, et&#xa0;al. Fenfluramine significantly reduces day&#x2010;to&#x2010;day seizure burden by increasing number of seizure&#x2010;free days and time between seizures in patients with Dravet syndrome: a time&#x2010;to&#x2010;event analysis. Epilepsia. 2022;63(1):130&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auvin S, Damera V, Martin M, Holland R, Simontacchi K, Saich A. The impact of seizure frequency on quality of life in patients with Lennox&#x2010;Gastaut syndrome or Dravet syndrome. Epilepsy Behav. 2021;123:108239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo SH, Lloyd A, Marshall J, Vyas K. Patient and caregiver health state Utilities in Lennox&#x2010;Gastaut Syndrome and Dravet Syndrome. Clin Ther. 2021;43(11):1861&#x2013;1876.e16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auvin S, Williams B, McMurray R, Kumar D, Perdomo C, Malhotra M. Novel seizure outcomes in patients with Lennox&#x2010;Gastaut syndrome: post hoc analysis of seizure&#x2010;free days in rufinamide study 303. Epilepsia Open. 2019;4(2):275&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>