<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41906622</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1934-1563</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PM &amp; R : the journal of injury, function, and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PM R</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predicting self-reported injury status among runners training for the New York City Marathon.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pmrj.70127</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Although numerous studies have examined risk factors and prevention strategies for running-related injuries, few have rigorously tested predictive models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To describe injury patterns throughout marathon training and assess the feasibility of machine learning (ML) models in predicting upcoming weekly running injury status during marathon training with activity logs and runner-reported survey data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective observational study, participants completed baseline surveys, 16 weekly interval surveys during marathon training, and shared GPS watch and smartphone-based running logs from Strava. Injury status was summarized and used to train two tabular ML models incorporating baseline, prior surveys, and aggregated training logs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">All data were collected remotely via online platforms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 643 adult runners (53% female, mean age 43&#x2009;years) training for the 2022 Tata Consultancy Services New York City Marathon were recruited and had linkable Strava running logs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">N/A.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Self-reported weekly injury status indicating modification of training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 643 runners, 307 (48%) experienced at least one injury requiring modification of training during the analysis window. Across 9002 runner-week observations, 75% indicated no injury. Injury status tended to persist, with most runners maintaining the same status week-to-week, and recovery was more common than worsening. For the first model (all runner-week observations), predictive modeling with generalized additive models yielded good performance, specifically an area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUROC)&#x2009;=&#x2009;87% and area under the precision-recall curve (AUPRC)&#x2009;=&#x2009;52%. For the second model (previously uninjured runner-week observations), performance was poor, yielding AUROC&#x2009;=&#x2009;67% and AUPRC&#x2009;=&#x2009;8%. Top features' partial dependency plots often showed nonlinear relationships with injury risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ML using survey and running activity data had low discriminatory power in predicting weekly running injury among runners not already modifying their training, though results highlight the importance of the prior week's injury status. Larger samples, more precise injury timing, and additional predictors are likely needed to improve performance and inform future injury prevention strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). PM&amp;R published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fontana</LastName><ForeName>Mark A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0529-9035</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedic Data Innovation Lab, Hospital for Special Surgery, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population Health Sciences, Weill Cornell Medical College, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egbert</LastName><ForeName>Jamie S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6288-8058</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toresdahl</LastName><ForeName>Brett G</ForeName><Initials>BG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3857-2779</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PM R</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101491319</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1934-1482</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41906622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pmrj.70127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hofstede H, Franke TPC, van Eijk RPA, Backx FJG, Kemler E, Huisstede BMA. In training for a marathon: runners and running&#x2010;related injury prevention. Phys Ther Sport. 2020;41:80&#x2010;86. doi:10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.11.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter SK, Stevens AA. Sex differences in marathon running with advanced age: physiology or participation? Article. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(1):148&#x2010;156. doi:10.1249/MSS.0b013e31826900f</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knechtle B, Di Gangi S, R&#xfc;st CA, Rosemann T, Nikolaidis PT. Men's participation and performance in the Boston Marathon from 1897 to 2017. Int J Sports Med. 2018;39(13):1018&#x2010;1027. doi:10.1055/a&#x2010;0660&#x2010;0061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitti A, Nikolaidis PT, Villiger E, Onywera V, Knechtle B. The &#x201c;New York City Marathon&#x201d;: participation and performance trends of 1.2M runners during half&#x2010;century. Res Sports Med. 2020;28(1):121&#x2010;137. doi:10.1080/15438627.2019.1586705</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluitenberg B, Van Middelkoop M, Diercks R, Van Der Worp H. What are the differences in injury proportions between different populations of runners? A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(8):1143&#x2010;1161. doi:10.1007/s40279&#x2010;015&#x2010;0331&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gent RN, Siem D, Van Middelkoop M, Van Os AG, Bierma&#x2010;Zeinstra SMA, Koes BW. Incidence and determinants of lower extremity running injuries in long distance runners: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41(8):469&#x2010;480. doi:10.1136/bjsm.2006.033548</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen RO, R&#xf8;nnow L, Rasmussen S, Lind M. A prospective study on time to recovery in 254 injured novice runners. PLoS One. 2014;9(6):e99877. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0099877</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Middelkoop M, Kolkman J, Van Ochten J, Bierma&#x2010;Zeinstra SMA, Koes BW. Risk factors for lower extremity injuries among male marathon runners. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2008;18(6):691&#x2010;697. doi:10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0838.2007.00768.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Miller JD. Incidence of training&#x2010;related injuries among marathon runners. Br J Sports Med. 1983;17(3):162&#x2010;165. doi:10.1136/bjsm.17.3.162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leppe J, Besomi M. Recent versus old previous injury and its association with running&#x2010;related injuries during competition by SeRUN&#xae; running profiles: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. Sports Med Open. 2018;4(1). doi:10.1186/s40798&#x2010;018&#x2010;0164&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clough PJ, Dutch S, Maughan RJ, Shepherd J. Pre&#x2010;race drop&#x2010;out in marathon runners: reasons for withdrawal and future plans. Br J Sports Med. 1987;21(4):148&#x2010;149. doi:10.1136/bjsm.21.4.148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang W&#x2010;L, Shih Y&#x2010;F, Chen W&#x2010;Y. Running injuries and associated factors in participants of ING Taipei Marathon. Phys Ther Sport. 2012;13(3):170&#x2010;174. doi:10.1016/j.ptsp.2011.08.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toresdahl B, McElheny K, Metzl J, et al. Factors associated with injuries in first&#x2010;time marathon runners from the New York City marathon. Phys Sportsmed. 2022;50(3):227&#x2010;232. doi:10.1080/00913847.2021.1907257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Mechelen W, Hlobil H, Kemper HC, Voorn WJ, de Jongh HR. Prevention of running injuries by warm&#x2010;up, cool&#x2010;down, and stretching exercises. Am J Sports Med. 1993;21(5):711&#x2010;719. doi:10.1177/036354659302100513</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredeweg SW, Zijlstra S, Bessem B, Buist I. The effectiveness of a preconditioning programme on preventing running&#x2010;related injuries in novice runners: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46(12):865&#x2010;870. doi:10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2012&#x2010;091397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltich J, Emery CA, Whittaker JL, Nigg BM. Running injuries in novice runners enrolled in different training interventions: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2017;27(11):1372&#x2010;1383. doi:10.1111/sms.12743</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan ZYS, Zhang JH, Au IPH, et al. Gait retraining for the reduction of injury occurrence in novice distance runners: 1&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up of a randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(2):388&#x2010;395. doi:10.1177/0363546517736277</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malisoux L, Delattre N, Urhausen A, Theisen D. Shoe cushioning influences the running injury risk according to body mass: a randomized controlled trial involving 848 recreational runners. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(2):473&#x2010;480. doi:10.1177/0363546519892578</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai P, Jungmalm J, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Karlsson J, Grau S. Effectiveness of an 18&#x2010;week general strength and foam&#x2010;rolling intervention on running&#x2010;related injuries in recreational runners. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2023;33(5):766&#x2010;775. doi:10.1111/sms.14313</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Does H, Kemler E, Gouttebarge V. Can running&#x2010;related injuries be prevented through an online behavioural intervention in adult novice runners? Results of a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9(2):e001522. doi:10.1136/bmjsem&#x2010;2022&#x2010;001522</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hooren B, Plasqui G, Meijer K. The effect of wearable&#x2010;based real&#x2010;time feedback on running injuries and running performance: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52(3):750&#x2010;765. doi:10.1177/03635465231222464</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leckey C, van Dyk N, Doherty C, Lawlor A, Delahunt E. Machine learning approaches to injury risk prediction in sport: a scoping review with evidence synthesis. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59 (7):491&#x2010;500. doi:10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2024&#x2010;108576</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;vdal SS, Den Hartigh RJR, Azzopardi G. Injury prediction in competitive runners with machine learning. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021;16(10):1522&#x2010;1531. doi:10.1123/ijspp.2020&#x2010;0518</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel M, Atallah R. Athletic runners injury prediction using support vector machines (SVM). International Journal of Innovative Science and Research Technology (IJISRT). 2024;9(9):654&#x2010;658. doi:10.38124/ijisrt/IJISRT24SEP239</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toresdahl BG, Metzl JD, Kinderknecht J, et al. Training patterns associated with injury in New York City Marathon runners. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(3):146&#x2010;152. doi:10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2022&#x2010;105670</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamato TP, Saragiotto BT, Lopes AD. A consensus definition of running&#x2010;related injury in recreational runners: a modified Delphi approach. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2015;45(5):375&#x2010;380. doi:10.2519/jospt.2015.5741</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarsen B, Bahr R, Myklebust G, et al. Improved reporting of overuse injuries and health problems in sport: an update of the Oslo Sport Trauma Research Center questionnaires. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(7):390&#x2010;396. doi:10.1136/bjsports&#x2010;2019&#x2010;101337</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, et al. The REDCap consortium: building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform. 2019;95:103208. doi:10.1016/j.jbi.2019.103208</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research Electronic Data Capture (REDCap)&#x2014;a metadata&#x2010;driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42(2):377&#x2010;381. doi:10.1016/j.jbi.2008.08.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou Y, Caruana R, Gehrke J, Hooker G. Accurate intelligible models with pairwise interactions. presented at: Proceedings of the 19th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining; 2013; Chicago, Illinois, USA. doi:10.1145/2487575.2487579</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddy JD, Shield AJ, Maniar N, et al. Predictive modeling of hamstring strain injuries in elite Australian footballers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(5):906&#x2010;914. doi:10.1249/mss.0000000000001527</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karnuta JM, Luu BC, Haeberle HS, et al. Machine learning outperforms regression analysis to predict next&#x2010;season Major League Baseball player injuries: epidemiology and validation of 13,982 player&#x2010;years from performance and injury profile trends, 2000&#x2010;2017. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(11):2325967120963046. doi:10.1177/2325967120963046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luu BC, Wright AL, Haeberle HS, et al. Machine learning outperforms logistic regression analysis to predict next&#x2010;season NHL player injury: An analysis of 2322 players from 2007 to 2017. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8(9):2325967120953404. doi:10.1177/2325967120953404</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi A, Pappalardo L, Cintia P, Iaia FM, Fern&#xe0;ndez J, Medina D. Effective injury forecasting in soccer with GPS training data and machine learning. PLoS One. 2018;13(7):e0201264. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0201264</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rommers N, R&#xf6;ssler R, Verhagen E, et al. A machine learning approach to assess injury risk in elite youth football players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(8):1745&#x2010;1751. doi:10.1249/mss.0000000000002305</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahamson J, Lindman I, Eriksen MB, Kibsgaard A, Nielsen RO. Using self&#x2010;reported training characteristics to better understand who is more likely to sustain running&#x2010;related injuries than others: the Garmin&#x2010;RUNSAFE running health study. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2025;35(1):e70004. doi:10.1111/sms.70004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fokkema T, van Damme A, Fornerod MWJ, de Vos RJ, Bierma&#x2010;Zeinstra SMA, van Middelkoop M. Training for a (half&#x2010;)marathon: training volume and longest endurance run related to performance and running injuries. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(9):1692&#x2010;1704. doi:10.1111/sms.13725</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredette A, Roy JS, Perreault K, Dupuis F, Napier C, Esculier JF. The association between running injuries and training parameters: a systematic review. J Athl Train. 2022;57(7):650&#x2010;671. doi:10.4085/1062&#x2010;6050&#x2010;0195.21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, McCall A, Ward P, Bornn L, Coutts AJ. Training load and its role in injury prevention, part 2: conceptual and methodologic pitfalls. J Athl Train. 2020;55(9):893&#x2010;901. doi:10.4085/1062&#x2010;6050&#x2010;501&#x2010;19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X, Huang Y, Bai Z, Wang Y. A novel approach for sports injury risk prediction: based on time&#x2010;series image encoding and deep learning. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1174525. doi:10.3389/fphys.2023.1174525</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Tenan MS, Kempton T, Novak A, Coutts AJ. Acute:chronic workload ratio: conceptual issues and fundamental pitfalls. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020;15(6):907&#x2010;913. doi:10.1123/ijspp.2019&#x2010;0864</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Woodcock S, Coutts AJ, Fanchini M, McCall A, Vigotsky AD. What role do chronic workloads play in the acute to chronic workload ratio? Time to dismiss ACWR and its underlying theory. Sports Med. 2021;51(3):581&#x2010;592. doi:10.1007/s40279&#x2010;020&#x2010;01378&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>