<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41742937</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2073-4433</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Atmosphere</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Atmosphere (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Revisiting the Convective Like Boundary Layer Assumption in the Urban Option of AERMOD.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1342</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1342</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/atmos16121342</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Urban areas and their surroundings feature unique, horizontally inhomogeneous spatial distributions of land use and land cover, leading to urban heat islands (UHIs) for both air and land surface temperature that complicate the estimation of urban sensible heat flux. The urban dispersion option in AERMOD, the American Meteorological Society (AMS)/Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Regulatory Model, incorporates this effect at night through a "convective like boundary layer" that modifies the single column meteorology based on a population number representative of the urban area. The model produces positive nighttime sensible heat flux values that often significantly overestimate observed values from the literature. This study re-examines the formulation of the AERMOD urban option assumptions, methodology, and original evaluation against a field study of a power plant in Indianapolis. We investigate replacing the population-based parameterizations of urban-surrounding temperature differences ( <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mi>&#x394;</mml:mi> <mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:math> ) with observations of remotely sensed land surface temperature (LST) data from the Advanced Baseline Imager on the GOES-16/R/East geostationary satellite. We generated a monthly averaged, hourly, wind direction-dependent, clear sky land surface urban heat island <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mi>&#x394;</mml:mi> <mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:math> database for 480 continental United States (CONUS) urban areas, as defined by the 2010 US Census. These <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mi>&#x394;</mml:mi> <mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:math> values are used to advise city-specific horizontal advection corrections to sensible heat flux estimates that are neglected from simple energy balance models. The four cities of Cleveland, Amarillo, Atlanta, and Baltimore are highlighted, showing that the AERMOD predicted nighttime <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mi>&#x394;</mml:mi> <mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:math> values are 794%, 416%, 1048%, and 758% higher, respectively, than the GOES-16 observations. These overestimated <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mi>&#x394;</mml:mi> <mml:mi>T</mml:mi></mml:math> values in AERMOD lead to nighttime sensible heat flux values &gt; 100 W/m<sup>2</sup> that rival daytime values. However, using the GOES-16 observations as horizontal advection corrections to sensible heat flux results in trends that match the expected neutral to slightly positive nighttime values from observations recorded in the literature. The annual nighttime average in 2021 was -0.8 W/m<sup>2</sup>, 8.6 W/m<sup>2</sup>, 3.0 W/m<sup>2</sup>, and 3.1 W/m<sup>2</sup> in Cleveland, Amarillo, Atlanta, and Baltimore, respectively, using this approach. Finally, reviewing the initial evaluation with the Indianapolis database against independent studies from the literature suggest that the AERMOD urban option inadvertently implements an urban heat island modeling approach to account for what was a low-level jet during the field study.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Retter</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6812-163X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education Research, Research Triangle Park, NC 27711, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>U.S. EPA Office of Research and Development, Center for Environmental Measurement and Modeling, Research Triangle Park, NC 27711, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owen</LastName><ForeName>Robert Christopher</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>U.S. EPA Office of Research and Development, Center for Environmental Measurement and Modeling, Research Triangle Park, NC 27711, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leske</LastName><ForeName>Annamarie</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Labs, Laurel, MD 20723, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Snyder</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4225-1556</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>WSP Global Inc., Durham, NC 27703, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sargent</LastName><ForeName>Rhett</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, Virginia Tech University, Blacksburg, VA 24061, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heist</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>U.S. EPA Office of Research and Development, Center for Environmental Measurement and Modeling, Research Triangle Park, NC 27711, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>EPA999999</GrantID><Acronym>ImEPA</Acronym><Agency>Intramural EPA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Atmosphere (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101562250</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2073-4433</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dispersion modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">remote sensing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urban heat islands</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urban sensible heat flux</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: The WSP Global Inc. had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in writing of the manuscript, or in the decision to publish results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41742937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2137399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12931099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/atmos16121342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Oke TR; Mills G; Christen A; Voogt JA Urban Heat Island. In Urban Climates; Cambridge University Press: Cambridge, UK, 2017; pp. 197&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimorelli AJ; Perry SG; Venkatram A; Weil JC; Paine RJ; Wilson RB; Lee RF; Peters WD; Brode RW AERMOD: A Dispersion Model for Industrial Source Applications. Part I: General Model Formulation and Boundary Layer Characterization. J. Appl. Meteorol 2005, 44, 682&#x2013;693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Census Bureau. 2020. 
Census Urban Areas Facts. Available online: https://www.census.gov/programs-surveys/geography/guidance/geo-areas/urban-rural/2020-ua-facts.html (accessed on 20 November 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luhar AK; Venkatram A; Lee S-M On relationships between urban and rural near-surface meteorology for diffusion applications. Atmos. Environ 2006, 40, 6541&#x2013;6553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y; Li Y; Bejan A; Wang Y; Yang X Horizontal extent of the urban heat dome flow. Sci. Rep 2017, 7, 11681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5601473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oke TR; Spronken-Smith RA; J&#xe1;uregui E; Grimmond CSJ The energy balance of central Mexico City during the dry season. Atmos. Environ 1999, 33, 3919&#x2013;3930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christen A; Bernhofer C; Parlow E; Rotach MW; Vogt R Partitioning of turbulent fluxes over different urban surfaces. In Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Urban Climate, &#x141;&#xf3;d&#x17a;, Poland, 1&#x2013;5 September 2003; Volume 1, p. 285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood CR; Lacser A; Barlow JF; Padhra A; Belcher SE; Nemitz E; Helfter C; Famulari D; Grimmond CSB Turbulent Flow at 190 m Height Above London During 2006&#x2013;2008: A Climatology and the Applicability of Similarity Theory. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 2010, 137, 77&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y; Zeng Q; Hu F; Ding W; Zhang Z; Zhang K; Liu L Different Turbulent Regimes and Vertical Turbulence Structures of the Urban Nocturnal Stable Boundary Layer. Adv. Atmos. Sci 2023, 40, 1089&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccioni A; Grandoni L; Di Bernardino A Evaluation of Profiles of Standard Deviation of Vertical Wind in the Urban Area of Rome: Performances of Monin&#x2013;Obukhov Similarity Theory Using Different Scaling Variables. Sustainability 2021, 13, 8426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigenwinter C; Vogt R; Christen A Eddy Covariance Measurements Over Urban Areas. In Eddy Covariance: A Practical Guide to Measurement and Data Analysis; Aubinet M, Vesala T, Papale D, Eds.; Springer: Dordrecht, The Netherlands, 2012; pp. 377&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna S; Marciotto E; Britter R Urban Energy Fluxes in Built-Up Downtown Areas and Variations across the Urban Area, for Use in Dispersion Models. J. Appl. Meteorol. Climatol 2011, 50, 1341&#x2013;1353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ching JKS; Clarke JF; Godowitch JM Modulation of heat flux by different scales of advection in an urban environment. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 1983, 25, 171&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna SR; Chang JC Boundary-layer parameterizations for applied dispersion modeling over urban areas. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 1992, 58, 229&#x2013;259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piringer M; Grimmond CSB; Joffre SM; Mestayer P; Middleton DR; Rotach MW; Baklanov A; De Ridder K; Ferreira J; Guilloteau E; et al. Investigating the Surface Energy Balance in Urban Areas&#x2013;Recent Advances and Future Needs, Water. Air Soil Pollut. Focus 2002, 2, 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piringer M; Joffre S; Baklanov A; Christen A; Deserti M; De Ridder K; Emeis S; Mestayer P; Tombrou M; Middleton D; et al. The surface energy balance and the mixing height in urban areas&#x2014;Activities and recommendations of COST Action 715. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 2007, 124, 3&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biraud S; Chen J; Christen A; Davis K; Lin J; McFadden J; Miller C; Nemitz E; Schade G; Stagakis S; et al. 
(AmeriFlux Urban Fluxes ad Hoc Committee), Eddy Covariance Measurements in Urban Environments, White Paper Prepared by the AmeriFlux Urban Fluxes ad Hoc Committee. 2021. Available online: https://ameriflux.lbl.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/EC-in-Urban-Environment-2021-07-31-Final.pdf (accessed on 20 November 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oke TR; Mills G; Christen A; Voogt JA Energy Balance. In Urban Climates; Christen A, Mills G, Voogt JA, Eds.; Cambridge University Press: Cambridge, UK, 2017; pp. 156&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stull RB An Introduction to Boundary Layer Meteorology; Springer Science &amp; Business Media: Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany, 1988; Volume 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigeon G; Lemonsu A; Grimmond CSB; Durand P; Thouron O; Masson V Divergence of turbulent fluxes in the surface layer: Case of a coastal city. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 2007, 124, 269&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidalgo J; Pigeon G; Masson V Urban-breeze circulation during the CAPITOUL experiment: Observational data analysis approach. Meteorol. Atmos. Phys 2008, 102, 223&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spronken-Smith RA; Kossmann M; Zawar-Reza P Where does all the energy go? Surface energy partitioning in sub-urban Christchurch under stable wintertime conditions. Theor. Appl. Climatol 2006, 84, 137&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuxart J; Wrenger B; Mart&#xed;nez-Villagrasa D; Reuder J; Jonassen MO; Jim&#xe9;nez MA; Lothon M; Lohou F; Hartogensis O; D&#xfc;nnermann J; et al. Estimation of the advection effects induced by surface heterogeneities in the surface energy budget. Atmos. Chem. Phys 2016, 16, 9489&#x2013;9504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford B; Grimmond CSB; Ward HC; Morrison W; Kotthaus S Spatial and temporal patterns of surface&#x2013;atmosphere energy exchange in a dense urban environment using scintillometry. Q. J. R. Meteorol. Soc 2017, 143, 817&#x2013;833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauter T; Galos SP Effects of local advection on the spatial sensible heat flux variation on a mountain glacier. Cryosphere 2016, 10, 2887&#x2013;2905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EPA-454/B-22&#x2013;009; AERMOD Model Formulation. U.S. EPA, Office of Air Quality Planning and Standards, A.Q.A Division: Research Triangle Park, NC, USA, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oke TR City size and the urban heat island. Atmos. Environ (1967) 1973, 7, 769&#x2013;779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EPA-454/B-22&#x2013;006; User&#x2019;s Guide for AERMOD Meteorological Preprocessor (AER-MET). U.S. EPA, Office of Air Quality Planning and Standards, A.Q.A Division: Research Triangle Park, NC, USA, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlow E Regarding Some Pitfalls in Urban Heat Island Studies Using Remote Sensing Technology. Remote Sens. 2021, 13, 3598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor PA A model of airflow above changes in surface heat flux, temperature and roughness for neutral and unstable conditions. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 1970, 1, 18&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor PA Airflow above changes in surface heat flux, temperature and roughness; an extension to include the stable case. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 1971, 1, 474&#x2013;497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vugts HF; Businger JA Air modification due to a step change in surface temperature. Bound.-Layer Meteorol 1977, 11, 295&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratcliffe M; Burd C; Holder K; Fields A Defining Rural at the US Census Bureau; ACSGEO-1; U.S Census Bureau: Washington, DC, USA, 2016; Volume 1, pp. 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demuzere M; Hankey S; Mills G; Zhang W; Lu T; Bechtel B Combining expert and crowd-sourced training data to map urban form and functions for the continental US. Sci. Data 2020, 7, 264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7421904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart ID; Oke TR Local Climate Zones for Urban Temperature Studies. Bull. Am. Meteorol. Soc 2012, 93, 1879&#x2013;1900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong P; Zhan WF; Wang CL; Miao SQ; Du HL; Li JF; Wang SS; Jiang L Diurnally continuous dynamics of surface urban heat island intensities of local climate zones with spatio-temporally enhanced satellite-derived land surface temperatures. Build. Environ 2022, 218, 109105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y; Tarpley D; Xu H GOES-R Advanced Baseline Imager (ABI) Algorithm Theoretical Basis Document For Land Surface Temperature; Version 2.5; National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration: College Park, MD, USA, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ignatov A GOES-R Advanced Baseline Imager (ABI) Algorithm Theoretical Basis Document for Sea Surface Temperature; National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration: College Park, MD, USA, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray DR; Bowne NE Urban Power Plant Plume Studies; Report EA-5468; Electric Power Research Institute: Palo Alto, CA, USA, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry SG; Cimorelli AJ; Paine RJ; Brode RW; Weil JC; Venkatram A; Wilson RB; Lee RF; Peters WD AERMOD: A Dispersion Model for Industrial Source Applications. Part II: Model Performance against 17 Field Study Databases. J. Appl. Meteorol 2005, 44, 694&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J; Hanna SR Modelers&#x2019; Data Archive a Collection of Atmospheric Transport and Dispersion Data Sets; American Meteorological Society: Boston, MA, USA, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EPA Support Center for Regulatory Atmospheric Modeling (SCRAM). Available online: https://www.epa.gov/scram/air-quality-dispersion-modeling-preferred-and-recommended-models#aermod (accessed on 20 November 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna SR; Chang JC Hybrid plume dispersion model (HPDM) improvements and testing at three field sites. Atmos. Environ. Part A Gen. Top 1993, 27, 1491&#x2013;1508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazzarini M; Marpu PR; Ghedira H Temperature-land cover interactions: The inversion of urban heat island phenomenon in desert city areas. Remote Sens. Environ 2013, 130, 136&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty T; Lee X A simplified urban-extent algorithm to characterize surface urban heat islands on a global scale and examine vegetation control on their spatio-temporal variability. Int. J. Appl. Earth Obs. Geoinf 2019, 74, 269&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L; Lee X; Smith RB; Oleson K Strong contributions of local background climate to urban heat islands. Nature 2014, 511, 216&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25008529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EPA Human Exposure Model. Available online: https://www.epa.gov/fera/download-human-exposure-model-hem (accessed on 20 November 2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>