<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41902702</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1875-8584</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2026</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Behavioural neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Behav Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Empowering Patients, Preventing Strokes: Knowledge of Risk Factors and Associated Factors, Prevention Strategies, and Treatment Awareness Among Chronic Disease Patients in Southern Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e7202918</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e7202918</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/bn/7202918</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The burden of stroke is largely due to modifiable risk factors. Lack of knowledge about stroke and its risk factors hinders prevention and treatment. Effective health promotion programs need context-specific data on the target population's knowledge and practices. However, there is a shortage of data on the public's understanding of stroke and its risk factors in sub-Saharan Africa.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study is aimed at assessing the knowledge of chronic disease patients about stroke risk factors, prevention methods, treatment options, and associated factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This cross-sectional study was conducted in southern Ethiopia from February to April 2024. A total of 430 chronic disease patients were included by systematic random sampling. Data were collected using a structured questionnaire and medical records. Statistical analysis was performed using SPSS. Ethical clearance was obtained.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 430 patients participated, with hypertension being the most prevalent chronic disease. Only 25.1% demonstrated good knowledge of stroke risk factors. In multivariable analysis, good knowledge of stroke risk factors was significantly associated with receiving care in private institutions (AOR = 2.6; 95% CI: 1.1-5.9), having a degree or higher education (AOR = 6.5; 95% CI: 1.9-21.9), urban residence (AOR = 3.3; 95% CI: 1.4-7.9), family history of stroke (AOR = 5.3; 95% CI: 2.1-13.0), appropriate follow-up (AOR = 3.4; 95% CI: 1.4-8.4), and prior information from healthcare providers (AOR = 2.2; 95% CI: 1.0-4.5). In contrast, merchants, farmers/housewives, and other occupational groups had significantly lower odds of good knowledge compared with employees. Some estimates showed wide confidence intervals, indicating limited precision and the need for cautious interpretation. Awareness of treatment and prevention methods was limited, with only 33.3% answering over 50% of prevention questions correctly.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study revealed a significant lack of knowledge about stroke risk factors and prevention methods among chronic disease patients in southern Ethiopia. This highlights the urgent need for targeted health education interventions. Implementing comprehensive health promotion programs that address stroke-related knowledge gaps is crucial. These should be tailored to specific demographics and delivered through various channels, healthcare settings, communities, and media.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Takla Tamir et al. Behavioural Neurology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tamir</LastName><ForeName>Takla</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3037-8341</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Science, Dilla University, Dilla, Ethiopia, du.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yizelkal</LastName><ForeName>Selamawit</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, College of Medicine and Health Science, Dilla University, Dilla, Ethiopia, du.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girma</LastName><ForeName>Bekahegn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5504-6047</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Science, Dilla University, Dilla, Ethiopia, du.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gessesse</LastName><ForeName>Abraham Dessie</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-8356-4460</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Science, Dilla University, Dilla, Ethiopia, du.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimekaw</LastName><ForeName>Atrsaw</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4084-7826</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Science, Dilla University, Dilla, Ethiopia, du.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Dilla University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Behav Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8914585</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0953-4180</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000079102" MajorTopicYN="Y">Empowerment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment awareness</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/bn/7202918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Johnson W., Onuma O., Owolabi M., and Sachdev S., Stroke: A Global Response Is Needed, Bulletin of the World Health Organization. (2016) 94, no. 9, 634, https://doi.org/10.2471/BLT.16.181636, 2-s2.0-84986208233, 27708464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27708464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2032;donnell M. J., Xavier D., Liu L., Zhang H., Chin S. L., Rao-Melacini P., Rangarajan S., Islam S., Pais P., MJ M. Q., and Mondo C., Risk Factors for Ischaemic and Intracerebral Haemorrhagic Stroke in 22 Countries (the INTERSTROKE Study): A Case-Control Study, Lancet. (2010) 376, no. 9735, 112&#x2013;123, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(10)60834-3, 2-s2.0-77955014011, 20561675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20561675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin V. L., Forouzanfar M. H., Krishnamurthi R., Mensah G. A., Connor M., Bennett D. A., Moran A. E., Sacco R. L., Anderson L., Truelsen T., O&#x2032;Donnell M., Venketasubramanian N., Barker-Collo S., Lawes C. M., Wang W., Shinohara Y., Witt E., Ezzati M., Naghavi M., Murray C., and Global Burden of Diseases, Injuries, and Risk Factors Study 2010 (GBD 2010) and the GBD Stroke Experts Group, Global and Regional Burden of Stroke During 1990&#x2013;2010: Findings From the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010, Lancet. (2014) 383, no. 9913, 245&#x2013;255, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(13)61953-4, 2-s2.0-84892515796, 24449944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24449944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deresse B. and Shaweno D., Epidemiology and In-Hospital Outcome of Stroke in South Ethiopia, Journal of the Neurological Sciences. (2015) 355, no. 1-2, 138&#x2013;142, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2015.06.001, 2-s2.0-84937516026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansa V., Oyo-Ita A., and Essien O., Perception of Ischaemic Heart Disease, Knowledge of and Attitude to Reduction of Its Risk Factors, East African Medical Journal. (2007) 84, no. 7, 318&#x2013;323, 17886425, https://doi.org/10.4314/eamj.v84i7.9586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17886425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virani S. S., Alonso A., Aparicio H. J., Benjamin E. J., Bittencourt M. S., Callaway C. W., Carson A. P., Chamberlain A. M., Cheng S., Delling F. N., Elkind M. S., and on Behalf of the American Heart Association Council on Epidemiology and Prevention Statistics Committee and Stroke Statistics Subcommittee, Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics&#x2014;2021 Update, Circulation. (2021) 143, no. 8, [published online ahead of print January 27, 2021]https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capirossi C., Laiso A., Renieri L., Capasso F., and Limbucci N., Epidemiology, Organization, Diagnosis and Treatment of Acute Ischemic Stroke, European Journal of Radiology Open. (2023) 11, 100527, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejro.2023.100527, 37860148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37860148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaste M., World Stroke Day, Stroke. (2011) 42, no. 10, 2715, https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.111.633859, 2-s2.0-80053296632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Courten M., Dan L., Uele F., Macdonald N., Prior J., Riley L. A., Raj S., Hughes R., Naidu S., and Misi N., American Samoa NCD Risk Factors STEPS Report: A Collaborative Effort Between the Department of Health, World Health Organization and Monash University, Australia, Supported by the Australian Agency for International Development, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amen M. R., Assessment of Hypertensive Patients&#x2019; Knowledge About Lifestyle Risk Factors and Warning Signs of Stroke, Journal of Contemporary Medical Sciences. (2016) 2, no. 5, 28&#x2013;32, https://doi.org/10.22317/jcms.v2i5.64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott H. and Sim F., Unit: Public Health Aspects of Stroke Workbook, 2010, Lorraine Williams and Fiona Sim, London.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appiah K. O., Minhas J. S., and Robinson T. G., Managing High Blood Pressure During Acute Ischemic Stroke and Intracerebral Hemorrhage, Current Opinion in Neurology. (2018) 31, no. 1, 8&#x2013;13, https://doi.org/10.1097/WCO.0000000000000508, 2-s2.0-85039759129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell K., Twiggs J., Olin B. R., and Date I. R., Hypertension: The Silent Killer: Updated JNC-8 Guideline Recommendations, Alabama Pharmacy Association. (2015) 334, 4222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahbanathul M. and John J., Assess the Prevalence of Hypertension and Knowledge Regarding the Prevention of Stroke, Asian Journal of Pharmaceutical and Clinical Research. (2017) 10, no. 8, 177&#x2013;180, https://doi.org/10.22159/ajpcr.2017.v10i8.18558, 2-s2.0-85026823217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arisegi S. A., Awosan K. J., Oche M. O., Sabir A. A., and Ibrahim M. T., Knowledge and Practices Related to Stroke Prevention Among Hypertensive and Diabetic Patients Attending Specialist Hospital, Sokoto, Nigeria. Pan African Medical Journal. (2018) 29, no. 1, 1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tibebu N. S., Emiru T. D., Tiruneh C. M., Nigat A. B., Abate M. W., and Demelash A. T., Knowledge on Prevention of Stroke and Its Associated Factors Among Hypertensive Patients at Debre Tabor General Hospital: An Institution-Based Cross-Sectional Study, Risk Management and Healthcare Policy. (2021) Volume 14, 1681, https://doi.org/10.2147/RMHP.S303876, 33911905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33911905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon S. S., Heller R. F., Levi C., Wiggers J., and Fitzgerald P. E., Knowledge Of Stroke Risk Factors, Warning Symptoms, And Treatment Among An Australian Urban Population, Stroke. (2001) 32, no. 8, 1926&#x2013;1930, https://doi.org/10.1161/01.STR.32.8.1926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saengsuwan J., Suangpho P., and Tiamkao S., Knowledge of Stroke Risk Factors and Warning Signs in Patients With Recurrent Stroke or Recurrent Transient Ischaemic Attack in Thailand, Neurology Research International. (2017) 2017, 7, https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/8215726, 2-s2.0-85042412955, 29130000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29130000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindsay M., Norrving B., Furie K. L., Donnan G., Langhorne P., and Davis S., Global Stroke Guidelines and Action Plan: A Road Map for Quality Stroke Care, 2016, World Stroke Organization, Geneva.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed O. A. A., Ahmed F. A., Koko A. E., Khalifa S. E., Abdelaziz H. A., Mohamed M. E., Harrington F., Abdelaziz S. I., and Abdalrahman I. B., Awareness About Stroke Among High and Low Risk Individuals in Khartoum, Sudan: A Cross-Sectional Study, Pan African Medical Journal. (2020) 36, 318&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abate A. T., Bayu N., and Mariam T. G., Hypertensive Patients&#x2019; Knowledge of Risk Factors and Warning Signs of Stroke at Felege Hiwot Referral Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia: A Cross-Sectional Study, Neurology Research International. (2019) 2019, 8570428, https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/8570428, 2-s2.0-85068967219, 31341680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31341680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legese Y. G., Gethachew H., Akmel F., and Deme S., Knowledge, Attitude, and Practice of Stroke and Its Risk Factors and Warning Symptoms in Ethiopia, BMC Neurology. (2025) 25, no. 1, 1&#x2013;10, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12883-025-04479-9, 41188748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41188748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getu R. A., Aga F., Badada T., Workie S. G., Belew M. A., and MekonnenRN K., Knowledge of Stroke Risk Factors and Warning Symptoms Among Adults With Type 2 Diabetes in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2021: An Institution-Based Cross-Sectional Study, BMC Cardiovascular Disorders. (2023) 23, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12872-022-03031-8, 36646999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36646999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniyi A., Idowu O., Ogwumike O., and Adeniyi C., Comparative Influence of Self-Efficacy, Social Support and Perceived Barriers on Low Physical Activity Development in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes, Hypertension or Stroke, Ethiopian Journal of Health Sciences. (2012) 22, no. 2, 113&#x2013;119, 22876075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22876075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X., Xu M., Yang L., Gao Z., Kuang J., and Zhou K., Determinants Influencing Health-Promoting Behaviors in Individuals at High Risk of Stroke: A Cross-Sectional Study, Health Education &amp; Behavior. (2024) 51, no. 3, 457&#x2013;466, https://doi.org/10.1177/10901981231160149, 36960724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36960724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alrawili N. K. A., Alanazi S. N., Alanazi S. N., Rikabi H. A., Abdulkareem E. M., and Eltaib L., Public Awareness and Knowledge of Stroke Risk Factors and Symptoms in Saudi Arabia: A Cross-Sectional Study, ARYA Atherosclerosis. (2025) 21, no. 4, 26&#x2013;35, https://doi.org/10.48305/arya.2025.43466.3027, 40893717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40893717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis C., Barley J., and Grubaugh A., Poststroke Knowledge and Symptom Awareness: A Global Issue for Secondary Stroke Prevention, Cerebrovascular Diseases. (2013) 35, no. 6, 572&#x2013;581, https://doi.org/10.1159/000351209, 2-s2.0-84879771331, 23838851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23838851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dar N. Z., Khan S. A., Ahmad A., and Maqsood S., Awareness of Stroke and Health-Seeking Practices Among Hypertensive Patients in a Tertiary Care Hospital: A Cross-Sectional Survey, Cureus. (2019) 11, no. 5, https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.4774, e4774, 31367493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31367493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elnady H. M., Mohammed G. F., Elhewag H. K., Mohamed M. K., and Borai A., Risk Factors for Early and Late Recurrent Ischemic Strokes, Egyptian Journal of Neurology, Psychiatry and Neurosurgery. (2020) 56, no. 1, 1&#x2013;7, https://doi.org/10.1186/s41983-020-00190-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Workina A., Kebede S., Fekadu C., and Wubetie A., Knowledge of Risk Factors and Warning Signs of Stroke Among Patients With Heart Disease at Tikur Anbessa Specialized Hospital, Open Access Emergency Medicine. (2021) Volume 13, 57&#x2013;66, https://doi.org/10.2147/OAEM.S291648, 33623445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33623445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alloubani A., Saleh A., and Abdelhafiz I., Hypertension and Diabetes Mellitus as a Predictive Risk Factors for Stroke, Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome: Clinical Research &amp; Reviews. (2018) 12, no. 4, 577&#x2013;584, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2018.03.009, 2-s2.0-85044134302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong H., Foody J. A., Linong J., Dong Z., Wang Y., Ma L., Meng H. J., Shiff S., and Dayi H., A Systematic Literature Review of Risk Factors for Stroke in China, Cardiology in Review. (2013) 21, no. 2, 77&#x2013;93, https://doi.org/10.1097/CRD.0b013e3182748d37, 2-s2.0-84873732518, 22990372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22990372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mc Lernon S., Appiah B., Moorley C., Thomas N., Mussa R., Gonzales S., Werring D., Olawade D. B., and Flood C., Public Awareness of Stroke Risk Factors in High-Income Countries: A Systematic Review, Journal of Stroke and Cerebrovascular Diseases. (2025) 34, no. 12, 108501, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2025.108501, 41276196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41276196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldetsadik F. K., Kassa T., Bilchut W. H., Kibret A., Guadie Y. G., and Eriku G. A., Stroke Related Knowledge, Prevention Practices and Associated Factors Among Hypertensive Patients at University of Gondar Comprehensive Specialized Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia, 2021, Frontiers in Neurology. (2022) 13, 839879, https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2022.839879, 35518203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35518203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negesa L. B., Magarey J., Rasmussen P., and Hendriks J. M. L., Patients&#x2019; Knowledge on Cardiovascular Risk Factors and Associated Lifestyle Behaviour in Ethiopia in 2018: A Cross-Sectional Study, Plos One. (2020) 15, no. 6, e0234198, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0234198, 32497079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaeb D., Mansour S., Barakat M., Cherri S., Kharaba Z. J., Jirjees F., al Zayer R., Eltayib E. M., Khidhair Z., AlObaidi H., el Khatib S., Alex R., Menon V., Hosseini B., Noureldine J., Alfoteih Y., Hallit S., and Hosseini H., Assessment of Knowledge and Awareness of Stroke Among Arabic Speaking Adults: Unveiling the Current Landscape in Seven Countries Through the First International Representative Study, Frontiers in Neurology. (2024) 15, 1492756, https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2024.1492756, 39650244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39650244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessup R. L., Osborne R. H., Beauchamp A., Bourne A., and Buchbinder R., Differences in Health Literacy Profiles of Patients Admitted to a Public and a Private Hospital in Melbourne,Australia, BMC Health Services Research. (2018) 18, no. 1, 1&#x2013;10, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-018-2921-4, 2-s2.0-85042525440, 29471836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29471836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durmu&#x15f; V., Differences in Health Literacy Level of Patients From Public and Private Hospitals: A Cross-Sectional Study in Turkey, Public Health. (2021) 200, 77&#x2013;83, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.puhe.2021.09.016, 34710717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Staden D., Deutshmann L. P., Ganas S., Manickam M., Manillal A., Ndlovu N. S., Nkosi N. G., and Oduntan O. A., Knowledge of Diabetes Mellitus and Its Ocular Complications Amongst Diabetic Patients Attending Private and Public Hospitals in eThekwini Municipality, KwaZulu-Natal Province, South Africa, African Vision and Eye Health. (2015) 74, no. 1, a36, https://doi.org/10.4102/aveh.v74i1.36, 2-s2.0-85057214293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atinga R. A., Bawole J. N., and Nang-Beifubah A., &#x2018;Some Patients Are More Equal Than Others&#x2019;: Patient-Centred Care Differential in Two-Tier Inpatient Ward Hospitals in Ghana, Patient Education and Counseling. (2016) 99, no. 3, 370&#x2013;377, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2015.09.008, 2-s2.0-84959156067, 26475729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26475729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaksson D., Blomqvist P., Pingel R., and Winblad U., Risk Selection in Primary Care: A Cross-Sectional Fixed Effect Analysis of Swedish Individual Data, BMJ Open. (2018) 8, no. 10, e020402, https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2017-020402, 2-s2.0-85055603854, 30355789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stack K., Robertson W., and Blackburn C., Does Socioeconomic Position Affect Knowledge of the Risk Factors and Warning Signs of Stroke in the WHO European Region? A Systematic Literature Review, BMC Public Health. (2020) 20, no. 1, 1&#x2013;12, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-020-09580-x, 32993624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent-Onabajo G. and Moses T., Knowledge of Stroke Risk Factors Among Stroke Survivors in Nigeria, Stroke Research and Treatment. (2016) 2016, no. 1, 5, https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/1902151, 2-s2.0-84997471125, 27882262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albalawi M. F., Shaqran T., Alhawiti S. H., Alwadiee A. S., Albalawi Y. M., and Albalawi W. H., Effect of an Educational Intervention on Knowledge and Perception of Individuals at Risk for Stroke in Tabuk, Saudi Arabia, Saudi Arabia. Neurosciences Journal. (2020) 25, no. 1, 18&#x2013;24, https://doi.org/10.17712/nsj.2020.1.20190018, 31982891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31982891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman D. and Smith J. P., The Increasing Value of Education to Health, Social Science &amp; Medicine. (2011) 72, no. 10, 1728&#x2013;1737, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.02.047, 2-s2.0-79955978636, 21555176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21555176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;ngora-Rivera F., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Aquines A., Muruet W., Barrera-Barrera S., Leal-Bailey H., Espinosa-Ortega M. A., Patr&#xf3;n-de Trevi&#xf1;o A., Jacobo-Saucedo L. A., Villarreal-Velazquez H. J., Garcia-Ortiz W., Saucedo-Ostos Y. Y., Cordero-Perez A. C., and Chavez-Luevanos B. E., Difference in Stroke Knowledge Between Rural and Urban Communities in a Developing Country After Community-Based Stroke Educational Campaigns: Results From a Cross-Sectional Study, Neuroepidemiology. (2018) 51, no. 3-4, 224&#x2013;229, https://doi.org/10.1159/000490724, 2-s2.0-85054783422, 30293077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30293077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla S., Mohamed E., and Elsabagh H., Stroke Perception and Risk Factors Knowledge Within Saudi Population, Ethics, Medicine and Public Health. (2022) 20, 100736, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jemep.2021.100736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz E., Lundvall B. &#xc5;., Kraemer-Mbula E., and Rasmussen P., Work Organisation, Forms of Employee Learning and National Systems of Education and Training, European Journal of Education. (2016) 51, no. 2, 154&#x2013;175, https://doi.org/10.1111/ejed.12177, 2-s2.0-84966705290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forster A., Brown L., Smith J., House A., Knapp P., Wright J. J., Young J., and Cochrane Stroke Group, Information Provision for Stroke Patients and Their Caregivers, Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. (2012) 11, no. 11, https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD001919.pub3, CD001919, 23152210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23152210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coombes J. A., Rowett D., Whitty J. A., and Cottrell N. W., Using a Structured, Patient-Centred, Educational Exchange to Facilitate a Shared Conversation About Stroke Prevention Medications, Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice. (2020) 26, no. 2, 635&#x2013;644, https://doi.org/10.1111/jep.13263, 2-s2.0-85070760118, 31418498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31418498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang J., Luo C., Ke S., and Tung T. H., Stroke Related Knowledge, Prevention Practices and Associated Factors Among Stroke Patients in Taizhou, China, Preventive Medicine Reports. (2023) 35, 102340, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmedr.2023.102340, 37576842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37576842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>