<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41721259</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2253</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC anesthesiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Anesthesiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nomogram prediction model for delayed extubation in patients undergoing robotic-assisted radical prostatectomy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">197</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12871-026-03693-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Delayed extubation after anesthesia can lead to adverse clinical outcomes. We aimed to identify the risk factors for delayed extubation in patients undergoing robot-assisted radical prostatectomy and to develop a visualized nomogram prediction model for clinical use.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 624 patients were enrolled and divided into training group, validation group, and temporal validation group. The training group was utilized to develop a nomogram, whereas the validation group and temporal validation group were used to assess its performance. LASSO regression was employed to refine variables and select predictors, and a nomogram was constructed using multivariate logistic regression. The performance of the model was internally validated using calibration and receiver operating characteristic curves. Additionally, decision curve analysis and clinical impact curves were used to assess the clinical utility of the model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Patients who underwent robot-assisted radical prostatectomy between January 2022 and April 2024 were included and divided into a training group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;389), a validation group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;98), and a temporal validation group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;137). Logistic regression identified cerebral infarction, pulmonary disease, coronary heart disease, age, and intraoperative hypotension as independent predictors of delayed extubation. A nomogram constructed based on these factors demonstrated excellent predictive performance, with area under the curve values of 0.763 (95% CI: 0.717&#x2013;0.810) in the training group, 0.811 (95% CI: 0.726&#x2013;0.897) in the validation group, and 0.769 (95% CI: 0.689&#x2013;0.848) in the temporal validation group. Across all three groups, the model demonstrated a good fit, as indicated by a non-significant P-value from the Hosmer&#x2013;Lemeshow test, and the calibration curves indicated a strong alignment between the predictions and actual observations. Furthermore, decision curve analysis and clinical impact curve demonstrated the clinical efficiency and benefits of the prediction model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study identified key risk factors for delayed extubation and established an effective predictive nomogram with high discriminative power and clinical applicability for predicting the risk of extubation delay in patients undergoing robot-assisted radical prostatectomy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">The Medical Ethics Committee of Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital granted ethical approval for this research(grant number: 2024&#x2013;742-01).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Tantan</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School, 321 Zhongshan Road, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chuanfei</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School, 321 Zhongshan Road, Nanjing, 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoping</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, The Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School, 321 Zhongshan Road, Nanjing, 210008, China. xiaopinggu@nju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Anesthesiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968535</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2253</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Airway extubation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anesthesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nomogram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prostate cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robotic-assisted radical prostatectomy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Medical Ethics Committee of Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital with the reference number 2024&#x2013;742-01, and in compliance with the Helsinki Declaration. Given that this study was conducted using anonymized observational data, individual informed consent for participation was waived by the Committee on Medical Ethics of Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41721259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13032207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-026-03693-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12871-026-03693-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zirka HA, John GG, Laura CL, Joanna LM, Eric JH, Mitchell F. Factors that correlate with the decision to delay extubation after multilevel prone spine surgery. J Neurosurg Anesthesiol. 2014;26(2):167&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ANA.0000000000000028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24296539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshua C, Toyokazu E, Matthew F. Tracheal resection for post-intubation/post-tracheostomy tracheal stenosis. Thorac Surg Clin. 2025;35(1):61&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.thorsurg.2024.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39515896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines for the Management of Adults with Hospital-acquired. Ventilator-associated, and Healthcare-associated Pneumonia. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005;171(4):388&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200405-644ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker J, Martino R, Reichardt B, Hickey EJ, Ralph-Edwards A. Incidence and impact of dysphagia in patients receiving prolonged endotracheal intubation after cardiac surgery. Can J Surg. 2009;52(2):119&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2663495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19399206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon MC, Abdoh A, Hamilton GA, Lindsay WG, Duke PC, Pascoe EA, et al. Safety and efficacy of fast track in patients undergoing coronary artery bypass surgery. J Card Surg. 2001;16(4):319&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1540-8191.2001.tb00528.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11833706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg H, Antognini JF, Muldoon S. Testing for malignant hyperthermia. Anesthesiology. 2002;96(1):232&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000542-200201000-00036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11753023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein RH, Dexter F, Cajigas I, Mahavadi AK, Shah AH, Abitbol N, et al. Prolonged tracheal extubation time after glioma surgery was associated with lack of familiarity between the anesthesia provider and the operating neurosurgeon. A retrospective, observational study. J Clin Anesthesia. 2020;60(0):118&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinane.2019.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31669746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2018. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018;68:7&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29313949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Siegel RL, Torre LA, Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018;68(6):394&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30207593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy GW, Gore JL, Forouzanfar MH, Naghavi M, Fitzmaurice C. Global burden of urologic cancers, 1990&#x2013;2013. Eur Urol. 2017;71(3):437&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2016.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28029399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong MC, Goggins WB, Wang HH, Fung FD, Leung C. Global incidence and mortality for prostate cancer: analysis of temporal patterns and trends in 36 countries. Eur Urol. 2016;70(5):862&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eururo.2016.05.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27289567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes T, Rai B, Madaan S, Chedgy E, Somani B. The availability, cost, limitations, learning curve and future of robotic systems in urology and prostate cancer surgery. J Clin Med. 2023;12(6):2268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12062268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10053304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36983269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel VR, Coelho RF, Chauhan S, Orvieto MA, Palmer KJ, Rocco B, et al. Continence, potency and oncological outcomes after robotic&#x2010;assisted radical prostatectomy: early trifecta results of a high&#x2010;volume surgeon. BJU Int. 2010;106(5):696&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1464-410X.2010.09541.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20707793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura T, Egawa S. Epidemiology of prostate cancer in Asian countries. Int J Urol. 2018;25(6):524&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iju.13593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong C, Miao Q, Zheng J, Wu J. A novel nomogram for predicting the decision to delayed extubation after thoracoscopic lung cancer surgery. Ann Med. 2023;55(1):800&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2022.2160490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9987746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36869647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veyckemans F, von Ungern&#x2010;Sternberg B. Tracheal extubation in children: planning, technique, and complications. Paediatr Anaesth. 2020;30(3):331&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pan.13774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31769576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vannucci A, Riordan IR, Prifti K, Sebastiani A, Helsten DL, Lander DP, et al. Prolonged time to extubation after general anaesthesia is associated with early escalation of care. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2021;38(5):494&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/EJA.0000000000001316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandell MS, Stoner TJ, Barnett R, Shaked A, Bellamy M, Biancofiore G, et al. A multicenter evaluation of safety of early extubation in liver transplant recipients. Liver Transpl. 2007;13(11):1557&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lt.21263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17969193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady K, Hogue CW. Intraoperative hypotension and patient outcome: does &#x201c;one size fit all?&#x201d; Anesthesiology. 2013;119(3):495&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0b013e3182a10cce</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5508107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23835588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch J, DePalma G, Tsai TT, Sands LP, Leung JM. Impact of intraoperative hypotension and blood pressure fluctuations on early postoperative delirium after non-cardiac surgery. Br J Anaesth. 2015;115(3):418&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aeu458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4533731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25616677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijker JB, Persoon S, Peelen LM, Moons KG, Kalkman CJ. Intraoperative hypotension and perioperative ischemic stroke after general surgery: a nested case-control study. Anesthesiology. 2012;116(3):658&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0b013e3182472320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22277949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmasi V, Maheshwari K, Yang D, Mascha EJ, Singh A. Relationship between intraoperative hypotension, defined by either reduction from baseline or absolute thresholds, and acute kidney and myocardial injury after noncardiac surgery: a retrospective cohort analysis. Anesthesiology. 2017;126(1):47&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000001432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27792044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. Univariate description and bivariate statistical inference: the first step delving into data. Ann Transl Med. 2016;4(5):91&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/atm.2016.02.11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4791343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27047950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S-S, Tian Y, Ma Y-J, Zhou Y-M, Tian Y, Gao R, et al. Development of a prediction score for evaluation of extubation readiness in neurosurgical patients with mechanical ventilation. Anesthesiology. 2023;139(5):614&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000004721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10566588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37535470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LG, Monta&#xf1;o AR, Masillati AM, Jones JA, Barth CW, Combs JR, et al. Nerve visualization using phenoxazine&#x2010;based near&#x2010;infrared fluorophores to guide prostatectomy. Adv Mater. 2024;36(16):e2304724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202304724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37653576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasian ZH, Kim M, Heyer EJ, Wang S, Berman MF. Attending handoff is correlated with the decision to delay extubation after surgery. Anesth Analg. 2016;122(3):758&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/ANE.0000000000001069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26649911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Liu J, Xu Z, Wang Y, Chen L, Bai Y, et al. Early identification of delayed extubation following cardiac surgery: development and validation of a risk prediction model. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9(0):1002768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.1002768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9576842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36267640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Tan R, Lin J-W, Li G, Xie J. Development of prediction models to estimate extubation time and midterm recovery time of ophthalmic patients undergoing general anesthesia: a cross-sectional study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2023;23(1):83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-023-02021-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10022177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36932318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Liu Y, Li W, Zhang C, Zhang X, Wang F, et al. Analysis of factors affecting smooth extubation in delayed extubation patients following intracranial surgery: an ambispective cohort study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2025;25(1):531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-025-03394-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12573943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41163173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasera CC, Gewehr PM, Domingues AMT. PET(CO2) measurement and feature extraction of capnogram signals for extubation outcomes from mechanical ventilation. Physiol Meas. 2015;36(2):231&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0967-3334/36/2/231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25582400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Zhang Y, Che L, Shen L, Huang Y. Risk factors for unplanned reintubation caused by acute airway compromise after general anesthesia: a case-control study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2021;21(1):17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-021-01238-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33435881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene NH, Lee LA. Modern and evolving understanding of cerebral perfusion and autoregulation. Adv Anesth. 2012;30(1):97&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aan.2012.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5339023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28275288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julian Y. Anaesthesia in chronic dialysis patients: a narrative review. World J Crit Care Med. 2025;14(1):100503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11671837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40060737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chetty M, Johnson TN, Polak S, Salem F, Doki K. Physiologically based pharmacokinetic modelling to guide drug delivery in older people. Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2018;135(0):85&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addr.2018.08.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30189273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torrez JP, Otsuki DA, Zeferino SP, Sanchez AF, Auler JO Jr, Zeferino S, et al. Vasoplegic syndrome following bypass: a comprehensive review of pathophysiology and proposed treatments. Cureus. 2025;17(1):e78057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11863290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40013224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>