<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41927531</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antiferroelectric polarization enabling physical activation in CuBiP<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>6</sub> for medical image processing.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70594-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Antiferroelectric materials, featuring field controllable antipolar ordering and reversible polarization switching, offer a promising platform for hardware efficient neuromorphic computing. The tunable polarization dynamics and layered van der Waals structure enable the multifunctional integration of sensing, learning, and computation within a single device architecture. Here, we demonstrate an antiferroelectric polarization driven diode exhibiting an extended linear operating region, which simultaneously enables physical activation and computing-in-memory. Building on the device capability, we construct an in-sensor computing system that achieves over 95% accuracy in medical image classification. We further integrate the devices to demonstrate a hardware-based activation function, attaining accuracy and training loss comparable to an ideal activation function. To enhance adaptability, we further propose a tunable activation circuit that enables linear modulation of the reverse bias slope via gain control. Overall, this work establishes a dual-functional antiferroelectric heterojunction, highlighting its strong potential for constructing optically triggered, compact, and low-power perception-computation-integrated neuromorphic systems for medical image processing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yinan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Quantum Physics, Key Laboratory of Advanced Optoelectronic Quantum Architecture and Measurement (MOE), School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Lab of Nanophotonics &amp; Ultra fine Optoelectronic Systems, School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Dongliang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Quantum Physics, Key Laboratory of Advanced Optoelectronic Quantum Architecture and Measurement (MOE), School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Lab of Nanophotonics &amp; Ultra fine Optoelectronic Systems, School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhongyi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Quantum Matter, School of Physics, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhen</LastName><ForeName>Weili</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Quantum Physics, Key Laboratory of Advanced Optoelectronic Quantum Architecture and Measurement (MOE), School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Lab of Nanophotonics &amp; Ultra fine Optoelectronic Systems, School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Tianze</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Quantum Physics, Key Laboratory of Advanced Optoelectronic Quantum Architecture and Measurement (MOE), School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Lab of Nanophotonics &amp; Ultra fine Optoelectronic Systems, School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xue</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9039-7088</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Quantum Matter, School of Physics, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Hongtao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, National Clinical Research Center for Digestive Disease, Xicheng District, Beijing, China. wht001@mail.ccmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Linfeng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5851-8206</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Quantum Physics, Key Laboratory of Advanced Optoelectronic Quantum Architecture and Measurement (MOE), School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China. sunlinfeng@bit.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Key Lab of Nanophotonics &amp; Ultra fine Optoelectronic Systems, School of Physics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China. sunlinfeng@bit.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. Z210006</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Beijing Municipality (Beijing Natural Science Foundation)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41927531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70594-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70594-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Guan Y. et al. World models for autonomous driving: an initial survey. IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh. 1&#x2013;17 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha, T. et al. AI-driven robotic chemist for autonomous synthesis of organic molecules. Sci. Adv. 9, eadj0461 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. et al. DriveGPT4: interpretable end-to-end autonomous driving via a large language model. IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett. 9, 8186&#x2013;8193 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X. et al. Vision language models in autonomous driving: a survey and outlook. IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh. 1&#x2013;20 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X. et al. A review of convolutional neural networks in computer vision. Artif. Intell. Rev. 57, 99 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, B., Kr&#xe4;henb&#xfc;hl, P. &amp; Koltun, V. Does computer vision matter for action? Sci. Robot. 4, eaaw6661 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Deep learning based 3D segmentation in computer vision: a survey. Inf. Fusion 115, 102722 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauriola, I., Lavelli, A. &amp; Aiolli, F. An introduction to deep learning in natural language processing: models, techniques, and tools. Neurocomputing 470, 443&#x2013;456 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasidhar, K. N. et al. Enhancing corrosion-resistant alloy design through natural language processing and deep learning. Sci. Adv. 9, eadg7992 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschberg, J. &amp; Manning, C. D. Advances in natural language processing. Science 349, 261&#x2013;266 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khurana, D., Koli, A., Khatter, K. &amp; Singh, S. Natural language processing: state of the art, current trends and challenges. Multimed. Tools Appl. 82, 3713&#x2013;3744 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., Ye Q. &amp; Doermann D. YOLOv12: attention-centric real-time object detectors. Preprint at: arXivhttps://arxiv.org/abs/2502.12524 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy, A. et al. An image is worth 16x16 words: transformers for image recognition at scale. In International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, K., Zhang, X., Ren, S. &amp; Sun, J. Deep residual learning for image recognition. In Proc. IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 770&#x2013;778 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touvron, H. et al. LLaMA: open and efficient foundation language models. Preprint at https://arxiv.org/abs/2302.13971 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani, A. et al. Attention is all you need. In Proc. 31st International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) 5998&#x2013;6008 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, S. et al. A survey on multimodal large language models. Natl. Sci. Rev. 11, nwae403 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford, A. et al. Learning transferable visual models from natural language supervision. In Proc. 38th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 8748&#x2013;8763 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Li, D., Xiong, C. &amp; Hoi, S. BLIP: bootstrapping language-image pre-training for unified vision-language understanding and generation. In Proceedings of the 39th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 12888&#x2013;12900 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W. et al. Neuro-inspired computing chips. Nat. Electron. 3, 371&#x2013;382 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo, Q. et al. A computing-in-memory macro based on three-dimensional resistive random-access memory. Nat. Electron. 5, 469&#x2013;477 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasch, M. J. et al. Hardware-aware training for large-scale and diverse deep learning inference workloads using in-memory computing-based accelerators. Nat. Commun. 14, 5282 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, V. et al. Accurate deep neural network inference using computational phase-change memory. Nat. Commun. 11, 2473 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanpour, M., Riera, M. &amp; Gonz&#xe1;lez, A. A survey of near-data processing architectures for neural networks. Mach. Learn. Knowl. Extr. 4, 66&#x2013;102 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita, R., Nishio, M., Do, R. K. G. &amp; Togashi, K. Convolutional neural networks: an overview and application in radiology. Insights Imaging 9, 611&#x2013;629 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu B., Wang N., Chen T. &amp; Li M. Empirical evaluation of rectified activations in convolutional network. Preprint at: arXiv https://arxiv.org/abs/1505.00853 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, R. et al. Compact artificial neuron based on anti-ferroelectric transistor. Nat. Commun. 13, 7018 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, J. et al. Reconfigurable neuromorphic functions in antiferroelectric transistors through coupled polarization switching and charge trapping dynamics. Nat. Commun. 16, 4368 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, G. et al. Full hardware implementation of neuromorphic visual system based on multimodal optoelectronic resistive memory arrays for versatile image processing. Nat. Commun. 14, 8489 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, W. et al. A compute-in-memory chip based on resistive random-access memory. Nature 608, 504&#x2013;512 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, X., Huang, S., Jiang, H., Lu, A. &amp; Yu, S. DNN+NeuroSim V2.0: an end-to-end benchmarking framework for compute-in-memory accelerators for on-chip training. IEEE Trans. Comput. Aided Des. Integr. Circuits Syst. 40, 2306&#x2013;2319 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, T., Zhong-liang, W., Guo-qiang, N. &amp; Li-qiang, T. NLOS single scattering model in digital UV communication. Proc. SPIE 7158 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krestinskaya, O., Salama, K. N. &amp; James, A. P. Learning in memristive neural network architectures using analog backpropagation circuits. IEEE Trans. Circuits Syst. I: Regul. Pap. 66, 719&#x2013;732 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, S. et al. Energy-efficient Mott activation neuron for full-hardware implementation of neural networks. Nat. Nanotechnol. 16, 680&#x2013;687 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, J. et al. Preventing vanishing gradient problem of hardware neuromorphic system by implementing imidazole-based memristive ReLU activation neuron. Adv. Mater. 35, e2300023 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, J. et al. An artificial L-ReLU neuron with asymmetric diffusive memristor for high-accuracy neuromorphic systems. Adv. Funct. Mater. 35 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, K. M. et al. In-plane and out-of-plane optical properties of monolayer, few-layer, and thin-film MoS2 from 190 to 1700 nm and their application in photonic device design. Adv. Photon. Res. 2 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, W., Kong, L., Yu, P. &amp; Yang, G. Record-high work-function p-type CuBiP(2) Se(6) atomic layers for high-photoresponse van der waals vertical heterostructure phototransistor. Adv. Mater. 35, e2209995 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. From bulk to monolayer MoS2: evolution of Raman scattering. Adv. Funct. Mater. 22, 1385&#x2013;1390 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. Y. et al. Large work function modulation of monolayer MoS2 by ambient gases. ACS Nano 10, 6100&#x2013;6107 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, C.-P., Li, G., Mao, J., Wang, L.-M. &amp; Andrei, E. Y. Bandgap, mid-gap states, and gating effects in MoS2. Nano Lett. 14, 4628&#x2013;4633 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, T., Jo, S.-H. &amp; Lu, W. Short-term memory to long-term memory transition in a nanoscale memristor. ACS Nano 5, 7669&#x2013;7676 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlynn, S. P. Concepts in photoconductivity and allied problems. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 86, 5707&#x2013;5707 (1964).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. MedMNIST v2 - a large-scale lightweight benchmark for 2D and 3D biomedical image classification. Sci. Data 10, 41 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chattopadhay, A., Sarkar, A., Howlader, P. &amp; Balasubramanian, V. N. Grad-CAM++: generalized gradient-based visual explanations for deep convolutional networks. In 2018 IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizhevsky A. Learning multiple layers of features from tiny images. University of Toronto, (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkhi, O. M., Vedaldi, A., Zisserman, A. &amp; Jawahar, C. V. Cats and dogs. In 2012 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 3498&#x2013;3505 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossard, L., Guillaumin, M. &amp; Van Gool, L. Food-101 &#x2013; mining discriminative components with random forests. In Computer Vision &#x2013; ECCV 2014 (eds. Fleet, D., Pajdla, T., Schiele, B. &amp; Tuytelaars, T.) (Springer International Publishing, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecun, Y., Bottou, L., Bengio, Y. &amp; Haffner, P. Gradient-based learning applied to document recognition. Proc. IEEE 86, 2278&#x2013;2324 (1998).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>