<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41608190</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-1078</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>When personal experience becomes professional power: how pre-service teachers discover their creative capacity during teaching internships.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1716459</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1716459</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1716459</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1716459</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Teacher education research has documented beginning teachers' struggles extensively, but we know surprisingly little about the innovative capabilities that emerge during intensive field experiences. This phenomenological study examines how 17 pre-service teachers, 16 women and one man, representing both Arab and Jewish students, aged 22-28, discovered their creative capacity during year-long teaching internships at an Israeli teacher training college. Through interpretative phenomenological analysis of in-depth interviews, we invited participants to share their most meaningful success stories about transformative work with individual students.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Through interpretative phenomenological analysis, three interconnected themes emerged.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">First, participants systematically transformed personal struggles into professional tools for healing, converting difficult life experiences into resources to support students facing similar challenges. Second, they developed sophisticated environmental awareness, paired with methodical relationship-building approaches that evolved from intuitive care into systematic professional practice. Third, they engaged in principled rule-breaking, prioritizing student success over institutional compliance and thoughtfully departing from conventional approaches when these failed to serve student needs. Our analysis reveals that pre-service teachers possess innovative potential that challenges deficit-focused perspectives dominating teacher preparation discourse.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This creative capacity flourishes when certain conditions are met: extended time for authentic relationship-building, supervision that encourages personal and professional integration, and institutional environments that support thoughtful innovation. Rather than viewing difficult life experiences as barriers to effective teaching, participants converted personal wisdom into professional resources. These findings suggest that teacher education needs fundamental rethinking. Rather than focusing primarily on fixing deficits, programs could recognize and systematically cultivate the creative power that emerges during intensive field experiences. This requires redesigned supervision approaches, curriculum modifications, and institutional structures that support principled innovation during teaching internships.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Diab and Green.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diab</LastName><ForeName>Al-Khansaa</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Special Education Department, David Yellin College of Education, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Edna</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Students' Dean Office, David Yellin College of Education, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550902</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-1078</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">innovation development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personal-professional integration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pre-service teachers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">success narratives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">teacher education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">teaching internships</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41608190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12835297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1716459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alase A. (2017). The interpretative phenomenological analysis (IPA): a guide to a good qualitative research approach. Int. J. Educ. Literacy Stud. 5, 9&#x2013;19. doi: 10.7575/aiac.ijels.v.5n.2p.9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7575/aiac.ijels.v.5n.2p.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almughyiri S. (2025). Influence of Bronfenbrenner ecological theory on career choices of preservice teachers of students with developmental disabilities. Sci. Rep. 15:29023. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-14958-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-14958-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12334688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40781120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amali N. A. K., Ridzuan M. U. M., Rahmat N. H., Seng H. Z., Mustafa N. C. (2023). Exploring learning environment through Bronfenbrenner's ecological systems theory. Int. J. Acad. Res. Progressive Educ. Dev. 12, 144&#x2013;162. doi: 10.6007/IJARPED/v12-i2/16516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6007/IJARPED/v12-i2/16516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnsby E. S., Aspfors J., Jacobsson K. (2023). Teachers' professional learning through mentor education: a longitudinal mixed-methods study. Educ. Inq. 16, 1&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1080/20004508.2023.2273019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20004508.2023.2273019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artola Bonanno A., Briesch A. M., Lifter K., Kemerer P. (2024). Measuring teacher-student relationships in adolescence: a systematic, cross-cultural review. Int. J. Sch. Educ. Psychol. 12, 96&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1080/21683603.2024.2328834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21683603.2024.2328834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacova D., Turner A. (2023). Teacher vulnerability in teacher identity in times of unexpected social change. Res. Post-Compulsory Educ. 28, 349&#x2013;372. doi: 10.1080/13596748.2023.2221115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13596748.2023.2221115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borremans E., Koomen H. M. Y., Spilt J. L. (2024). Fostering teacher-student relationship-building competence: a three-year learning trajectory for initial pre-primary and primary teacher education. Front. Educ. 9:1349532. doi: 10.3389/feduc.2024.1349532</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feduc.2024.1349532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V., Clarke V. (2019). Reflecting on reflexive thematic analysis. Qual. Res. Sport, Exercise Health 11, 589&#x2013;597. doi: 10.1080/2159676X.2019.1628806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2159676X.2019.1628806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner C. A. (2022). Self-regulated learning, self-determination theory and teacher candidates' development of competency-based teaching practices. Smart Learn. Environ. 9:3. doi: 10.1186/s40561-021-00184-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40561-021-00184-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronfenbrenner U. (1979). The Ecology of Human Development: Experiments by Nature and Design. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press. doi: 10.4159/9780674028845</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4159/9780674028845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browning E., Hohenstein J. (2024). The narrative teacher: narrative nonfiction as a teaching tool in the primary history classroom. Rev. Educ. 12:e3459. doi: 10.1002/rev3.3459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rev3.3459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler B. M., Burns R. W., Willey C. (2023). Toward a renewal of supervisory scholarship and practice in teacher education: a collaborative self-study. J. Educ. Supervision 6, 47&#x2013;68. doi: 10.31045/jes.6.3.3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31045/jes.6.3.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z., Zhu J., Tian S. (2022). Preservice teachers' teaching internship affects professional identity: self-efficacy and learning engagement as mediators. Front. Psychol. 13:1070763. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1070763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.1070763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9748549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36532965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbonneau N., Vallerand R. J., Fernet C., Guay F. (2008). The role of passion for teaching in intrapersonal and interpersonal outcomes. J. Educ. Psychol. 100, 977&#x2013;987. doi: 10.1037/a0012545</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0012545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen-Levi T., Buskila Y., Schechter C. (2024). Transformative agency in times of global crisis. J. Transformative Educ. 22, 358&#x2013;378. doi: 10.1177/15413446241234832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15413446241234832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chichekian T., Sverdlik A., Vallerand R. J., Maheux C. (2025). The interplay of teachers&#x2018; passion, social support, and students' passion for a field of study in higher education. Eur. J. Psychol. Educ. 40:41. doi: 10.1007/s10212-025-00940-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10212-025-00940-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chichekian T., Vallerand R., Rahimi S. (2024). Investigating emotions as a mediator in the transmission of passion in education. Curr. Psychol. 43, 13428&#x2013;13442. doi: 10.1007/s12144-023-05335-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-023-05335-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu T. K. F., Falloon G., Song Y., Wong V. W. L., Zhao L., Ismailov M., et al. (2024). A self-determination theory approach to teacher digital competence development. Comp. Educ. 214:105017. doi: 10.1016/j.compedu.2024.105017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compedu.2024.105017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig C. (2022). &#x201c;Eros and education: rachel Ben-Peretz's favourite work,&#x201d; in A Life of Optimism: Selected Works of Rachel Ben-Peretz, eds. L. Orland-Barak, M. A. Flores, A. Guberman, and C. J. Craig (Leiden: Brill; ), 145&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lisio G., Mil&#xe1; Roa A., Halty A., Ber&#xe1;stegui A., Couso Losada A., Pitillas C. (2025). Nurturing bonds that empower learning: a systematic review of the significance of teacher-student relationship in education. Front. Educ. 10:1522997. doi: 10.3389/feduc.2025.1522997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feduc.2025.1522997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci E. L., Ryan R. M. (2000). The &#x201c;what&#x201d; and &#x201c;why&#x201d; of goal pursuits: human needs and the self-determination of behavior. Psychol. Inq. 11, 227&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1207/S15327965PLI1104_01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15327965PLI1104_01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diab A-. K., Green E. (2024). Cultivating resilience and success: support systems for novice teachers in diverse contexts. Educ. Sci. 14:711. doi: 10.3390/educsci14070711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci14070711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dursun F., Aykan A. (2025). Exploring teachers' narratives: challenges and strategies for enhancing the teaching process. SAGE Open 15. doi: 10.1177/21582440251332557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21582440251332557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dvir N., Schatz-Oppenheimer O. (2020). Novice teachers in a changing reality. Eur. J. Teach. Educ. 43, 639&#x2013;656. doi: 10.1080/02619768.2020.1821360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02619768.2020.1821360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Zaatari W., Maalouf I. (2022). How the Bronfenbrenner bio-ecological system theory explains the development of students' sense of belonging to school? SAGE Open 12. doi: 10.1177/21582440221134089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21582440221134089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott S., Davis J. M. (2020). &#x201c;Challenging taken-for-granted ideas in early childhood education: a critique of Bronfenbrenner's ecological systems theory in the age of post-humanism,&#x201d; in Research Handbook on Childhood Nature: Assemblages of Childhood and Nature Research, eds. A. Cutter-Mackenzie-Knowles, K. Malone, E. Barratt Hacking (Cham: Springer; ), 1305&#x2013;1320. doi: 10.1007/978-3-319-67286-1_60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-67286-1_60</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewing L. A. (2021). Mentoring novice teachers. Mentoring Tutoring Partnership Learn. 29, 50&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1080/13611267.2021.1899585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13611267.2021.1899585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbrother M., Specht J., Delorey J., Whitley J., Ismailos L., Villella M., et al. (2025). Integrating practice and theory in teacher education: enhancing pre-service self-efficacy for inclusive education. Educ. Sci. 15:497. doi: 10.3390/educsci15040497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci15040497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzsimons S., Sexton P. J., Lehane P., Donlon E., McDonald E., Karakolidis A., et al. (2024). Understanding pre-service teachers' improvement in professional practice: a quantitative perspective. Ir. Educ. Stud. 44, 341&#x2013;357. doi: 10.1080/03323315.2024.2330883</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03323315.2024.2330883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flores M. A. (2020). Feeling like a student but thinking like a teacher: a study of the development of professional identity in initial teacher education. J. Educ. Teach. 46, 145&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1080/02607476.2020.1724659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02607476.2020.1724659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gidalevich S., Shalev M. (2022). Changing needs of special education preservice teachers in the practicum. Aust. J. Teach. Educ. 47, 21&#x2013;38. doi: 10.14221/ajte.2022v47n4.2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14221/ajte.2022v47n4.2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gro&#xdf;mann N., Fries S., Wilde M. (2023). Is the practice of autonomy support the missing element in teacher training at university? A study on the effects of an intervention based on self-determination theory on biology preservice teachers' knowledge, beliefs, and intentions. Front.Psychol. 14:1279771. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1279771</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1279771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10722232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38106398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guay F. (2022). Applying self-determination theory to education: regulations types, psychological needs, and autonomy supporting behaviors. Can. J. Sch. Psychol. 37, 75&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1177/08295735211055355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08295735211055355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guberman A., Mendels J., Arviv Elyashiv R., Berglas Shapiro T., Avraham I., Mishkin H., et al. (2024). &#x201c;Weaving practice, research and policymaking into teachers' preparation and induction in Israel,&#x201d; in Enhancing the Value of Teacher Education Research: Implications for Policy and Practice, ed. V. Symeonidis (Leiden: Brill; ), 195&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1163/9789004689992_010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/9789004689992_010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han W., Abdrahim N. A. (2023). The role of teachers' creativity in higher education: a systematic literature review and guidance for future research. Thinking Skills Creativity 48:101302. doi: 10.1016/j.tsc.2023.101302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsc.2023.101302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattie J. (2003). &#x201c;Teachers make a difference: what is the research evidence?,&#x201d; in Australian Council for Educational Research Annual Conference on Building Teacher Quality (Melbourne: ACER; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holappa A., Lassila E. T., Lutovac S., Uitto M. (2021). Vulnerability as an emotional dimension in student teachers' narrative identities told with self-portraits. Scan. J. Educ. Res. 66, 893&#x2013;906. doi: 10.1080/00313831.2021.1939144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00313831.2021.1939144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard J. L., Gagn&#xe9; M., Morin A. J. S. (2020). Putting the pieces together: reviewing the structural conceptualization of motivation within SDT. Motivation Emotion 44, 846&#x2013;861. doi: 10.1007/s11031-020-09838-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11031-020-09838-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang H. R., Cheon S. H., Reeve J., Song Y. G., Lee Y. (2023). Two ways teachers can develop greater harmonious passion. Phys. Educ. Sport Pedagogy 30, 184&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1080/17408989.2023.2206832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17408989.2023.2206832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jons L. (2024). Love actually: a thematic review of teacher passion for the subject. Discover Educ. 3:160. doi: 10.1007/s44217-024-00272-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44217-024-00272-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur H. (2024). Evaluating effectiveness and challenges in B.Ed. student teacher internships. Shodh Sari Int. Multidiscip. J. 3, 67&#x2013;76. doi: 10.59231/SARI7747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59231/SARI7747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozikoglu I. (2019). Investigating critical thinking in prospective teachers: metacognitive skills, problem solving skills and academic self-efficacy. J. Soc. Stud. Educ. Res. 10, 111&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai L., Shi W., Xie Y., Zhao J. (2024). Factors influencing the generation of teachers' emotions. Front. Psychol. 15:1392965. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1392965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1392965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11310131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39131858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landrum R. E., Brakke K., McCarthy M. A. (2019). The pedagogical power of storytelling. Scholarship Teach. Learn. Psychol. 5, 247&#x2013;253. doi: 10.1037/stl0000152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/stl0000152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Huu Nghia T., Ngoc Tai H. (2017). Preservice teachers' identity development during the teaching internship. Aust. J. Teach. Educ. 42:1. doi: 10.14221/ajte.2017v42n8.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14221/ajte.2017v42n8.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Zhang L. (2024). Exploring the relationships among teacher-student dynamics, learning enjoyment, and burnout in EFL students: the role of emotional intelligence. Front. Psychol. 14:1329400. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1329400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1329400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10800580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38259574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim W. M. (2025). What is qualitative research? An overview and guidelines. Australas. Mark. J. 33, 199&#x2013;229. doi: 10.1177/14413582241264619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14413582241264619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Yin H., Wang Y., Lu J. (2024). Teacher innovation: conceptualizations, methodologies, and theoretical framework. Teach. Teach. Educ. 145:104611. doi: 10.1016/j.tate.2024.104611</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tate.2024.104611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X. (2024). Effect of teacher-student relationship on academic engagement: the mediating roles of perceived social support and academic pressure. Front. Psychol. 15, 1331667. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1331667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1331667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11223674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38966726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Main S. (2012). &#x2018;The other half' of education: unconscious education of children. Educ. Philos. Theory 44, 82&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-5812.2010.00643.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-5812.2010.00643.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantel C., Kamm E., Bieri Buschor C. (2024). International teaching internships for future teachers: potential and challenges for learning. Educ. Res. Policy Pract. 23, 215&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1007/s10671-022-09313-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10671-022-09313-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer D., Doll J., Kaiser G. (2023). Professional identity of pre-service teachers: actual and designated identity profiles and their relationship to teacher education programs. Front. Educ. 8:1134848. doi: 10.3389/feduc.2023.1134848</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feduc.2023.1134848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray E., Leonard H. S., Bonaccorso V. D. (2025). Teacher growth through professional development centered on the teaching for robust understanding framework. Educ. Sci. 15:18. doi: 10.3390/educsci15010018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci15010018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neander Christensson J. (2024). Teacher identity discourses in place-exploring discursive resources in pre-service teachers' constructions of teacher identity. Educ. Sci. 14:1244. doi: 10.3390/educsci14111244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci14111244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera K. D. R. L. J. (2023). &#x201c;Bronfenbrenner's ecological systems theory and student motivation,&#x201d; in Proceedings of the Open University Research Sessions (OURS 2023) (Nugegoda: The Open University of Sri Lanka; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin S. (2025). How does teacher collaboration impact innovative ability? Findings from TALIS-based structural modeling. Humanit. Soc. Sci. Commun. 12:59. doi: 10.1057/s41599-025-04965-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/s41599-025-04965-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renn K. A., Smith B. R. G. (2023). Ecological models in higher education research: overview and synthesis. New Directions High. Educ. 2023, 11&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1002/he.20491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/he.20491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson C., Williams H. (2024). Interpretative phenomenological analysis: learnings from employing IPA as a qualitative methodology in educational research. Qual. Rep. 29, 939&#x2013;956. doi: 10.46743/2160-3715/2024.6487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46743/2160-3715/2024.6487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan R. M., Deci E. L. (2020). Intrinsic and extrinsic motivation from a self-determination theory perspective: definitions, theory, practices, and future directions. Contemp. Educ. Psychol. 61:101860. doi: 10.1016/j.cedpsych.2020.101860</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2020.101860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serin H. (2024). Effective teaching: passion and commitment. Int. J. Soc. Sci. Educ. Stud. 10, 60&#x2013;64. doi: 10.23918/ijsses.v10i3p60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23918/ijsses.v10i3p60</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalgimbekova K., Smagliy T., Kalimzhanova R., Suleimenova Z. (2024). Innovative teaching technologies in higher education: efficiency and student motivation. Cogent Educ. 11:2425205. doi: 10.1080/2331186X.2024.2425205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2331186X.2024.2425205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H., Cheung L. M. E. (2024). Storytelling for understanding: a case study of an English-language digital storytelling service-learning subject for refugee children in Hong Kong. J. Multicult. Educ. 18, 81&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1108/JME-10-2023-0116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JME-10-2023-0116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohdi R. (2025). A design-based approach to bridging the gap between university learning and classroom pedagogy in initial teacher education. J. Learn. Dev. Higher Educ. 34. doi: 10.47408/jldhe.vi34.1376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47408/jldhe.vi34.1376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer T., Pierce C. (2023). Classroom-based oral storytelling: reading, writing, and social benefits. Read. Teach. 76, 525&#x2013;534. doi: 10.1002/trtr.2144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/trtr.2144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens T. M., Day I. N. Z., den Brok P. J., Prins F. J., Assen H. J. H. E., ter Beek M., et al. (2024). Teacher professional learning and development in the context of educational innovations in higher education: a typology of practices. High. Educ. Res. Dev. 43, 437&#x2013;454. doi: 10.1080/07294360.2023.2246412</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07294360.2023.2246412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sydnor J., Daley S., Davis T. R., Ascolani M. (2023). Novice teachers navigating mentoring relationships in the United States. Child Stud. 87&#x2013;107. doi: 10.21814/childstudies.4498</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21814/childstudies.4498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan D., Levesque-Bristol C. (2024). Understanding preservice teachers' intentions to enact autonomy support: the combined perspectives from self-determination theory and mindset theory. Curr. Psychol. 43, 6939&#x2013;6953. doi: 10.1007/s12144-023-04860-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-023-04860-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong P., An I. S. (2024). Review of studies applying Bronfenbrenner's bioecological theory in international and intercultural education research. Front. Psychol. 14:1233925. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1233925</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1233925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10801006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38259539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsabar B. (2014). Poverty and resourcefulness: on the formative significance of eros in educational practice. Stud. Philos. Educ. 33, 75&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1007/s11217-013-9364-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11217-013-9364-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X. (2023). Exploring positive teacher-student relationships: the synergy of teacher mindfulness and emotional intelligence. Front. Psychol. 14:1301786. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1301786</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1301786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10716249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38094701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Chen J., Xin Z. (2025). Self-determination theory and the influence of social support, self-regulated learning, and flow experience on student learning engagement in self-directed e-learning. Front. Psychol. 16:1545980. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1545980</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1545980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11979257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40207130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaman A. M. S., Mahanta S. R. (2025). Exploring the gaps in practice teaching and internship programmes: a study on the challenges faced by B.Ed. Colleges in Central Assam. Int. J. Res. Soc. Sci. Hum. 15, 60&#x2013;68. doi: 10.37648/ijrssh.v15i01.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37648/ijrssh.v15i01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhou S., Wu X., Cheung A. C. K. (2024). The effect of teacher training programs on pre-service and in-service teachers' global competence: a meta-analysis. Educ. Res. Rev. 45:100627. doi: 10.1016/j.edurev.2024.100627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.edurev.2024.100627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>