<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41547979</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Uncertainty aware hybrid learning framework for fast and safe charging of lithium-ion batteries using multi-fidelity observers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2452</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2452</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2452</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-31976-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate and real-time estimation of the state of charge (SoC) is critical for ensuring the performance, safety, and longevity of lithium-ion batteries in electric vehicles (EVs). This research work presents an Uncertainty-Aware Hybrid Learning Framework for accurate and safe State-of-Charge (SoC) prediction in lithium-ion batteries, particularly under dynamic and thermal-varying conditions during fast charging. The framework integrates multi-fidelity electrochemical observer outputs with a Tuned Multilayer Perceptron (MLP) Regressor, enabling real-time estimation of high-fidelity SoC while quantifying uncertainty using a Negative Log-Likelihood (NLL) loss. Case studies were conducted on a modified dataset simulating sensor faults and thermal distortions. The proposed model achieved a peak R&#xb2; of 0.9921 and MSE of 0.000021 under clean conditions. Under thermal noise, the retrained MLP maintained strong generalization with R&#xb2; as 0.9657, MSE as 0.00053, and Prediction Interval Coverage Probability (PICP) of 0.975 with a narrow MPIW of 0.200. Comparative evaluation against Random Forest, Gradient Boosting, and Linear Regression confirms the MLP's superior adaptability and robustness. This hybrid framework is particularly suitable for deployment in real-time Battery Management Systems (BMS) and offers a foundation for future thermal-aware predictive control in electric vehicles. The proposed framework also highlights the potential of integrating low-complexity observer models with learning algorithms for real-time applications in EV systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parimala</LastName><ForeName>C H Hadassa</ForeName><Initials>CHH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of EEE Koneru Lakshmaiah Education Foundation, Green Fields, Vaddeswaram, 522302, A.P, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varma</LastName><ForeName>P Srinivasa</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of EEE Koneru Lakshmaiah Education Foundation, Green Fields, Vaddeswaram, 522302, A.P, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Rangu Seshu</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Mangement, Central Power Research Institute Bangalore, Bangalore, 560080, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Arvind R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, School of Physics and Electronic Engineering, Hanjiang Normal University, Hanjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohapatra</LastName><ForeName>Bhabasis</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, ITER, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, 751030, Odisha, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Addis</LastName><ForeName>Hailu Kendie</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amhara Agricultural Research Institute, Soil and Water Management Research Directorate, Bahir Dar, PO Box. 527, Ethiopia. hailu.kendie@arari.gov.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electric vehicles (EVs)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lithium-ion battery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-Fidelity models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multilayer perceptron (MLP)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">State of charge (SoC) estimation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Disclosure of interest: On behalf of all authors, the corresponding author states that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41547979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12819502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-31976-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-31976-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Park, Saehong&amp; Pozzi, Andrea &amp; Whitmeyer, Michael &amp; Perez, Hector &amp; Kandel, Aaron&amp; Kim, Geumbee&amp; Choi, Yohwan&amp; Joe, Won Tae &amp; Raimondo, D.M. &amp; Moura, Scott. (2022).A Deep Reinforcement Learning Framework for Fast Charging of Li-Ion Batteries. IEEE Transactions on Transportation Electrification. 1&#x2013;1. 10.1109/TTE.2022.3140316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Tan, X. &amp; Wang, Z. Stat-of-charge Estimation for lithium-ion batteries based on recurrent neural network: current status and perspectives. <i>J. Energy Storage</i>, 112, 2025, 115575, ISSN 2352-152X, 10.1016/j.est.2025.115575</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longxing Wu, Z., Lyu, Z., Huang, C., Zhang, C. &amp; Wei Physics-based battery SOC Estimation methods: recent advances and future perspectives. <i>J. Energy Chem. </i>&#xa0;<b>89</b>10.1016/j.jechem.2023.09.045 (2024). 27&#x2013;40, ISSN 2095&#x2013;4956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo Yang, J. et al. Classification, summarization and perspectives on state-of-charge Estimation of lithium-ion batteries used in electric vehicles: A critical comprehensive survey. <i>J. Energy Storage</i>. <b>39</b>, 2352&#x2013;2152. 10.1016/j.est.2021.102572 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2021.102572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogelquist, J. &amp; Lin, X. Joint parameterization of hybrid Physics-Based and machine learning Li-Ion battery model. (2025). 10.48550/arXiv.2505.06473</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri, E. et al. State Estimation of an electrochemical lithium-ion battery model: improved observer performance by hybrid redesign. (2023). 10.48550/arXiv.2304.09680</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, H., Moura, S. &amp; Fang, H. Integrating Electrochemical Modeling with Machine Learning for Lithium-Ion Batteries, 2021 American Control Conference (ACC), New Orleans, LA, USA, pp. 4401&#x2013;4407, (2021). 10.23919/ACC50511.2021.9482997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firoozi, R., Sattarzadeh, S. &amp; Dey, S. Cylindrical battery fault detection under extreme fast charging: A Physics-Based learning approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Energy Convers.</i><b>37</b> (2), 1241&#x2013;1250. 10.1109/TEC.2021.3112950 (June 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, J., Chen, C., Shen, W. &amp; Sun, F. Rui Xiong,Deep Learning Framework for Lithium-ion Battery State of Charge Estimation: Recent Advances and Future Perspectives,Energy Storage Materials,Volume 61,2023,102883,ISSN 2405&#x2013;8297,10.1016/j.ensm.2023.102883</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, Y., Long, M., Yang, F. &amp; Peng, W. A bayesian deep learning pipeline for lithium-ion battery SOH Estimation with uncertainty quantification. <i>Qual. ReliabEngng Int.</i><b>40</b>, 406&#x2013;427. 10.1002/qre.3424 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/qre.3424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S., Liu, Zhitao, Xu, Y., Su, H. &amp; &amp; &amp; A Physics-Informed hybrid multitask learning for Lithium-Ion battery Full-Life aging Estimation at early lifetime. <i>IEEE Trans. Industrial Inf. </i>&#xa0;1&#x2013;10. 10.1109/TII.2024.3452273 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J., Zhang, Y. &amp; Khoo, E. Hybrid physics-based and data-driven modelling with calibrated uncertainty for lithium-ion battery degradation diagnosis and prognosis. (2021). 10.48550/arXiv.2110.13661</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thelen, A. et al. Probabilistic machine learning for battery health diagnostics and prognosticsreview and perspectives. <i>Npj Mater. Sustain.</i><b>2</b>, 14. 10.1038/s44296-024-00011-1 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44296-024-00011-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, M. et al. Accounting for the Effects of Probabilistic Uncertainty During Fast Charging of Lithium-ion Batteries, 2024 American Control Conference (ACC), Toronto, ON, Canada, 5339&#x2013;5344, (2024). 10.23919/ACC60939.2024.10644639</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, X. &amp; Liu, L. A Multi-Timescale method for state of charge Estimation for Lithium-Ion batteries in electric UAVs based on battery model and Data-Driven fusion. <i>Drones</i><b>9</b> (4), 247. 10.3390/drones9040247 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones9040247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Z., Tu, H., Fang, H., Wang, Y. &amp; Mou, S. Integrated Optimal Fast Charging and Active Thermal Management of Lithium-Ion Batteries in Extreme Ambient Temperatures. <i>IEEE Trans. Control Syst. Technol.</i><b>33</b>(2), 714&#x2013;728. 10.1109/TCST.2024.3498812 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCST.2024.3498812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailemichael, H. &amp; Ayalew, B. Continual hybrid model learning for lithium-ion batteries, Journal of Energy Storage, <b>109</b>, 115105, (Elsevier, 2025). 10.1016/j.est.2024.115105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sina Navidi, A., Thelen, T. &amp; Li Chao Hu,Physics-informed machine learning for battery degradation diagnostics: A comparison of state-of-the-art methods,Energy Storage Materials,Volume 68,2024,103343,ISSN 2405&#x2013;8297,10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu, D. O. P. Enhanced SOC Estimation of lithium ion batteries with realtime data using machine learning algorithms. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 16036. 10.1038/s41598-024-66997-9 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-66997-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11239840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38992178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Zhao, Sun, X., Lin, M. &amp; Chen, Q. Uncertainty-Aware Energy Management Strategy for Hybrid Electric Vehicle Using Hybrid Deep Learning Method. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>10</b>, 1&#x2013;1, 10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3182805 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3182805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. et al. Practical Battery Health Monitoring using Uncertainty-Aware Bayesian Neural Network, 2024 IEEE 100th Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2024-Fall), Washington, DC, USA, 1&#x2013;6, (2024). 10.1109/VTC2024-Fall63153.2024.10757952</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>(eds Zhong, H., Meng &amp; Zhang) Shujuan&amp; Xinan&amp; Wei, Z., Zhang, C. &amp; Du, L. Multiphysics-Constrained Fast Charging of Lithium-Ion Battery With Active Set Predictive Control. IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems. 1&#x2013;11. (2024). 10.1109/TITS.2023.3342207</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, Z. et al. Machine Learning-Based Fast Charging of Lithium-Ion Battery by Perceiving and Regulating Internal Microscopic States.. <i>Energy Storage Materials.</i><b>56</b>, 62&#x2013;75. 10.1016/j.ensm.2022.12.034 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2022.12.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringbeck, F., Garbade, M., Sauer, D. U. &amp; &amp; Uncertainty-aware state Estimation for electrochemical model-based fast charging control of lithium-ion batteries. <i>J. Power Sources</i>. <b>470</b>, 228221. 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2020.228221 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2020.228221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setiawan, H., Tampati, I. F., Putra, I. G. M. &amp; Girinoto Optimization of MLP-Regressor for Predicting Student&#x2019;s Cumulative Grade Point Average (GPA), 2024 4th International Conference of Science and Information Technology in Smart Administration (ICSINTESA), Balikpapan, Indonesia, 628&#x2013;633, (2024). 10.1109/ICSINTESA62455.2024.10747977</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keogh, D. F., Baldry, M., Timchenko, V. &amp; Reizes, J. Chris Menictas,Modelling the effects of areal capacity on mass transport in liquid metal batteries,Journal of Power Sources,Volume 573,2023,233142,ISSN 0378&#x2013;7753,10.1016/j.jpowsour.2023.233142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmughasundaram, R. Estimation of Soc and Soh Using Mixed Neural Network and Coulomb Counting Algorithm. <i>Int. J. Innovative Technol. Exploring Eng.</i><b>8</b>, 10.35940/ijitee.J1308.0881019 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi, M. H., Arjmandzadeh, Z., Zhang, J. &amp; Xu, B. Venkat Krovi,Deep reinforcement learning based fast charging and thermal management optimization of an electric vehicle battery pack. <i>J. Energy Storage Volume</i> 95,2024,112466,ISSN 2352-152X,10.1016/j.est.2024.112466</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, Z., Li, X., Niu, J. &amp; Zhou, R. Feng Li,Enhancing operation flexibility of distributed energy systems: A flexible multi-objective optimization planning method considering long-term and temporary objectives,Energy,288,2024,129612,ISSN 0360&#x2013;5442 10.1016/j.energy.2023.129612</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haraz, A., Abualsaud, K. &amp; Massoud, A. Ensemble Learning for Precise State-of-Charge Estimation in Electric Vehicles Lithium-Ion Batteries Considering Uncertainty. <i>IEEE Access.</i> 1&#x2013;1. 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3539792 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavus, M., Dissanayake, D., Bell, M. &amp; &amp; Next generation of electric vehicles: AI-Driven approaches for predictive maintenance and battery management. <i>Energies</i><b>18</b>, 1041. 10.3390/en18051041 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18051041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieger, L. et al. Uncertainty-Aware and explainable machine learning for early prediction of battery cell degradation. <i>SSRN Electron. J.</i>10.2139/ssrn.3991083 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.3991083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sufi, F. &amp; Alsulami, M. Automated Multidimensional Analysis of Global Events With Entity Detection, Sentiment Analysis and Anomaly Detection. <i>IEEE Access.</i> 1&#x2013;1. 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3127571 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Y. et al. Multi-fidelity physics-informed convolutional neural network for heat map prediction of battery packs.. <i>Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety.</i><b>256</b>, 110752, 10.1016/j.ress.2024.110752 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari, S. &amp; Byun, Y. C. A CNN-GRU approach to the accurate prediction of batteries&#x2019; remaining useful life from charging profiles. <i>Computers</i><b>12</b> (11), 219. 10.3390/computers12110219 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/computers12110219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, P. . H. . et al. Integrated thermal and battery management for electric vehicles: Experimental validation and simulation-based optimization of lithium-ion batteries. <i>Energy Exploration &amp; Exploitation</i><b>43</b>(5), 2100&#x2013;2158 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01445987251337094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazal, T. M., Saeed, A. Q., Abualhaj, M. M., Abdali, T. A. N. &amp; Ahmad, M. <i>Pioneering CPMI Framework for Accurate State-of-Health Assessment in Lithium Ion Battery Power Management Using FBG Sensors</i> 101967 (Sensors, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agyekum, E. B., Abdullah, M., Odoi-Yorke, F., Ameen, A., Chowdhury, P., Raza, M. A.,&#x2026; Hussein, A. K. (2025). A state-of-the-art review of electrolyte systems for vanadium redox flow battery&#x2013;status of the technology, and future research directions. Energy Conversion and Management: X, 101180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agyekum, E. B. et al. Review of trends and emerging optimization techniques for battery thermal management&#x2013;Traditional and bibliometric approach. <i>J. Energy Storage</i>. <b>119</b>, 116437 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.116437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkateswarlu, B., Chavan, S., Joo, S. W., Kim, S. C. &amp; Nisar, K. S. A numerical investigation of heat transfer performance in a prismatic battery cooling system using hybrid nanofluids. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i><b>66</b>, 105719 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2024.105719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, A., Trivedi, T., B, S., Aulakh, D., Yadav, Y., A, R., &#x2026; Sintie Geremew, M.(2025). Accurate state of charge estimation for INR18650 (NMC) lithium-ion cells using a validated 1RC equivalent circuit model for BMS applications. Energy Exploration&amp; Exploitation, 01445987251371263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R. S. et al. Hybrid machine learning framework for predictive maintenance and anomaly detection in lithium-ion batteries using enhanced random forest. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 6243 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-90810-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11842581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39979634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehman, W. U., Khan, Z., Zahra, F., Laaskri, A., Khan, H., Farooq, U., &#x2026; Zaitsev,I. (2024). Preparation of interconnected tin oxide nanoparticles on multi-layered MXene for lithium storage anodes. Scientific Reports, <b>14</b>(1), 25107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11500183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39443637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>