<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600543</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vibration Signal Denoising Method Based on ICFO-SVMD and Improved Wavelet Thresholding.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">750</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020750</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Non-stationary, multi-component vibration signals in rotating machinery are easily contaminated by strong background noise, which masks weak fault features and degrades diagnostic reliability. This paper proposes a joint denoising method that combines an improved cordyceps fungus optimization algorithm (ICFO), successive variational mode decomposition (SVMD), and an improved wavelet thresholding scheme. ICFO, enhanced by Chebyshev chaotic initialization, a longitudinal-transverse crossover fusion mutation operator, and a thinking innovation strategy, is used to adaptively optimize the SVMD penalty factor and number of modes. The optimized SVMD decomposes the noisy signal into intrinsic mode functions, which are classified into effective and noise-dominated components via the Pearson correlation coefficient. An improved wavelet threshold function, whose threshold is modulated by the sub-band signal-to-noise ratio, is then applied to the effective components, and the denoised signal is reconstructed. Simulation experiments on nonlinear, non-stationary signals with different noise levels (SNR = 1-20 dB) show that the proposed method consistently achieves the highest SNR and lowest RMSE compared to VMD, SVMD, VMD-WTD, CFO-SVMD, and WTD. Tests on CWRU bearing data and gearbox vibration signals with added -2 dB Gaussian white noise further confirm that the method yields the lowest residual variance ratio and highest signal energy ratio while preserving key fault characteristic frequencies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Yanping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Hebei University of Science and Technology, Shijiazhuang 050018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-6749-6640</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Hebei University of Science and Technology, Shijiazhuang 050018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Zhe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Hebei University of Science and Technology, Shijiazhuang 050018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Vehicle Transmission, China North Vehicle Research Institute, Beijing 100072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Yachao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4552-7485</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Hebei University of Science and Technology, Shijiazhuang 050018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>VTDP-3202</GrantID><Agency>National Defense Science and Technology Industry Bureau Vehicle Power Special Projec</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>254Z1904G</GrantID><Agency>Central Guidance on Local Science and Technology Development Fund of Hebei Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SJMYF2025004</GrantID><Agency>Hebei Provincial Military-Civil Fusion Science and Technology Innovation Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CXY2025041</GrantID><Agency>Research Project of Hebei Education Department</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>241791157A</GrantID><Agency>Shijiazhuang science and Technology Bureau Basic Research Project of Shijiazhuang University in Hebei Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">denoising</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">improved cordyceps fungus optimization algorithm (ICFO)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">improved wavelet thresholding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">successive variational mode decomposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vibration signals</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12846175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jia Y., Yao D., Yang J., Jia L., Zhou T., Long Q. A Multi-Scale Wavelet and Spectral Kurtosis-Guided Framework for Noise-Resistant Rolling Bearing Fault Diagnosis. J. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 2026;242:113662. doi: 10.1016/j.ymssp.2025.113662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymssp.2025.113662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A., Wy&#x142;oma&#x144;ska A., Zimroz R., Xiang J., Antoni J. Critical Challenges and Advances in Vibration Signal Processing for Non-Stationary Condition Monitoring. Adv. Eng. Inform. 2025;65:103290. doi: 10.1016/j.aei.2025.103290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aei.2025.103290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajabi S., Saman Azari M., Santini S., Flammini F. Fault Diagnosis in Industrial Rotating Equipment Based on Permutation Entropy, Signal Processing and Multi-Output Neuro-Fuzzy Classifier. Expert Syst. Appl. 2022;206:117754. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2022.117754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2022.117754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Li C., Wang X., Wu H. A Novel Fault Diagnosis Procedure Based on Improved Symplectic Geometry Mode Decomposition and Optimized SVM. Measurement. 2021;173:108644. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2020.108644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2020.108644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J., Si Z., Xiang J. A Compound Fault Diagnosis Method of Rolling Bearing Based on Wavelet Scattering Transform and Improved Soft Threshold Denoising Algorithm. Measurement. 2022;196:111276. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2022.111276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2022.111276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Fan Z., Liu Y., Xu X., Wang H. A Dynamically Balanced Wavelet Coefficient Matching Transient Energy Operator for State Identification of Rotating Machinery. Adv. Eng. Inform. 2025;65:103276. doi: 10.1016/j.aei.2025.103276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aei.2025.103276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H., Yao X., Chen Z., Wang L., Ding X., Xiao H. A Novel Multi-Resolution Sub-Band Adaptive Filter for Hybrid Noise Cancellation in Fault Diagnosis of Gear Transmission System. Measurement. 2026;257:118647. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.118647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.118647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W., Li J., Wang Q., Han K. Fault Feature Extraction and Diagnosis of Rolling Bearings Based on Wavelet Thresholding Denoising with CEEMDAN Energy Entropy and PSO-LSSVM. Measurement. 2021;172:108901. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2020.108901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2020.108901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye A., Tang Y., Li X., Niu Y., Gong S. Improved Vector Magnetic Field Signal-to-Noise Ratio by Wavelet Packet Transform in the Negatively Charged Nitrogen&#x2013;Vacancy Diamond Magnetometer. Measurement. 2025;256:118106. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.118106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.118106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang K., Yang F., Wang M., Yang J. Low-Complexity Bone Conduction-Aided Speech Enhancement Leveraging Sub-Band and Full-Band Architecture. Appl. Acoust. 2025;240:110924. doi: 10.1016/j.apacoust.2025.110924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apacoust.2025.110924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhao X., Peng Z., Xu R., Chen P. WD-KANTF: An Interpretable Intelligent Fault Diagnosis Framework for Rotating Machinery under Noise Environments and Small Sample Conditions. Adv. Eng. Inform. 2025;66:103452. doi: 10.1016/j.aei.2025.103452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aei.2025.103452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuvaraju B.A.G., Srinivas J., Ioannou I., Guruguntla V., Ghantasala G.S.P. Advanced chatter detection in internal turning for Industry 4.0: Adaptive Threshold Wavelet De-noising with enhanced ICEEMDAN&#x2013;Hilbert fusion using Adaptive Probabilistic Neural Network. J. Manuf. Process. 2025;149:1078&#x2013;1105. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2025.05.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2025.05.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J., Hou J., Fang B., Wang P., Wu S., Qi Z. Deep learning for the localization of seismic sources based on synthetic full waveform and wavelet de-noising. J. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 2026;200:109832. doi: 10.1016/j.soildyn.2025.109832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soildyn.2025.109832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melluso F., Spirto M., Nicolella A., Malfi P., Tordela C., Cosenza C., Savino S., Niola V. Torque fault signal extraction in hybrid electric powertrains through a wavelet-supported processing of residuals. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 2026;242:113652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Li T., He J., Liu T. An Interpretable Wavelet Kolmogorov-Arnold Convolutional LSTM for Spatial-temporal Feature Extraction and Intelligent Fault Diagnosis. J. Dyn. Monit. Diagn. 2025;4:183&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du F., Zhang C., Duan Y., Li J. Wavelet denoising based on improved threshold strategy for laser absorption spectroscopy signal processing. Infrared Phys. Technol. 2026;152:106219. doi: 10.1016/j.infrared.2025.106219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.infrared.2025.106219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang S., Zhang H., Lu Y., Han R., Gao Y., Wang Y., Jin B. SNR enhancement for Raman distributed temperature sensors using intrinsic modal functions with improved adaptive wavelet threshold denoising. Opt. Lasers Eng. 2025;189:108949. doi: 10.1016/j.optlaseng.2025.108949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlaseng.2025.108949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassef M.G.A., Hussein T.M., Mokhiamar O. An Adaptive Variational Mode Decomposition Based on Sailfish Optimization Algorithm and Gini Index for Fault Identification in Rolling Bearings. Measurement. 2021;173:108514. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2020.108514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2020.108514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W., Zhou Q., Wu S., Xing J., Chen X., Du S., Xu Z., Zhang R. EI-ISOA-VMD: Adaptive Denoising and Detrending Method for Nuclear Circulating Water Pump Impeller. Measurement. 2025;242:115890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Z., He D., Ma R., Zou X., Chen Y., Shan S. Fault Diagnosis of Train Rotating Parts Based on Multi-Objective VMD Optimization and Ensemble Learning. Digit. Signal Process. 2022;121:103312. doi: 10.1016/j.dsp.2021.103312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsp.2021.103312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Luo W., Bai M., Song M. Fault Diagnosis of High-Speed Rolling Bearing in the Whole Life Cycle Based on Improved Grey Wolf Optimizer-Least Squares Support Vector Machines. Digit. Signal Process. 2024;145:104345. doi: 10.1016/j.dsp.2023.104345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsp.2023.104345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An Q., Li P., An G., Liu D. Improved Crested Porcupine Optimizer-VMD Method Applied to Partial Discharge Signal. Measurement. 2026;258:119145. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.119145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.119145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dibaj A., Hassannejad R., Ettefagh M.M., Ehghaghi M.B. Incipient Fault Diagnosis of Bearings Based on Parameter-Optimized VMD and Envelope Spectrum Weighted Kurtosis Index with a New Sensitivity Assessment Threshold. ISA Trans. 2021;114:413&#x2013;433. doi: 10.1016/j.isatra.2020.12.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isatra.2020.12.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33431114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu M., Zhang Y., Yang C. Rolling Bearing Faults Identification Based on Multiscale Singular Value. Adv. Eng. Inform. 2023;57:102040. doi: 10.1016/j.aei.2023.102040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aei.2023.102040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Y., Feng X., Lv J., Shen Y., Zhou S., Zhou N., Du Z. Sealing Strip Acoustic Performance Evaluation Using WF-VMD Based Signal Enhancement Method. Appl. Acoust. 2024;217:109860. doi: 10.1016/j.apacoust.2024.109860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apacoust.2024.109860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F., Li Y., Du J., Zheng W., Shao Q. De-noising magnetotelluric data using variational mode decomposition combined with mathematical morphology filtering and wavelet thresholding. J. Appl. Geophys. 2022;204:104751. doi: 10.1016/j.jappgeo.2022.104751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jappgeo.2022.104751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Huang J., Liu W., Pang Y., Zhu T. Anti-Noise UWFBG Hydrophone Array Enhanced DAS System Using Optimising SVMD Based on Matched Interferometric. Opt. Fiber Technol. 2024;88:104051. doi: 10.1016/j.yofte.2024.104051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yofte.2024.104051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Xiong C., Li Z., Shang Z., Cao H. Dynamic Monitoring and Modal Identification of Offshore Platform Based on High-Rate Sensor Measurements Using Two-Stage SVMD and RDT Approach. Structures. 2025;77:109128. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2025.109128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2025.109128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Z., Qian H., Chu X., Yang F., Guo C., Wang F. Hybrid Ultra-Short-Term Wind Speed Forecasting Model Based on Improved BO-HMA-BiGRU and GMBInformer: Integrating SVMD-SWT Dual Decomposition and MPE-Driven Modeling Mechanism. Energy. 2025;339:139078. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2025.139078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2025.139078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Xiao G., Lu J., Liu Y., Chen H., Yang N. Robust Load Feature Extraction Based Secondary VMD Novel Short-Term Load Demand Forecasting Framework. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 2025;239:111198. doi: 10.1016/j.epsr.2024.111198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2024.111198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Q., Cao C., Xue G., Xie W. Short-Term Heating Load Forecasting Model Based on SVMD and Improved Informer. Energy. 2024;312:133535. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2024.133535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2024.133535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu B., Zhang X. SVMD-AAPE-RPE-CC-AWTD Algorithm for Ship Radiated Noise Signals. Ocean Eng. 2024;313:119271. doi: 10.1016/j.oceaneng.2024.119271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2024.119271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H., Xu Y., Wang J., Song M., Zhang S. SVMD Coupled with Dual-Threshold Criteria of Correlation Coefficient: A Self-Adaptive Denoising Method for Ship-Radiated Noise Signal. Ocean Eng. 2023;281:114931. doi: 10.1016/j.oceaneng.2023.114931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2023.114931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parri S., Teeparthi K. SVMD-TF-QS: An Efficient and Novel Hybrid Methodology for the Wind Speed Prediction. Expert Syst. Appl. 2024;249:123516. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu B., Zhang X. SVMD-WD-SE-ESS-IWTD Algorithm for Ship Shaft-Rate Magnetic Field Signals. Measurement. 2026;260:119869. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.119869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.119869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Zhao X. An Interpretable Fault Diagnosis Method for Marine Rotating Machinery under Strong Noise Based on Constrained Penalty Leech Algorithm Optimized ICEEMDAN. Ocean Eng. 2026;344:123685. doi: 10.1016/j.oceaneng.2025.123685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2025.123685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu N., Li M., Zhang G., Li R., Zhou T., Su C. Fault Feature Extraction Method for Rotating Machinery Based on a CEEMDAN-LPP Algorithm and Synthetic Maximum Index. Measurement. 2022;189:110636. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2021.110636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2021.110636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He C., Shi H., Si J., Li J. Physics-Informed Interpretable Wavelet Weight Initialization and Balanced Dynamic Adaptive Threshold for Intelligent Fault Diagnosis of Rolling Bearings. J. Manuf. Syst. 2023;70:579&#x2013;592. doi: 10.1016/j.jmsy.2023.08.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmsy.2023.08.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Shao T., Zhang X. BCG Signal Analysis Based on Improved VMD Algorithm. Measurement. 2024;231:114631. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2024.114631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2024.114631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W., Li J., Wu S. Multi-Source Manifold Space Domain Adaptation with a Full-Thresholding Residual Network for Machinery Fault Diagnosis. Appl. Soft Comput. 2025;183:113611. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2025.113611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2025.113611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parolai S. Denoising of seismograms using the S transform. Bull. Seismol. Soc. Am. 2009;99:226&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1785/0120080001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1785/0120080001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ditommaso R., Mucciarelli M., Ponzo F.C. Analysis of non-stationary structural systems by using a band-variable filter. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2012;10:895&#x2013;911. doi: 10.1007/s10518-012-9338-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-012-9338-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ditommaso R., Mucciarelli M., Parolai S. Monitoring the structural dynamic response of a masonry tower: Comparing classical and time-frequency analyses. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2012;10:1221&#x2013;1235. doi: 10.1007/s10518-012-9347-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-012-9347-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Langston C.A., Yang H. Denoising of Dense Spatial Array Data Using the Curvelet Transform. Bull. Seismol. Soc. Am. 2024;114:2325&#x2013;2340. doi: 10.1785/0120240030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1785/0120240030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donoho D.L., Johnstone I.M. Adapting to unknown smoothness via wavelet shrinkage. J. Am. Stat. Assoc. 1995;90:1200&#x2013;1224. doi: 10.1080/01621459.1995.10476626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01621459.1995.10476626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang T., Liang R., Wang Q., Bao Y. Speech noise reduction algorithm in digital hearing aids based on an improved sub-band SNR estimation. Circuits Syst. Signal Process. 2018;37:1243&#x2013;1267. doi: 10.1007/s00034-017-0605-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00034-017-0605-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donoho D.L. De-noising by soft-thresholding. IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory. 2002;41:613&#x2013;627. doi: 10.1109/18.382009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/18.382009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donoho D.L., Johnstone I.M. Ideal spatial adaptation via wavelet shrinkage. Biometrika. 1994;81:425&#x2013;455. doi: 10.1093/biomet/81.3.425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/biomet/81.3.425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari M., Sakhaei S.M. Successive variational mode decomposition. Signal Process. 2020;174:107610. doi: 10.1016/j.sigpro.2020.107610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sigpro.2020.107610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B., Liang B., Zhou S., Qian Y., Zheng R., Shu H., He P., Wang J., Jiang L., Sang Y., et al. A novel bio-inspired caterpillar fungus (Ophiocordyceps sinensis) optimizer for SOFC parameter identification via GRNN. Renew. Energy. 2026;256:123995. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2025.123995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2025.123995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H., Zhou X., Zhang J. Thinking Innovation Strategy (TIS): A novel mechanism for metaheuristic algorithm design and evolutionary update. Appl. Soft Coput. 2025;175:113071. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2025.113071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2025.113071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith W.A., Randall R.B. Rolling element bearing diagnostics using the Case Western Reserve University data: Abenchmark study. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 2015;64&#x2013;65:100&#x2013;131. doi: 10.1016/j.ymssp.2015.04.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymssp.2015.04.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>