<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41469467</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synergistic comparison of ANN and ANFIS predictive modeling with experimental electrochemical performance data in CO&#x2082; conversion.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3976</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3976</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3976</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34138-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This work systematically evaluated CO&#x2082; conversion performance metrics across the recent&#x2002;high-impact literature by focusing on five key inputs; applied potential (AP), catalyst loading (CL), composition (CO), support (SU) and electrolyte (EL) and two outputs; Faradaic efficiency (FE) and current density (CD). Dataset Sixty-four series were evaluated&#x2002;to generate predictive models for FE and CD. Residual plots showed a good fit along the fitted axis with deviations from normality being quite small,&#x2002;confirming linear relationships between input and output. Histograms have shown most&#x2002;of the errors were on the ranges -&#x2009;0.8 to 0.8 for FE and -&#x2009;4 to 4 for CD, thus confirming that the error was normally distributed and improving prediction reliability. Optimal electrode with reference to SN ratio was determined to be AP2-CL1-CO1-SU 2-E12 (-1.29&#xa0;V, 0.426&#xa0;mg/cm&#xb2;, 10% of Cu-In, carbon papers support and 0.1&#xa0;M KOH) as optimal for increasing Faradic efficiency and AP1-CL1-CO1-SU1-EL1 (-1.29&#xa0;V, 0.426&#xa0;mg/cm&#xb2;, 10% of Cu-In, graphene papers and 0.1&#xa0;M KHCO3) as optimal for improving Current Density. ANOVA results showed that the catalyst loading and applied potential are two major factors influencing FE&#x2002;and CD.ANN (5-10-2) exhibited good prediction performance (overall R&#xb2; = 0.93726). From the performance metrics, ANFIS exhibited low error values RMSE (0.0725 &amp; 0.0525) and MAE (0.1411 &amp; 0.0811) for both FE and CD when compared with ANN and also the corresponding &#x394;R&#xb2; confirmed that ANFIS delivered the better predictive accuracy. This comparison demonstrated the strong predictive power of the ANFIS&#x2002;with respect to ANN, verifying the reliability of the modelling approach based on experimental results.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deepati</LastName><ForeName>Anil Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering Technology, CAIT, Jazan University, Jizan, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swapna Sri</LastName><ForeName>Movva Naga</ForeName><Initials>MN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, P V P Siddhartha Institute of Technology, Vijayawada, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peyyala</LastName><ForeName>Anusha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, P V P Siddhartha Institute of Technology, Vijayawada, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veeranjaneyulu</LastName><ForeName>Itha</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Aditya University, Surampalem, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajulapati</LastName><ForeName>Amaleswari</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Academy of Maritime Education and Training (AMET) Deemed University, East Coast Road, Kanathur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pydi</LastName><ForeName>Hari Prasadarao</ForeName><Initials>HP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, College of Engineering and Technology, Bule Hora University, Bule Hora Town, Oromia Region, India. hari.pydi@bhu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Revathi</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research and Innovation, Saveetha School of Engineering, SIMATS, Chennai, 602105, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramya</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Research and Development, Lovely Professional University, Jalandhar - Delhi G.T.Road, Phagwara, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ANFIS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial neural network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon dioxide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Current density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrochemical process</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable production</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41469467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12855960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34138-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34138-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vakhshouri, B. &amp; Nejadi, S. Prediction of compressive strength of self-compacting concrete by ANFIS models, <i>Neurocomputing</i>, <b>280</b>, 13&#x2013;22. 10.1016/j.neucom.2017.09.099 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yesupatham, M. S. et al. Recent developments in Copper-Based catalysts for enhanced electrochemical CO 2 reduction. <i>Adv. Sustain. Syst.</i><b>8</b> (6). 10.1002/adsu.202300549 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, T. N. &amp; Dinh, C. T. Gas diffusion electrode design for electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction. <i>Chem. Soc. Rev.</i><b>49</b> (21), 7488&#x2013;7504. 10.1039/D0CS00230E (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0CS00230E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samu, A. A., Szenti, I., Kukovecz, &#xc1;., Endr&#x151;di, B. &amp; Jan&#xe1;ky, C. Systematic screening of gas diffusion layers for high performance CO2 electrolysis. <i>Commun. Chem.</i><b>6</b> 1, 41. 10.1038/s42004-023-00836-2 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9958001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagias, V. D., Zacharia, P., Tempeloudis, A. &amp; Stergiou, C. Adaptive Neuro-Fuzzy Inference System-Based Predictive Modeling of Mechanical Properties in Additive Manufacturing, <i>Machines</i>, <b>12</b>, 8, 523. (2024). 10.3390/machines12080523</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakshmaiya, N. High ionic permeability of Piper ION membrane boosts efficiency in CO2 electrolysis cells, in <i>International Conference on Medical Imaging, Electronic Imaging, Information Technologies, and Sensors (MIEITS 2024)</i>, 30. 10.1117/12.3030841 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alreshidi, M. A. et al. A review on the evolution of ionic liquids: sustainable synthesis, applications, and future prospects. <i>Mater. Today Sustain.</i><b>31, 101160</b>, 10.1016/j.mtsust.2025.101160 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varhade, S. et al. Electrochemical CO 2 Reduction: Commercial Innovations and Prospects, <i>ChemElectroChem</i>, vol. 12, no. 2, (2025). 10.1002/celc.202400512</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei, B. et al. Modulating the environment and metal choice doped in BC4N monolayer for carbon dioxide reduction: A computational study. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>511, 162250</b>, 10.1016/j.cej.2025.162250 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, P., Paramasivam, P., Bora, B. J. &amp; Sivasundar, V. Application of nanomaterials for emission reduction from diesel engines powered with waste cooking oil biodiesel. <i>Int. J. Low-Carbon Technol.</i><b>18</b>, 795&#x2013;801. 10.1093/ijlct/ctad060 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ijlct/ctad060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, J. et al. CO2 electrolysis to multi-carbon products in strong acid at ampere-current levels on La-Cu spheres with channels. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>15</b> (1, 4821, ). 10.1038/s41467-024-49308-8 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11156665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38844773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jlidi, M., Barambones, O., Hamidi, F. &amp; Aoun, M. ANN for Temperature and Irradiation Prediction and Maximum Power Point Tracking Using MRP-SMC, <i>Energies</i>, <b>17</b>, 12, 2802. 10.3390/en17122802 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, F. et al. Boosting the electroreduction of CO2 to liquid products via nanostructure engineering of Cu2O catalysts. <i>J. Catal.</i><b>432, 115458</b>, 10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115458 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, Y. et al. Modulating CO2 electroreduction pathways through controlled ionomer arrangement on catalyst surfaces via solvent dispersion. <i>Innov</i><b>6</b> (6, 100882, ). 10.1016/j.xinn.2025.100882 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12169282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40528879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, S. et al. Density Functional Theory Study of CuAg Bimetal Electrocatalyst for CO2RR to Produce CH3OH, <i>Catalysts</i>, vol. 14, no. 1, 7, (2023). 10.3390/catal14010007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. W. et al. Development of different kinds of electrocatalyst for the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide reactions: an overview. <i>Molecules</i><b>28</b> (20, 7016, ). 10.3390/molecules28207016 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37894499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birdja, Y. Y. &amp; Vaes, J. Towards a Critical Evaluation of Electrocatalyst Stability for CO 2 Electroreduction, <i>ChemElectroChem</i>, <b>7</b>, 23, 4713&#x2013;4717. 10.1002/celc.202001227 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Perovskite oxyfluoride electrode enabling direct electrolyzing carbon dioxide with excellent electrochemical performances. <i>Adv. Energy Mater.</i><b>9</b> (3). 10.1002/aenm.201803156 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitopi, S. et al. Progress and perspectives of electrochemical CO 2 reduction on copper in aqueous electrolyte. <i>Chem. Rev.</i><b>119</b> (12), 7610&#x2013;7672. 10.1021/acs.chemrev.8b00705 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.8b00705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31117420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jouny, M., Luc, W. &amp; Jiao, F. General Techno-Economic analysis of CO 2 electrolysis systems. <i>Ind. Eng. Chem. Res.</i><b>57</b> (6), 2165&#x2013;2177. 10.1021/acs.iecr.7b03514 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.7b03514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, B. et al. Electrochemical CO 2 conversion commercialization pathways: A concise review on experimental frontiers and technoeconomic analysis. <i>Environ. Sci. Technol. Lett.</i><b>11</b> (11), 1161&#x2013;1174. 10.1021/acs.estlett.4c00564 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.estlett.4c00564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11562736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39554597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J., Sharma, P. P., Harris, B. H. &amp; Zhou, X. D. Electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide: IV dependence of the Faradaic efficiency and current density on the microstructure and thickness of Tin electrode. <i>J. Power Sources</i>. <b>258</b>, 189&#x2013;194. 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.02.014 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.02.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merino-Garcia, I., Albo, J., Solla-Gull&#xf3;n, J., Montiel, V. &amp; Irabien, A. Cu oxide/ZnO-based surfaces for a selective ethylene production from gas-phase CO2 electroconversion. <i>J. CO2 Util.</i><b>31</b>, 135&#x2013;142. 10.1016/j.jcou.2019.03.002 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcou.2019.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, S. et al. Flow field design matters for high current density Zero-Gap CO 2 electrolyzers. <i>ACS Energy Lett.</i><b>9</b> (12), 5945&#x2013;5954. 10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02534 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. et al. Electrochemical CO2-to-ethylene conversion on polyamine-incorporated Cu electrodes. <i>Nat. Catal.</i><b>4</b> (1), 20&#x2013;27. 10.1038/s41929-020-00547-0 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41929-020-00547-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az-Sainz, G., Alvarez-Guerra, M. &amp; Irabien, A. Continuous electroreduction of CO2 towards formate in gas-phase operation at high current densities with an anion exchange membrane. <i>J. CO2 Util.</i><b>56, 101822</b>, 10.1016/j.jcou.2021.101822 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, S. et al. Robust and efficient electroreduction of CO2 to CO in a modified zero-gap electrochemical cell. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>509, 161119</b>, 10.1016/j.cej.2025.161119 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hori, Y. Electrochemical CO2 Reduction on Metal Electrodes. In <i>Modern Aspects of Electrochemistry</i> 89&#x2013;189 (Springer, ). 10.1007/978-0-387-49489-0_3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarfraz, S., Garcia-Esparza, A. T., Jedidi, A., Cavallo, L. &amp; Takanabe, K. Cu&#x2013;Sn bimetallic catalyst for selective aqueous electroreduction of CO 2 to CO, ACS Catal., <b>6</b>, 5, 2842&#x2013;2851. 10.1021/acscatal.6b00269 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niknam Shahrak, M., Esfandyari, M. &amp; Karimi, M. Efficient prediction of water vapor adsorption capacity in porous metal&#x2013;organic framework materials: ANN and ANFIS modeling. <i>J. Iran. Chem. Soc.</i><b>16</b> (1), 11&#x2013;20. 10.1007/s13738-018-1476-y (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13738-018-1476-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esfandyari, M., Amiri, M. &amp; Salooki, M. K. Neural network prediction of the Fischer-Tropsch synthesis of natural gas with Co (III)/Al2O3 catalyst. <i>Chem. Eng. Res. Bull.</i><b>17</b> (1). 10.3329/cerb.v17i1.22915 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmanian, B. et al. Prediction of MEUF process performance using artificial neural networks and ANFIS approaches. <i>J. Taiwan. Inst. Chem. Eng.</i><b>43</b> (4), 558&#x2013;565. 10.1016/j.jtice.2012.01.002 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtice.2012.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abner, S. &amp; Chen, A. Nanostructured cobalt/copper catalysts for efficient electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction. <i>Nanoscale</i><b>16</b> (27), 12967&#x2013;12981. 10.1039/D4NR00909F (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4NR00909F</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38899409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi, H., Amiri, M. &amp; Esfandyari, M. Using artificial neural network (ANN) for manipulating energy gain of nansulate coating. <i>J. Nanotechnol Eng. Med.</i><b>2</b> (1). 10.1115/1.4003500 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar, S. Optimization of friction stir welding parameters for dissimilar aluminium alloys using RSM-GRA and RSM-TOPSIS: towards sustainable manufacturing in industry 4.0. <i>Results Eng.</i> (107054), 107054. 10.1016/j.rineng.2025.107054 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinh, C. T. et al. CO 2 electroreduction to ethylene via hydroxide-mediated copper catalysis at an abrupt interface, <i>Science (80-.).</i>, vol. 360, no. 6390, 783&#x2013;787, (2018). 10.1126/science.aas9100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29773749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, R., Guo, J., Li, X., Patel, P. &amp; Seifitokaldani, A. Electrochemical Reactors for CO2 Conversion, <i>Catalysts</i>, <b>10</b>, 5, 473. 10.3390/catal10050473 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, W. et al. Electrochemical CO2 reduction to ethylene by ultrathin CuO nanoplate arrays. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>13</b> (1, 1877, ). 10.1038/s41467-022-29428-9 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8986799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35387994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J., Yan, S., Zhang, C., Hu, Q. &amp; Cheng, Z. Electroreduction of CO2 toward High Current Density, <i>Processes</i>, <b>10</b>, 5, 826. 10.3390/pr10050826 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasin, N. H., Sopi, S. A. I. M., Yahya, W. Z. N. &amp; Bustam, M. A. Optimisation of operating parameters for enhanced CO2 electrochemical reduction to ethylene in flow cell configuration: A study on catalytic performance. <i>Sustain. Chem. Clim. Action</i>. <b>6, 100076</b>, 10.1016/j.scca.2025.100076 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usman, M. et al. Electrochemical Reduction of CO2: A Review of Cobalt Based Catalysts for Carbon Dioxide Conversion to Fuels, <i>Nanomaterials</i>, vol. 11, no. 8, Aug. 2021, (2029). 10.3390/nano11082029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8400998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34443860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. High Faradic efficiency of CO2 conversion to formic acid catalyzed by Cu2O hollow-dices. <i>Carbon Neutrality</i>. <b>1</b> (1, 36, ). 10.1007/s43979-022-00037-1 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena, A., Singh, H. &amp; Nath, M. Cobalt telluride electrocatalyst for selective electroreduction of CO2 to value-added chemicals. <i>Mater. Renew. Sustain. Energy</i>. <b>11</b> (2), 115&#x2013;129. 10.1007/s40243-022-00211-6 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40243-022-00211-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esfandyari, M., Esfandyari, M. &amp; Jafari, D. Prediction of thiophene removal from diesel using [BMIM][AlCl4] in EDS Process: GA-ANFIS and PSO-ANFIS modeling, <i>Pet. Sci. Technol.</i>, vol. 36, no. 16, 1305&#x2013;1311, (2018). 10.1080/10916466.2018.1471500</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Zhang, Z., Chen, T., Zhang, J. &amp; Zhang, Y. Electrolyte Effect on Electrocatalytic CO2 Reduction, <i>Nanomaterials</i>, 15, 9, 648. 10.3390/nano15090648 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12074274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40358265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Lowering *CO affinity over Cu nanoparticles for enhanced electrochemical CO 2 conversion to multicarbon products at high current density, CCS Chem., <b>6</b> (12), 2950&#x2013;2960, 10.31635/ccschem.024.202404245 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>