<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41855885</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-2782</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>200</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neural networks : the official journal of the International Neural Network Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neural Netw</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An approximation theory perspective on machine learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108841</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108841</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neunet.2026.108841</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0893-6080(26)00303-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A central problem in machine learning is often formulated as follows: Given a dataset [Formula: see text] , which is a sample drawn from an unknown probability distribution, the goal is to construct a functional model f such that f(x)&#x202f;&#x2248;&#x202f;y for any (x, y) drawn from the same distribution. Neural networks and kernel-based methods are commonly employed for this task due to their capacity for fast and parallel computation. The approximation capabilities, or expressive power, of these methods have been extensively studied over the past 35 years. In this paper, we will present examples of key ideas in this area found in the literature. We will discuss emerging trends in machine learning including the role of shallow/deep networks, approximation on manifolds, physics-informed neural surrogates, neural operators, and transformer architectures. Despite function approximation being a fundamental problem in machine learning, approximation theory does not play a central role in the theoretical foundations of the field. One unfortunate consequence of this disconnect is that it is often unclear how well trained models will generalize to unseen or unlabeled data. In this review, we examine some of the shortcomings of the current machine learning framework and explore the reasons for the gap between approximation theory and machine learning practice. We will then review some of recent work that achieves function approximation on unknown manifolds without the need to learn specific manifold features, such as the eigen-decomposition of the Laplace-Beltrami operator or atlas construction. In many machine learning problems, particularly classification tasks, the labels y<sub>j</sub> are drawn from a finite set of values. We summarize another recent paper that establishes a deep connection between signal separation problems and classification problems, proposing that classification tasks should be approached as instances of signal separation. We conclude by identifying several open research problems that warrant further investigation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mhaskar</LastName><ForeName>Hrushikesh N</ForeName><Initials>HN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Claremont Graduate University, CA, 91711, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsoukanis</LastName><ForeName>Efstratios</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Claremont Graduate University, CA, 91711, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagtap</LastName><ForeName>Ameya D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aerospace Engineering Department, Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA, 01609, USA. Electronic address: ajagtap@wpi.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neural Netw</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8805018</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0893-6080</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Approximation theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Local kernels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neural operators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physics informed neural surrogates</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: H. N. Mhaskar, E. Tsoukanis reports financial support was provided by Office of Naval Research. Given Dr. A.D. Jagtap&#x2019;s role as an Action Editor for Neural Networks, he had no involvement in the peer review of this article and had no access to information regarding its peer review. Full responsibility for the editorial process for this article was delegated to another journal editor. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41855885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neunet.2026.108841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0893-6080(26)00303-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>