<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41900595</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Laser Wire Directed Energy Deposition of 5356 Aluminum Alloy: Process Parameter Optimization and Porosity Prediction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1104</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19061104</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Laser wire directed energy deposition (LWDED) has garnered significant attention for the fabrication of large metallic components. However, the complex coupling effects among its process parameters pose challenges for porosity control. Optimizing parameter combinations to effectively minimize porosity is therefore critical to the broader adoption of this technology. In this study, systematic experiments and modeling were conducted to optimize the LWDED process parameters and predict porosity. First, single-factor and orthogonal experiments were performed to evaluate the individual effects of laser power, scanning speed, wire feeding speed, and air pressure on porosity. Subsequently, range analysis and analysis of variance were employed to determine the influence of each parameter and the significance of their interactions. Four machine learning models-SVR, RF, GPR, and XGBoost-were then trained and compared. Among them, the SVR model exhibited the best predictive performance, achieving an R<sup>2</sup> of 0.8960, an RMSE of 0.19, and an MAE of 0.15, outperforming the other three models. Based on this, the SVR model was further utilized to establish the mapping between process parameters and porosity. Contour maps and three-dimensional surface plots were generated to visualize porosity variation patterns under interacting parameters. Validation experiments showed that the maximum relative error between model predictions and experimental measurements was 0.514%, with an average error of 0.251%. This study provides a reliable reference for selecting low-porosity parameter combinations in the LWDED fabrication of 5356 aluminum alloy components.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiangfei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electronics and Information Engineering, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mei</LastName><ForeName>Yujia</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electronics and Information Engineering, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Huomu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electronics and Information Engineering, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Shouhuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Electronics and Information Engineering, Sichuan University, Chengdu 610065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">5356 aluminum alloy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">laser wire directional energy deposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">porosity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41900595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13027603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19061104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19061104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pan J., Yuan B., Ge J., Ren Y., Chen H., Zhang L., Lu H. Influence of arc mode on the microstructure and mechanical properties of 5356 aluminum alloy fabricated by wire arc additive manufacturing. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2022;20:1893&#x2013;1907. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.08.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aversa A., Marchese G., Saboori A., Bassini E., Manfredi D., Biamino S., Ugues D., Fino P., Lombardi M. New Aluminum Alloys Specifically Designed for Laser Powder Bed Fusion: A Review. Materials. 2019;12:1007. doi: 10.3390/ma12071007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma12071007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6480675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30934694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W., Chen S., Xiao J., Jiang X., Jia Y. Laser wire-feed metal additive manufacturing of the Al alloy. Opt. Laser Technol. 2021;134:106627. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2020.106627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2020.106627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang X., Yan T., Wang L., Gao Q., Zhan X. Study on the distribution, element characteristics, and formation mechanism of porosity during laser welding for Ti-6Al-4V bottom-locking joint. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2022;123:2691&#x2013;2701. doi: 10.1007/s00170-022-10302-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-022-10302-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu R., Tang S., Lu J., Cui Y., Li Z., Zhang H., Xu T., Chen Z., Liu C. Hot-wire arc additive manufacturing of aluminum alloy with reduced porosity and high deposition rate. Mater. Des. 2021;199:109370. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2020.109370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2020.109370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toda H., Hidaka T., Kobayashi M., Uesugi K., Takeuchi A., Horikawa K. Growth behavior of hydrogen micropores in aluminum alloys during high-temperature exposure. Acta Mater. 2009;57:2277&#x2013;2290. doi: 10.1016/j.actamat.2009.01.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2009.01.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Zhou X., Liu T., Kang Y., Zhan X. Investigate on the porosity morphology and formation mechanism in laser-MIG hybrid welded joint for 5A06 aluminum alloy with Y-shaped groove. J. Manuf. Process. 2020;57:847&#x2013;856. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2020.07.044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2020.07.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojumder S., Gan Z., Li Y., Al Amin A., Liu W.K. Linking process parameters with lack-of-fusion porosity for laser powder bed fusion metal additive manufacturing. Addit. Manuf. 2023;68:103500. doi: 10.1016/j.addma.2023.103500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addma.2023.103500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Xu L., Hao K., Han Y., Zhao L., Ren W. High-power laser-arc hybrid additive manufacturing of aluminum alloys: Resolving the conflict between forming precision and keyhole-induced porosity via beam oscillation. J. Mater. Process. Technol. 2026;347:119146. doi: 10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2025.119146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2025.119146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal S., Lojen G., Gubeljak N., Kokol V., Drstvensek I. Melting, fusion and solidification behaviors of Ti-6Al-4V alloy in selective laser melting at different scanning speeds. Rapid Prototyp. J. 2020;26:1209&#x2013;1215. doi: 10.1108/RPJ-07-2019-0206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/RPJ-07-2019-0206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao W., Yang Z., Chen Y., Li L., Jiang Z., Zhang Y. Double-sided fiber laser beam welding process of T-joints for aluminum aircraft fuselage panels: Filler wire melting behavior, process stability, and their effects on porosity defects. Opt. Laser Technol. 2013;52:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2013.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2013.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arana M., Ukar E., Rodriguez I., Iturrioz A., Alvarez P. Strategies to Reduce Porosity in Al-Mg WAAM Parts and Their Impact on Mechanical Properties. Metals. 2021;11:524. doi: 10.3390/met11030524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met11030524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javidrad H., Aydin H., Karaka&#x15f; B., Alptekin S., Kahraman A.S., Koc B. Process parameter optimization for laser powder directed energy deposition of Inconel 738LC. Opt. Laser Technol. 2024;176:110940. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2024.110940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2024.110940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao W., Liu Y., Huang J., Zou S., Ren Z., Liu S., Wang Y. Process parameter optimization for laser directed energy deposition B4C/Al neutron absorbing material via Taguchi method. Opt. Laser Technol. 2025;184:112507. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2025.112507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2025.112507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saad M.S., Mohd Nor A., Zakaria M.Z., Baharudin M.E., Yusoff W.S. Modelling and evolutionary computation optimization on FDM process for flexural strength using integrated approach RSM and PSO. Prog. Addit. Manuf. 2021;6:143&#x2013;154. doi: 10.1007/s40964-020-00157-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40964-020-00157-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamath C., El-Dasher B., Gallegos G.F., King W.E., Sisto A. Density of additively-manufactured, 316L SS parts using laser powder-bed fusion at powers up to 400 W. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2014;74:65&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1007/s00170-014-5954-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-014-5954-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tercan H., Meisen T. Machine learning and deep learning based predictive quality in manufacturing: A systematic review. J. Intell. Manuf. 2022;33:1879&#x2013;1905. doi: 10.1007/s10845-022-01963-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10845-022-01963-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Jaiswal P., Rai R., Guerrier P., Baggs G. Convolutional neural network-based inspection of metal additive manufacturing parts. Rapid Prototyp. J. 2019;25:530&#x2013;540. doi: 10.1108/RPJ-04-2018-0096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/RPJ-04-2018-0096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maitra V., Shi J., Lu C. Robust prediction and validation of as-built density of Ti-6Al-4V parts manufactured via selective laser melting using a machine learning approach. J. Manuf. Process. 2022;78:183&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1016/j.jmapro.2022.04.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2022.04.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An Z., Sun H., Zhang X. Bead geometry prediction for gas metal arc directed energy deposited layer using interpretable machine learning. Mater. Today Commun. 2025;42:111138. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvan S.P., Raja D.E., Muthukumar V., Sonar T. Optimization of process parameters and predicting surface finish of PLA in additive manufacturing&#x2014;A neural network approach. Int. J. Interact. Des. Manuf. 2025;19:2511&#x2013;2520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Li Z., Wang Y., Guo W., Lu B. Study on the Process Window in Wire Arc Additive Manufacturing of a High Relative Density Aluminum Alloy. Metals. 2024;14:330. doi: 10.3390/met14030330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met14030330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa A., Buffa G., Palmeri D., Pollara G., Fratini L. Hybrid prediction-optimization approaches for maximizing parts density in SLM of Ti6Al4V titanium alloy. J. Intell. Manuf. 2022;33:1967&#x2013;1989. doi: 10.1007/s10845-022-01938-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10845-022-01938-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L., Zhang C., Jiang X., Zhang R., Wang Y., Yin H., Liu G., Su J., Qu X. Optimizing additive manufacturing parameters for martensitic stainless steel via machine learning. Mater. Today Commun. 2024;41:110290. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.110290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Zhuo S., Lu X., Yan J., Gong P., Zhang T., Wu D., Liu H. Optimization of Process Parameters to Minimize Porosity and Splash in Cold Metal Transfer and Pulse Wire Arc Additive Manufacturing of High-Strength Aluminum Alloy. Adv. Eng. Mater. 2025;27:2402155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barik S., Bhandari R., Mondal M.K. Optimization of Wire Arc Additive Manufacturing Process Parameters for Low-Carbon Steel and Properties Prediction by Support Vector Regression Model. Steel Res. Int. 2024;95:2300369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Brice C., Zhang X. Interrelated process-geometry-microstructure relationships for wire-feed laser additive manufacturing. Mater. Today Commun. 2022;31:103794. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2022.103794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2022.103794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuabiah M., Weidemann T.C., Elahi M.A., Shaqour B., Day R., Plapper P., Bergs T. Investigating the Impact of Process Parameters on Bead Geometry in Laser Wire-Feed Metal Additive Manufacturing. J. Manuf. Mater. Process. 2024;8:204. doi: 10.3390/jmmp8050204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmmp8050204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Chen X., Chen T., Ma G., Zhang W., Huang L. Influence of Pulse Energy and Defocus Amount on the Mechanism and Surface Characteristics of Femtosecond Laser Polishing of SiC Ceramics. Micromachines. 2022;13:1118. doi: 10.3390/mi13071118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mi13071118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9324907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35888935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L., Wang H., Li N., Chen X., Li T., Liu L. Microstructure and mechanical properties of 5356 aluminum alloy fabricated by dual-beam laser metal deposition. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2025;36:3112&#x2013;3122. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2025.03.255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2025.03.255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory E., Frankforter E., Spaeth P., Schneck W., Juarez P. High performance simulation of ultrasound inspection of porosity in additive manufactured parts. NDT E Int. 2023;139:102931. doi: 10.1016/j.ndteint.2023.102931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ndteint.2023.102931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Zhou Q., Cao L., Wang Y., Hu J. A convolutional neural network-based multi-sensor fusion approach for in-situ quality monitoring of selective laser melting. J. Manuf. Syst. 2022;64:429&#x2013;442. doi: 10.1016/j.jmsy.2022.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmsy.2022.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins T.J. ImageJ for Microscopy. BioTechniques. 2007;43:S25&#x2013;S30. doi: 10.2144/000112517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2144/000112517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17936939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao W.W., Zhang B., Liu Y., Liu C.S., Tan P., Shang S., Zhang G.P. Effect of laser power on porosity and mechanical properties of GH4169 fabricated by laser melting deposition. Tungsten. 2019;1:297&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1007/s42864-020-00034-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42864-020-00034-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P., Farah J., Akram J., Teng C., Ginn J., Misra M. Influence of laser processing parameters on porosity in Inconel 718 during additive manufacturing. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2019;103:1497&#x2013;1507. doi: 10.1007/s00170-019-03655-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-019-03655-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter B., Hocker S.J., Frankforter E.L., Tayon W.A., Glaessgen E.H. Influence of ultrasonic excitation on the melt pool and microstructure characteristics of Ti-6Al-4V at powder bed fusion additive manufacturing solidification velocities. Addit. Manuf. 2024;89:104228. doi: 10.1016/j.addma.2024.104228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addma.2024.104228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang J., Li M., Lian Y., Peng S., Liu C. A Fast Prediction Model for Liquid Metal Transfer Modes during the Wire Arc Additive Manufacturing Process. Materials. 2023;16:2911. doi: 10.3390/ma16072911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16072911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37049203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teichmann E.W., Kelbassa J., Gasser A., Tarner S., Schleifenbaum J.H. Effect of wire feeder force control on laser metal deposition process using coaxial laser head. J. Laser Appl. 2021;33:012041. doi: 10.2351/7.0000304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2351/7.0000304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tani G., Tomesani L., Campana G., Fortunato A. Evaluation of molten pool geometry with induced plasma plume absorption in laser-material interaction zone. Int. J. Mach. Tools Manuf. 2007;47:971&#x2013;977. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmachtools.2006.07.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmachtools.2006.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahul M., Pavl&#xed;k M., Ludrovcov&#xe1; B., Sahul M., Ber&#xe1;nek L., Horv&#xe1;th J. Influence of argon gas flow rate on the porosity of AA5087 aluminum alloy walls made by metal inert gas wire and arc additive manufacturing. Mater. Lett. 2025;399:139025. doi: 10.1016/j.matlet.2025.139025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2025.139025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadiani N., Barnard A.S., Gunasegaram D., Fayyazifar N. Best practices for machine learning strategies aimed at process parameter development in powder bed fusion additive manufacturing. J. Intell. Manuf. 2025;36:4477&#x2013;4517. doi: 10.1007/s10845-024-02490-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10845-024-02490-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.A., Sagong M.J., Jung J., Kim E.S., Kim H.S. Explainable machine learning for understanding and predicting geometry and defect types in Fe-Ni alloys fabricated by laser metal deposition additive manufacturing. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2023;22:413&#x2013;423. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.11.137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.11.137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai R., Wang K., Wen W., Peng Y., Baniassadi M., Ahzi S. Application of machine learning methods on dynamic strength analysis for additive manufactured polypropylene-based composites. Polym. Test. 2022;110:107580. doi: 10.1016/j.polymertesting.2022.107580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymertesting.2022.107580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamri F., Barsoum I., Bojanampati S., Maalouf M. Prediction of porosity, hardness and surface roughness in additive manufactured AlSi10Mg samples. PLoS ONE. 2025;20:e0316600. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0316600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0316600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11892887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40063673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai R., Liang G., Cheng H., Naceur H., Coutellier D., Zhao J., Luo J., Pu H., Yi J. Optimizing additive manufacturing path pattern for Ti-6Al-4V thin rods using a combinatorial radial basis function surrogate-assisted genetic algorithm. Mater. Des. 2023;236:112447. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2023.112447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2023.112447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>