<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41571542</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0267</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Injury</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Injury</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of a new tool for prediction of hospital length of stay and intensive care needs in trauma patients using Machine Learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>113047</StartPage><MedlinePgn>113047</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.injury.2026.113047</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0020-1383(26)00034-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Trauma is a major global health burden leading to significant morbidity, disability, and mortality. Predictive models in trauma care traditionally focus on mortality, but early predictions of hospital length of stay (LOS) and intensive care unit (ICU) needs could greatly enhance hospital planning and resource allocation. Machine learning (ML) offers new possibilities for developing prediction tools for these outcomes but remain underexplored in large, unselected trauma populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To develop and validate machine learning-based models for early prediction of hospital length of stay and ICU admission among severely injured trauma patients using a large patient cohort from a national trauma registry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patient data from 9056 adult severely injured trauma patients (NISS &gt;15) registered in the Swedish trauma registry SweTrau between 2015 and 2019 were analyzed. Only variables available at hospital arrival were used as predictors. Outcomes were LOS (1-2, 3-9, or &#x2265;10 days) and ICU admission (yes/no). Patients from 2015 to 2018 (n = 6706) were used for training Generalized Linear Model (GLM), Random Forest (RF), and Extreme Gradient Boosting (XGB) models, and patients from 2019 (n = 2350) were used for temporal internal-external validation. Model performance was assessed with ROC curves, calibration curves and DCA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The XGB models consistently outperformed GLM and RF models for all outcomes. For estimation of ICU admission, the XGB model achieved an AUC of 0.85 (95% CI: 0.84-0.87). For estimations of LOS, the XGB model achieved "one-vs- all" AUCs of 0.69, 0.64, and 0.71 for the three LOS categories, respectively. A clinical prediction tool based on the best-performing models was created and is available online (https://hipfx.shinyapps.io/traumaadvisorapp/).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Machine learning models trained on national trauma registry data demonstrated strong performance in predicting ICU admission and moderate accuracy in categorizing hospital length of stay. The XGB model showed the highest overall predictive power and may serve as a useful tool to support early triage, guide clinical decision-making, and optimize resource allocation in trauma care settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mosfeldt</LastName><ForeName>Mathias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and Surgery, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden. Electronic address: mathias.mosfeldt@regionstockholm.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holtenius</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Science, Intervention and Technology, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berg</LastName><ForeName>Hans E</ForeName><Initials>HE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Science, Intervention and Technology, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; Department of Physiology and Pharmacology Division of Environmental Physiology, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Enocson</LastName><ForeName>Anders</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and Surgery, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden; Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Injury</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0226040</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0020-1383</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hospital length of stay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trauma</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41571542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.injury.2026.113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0020-1383(26)00034-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>