<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600185</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>HAARN: A Deep Neural Network-Based Intelligent Control Method for High-Altitude Adaptability of Heavy-Load UAV Power Systems.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">389</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020389</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The construction of ultra-high voltage transmission lines puts extremely high demands on the high-altitude operation of heavy-load unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV). Air density and temperature at high altitudes have a great influence on the efficiency and stability of the UAV power system. Traditional regulation methods based on parameters pre-set or simple look-up tables cannot achieve the best adaptability. In this paper, we presents an intelligent method for the high-altitude adaptability control of heavy-load UAV power systems using a deep neural network. The proposed method collects real-time, multi-dimensional environmental parameters, including altitude, temperature, and air pressure, using a barometric altimeter and GPS receiver, constructs a High-Altitude Adaptive Regulation Network (HAARN), and intelligently learns complex nonlinear relationships to predict the optimal motor speed, propeller pitch angle, and current limit under the current environmental conditions so as to dynamically adjust power output. The HAARN model was trained on a dataset of 12,000 synchronized samples collected from both controlled environmental-chamber experiments (temperature range: -10 &#xb0;C to 20 &#xb0;C; pressure range: 100-50 kPa, corresponding approximately to 0-5500 m) and multi-point plateau flight trials conducted at 2000 m, 3000 m, 4000 m, and 4500 m. This combined dataset was used for feature engineering, exhaustive-label generation, and model validation to ensure robust generalization across realistic high-altitude operating conditions. Experimental results show that, compared with traditional PID control and lookup-table approaches, the proposed method reduces thrust attenuation by about 12.5% and improves energy efficiency by 8.3% at the altitude of 4000 m. In addition, HAARN demonstrates consistent improvements across the tested altitude range (0-4500 m).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Haihong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Power Transmission and Transformation Engineering Company Limited, Xi'an 710003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Xinsheng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Power Transmission and Transformation Engineering Company Limited, Xi'an 710003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Power Transmission and Transformation Engineering Company Limited, Xi'an 710003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Jianrong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Power Transmission and Transformation Engineering Company Limited, Xi'an 710003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Shaanxi Electric Power Co., Ltd., Construction Branch, Xi'an 710005, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Power Transmission and Transformation Engineering Company Limited, Xi'an 710003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Lejia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Microelectronics, Xidian University, Xi'an 710126, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>None</GrantID><Agency>Qinling Region Full-Process Mechanization Construction Special Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep neural network (DNN)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heavy-load UAV</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-altitude adaptability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power system regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultra-high voltage (UHV) construction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Haihong Zhou, Xinsheng Duan, Xiaojun Li, Jianrong Luo and Xiaoyu Guo were employed by the company Shaanxi Power Transmission and Transformation Engineering Company Limited. Author Bin Zhang was employed by the company State Grid Shaanxi Electric Power Co., Ltd., Construction Branch. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12845981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Reddy S.A., Kumari M.S. A review of switching overvoltage modeling in UHV AC transmission lines. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 2024;236:110902. doi: 10.1016/j.epsr.2024.110902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2024.110902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng X., Chen W., Mei H., Wang L. Corrosion mechanism of UHV transmission line tower foot in Southern China. IEEE Trans. Power Deliv. 2023;39:210&#x2013;219. doi: 10.1109/TPWRD.2023.3329140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2023.3329140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J., Xu J., Qian J., Chen Z., Yin J., Gao Y., Hu Z. A precise measurement method for positive sequence parameters of EHV and UHV transmission lines and its application; Proceedings of the 2011 IEEE Power Engineering and Automation Conference; Wuhan, China. 8&#x2013;9 September 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou Y., Tan Q., Zhu J., Zhao H., Zhu B., Zhang J., Zhou L. Microprocessor-based protection algorithm in UHV transmission lines with series compensated capacitor. Power Syst. Prot. Control. 2015;43:45&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Ge X., Hou X.L. The Research of Application Mode of Unmanned Aircraft Patrol in UHV Transmission Lines. Appl. Mech. Mater. 2014;536&#x2013;537:989&#x2013;992. doi: 10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMM.536-537.989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMM.536-537.989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Zhou Y., Lamont L., Deziel M. A token circulation scheme for code assignment and cooperative transmission scheduling in CDMA-based UAV ad hoc networks. Wirel. Netw. 2013;19:1469&#x2013;1484. doi: 10.1007/s11276-013-0545-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11276-013-0545-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Gao J., Gao J., Wang X., Song J., Jiang S. Investigation on strategies for reducing exhaust losses in opposed rotary piston engine and the impact of structure-induced internal EGR on engine performance. Energy. 2025;330:136934. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2025.136934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2025.136934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenyvesi B., Kriegseis J., Horv&#xe1;th C. An automated method for the identification of interaction tone noise sources on the beamforming maps of counter-rotating rotors. Phys. Fluids. 2022;34:047105. doi: 10.1063/5.0083634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0083634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brulin P.Y., Khenfri F., Rizoug N. Generating Fault Databases Through Simulated and Experimental Multi-Rotor UAV Propulsion Systems. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2024;73:12. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2024.3352172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2024.3352172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q.L., Zhang Y., Rabbath C.A., Theilliol D. Design of feedback linearization control and reconfigurable control allocation with application to a quadrotor UAV; Proceedings of the Control &amp; Fault-Tolerant Systems; Nice, France. 6&#x2013;8 October 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatini R., Salazar L.R., Kaharkar A., Bartel C., Shaid T. Carrier-phase GNSS Attitude Determination and Control System for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Applications. J. Aerosp. Eng. 2012;2:297&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan A., Sivadas M., Samuel E.R. Control of Attitude Trajectory of Launch Vehicle Using Optimal LQR-Based PID Controller; Proceedings of the Congress on Control, Robotics, and Mechatronics; Warangal, India. 3&#x2013;4 February 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Z., Li W., Xing Y., Li Z. Attitude control of quadrotor based on PID-ADRC; Proceedings of the 2024 43rd Chinese Control Conference (CCC); Kunming, China. 28&#x2013;31 July 2024; pp. 4198&#x2013;4203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eze P.C., Ezenugu I.A. Microsatellite Yaw-axis Attitude Control System Using Model Reference Adaptive Control Based PID Controller. Int. J. Electr. Comput. Eng. Res. (IJECER) 2024;4:8&#x2013;16. doi: 10.53375/ijecer.2024.389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53375/ijecer.2024.389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad S.M., Fareed S. Attitude modelling and real-time robust control of a 3-DoF quadcopter UAV test bench. Aeronaut. J. 2024;128:1767&#x2013;1788. doi: 10.1017/aer.2024.11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/aer.2024.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang X., Kong B., Gholizadeh F. Assessment and comparison of the operation of an unmanned aerial vehicle&#x2019;s propulsion system based on the different fuel cells. Energy Sources Part A Recovery Util. Environ. Eff. 2022;44:3294&#x2013;3312. doi: 10.1080/15567036.2022.2061645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15567036.2022.2061645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tippetts B.J., Lee D.J., Fowers S.G., Archibald J.K. Real-Time Vision Sensor for an Autonomous Hovering Micro Unmanned Aerial Vehicle. J. Aerosp. Comput. Inf. Commun. 2012;6:570&#x2013;584. doi: 10.2514/1.40185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2514/1.40185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuksek B., Vuruskan A., Ozdemir U., Yukselen M.A., Inalhan G. Transition Flight Modeling of a Fixed-Wing VTOL UAV. J. Intell. Robot. Syst. 2016;84:1&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1007/s10846-015-0325-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10846-015-0325-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benbouali A., Chabni F., Taleb R., Mansour N. Flight parameters improvement for an unmanned aerial vehicle using a lookup table based fuzzy PID controller. Inst. Adv. Eng. Sci. 2021;23:171&#x2013;178. doi: 10.11591/ijeecs.v23.i1.pp171-178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11591/ijeecs.v23.i1.pp171-178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M., Zhu H., Xia X., Liu Z., Yao W. Adaptive Optimization Tracking Control for an Unmanned Aerial Vehicle with Disturbance Suppression; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC); Kuching, Malaysia. 6&#x2013;10 October 2024; pp. 765&#x2013;771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Li Y., Tai Y., Lu X., Jia Y., Wang Y. A* algorithm based on adaptive expansion convolution for unmanned aerial vehicle path planning. Intell. Serv. Robot. 2024;17:521&#x2013;531. doi: 10.1007/s11370-024-00536-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11370-024-00536-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emami H. An adaptive local search-based arithmetic optimization algorithm for unmanned aerial vehicle placement. J. Supercomput. 2025;81:302. doi: 10.1007/s11227-024-06812-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-024-06812-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G., Wang W., Dong J. Performance-Optimize Adaptive Robust Tracking Control for USV-UAV Heterogeneous Systems with Uncertainty. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2025;74:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2025.3526360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2025.3526360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G., Huang F., Shu B., Wei G. MAHACO: Multi-algorithm hybrid ant colony optimizer for 3D path planning of a group of UAVs. Inf. Sci. 2025;694:121714. doi: 10.1016/j.ins.2024.121714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ins.2024.121714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citroni R., Di Paolo F., Livreri P. A novel energy harvester for powering small UAVs: Performance analysis, model validation and flight results. Sensors. 2019;19:1771. doi: 10.3390/s19081771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s19081771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6514568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31013890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung P.H., Amitay M. Control of a Miniducted-Fan Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Using Active Flow Control. J. Aircr. 2002;39:561. doi: 10.2514/2.2993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2514/2.2993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou Q., Chen X.Q., Park D., Marburg A., Pinchin J. Integrated Flight Dynamics Modelling for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles; Proceedings of the 2008 IEEE/ASME International Conference on Mechtronic and Embedded Systems and Applications; Beijing, China. 12&#x2013;15 October 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segui M., Botez R.M. Electric Motor Chain Modeling Using Artificial Neural Networks and Semi-Empirical Methods. J. Aerosp. Inf. Syst. 2024;21:18. doi: 10.2514/1.I011250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2514/1.I011250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>