<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41927823</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2948-2933</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of imaging informatics in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Imaging Inform Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multimodal Imaging-Based Prediction of Pathological Complete Response After Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy for Breast Cancer.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10278-026-01946-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The objective of this study was to develop a nomogram and assess the predictive value of imaging features-derived from ultrasound, mammography, and contrast-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of primary breast lesions-in combination with clinicopathological factors and serological tumor markers, for predicting pathological complete response (pCR) after neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC) in patients with breast cancer (BC).&#xa0;Retrospective analysis was used in 294 breast cancer patients who received NAC&#xa0;and subsequently underwent surgery at the Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital from 2017 to 2023. Patients were randomly assigned to a training cohort (n = 206) or a validation cohort (n = 88) in a 7:3 ratio. Data collected included preoperative imaging features of the primary breast lesion from conventional ultrasound, mammography, and contrast-enhanced MRI, as well as clinicopathological factors and serological tumor markers. After comparing the baseline characteristics between the two cohorts, univariate analysis was performed on the training cohort. Variables with significant results in the univariate analysis were incorporated into a multivariate logistic regression model. Backward stepwise selection was employed to identify independent risk factors of nonpathological complete response (non-pCR). A nomogram was constructed based on the final multivariate model. The model's discriminatory power was evaluated using the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve, and its calibration was assessed with a calibration plot and the Hosmer Lemeshow goodness-of-fit test.&#xa0;Of 294 enrolled patients, 87 (29.6%) achieved pCR. Univariate analysis in the training cohort identified multiple factors potentially associated with non-pCR. These factors included clinical pathological markers such&#xa0;as ER, PR, HER2, and Ki-67 status; ultrasound features including tumor location, distance from the nipple, hyperechoic halo, posterior echo, and calcification; mammographic characteristics encompassing mass margin, microcalcification, distribution and morphology of microcalcification, asymmetry, density of asymmetry, and other signs; and contrast-enhanced MRI parameters like background parenchymal enhancement (BPE) and mass margin. Multivariate logistic regression analysis subsequently demonstrated that ER, HER2, Ki-67, tumor location, distance from the nipple, morphology of microcalcification, and mass margin on contrast-enhanced MRI independently predicted non-pCR (p &lt; 0.05). A nomogram incorporating these independent predictors showed excellent discrimination; the training cohort's AUC was 0.833 (95% CI 0.772-0.893), the validation cohort's AUC was 0.749 (95% CI 0.640-0.857). This robust predictive model represents a significant step toward individualized treatment strategies by accurately forecasting the likelihood of pCR following neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s) under exclusive licence to Society for Imaging Informatics in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wenhui</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Wenqi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuling</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yizhuo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, Harbin, China. connie86318@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Imaging Inform Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918663679206676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2948-2925</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mammography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neoadjuvant chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pathological complete response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasound</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval: This research study was conducted retrospectively from data obtained for clinical purposes. We consulted extensively with the IRB of Harbin Medical University Cancer Hospital, which determined that our study did not need ethical approval. Consent to Participate: Informed consent was obtained from all individual participants included in the study. Consent for Publication: The authors affirm that human research participants provided informed consent for publication of the images in Figs. 5&#x2009;A, 5B, 5&#x2009;C, 5D, 6&#x2009;A, 6B, 6&#x2009;C, and 6D. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41927823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-026-01946-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10278-026-01946-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global Cancer Statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN Estimates of Incidence and Mortality Worldwide for 36 Cancers in 185 Countries. CA: a cancer journal for clinicians. May 2021;71(3):209&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gradishar WJ, Moran MS, Abraham J, et al. Breast Cancer, Version 3.2024, NCCN Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology. Journal of the National Comprehensive Cancer Network : JNCCN. Jul 2024;22(5):331&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham PJ, Brar MS, Foster T, et al. Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy for Breast Cancer, Is Practice Changing? A Population-Based Review of Current Surgical Trends. Annals of surgical oncology. Oct 2015;22(10):3376-3382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-015-4714-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26202561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Minckwitz G, Untch M, Blohmer JU, et al. Definition and impact of pathologic complete response on prognosis after neoadjuvant chemotherapy in various intrinsic breast cancer subtypes. Journal of clinical oncology : official journal of the American Society of Clinical Oncology. May 20 2012;30(15):1796-1804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2011.38.8595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crivelli P, Ledda RE, Parascandolo N, Fara A, Soro D, Conti M. A New Challenge for Radiologists: Radiomics in Breast Cancer. BioMed research international. 2018;2018:6120703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/6120703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30402486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6196984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caudle AS, Gonzalez-Angulo AM, Hunt KK, et al. Predictors of tumor progression during neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer. Journal of clinical oncology : official journal of the American Society of Clinical Oncology. Apr 10 2010;28(11):1821-1828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2009.25.3286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20231683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2860366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans A, Whelehan P, Thompson A, et al. Prediction of Pathological Complete Response to Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy for Primary Breast Cancer Comparing Interim Ultrasound, Shear Wave Elastography and MRI. Ultraschall in der Medizin (Stuttgart, Germany : 1980). Aug 2018;39(4):422&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefgen B, Mati M, Sinn HP, et al. Can Routine Imaging After Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy in Breast Cancer Predict Pathologic Complete Response? Annals of surgical oncology. Mar 2016;23(3):789&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-015-4918-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26467456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwase M, Hattori M, Sawaki M, et al. Presence of small residual malignant lesions in pathologic complete response after neo-adjuvant chemotherapy in patients with breast cancer. The breast journal. Nov 2019;25(6):1303-1305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbj.13473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31318111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto Y, Higuchi T, Nishimukai A, et al. High levels of serum CA15-3 and residual invasive tumor size are associated with poor prognosis for breast cancer patients with non-pathological complete response after neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Journal of surgical oncology. Jul 2018;118(1):228&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jso.25125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29936704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan S, Li J, Chen J, et al. Clinical Efficacy of Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy plus Modified Radical Mastectomy for Stage II-III Breast Cancer Patients and Its Influence on Serum Tumor Markers. Alternative therapies in health and medicine. Jan 2024;30(1):260&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37773687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan W, Yang M, Yang H, Zhou F, Shen W. Predicting the response to neoadjuvant therapy for early-stage breast cancer: tumor-, blood-, and imaging-related biomarkers. Cancer management and research. 2018;10:4333-4347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CMAR.S174435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6188192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spak DA, Plaxco JS, Santiago L, Dryden MJ, Dogan BE. BI-RADS(&#xae;) fifth edition: A summary of changes. Diagnostic and interventional imaging. Mar 2017;98(3):179&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diii.2017.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28131457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Horton JK, Yin FF, Chang Z. Assessment of Treatment Response With Diffusion-Weighted MRI and Dynamic Contrast-Enhanced MRI in Patients With Early-Stage Breast Cancer Treated With Single-Dose Preoperative Radiotherapy: Initial Results. Technology in cancer research &amp; treatment. Oct 2016;15(5):651&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1533034615593191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammond ME, Hayes DF, Dowsett M, et al. American Society of Clinical Oncology/College Of American Pathologists guideline recommendations for immunohistochemical testing of estrogen and progesterone receptors in breast cancer. Journal of clinical oncology : official journal of the American Society of Clinical Oncology. Jun 1 2010;28(16):2784-2795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2009.25.6529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20404251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2881855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartlett JM, Starczynski J, Atkey N, et al. HER2 testing in the UK: recommendations for breast and gastric in-situ hybridisation methods. Journal of clinical pathology. Aug 2011;64(8):649&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jcp.2011.089847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21690244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldhirsch A, Winer EP, Coates AS, et al. Personalizing the treatment of women with early breast cancer: highlights of the St Gallen International Expert Consensus on the Primary Therapy of Early Breast Cancer 2013. Annals of oncology : official journal of the European Society for Medical Oncology. Sep 2013;24(9):2206-2223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdt303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3755334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litton JK, Regan MM, Pusztai L, et al. Standardized Definitions for Efficacy End Points in Neoadjuvant Breast Cancer Clinical Trials: NeoSTEEP. Journal of clinical oncology : official journal of the American Society of Clinical Oncology. Sep 20 2023;41(27):4433-4442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.23.00435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10522109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candelaria RP, Adrada BE, Lane DL, et al. Mid-treatment Ultrasound Descriptors as Qualitative Imaging Biomarkers of Pathologic Complete Response in Patients with Triple-Negative Breast Cancer. Ultrasound in medicine &amp; biology. Jun 2022;48(6):1010-1018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultrasmedbio.2022.01.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang MQ, Liu XP, Du Y, et al. Prediction of pathological complete response of breast cancer patients who received neoadjuvant chemotherapy with a nomogram based on clinicopathologic variables, ultrasound, and MRI. The British journal of radiology. Jan 23 2024;97(1153):228&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjr/tqad014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38263817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11027305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hattali S, Vinnicombe SJ, Gowdh NM, et al. Breast MRI and tumour biology predict axillary lymph node response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy for breast cancer. Cancer imaging : the official publication of the International Cancer Imaging Society. Dec 26 2019;19(1):91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan C, Stringfellow TD, Rolph R, et al. Neoadjuvant chemotherapy in patients with breast cancer: Does response in the breast predict axillary node response? European journal of surgical oncology : the journal of the European Society of Surgical Oncology and the British Association of Surgical Oncology. Apr 2020;46(4 Pt A):522&#x2013;526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwamoto N, Aruga T, Horiguchi S, et al. Predictive factors of an axillary pathological complete response of node-positive breast cancer to neoadjuvant chemotherapy. Surgery today. Feb 2020;50(2):178&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00595-019-01858-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31367884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peduzzi P, Concato J, Kemper E, Holford TR, Feinstein AR. A simulation study of the number of events per variable in logistic regression analysis. Journal of clinical epidemiology. Dec 1996;49(12):1373-1379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0895-4356(96)00236-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8970487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J, Tong T, Xu D, et al. Deep learning radiomics of ultrasonography for comprehensively predicting tumor and axillary lymph node status after neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer patients: A multicenter study. Cancer. Feb 1 2023;129(3):356&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.34540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36401611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciruelos Gil EM. Targeting the PI3K/AKT/mTOR pathway in estrogen receptor-positive breast cancer. Cancer treatment reviews. Aug 2014;40(7):862&#x2013;871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctrv.2014.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24774538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokunaga E, Hisamatsu Y, Tanaka K, et al. Molecular mechanisms regulating the hormone sensitivity of breast cancer. Cancer science. Nov 2014;105(11):1377-1383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cas.12521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25155268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4462367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vriens BE, de Vries B, Lobbes MB, et al. Ultrasound is at least as good as magnetic resonance imaging in predicting tumour size post-neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer. European journal of cancer (Oxford, England : 1990). Jan 2016;52:67&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li H, Wang C, et al. Evaluating the Accuracy of Breast Cancer and Molecular Subtype Diagnosis by Ultrasound Image Deep Learning Model. Frontiers in oncology. 2021;11:623506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2021.623506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33747937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7973262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma W, Zhao Y, Ji Y, et al. Breast Cancer Molecular Subtype Prediction by Mammographic Radiomic Features. Academic radiology. Feb 2019;26(2):196&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acra.2018.01.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son J, Lee SE, Kim EK, Kim S. Prediction of breast cancer molecular subtypes using radiomics signatures of synthetic mammography from digital breast tomosynthesis. Scientific reports. Dec 9 2020;10(1):21566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Ende NS, Nguyen AH, Jager A, Kok M, Debets R, van Deurzen CHM. Triple-Negative Breast Cancer and Predictive Markers of Response to Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy: A Systematic Review. International journal of molecular sciences. Feb 3 2023;24(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JH, Jeon W, Kim K, et al. Prognostic Significance of Inner Quadrant Involvement in Breast Cancer Treated with Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy. Journal of breast cancer. Dec 2016;19(4):394&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4048/jbc.2016.19.4.394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28053627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5204045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai AA, Hoskin TL, Day CN, Habermann EB, Boughey JC. Effect of Primary Breast Tumor Location on Axillary Nodal Positivity. Annals of surgical oncology. Oct 2018;25(10):3011-3018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-018-6590-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29968027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byon W, Kim E, Kwon J, Park YL, Park C. Magnetic resonance imaging and clinicopathological factors for the detection of occult nipple involvement in breast cancer patients. Journal of breast cancer. Dec 2014;17(4):386&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4048/jbc.2014.17.4.386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25548588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4278059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romeo V, Accardo G, Perillo T, et al. Assessment and Prediction of Response to Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy in Breast Cancer: A Comparison of Imaging Modalities and Future Perspectives. Cancers. Jul 14 2021;13(14).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen MM, Doyle S, van den Belt-Dusebout AW, et al. Clinicopathological and prognostic value of calcification morphology descriptors in ductal carcinoma in situ of the breast: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Insights into imaging. Dec 5 2023;14(1):213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YH, Ye JM, Xu L, et al. Effectiveness of dynamic contrast-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging in evaluating clinical responses to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in breast cancer. Chinese medical journal. Jan 2011;124(2):194&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21362364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal S, Brown NJ, Holen I. The breast tumor microenvironment: role in cancer development, progression and response to therapy. Expert review of molecular diagnostics. Mar 2018;18(3):227&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gkretsi V, Stylianou A, Papageorgis P, Polydorou C, Stylianopoulos T. Remodeling Components of the Tumor Microenvironment to Enhance Cancer Therapy. Frontiers in oncology. 2015;5:214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehraj U, Dar AH, Wani NA, Mir MA. Tumor microenvironment promotes breast cancer chemoresistance. Cancer chemotherapy and pharmacology. Feb 2021;87(2):147-158.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>