<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41769769</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1930-613X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Military medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mil Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Building the Bench: How Health Professions Education Programs Can Improve Organizational Retention.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">usag073</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/milmed/usag073</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Graduate degree programs in Health Professions Education (HPE) are one method of addressing the challenges associated with transitioning from being a full-time clinician to an educator, leader, and scholar of health professionals. Although previous research has focused on the individual benefits of HPE, such as increased self-efficacy and professional identity, little is known about the organizational impact - specifically on faculty retention rates. This study investigated whether participating in and earning a graduate degree from an HPE program influenced alumni decisions to remain in the Military Health System (MHS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted an anonymous electronic survey of alumni who graduated with a Masters or PhD in HPE from the Uniformed Services University between 2017 and 2024. The survey asked questions about the HPE degree's contribution to their desire to stay in the MHS and included open-ended questions to elaborate on responses. Descriptive statistics were calculated, and thematic analysis assessed the qualitative data to identify key themes and subthemes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Forty recent graduates responded to the survey for a 71% response rate. A majority of active duty military (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;24/36, 66.7%) and MHS civilian (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;3/4, 75%) respondents indicated that the HPE degree contributed to their desire to stay in the MHS. Over half of active duty alumni (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;20/36, 55.6%) stated they had or would stay longer than their current commitment, with nearly half (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;16/35, 45.7%) attributing this decision at least partially to the degree program and a further 23% (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;8/35) saying they were unsure. Thematic analysis revealed 3 themes representing mechanisms linking the HPE degree to retention: increased job opportunities (e.g., selection for next academic leadership positions), enhanced job satisfaction (via improved self-efficacy and community integration), and strengthened organizational loyalty and influence (e.g., feelings of gratitude toward the MHS and increased belief in the power to make an organizational impact).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Participation in the graduate HPE degree programs positively influenced the retention of health professional faculty by providing pathways to academic leadership, improving professional competence and satisfaction, and fostering organizational commitment. These findings suggest that investing in advanced HPE degrees is an important strategic tool for healthcare organizations seeking to cultivate and retain high-performing health professional faculty, educational leaders, and scholars.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Association of Military Surgeons of the United States 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>Beth</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Professions Education (HPE), Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, Bethesda, MD 20814, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, Inc, Bethesda, MD 20817, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durning</LastName><ForeName>Steven J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5223-1597</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Professions Education (HPE), Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, Bethesda, MD 20814, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pflipsen</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4195-2799</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Professions Education (HPE), Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences, Bethesda, MD 20814, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Mil Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2984771R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0026-4075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41769769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/milmed/usag073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">8503391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>