<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41592048</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2767-3375</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLOS global public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLOS Glob Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating the perceived outcome and impact of an integrated knowledge translation approach in the development of an equity reporting guideline: A cross-sectional survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0005854</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0005854</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0005854</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pgph.0005854</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Integrated knowledge translation (IKT) involves active engagement of knowledge users in co-producing research, ensuring their perspectives shape study design, analysis, and reporting. This can strengthen justice, equity, diversity, and inclusion (JEDI) considerations. We adopted an IKT approach in developing STROBE-Equity, an equity-focused reporting guidelin extension. The perceived value of embedding JEDI principles in reporting guideline development is unknown. This study examines the team's perceptions on the implementation of the JEDI-enhanced IKT process and its influence on the guideline. We conducted a cross-sectional survey of STROBE-Equity project members (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;68) between July-August 2024. The 19-item survey assessed disciplinary background, participation, and perceived benefits, challenges, and potential impacts of the JEDI-enhanced IKT approach. Inductive content analysis was used to identify themes, which were quantified with frequencies and percentages. Thirty-one members responded. Most were aged 35-54 (61%), female (55%), based in Canada (35%), and trained in epidemiology (61%). Reported benefits of IKT included integrating diverse perspectives, inclusive representation, and collaborative learning. Challenges involved accessibility and accommodations, consensus-building, and navigating power dynamics between researchers, policymakers, and those with lived experience. Participants perceived that IKT broadened the understanding of social conditions in the development process and facilitated incorporation of end-user perspectives, which they believed would strengthen the credibility and applicability of the guideline. They also noted that this collaborative approach would likely enhance the dissemination and uptake of STROBE-Equity and enhance its acceptability moving forward. A JEDI-enhanced IKT approach was viewed as beneficial to the development of the reporting guideline. Challenges such as accessibility and balancing power dynamics highlight areas where the participatory process could be improved. Future research should continue to refine and evaluate inclusive approaches to guideline development to further advance JEDI in research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Brown et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-4431-5656</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dewidar</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6420-887X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Temerty Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#xe8;re Health Research Institute, University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chamberlain</LastName><ForeName>Catherine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3446-0227</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Indigenous Health Equity Unit, Melbourne School of Population and Global Health, The University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuervo</LastName><ForeName>Luis Gabriel</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Doctoral Programme on Methodology of Biomedical Research and Public Health, Department of Paediatrics, Obstetrics, Gynaecology and Preventive Medicine and Public Health, Autonomous University of Barcelona, Bellaterra, Catalu&#xf1;a, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Academy of Medicine of Colombia, Bogot&#xe1;, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ellingwood</LastName><ForeName>Holly North</ForeName><Initials>HN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-1493-1905</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Law, Department of Psychology, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faber</LastName><ForeName>Sonya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1122-4109</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Epidemiology and Public Health, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Cindy</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Health and Epidemiology, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Francis</LastName><ForeName>Damian K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5449-1904</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Human Performance, Center for Health and Social Issues, Georgia College and State University, Milledgeville, Georgia, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Funnell</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Queen's University, Kingston, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghogomu</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0130-0182</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#xe8;re Health Research Institute, University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardy</LastName><ForeName>Billie-Jo</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3380-8076</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dalla Lana School of Public Health, University of Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Well Living House, Li Ka Shing Knowledge Institute, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horsley</LastName><ForeName>Tanya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada, Research, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasonde</LastName><ForeName>Mwenya</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, London, United Kingdon; World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kennedy</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Public Health, The University of Newcastle, Callaghan, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kredo</LastName><ForeName>Tamara</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Systems Research Unit, South African Medical Research Council, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Little</LastName><ForeName>Julian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5026-5531</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahande</LastName><ForeName>Michael Johnson</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology &amp; Biostatistics, Institute of Public Health, Kilimanjaro Christian Medical College, Moshi, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>Zack</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2315-3512</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Research Methods, Evidence and Impact, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mbuagbaw</LastName><ForeName>Lawrence</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruyere Health Research Institute, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nkangu</LastName><ForeName>Miriam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Africa Centre for Systematic Reviews and Knowledge Translation, College of Health Sciences, Makerere University, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Medicine, College of Health Sciences, Makerere University, Kampala, Uganda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Epidemiology &amp; Population Health, London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obuku</LastName><ForeName>Ekwaro A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sefako Makgatho Health Sciences University, Pretoria, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oloyede</LastName><ForeName>Oyekola</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1236-1009</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Rural Development and Innovation Studies, Kwame Nkrumah University of Science &amp; Technology, Kumasi, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owusu-Addo</LastName><ForeName>Ebenezer</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Pontificia Universidad Cat&#xf3;lica de Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pantoja</LastName><ForeName>Tom&#xe1;s</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5473-3053</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pottie</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rizvi</LastName><ForeName>Anita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3826-1439</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Knowledge Translation Program, Li Ka Shing Knowledge Institute, St. Michael's Hospital, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shamseer</LastName><ForeName>Larissa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#xe8;re Health Research Institute, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shea</LastName><ForeName>Beverley</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hassanah Consulting, Seattle, Washington, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tufte</LastName><ForeName>Janice</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4346-3238</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, and School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#xe8;re Health Research Institute, Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tugwell</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Global Child Health, Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhutta</LastName><ForeName>Zulfiqar</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Global Health &amp; Development, The Aga Khan University, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Evidence Based Health Care, Department of Global Health, Stellenbosch University, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiysonge</LastName><ForeName>Charles S</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1273-4779</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cochrane South Africa, South African Medical Research Council, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolfenden</LastName><ForeName>Luke</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Newcastle, School of Medicine and Public Health, Newcastle, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jull</LastName><ForeName>Janet</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0404-4313</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Carleton University, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, School of Rehabilitation Therapy, Queen's University, Kingston, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Welch</LastName><ForeName>Vivian</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5238-7097</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#xe8;re Health Research Institute, University of Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Epidemiology and Public Health, Faculty of Medicine University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLOS Glob Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918283779606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2767-3375</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>I have read the journal&#x2019;s policy and the authors of this manuscript have the following competing interests: VW and SF received support from the Canadian Institutes of Health Research grant for the submitted work. Payments were made to Bruy&#xe8;re Health Research Institute. SF serves as a Board Member on College of Family Physicians of Canada and National Circle of Indigenous Medical Education. LGC declares no support from any organization for the submitted work. He has no financial relationships with organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. He serves as an advisor and editorial board member for journals as a voluntary contribution, with details listed in his CV and ORCID profile. His employer, the Pan American Health Organization (PAHO/WHO), has covered travel incurred as part of his full-time position, and a copyright agreement was submitted through the corresponding author. He holds a retirement fund with BMA (BMP PG) and the United Nations Joint Staff Pension Fund, over which he has no control. His views expressed in this article do not necessarily represent PAHO or WHO policies, and reproduction of the article must avoid implying endorsement by these organizations. SF is an unpaid Board member of Chacruna Institute for Psychedelic Plant Medicines, and an employee of Angelini Pharma and a partner in the Bioville GmbH. TK is a Cochrane Board member and was an elected trustee since 2020. ZM reports grants from NSERC CREATE grant (Responsible AI), SSHRC Knowledge Synthesis Grants: Gender-Based Violence, and CIHR Catalyst Grant: Moving Upstream: Structural Determinants of Health. KP reports grants from the Public Health Agency of Canada and the Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR) and has been involved in multiple funded research projects related to COVID-19 and health equity, with payments made to Western University. He received consulting fees from CSL Behring for Ferinject clinical consultancy, honoraria for a guest lecture in Community Diabetes CME, and holds a pending patent related to health information-based communities and knowledge incentive systems. He also holds leadership roles in The Canadian Collaboration for Immigrant and Refugee Health, Cochrane Canada, and MSF Canada, all of which are unpaid. All authors have completed the ICMJE uniform disclosure form at www.icmje.org/disclosure-of-interest. The remaining authors have nothing to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41592048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12843522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0005854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PGPH-D-25-02783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hosseinpoor AR, Bergen N, Schlotheuber A, Grove J. Measuring health inequalities in the context of sustainable development goals. Bull World Health Organ. 2018;96(9):654&#x2013;9. doi: 10.2471/BLT.18.210401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2471/BLT.18.210401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6154075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30262947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart MJ, Kushner KE. Promoting Health Equity Research: Insights from a Canadian Initiative. Can J Nurs Res. 2014;46(1):102&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1177/084456211404600108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/084456211404600108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29509467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gee GC, Ford CL. Structural racism and health inequities: old issues, new directions. Du Bois Review. 2011;8(1):115&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4306458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25632292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funnell S, Jull J, Mbuagbaw L, Welch V, Dewidar O, Wang X, et al. Improving social justice in observational studies: protocol for the development of a global and Indigenous STROBE-equity reporting guideline. Int J Equity Health. 2023;22(1):55. doi: 10.1186/s12939-023-01854-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-023-01854-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10060140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36991403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmot M, Bell R. The Sustainable Development Goals and Health Equity. Epidemiology. 2018;29(1):5&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29053554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill J, Tabish H, Welch V, Petticrew M, Pottie K, Clarke M, et al. Applying an equity lens to interventions: using PROGRESS ensures consideration of socially stratifying factors to illuminate inequities in health. J Clin Epidemiol. 2014;67(1):56&#x2013;64. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.08.005 24189091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24189091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matheson A. Health Inequality as a Large-Scale Outcome of Complex Social Systems: Lessons for Action on the Sustainable Development Goals. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(8):2684. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17082684</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17082684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32295177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boland L, Kothari A, McCutcheon C, Graham ID, Integrated Knowledge Translation Research Network. Building an integrated knowledge translation (IKT) evidence base: colloquium proceedings and research direction. Health Res Policy Syst. 2020;18(1):8. doi: 10.1186/s12961-019-0521-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12961-019-0521-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6972018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31959184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jull J, Giles A, Graham ID. Community-based participatory research and integrated knowledge translation: advancing the co-creation of knowledge. Implement Sci. 2017;12(1):150. doi: 10.1186/s13012-017-0696-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-017-0696-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5735911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29258551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi AR, Berta W, Kothari A, Boyko J, Urquhart R. Integrated knowledge translation (IKT) in health care: a scoping review. Implement Sci. 2016;11:38. doi: 10.1186/s13012-016-0399-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-016-0399-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4797171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26988000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmartin-Thomas JF, Liew D, Hopper I. Observational studies and their utility for practice. Aust Prescr. 2018;41(3):82&#x2013;5. doi: 10.18773/austprescr.2018.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18773/austprescr.2018.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6003013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29922003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewidar O, Podinic I, Barbeau V, Patel D, Antequera A, Birnie D, et al. Integrating sex and gender in studies of cardiac resynchronization therapy: a systematic review. ESC Heart Fail. 2022;9(1):420&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1002/ehf2.13733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ehf2.13733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8788138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34821083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker LC, Hussain-Shamsy N, Rajendra KL, Bronskill SE, Brown HK, Kurdyak P, et al. The use of key social determinants of health variables in psychiatric research using routinely collected health data: a systematic analysis. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2023;58(2):183&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1007/s00127-022-02368-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-022-02368-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36149450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewidar O, Al-Zubaidi A, Bondok M, Abdelrazeq L, Huang J, Jearvis A, et al. Reporting of equity in observational epidemiology: A methodological review. J Glob Health. 2024;14:04046. doi: 10.7189/jogh.14.04046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.14.04046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10903926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38491911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Dewidar O, Rizvi A, Huang J, Desai P, Doyle R, et al. A scoping review establishes need for consensus guidance on reporting health equity in observational studies. J Clin Epidemiol. 2023;160:126&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2023.06.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2023.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37330072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizvi A, Lawson DO, Young T, Dewidar O, Nicholls S, Akl EA, et al. Guidance relevant to the reporting of health equity in observational research: a scoping review protocol. BMJ Open. 2022;12(5):e056875. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-056875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-056875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9121499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35589369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Minh Duc NT, Luu Lam Thang T, Nam NH, Ng SJ, Abbas KS, et al. A Consensus-Based Checklist for Reporting of Survey Studies (CROSS). J Gen Intern Med. 2021;36(10):3179&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1007/s11606-021-06737-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-021-06737-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8481359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petkovic J, Jull J, Yoganathan M, Dewidar O, Baird S, Grimshaw JM, et al. Reporting of health equity considerations in cluster and individually randomized trials. Trials. 2020;21(1):308. doi: 10.1186/s13063-020-4223-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-020-4223-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32245522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jull J, Smith M, Carley M, Stacey D, Graham ID, Cochrane Decision Coaching Review Team. Co-production of a systematic review on decision coaching: a mixed methods case study within a review. Syst Rev. 2024;13(1):149. doi: 10.1186/s13643-024-02563-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-024-02563-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11149211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38831444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontanarosa P, Bauchner H, Flanagin A. Authorship and Team Science. JAMA. 2017;318(24):2433&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/jama.2017.19341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.19341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29279909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jull J, Giles A, Boyer Y, Stacey D. Development of a collaborative research framework: The example of a study conducted by and with a First Nations, Inuit, and Metis women&#x2019;s community and their research partners. ACME: An International Journal for Critical Geographies. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jull J, Graham ID, Kristjansson E, Moher D, Petkovic J, Yoganathan M, et al. Taking an integrated knowledge translation approach in research to develop the CONSORT-Equity 2017 reporting guideline: an observational study. BMJ Open. 2019;9(7):e026866. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6678066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31366641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staniszewska S, Brett J, Simera I, Seers K, Mockford C, Goodlad S, et al. GRIPP2 reporting checklists: tools to improve reporting of patient and public involvement in research. BMJ. 2017;358:j3453. doi: 10.1136/bmj.j3453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j3453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28768629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morse J, Field P. Nursing research: the application of qualitative approaches. London. 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S E, H K. The qualitative content analysis: Journal of Advance Nursing; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denscombe M. Decolonial research methodology: an assessment of the challenge to established practice. International Journal of Social Research Methodology. 2024;28(2):231&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1080/13645579.2024.2357558</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13645579.2024.2357558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence LM, Bishop A, Curran J. Integrated Knowledge Translation with Public Health Policy Makers: A Scoping Review. Healthc Policy. 2019;14(3):55&#x2013;77. doi: 10.12927/hcpol.2019.25792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12927/hcpol.2019.25792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7008688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31017866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kothari A, Wathen CN. A critical second look at integrated knowledge translation. Health Policy. 2013;109(2):187&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1016/j.healthpol.2012.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthpol.2012.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23228520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham ID, Kothari A, McCutcheon C, Integrated Knowledge Translation Research Network Project Leads. Moving knowledge into action for more effective practice, programmes and policy: protocol for a research programme on integrated knowledge translation. Implement Sci. 2018;13(1):22. doi: 10.1186/s13012-017-0700-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-017-0700-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5797415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29394932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin MH, Clarke AR, Nocon RS, Casey AA, Goddu AP, Keesecker NM, et al. A roadmap and best practices for organizations to reduce racial and ethnic disparities in health care. J Gen Intern Med. 2012;27(8):992&#x2013;1000. doi: 10.1007/s11606-012-2082-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-012-2082-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3403142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22798211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaham S. Does SHRM&#x2019;s removal of &#x2018;equity&#x2019; from inclusion, equity, and diversity point to a new strategy or signal something much bigger?. Forbes. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn SI, Bhati DK, Reszel J, Kothari A, McCutcheon C, Graham ID. Understanding how and under what circumstances integrated knowledge translation works for people engaged in collaborative research: metasynthesis of IKTRN casebooks. JBI Evid Implement. 2023;21(3):277&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1097/XEB.0000000000000367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/XEB.0000000000000367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36988573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibley K, Femke H, Anita K, Kelly M. Effects, facilitators, and barriers of research coproduction reported in peer-reviewed literature. Hoboken: Wiley. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banner D, Bains M, Carroll S, Kandola DK, Rolfe DE, Wong C, et al. Patient and Public Engagement in Integrated Knowledge Translation Research: Are we there yet?. Res Involv Engagem. 2019;5:8. doi: 10.1186/s40900-019-0139-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40900-019-0139-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6373045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30805202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>