<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731144</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-2218</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Surgical endoscopy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Surg Endosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prediction of delayed bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection in early gastric cancer and precancerous lesions by BEST-C score.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00464-026-12666-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Delayed bleeding is a serious complication after endoscopic submucosal dissection (ESD) for early gastric cancer and precancerous lesions. Existing prediction models predominantly rely on pre-procedural factors, such as antithrombotic therapy (ATT), and overlook critical intraoperative variables. This study aimed to develop and validate a novel, procedure-centered risk model that integrates these intraoperative variables to improve predictive performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this retrospective, single-center study, we enrolled 1523 patients undergoing gastric ESD (January 2018 to September 2025). The primary outcome was delayed post-ESD bleeding. We focused on variables available before or immediately after ESD. Independent risk factors were identified via multivariate logistic regression to construct the Bleeding after ESD Trend from China (BEST-C) score. Model performance was assessed using the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC), calibration, and decision curve analysis, with internal validation via bootstrapping. Its discriminative ability was directly compared with two established models (BEST-J and BEST-FH).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Delayed bleeding occurred in 52 patients (3.4%). Multivariate analysis revealed that dual-ATT interruption, intraoperative bleeding, and the interaction between intraoperative bleeding and muscular layer injury were independent risk factors, whereas the use of hemostatic clips was identified as a protective factor. The BEST-C model demonstrated excellent discrimination (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.868) and calibration, significantly outperforming the BEST-J and BEST-FH scores (AUC difference 0.321, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). The derived integer score effectively stratified patients into low- (bleeding rate 1.0%), intermediate- (11.6%), and high-risk (88.2%) groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The BEST-C score, which uniquely incorporates critical intraoperative variables, most notably a key interaction term, provides a robust tool, centered on intraoperative factors, for immediate post-ESD risk stratification of delayed bleeding after gastric ESD. It demonstrates superior predictive performance to existing models and shows promising clinical utility.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Kaier</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Shaoxing Maternity and Child Health Care Hospital, Shaoxing, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Tianer</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second Sanatorium of Air Force Healthcare Center for Special Services, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bu</LastName><ForeName>Han</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weng</LastName><ForeName>Tianhao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Juzeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Sisi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-7923-5584</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China. liuyangmd@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Y20220365</GrantID><Agency>Wenzhou Municipal Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Surg Endosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8806653</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0930-2794</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Delayed bleeding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endoscopic submucosal dissection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastric precancerous lesions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemostatic clips</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intraoperative bleeding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction model</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Disclosures: Kaier Gu, Tianer Gu, Wei Xie, Han Bu, Tianhao Weng, Juzeng Zheng, Sisi Jin, and Yang Liu have no conflicts of interest or financial ties to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-026-12666-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00464-026-12666-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pimentel-Nunes P, Lib&#xe2;nio D, BaJ B, Bhandari P, Bisschops R, Bourke MJ, Esposito G, Lemmers A, Maselli R, Messmann H, Pech O, Pioche M, Vieth M, Weusten B, Van Hooft JE, Deprez PH, Dinis-Ribeiro M (2022) Endoscopic submucosal dissection for superficial gastrointestinal lesions: European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) Guideline - Update 2022. Endoscopy 54(6):591&#x2013;622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35523224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1811-7025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono H, Yao K, Fujishiro M, Oda I, Nimura S, Yahagi N, Iishi H, Oka M, Ajioka Y, Ichinose M, Matsui T (2016) Guidelines for endoscopic submucosal dissection and endoscopic mucosal resection for early gastric cancer. Digest Endosc 28(1):3&#x2013;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/den.12518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lib&#xe2;nio D, Pimentel-Nunes P, Bastiaansen B, Bisschops R, Bourke MJ, Deprez PH, Esposito G, Lemmers A, Leclercq P, Maselli R, Messmann H, Pech O, Pioche M, Vieth M, Weusten B, Fuccio L, Bhandari P, Dinis-Ribeiro M (2023) Endoscopic submucosal dissection techniques and technology: European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) technical review. Endoscopy 55(4):361&#x2013;389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36882090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2031-0874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano T, Tanabe S, Ishido K, Suzuki M, Kawanishi N, Yamane S, Watanabe A, Wada T, Azuma M, Katada C, Koizumi W (2017) Different clinical characteristics associated with acute bleeding and delayed bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection in patients with early gastric cancer. Surg Endosc 31(11):4542&#x2013;4550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28378078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-017-5513-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh R, Hirasawa K, Yahara S, Oka H, Sugimori K, Morimoto M, Numata K, Kokawa A, Sasaki T, Nozawa A, Taguri M, Morita S, Maeda S, Tanaka K (2013) Antithrombotic drugs are risk factors for delayed postoperative bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection for gastric neoplasms. Gastrointest Endosc 78(3):476&#x2013;483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23622974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2013.03.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JH, Kim SG, Kim JW, Choi YJ, Kwon J, Kim JY, Lee YB, Choi J, Im JP, Kim JS, Jung HC, Song IS (2012) Do antiplatelets increase the risk of bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection of gastric neoplasms? Gastrointest Endosc 75(4):719&#x2013;727</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22317881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2011.11.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato C, Hirasawa K, Koh R, Ikeda R, Fukuchi T, Kobayashi R, Kaneko H, Makazu M, Maeda S (2017) Postoperative bleeding in patients on antithrombotic therapy after gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection. World J Gastroenterol 23(30):5557&#x2013;5566</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28852315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5558119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v23.i30.5557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyokawa T, Inaba T, Omote S, Okamoto A, Miyasaka R, Watanabe K, Izumikawa K, Horii J, Fujita I, Ishikawa S, Morikawa T, Murakami T, Tomoda J (2012) Risk factors for perforation and delayed bleeding associated with endoscopic submucosal dissection for early gastric neoplasms: analysis of 1123 lesions. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 27(5):907&#x2013;912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22142449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1746.2011.07039.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y, Ji M, Yuan L, Yuan J, Shen L (2024) A risk prediction model for delayed bleeding after ESD for gastric precancerous lesions. Surg Endosc 38(7):3967&#x2013;3975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38844732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-024-10923-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lib&#xe2;nio D, Costa MN, Pimentel-Nunes P, Dinis-Ribeiro M (2016) Risk factors for bleeding after gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastrointest Endosc 84(4):572&#x2013;586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27345132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2016.06.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada K, Yamamoto Y, Kasuga A, Omae M, Kubota M, Hirasawa T, Ishiyama A, Chino A, Tsuchida T, Fujisaki J, Nakajima A, Hoshino E, Igarashi M (2011) Risk factors for delayed bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection for gastric neoplasm. Surg Endosc 25(1):98&#x2013;107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20549245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-010-1137-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatta W, Tsuji Y, Yoshio T, Kakushima N, Hoteya S, Doyama H, Nagami Y, Hikichi T, Kobayashi M, Morita Y, Sumiyoshi T, Iguchi M, Tomida H, Inoue T, Koike T, Mikami T, Hasatani K, Nishikawa J, Matsumura T, Nebiki H, Nakamatsu D, Ohnita K, Suzuki H, Ueyama H, Hayashi Y, Sugimoto M, Yamaguchi S, Michida T, Yada T, Asahina Y, Narasaka T, Kuribasyashi S, Kiyotoki S, Mabe K, Nakamura T, Nakaya N, Fujishiro M, Masamune A (2021) Prediction model of bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection for early gastric cancer: BEST-J score. Gut 70(3):476&#x2013;484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32499390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2019-319926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choe YH, Jung DH, Park JC, Kim HY, Shin SK, Lee SK, Lee YC (2021) Prediction model for bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection of gastric neoplasms from a high-volume center. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 36(8):2217&#x2013;2223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33646614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgh.15478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugimoto M, Hatta W, Tsuji Y, Yoshio T, Yabuuchi Y, Hoteya S, Doyama H, Nagami Y, Hikichi T, Kobayashi M, Morita Y, Sumiyoshi T, Iguchi M, Tomida H, Inoue T, Mikami T, Hasatani K, Nishikawa J, Matsumura T, Nebiki H, Nakamatsu D, Ohnita K, Suzuki H, Ueyama H, Hayashi Y, Murata M, Yamaguchi S, Michida T, Yada T, Asahina Y, Narasaka T, Kuribayashi S, Kiyotoki S, Mabe K, Fujishiro M, Masamune A, Kawai T (2021) Risk factors for bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection for gastric cancer in elderly patients older than 80 years in Japan. Clin Transl Gastroenterol 12(9):e00404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34644281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8659993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ctg.0000000000000404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kagawa Y, Fukuzawa M, Sugimoto M, Nemoto D, Muramatsu T, Shinohara H, Matsumoto T, Madarame A, Yamaguchi H, Uchida K, Morise T, Koyama Y, Sugimoto A, Yamauchi Y, Kono S, Naito S, Yamamoto K, Kishimoto Y, Inuyama M, Kawai T, Itoi T (2022) Validation of the BEST-J score, a prediction model for bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection for early gastric cancer: a multicenter retrospective observational study. Surg Endosc 36(10):7240&#x2013;7249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-022-09096-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wu S, Xing J, Li P, Zhang S, Sun X (2022) External validation of the BEST-J score and a new risk prediction model for ESD delayed bleeding in patients with early gastric cancer. BMC Gastroenterol 22(1):194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35443628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9022319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12876-022-02273-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo Silva V, Ferreira AI, Lima Capela T, Xavier S, Boal Carvalho P, Cotter J (2024) BEST-J score: validation of a predicting model for delayed bleeding after gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection on a European sample. Dig Dis Sci 69(4):1372&#x2013;1379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38353789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-024-08293-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong Y, Zhang YM, Zhu JQ, He S, Dou LZ, Liu Y, Ke Y, Liu XD, Liu YM, Wu HR, Lyu Y, Wang GQ (2021) [Analysis of risk factors for delayed bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection of gastric epithelial neoplasm]. Zhonghua zhong liu za zhi [Chinese Journal of Oncology] 43(8):861&#x2013;865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34407592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotoda T, Yamamoto H, Soetikno RM (2006) Endoscopic submucosal dissection of early gastric cancer. J Gastroenterol 41(10):929&#x2013;942</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17096062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00535-006-1954-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>(2016) [The Chinese expert recommendation on prevention of gastrointestinal injury related to antithrombotic therapy]. Zhonghua nei ke za zhi.55(7):564&#x2013;567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada S, Yabuuchi Y, Kawata N, Maeda Y, Yoshida M, Yamamoto Y, Minamide T, Shigeta K, Takada K, Kishida Y, Ito S, Imai K, Hotta K, Ishiwatari H, Matsubayashi H, Ono H (2023) Endoscopic causes and characteristics of missed gastric cancers after endoscopic submucosal dissection. Gastrointest Endosc 98(5):735-743.e732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36849058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2023.02.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagami Y, Hatta W, Tsuji Y, Yoshio T, Kakushima N, Hoteya S, Tsuji S, Fukunaga S, Hikichi T, Kobayashi M, Morita Y, Sumiyoshi T, Iguchi M, Tomida H, Inoue T, Mikami T, Hasatani K, Nishikawa J, Matsumura T, Nebiki H, Nakamatsu D, Ohnita K, Suzuki H, Ueyama H, Hayashi Y, Yoshida H, Fujishiro M, Masamune A, Fujiwara Y (2022) Antithrombotics increase bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection for gastric cancer: nationwide propensity score analysis. Digest Endosc 34(5):974&#x2013;983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/den.14151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kagawa T, Ishikawa S, Hidaka Y, Colvin HS, Nakanishi A, Ohkawa J, Negishi S, Yasutomi E, Yamauchi K, Okamoto K, Sakakihara I, Izumikawa K, Yamamoto K, Takahashi S, Tanaka S, Matsuura M, Wato M, Hasui T, Inaba T (2024) Risk factors for postgastric endoscopic submucosal dissection bleeding in direct oral anticoagulant users. Digest Endosc 36(10):1130&#x2013;1139</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi T, Ota K, Harada S, Edogawa S, Kojima Y, Tokioka S, Umegaki E, Higuchi K (2013) The postoperative bleeding rate and its risk factors in patients on antithrombotic therapy who undergo gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection. BMC Gastroenterol 13:136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24010587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3844538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-230X-13-136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So S, Ahn JY, Kim N, Na HK, Jung KW, Lee JH, Kim DH, Choi KD, Song HJ, Lee GH, Jung HY (2019) Comparison of the effects of antithrombotic therapy on delayed bleeding after gastric endoscopic resection: a propensity score-matched case-control study. Gastrointest Endosc 89(2):277-285.e272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30145315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2018.08.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomida H, Yoshio T, Igarashi K, Morita Y, Oda I, Inoue T, Hikichi T, Sumiyoshi T, Doyama H, Tsuji Y, Nishikawa J, Hatta W, Mikami T, Iguchi M, Sumiyama K, Yamamoto K, Kitamura K, Kuribayashi S, Yanagitani A, Uraoka T, Yada T, Hasatani K, Kawaguchi K, Fujita T, Nishida T, Hiasa Y, Fujishiro M (2021) Influence of anticoagulants on the risk of delayed bleeding after gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection: a multicenter retrospective study. Gastric Cancer 24(1):179&#x2013;189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32683602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10120-020-01105-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida N, Hayashi Y, Togo D, Oka S, Takada K, Fukunaga S, Morita Y, Hayashi T, Kozuka K, Tsuji Y, Murakami T, Yamamura T, Komeda Y, Takeuchi Y, Shinmura K, Fukuda H, Yoshii S, Ono S, Katsuki S, Kawashima K, Nemoto D, Yamamoto H, Saito Y, Tamai N, Iwao A, Itoi Y, Tsuji S, Inagaki Y, Inada Y, Soga K, Hasegawa D, Murakami T, Yoriki H, Fukumoto K, Motoyoshi T, Nakatani Y, Sano Y, Iguchi M, Fujii S, Ban H, Harada K, Okamoto K, Nishiyama H, Sasaki F, Mizukami K, Shono T, Shimoda R, Miike T, Yamaguchi N (2024) An analysis of delayed bleeding in cases of colorectal endoscopic submucosal dissection due to types of direct oral anticoagulants in Japan. Clinic Gastroenterol Hepatol 22(2):271-282.e273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2023.09.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada H, Suehiro S, Murakami D, Nakahara R, Nagasaka T, Ujihara T, Sagami R, Katsuyama Y, Hayasaka K, Amano Y (2019) Feasibility of gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection with continuous low-dose aspirin for patients receiving dual antiplatelet therapy. World J Gastroenterol 25(4):457&#x2013;468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6350173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v25.i4.457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J, Wei K, Deng J, Zhou X, Huang X, Deng M, L&#xfc; M (2017) Effects of antithrombotic therapy on bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection. Gastrointest Endosc 86(5):807&#x2013;816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28732709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2017.07.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata N, Yasunaga H, Matsui H, Fushimi K, Watanabe K, Akiyama J, Uemura N, Niikura R (2018) Therapeutic endoscopy-related GI bleeding and thromboembolic events in patients using warfarin or direct oral anticoagulants: results from a large nationwide database analysis. Gut 67(10):1805&#x2013;1812</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28874418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2017-313999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murata M, Sugimoto M, Ueshima S, Nagami Y, Ominami M, Sawaya M, Nakatani Y, Furumoto Y, Dohi O, Sumiyoshi T, Fukuzawa M, Tsuji S, Miyahara K, Takeuchi Y, Suzuki S, Tominaga N, Yagi N, Osawa S, Sakata Y, Yamada T, Yoshizawa Y, Yamauchi A, Yamamura T, Orihara S, Miyamoto S, Matsuda S, Hira D, Terada T, Katsura T, Gotoda T, Fujishiro M, Kawai T (2024) Association of direct oral anticoagulant and delayed bleeding with pharmacokinetics after endoscopic submucosal dissection. Gastrointest Endosc 99(5):721-731.e724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38042206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2023.11.048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow CWS, Fung TLD, Chan PT, Kwok KH (2023) Endoscopic submucosal dissection for colorectal polyps: outcome determining factors. Surg Endosc 37(2):1293&#x2013;1302</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-022-09672-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato K, Ito S, Kitagawa T, Kato M, Tominaga K, Suzuki T, Maetani I (2014) Factors affecting the technical difficulty and clinical outcome of endoscopic submucosal dissection for colorectal tumors. Surg Endosc 28(10):2959&#x2013;2965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24853849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-014-3558-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi Y, Iishi H, Tanaka S, Saito Y, Ikematsu H, Kudo SE, Sano Y, Hisabe T, Yahagi N, Saitoh Y, Igarashi M, Kobayashi K, Yamano H, Shimizu S, Tsuruta O, Inoue Y, Watanabe T, Nakamura H, Fujii T, Uedo N, Shimokawa T, Ishikawa H, Sugihara K (2014) Factors associated with technical difficulties and adverse events of colorectal endoscopic submucosal dissection: retrospective exploratory factor analysis of a multicenter prospective cohort. Int J Colorectal Dis 29(10):1275&#x2013;1284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24986141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00384-014-1947-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isomoto H, Nishiyama H, Yamaguchi N, Fukuda E, Ishii H, Ikeda K, Ohnita K, Nakao K, Kohno S, Shikuwa S (2009) Clinicopathological factors associated with clinical outcomes of endoscopic submucosal dissection for colorectal epithelial neoplasms. Endoscopy 41(8):679&#x2013;683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19670135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0029-1214979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi CW, Kim HW, Kang DH, Hong YM, Kim SJ, Park SB, Cho M, Kim DJ, Hong JB (2014) Clinical outcomes of second-look endoscopy after gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection: predictive factors with high risks of bleeding. Surg Endosc 28(7):2213&#x2013;2220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24570014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-014-3457-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto O, Fujishiro M, Kodashima S, Ono S, Niimi K, Hirano K, Yamamichi N, Koike K (2010) A second-look endoscopy after endoscopic submucosal dissection for gastric epithelial neoplasm may be unnecessary: a retrospective analysis of postendoscopic submucosal dissection bleeding. Gastrointest Endosc 71(2):241&#x2013;248</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2009.08.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong RC, Chak A, Kobayashi K, Isenberg GA, Cooper GS, Carr-Locke DL, Sivak MV Jr. (2000) Role of Doppler US in acute peptic ulcer hemorrhage: can it predict failure of endoscopic therapy? Gastrointest Endosc 52(3):315&#x2013;321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10968843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mge.2000.106688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takizawa K, Oda I, Gotoda T, Yokoi C, Matsuda T, Saito Y, Saito D, Ono H (2008) Routine coagulation of visible vessels may prevent delayed bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection--an analysis of risk factors. Endoscopy 40(3):179&#x2013;183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2007-995530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobara H, Tada N, Fujihara S, Nishiyama N, Masaki T (2023) Clinical and technical outcomes of endoscopic closure of postendoscopic submucosal dissection defects: literature review over one decade. Dig Endosc 35(2):216&#x2013;231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35778927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/den.14397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukai S, Cho S, Nakamura S, Hatano Y, Kotachi T, Shimizu A, Matsuura G, Azakami T, Takaba A, Hamada T, Hirata K, Nakanishi T (2013) Postprocedural combined treatment using the coagulation plus artery-selective clipping (2C) method for the prevention of delayed bleeding after ESD. Surg Endosc 27(4):1292&#x2013;1301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23232998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-012-2600-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azumi M, Takeuchi M, Koseki Y, Kumagai M, Kobayashi Y, Takatsuna M, Yoshioka A, Yoshikawa S, Miura T, Terai S (2019) The search, coagulation, and clipping (SCC) method prevents delayed bleeding after gastric endoscopic submucosal dissection. Gastric Cancer 22(3):567&#x2013;575</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30267178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10120-018-0878-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang QS, Han B, Xu JH, Gao P, Shen YC (2015) Clip closure of defect after endoscopic resection in patients with larger colorectal tumors decreased the adverse events. Gastrointest Endosc 82(5):904&#x2013;909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25975527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2015.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung IK, Lee JH, Lee SH, Kim SJ, Cho JY, Cho WY, Hwangbo Y, Keum BR, Park JJ, Chun HJ, Kim HJ, Kim JJ, Ji SR, Seol SY (2009) Therapeutic outcomes in 1000 cases of endoscopic submucosal dissection for early gastric neoplasms: Korean ESD Study Group multicenter study. Gastrointest Endosc 69(7):1228&#x2013;1235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19249769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2008.09.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmunzer BJ, Young SD, Inadomi JM, Schoenfeld P, Laine L (2008) Systematic review of the predictors of recurrent hemorrhage after endoscopic hemostatic therapy for bleeding peptic ulcers. Am J of Gastroenterol 103(10):2625&#x2013;2632</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1572-0241.2008.02070.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brullet E, Campo R, Calvet X, Coroleu D, Rivero E, Sim&#xf3; Deu J (1996) Factors related to the failure of endoscopic injection therapy for bleeding gastric ulcer. Gut 39(2):155&#x2013;158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8977333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1383290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gut.39.2.155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumura T, Arai M, Maruoka D, Okimoto K, Minemura S, Ishigami H, Saito K, Nakagawa T, Katsuno T, Yokosuka O (2014) Risk factors for early and delayed post-operative bleeding after endoscopic submucosal dissection of gastric neoplasms, including patients with continued use of antithrombotic agents. BMC Gastroenterol 14:172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25280756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4287424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-230X-14-172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato M, Uedo N, Hokimoto S, Ieko M, Higuchi K, Murakami K, Fujimoto K (2018) Guidelines for gastroenterological endoscopy in patients undergoing antithrombotic treatment: 2017 appendix&#xa0;on anticoagulants including direct oral anticoagulants. Dig Endosc 30(4):433&#x2013;440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29733468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/den.13184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>