<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41793711</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2472-5846</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>IISE transactions on occupational ergonomics and human factors</Title><ISOAbbreviation>IISE Trans Occup Ergon Hum Factors</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predicting Behavioral Reliance on AI-Based Depression Treatment Recommendations Among Engineering Graduate Students: A Pilot Study Using EEG Signals.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>11</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-11</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/24725838.2026.2638568</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>OCCUPATIONAL APPLICATIONSThis pilot study demonstrates the feasibility of using EEG-derived features to characterize behavioral reliance among engineering graduate students interacting with AI-labeled recommendations. Engineering professionals frequently engage with AI-supported decision systems in safety-critical and cognitively demanding contexts. In such occupational environments, inappropriate reliance, either over-reliance or unwarranted rejection, may compromise performance, safety, and decision quality. Although predictive performance was modest, the use of conservative participant-wise validation underscores the importance of rigorous evaluation when developing neurophysiological models for occupational human-AI interaction. These findings support EEG as a complementary tool for studying reliance behavior in professional settings while highlighting the need for multimodal and context-sensitive approaches in real-world engineering applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahsavar</LastName><ForeName>Yeganeh</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3422-7257</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Armstrong Institute Center for Health Care Human Factors, Johns Hopkins Medicine, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choudhury</LastName><ForeName>Avishek</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5342-0709</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Industrial and Management Systems Engineering, Benjamin M. Statler College of Engineering and Mineral Resources, West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>IISE Trans Occup Ergon Hum Factors</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101738444</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2472-5838</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText><b>Objectives:</b> This study investigated whether EEG signals could predict behavioral reliance of engineering graduate students on AI-labeled treatment recommendations during depression-related decision-making, using conservative participant-wise machine-learning evaluation.<b>Methods:</b> Thirteen participants completed ten depression treatment scenarios in a task-based Qualtrics experiment. Each scenario presented three treatment options; one labeled as the AI recommendation. The AI-labeled option was clinically appropriate in five scenarios and inappropriate in another five scenarios. Behavioral reliance was operationalized as selection <i>versus</i> non-selection of the AI-labeled option. EEG signals were recorded from frontal electrodes (F3, Fz, F4, FC1, FC2). Beta-band (13&#x2013;30&#x2009;Hz) power features were extracted from 5-s EEG segments ending 1&#x2009;s before decision. Random Forest (RF) and Extreme Gradient Boosting (XGB) classifiers were evaluated using a leave-one-participant-out (LOPO) framework, with nested 5-fold cross-validation applied within training folds for hyperparameter tuning.<b>Results:</b> Frontal beta activity was significantly higher during task engagement compared to resting baseline, reflecting increased cognitive effort during decision-making; however, no significant differences were observed across individual scenarios. Under participant-wise LOPO evaluation, machine-learning models demonstrated modest, above-chance discrimination of behavioral reliance. XGB achieved AUROC of 0.636, with wide variability across held-out participants.<b>Conclusion:</b> Short EEG segments contained limited but detectable information related to behavioral reliance on AI-labeled recommendations. However, modest performance and strong inter-individual variability indicate that EEG alone is insufficient for robust reliance prediction. These findings underscore the importance of conservative validation strategies and a clear distinction between behavioral reliance and subjective trust in human&#x2013;AI interaction research.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behavioral reliance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EEG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human&#x2013;AI interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health decision support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trust in AI</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41793711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24725838.2026.2638568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>