<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41715937</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-6924</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Risk analysis : an official publication of the Society for Risk Analysis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Risk Anal</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Failure Event Mining With Fine-Tuned Large Language Model: Case Study of Analyzing United States Nuclear Power Plant Failure Event Reports.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70191</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70191</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/risa.70191</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Failure event narratives contain detailed and valuable information describing how failures initiate and propagate. Event causality analysis can help improve the understanding of failure physics and facilitate the use of non-failure data (e.g., near-misses and degradations) to complement the limited data pool of failures, which is common in high-reliability industries such as the nuclear power industry. Automatically extracting event causality from text data, however, is challenging given complex and diverse language structures and causal patterns, and the lack of access to large, annotated datasets for use as training data. Existing automated mining approaches are mainly knowledge-based and extract causality using a set of predefined keywords and rules, which have difficulty achieving good performance. In this paper, we propose a novel large language model (LLM)-based approach for automated causality extraction. It leveraged the strong capability of LLM to understand intricate language patterns in long-range contexts and accurately extract cause-and-effect pairs from texts. The proposed approach has a twofold framework: causality detection and causality extraction. The causality detection step trained a deep learning model to identify texts with causality. The causality extraction step developed a T5-CE LLM to identify and extract cause-and-effect pairs in each text sample. A large, annotated dataset of the U.S. nuclear power plant failure event reports was used to train and evaluate the models. The model evaluation was performed using three performance metrics, including precision, recall, and F<sub>1</sub> score. The proposed approach can effectively detect implicit and embedded causalities across multiple sentences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Society for Risk Analysis.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Sai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regulatory Research &amp; Plant Optimization Division, Idaho National Laboratory, Idaho Falls, Idaho, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sohag</LastName><ForeName>Shahidur Rahoman</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, College of Engineering, University of Idaho, Idaho Falls, Idaho, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xian</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6098-4441</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, College of Engineering, University of Idaho, Idaho Falls, Idaho, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Shoukun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, College of Engineering, University of Idaho, Idaho Falls, Idaho, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Zhegang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regulatory Research &amp; Plant Optimization Division, Idaho National Laboratory, Idaho Falls, Idaho, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>31310019N0006</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Risk Anal</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8109978</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0272-4332</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">causality extraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">failure event narrative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">large language model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nuclear power plant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">text mining</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41715937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/risa.70191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdali, S., A. Parikh, S. Lim, and E. Kiciman. 2023. &#x201c;Extracting Self&#x2010;Consistent Causal Insights From Users Feedback With LLMs and In&#x2010;Context Learning.&#x201d; Proceedings Of, 1. https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.06820v1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarap, A. 2018. &#x201c;Deep Learning Using Rectified Linear Units (Relu).&#x201d; Arxiv.Org 1&#x2013;7. https://arxiv.org/abs/1803.08375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam, M. T., D. Bhusal, Y. Park, and N. Rastogi. 2022. &#x201c;Cyner: A Python Library for Cybersecurity Named Entity Recognition.&#x201d; ArXiv:2204.05754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, W., W. Zuo, W. Ying, R. Ali, G. Rahman, and I. Ullah. 2023. &#x201c;Causality Extraction: A Comprehensive Survey and New Perspective.&#x201d; Journal of King Saud University&#x2010;Computer and Information Sciences 101593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athe, P., and N. Dinh. 2023. &#x201c;Testing Generative Pre&#x2010;Trained Transformer for Knowledge Abstraction and Reasoning for Nuclear Reactor Design and Safety Applications.&#x201d; Probabilistic Safety Assessment and Management (PSAM) Topical. https://hdl.handle.net/2142/121795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, L., K. Pazdernik, D. Fortin, B. Wilson, R. Goychayev, and J. Mattingly. 2021. &#x201c;NukeLM: Pre&#x2010;Trained and Fine&#x2010;Tuned Language Models for the Nuclear and Energy Domains.&#x201d; ArXiv:2105.12192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo and Klein. 2024. &#x201c;Classification Modeling of Nuclear Power Plant Outage Severities.&#x201d; Proceedings of the 2024 American Nuclear Society Annual Meeting. https://www.ans.org/pubs/transactions/article&#x2010;55984/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier, Z. A., R. J. Gruss, and A. S. Abrahams. 2024. &#x201c;How Good Are Large Language Models at Product Risk Assessment?&#x201d; Risk Analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes, C., and V. Vapnik. 1995. &#x201c;Support&#x2010;Vector Networks.&#x201d; Machine Learning 20, no. 3: 273&#x2013;297. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00994018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eide, S. A., T. E. Wierman, C. D. Gentillon, D. M. Rasmuson, and C. L. Atwood. 2007. &#x201c;Industry&#x2010;Average Performance for Components and Initiating Events at US Commercial Nuclear Power Plants.&#x201d; Citeseer. https://www.nrc.gov/reading&#x2010;rm/doc&#x2010;collections/nuregs/contract/cr6928/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y., Y. Goktas, D. D. Yellamati, and C. De Tassigny. 2024. &#x201c;The Use and Misuse of Pre&#x2010;Trained Generative Large Language Models in Reliability Engineering.&#x201d; 2024 Annual Reliability and Maintainability Symposium (RAMS) 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Z., W. Xu, and K. Yu. 2015. &#x201c;Bidirectional LSTM&#x2010;CRF Models for Sequence Tagging.&#x201d; ArXiv:1508.01991. https://arxiv.org/abs/1508.01991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioffe, S., and C. Szegedy. 2015. &#x201c;Batch Normalization: Accelerating Deep Network Training by Reducing Internal Covariate Shift.&#x201d; International Conference on Machine Learning 1&#x2013;9. http://proceedings.mlr.press/v37/ioffe15.html..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfc;ttner, V., M. Grimmer, and E. Buchmann. 2024. &#x201c;ChatIDS: Advancing Explainable Cybersecurity Using Generative AI.&#x201d; International Journal on Advances in Security 17, no. 1: 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x131;c&#x131;man, E., R. Ness, A. Sharma, and C. Tan. 2023. &#x201c;Causal Reasoning and Large Language Models: Opening a New Frontier for Causality.&#x201d; https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.00050v2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, Y., X. Xu, D. McDuff, C. Breazeal, and H. W. Park. 2024. &#x201c;Health&#x2010;LLM: Large Language Models for Health Prediction via Wearable Sensor Data.&#x201d; ArXiv:2401.06866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma, D. P., and J. L. Ba. 2015. &#x201c;Adam: A Method for Stochastic Optimization.&#x201d; 3rd International Conference on Learning Representations, ICLR 2015, Conference Track Proceedings.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaValley, M. P. 2008. &#x201c;Logistic Regression.&#x201d; Circulation 117, no. 18: 2395&#x2013;2399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y.&#x2010;F., H. Wang, and M. Sun. 2023. &#x201c;ChatGPT&#x2010;Like Large&#x2010;Scale Foundation Models for Prognostics and Health Management: A Survey and Roadmaps.&#x201d; Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety 109850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, S., T. Schuster, and A. Pich&#xe9;. 2023. Can Large Language Models Build Causal Graphs? https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.05279v2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Z., and K. J. Kvarfordt. 2019. Causal CCF Parameter Estimations 2020. https://www.inl.gov.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Z., and K. J. Kvarfordt. 2021. CCF Parameter Estimations, 2020 Update. https://doi.org/10.2172/1846976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Z., T. E. Wierman, and K. J. Kvarfordt. 2021. Industry&#x2010;Average Performance for Components and Initiating Events at U.S. Commercial Nuclear Power Plants: 2020 Update. https://doi.org/10.2172/1847110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martelo, R., and R.&#x2010;Q. Wang. 2024. &#x201c;Towards Democratized Flood Risk Management: An Advanced AI Assistant Enabled by GPT&#x2010;4 for Enhanced Interpretability and Public Engagement.&#x201d; ArXiv:2403.03188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, Z., Y. Luan, J. Chen, and T. Li. 2024. &#x201c;ParInfoGPT: An LLM&#x2010;Based Two&#x2010;Stage Framework for Reliability Assessment of Rotating Machine Under Partial Information.&#x201d; Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety 250: 110312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffel, C., N. Shazeer, A. Roberts, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;Exploring the Limits of Transfer Learning With a Unified Text&#x2010;to&#x2010;Text Transformer.&#x201d; Journal of Machine Learning Research 21, no. 140: 1&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimers, N., and I. Gurevych. 2019. &#x201c;Sentence&#x2010;Bert: Sentence Embeddings Using Siamese Bert&#x2010;Networks.&#x201d; ArXiv:1908.10084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rychkov, V., C. Picoco, and E. Caleca. 2024. &#x201c;Impact of Generative AI (Large Language Models) on the PRA Model Construction and Maintenance, Observations.&#x201d; ArXiv:2406.01133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silberg, J., K. Swanson, E. Simon, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;UniTox: Leveraging LLMs to Curate a Unified Dataset of Drug&#x2010;Induced Toxicity From FDA Labels.&#x201d; MedRxiv 2024&#x2013;2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohag, S. R., S. Zhang, M. Xian, F. Xu, and Z. Ma. 2024. &#x201c;Causality Extraction in Nuclear Licensee Event Reports Using a Hybrid Framework.&#x201d; Proceedings of the 2024 ANS Annual Conference, 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava, N., G. Hinton, A. Krizhevsky, and R. Salakhutdinov. 2014. &#x201c;Dropout: A Simple Way to Prevent Neural Networks From Overfitting.&#x201d; Journal of Machine Learning Research 15: 1929&#x2013;1958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf8;dle, K., R. Flage, S. Guikema, and T. Aven. 2024. &#x201c;Artificial Intelligence for Risk Analysis: A Risk Characterization Perspective on Advances, Opportunities, and Limitations.&#x201d; Risk Analysis. https://doi.org/10.1111/risa.14307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szab&#xf3;, Z., and V. Bilicki. 2023. &#x201c;A New Approach to Web Application Security: Utilizing Gpt Language Models for Source Code Inspection.&#x201d; Future Internet 15, no. 10: 326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira, A. C., V. Marar, H. Yazdanpanah, A. Pezente, and M. Ghassemi. 2023. &#x201c;Enhancing Credit Risk Reports Generation Using LLMs: An Integration of Bayesian Networks and Labeled Guide Prompting.&#x201d; Proceedings of the Fourth ACM International Conference on AI in Finance, 340&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tewari, A. 2024. &#x201c;LegalPro&#x2010;BERT: Classification of Legal Provisions by Fine&#x2010;Tuning BERT Large Language Model.&#x201d; ArXiv:2404.10097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission. 2024. Search Licensee Event Reports. https://lersearch.inl.gov/LERSearchCriteria.aspx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani, A., N. Shazeer, N. Parmar, et&#xa0;al. 2017. &#x201c;Attention Is All You Need.&#x201d; Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C., D. Mandelli, and J. Cogliati. 2024. &#x201c;Technical Language Processing of Nuclear Power Plants Equipment Reliability Data.&#x201d; Energies 17, no. 7: 1785. https://doi.org/10.3390/EN17071785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L., H. Jiang, P. Cai, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;AccidentGPT: Accident Analysis and Prevention From V2X Environmental Perception With Multi&#x2010;Modal Large Model.&#x201d; ArXiv:2312.13156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willig, M., M. Z. Ze&#x10d;evi&#xb4;c, D. S. Dhami, and K. Kersting. 2022. Can Foundation Models Talk Causality? https://arxiv.org/abs/2206.10591v2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, S., C. Zheng, X. Su, and Y. Tang. 2024. &#x201c;Construction Contract Risk Identification Based on Knowledge&#x2010;Augmented Language Models.&#x201d; Computers in Industry 157: 104082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xian, M., T. Wang, S. Zhang, F. Xu, and Z. Ma. 2024. &#x201c;A Knowledge&#x2010;Informed Large Language Model Framework for U.S.&#x201d; Nuclear Power Plant Shutdown Initiating Event Classification for Probabilistic Risk Assessment. https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.00929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J., S. C. Han, and J. Poon. 2022. &#x201c;A Survey on Extraction of Causal Relations From Natural Language Text.&#x201d; Knowledge and Information Systems 64, no. 5: 1161&#x2013;1186. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10115&#x2010;022&#x2010;01665&#x2010;w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, G., X. Wang, Q. Li, and Y. Zhao. 2024. &#x201c;Fusing LLMs and KGs for Formal Causal Reasoning Behind Financial Risk Contagion.&#x201d; ArXiv:2407.17190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C., S. Bauer, P. Bennett, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;Understanding Causality With Large Language Models: Feasibility and Opportunities.&#x201d; https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.05524v1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. 2004. &#x201c;The Optimality of Na&#xef;ve Bayes.&#x201d; Aa 1, no. 2: 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, S., T. Liu, S. Zhao, Y. Chen, and J. Y. Nie. 2016. &#x201c;Event Causality Extraction Based on Connectives Analysis.&#x201d; Neurocomputing 173: 1943&#x2013;1950. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.NEUCOM.2015.09.066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y., X. Diao, J. Huang, and C. Smidts. 2019. &#x201c;Automated Identification of Causal Relationships in Nuclear Power Plant Event Reports.&#x201d; Nuclear Technology 205, no. 8: 1021&#x2013;1034. https://doi.org/10.1080/00295450.2019.1580967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, S., K. Pan, J. Liu, and Y. Chen. 2024. &#x201c;Empirical Study on Fine&#x2010;Tuning Pre&#x2010;Trained Large Language Models for Fault Diagnosis of Complex Systems.&#x201d; Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety 252: 110382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, X., H. Jin, J. Li, and Y. Wang. 2024. Topic&#x2010;Gpt: A Novel Risk Identification Method Based on Large Language Model. SSRN 4885365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, F., S. Hu, W. Yu, Z. Yan, and S. Chan. 2024. &#x201c;Research on Financial Fraud Text Classification Based on PET&#x2010;BiLSTM.&#x201d; Proceedings of the 2024 3rd International Conference on Cyber Security, Artificial Intelligence and Digital Economy, 341&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>