<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41843961</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-2653</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>148</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neuroscience : official journal of the Neurosurgical Society of Australasia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development and validation of stability prediction models for intracranial aneurysms based on ensemble learning algorithms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>111974</StartPage><MedlinePgn>111974</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jocn.2026.111974</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0967-5868(26)00125-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to develop and validate ensemble learning models based on pre-rupture or pre-growth images andmultiple features to predict stability of intracranial aneurysm (IA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Retrospectively collected aneurysms diagnosed through computed tomography angiography (CTA), magnetic resonance angiography (MRA) or digital subtraction angiography (DSA) from 7 hospitals. Internal dataset consists of data from Beijing Tiantan Hospital, and independent external validation set consists of data from the other 6 hospitals. We collected clinical information from medical records. Morphological and radiomics features were extracted from medical images. Each patient had at least one imaging follow-up. Predictive features are based on pre-rupture or pre-growth images. Univariate analysis, multivariate analysis and recursive feature elimination (RFE) algorithm were performed to select key features. We utilized ensemble learning algorithm to train models. Radiomics model, conventional model (based on clinical and morphological features) and combined model (based on radiomics, clinical and morphological features) were established and evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">646 patients with 840 aneurysms were included from Beijing Tiantan Hospital as internal dataset, 206 patients with 271 aneurysms were included from the other 6 hospitals as independent external validation set. 15 radiomics features, 6 morphological features, and 2 clinical features were selected to build models. The radiomics model, conventional model and combined model obtained an AUC of 0.85(0.77-0.94), 0.61(0.48-0.74) and 0.78(0.67-0.89) in external validation set, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Radiomics features can be used to predict the stability of unruptured intracranial aneurysm (UIA). The combination of radiomics features and conventional features did not show the power to improve the predictive capability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Jiliang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: jiliang511@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Huibin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Southern Medical University Nanfang Hospital, 1838 North Guangzhou Avenue, Guangzhou CN 510515, PR China. Electronic address: kanghuibindoctor@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turhon</LastName><ForeName>Mirzat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: 18699158800@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Mengxing</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: eureka_archimedes@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoxu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: zhaoxuzheng1998@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Fujunhui</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: zfjh0720@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: jianliu_ns@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yisen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: zhang-yisen@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute, Capital Medical University, Department of Interventional Neuroradiology, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China; Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University, Neurosurgery Center, Department of Neurosurgery, No. 119 South Fourth Ring West Road, Fengtai District, Beijing CN 100070, PR China. Electronic address: yingzhang829@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D023361">Validation Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Scotland</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9433352</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0967-5868</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002532" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intracranial Aneurysm</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015901" MajorTopicYN="N">Angiography, Digital Subtraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072226" MajorTopicYN="N">Computed Tomography Angiography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018810" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Angiography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000098406" MajorTopicYN="N">Ensemble Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ensemble learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intracranial aneurysm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radiomics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no competing financial interests or personal relationships that could influence the work reported in this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41843961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2026.111974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0967-5868(26)00125-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>