<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41512127</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1875-9270</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Work (Reading, Mass.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Work</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strain on the streets: A cross-sectional study on the prevalence and risk factors of musculoskeletal disorders Among 50 urban street sweepers in the Philippines.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10519815251410885</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10519815251410885</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/10519815251410885</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BackgroundMusculoskeletal disorders (MSDs) are a significant occupational health issue for street sweepers due to the physically demanding nature of their tasks and prolonged exposure to ergonomic and psychosocial risks. These risks result in discomfort and reduced productivity, especially in labor-intensive jobs in developing countries.ObjectivesThis study assessed the prevalence of MSDs among street sweepers in the Philippines, identified contributing ergonomic and psychosocial factors, and proposed interventions to enhance their health and well-being.MethodsA cross-sectional design was used with 50 street sweepers. Data collection tools included the Nordic Musculoskeletal Questionnaire (NMQ) for MSD prevalence, the Rapid Entire Body Assessment (REBA) for ergonomic risks, and the Copenhagen Psychosocial Questionnaire (COPSOQ) for psychosocial risks. Statistical analyses, including chi-square tests and logistic regression, examined variable associations.ResultsLogistic regression analysis revealed that ergonomic and psychosocial risks were significantly associated with musculoskeletal disorder (MSD) prevalence. Medium ergonomic risk (REBA) increased the odds of MSDs by 12.18 times (95% CI: 3.76-39.49, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), while low ergonomic risk still showed elevated odds at 6.05 (95% CI: 2.27-16.12, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Low psychosocial risk (COPSOQ) was also associated with a 7.39-fold increase in MSD odds (95% CI: 2.77-19.67, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), while moderate psychosocial risk reduced the odds (OR = 0.45, 95% CI: 0.21-0.98, p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04). Female gender and overweight status were also significant predictors. The study's sample size (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;50) may have limited statistical power; larger, more diverse samples are needed to clarify these relationships and improve generalizability.ConclusionFindings highlight the need for interventions, including ergonomic tools, task rotation, flexible schedules, and social support programs. Regular training and health assessments are essential to mitigate risks. A holistic approach to occupational health is crucial for improving the well-being and productivity of street sweepers. Future studies should explore intervention effectiveness and broader comparative analyses.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gumasing</LastName><ForeName>Ma Janice J</ForeName><Initials>MJJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Industrial and Systems Engineering, Gokongwei College of Engineering, De La Salle University, Manila, Philipines.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Work</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9204382</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1051-9815</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ergonomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occupational injury prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">repetitive strain injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">safety and health</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41512127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10519815251410885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>