<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41566328</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2415</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC ophthalmology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development and internal validation of a prescriptive multi-task learning model for horizontal strabismus surgery planning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37</StartPage><MedlinePgn>37</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12886-026-04628-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND &amp; AIM">Horizontal strabismus affects&#x2009;&#x2248;&#x2009;1.9% of the global population. Traditional &#x201c;1&#xa0;mm&#x2009;&#x2248;&#x2009;2 &#x394;&#x201d; nomograms disregard patient heterogeneity, leaving re-operation rates at 7&#x2013;8% even after primary horizontal surgery. We aimed to develop a single prescriptive model that simultaneously predicts which horizontal extra-ocular muscles require surgery and the precise recession/resection dose for each, following the TRIPOD&#x2009;+&#x2009;AI reporting checklist.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this retrospective single-centre study, 634 consecutive patients (2019&#x2013;2024) undergoing primary horizontal-muscle surgery were analysed. Fourteen routinely recorded pre-operative variables&#x2014;including age, prism-cover deviation, axial-length metrics, refractive error and visual acuity&#x2014;fed a fully connected multi-task neural network with a shared trunk and two heads: (i) 8-label classification for muscle-procedure selection and (ii) 8-output regression for surgical dose. Model development exceeded recommended sample-size heuristics for an expected AUC&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.90 and was internally validated with multilabel-stratified 10-fold cross-validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The model achieved excellent discrimination for muscle selection (macro-AUC 0.97&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.01; macro-MCC 0.83) with near-perfect calibration (ECE 0.008). Dose predictions were highly accurate (MAE 0.42&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.04&#xa0;mm; RMSE 0.54&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.07&#xa0;mm; R&#xb2; 0.86&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.04); 95% of estimates lay within &#xb1;&#x2009;0.30&#xa0;mm of the surgeon&#x2019;s plan. Exact match of the entire surgical plan reached 55%, far surpassing the majority baseline of 17%. These figures markedly outperform earlier regression-only approaches that reported MAE 0.5&#x2013;0.8&#xa0;mm and indication-level AUC 0.82.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">A transparent multi-task learning model can replicate expert, patient-specific surgical plans for horizontal strabismus with sub-millimetre precision. The tool could standardise planning and reduce inter-surgeon variability; multi-centre external validation remains essential.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12886-026-04628-9.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jieyue</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Center of Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, 87 Xiangya Road, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Key Laboratory of Ophthalmology, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Disorders, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7913-118X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Center of Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, 87 Xiangya Road, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China. hewuan@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Key Laboratory of Ophthalmology, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China. hewuan@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Disorders, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China. hewuan@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ou</LastName><ForeName>Sheng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Center of Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, 87 Xiangya Road, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Key Laboratory of Ophthalmology, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Disorders, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Ophthalmol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967802</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2415</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="eng"><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Strengths of this study Limitations of this study First integrated prescriptive model that jointly predicts which horizontal extra-ocular muscles to operate and their recession/resection dose, outperforming earlier regression-only SVM and decision-tree approaches (0.97 macro-AUC vs. 0.82; 0.42&#xa0;mm MAE vs. 0.5&#x2013;0.8&#xa0;mm). Robust, adequately powered dataset of 634 consecutive cases; exceeds published sample-size guidance for developing an AUC&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.90 model and maintains a favourable events-per-parameter ratio. Methodological rigour: multilabel-stratified 10-fold cross-validation, bootstrap CIs, and probability calibration executed in line with TRIPOD&#x2009;+&#x2009;AI reporting standards, enhancing transparency and reproducibility. Ground-truth surgical plans were associated with uniformly positive outcomes, ensuring that the model learned from high-quality examples. High clinical fidelity: 55% exact plan match and 95% of dose errors&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.30&#xa0;mm&#x2014;well below the 0.5&#xa0;mm threshold deemed clinically perceptible&#x2014;suggest potential to standardise surgical planning. Single-centre, retrospective design may encode local practice patterns; optimism bias is possible without external validation in diverse settings. Class imbalance effects: rare procedures (e.g., left lateral-rectus resection) have fewer training examples and slightly lower accuracy despite stratified sampling.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12886-026-04628-9.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical decision support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Personalised surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prescriptive model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strabismus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study protocol was approved by the Institutional Review Board of Xiangya Hospital, Central South University (Approval No. 2025040585; 14 April 2025). The requirement for written informed consent was waived because this retrospective analysis used fully de-identified data and involved no direct patient contact. Patient and public involvement: Patients or members of the public were not involved in the design, conduct, reporting, or dissemination plans of this research. Transparency statement: The lead author (Xiaoying Wu) affirms that this manuscript is an honest, accurate, and transparent account of the study being reported; no important aspects have been omitted, and any discrepancies from the study as originally planned have been explained. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41566328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12828921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12886-026-04628-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12886-026-04628-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hashemi H, Pakzad R, Heydarian S, et al. Global and regional prevalence of strabismus: a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis. Strabismus. 2019;27:54&#x2013;65. 10.1080/09273972.2019.1604773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09273972.2019.1604773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31012389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagi LR, Velez FG, Archer SM, et al. Adult strabismus preferred practice Pattern<sup>&#xae;</sup>. Ophthalmology. 2020;127:P182&#x2013;298. 10.1016/j.ophtha.2019.09.023.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ophtha.2019.09.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31757496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paduca A, Arnaut O, Bendelic E, et al. Extraocular muscle resection, recession length and surgery outcome modelling in strabismus treatment: a pilot study. BMJ Open Ophthalmol. 2021;6:e000802. 10.1136/bmjophth-2021-000802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjophth-2021-000802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8573654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34796269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen M, Pierson K, Leffler C. Reoperation following strabismus surgery among medicare beneficiaries: associations with geographic region, academic affiliation, surgeon volume, and adjustable suture technique. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2018;66:1149. 10.4103/ijo.IJO_18_18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijo.IJO_18_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6080478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30038162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida JDSD, Silva AC, Teixeira JAM, et al. Surgical planning for horizontal strabismus using support vector regression. Comput Biol Med. 2015;63:178&#x2013;86. 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2015.05.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2015.05.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26093785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite FHF, Almeida JDSD, Cruz LBD, et al. Surgical planning of horizontal strabismus using multiple output regression tree. Comput Biol Med. 2021;134:104493. 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34119920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Moons KGM, Dhiman P, et al. TRIPOD&#x2009;+&#x2009;AI statement: updated guidance for reporting clinical prediction models that use regression or machine learning methods. BMJ. 2024;e078378. 10.1136/bmj-2023-078378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11019967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38626948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elm EV, Altman DG, Egger M, et al. Strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. BMJ. 2007;335:806&#x2013;8. 10.1136/bmj.39335.541782.AD.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.39335.541782.AD</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2034723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17947786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chougule P, Kekunnaya R. Surgical management of intermittent exotropia: do we have an answer for all? BMJ Open Ophthalmol. 2019;4:e000243. 10.1136/bmjophth-2018-000243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjophth-2018-000243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6440598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30997406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley RD, Ensor J, Snell KIE et al. Calculating the sample size required for developing a clinical prediction model. BMJ. 2020;m441. 10.1136/bmj.m441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, White IR, Carlin JB, et al. Multiple imputation for missing data in epidemiological and clinical research: potential and pitfalls. BMJ. 2009;338:b2393&#x2013;2393. 10.1136/bmj.b2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.b2393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19564179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthimiou O, Seo M, Chalkou K et al. Developing clinical prediction models: a step-by-step guide. BMJ. 2024;e078276. 10.1136/bmj-2023-078276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11369751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39227063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Dhiman P, Ma J, et al. Evaluation of clinical prediction models (part 1): from development to external validation. BMJ. 2024;e074819. 10.1136/bmj-2023-074819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10772854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38191193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamoto K, Houlihan CA, Balas EA, et al. Improving clinical practice using clinical decision support systems: a systematic review of trials to identify features critical to success. BMJ. 2005;330:765. 10.1136/bmj.38398.500764.8F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.38398.500764.8F</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC555881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15767266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;orbac&#x131;o&#x11f;lu &#x15e;K, Aksel G. Receiver operating characteristic curve analysis in diagnostic accuracy studies: A guide to interpreting the area under the curve value. Turk J Emerg Med. 2023;23:195&#x2013;8. 10.4103/tjem.tjem_182_23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/tjem.tjem_182_23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10664195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38024184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Li W, Macheret F, et al. A tutorial on calibration measurements and calibration models for clinical prediction models. J Am Med Inf Assoc. 2020;27:621&#x2013;33. 10.1093/jamia/ocz228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocz228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7075534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32106284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers AJ, Van Calster B, Steyerberg EW. Net benefit approaches to the evaluation of prediction models, molecular markers, and diagnostic tests. BMJ. 2016;i6. 10.1136/bmj.i6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4724785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26810254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM, Erion G, Chen H, et al. From local explanations to global Understanding with explainable AI for trees. Nat Mach Intell. 2020;2:56&#x2013;67. 10.1038/s42256-019-0138-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42256-019-0138-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32607472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Reitsma JB, Altman DG, et al. Transparent reporting of a multivariable prediction model for individual prognosis or diagnosis (TRIPOD): the TRIPOD statement. BMJ. 2015;350:g7594&#x2013;7594. 10.1136/bmj.g7594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g7594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25569120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidey-Gibbons JAM, Sidey-Gibbons CJ. Machine learning in medicine: a practical introduction. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2019;19:64. 10.1186/s12874-019-0681-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-019-0681-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6425557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30890124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyer C. Doctor is charged with four counts of sexual assault. BMJ. 2019;l5575. 10.1136/bmj.l5575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31527145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>