<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41632791</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An intelligent control algorithm for gas precise drainage problem based on Model Predictive Control.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0332836</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0332836</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0332836</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0332836</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Intelligent extraction of coal seam gas constitutes a crucial development direction for managing underground gas disasters. Building on an established mathematical model, this study develops an intelligent control model for gas extraction. In this model, controlled variables include gas extraction concentration, gas extraction flow rate, negative pressure, and extraction pump efficiency ratio, while control variables are defined as the valve opening of extraction boreholes and the power of extraction pumps. The ideal curve of the controlled quantity with time is obtained by using the recurrent neural network (SimpleRNN), and the controlled quantity is intelligently controlled by the model predictive control (MPC) algorithm so that the actual value of controlled quantity approaches the reference value at the corresponding time of its ideal curve. Taking the simulated gas extraction data as an example, an algorithm simulation experiment is performed. The experimental results show that the ideal reference curve of the controlled quantity obtained by the cyclic neural network has a good data fitting degree. The dynamic control of the controlled quantity by the model predictive control algorithm can overcome the interference of environmental and nonlinear factors and achieve a better control effect, which provides a certain reference for the intelligent control of gas drainage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Han, Wang. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Liyun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-6442-0311</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Economics and Management, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of International Education, Xi'an Peihua University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yanli</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Economics and Management, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005740">Gases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003031">Coal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Theoretical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005740" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003031" MajorTopicYN="N">Coal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41632791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12867243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0332836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-48351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yuan L. Scientific problem and countermeasure for precision mining of coal and associated resources. J China Coal Soc. 2019;44(01):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Lin B, Fu X, Zhu C. Modeling air leakage around gas extraction boreholes in mining-disturbed coal seams. Process Safe Environ Protect. 2020;141:202&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2020.05.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2020.05.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Liu Y, Shen K, Ba Q. Influence factors analysis of coal seam drainage effect and its technical countermeasures. Safe Coal Mines. 2019;50(01):179&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Tao Y, Liu D. Study on pressure released scope of hydraulic flushing and gas drainage law. Coal Sc Technol. 2017;45(10):96&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z. Research on gas extraction radius law based on FLUENT. China Energy Environ Protect. 2018;40(2):3437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassie SA, Cloete S, Zaabout A, Gallucci F, van Sint Annaland M, Amini S. Experimental investigation on the generic effects of gas permeation through flat vertical membranes. Powder Technol. 2017;316:207&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2016.12.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2016.12.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Wang X, Xia T. A model of safe drainage of coal seam gas. J China Coal Soc. 2014;39(08):1659&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Liu C, Xia T, Liu Y, Sun Y. Intelligent gas extraction and control strategy in coal mine. J China Coal Soc. 2019;44(08):2377&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia T, Zhou F, Wang X, Kang J, Pan Z. Safety evaluation of combustion-prone longwall mining gobs induced by gas extraction: A simulation study. Process Safe Environ Protect. 2017;109:677&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2017.04.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2017.04.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Li P. Soft sensor modeling of coal and gas outburst based on PCA and IFOA-BP. Mining Res Develop. 2018;38(04):109&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Liu H, Mao S, Shi C. Dynamic prediction of gas concentration based on multivariate distribution lag model. J China Univ Min Technol. 2016;45(03):455&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma S, Li X. Study on prediction model of coal mine gas emission by improved BP neural network. Mining Res Develop. 2019;39(10):138&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Cai H. Research on mine water inrush discriminating mathematical model based on GA-BP neural network. Coal Technol. 2019;38(05):121&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Gao R, Yang J. Prediction of coal and gas outburst: A method based on the BP neural network optimized by GASA. Process Safety Environ Protect. 2020;133:64&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2019.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2019.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan L. Research progress on risk identification, assessment, monitoring and early warning technologies of typical dynamic hazards in coal mines. J China Coal Soc. 2020;45(5):1557&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong G, Ren X, Wang Z. A novel early-warning method for atypical outbursts disasters in mines: extraction of indexes from gas concentration data for the early warning of atypical outbursts. Arab J Geosci. 2019;12(24):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1007/s12517-019-4999-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-019-4999-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y, Deng Y, Zhang Q. Deterministic prediction of wavelet neural network model and its application. J Comput Appl. 2013;33(4):1001&#x2013;5. doi: 10.3724/sp.j.1087.2013.01001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3724/sp.j.1087.2013.01001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziyuan T, Minming T. Research on Gas Emission Distribution in Coalface Based on Trend Surface Polynomial Analysis. IEEE Sensor J. 2015;15(1):164&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia P, Liu H, Wang S, Wang P. Research on a Mine Gas Concentration Forecasting Model Based on a GRU Network. IEEE Access. 2020;8:38023&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1109/access.2020.2975257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2020.2975257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H, Zhao Y, Zhang W. Prediction of surface subsidence with improved BP neural network based on Adaboost. Coal Sci Technol. 2019;47(2):161&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demissie A, Zhu W, Belachew CT. A multi-objective optimization model for gas pipeline operations. Comput Chem Eng. 2017;100:94&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1016/j.compchemeng.2017.02.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compchemeng.2017.02.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salahshoor K, Asheri MH, Hadian M, Doostinia M, Babaei M. A Novel Exergy-Based Optimization Approach in Model Predictive Control for Energy-Saving Assessment. J Control Autom Electr Syst. 2020;31(6):1481&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1007/s40313-020-00640-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40313-020-00640-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Ren Z, Chen A. Application of multivariable control based on predictive PI in boiler combustion system. Comput Measure Control. 2017;25(09):55&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Li Z, Jiang T, Li X, Zhang R, Li G. Flexible energy scheduling strategy in smart buildings based on model predictive control. Automat Electric Power Syst. 2019;43(16):116&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H, Zhou J, Gao F, et al. Coal seam gas content prediction based on fusion of feature selection and machine learning. Coal Sci Technol. 2021;49(5):44&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jos&#xe9; M, Manzano, Limon D, Mu&#xf1;oz de la Pe&#xf1; D, Calliess J-P. Robust learning-based MPC for nonlinear constrained systems. Elsevier Ltd; 2020;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarragona J, Fern&#xe1;ndez C, de Gracia A. Model predictive control applied to a heating system with PV panels and thermal energy storage. Elsevier Ltd; 2020. p. 197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Albalawi F, Laleg-Kirati T-M. Observer-based Economic Model Predictive Control for Direct Contact Membrane Distillation. Chem Eng Res Design. 2020;156:86&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1016/j.cherd.2020.01.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cherd.2020.01.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Zhang L, Pan J. Research status and prospect of coalbed methane intelligent extraction in China. Coal Sci Technol. 2020;1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Xue G- zhe, Fang X- qiu, Yang Q- feng, He C, Han S- feng, et al. Discussion on coal mine intelligent safety security system and key technologies. J China Coal Soc. 2020;45(6):2320&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Li G, Meng Z, Zhang Y, Liu L, Li D, et al. The key technology of ground extraction coal bed methane wells crossing goaf. J China Coal Soc. 2020;45(7):2552&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>