<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41618009</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Position prediction from performance and anthropometric indicators in young footballers: a machine learning approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6766</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6766</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6766</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-37957-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The early and accurate identification of playing position-specific skills in young footballers is of critical importance for both performance development and long-term player planning. In this context, the evaluation of quantitative data obtained from technical tests using analytical methods provides a more objective approach that supports the coach&#x2019;s intuition. This study aims to predict the playing positions of young footballers by using data obtained from anthropometric and technical performance tests with machine learning (ML) algorithms. This study involved 200 male footballers aged 15&#x2013;17 who played in different positions (defence&#x2009;=&#x2009;66, midfield&#x2009;=&#x2009;67, forward&#x2009;=&#x2009;67) and were recorded according to the primary tactical role assigned to them by the coach. The participants&#x2019; football-specific technical skills (ball control, shooting, dribbling) and anthropometric characteristics (height, weight, age, BMI) were recorded. Their technical and anthropometric characteristics were compared according to their playing positions using an ANOVA test, and the Bonferroni post-hoc test was performed to test for differences between groups. After data pre-processing and standardisation, the model created with the obtained technical and anthropometric parameters was analysed using Support Vector Machines (SVM, RBF kernel), K-Nearest Neighbour (KNN), Logistic Regression (LR) and Gaussian Naive Bayes algorithms. Model performances were compared based on accuracy, precision, sensitivity, and macro F1 scores. ROC curves and confusion matrices were analysed for the model with the highest performance. Furthermore, the technical and anthropometric parameters affecting the highest performance were analysed using the permutation importance method. The results of the one-way ANOVA showed significant differences between playing positions in terms of age, height, BMI, heading, and dribbling performance (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Post-hoc analyses revealed that midfielders were older than defenders. Forwards, on the other hand, were both taller and had lower BMI values. Furthermore, forwards demonstrated higher heading performance and achieved better results in dribbling skills compared to defenders. Among the ML models, the highest classification success was achieved with the SVM (RBF kernel) model (accuracy&#x2009;=&#x2009;86%); the model correctly classified forwards at a rate of 100%, midfielders at 85%, and defenders at 75%. ROC analysis revealed high discriminative power for all playing positions, with AUC values of 1.00 for Forwards, 0.96 for Defenders, and 0.94 for Midfielders. Feature importance analysis revealed that the most influential variables in playing position classification were 20&#xa0;m dribbling, shooting, body weight, and dribbling; while the head juggling and mixed juggling variables contributed the least to the model. These findings demonstrate that playing position-specific physical and technical characteristics in footballers can be reliably distinguished using both statistical methods and machine learning models, and that performance variables based on speed, finishing ability and physical capacity are particularly decisive in playing position classification.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Izhanov</LastName><ForeName>Zhomart</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Culture and Sports, Abai Kazakh National Pedagogical University, Almaty, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seisenbekov</LastName><ForeName>Yerlan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Culture and Sports, Abai Kazakh National Pedagogical University, Almaty, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marchibayeva</LastName><ForeName>Ulbossyn</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Culture and Sports, L.N. Gumilyov Eurasian National University, Astana, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yessirkepov</LastName><ForeName>Zhandos</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Schools Physical Education and Sports, International University of Tourism and Hospitality, Turkestan, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bakhtiyarova</LastName><ForeName>Sayagul</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Educational Programs for The Training of Teachers of Primary Military Training and Physical Education, Makhambet Utemisov West Kazakhstan University, Uralsk, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yermakhanov</LastName><ForeName>Baglan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sports and Arts, Khoja Akhmet Yassawi International Kazakh-Turkish University, Turkistan, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ryskaliyev</LastName><ForeName>Sayat</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Education and Coaching, Kazakh National University of Sports, Astana, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurto&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Ahmet</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sport Science, Bandirma Onyedi Eylul University, Balikesir, Turkey. kurtogluahmet18@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aldhahi</LastName><ForeName>Monira I</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5255-4860</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, College of Health and Rehabilitation Sciences, Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University, P.O. Box 84428, Riyadh, 11671, Saudi Arabia. mialdhahi@pnu.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PNURSP2026R286</GrantID><Agency>Princess Nourah Bint Abdulrahman University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Footbal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Position prediction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by Faculty of Physical Education and Basic Military Sciences Ethics Committee with decision number 2024/11. In addition, all participants and their families were informed about the purpose, reason, and possible contributions of the study to the literature and consent forms were signed by both participants and their families. The study was conducted in accordance with the principles set out in the Declaration of Helsinki.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41618009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12913652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-37957-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-37957-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mou, C. The attention mechanism performance analysis for football players using the internet of things and deep learning. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>12</b>, 4948&#x2013;4957 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3350036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Castellanos, A. et al. How do the football teams play in laliga? Analysis and comparison of playing styles according to the outcome. <i>Int. J. Perform. Anal. Sport</i>. <b>24</b>, 18&#x2013;30 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24748668.2023.2262813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter, C., O&#x2019;Reilly, M. &amp; Delahunt, E. Machine learning in sports science: challenges and opportunities. <i>Sports Biomech.</i><b>23</b>, 961&#x2013;967 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2021.1910334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross, G. B., Clouthier, A. L., Boyle, A., Fischer, S. L. &amp; Graham, R. B. Comparison of machine learning classifiers for differentiating level and sport using movement data. <i>J. Sports Sci.</i><b>40</b>, 2166&#x2013;2172 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2022.2145430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36415053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurto&#x11f;lu, A. et al. The role of morphometric characteristics in predicting 20-meter sprint performance through machine learning. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 16593 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-67405-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11258122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39025965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silacci, A., Taiar, R. &amp; Caon, M. Towards an AI-Based tailored training planning for road cyclists: A case study. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>11</b>, 313 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11010313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, L. S., Kao, C. H., Li, Y. J., Chen, H. H. &amp; Chen, H. Y. Improved support vector machine classification for imbalanced medical datasets by novel hybrid sampling combining modified mega-trend-diffusion and bagging extreme learning machine model. <i>Math. Biosci. Eng.</i><b>20</b>, 17672&#x2013;17701 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3934/mbe.2023786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38052532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dijkhuis, T. B., Kempe, M. &amp; Lemmink, K. A. P. M. Early prediction of physical performance in elite soccer Matches&#x2014;A machine learning approach to support substitutions. <i>Entropy</i><b>23</b>, 952 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e23080952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8394038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34441092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassis, G., Verhagen, E., Brito, J., Figueiredo, P. &amp; Krustrup, P. A review of machine learning applications in soccer with an emphasis on injury risk. <i>Biol. Sport</i>. <b>40</b>, 233&#x2013;239 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.114283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9806760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36636180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillitteri, G. et al. Relationship between external and internal load indicators and injury using machine learning in professional soccer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. <i>Res. Sports Med.</i><b>1&#x2013;37</b>10.1080/15438627.2023.2297190 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38146925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rico-Gonz&#xe1;lez, M., Pino-Ortega, J., M&#xe9;ndez, A., Clemente, F. &amp; Baca, A. Machine learning application in soccer: a systematic review. <i>Biol. Sport</i>. <b>40</b>, 249&#x2013;263 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.112970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9806754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36636183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuth, G. et al. Football movement Profile&#x2013;Based Creatine-Kinase prediction performs similarly to global positioning System&#x2013;Derived machine learning models in National-Team soccer players. <i>Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform.</i><b>1&#x2013;8</b>10.1123/ijspp.2024-0077 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38917990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berrar, D., Lopes, P. &amp; Dubitzky, W. Incorporating domain knowledge in machine learning for soccer outcome prediction. <i>Mach. Learn.</i><b>108</b>, 97&#x2013;126 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10994-018-5747-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memmert, D., Lemmink, K. A. P. M. &amp; Sampaio, J. Current approaches to tactical performance analyses in soccer using position data. <i>Sports Med.</i><b>47</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0562-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27251334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt, J. H. &amp; Karaku&#x15f;, O. A machine learning approach for player and position adjusted expected goals in football (soccer). <i>Frankl. Open.</i><b>4</b>, 100034 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fraope.2023.100034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manish., S., Bhagat, V. &amp; Pramila, R. Prediction of Football Players Performance using Machine Learning and Deep Learning Algorithms. in <i>2nd International Conference for Emerging Technology (INCET)</i> 1&#x2013;5 (IEEE, 2021). 1&#x2013;5. 10.1109/INCET51464.2021.9456424 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortez, A., Trigo, A. &amp; Loureiro, N. Football match Line-Up prediction based on physiological variables: A machine learning approach. <i>Computers</i><b>11</b>, 40 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/computers11030040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongiovanni, T. et al. How do football playing positions differ in body composition? A first insight into white Italian Serie A and Serie B players. <i>J. Funct. Morphol. Kinesiol.</i><b>8</b>, 80 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk8020080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10299074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37367244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira, J. E. et al. Effects of match Location, quality of opposition and match outcome on match running performance in a Portuguese professional football team. <i>Entropy</i><b>23</b>, 973 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e23080973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8391710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34441113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michailidis, Y. The relationship between aerobic Capacity, anthropometric Characteristics, and performance in the Yo-Yo intermittent recovery test among elite young football players: differences between playing positions. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>14</b>, 3413 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14083413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul, F., Erdfelder, E., Lang, A. G. &amp; Buchner, A. G*Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. <i>Behav. Res. Methods</i>. <b>39</b>, 175&#x2013;191 (2007).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BF03193146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;ksal, M., G&#xfc;l, G. K. &amp; Do&#x11f;anay, M. &amp; &#xc1;lvarez-Garcia, C. Effects of coordination training on the technical development in 10-/13-year-old football players. <i>J. Sports Med. Phys. Fitness</i><b>61</b>, (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32744045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, C., Kuan, G., Muhamad, A. S., Kueh, Y. C. &amp; Chin, N. S. The effect of virtual reality imagery on motivation and football kicking skill performance among youth football players in Sarawak. 57&#x2013;70. 10.1007/978-981-19-8159-3_5 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arslan, Y. &amp; Ermi&#x15f;, E. The effects of life kinetic exercises on technical skills and motor skills performance in young football players. <i>Eur. J. Phys. Educ. Sport Sci.</i><b>9</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell, M., Benton, D. &amp; Kingsley, M. Reliability and construct validity of soccer skills tests that measure passing, shooting, and dribbling. <i>J. Sports Sci.</i><b>28</b>, 1399&#x2013;1408 (2010).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2010.511247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20967673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, C. Player detection based on support vector machine in football videos. <i>Int. J. Perform. Eng.</i>10.23940/ijpe.18.02.p12.309319 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23940/ijpe.18.02.p12.309319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes, C. &amp; Vapnik, V. Support-vector networks. <i>Mach. Learn.</i><b>20</b>, 273&#x2013;297 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022627411411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halder, R. K., Uddin, M. N., Uddin, M. A., Aryal, S. &amp; Khraisat, A. Enhancing K-nearest neighbor algorithm: a comprehensive review and performance analysis of modifications. <i>J. Big Data</i>. <b>11</b>, 113 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-024-00973-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adem, K. Diagnosis of breast cancer with stacked autoencoder and subspace kNN. <i>Phys. A: Stat. Mech. Its Appl.</i><b>551</b>, 124591 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physa.2020.124591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nusinovici, S. et al. Logistic regression was as good as machine learning for predicting major chronic diseases. <i>J. Clin. Epidemiol.</i><b>122</b>, 56&#x2013;69 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2020.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32169597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy, J. J. &amp; O&#x2019;Malley, A. J. Don&#x2019;t dismiss logistic regression: the case for sensible extraction of interactions in the era of machine learning. <i>BMC Med. Res. Methodol.</i><b>20</b>, 171 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-020-01046-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7325087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herold, M. et al. Machine learning in men&#x2019;s professional football: current applications and future directions for improving attacking play. <i>Int. J. Sports Sci. Coach</i>. <b>14</b>, 798&#x2013;817 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747954119879350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x106;wiklinski, B., Gie&#x142;czyk, A. &amp; Chora&#x15b;, M. Who will score? A machine learning approach to supporting football team Building and transfers. <i>Entropy</i><b>23</b>, 90 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e23010090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33435241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frangoudes, F., Matsangidou, M., Schiza, E. C., Neokleous, K. &amp; Pattichis, C. S. Assessing human motion during exercise using machine learning: A literature review. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>10</b>, 86874&#x2013;86903 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3198935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, R. C., Dewi, C., Huang, S. W. &amp; Caraka, R. E. Selecting critical features for data classification based on machine learning methods. <i>J. Big Data</i>. <b>7</b>, 52 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-020-00327-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, H. Research on SVM improved algorithm for large data classification. in. <i>IEEE 3rd International Conference on Big Data Analysis (ICBDA)</i> 181&#x2013;185 (IEEE, 2018). 10.1109/ICBDA.2018.8367673 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedretti, A., Pedretti, A., De Oliveira Fernandes, J. B. &amp; Rebelo, C. A. N. &amp; Teixeira Seabra, A. F. The relative age effects in young soccer players and it relations with the competitive level, specific position, morphological characteristics, physical fitness and technical skills. <i>Pensar a Pr&#xe1;tica</i><b>19</b>, (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo, C. H. &amp; Seo, D. I. Analysis of physical fitness and technical skills of youth soccer players according to playing position. <i>J. Exerc. Rehabil</i>. <b>12</b>, 548&#x2013;552 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.1632730.365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5227316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28119876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razali, N., Mustapha, A. &amp; Yatim, F. A. Ab Aziz, R. Predicting player position for talent identification in association football. <i>IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng.</i><b>226</b>, 012087 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1757-899X/226/1/012087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sander Utomo, K. &amp; Wiradinata, T. Optimal playing position prediction in football matches: A machine learning approach. <i>Int. J. Inform. Eng. Electron. Bus.</i><b>15</b>, 30&#x2013;47 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves, B. V., Figueira, B. E., Ma&#xe7;&#xe3;s, V. &amp; Sampaio, J. Effect of player position on movement behaviour, physical and physiological performances during an 11-a-side football game. <i>J. Sports Sci.</i><b>32</b>, 191&#x2013;199 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2013.816761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24016056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato, M., Youngs, A. &amp; Costin, A. J. The analysis of physical performance during official competitions in professional english football: do Positions, game Locations, and results influence players&#x2019; game demands? <i>J. Strength. Cond Res.</i><b>38</b>, e226&#x2013;e234 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38231139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x141;ukaszuk, T. &amp; Krawczuk, J. Importance of feature selection stability in the classifier evaluation on high-dimensional genetic data. <i>PeerJ</i><b>12</b>, e18405 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.18405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeys, Y., Inza, I. &amp; Larra&#xf1;aga, P. A review of feature selection techniques in bioinformatics. <i>Bioinformatics</i><b>23</b>, 2507&#x2013;2517 (2007).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btm344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17720704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pudjihartono, N., Fadason, T., Kempa-Liehr, A. W. &amp; O&#x2019;Sullivan, J. M. A review of feature selection methods for machine Learning-Based disease risk prediction. <i>Front. Bioinf.</i><b>2</b>, (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36304293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>