<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41516787</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2073-4360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Polymers</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Polymers (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on Viscoelastic Characteristics of Polymer Solution Formation and Their Effect on Oil Displacement Efficiency.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/polym18010002</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Polymer solutions exhibit radial flow characteristics upon injection into a formation via the wellbore. Accurately characterizing their viscoelastic properties at varying seepage velocities and quantifying their impact on displacement efficiency are crucial for advancing polymer flooding technology. This study simulated shear rate variations during polymer injection and integrated laboratory-measured viscoelastic properties with permeability characteristics in porous media. An analysis of the oil displacement performance between viscoelastic polymer solutions and a purely viscous fluid, glycerol, was conducted. The key findings are as follows: (1) Polymer elasticity, characterized by the first normal stress difference, diminishes with decreasing injection time/solution concentration. Significant viscoelasticity is observed near the wellbore, weakening in deeper reservoir regions. (2) The polymer type and injection conditions govern the development of solution "effective viscosity" during porous medium flow. A fundamental trend under elevated flow velocities is an increase in effective viscosity with shear rate. (3) Comparison with glycerol demonstrates that the viscoelastic effect of polymer solutions enhances heavy-oil displacement efficiency. The magnitude of this viscoelastic effect within the porous medium directly correlates with its contribution to improved displacement efficiency.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Shijie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2193-2646</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Logistics Support Force Engineering University, Chongqing 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, Chongqing University of Science and Technology, Chongqing 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lijun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sinopec Zhongyuan Petrochemical Co., Ltd., Puyang 457000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sinopec Zhongyuan Petrochemical Co., Ltd., Puyang 457000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Xueli</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Binzhou Inspection and Testing Center, Dongying 257000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Yunxiong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3309-0615</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Logistics Support Force Engineering University, Chongqing 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Xinsheng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Logistics Support Force Engineering University, Chongqing 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023M744278</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KJQN202301518</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Research Project of Chongqing Education Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Polymers (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2073-4360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heavy oil</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymer solution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">residual resistance factor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance factor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viscoelasticity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Lijun Chen and Jie Zhang were employed by the company Sinopec Zhongyuan Petrochemical Co., Ltd. Author Xueli Duan was employed by the company Binzhou Inspection and Testing Center. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as potential conflicts of interest. The funding sponsors had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the manuscript; and in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41516787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12788124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym18010002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">polym18010002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Levitt D., Jouenne S., Bondino I., Santanach-Carreras E., Bourrel M. Polymer Flooding of Heavy Oil Under Adverse Mobility Conditions; Proceedings of the SPE Enhanced Oil Recovery Conference; Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. 2&#x2013;4 July 2013; Richardson, TX, USA: Society of Petroleum Engineers; 2013. p. SPE165267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Shi L., Ye Z., Wang Y., Liu C., Xue X. Microscopic experimental study on the sweep and displacement efficiencies in heterogeneous heavy oil reservoirs. Energy Rep. 2021;7:1627&#x2013;1635. doi: 10.1016/j.egyr.2021.03.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2021.03.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M., Yu H., Zhou C., Jia Z., Huang W., Guo S., Zhang P., Pan B., Wang Y. Seepage flow characteristics and ability for enhanced oil recovery based on ultra high molecular weight partially hydrolysed polyacrylamide. Int. J. Oil Gas Coal Technol. 2017;14:216&#x2013;231. doi: 10.1504/IJOGCT.2017.082045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJOGCT.2017.082045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malkin A.Y., Subbotin A.V., Kulichikhin V.G. Stability of polymer jets in extension: Physicochemical and rheological mechanisms. Russ. Chem. Rev. 2020;89:811&#x2013;823. doi: 10.1070/RCR4941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1070/RCR4941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgaertel M., Schausberger A., Winter H.H. The relaxation of polymers with linear flexible chains of uniform length. Rheol. Acta. 1990;29:400&#x2013;408. doi: 10.1007/BF01376790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01376790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Liu H. Anovel model sensitivity analysis for viscoelastic polymer flooding in offshore oilfield. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2014;20:656&#x2013;667. doi: 10.1016/j.jiec.2013.05.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2013.05.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subbotin A.V., Malkin A.Y., Kulichikhin V.G. The Elasticity of Polymer Melts and Solutions in Shear and Extension Flows. Polymers. 2023;15:1051. doi: 10.3390/polym15041051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15041051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9961469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36850333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinogradov G.V., Malkin A.Y. Rheology of Polymers. Springer; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malkin A.Y., Petrie C.J.S. Some conditions for rupture of polymer liquids in extension. J. Rheol. 1997;41:1&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1122/1.550881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1122/1.550881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;nstedt H. Extensional Rheology and Processing of Polymeric Materials. Int. Polym. Process. 2018;33:594&#x2013;618. doi: 10.3139/217.3532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3139/217.3532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malkin A., Arinstein A., Kulichikhin V. Polymer extension flows and instabilities. Prog. Polym. Sci. 2014;39:959&#x2013;978. doi: 10.1016/j.progpolymsci.2014.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.progpolymsci.2014.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulichikhin V.G., Malkin A.Y. The Role of Structure in Polymer Rheology: Review. Polymers. 2022;14:1262. doi: 10.3390/polym14061262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14061262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8951770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35335592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anurag P., Qamar S.F., Das S., Basu S., Kesarwani H., Saxena A., Sharma S., Sarkar J. Advanced multi-wall carbon nanotube-optimized surfactant-polymer flooding for enhanced oil recovery. Fuel. 2024;355:129463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y., Chang H., Du Z., Yuan B., Dandekar A., Zhang Y. A laboratory investigation of CO2 influence on solvent-assisted polymer flooding for improving viscous oil recovery on Alaska North Slope. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 2023;229:212053. doi: 10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Hu M., Cheng Y., Wang Z., Zhang H., Chen R., Guo J. Design of high-temperature salt-responsive hydrogel based on W/O/W double emulsion. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2025;717:136852. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.136852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohsen M.Y., Pouyan E.B., Pacelli Z. Fundamentals and Recent Progress in the Flow of Water-Soluble Polymers in Porous Media for Enhanced Oil Recovery. Energies. 2022;15:8575. doi: 10.3390/en15228575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15228575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegbert R., Behr M., Elgeti S. AIP Conference Proceedings. Vol. 1769. AIP Publishing; Melville, NY, USA: 2016. Die swell as an objective in the design of polymer extrusion dies; p. 140003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.4963540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Dan L., Wang L. Application of horizontal well discontinuous chemical flooding technology in Bohai Oilfield. Front. Energy Res. 2023;10:1036835. doi: 10.3389/fenrg.2022.1036835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2022.1036835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao H., Tan L. The Characteristic of Oil and Gas Accumulation and Main Factors of Reservoir Enrichment in SZ36-1 Region. Appl. Mech. Mater. 2015;737:859&#x2013;862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Meng X., Zhang Y., Xia H., Cao B., Luo Y. Numerical simulation of separate-layer injection-production effect and its influencing factors in offshore oilfield -by taking SZ36-1 oilfield in Bohai sea as an example. Pet. Geol. Eng. 2020;34:95&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue X., Zhu S., Ma X., Zhang S., Yang S., Huang Z., Xu M., Huang H. Enhancing heavy-oil displacement efficiency through viscoelasticity of polymer solution by investigating the viscosity limit of crude oil: An experimental study. Energy Sci. Eng. 2024;12:2493&#x2013;2504. doi: 10.1002/ese3.1753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ese3.1753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue X. Doctoral Thesis. Southwest Petroleum University; Chengdu, China: 2009. Study on the Influence of Rheological Properties of Polymer Solutions on Enhanced Oil Recovery.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedde G.M., Santo L., Bellisarbo D., Quandini F. Frozen Stresses in Shape Memory Polymer Composites. Mater. Plast. 2022;55:2018494. doi: 10.37358/MP.18.4.5060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.37358/MP.18.4.5060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Sun F., Xie X., Kang X.D., Li B.Z. Reservoir technical-economic limit of polymer flooding and classification in Bohai Sea. China Offshore Oil Gas. 2014;26:51&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S., Xu M., Yang S., Huang Z., Wang Y., Zhu Y. Evaluation of shear resistance of dendritic hydrophobic association polymers. J. Polym. Res. 2024;31:318. doi: 10.1007/s10965-024-04177-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10965-024-04177-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao G., Zhu S., Wang J., Huang Z., Xu M. Feasibility of Oil Mud Reinjection from Offshore Platforms in Bohai Oilfield. J. Basic Appl. Sci. 2023;19:68&#x2013;76. doi: 10.29169/1927-5129.2023.19.06.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29169/1927-5129.2023.19.06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves M., Oliveira P., Pinho F. Numerical Methods for Viscoelastic Fluid Flows. Annu. Rev. Fluid Mech. 2021;53:509&#x2013;541. doi: 10.1146/annurev-fluid-010719-060107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-fluid-010719-060107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Shi L., Ye Z., Zhang X., Zhang L., Li X. Experimental study on improving oil recovery in fluvial reservoir with polymer solutions. AIP Adv. 2021;11:055121. doi: 10.1063/5.0042539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0042539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne C.A., Datta S.S. Elastic turbulence generates anomalous flow resistance in porous media. Sci. Adv. 2021;7:eabj2619. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.abj2619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abj2619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8570596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34739321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S., Zhang S., Xue X., Zhang J., Xu J., Liu Z. Influencing factors for effective establishment of residual resistance factor of polymer solution in porous media. J. Polym. Res. 2022;29:210. doi: 10.1007/s10965-022-03066-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10965-022-03066-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L., Zhu S., Zou J., Xue X., Zhao W., Ye Z. Research on the Time Range and Influencing Factors of Effective Flow Control in Polymer Flooding. Pet. Reserv. Eval. Dev. 2019;9:31&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang L., Hu M., Cao J., Cheng Y., Li P., Guo J., Zhang H. Design of Janus Nanoparticles for Mobility Control in Heterogeneous Reservoirs. ACS Omega. 2024;9:16536&#x2013;16546. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c00317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c00317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11007849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38617606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>