<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41471330</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1424-8247</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pharmaceuticals (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pharmaceuticals (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Decoding GuaB: Machine Learning-Powered Discovery of Enzyme Inhibitors Against the Superbug <i>Acinetobacter baumannii</i>.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1842</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ph18121842</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background/Objectives:</b> GuaB, which is known as inosine 5'-phosphate dehydrogenase (IMPDH), is an enzymatic target involved in the de novo guanine biosynthetic pathway of the multidrug-resistant (MDR) <i>Acinetobacter baumannii</i>. GuaB has emerged as a potential therapeutic target to cope with increasing antibiotic resistance. Here, we used machine learning-based virtual screening as a verification technique to find potential inhibitors possessing different chemical scaffolds, using structure-based drug design as a discovery platform. <b>Methods:</b> Four machine learning models, built based on chemical fingerprint data, were trained, and the best models were used for virtual screening of the ChEMBL library, which covers 153 active molecules. Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of 200 ns were carried out for all three compounds in order to explain conformational changes, evaluate stability, and provide validation of the docking results. Post-simulation analyses include principal component analysis (PCA), bond analysis, free-energy landscape (FEL), dynamic cross-correlation matrix (DCCM), radial distribution function (RDF), salt-bridge identification, and secondary-structure profiling, etc. <b>Results:</b> For molecular docking, the screened compounds were used against the GuaB protein to achieve proper docked conformation. Upon visual examination of the best-docked compounds, three leads (lead-1, lead-2, and lead-3) were found to have better interaction with the GuaB protein in comparison to the control. The mean RMSD scores between the three leads and the control were between 2.54 and 2.89 &#xc5;. In addition, the three leads as well as the control were characterized for pharmacokinetic features. All three leads met Lipinski's Rule 5 and were thus drug-like. PCA and FEL analyses showed that lead-2 exhibited improved conformational stability, identified as deeper energy minima, whereas RDF and DCCM analyses revealed that lead-2 and lead-3 exhibited strong local structuring and concerted dynamics. In addition, lead-2 displayed a very rich hydrogen-bonding network with a total of 460 frames possessing such interactions, which is the highest among the complexes investigated here. Based on entropy calculations and the maximum entropy method of gamma-gram, lead-1 proved to be the most stable one with the lowest binding free-energy. <b>Conclusions:</b> This study provides an integrated machine learning-based virtual screening pipeline for the identification of new scaffolds to moderate infections associated with AMR; however, in vitro validation is still required to assess the efficacy of such compounds.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aljasir</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3708-9200</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratories, College of Applied Medical Sciences, Qassim University, Buraydah 52571, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Sajjad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0754-1742</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Biological Sciences, Abasyn University, Peshawar 25000, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Pharmaceuticals (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101238453</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8247</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MMGB/PBSA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RDF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial resistance (AMR)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular docking</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41471330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12735981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph18121842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ph18121842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Salam M.A., Al-Amin M.Y., Salam M.T., Pawar J.S., Akhter N., Rabaan A.A., Alqumber M.A.A. Antimicrobial Resistance: A Growing Serious Threat for Global Public Health. Healthcare. 2023;11:1946. doi: 10.3390/healthcare11131946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11131946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10340576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37444780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh T.R., Gales A.C., Laxminarayan R., Dodd P.C. Antimicrobial Resistance: Addressing a Global Threat to Humanity. PLoS Med. 2023;20:e1004264. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1004264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1004264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10317217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37399216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson R.E., Hyun D., Jezek A., Samore M.H. Mortality, Length of Stay, and Healthcare Costs Associated with Multidrug-Resistant Bacterial Infections among Elderly Hospitalized Patients in the United States. Clin. Infect. Dis. 2022;74:1070&#x2013;1080. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciab696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8946701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34617118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Xu G., Miao F., Huang W., Wang H., Wang X. Insights into the Epidemiology, Risk Factors, and Clinical Outcomes of Carbapenem-Resistant Acinetobacter baumannii Infections in Critically Ill Children. Front. Public Health. 2023;11:1282413. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2023.1282413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1282413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10720883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38098829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller W.R., Arias C.A. ESKAPE Pathogens: Antimicrobial Resistance, Epidemiology, Clinical Impact and Therapeutics. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2024;22:598&#x2013;616. doi: 10.1038/s41579-024-01054-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-024-01054-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38831030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colman R.E., Sahl J.W. Practical Handbook of Microbiology. CRC Press; Boca Raton, FL, USA: 2021. Other Gram-Negative Bacteria: Acinetobacter, Burkholderia, and Moraxella; pp. 613&#x2013;618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhayek A., Abdelsamie A.S., Sch&#xf6;nauer E., Camberlein V., Hutterer E., Posselt G., Serwanja J., Bl&#xf6;chl C., Huber C.G., Haupenthal J., et al. Discovery and Characterization of Synthesized and FDA-Approved Inhibitors of Clostridial and Bacillary Collagenases. J. Med. Chem. 2022;65:12933&#x2013;12955. doi: 10.1021/acs.jmedchem.2c00785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jmedchem.2c00785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9574867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36154055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knejzl&#xed;k Z., Dole&#x17e;al M., Herkommerov&#xe1; K., Clarova K., Kl&#xed;ma M., Dedola M., Zborn&#xed;kov&#xe1; E., Rejman D., Pichov&#xe1; I. The Mycobacterial GuaB1 Gene Encodes a Guanosine 5&#x2032;-monophosphate Reductase with a Cystathionine-&#x3b2;-synthase Domain. FEBS J. 2022;289:5571&#x2013;5598. doi: 10.1111/febs.16448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/febs.16448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9790621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35338694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adugna A. Therapeutic Strategies and Promising Vaccine for Hepatitis C Virus Infection. Immun. Inflamm. Dis. 2023;11:e977. doi: 10.1002/iid3.977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/iid3.977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10461427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37647422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kofoed E.M., Aliagas I., Crawford T., Mao J., Harris S.F., Xu M., Wang S., Wu P., Ma F., Clark K. Discovery of GuaB Inhibitors with Efficacy against Acinetobacter baumannii Infection. mBio. 2024;15:e00897-24. doi: 10.1128/mbio.00897-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mbio.00897-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11481871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39207111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya A., Agarwal R., Baker M.B., Baudry J., Bhowmik D., Boehm S., Byler K.G., Chen S.Y., Coates L., Cooper C.J., et al. Supercomputer-Based Ensemble Docking Drug Discovery Pipeline with Application to COVID-19. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2020;60:5832&#x2013;5852. doi: 10.1021/acs.jcim.0c01010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.0c01010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7754786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33326239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarajan K., Sundaram D.P., Marimuthu S.K. Innovations in Pharmaceutical Biotechnology. Academic Guru Publishing House; Bhopal, India: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satpathy R. Artificial Intelligence Techniques in the Classification and Screening of Compounds in Computer-Aided Drug Design (CADD) Process. Artif. Intell. Mach. Learn. Drug Des. Dev. 2024:473&#x2013;497. doi: 10.1002/9781394234196.ch15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781394234196.ch15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dara S., Dhamercherla S., Jadav S.S., Babu C.H.M., Ahsan M.J. Machine Learning in Drug Discovery: A Review. Artif. Intell. Rev. 2022;55:1947&#x2013;1999. doi: 10.1007/s10462-021-10058-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-021-10058-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8356896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34393317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamri M.A., Mirza M.U., Adeel M.M., Ashfaq U.A., Tahir Ul Qamar M., Shahid F., Ahmad S., Alatawi E.A., Albalawi G.M., Allemailem K.S., et al. Structural Elucidation of Rift Valley Fever Virus L Protein towards the Discovery of Its Potential Inhibitors. Pharmaceuticals. 2022;15:659. doi: 10.3390/ph15060659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph15060659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9228520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35745579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y., Moffat J.G., DuPai C., Kofoed E.M., Skippington E., Modrusan Z., Gloor S.L., Clark K., Xu Y., Li S. Differential Effects of Inosine Monophosphate Dehydrogenase (IMPDH/GuaB) Inhibition in Acinetobacter baumannii and Escherichia coli. J. Bacteriol. 2024;206:e00102-24. doi: 10.1128/jb.00102-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jb.00102-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11500612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39235234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha V., Devkar S., Gharat K., Kasbe S., Matharoo D.K., Pendse S., Bhosale A., Bhargava A. Screening of Phytochemicals as Potential Inhibitors of Breast Cancer Using Structure Based Multitargeted Molecular Docking Analysis. Phytomedicine Plus. 2022;2:100227. doi: 10.1016/j.phyplu.2022.100227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phyplu.2022.100227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funari R., Bhalla N., Gentile L. Measuring the Radius of Gyration and Intrinsic Flexibility of Viral Proteins in Buffer Solution Using Small-Angle X-Ray Scattering. ACS Meas. Sci. Au. 2022;2:547&#x2013;552. doi: 10.1021/acsmeasuresciau.2c00048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsmeasuresciau.2c00048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9783065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36573077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnuqaydan A.M., Almutary A.G., Alsahli M.A., Alnasser S., Rah B. Tamarix Articulata Induced Prevention of Hepatotoxicity Effects of In Vivo Carbon Tetrachloride by Modulating Pro-Inflammatory Serum and Antioxidant Enzymes to Reverse the Liver Fibrosis. Antioxidants. 2022;11:1824. doi: 10.3390/antiox11091824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox11091824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9496017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36139897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Fonseca A.M., Caluaco B.J., Madureira J.M.C., Cabongo S.Q., Gaieta E.M., Djata F., Colares R.P., Neto M.M., Fernandes C.F.C., Marinho G.S. Screening of Potential Inhibitors Targeting the Main Protease Structure of SARS-CoV-2 via Molecular Docking, and Approach with Molecular Dynamics, RMSD, RMSF, H-Bond, SASA and MMGBSA. Mol. Biotechnol. 2024;66:1919&#x2013;1933. doi: 10.1007/s12033-023-00831-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12033-023-00831-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37490200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandfort M., Vantaux A., Kim S., Obadia T., Pepey A., Gardais S., Khim N., Lek D., White M., Robinson L.J., et al. Forest Malaria in Cambodia: The Occupational and Spatial Clustering of Plasmodium Vivax and Plasmodium Falciparum Infection Risk in a Cross-Sectional Survey in Mondulkiri Province, Cambodia. Malar. J. 2020;19:413. doi: 10.1186/s12936-020-03482-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-020-03482-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7678315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33213471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akash S., Bay&#x131;l I., Rahman M.A., Mukerjee N., Maitra S., Islam M.R., Rajkhowa S., Ghosh A., Al-Hussain S.A., Zaki M.E.A., et al. Target Specific Inhibition of West Nile Virus Envelope Glycoprotein and Methyltransferase Using Phytocompounds: An in Silico Strategy Leveraging Molecular Docking and Dynamics Simulation. Front. Microbiol. 2023;14:1189786. doi: 10.3389/fmicb.2023.1189786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1189786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10338848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37455711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharbi A.S., Altwaim S.A., El-Daly M.M., Hassan A.M., Al-Zahrani I.A., Bajrai L.H., Alsaady I.M., Dwivedi V.D., Azhar E.I. Marine Fungal Diversity Unlocks Potent Antivirals against Monkeypox through Methyltransferase Inhibition Revealed by Molecular Dynamics and Free Energy Landscape. BMC Chem. 2024;18:141. doi: 10.1186/s13065-024-01251-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13065-024-01251-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11290312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39080756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta M.N., Uversky V.N. Biological Importance of Arginine: A Comprehensive Review of the Roles in Structure, Disorder, and Functionality of Peptides and Proteins. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2023;257:128646. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.128646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.128646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38061507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak J., Grishina M.A., Potemkin V.A. The Influence of Hydrogen Atoms on the Performance of Radial Distribution Function-Based Descriptors in the Chemoinformatic Studies of HIV-1 Protease Complexes with Inhibitors. Curr. Drug Discov. Technol. 2021;18:414&#x2013;422. doi: 10.2174/1570163817666200102130415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570163817666200102130415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31899678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trong D.N., Long V.C. Effects of Number of Atoms, Shell Thickness, and Temperature on the Structure of Fe Nanoparticles Amorphous by Molecular Dynamics Method. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2021;2021:9976633. doi: 10.1155/2021/9976633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/9976633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coimbra J.T.S., Feghali R., Ribeiro R.P., Ramos M.J., Fernandes P.A. The Importance of Intramolecular Hydrogen Bonds on the Translocation of the Small Drug Piracetam through a Lipid Bilayer. RSC Adv. 2021;11:899&#x2013;908. doi: 10.1039/D0RA09995C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0RA09995C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8693363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35423709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konermann L., Aliyari E., Lee J.H. Mobile Protons Limit the Stability of Salt Bridges in the Gas Phase: Implications for the Structures of Electrosprayed Protein Ions. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2021;125:3803&#x2013;3814. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c00944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c00944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33848419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Feng K., Liu J., Ren Y. Molecular Modeling Studies of Novel Naphthyridine and Isoquinoline Derivatives as CDK8 Inhibitors. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2021;39:6355&#x2013;6369. doi: 10.1080/07391102.2020.1797537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07391102.2020.1797537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles A.J., Ramalli S.G., Wallace B.A. DichroWeb, a Website for Calculating Protein Secondary Structure from Circular Dichroism Spectroscopic Data. Protein Sci. 2022;31:37&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1002/pro.4153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pro.4153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34216059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashem H.E., Ahmad S., Kumer A., Bakri Y. El In Silico and in Vitro Prediction of New Synthesized N-Heterocyclic Compounds as Anti-SARS-CoV-2. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:1152. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-51443-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-51443-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10784557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent F., Nueda A., Lee J., Schenone M., Prunotto M., Mercola M. Phenotypic Drug Discovery: Recent Successes, Lessons Learned and New Directions. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 2022;21:899&#x2013;914. doi: 10.1038/s41573-022-00472-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41573-022-00472-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9708951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35637317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S.P., Girija A.S.S., Priyadharsini J.V. Targeting NM23-H1-Mediated Inhibition of Tumour Metastasis in Viral Hepatitis with Bioactive Compounds from Ganoderma Lucidum: A Computational Study. Indian J. Pharm. Sci. 2020;82:300. doi: 10.36468/pharmaceutical-sciences.650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36468/pharmaceutical-sciences.650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidarinia H., Tajbakhsh E., Rostamian M., Momtaz H. Design and Validation of a Multi-Epitope Vaccine Candidate against Acinetobacter baumannii Using Advanced Computational Methods. Res. Sq. 2023 doi: 10.21203/rs.3.rs-3182215/v1. preprint .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-3182215/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12255626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40650846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari M., Singh R., Subbarao N. Exploring the Interaction Mechanism between Potential Inhibitor and Multi-Target Mur Enzymes of Mycobacterium Tuberculosis Using Molecular Docking, Molecular Dynamics Simulation, Principal Component Analysis, Free Energy Landscape, Dynamic Cross-Correlation. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2022;40:13497&#x2013;13526. doi: 10.1080/07391102.2021.1989040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07391102.2021.1989040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34662260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshehri F.F. Integrated Virtual Screening, Molecular Modeling and Machine Learning Approaches Revealed Potential Natural Inhibitors for Epilepsy. Saudi Pharm. J. 2023;31:101835. doi: 10.1016/j.jsps.2023.101835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsps.2023.101835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10641561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37965486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapero A., Pacitto A., Singh V., Sabbah M., Coyne A.G., Mizrahi V., Blundell T.L., Ascher D.B., Abell C. Fragment-Based Approach to Targeting Inosine-5&#x2032;-Monophosphate Dehydrogenase (IMPDH) from Mycobacterium Tuberculosis. J. Med. Chem. 2018;61:2806&#x2013;2822. doi: 10.1021/acs.jmedchem.7b01622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jmedchem.7b01622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5900554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29547284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattabiraman N., Lobello C., Rushmore D., Mologni L., Wasik M., Basappa J. A Novel Allosteric Inhibitor Targeting IMPDH at Y233 Overcomes Resistance to Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors in Lymphoma. Cancers. 2025;17:3389. doi: 10.3390/cancers17203389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers17203389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12563536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41154443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertoni M., Duran-Frigola M., Badia-i-Mompel P., Pauls E., Orozco-Ruiz M., Guitart-Pla O., Alcalde V., Diaz V.M., Berenguer-Llergo A., Brun-Heath I. Bioactivity Descriptors for Uncharacterized Chemical Compounds. Nat. Commun. 2021;12:3932. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-24150-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-24150-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8225676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Berre M., Gerlach J.Q., Dziemba&#x142;a I., Kilcoyne M. Glycan Microarrays: Methods and Protocols. Springer; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 2022. Calculating Half Maximal Inhibitory Concentration (IC50) Values from Glycomics Microarray Data Using GraphPad Prism; pp. 89&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34972932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamzehali H., Lotfi S., Ahmadi S., Kumar P. Quantitative Structure&#x2013;Activity Relationship Modeling for Predication of Inhibition Potencies of Imatinib Derivatives Using SMILES Attributes. Sci. Rep. 2022;12:21708. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-26279-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-26279-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9755126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36522400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mervin L.H., Trapotsi M.-A., Afzal A.M., Barrett I.P., Bender A., Engkvist O. Probabilistic Random Forest Improves Bioactivity Predictions Close to the Classification Threshold by Taking into Account Experimental Uncertainty. J. Cheminform. 2021;13:62. doi: 10.1186/s13321-021-00539-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13321-021-00539-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8375213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34412708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabot J.H., Ross E.G. Evaluating Prediction Model Performance. Surgery. 2023;174:723&#x2013;726. doi: 10.1016/j.surg.2023.05.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surg.2023.05.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10529246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37419761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varoquaux G., Colliot O. Machine Learning for Brain Disorders. Humana; New York, NY, USA: 2023. Evaluating Machine Learning Models and Their Diagnostic Value; pp. 601&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37988512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salama M. Optimization of Regression Models Using Machine Learning: A Comprehensive Study with Scikit-Learn. Int. Uni-Sci. Res. J. 2024;5:119&#x2013;129. doi: 10.59271/s45500.024.0624.16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59271/s45500.024.0624.16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurniasih A., Previana C.N. Implementation of GridSearchCV to Find the Best Hyperparameter Combination for Classification Model Algorithm in Predicting Water Potability. J. Artif. Intell. Eng. Appl. 2025;4:1174&#x2013;1182. doi: 10.59934/jaiea.v4i2.844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59934/jaiea.v4i2.844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahm F.S. Receiver Operating Characteristic Curve: Overview and Practical Use for Clinicians. Korean J. Anesthesiol. 2022;75:25&#x2013;36. doi: 10.4097/kja.21209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4097/kja.21209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8831439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35124947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali I., Iqbal M.N., Ibrahim M., Haq I.U., Alonazi W.B., Siddiqi A.R. Computational Exploration of Novel ROCK2 Inhibitors for Cardiovascular Disease Management; Insights from High-Throughput Virtual Screening, Molecular Docking, DFT and MD Simulation. PLoS ONE. 2023;18:e0294511. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0294511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0294511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10653426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37972144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Periwal V., Bassler S., Andrejev S., Gabrielli N., Patil K.R., Typas A., Patil K.R. Bioactivity Assessment of Natural Compounds Using Machine Learning Models Trained on Target Similarity between Drugs. PLoS Comput. Biol. 2022;18:e1010029. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1010029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1010029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9071136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35468126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran M., Panchal S., Chauhan V., Brahmbhatt N., Mevawalla A., Fraser R., Fowler M. Python-based Scikit-learn Machine Learning Models for Thermal and Electrical Performance Prediction of High-capacity Lithium-ion Battery. Int. J. Energy Res. 2022;46:786&#x2013;794. doi: 10.1002/er.7202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/er.7202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suyal M., Goyal P. A Review on Analysis of K-Nearest Neighbor Classification Machine Learning Algorithms Based on Supervised Learning. Int. J. Eng. Trends Technol. 2022;70:43&#x2013;48. doi: 10.14445/22315381/IJETT-V70I7P205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14445/22315381/IJETT-V70I7P205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadevi P., Das R. An Extensive Analysis of Machine Learning Techniques with Hyper-Parameter Tuning by Bayesian Optimized SVM Kernel for the Detection of Human Lung Disease. IEEE Access. 2024;12:97752&#x2013;97770. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3422449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3422449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y., Zhou X., Shen J., Xiao G., Hong H., Lin H., Wu F., Liao B.-Q. New Methods Based on Back Propagation (BP) and Radial Basis Function (RBF) Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) for Predicting the Occurrence of Haloketones in Tap Water. Sci. Total Environ. 2021;772:145534. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.145534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.145534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33571763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samad A., Ajmal A., Mahmood A., Khurshid B., Li P., Jan S.M., Rehman A.U., He P., Abdalla A.N., Umair M., et al. Identification of Novel Inhibitors for SARS-CoV-2 as Therapeutic Options Using Machine Learning-Based Virtual Screening, Molecular Docking and MD Simulation. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2023;10:1060076. doi: 10.3389/fmolb.2023.1060076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmolb.2023.1060076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10028080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36959979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL-Hadidi T.N., Hasoon S.O. Software Defect Prediction Using Extreme Gradient Boosting (XGBoost) with Optimization Hyperparameter. Al-Rafidain J. Comput. Sci. Math. 2024;18:22&#x2013;29. doi: 10.33899/csmj.2023.142739.1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33899/csmj.2023.142739.1081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brophy J., Hammoudeh Z., Lowd D. Adapting and Evaluating Influence-Estimation Methods for Gradient-Boosted Decision Trees. J. Mach. Learn. Res. 2023;24:1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauf A., Rashid U., Akram Z., Ghafoor M., Muhammad N., Al Masoud N., Alomar T.S., Naz S., Iriti M. In Vitro and in Silico Antiproliferative Potential of Isolated Flavonoids Constitutes from Pistacia Integerrima. Zeitschrift Fur Naturforsch.-Sect. C J. Biosci. 2024;79:187&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1515/znc-2023-0153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/znc-2023-0153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38549290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akshaya J., Rahul G., Karthigayan S.R., Rishekesan S.V., Harischander A., Kumar S.S., Soman K.P. Proceedings of the Journal of Physics: Conference Series. Volume 2484. IOP Publishing; Bristol, UK: 2023. A Comparison between Steepest Descent and Non-Linear Conjugate Gradient Algorithms for Binding Energy Minimization of Organic Molecules; p. 12004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondapuram S.K., Sarvagalla S., Coumar M.S. Molecular Docking for Computer-Aided Drug Design. Elsevier; Amsterdam, The Netherlands: 2021. Docking-Based Virtual Screening Using PyRx Tool: Autophagy Target Vps34 as a Case Study; pp. 463&#x2013;477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takio N., Basumatary D., Yadav M., Yadav H.S. Biochemistry: Fundamentals and Bioenergetics. Bentham Science Publishers; Sharjah, United Arab Emirates: 2021. Electrostatic and Van Der Waals Forces; pp. 55&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari P., Sharma P., Kumar M., Kapil A., Abdul Samath E., Kaur P. Identification of Novel Natural MurD Ligase Inhibitors as Potential Antimicrobial Agents Targeting Acinetobacter baumannii: In Silico Screening and Biological Evaluation. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2022;40:14051&#x2013;14066. doi: 10.1080/07391102.2021.2000497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07391102.2021.2000497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34766874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mou M., Zhang Y., Qian Y., Zhou Z., Liao Y., Niu T., Hu W., Chen Y., Jiang R., Zhao H. DruglikeFilter 1.0: An AI Powered Filter for Collectively Measuring the Drug-Likeness of Compounds. J. Pharm. Anal. 2025;15:101298. doi: 10.1016/j.jpha.2025.101298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpha.2025.101298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12268052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40678482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guterres H., Park S., Zhang H., Perone T., Kim J., Im W. CHARMM-GUI High-throughput Simulator for Efficient Evaluation of Protein&#x2013;Ligand Interactions with Different Force Fields. Protein Sci. 2022;31:e4413. doi: 10.1002/pro.4413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pro.4413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta A., Li Z., Song L.F., Li P., Merz K.M., Jr. Parameterization of Monovalent Ions for the OPC3, OPC, TIP3P-FB, and TIP4P-FB Water Models. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2021;61:869&#x2013;880. doi: 10.1021/acs.jcim.0c01390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.0c01390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Minkara M.S. Comparative Assessment of Water Models in Protein&#x2013;Glycan Interaction: Insights from Alchemical Free Energy Calculations and Molecular Dynamics Simulations. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2024;64:9459&#x2013;9473. doi: 10.1021/acs.jcim.4c01361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.4c01361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11684738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39378441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger-Hoerschinger V.J., Waibl F., Molino V., Carter H., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Quintero M., Ramsey S., Roe D.R., Liedl K.R., Gilson M.K., Kurtzman T. Quantifying Spatially Resolved Hydration Thermodynamics Using Grid Inhomogeneous Solvation Theory [v1. 0] Living J. Comput. Mol. Sci. 2025;6:3059. doi: 10.33011/livecoms.6.1.3059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33011/livecoms.6.1.3059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George A., Mondal S., Purnaprajna M., Athri P. Review of Electrostatic Force Calculation Methods and Their Acceleration in Molecular Dynamics Packages Using Graphics Processors. ACS Omega. 2022;7:32877&#x2013;32896. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.2c03189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.2c03189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9494432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36157750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J., Zheng K., Ren L., Cheng J., Feng X., Zhang R. Molecular Screening of Natural Compounds Targeting KRAS (G12C): A Multi-Parametric Strategy against Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia. J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2025;40:2568121. doi: 10.1080/14756366.2025.2568121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14756366.2025.2568121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12512771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41065364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dindo M., Metson J., Ren W., Chatzittofi M., Yagi K., Sugita Y., Golestanian R., Laurino P. Enzymes Can Activate and Mobilize the Cytoplasmic Environment across Scales. bioRxiv. 2025 doi: 10.1101/2025.01.28.635259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2025.01.28.635259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Yang H., Xue B., Liu T., Zhang X., Xu Y., Zhao X., Yue X. Investigating the Binding Mechanism of AML Inhibitors Based on Panobinostat with HDAC3 Proteins Using Gaussian Accelerated Molecular Dynamics. RSC Adv. 2025;15:26240&#x2013;26252. doi: 10.1039/D5RA01129A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5RA01129A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12284631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40703086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Villellas L., Mikkelsen C.C.K., Galano-Frutos J.J., Marco-Sola S., Alastruey-Bened&#xe9; J., Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez P., Echenique P., Moret&#xf3; M., De Rosa M.C., Garc&#xed;a-Risue&#xf1;o P. ILVES: Accurate and Efficient Bond Length and Angle Constraints in Molecular Dynamics. J. Chem. Theory Comput. 2025;21:8711&#x2013;8719. doi: 10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.5c01376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12461920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40905177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Zhang T., Kong C., Sun B., Zhu R. Application of Python-Based Abaqus Secondary Development in Laser Shock Forming of Aluminum Alloy 6082-T6. Micromachines. 2024;15:439. doi: 10.3390/mi15040439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mi15040439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11052170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38675251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelsattar A.S., Mansour Y., Aboul-ela F. The Perturbed Free-energy Landscape: Linking Ligand Binding to Biomolecular Folding. ChemBioChem. 2021;22:1499&#x2013;1516. doi: 10.1002/cbic.202000695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbic.202000695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaker B., Ahmad S., Lee J., Jung C., Na D. In Silico Methods and Tools for Drug Discovery. Comput. Biol. Med. 2021;137:104851. doi: 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34520990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chafiq M., Chaouiki A., Suhartono T., Ko Y.G. Albumin Protein Encapsulation into a ZIF-8 Framework with Co-LDH-Based Hierarchical Architectures for Robust Catalytic Reduction. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2023;11:23984&#x2013;23998. doi: 10.1039/D3TA03623E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3TA03623E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivaramakrishnan M., Kandaswamy K., Natesan S., Devarajan R.D., Ramakrishnan S.G., Kothandan R. Molecular Docking and Dynamics Studies on Plasmepsin V of Malarial Parasite Plasmodium Vivax. Inform. Med. Unlocked. 2020;19:100331. doi: 10.1016/j.imu.2020.100331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imu.2020.100331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil P.B., Kumbhar S.T. Identification of Potential CDK 8 Inhibitor from Pyrimidine Derivatives via In-Silico Approach. J. Med. Pharm. Allied Sci. 2023;12:6038&#x2013;6048. doi: 10.55522/jmpas.V12I5.4784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55522/jmpas.V12I5.4784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao W., Yang H., Zhou S., Huang F., Wei Z., Peng Z. Deoxythymidylate Kinase (DTYMK) Participates in Cell Cycle Arrest to Promote Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma Progression Regulated by MiR-491-5p through TP53 and Is Associated with Tumor Immune Infiltration. J. Gastrointest. Oncol. 2023;14:1546&#x2013;1559. doi: 10.21037/jgo-23-393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jgo-23-393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10331742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37435228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selva Sharma A., Viswadevarayalu A., Bharathi A.C., Anand K., Ali S., Li H., Ibrahim B.S., Chen Q. Unravelling the Distinctive Mode of Cooperative and Independent Interaction Mechanism of 1-Butyl-2,3-Dimethylimidazolium Tetrafluoroborate Ionic Liquid with Model Transport Proteins by Comprehensive Spectroscopic and Computational Studies. J. Mol. Struct. 2020;1205:127591. doi: 10.1016/j.molstruc.2019.127591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2019.127591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilla-Bernal G., Vargas R., Mart&#xed;nez A. Salt Bridge: Key Interaction between Antipsychotics and Receptors. Theor. Chem. Acc. 2023;142:65. doi: 10.1007/s00214-023-03016-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00214-023-03016-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miandad K., Ullah A., Bashir K., Khan S., Abideen S.A., Shaker B., Alharbi M., Alshammari A., Ali M., Haleem A., et al. Virtual Screening of Artemisia Annua Phytochemicals as Potential Inhibitors of SARS-CoV-2 Main Protease Enzyme. Molecules. 2022;27:8103. doi: 10.3390/molecules27228103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27228103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9695405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36432204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arango-Restrepo A., Rubi J.M. Thermodynamic Insights into Symmetry Breaking: Exploring Energy Dissipation across Diverse Scales. Entropy. 2024;26:231. doi: 10.3390/e26030231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e26030231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10969087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38539743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>