<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41832201</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ferroelectricity-modulated asymmetric van der Waals heterostructure for ultralow-power neuromorphic synapse and logic-in-memory operations.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70668-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vertical integration of two-dimensional materials holds tremendous potential for integrated sensing, memory, and computing applications, yet it still confronts challenges such as single device functionality, limited in-memory logic capability, and high power consumption. To address these issues, we propose an asymmetric van der Waals integration strategy based on an In&#x2082;Se&#x2083;/MoO&#x2093;/MoS&#x2082;/graphene heterojunction, which integrates five reconfigurable logic gates (AND, OR, NOT, NOR, and NAND), dual-mode photodetection (~10 fA dark current, a high responsivity of 89.3&#x2009;mA/W and a specific detectivity of 1.4&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10&#xb9;&#xb9;Jones), and low-power neurosynaptic functions (7-bit conductance states, subfemtojoule energy consumption) into a single device. By virtue of these characteristics, the device enables high-precision image recognition, simulation of classical Pavlovian conditioning and single-pixel dual-band optical imaging. This work paves a feasible path for the development of multifunctionally integrated sensor-memory-computing devices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhi</LastName><ForeName>Jiake</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3518-5394</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China. wenyao@whu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jiajie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Chuanyang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Shoufeng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Ruiqing</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3618-4759</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Shiheng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2133-2659</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physics, Hubei University, Wuhan, China. shihengliang@hubu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5998-5225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Artificial Micro- and Nano-structures of Ministry of Education, and School of Physical and Technology, Wuhan University, Wuhan, China. He-jun@whu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan Institute of Quantum Technology, Wuhan, China. He-jun@whu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Materials Science and Optoelectronics Engineering, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China. He-jun@whu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>92464303</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U23A20364</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62134001</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U25A20499</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>12274119</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41832201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70668-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70668-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pei, J. et al. Towards artificial general intelligence with hybrid Tianjic chip architecture. Nature 572, 106&#x2013;111 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J. et al. An integrated imaging sensor for aberration-corrected 3D photography. Nature 612, 62&#x2013;71 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, F. et al. Optoelectronic resistive random access memory for neuromorphic vision sensors. Nat. Nanotechnol. 14, 776&#x2013;782 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, Z. et al. Ionic-electronic photodetector for vision assistance with in-sensor image processing. Nat. Commun. 16, 7096 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. et al. Sub-pA dark current infrared photodetection enabled by polarized water-intercalated heterojunctions. Nat. Commun. 16, 3821 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. et al. High-order dynamics in an ultra-adaptive neuromorphic vision device. Nat. Nanotechnol. 20, 1419&#x2013;1430 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang, B. et al. Reconfigurable in-sensor processing based on a multi-phototransistor&#x2013;one-memristor array. Nat. Electron 7, 991&#x2013;1003 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. et al. In-sensor dynamic computing for intelligent machine vision. Nat. Electron 7, 225&#x2013;233 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. et al. Optically controlled memristor enabling synergistic sensing-memory-computing for neuromorphic vision systems. Adv. Mater. 38, e11411 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S. et al. Third-order nanocircuit elements for neuromorphic engineering. Nature 585, 518&#x2013;523 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, P. et al. Fully hardware-implemented memristor convolutional neural network. Nature 577, 641&#x2013;646 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. Power-efficient neural network with artificial dendrites. Nat. Nanotechnol. 15, 776&#x2013;782 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, F. et al. A fully integrated reprogrammable memristor&#x2013;CMOS system for efficient multiply&#x2013;accumulate operations. Nat. Electron 2, 290&#x2013;299 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan, P. M. et al. Sparse coding with memristor networks. Nat. Nanotechnol. 12, 784&#x2013;789 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. et al. Scalable massively parallel computing using continuous-time data representation in nanoscale crossbar array. Nat. Nanotechnol. 16, 1079&#x2013;1085 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, F. &amp; Chai, Y. Near-sensor and in-sensor computing. Nat. Electron 3, 664&#x2013;671 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C.-Y. et al. Gate-tunable van der Waals heterostructure for reconfigurable neural network vision sensor. Sci. Adv. 6, eaba6173 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, C. et al. Intelligent infrared sensing enabled by tunable moir&#xe9; quantum geometry. Nature 604, 266&#x2013;272 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. All-in-one two-dimensional retinomorphic hardware device for motion detection and recognition. Nat. Nanotechnol. 17, 27&#x2013;32 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, T. et al. In-sensor computing: materials, devices, and integration technologies. Adv. Mater. 35, 2203830 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudek, P. et al. Sensor-level computer vision with pixel processor arrays for agile robots. Sci. Robot 7, eabl7755 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mennel, L. et al. Ultrafast machine vision with 2D material neural network image sensors. Nature 579, 62&#x2013;66 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. et al. Programmable black phosphorus image sensor for broadband optoelectronic edge computing. Nat. Commun. 13, 1485 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, L. et al. In-sensor reservoir computing for language learning via two-dimensional memristors. Sci. Adv. 7, eabg1455 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, K. et al. An optoelectronic synapse based on &#x3b1;-In<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>3</sub> with controllable temporal dynamics for multimode and multiscale reservoir computing. Nat. Electron 5, 761&#x2013;773 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J. et al. Optoelectronic graded neurons for bioinspired in-sensor motion perception. Nat. Nanotechnol. 18, 882&#x2013;888 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, X. et al. Multifunctional logic gates via coexistent positive and negative photoconductivity of a single Bi2Se3 photodetector. Adv. Mater. 37, 2416934 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, W. et al. Achieving entire seven fundamental Boolean logic operations in a two-terminal Li-based memristor. ACS Appl. Electron Mater. 6, 9194&#x2013;9202 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, X. et al. Gate and bias voltage-modulation photodetector based on Cs3Bi2Br9 for multifunctional optoelectronic logic gate. Adv. Funct. Mater. 35, 2502415 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z.-A. et al. In-pixel dual-band intercorrelated compressive sensing based on MoS<sub>2</sub>/h-BN/PdSe<sub>2</sub> vertical heterostructure. ACS Nano 19, 6263&#x2013;6270 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der, J. et al. Organic permeable base transistors for high-performance photodetection with photo-memory effect. Nat. Photonics 19, 1088&#x2013;1098 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Ultrafast self-driven WSe<sub>2</sub> photodetectors with bottom Schottky contacts. Adv. Sci. 12, e10373 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, T. et al. Neuromorphic transistors integrating photo-sensor, optical memory and visual synapses for artificial vision application. Adv. Mater. 37, 2419208 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Y. et al. Intrinsic defect-driven synergistic synaptic heterostructures for gate-free neuromorphic phototransistors. Adv. Mater. 36, 2309940 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, B. et al. Artificial visual systems fabricated with ferroelectric van der Waals heterostructure for in-memory computing applications. ACS Nano 17, 21297&#x2013;21306 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, S. et al. A hyperconformal dual-modal metaskin for well-defined and high-precision contextual interactions. Nat. Commun. 16, 10573 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. A stable rhombohedral phase in ferroelectric Hf<sub>(Zr)1+xO2</sub> capacitor with ultralow coercive field. Science 381, 558&#x2013;563 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Phase-engineered In<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>3</sub> ferroelectric P-N junctions in phototransistors for ultra-low power and multiscale reservoir computing. ACS Nano 19, 13220&#x2013;13229 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, H. et al. Enhanced giant ferroelectric tunneling electroresistance in 2D Ruddlesden&#x2013;popper oxides. ACS Nano 19, 33256&#x2013;33267 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y. et al. Stacking selected polarization switching and phase transition in vdW ferroelectric &#x3b1;-In<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>3</sub> junction devices. Nat. Commun. 15, 10481 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. et al. A spatiotemporal-specific artificial neuron based on In2Se3 ferroelectric memristor for adaptable information processing. InfoMat 7, e70047 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Y. et al. 2D ferroelectric narrow-bandgap semiconductor Wurtzite&#x2019; type &#x3b1;-In<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>3</sub> and its silicon-compatible growth. Nat. Commun. 16, 7364 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, C. et al. Ferroelectricity-driven strain-mediated magnetoelectric coupling in two-dimensional multiferroic heterostructure. Nat. Commun. 16, 10664 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, C. et al. Non-volatile electric-field control of room-temperature ferromagnetism in Fe<sub>3</sub>GaTe<sub>2</sub> heterostructures. Nat. Commun. 16, 6797 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y.-Z. et al. The tunneling electroresistance effect in a van der Waals ferroelectric tunnel junction based on a graphene/In<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>3</sub>/MoS<sub>2</sub>/graphene heterostructure. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 25, 48 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, Y. et al. 12-inch growth of uniform MoS<sub>2</sub> monolayer for integrated circuit manufacture. Nat. Mater. 22, 1324&#x2013;1331 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. et al. Flexible optical synapses based on In<sub>2</sub>Se<sub>3</sub>/MoS<sub>2</sub> heterojunctions for artificial vision systems in the near-infrared range. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 14, 55839&#x2013;55849 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huh, W. et al. Heterosynaptic MoS<sub>2</sub> memtransistors emulating biological neuromodulation for energy-efficient neuromorphic electronics. Adv. Mater. 35, 2211525 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ci, W. et al. Engineering ferroelectric-/ion-modulated conductance in 2D vdW CuInP<sub>2</sub>S<sub>6</sub> for non-volatile digital memory and artificial synapse. Adv. Funct. Mater. 34, 2316360 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, M. et al. Flexoelectric thin-film photodetectors. Nano Lett. 21, 2946&#x2013;2952 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang, Z. et al. Black phosphorus/ferroelectric P(VDF-TrFE) field-effect transistors with high mobility for energy-efficient artificial synapse in high-accuracy neuromorphic computing. Nano Lett. 23, 6752&#x2013;6759 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon, J. et al. Environmentally stable and reconfigurable ultralow-power two-dimensional tellurene synaptic transistor for neuromorphic edge computing. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 15, 18463&#x2013;18472 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. et al. Ultra-low power and Robust Bi<sub>2</sub>SeO<sub>5</sub> films optoelectronic memristors for bio-visual perception computing systems. Adv. Mater. 37, 2509174 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, H. et al. A low-power vertical dual-gate neurotransistor with short-term memory for high energy-efficient neuromorphic computing. Nat. Commun. 14, 6385 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>