<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41645985</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2583-150X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Nov-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The National medical journal of India</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Natl Med J India</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Perceptions of doctors, medical students, and patients on the use of smartphones and digital devices in patient care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>339</StartPage><EndPage>343</EndPage><MedlinePgn>339-343</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/NMJI_364_2023</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/NMJI_364_2023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Integration of smart mobile devices (SMD) like smartphones and digital tablets into medical practice continues to be hindered despite the benefits of access to guidelines at the point of care and patient safety. The barriers include administrator attitudes, perceptions about how patients would receive it, shyness about accessing it in the presence of coworkers, and perceived attrition in medical education. We aimed to understand the perceptions of doctors, medical students, and patients about the use of SMDs in patient care areas. Methods A cross-sectional survey of doctors, medical students, and patients across multiple states in India was conducted. Data were collected using a validated questionnaire after ethical clearance and participant consent. A sample size of 385 was estimated for each group (95% confidence interval, alpha error 0.5, power 80%). Results 406 doctors, 425 medical students, and 418 patients responded to the survey. 92% doctors, 96% medical students, and 57% patients owned an SMD. 81% doctors had used an SMD for patient care, with a little over 50% having used it in front of their juniors, and only 34% approved the use in patient contact areas. 99% medical students used SMD for studying; 93% advocated it to their juniors for learning, but only 68% used it in front of their juniors, and 29% in front of their patients. About 90% patients were ready for doctors to use SMDs in front of them, with over 75% agreeing that SMD use will lead to better and safer care. Conclusions SMDs are widely used in the patient care area and for medical education. Some perceived barriers such as patient perceptions about doctors require behavioural change and acceptance of changing times.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sagar</LastName><ForeName>Anubha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Himalayan Institute of Medical Sciences, Jolly Grant, Dehradun, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Anmol</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Base Hospital Delhi Cantt, Brar Square, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sagar</LastName><ForeName>Amitabh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Acute Medicine, Lincoln County Hospital, ULHT NHS, Greetwell Road, Lincoln LN25QY, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pathak</LastName><ForeName>Abhishek</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Command Hospital Eastern Command, Kolkata, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Natl Med J India</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8809315</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0970-258X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013337" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students, Medical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068997" MajorTopicYN="Y">Smartphone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010820" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physicians</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001291" MajorTopicYN="Y">Attitude of Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005791" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D034201" MajorTopicYN="Y">Computers, Handheld</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010361" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patients</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41645985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25259/NMJI_364_2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.25259/NMJI_364_2023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title/><Reference><Citation>Abolfotouh MA, Banimustafa A, Salam M, Al-Assiri M, Aldebasi B, Bushnak I, et al. Use of smartphone and perception towards the usefulness and practicality of its medical applications among healthcare workers in Saudi Arabia. BMC Health Serv Res. 2019; 19:826</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karan A, Negandhi H, Hussain S, Zapata T, Mairembam D, De Graeve H, et al. Size, composition and distribution of health workforce in India: Why, and where to invest?. Hum Resour Health. 2021; 19:39</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Pal R,. India achieves WHO recommended doctor population ratio: A call for paradigm shift in public health discourse. J Family Med Prim Care. 2018; 7:841-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short SS, Lin AC, Merinos DJ,. Smartphones, trainees, and mobile education: Implications for graduate medical education. J Grad Med Educ. 2014; 6:199-202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothschild JM, Fang E, Liu V,. Use and perceived benefits of handheld computer-based clinical references. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2006; 13:619-26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace S, Clark M, White J,. 'It's on my iPhone': Attitudes to the use of mobile computing devices in medical education, a mixed-methods study. BMJ Open. 2012; 2:e001099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter C, Carroll JA, Keogh B, Vandelanotte C,. Assessment of mobile health apps using built-in smartphone sensors for diagnosis and treatment: Systematic survey of apps listed in international curated health app libraries. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020; 8:e16741</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne KFB, Wharrad H, Watts K,. Smartphone and medical related app use among medical students and junior doctors in the United Kingdom: A regional survey. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2012; 12:121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flannigan C, McAloon J,. Students prescribing emergency drug infusions utilising smartphones outperform consultants using BNFCs. Resuscitation. 2011; 82:1424-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berner ES, Houston TK, Ray MN,. Improving ambulatory prescribing safety with a handheld decision support system: A randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2006; 13:171-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Evidence standards framework for digital health technologies [ECD7]. London NICE: 2018; Available at www.nice.org.uk/corporate/ecd7/resources/evidence-standards-framework-for-digital-health-technologies-user-guide-9024813901/chapter/what-are-digital-health-technologies (accessed on 9 May 2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulos MN, Wheeler S, Tavares C, Jones R,. How smartphones are changing the face of mobile and participatory healthcare: An overview, with example from eCAALYX. Biomed Eng Online. 2011; 10:24</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerry G, Gokani S, Rasasingam D, Zargaran A, Ash J, Mittal A, et al. Patient perception of smartphone usage by doctors. Smart Homecare Technol Telehealth. 2017; 4:31-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolarinde SO, Olasoji OB, Daniel IO,. Perception of patients on usage of smartphones by health care professionals during clinic hours. Int J Multidiscip Res Anal. 2021; 4:692-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alameddine M, Tamim H, Hadid D, Cheaito MA, Makki M, Maatouk H, et al. Patient attitudes toward mobile device use by health care providers in the emergency department: Cross-sectional survey. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020; 8:e16917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R, Bakshi H, Kumar P,. Competency-based undergraduate curriculum: A critical view. Indian J Community Med. 2019; 44:77-80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Medical Commission (Undergraduate Medical Education Board). Implementation of new competency-based medical education for undergraduate course curriculum (U11026/1/2022-UGMEB). New Delhi NMC: 2022; Available at www.nmc.org.in/MCIRest/open/getDocument?path=/Documents/Public/Portal/LatestNews/Implementation.pdf (accessed on 9 May 2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le&#xf3;n SA, Fontelo P, Green L, Ackerman M, Liu F,. Evidence-based medicine among internal medicine residents in a community hospital program using smartphones. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2007; 7:5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Communications, Government of India. Year end review 2022: Ministry of Communications. New Delhi: PIB; 16 Dec 2022. Available at pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1884072 (accessed on 9 May 2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telecom Regulatory Authority of India. Highlights of telecom subscription data as on 30 June 2021 [Press release]. New Delhi TRAI: 23 Aug 2021. Available at www.trai.gov.in/sites/default/files/PR_No.37of2021_0.pdf (accessed on 9 May 2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brahmapurkar KP, Zodpey SP, Sabde YD, Brahmapurkar VK,. The need to focus on medical education in rural districts of India. Natl Med J India. 2018; 31:164-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabde Y, Diwan V, Mahadik VK, Parashar V, Negandhi H, Trushna T, et al. Medical schools in India: Pattern of establishment and impact on public health-a geographic information system-based exploratory study. BMC Public Health. 2020; 20:755</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma V,. How Byju's is uplifting its tech game. Econ Times CIO 2021 Dec 30. Available at cio.economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/strategy-andmanagement/how-byjus-is-uplifting-its-tech-game/88579515 (accessed on 9 May 2023)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>