<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41388694</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Utilization of Diamagnetic Force Introduced by External Magnetic Fields for Printing Scalable Organic Photovoltaics.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e20583</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e20583</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202520583</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The photovoltaic performance and stability of scalable organic solar cells (OSCs) are significantly governed by the micromorphology, molecular interactions, and stacking behavior of the active layer. As the device area increases, these effects are amplified, making long-range morphological control of small-molecule acceptors challenging and frequently leading to performance degradation. Herein, a non-contact and size-insensitive magnetic-field-assisted printing strategy is developed, which modulates the chemical environment of molecular end groups during film formation and enhances intermolecular interactions, thereby regulating the molecular stacking behavior. These collectively improve the film homogeneity, reduce the defect density, and minimize the performance loss in large-area devices. Finally, the optimal pseudo-planar heterojunction OSCs, fabricated via air atmosphere printing, achieve a champion power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 20.23%. Furthermore, large-area binary modules with an aperture area of 25.00 cm<sup>2</sup> retain an optimized PCE of 16.70%, underscoring their strong potential for scalable production. Overall, this work proposes a universal approach for printing high-quality photoactive films and provides a valuable framework for the collaborative optimization of organic electronic devices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering/Film Energy Chemistry for Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory (FEC)/Institute of Polymers and Energy Chemistry (IPEC), Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering/Film Energy Chemistry for Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory (FEC)/Institute of Polymers and Energy Chemistry (IPEC), Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chenzhuo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering/Film Energy Chemistry for Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory (FEC)/Institute of Polymers and Energy Chemistry (IPEC), Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Photochemical Conversion and Optoelectronic Materials, Technical Institute of Physics and Chemistry, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100190, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Junjiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, State Key Laboratory of Advanced Materials for Intelligent Sensing, Key Laboratory of Organic Integrated Circuits, Ministry of Education, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Molecular Optoelectronic Sciences, Collaborative Innovation Center of Chemical Science and Engineering, Tianjin University, Tianjin, 300072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Fluorine and Silicon for Energy Materials and Chemistry of Ministry of Education, Jiangxi Normal University, 99 Ziyang Avenue, Nanchang, 330022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Qianyong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering/Film Energy Chemistry for Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory (FEC)/Institute of Polymers and Energy Chemistry (IPEC), Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Long</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, State Key Laboratory of Advanced Materials for Intelligent Sensing, Key Laboratory of Organic Integrated Circuits, Ministry of Education, Tianjin Key Laboratory of Molecular Optoelectronic Sciences, Collaborative Innovation Center of Chemical Science and Engineering, Tianjin University, Tianjin, 300072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Zengqi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Fluorine and Silicon for Energy Materials and Chemistry of Ministry of Education, Jiangxi Normal University, 99 Ziyang Avenue, Nanchang, 330022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering/Film Energy Chemistry for Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory (FEC)/Institute of Polymers and Energy Chemistry (IPEC), Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peking University Yangtze Delta Institute of Optoelectronics, Nantong, 226010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Xiangchuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering/Film Energy Chemistry for Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory (FEC)/Institute of Polymers and Energy Chemistry (IPEC), Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yiwang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4709-7623</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering/Film Energy Chemistry for Jiangxi Provincial Key Laboratory (FEC)/Institute of Polymers and Energy Chemistry (IPEC), Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peking University Yangtze Delta Institute of Optoelectronics, Nantong, 226010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20252BAC200630</GrantID><Agency>Jiangxi Provincial Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52333006</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52527804</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52463021</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52203311</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>gpyc20250038</GrantID><Agency>"Ganpo Talent Plan" Innovation Leading Talent Project of Jiangxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>20243BCE51134</GrantID><Agency>Training Plan for Academic and Technical Leaders of Major Disciplines in Jiangxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025_000862</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Innovation Team in Key Fields of Jiujiang</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diamagnetic repulsive force</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">film homogeneity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intermolecular interactions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic&#x2010;field&#x2010;assisted printing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organic solar cells</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41388694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202520583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>B. Du, S. Xiong, L. Sun, Y. Tagawa, D. Inoue, D. Hashizume, W. Wang, R. Guo, T. Yokota, S. Wang, Y. Ishida, S. Lee, K. Fukuda, T. Someya, Sci. Adv. 2024, 10, adp2679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, X. Huang, H. K. M. Sheriff, S. R. Forrest, Nat. Rev. Mater. 2022, 8, 186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wang, S. Liu, H. Li, M. Li, X. Wu, S. Zhang, L. Ye, X. Hu, Y. Chen, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2313098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Chen, S. Liu, X. Hu, F. Wu, J. Liu, K. Zhou, L. Ye, L. Chen, Y. Chen, Sci. China Chem. 2021, 65, 182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, Y. Ochiai, N. Wu, K. Adachi, D. Inoue, D. Hashizume, D. Kong, N. Matsuhisa, T. Yokota, Q. Wu, W. Ma, L. Sun, S. Xiong, B. Du, W. Wang, C. J. Shih, K. Tajima, T. Aida, K. Fukuda, T. Someya, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 4902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Chen, J. Ge, W. Song, X. Tong, H. Liu, X. Yu, J. Li, J. Shi, L. Xie, C. Han, Q. Liu, Z. Ge, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2406690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Zhu, M. Zhang, G. Zhou, Z. Wang, W. Zhong, J. Zhuang, Z. Zhou, X. Gao, L. Kan, B. Hao, F. Han, R. Zeng, X. Xue, S. Xu, H. Jing, B. Xiao, H. Zhu, Y. Zhang, F. Liu, Joule 2024, 8, 3153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Jiang, S. Sun, R. Xu, F. Liu, X. Miao, G. Ran, K. Liu, Y. Yi, W. Zhang, Z. Zhu, Nat. Energy 2024, 9, 930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Li, J. Song, H. Lai, H. Zhang, R. Zhou, J. Xu, H. Huang, L. Liu, J. Gao, Y. Li, M. H. Jee, Z. Zheng, S. Liu, J. Yan, X. K. Chen, Z. Tang, C. Zhang, H. Y. Woo, F. He, F. Gao, H. Yan, Y. Sun, Nat. Mater. 2025, 24, 433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Deng, W. Li, R. Zeng, J. Song, S. Tan, L. Kan, Z. Qin, Y. Zhao, F. Liu, Y. Sun, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2501243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Xu, J. Han, M. Babics, L. Huerta Hernandez, D. Rosas Villalva, M. Sanviti, J. Bertrandie, Y. Zhang, Y. Liu, H. Chen, L. Zhao, J. Troughton, J. Martin, F. Laquai, S. De Wolf, D. Baran, Nat. Photonics 2025, 19, 415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cheng, C. Guo, L. Wang, Y. Fu, D. Li, C. Chen, Z. Gan, Y. Sun, D. Liu, W. Li, T. Wang, Joule 2024, 8, 2250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Gan, L. Wang, J. Cai, C. Guo, C. Chen, D. Li, Y. Fu, B. Zhou, Y. Sun, C. Liu, J. Zhou, D. Liu, W. Li, T. Wang, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 6297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Cui, J. Qiao, Y. Xu, Z. Fu, R. Gui, C. Zhang, R. Zhou, L. Ye, X. Du, F. Chen, X. Hao, H. Yan, H. Yin, Sci. Adv. 2024, 10, adp2679.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Zhang, W. Chen, J. Zhang, H. Mao, X. Gu, Z. Qin, D. Luo, L. Zhang, Y. Chen, Sci. China Mater. 2025, 68, 2264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Chen, R. Zhang, X. Chen, G. Zeng, L. Kobera, S. Abbrent, B. Zhang, W. Chen, G. Xu, J. Oh, S.&#x2010;H. Kang, S. Chen, C. Yang, J. Brus, J. Hou, F. Gao, Y. Li, Y. Li, Nat. Energy 2021, 6, 1045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Lu, C. Xie, Y. Liu, H. Zheng, K. Feng, Z. Xiong, W. Wei, Y. Zhou, Nat. Energy 2024, 9, 793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Zhang, W. Chen, H. Chen, G. Zeng, R. Zhang, H. Li, Y. Wang, X. Gu, W. Sun, H. Gu, F. Gao, Y. Li, Y. Li, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 2935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Li, N. Deng, Y. Fu, C. Guo, B. Zhou, L. Wang, J. Zhou, D. Liu, W. Li, K. Wang, Y. Sun, T. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2208211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Song, C. Zhang, C. Li, J. Qiao, J. Yu, J. Gao, X. Wang, X. Hao, Z. Tang, G. Lu, R. Yang, H. Yan, Y. Sun, Angew Chem. Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202404297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. He, X. Li, J. Zhang, Z. Chen, Y. Gong, H. Zhuo, X. Wu, Y. Li, S. Wang, Z. Bi, B. Song, K. Zhou, T. Liang, W. Ma, G. Lu, L. Ye, L. Meng, B. Zhang, Y. Li, Y. Li, Nat. Commun. 2025, 16, 787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Wupur, Y. Li, Y. Luo, T. Chen, M. Wang, Y. Zhang, Z. X. Liu, H. Wu, H. Tan, Q. Zhang, X. Sun, H. Hu, X. Li, J. Wu, W. Fu, W. Qiu, X. Yang, H. Chen, Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2403132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. He, Z. X. Liu, H. Chen, C. Li, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2306681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Xie, C. Zhou, X. Ma, S. Y. Jeong, H. Y. Woo, F. Huang, Y. Yang, H. Yu, J. Li, F. Zhang, K. Wang, X. Zhu, Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2400013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, W. Wang, F. Dong, Z. Zhang, L. Han, X. Luo, J. Huang, Z. Feng, Z. Chen, G. Jia, T. Zhang, ACS Catal. 2011, 11, 4739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Yang, L. Lan, L. Li, X. Liu, P. Naumov, H. Zhang, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 2322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Mori, K. Mori, T. Mizutani, Thin Solid Films 2001, 393, 143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Wang, C. Yi, C. Liu, X. Hu, S. Chuang, X. Gong, Sci. Rep. 2015, 5, 9265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. W. Majewski, M. Gopinadhan, C. O. Osuji, J. Polym. Sci. Pol. Phys. 2011, 50, 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhao, B. Hou, C. Liu, X. Ji, Y. Huang, J. Sui, D. Liu, N. Wang, H. Hao, Ind. Eng. Chem. Res 2021, 60, 15741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Potticary, C. L. Hall, R. Guo, S. L. Price, S. R. Hall, Cryst. Growth Des. 2021, 21, 6254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. J. Comeau, R. R. Cranston, H. R. Lamontagne, A. J. Shuhendler, B. H. Lessard, Small 2023, 19, 2206792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Pan, F. Chen, L. Hu, K. Zhang, J. Dai, F. Zhang, Adv. Funct. Materi. 2015, 25, 5126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Kimura, Polym. J. 2003, 35, 823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. R. Graham, C. Cabanetos, J. P. Jahnke, M. N. Idso, A. El Labban, G. O. Ngongang Ndjawa, T. Heumueller, K. Vandewal, A. Salleo, B. F. Chmelka, A. Amassian, P. M. Beaujuge, M. D. McGehee, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2014, 136, 9608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Du, M. Mainville, J. Vollbrecht, A. L. Dixon, N. Schopp, M. Schrock, Z. Peng, J. Huang, S. Chae, H. Ade, M. Leclerc, G. N. M. Reddy, T.&#x2010;Q. Nguyen, Sol. RRL 2021, 5, 2100213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. R. Luginbuhl, P. Raval, T. Pawlak, Z. Du, T. Wang, G. Kupgan, N. Schopp, S. Chae, S. Yoon, A. Yi, H. Jung Kim, V. Coropceanu, J. L. Bredas, T. Q. Nguyen, G. N. M. Reddy, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2105943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Fu, L. Xu, Y. Li, E. J. Yang, Y. Guo, G. Cai, P. F. Chan, Y. Ke, C.&#x2010;J. Su, U. S. Jeng, P. C. Y. Chow, J.&#x2010;S. Kim, M.&#x2010;C. Tang, X. Lu, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 8893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Zhang, X. K. Chen, J. Xiao, P. C. Y. Chow, M. Ren, G. Kupgan, X. Jiao, C. C. S. Chan, X. Du, R. Xia, Z. Chen, J. Yuan, Y. Zhang, S. Zhang, Y. Liu, Y. Zou, H. Yan, K. S. Wong, V. Coropceanu, N. Li, C. J. Brabec, J. L. Bredas, H. L. Yip, Y. Cao, Nat. Commun. 2020, 11, 3943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yan, S. Zhao, Y. Zhang, T. Wang, Y. Shi, D. Qiu, J. Zhang, L. Zhu, M. Wang, J. Qiao, X. Hao, X. Zhang, Z. Wei, Sol. RRL 2023, 7, 2300342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Gong, Q. Yan, Z. Xing, H. Wang, L. Tan, X. Meng, X. Hu, Y. Chen, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2501033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Chen, L. Wang, W. Xia, K. Qiu, C. Guo, Z. Gan, J. Zhou, Y. Sun, D. Liu, W. Li, T. Wang, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 6865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Chen, F. Ye, J. Lai, P. Dai, S. Lu, C. Ma, Y. Zhao, Y. Xie, L. Chen, Nano Energy 2017, 40, 454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Xiao, Y. Meng, L. Tang, P. Li, L. Tang, W. Zhang, B. Hu, F. Yi, T. Jia, J. Cao, C. Xu, G. Lu, X. Hao, W. Ma, Q. Fan, Adv. Funct.Mater. 2023, 34, 2311216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Sun, H. Ma, S. Yang, Y. Cho, S. Lee, J. Park, T. L. H. Mai, W. Kim, S. Jeong, S. Kim, C. Yang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2403093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Wang, X. Ma, Y.&#x2010;f. Shen, D. Deng, H. Zhang, T. Wang, J. Zhang, J. Li, R. Wang, L. Zhang, Q. Cheng, Z. Zhang, H. Zhou, C. Tian, Z. Wei, Joule 2023, 7, 2386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Liu, B. Liu, C.&#x2010;Q. Ma, F. Huang, G. Feng, H. Chen, J. Hou, L. Yan, Q. Wei, Q. Luo, Q. Bao, W. Ma, W. Liu, W. Li, X. Wan, X. Hu, Y. Han, Y. Li, Y. Zhou, Y. Zou, Y. Chen, Y. Liu, L. Meng, Y. Li, Y. Chen, Z. Tang, Z. Hu, Z.&#x2010;G. Zhang, Z. Bo, Sci.China Chem. 2022, 65, 1457.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>