<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41667530</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AI based optimization of injection pressure for hydrogen and spirogyra biodiesel dual fuel engine to enhance combustion performance and emission characteristics.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8017</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34179-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The principal objective of this research is to employ modern machine learning techniques to optimize high-pressure biofuel injection strategies for sustainable energy applications. An engine powered with biofuel and hydrogen (H&#x2082;) under dual-fuel (DF) mode was tested under a varied fuel injection pressure range from 180 to 240&#xa0;bar for optimization and modeling. The results demonstrate that an injection pressure of 220&#xa0;bar produces enhanced engine performance. At this pressure, enhancements were noted in combustion characteristics, efficiency, and emission levels. The ignition delay (ID) at 220&#xa0;bar injection pressure was 9.4% longer than at 240&#xa0;bar injection pressure. The 220&#xa0;bar IP mix demonstrated reduced peak cylinder pressure (PCP) and heat release rate (HRR) compared to the 240&#xa0;bar. A 12.4% rise in brake-specific fuel consumption (BSFC) was observed at 220&#xa0;bar inlet pressure. Nevertheless, although brake thermal efficiency (BTE) increased with increasing injection pressure (IP), the increase at 220&#xa0;bar was somewhat less than that at 240&#xa0;bar. Despite elevated nitrogen oxide (NOx) emissions with the 220 bars compared to pure diesel, carbon monoxide (CO) and hydrocarbon (HC) emissions were markedly decreased. Smoke emissions were reduced with the 220 bars in comparison to diesel and other fuel combinations. Three machine learning models were employed to establish a predictive control framework. The decision tree (DT) model had the greatest accuracy, with R&#xb2; values of 0.9792 for PCP and 0.9710 for HC, alongside near-zero MAPE for BTE and HC This study underscores the potential of AI-driven biofuel optimization for fostering sustainable transportation and renewable fuel strategies, paving the way for large-scale adoption of low-carbon, high-efficiency energy solutions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aravind</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Karpagam Academy of Higher Education, Coimbatore, 641021, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barik</LastName><ForeName>Debabrata</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Karpagam Academy of Higher Education, Coimbatore, 641021, India. debabrata.barik@kahedu.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Energy and Environment, Karpagam Academy of Higher Education, Coimbatore, 641021, India. debabrata.barik@kahedu.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paramasivam</LastName><ForeName>Prabhu</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Research Impact and Outcome, Chitkara University, Rajpura, Punjab, 140401, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balasubramanian</LastName><ForeName>Dhinesh</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Port Engineering, Lithuanian Maritime Academy (LMA), Vilnius Gediminas Technical University, Klaip&#x117;da, Lithuania. dhinesh.balasubramanian@vilniustech.lt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kale</LastName><ForeName>Utku</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Aeronautics and Naval Architecture, Faculty of Transportation Engineering and Vehicle Engineering, Budapest University of Technology and Economics, M&#x171;egyetem rkp. 3., Budapest, H-1111, Hungary. kale.utku@kjk.bme.hu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Science Institute, Vilnius Gediminas Technical University, Plytin&#x117;s g. 25, Vilnius, 10105, Lithuania. kale.utku@kjk.bme.hu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kilikevi&#x10d;ius</LastName><ForeName>Art&#x16b;ras</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Science Institute, Vilnius Gediminas Technical University, Plytin&#x117;s g. 25, Vilnius, 10105, Lithuania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-Driven calibration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eco-Friendly fuel optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrogen energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning for biofuels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renewable energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable biofuels</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41667530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12957473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34179-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34179-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jain, A. et al. Impact of titanium dioxide (TiO2) nanoparticles addition in Eichhornia crassipes biodiesel used to fuel compression ignition engine at variable injection pressure. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i> 49. 10.1016/j.csite.2023.103295 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamrat, S., Ancha, V. R., Gopal, R., Nallamothu, R. B. &amp; Seifu, Y. Emission and performance analysis of diesel engine running with CeO2 nanoparticle additive blended into castor oil biodiesel as a substitute fuel. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 7634. 10.1038/s41598-024-58420-0 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-58420-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10985105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38561406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezki, B. et al. A comprehensive review on apatite-derived catalysts for sustainable biodiesel production: Classification, features and challenges. <i>J. Environ. Chem. Eng.</i> 12. 10.1016/j.jece.2024.111913 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohite, A. et al. Optimization of the pilot fuel injection and engine load for an algae biodiesel - hydrogen run dual fuel diesel engine using response surface methodology. Fuel 2024;357. 10.1016/j.fuel.2023.129841</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paramasivam, P. et al. Machine learning based prognostics and statistical optimization of the performance of biogas-biodiesel blends powered engine. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i><b>61</b>, 105116. 10.1016/j.csite.2024.105116 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2024.105116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismael, M. A. et al. The effect of fuel injection equipment on the dispersed phase of water-in-diesel emulsions. <i>Appl. Energy</i> 2018;222. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2018.03.070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthuswamy, S. &amp; Veerasigamani, M. Comparative experimental analysis on dual fuel with biodiesel-acetylene in reactivity controlled compression ignition engine. <i>Int. J. Ambient Energy</i>. <b>43</b>10.1080/01430750.2021.2014958 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SoudagarMEM et al. Study of diesel engine characteristics by adding nanosized zinc oxide and diethyl ether additives in Mahua biodiesel&#x2013;diesel fuel blend. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>10</b>10.1038/s41598-020-72150-z (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32948806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fodah, A. E. M. &amp; Abdelwahab, T. A. M. Process optimization and technoeconomic environmental assessment of biofuel produced by solar powered microwave pyrolysis. <i>Sci. Rep.</i> 12. 10.1038/s41598-022-16171-w (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., Prabhahar, M. &amp; Venkatesh, R. Performance and emission characteristics of chlorella algae Methyl ester fuelled diesel engine with varying injection pressure. <i>Int. J. Innovative Technol. Exploring Eng.</i><b>9</b>10.35940/ijitee.A5176.119119 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajak, U., Nashine, P. &amp; Verma, T. N. Effect of fuel injection pressure of microalgae spirulina biodiesel blends on engine characteristics. <i>J. Comput. Appl. Res. Mech. Eng.</i><b>11</b>, 113&#x2013;125. 10.22061/JCARME.2019.4767.1578 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22061/JCARME.2019.4767.1578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatikonda, N. C. &amp; Naveenchandran, D. P. An experimental assessment on the impact of injection pressure on the characteristics of a diesel engine powered with the blend of diesel and microalgae biodiesel. <i>Int. J. Eng. Adv. Technol.</i><b>8</b>, 3284&#x2013;3291. 10.35940/ijeat.F9500.088619 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35940/ijeat.F9500.088619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvaraj, K. &amp; Thangavel, M. The effects of fuel injection pressure on combustion and emission characteristics of a diesel engine using frying oil Methyl ester. <i>Energy Sources Part. A: Recovery Utilization Environ. Eff.</i><b>00</b>, 1&#x2013;17. 10.1080/15567036.2019.1675818 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15567036.2019.1675818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A., Singh, Y. &amp; Kumar, N. A. Effect of fuel injection pressure and timing on Polanga (Calophyllum Inophyllum) biodiesel blends for engine performance and emissions analysis. <i>Energy Sources Part. A: Recovery Utilization Environ. Eff.</i><b>41</b>, 3046&#x2013;3057. 10.1080/15567036.2019.1583696 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15567036.2019.1583696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutyalu, K. B., Das, V. C. &amp; Srinivasa Rao, K. Experimental investigation on characteristics of Di-Ci engine fueled with Shea Olein biodiesel. <i>Int. J. Mech. Eng. Technol.</i> ;<b>9</b>. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sar&#x131;demir, S., Etem G&#xfc;rel, A., A&#x11f;bulut, &#xdc;. &amp; Bakan, F. Investigating the role of fuel injection pressure change on performance characteristics of a DI-CI engine fuelled with Methyl ester. <i>Fuel</i><b>271</b>, 117634. 10.1016/j.fuel.2020.117634 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2020.117634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S., Dinesha, P. &amp; Rosen, M. A. Effect of injection pressure on the combustion, performance and emission characteristics of a biodiesel engine with cerium oxide nanoparticle additive. <i>Energy</i><b>185</b>, 1163&#x2013;1173. 10.1016/j.energy.2019.07.124 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2019.07.124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivastava, P. &amp; Verma, T. N. Effect of fuel injection pressure on the characteristics of CI engine fuelled with biodiesel from roselle oil. <i>Fuel</i><b>265</b>, 117005. 10.1016/j.fuel.2019.117005 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2019.117005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. Y., Ge, J. C. &amp; Choi, N. J. Effects of fuel injection pressure on combustion and emission characteristics under low speed conditions in a diesel engine fueled with palm oil biodiesel. <i>Energies (Basel)</i>. 12. 10.3390/en12173264 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karikalan, L., Jacob, S., Baskar, S. &amp; Venugopal, S. Analyzing the influence of varied fuel injection pressure on diesel engine fueled with Karanja biodiesel. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>21</b>10.1016/j.matpr.2019.05.439 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yesilyurt, M. K. The effects of the fuel injection pressure on the performance and emission characteristics of a diesel engine fuelled with waste cooking oil biodiesel-diesel blends. <i>Renew. Energy</i> 2019;132. 10.1016/j.renene.2018.08.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arunprasad, S. &amp; Balusamy, T. Experimental investigation on the performance and emission characteristics of a diesel engine by varying the injection pressure and injection timing using mixed biodiesel. <i>Int. J. Green. Energy</i>. <b>15</b>10.1080/15435075.2018.1464923 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon, S. K., Ge, J. C. &amp; Choi, N. J. Influence of fuel injection pressure on the emissions characteristics and engine performance in a CRDI diesel engine fueled with palm biodiesel blends. <i>Energies (Basel)</i>. 12. 10.3390/en12203837 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RAJAK, U., NASH&#x130;NE, P., VERMA T. COMPARATIVE ASSESSMENT OF THE EMISSION CHARACTERISTICS OF FIRST &amp; SECOND AND THIRD GENERATION BIODIESELS AS FUEL IN A DIESEL ENGINE. <i>J. Therm. Eng.</i> ;<b>6</b>:211&#x2013;225. 10.18186/thermal.818036. (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18186/thermal.818036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan, C. G., Raj Kiran, K., Vikneswaran, M., Rajakrishnamoorthy, P. &amp; Yadav, S. P. R. Impact of fuel injection pressure on the engine characteristics of CRDI engine powered by pine oil biodiesel blend. Fuel 2020;264. 10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116760</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anas, M. I. et al. Analysis of the effect of injection pressure on ignition delay and combustion process of biodiesel from palm oil, algae and waste cooking oil. <i>J. Phys. Conf. Ser.</i><b>914</b>, 012008. 10.1088/1742-6596/914/1/012008 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/914/1/012008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagadish, D. Effect of fuel injection pressure on performance of constant-speed diesel engine fuelled with biofuel mixtures. Biofuels 2017;8. 10.1080/17597269.2016.1236003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasavi, A. Effect of various injection pressures on performance and emission characteristics of a four stroke CI engine fuelled with algae biodiesel. <i>Int. J. Res. Appl. Sci. Eng. Technol.</i><b>V</b>10.22214/ijraset.2017.10295 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinayagam, N. K. et al. Smart control strategy for effective hydrocarbon and carbon monoxide emission reduction on a conventional diesel engine using the pooled impact of pre-and post-combustion techniques. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>306</b>, 127310. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.127310 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.127310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bui, V. G. et al. Hydrogen-enriched biogas premixed charge combustion and emissions in direct injection and indirect injection diesel dual fueled engines: A comparative study. <i>J. Energy Resour. Technol. Trans. ASME</i>. <b>143</b>, 1&#x2013;13. 10.1115/1.4051574 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4051574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, V. N. et al. Potential of explainable artificial intelligence in advancing renewable energy: challenges and prospects. <i>Energy Fuels</i>. <b>38</b>, 1692&#x2013;1712. 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04343 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natrayan, L., Janardhan, G., Paramasivam, P. &amp; Dhanasekaran, S. Enhancing mechanical performance of TiO2 filler with Kevlar/epoxy-based hybrid composites in a cryogenic environment: a statistical optimization study using RSM and ANN methods. <i>Front. Mater.</i> 10. 10.3389/fmats.2023.1267514 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Pan, L., Suvarna, M., Tong, Y. W. &amp; Wang, X. Fuel properties of hydrochar and pyrochar: prediction and exploration with machine learning. <i>Appl. Energy</i>. 269. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2020.115166 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Comparison and implementation of machine learning models for predicting the combustion phases of hydrogen-enriched wankel rotary engines. <i>Fuel</i><b>310</b>, 122371. 10.1016/j.fuel.2021.122371 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2021.122371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandie, M., Ng, H. K., Gan, S., Muhamad Said, M. F. &amp; Cheng, X. Multi-input multi-output machine learning predictive model for engine performance and stability, emissions, combustion and ignition characteristics of diesel-biodiesel-gasoline blends. <i>Energy</i><b>262</b>, 125425. 10.1016/J.ENERGY.2022.125425 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.ENERGY.2022.125425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, B., Liang, Q., Tvete, H. A., Brinks, H. &amp; Vanem, E. Combined machine learning and physics-based models for estimating fuel consumption of cargo ships. <i>Ocean Eng.</i><b>255</b>, 111435. 10.1016/j.oceaneng.2022.111435 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oceaneng.2022.111435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliramezani, M., Koch, C. R. &amp; Shahbakhti, M. Modeling, diagnostics, optimization, and control of internal combustion engines via modern machine learning techniques: A review and future directions. <i>Prog Energy Combust. Sci.</i><b>88</b>, 100967. 10.1016/J.PECS.2021.100967 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.PECS.2021.100967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghavifar, H. et al. Appraisal of artificial neural networks to the emission analysis and prediction of CO2, soot, and nox of n-heptane fueled engine. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>112</b>, 1729&#x2013;1739. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.03.035 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.03.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghavifar, H., Taghavifar, H., Mardani, A. &amp; Mohebbi, A. Exhaust emissions prognostication for DI diesel group-hole injectors using a supervised artificial neural network approach. <i>Fuel</i><b>125</b>, 81&#x2013;89. 10.1016/j.fuel.2014.02.016 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2014.02.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghavifar, H., Taghavifar, H., Mardani, A., Mohebbi, A. &amp; Khalilarya, S. A numerical investigation on the wall heat flux in a DI diesel engine fueled with n-heptane using a coupled CFD and ANN approach. <i>Fuel</i><b>140</b>, 227&#x2013;236. 10.1016/j.fuel.2014.09.092 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2014.09.092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, K. et al. An experimental and ANN analysis of ammonia energy integration in biofuel powered low-temperature combustion engine to enhance cleaner combustion. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i><b>63</b>, 105284. 10.1016/j.csite.2024.105284 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2024.105284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, K. et al. Production and utilization of hydrogen enriched fifth generation biofuel in LTC engines with reformed EGR. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 1&#x2013;19. 10.1038/s41598-025-08259-w (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-08259-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12271319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40676063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Haersma Buma, B. N. D., Peretto, M., Matar, Z. M. &amp; van de Kaa, G. Towards renewable hydrogen-based electrolysis: alkaline vs proton exchange membrane. Heliyon 2023;9. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10395340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37539202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helen McCay, M. Hydrogen. An Energy Carrier. Future Energy: Improved, Sustainable and Clean Options for Our Planet :495&#x2013;510. (2013). 10.1016/B978-0-08-099424-6.00023-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsujimura, T. &amp; Suzuki, Y. The utilization of hydrogen in hydrogen/diesel dual fuel engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrogen Energy</i>. <b>42</b>, 14019&#x2013;14029. 10.1016/J.IJHYDENE.2017.01.152 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.IJHYDENE.2017.01.152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aravind, S., Barik, D., Praveenkumar, S., Tudu, K. &amp; Dara, R. N. Influence of compression ratio variations on hydrogen combustion dynamics in a tri-fuel agricultural diesel engine operating with diesel, algae spirogyra Methyl ester, and di-tert-butyl peroxide. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i>. <b>143</b>, 429&#x2013;440. 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.113 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki, Y. &amp; Tsujimura, T. The utilization of hydrogen in hydrogen/diesel dual fuel engine. <i>WHEC 2016&#x2013;21st World Hydrogen Energy Conf. 2016 Proc.</i><b>42</b>, 714&#x2013;715 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aravind, S. et al. Exposure the role of hydrogen with algae spirogyra biodiesel and fuel-borne additive on a diesel engine: an experimental assessment on dual fuel combustion mode. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i><b>65</b>, 105566. 10.1016/j.csite.2024.105566 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2024.105566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan, C., Li, X., Liao, B. &amp; Huang, Z. Effects of fuel injection strategies on emissions characteristics of a diesel engine equipped with a particle oxidation catalyst (POC). <i>J. Environ. Chem. Eng.</i><b>4</b>, 4822&#x2013;4829. 10.1016/j.jece.2016.01.037 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2016.01.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouda, M. M., Etaiw, S. E. H., Abd El-Aziz, D. M., Elkelawy, M. &amp; Bastawissi, H. A. E. Improvement of the diesel engine performance and emissions attribute by using supramolecular coordination polymer as a combined multifunctional nanoparticles additive. <i>J. Environ. Chem. Eng.</i><b>13</b>, 116697. 10.1016/j.jece.2025.116697 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2025.116697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibin, C., Sheeja, R., Devarajan, Y. &amp; Ponnappan, S. M. Environment impact assessment of agricultural diesel engines utilizing biodiesel derived from Phoenix sylvestris oil. <i>Environ. Res.</i><b>224</b>, 115432. 10.1016/j.envres.2023.115432 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2023.115432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36791837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazikhani, M. et al. Exergy recovery from the exhaust cooling in a DI diesel engine for BSFC reduction purposes. <i>Energy</i><b>65</b>, 44&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.energy.2013.12.004 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2013.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ler, M. &amp; &#xd6;zkan, M. Energy balance analysis of a DI diesel engine with multiple pilot injections strategy and optimization of brake thermal efficiency. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i> 2022;204. 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2021.117972</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmugasundar, G. et al. A comparative study of linear, random forest and adaboost regressions for modeling non-traditional machining. <i>Processes</i><b>9</b>10.3390/pr9112015 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak, S. &amp; Il, Oh, T. H. Correlation and simple linear regression. <i>J. Veterinary Clin.</i> 2010;27. 10.1007/978-3-319-89993-0_6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mienye, I. D., Sun, Y. &amp; Wang, Z. Prediction performance of improved decision tree-based algorithms: A review. <i>Procedia Manuf.</i><b>35</b>10.1016/j.promfg.2019.06.011 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canete-Sifuentes, L., Monroy, R. &amp; Medina-Perez, M. A. A review and experimental comparison of multivariate decision trees. <i>IEEE Access.</i> 9. 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3102239 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talekar, B. &amp; A Detailed Review on Decision Tree and Random Forest. <i>Biosci. Biotechnol. Res. Commun.</i> ;<b>13</b>. 10.21786/bbrc/13.14/57. (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraishi, H., Nakamura, T. &amp; Shibuki, R. Time series quantile regression using random forests. <i>J. Time Ser. Anal.</i><b>45</b>, 639&#x2013;659. 10.1111/jtsa.12731 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jtsa.12731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeini, H. A. et al. Random forest algorithm for the strength prediction of geopolymer stabilized clayey soil. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b>, 1408. 10.3390/su15021408 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15021408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarina, N. D. et al. Machine learning using random forest to model heavy metals removal efficiency using a zeolite-embedded sheet in water. <i>Global J. Environ. Sci. Manage.</i><b>10</b>, 321&#x2013;336. 10.22034/gjesm.2024.01.20 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22034/gjesm.2024.01.20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chintala, V. &amp; Subramanian, K. A. Experimental investigation of autoignition of hydrogen-air charge in a compression ignition engine under dual-fuel mode. <i>Energy</i><b>138</b>, 197&#x2013;209. 10.1016/j.energy.2017.07.068 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2017.07.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohite, A. et al. Optimization of the pilot fuel injection and engine load for an algae biodiesel - hydrogen run dual fuel diesel engine using response surface methodology. <i>Fuel</i><b>357</b>, 129841. 10.1016/j.fuel.2023.129841 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.129841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Karthickeyan, V., Sivakumar, E. &amp; Lakshmikandan, M. Experimental investigation on pumpkin seed oil Methyl ester blend in diesel engine with various injection pressure, injection timing and compression ratio. <i>Fuel</i><b>264</b>, 116868. 10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116868 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A&#x11f;bulut, &#xdc;., Ayy&#x131;ld&#x131;z, M. &amp; Sar&#x131;demir, S. Prediction of performance, combustion and emission characteristics for a CI engine at varying injection pressures. <i>Energy</i>10.1016/j.energy.2020.117257 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.117257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loyte, A. et al. Influence of injection strategies on ignition patterns of RCCI combustion engine fuelled with hydrogen enriched natural gas. <i>Environ. Res.</i> 234. 10.1016/j.envres.2023.116537 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37402432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MASOOD, M. &amp; ISHRAT, M. Computational combustion and emission analysis of hydrogen&#x2013;diesel blends with experimental verification. <i>Int. J. Hydrogen Energy</i>. <b>32</b>, 2539&#x2013;2547. 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2006.11.008 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2006.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun, S., Lee, J., Cho, H. &amp; Kim, J. Oxy-fuel combustion-based blue hydrogen production with the integration of water electrolysis. <i>Energy Convers. Manag</i>. <b>291</b>, 117275. 10.1016/j.enconman.2023.117275 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2023.117275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beita, J., Talibi, M., Sadasivuni, S. &amp; Balachandran, R. Thermoacoustic instability considerations for high hydrogen combustion in lean premixed gas turbine combustors: A review. <i>Hydrogen</i><b>2</b>, 33&#x2013;57. 10.3390/hydrogen2010003 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/hydrogen2010003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. et al. Review on blended hydrogen-fuel internal combustion engines: A case study for China. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>8</b>, 6480&#x2013;6498. 10.1016/j.egyr.2022.04.079 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2022.04.079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>