<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41839988</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An adaptive A-Star algorithm to handle blood transportation using UAVs.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40040-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Efficient and timely transportation of blood samples across medical centers is critically important, particularly in countries where traffic congestion significantly delays road-based delivery. The operational range of the unmanned aerial vehicles remains constrained by limited battery capacity and variable energy consumption across different terrains. This paper proposes an integrated approach for optimizing drone-based medical transportation by combining a 3D enhanced A* pathfinding algorithm with a K-means clustering method for strategic deployment of drone charging stations. The 3D A* algorithm incorporates elevation and environmental obstacles, enabling accurate estimation of flight costs. Charging station placement considers population density, topography, power infrastructure, and drone power consumption models. A case study involving Lebanese hospitals demonstrates the effectiveness of the proposed system in minimizing flight distance, reducing energy consumption, and ensuring mission feasibility under real-world constraints.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaki</LastName><ForeName>Chamseddine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering and Technology, American University of the Middle East, Kuwait City, Kuwait.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taleb</LastName><ForeName>Houssein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, Saint Joseph University of Beirut, Beirut, Lebanon. houssein.taleb@usj.edu.lb.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, American University of Science and Technology, Beirut, Lebanon. houssein.taleb@usj.edu.lb.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taki</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Arts and Science, American University of Culture and Education, Beirut, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>AlArnaout</LastName><ForeName>Zakwan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering and Technology, American University of the Middle East, Kuwait City, Kuwait.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saker</LastName><ForeName>Louai</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering and Technology, American University of the Middle East, Kuwait City, Kuwait.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Moustafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering and Technology, American University of the Middle East, Kuwait City, Kuwait.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nasser</LastName><ForeName>Abbass</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CIRAME Research Center, Business School, Holy-Spirit University of Kaslik, Po Box 446, Jounieh, Lebanon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood transportation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GIS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthcare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UAV</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41839988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40040-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40040-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Taleb, H., Andrieux, G., Khalife, D., Ajami, A. &amp; Nasser, A. Exploring healthcare in the 6G and AI era: Opportunities and challenges. Internet Things 6, 101744 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Euchi, J. Do Drones have a Realistic Place in a Pandemic Fight for Delivering Medical Supplies in Healthcare Systems Problems? (Elsevier, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brovkina, V. R., Ermakov, A. S., Shevketova, E. S., Chernetskaya, N. N. &amp; Basan, E. S. Algorithm for finding a descriptive path for delivering cargo to hard-to-reach areas. In: 2023 IEEE XVI International Scientific and Technical Conference Actual Problems of Electronic Instrument Engineering (APEIE) 1110&#x2013;1115. (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohsan, S. A. H., Khan, M. A., Noor, F., Ullah, I. &amp; Alsharif, M. H. Towards the unmanned aerial vehicles (uavs): A comprehensive review. Drones 6(6), 147 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, M., Bagheri, M., James, A. P. &amp; Phung, T. Wireless charging techniques for uavs: A review, reconceptualization, and extension. IEEE Access 6, 29865&#x2013;29884 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, H. &amp; Savkin, A. V. Optimal deployment of charging stations for aerial surveillance by uavs with the assistance of public transportation vehicles. Sensors 21(16), 5320 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, H., Savkin, A. V. &amp; Huang, C. Decentralized autonomous navigation of a uav network for road traffic monitoring. IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst. 57(4), 2558&#x2013;2564 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, H. &amp; Savkin, A. V. An algorithm of reactive collision free 3-d deployment of networked unmanned aerial vehicles for surveillance and monitoring. IEEE Trans. Industr. Inf. 16(1), 132&#x2013;140 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauba, P. et al. Adopting drone technology for blood delivery: A feasibility study to evaluate its efficiency and sustainability. Arch. Public Health 83(1), 163 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stierlin, N., Loertscher, F., Renz, H., Risch, L. &amp; Risch, M. Preanalytic integrity of blood samples in uncrewed aerial vehicle (uav) medical transport: A comparative study. Drones 8(9), 517 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Z., Yu, K. &amp; Qiu, R. Location-routing optimization of uav collaborative blood delivery vehicle distribution on complex roads. Complex Intell. Syst. 10(6), 8127&#x2013;8141 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maguire, D. J. An overview and definition of gis. Geograph. Inf. Syst. Principles Appl. 1(1), 9&#x2013;20 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, M., Singh, R., Singh, A., Pravesh, R., Majid, S. I. &amp; Tiwari, A. Referencing and coordinate systems in gis. In: Geographic Information Systems in Urban Planning and Management 25&#x2013;46. (Springer, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elshaer, A., Elmanfaloty, R. A., Abou-Bakr, E., Elrakaiby, M. &amp; Saada, K. Exploring algorithmic efficiency of a-star and dijkstra for optimal route planning in green transportation. Int. J. Intell. Transport. Syst. Res. 8, 1&#x2013;11 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beigi, P., Rajabi, M. S. &amp; Aghakhani, S. An overview of drone energy consumption factors and models. Handbook Smart Energy Syst. 5, 529&#x2013;548 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Franco, C. &amp; Buttazzo, G. Energy-aware coverage path planning of uavs. In 2015 IEEE International Conference on Autonomous Robot Systems and Competitions 111&#x2013;117 (IEEE, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, G. Research and development of poyang lake hydrodynamic modeling system based on mapwingis. In Advances in Computational Environment Science: Selected Papers from 2012 International Conference on Environment Science (ICES 2012), Australia, Melbourne, 15&#x2013;16 January, 2012 41&#x2013;50. (Springer, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusupova, N., Smetanina, O., Sazonova, E. &amp; Sadretdinova, M. Models and methods of routing problem of transport in power industry. In 2021 International Conference on Electrotechnical Complexes and Systems (ICOECS) 453&#x2013;458. (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beirut-Lebanon-YearRound. The typical weather anywhere on earth. Accessed 19.04.2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>