<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41790681</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Shear wave elastography of the plantar fascia: A cross-sectional observational study in asymptomatic runners and sedentary controls.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e47970</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e47970</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e47970</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000047970</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The plantar fascia (PF) is exposed to repetitive loading in runners; it remains unclear whether chronic training in young, asymptomatic athletes leads to changes in PF thickness or stiffness. To compare PF thickness and elasticity between asymptomatic elite runners and sedentary controls using B-mode ultrasound and shear-wave elastography (SWE), and to test the hypothesis that prolonged mechanical loading induces adaptive changes in PF stiffness. In this cross-sectional study, 56 participants were included: 38 elite runners (12 short-distance, 11 middle-distance, 15 long-distance) and 18 sedentary controls. Bilateral B-mode ultrasound and longitudinal 2-dimensional SWE virtual touch tissue imaging quantification were performed at proximal (&#x2248;1&#x2009;cm from the calcaneal insertion) and distal (&#x2248;6&#x2009;cm) PF sites using an Acuson S2000 system (Siemens, Munich, Germany) with a 4 to 9 MHz linear array transducer. Primary outcomes were PF thickness (mm) and shear-wave velocity (m/s). Gender distribution did not differ between groups (&#x3c7;2, P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.748). Age differed across subgroups (analysis of variance, P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.011), and body mass index was lower in middle- and long-distance runners than in sedentary controls (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.042). Thickness: No differences were observed between runners and sedentary controls (all P&#x2005;&gt;&#x2005;.10); among runner subgroups, a difference was detected only at the left-proximal site (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.043), with the highest values in short-distance runners. Proximal thickness exceeded distal thickness (P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.001). SWE: No differences were found between-group at any site (all analysis of variance, P&#x2005;&gt;&#x2005;.45); effect sizes were small (Hedges, g &#x2005;-0.07 to&#x2005;-0.29), and post hoc power to detect such small effects was low (~6%-16%). Proximal SWE was higher than distal SWE (P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.001); at the distal site, left-sided values were higher than right-sided values (Wilcoxon, P&#x2005;=&#x2005;.032). Among sedentary participants, females had higher proximal SWE than males (P&#x2005;&#x2248;&#x2005;0.014-0.053), whereas no gender effect was observed in runners. Reliability: Intraclass correlation coefficient was 0.965 to 0.979 for distal SWE (excellent) and 0.755 for right-proximal SWE (good); thickness intraclass correlation coefficients ranged from 0.765 to 0.814. In young, asymptomatic elite runners, chronic training is not associated with a measurable change in PF thickness or stiffness compared with sedentary peers. Differences are predominantly site-dependent (proximal&#x2005;&gt;&#x2005;distal), and a gender effect was observed only among sedentary individuals. Adaptation of the PF to mechanical loading may occur without macroscopic hypertrophy or increased stiffness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akdemir</LastName><ForeName>Z&#xfc;lk&#xfc;f</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7958-7235</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Faculty of Medicine, Van Yuzuncu Yil University, Van, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zkan</LastName><ForeName>Zekiye</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Management, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Van Yuzuncu Yil University, Van, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orak</LastName><ForeName>Suat</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Lokman Hekim Van Hospital, Van, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arslan</LastName><ForeName>Harun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Faculty of Medicine, Van Yuzuncu Yil University, Van, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akdeniz</LastName><ForeName>H&#xfc;seyin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Faculty of Medicine, Van Yuzuncu Yil University, Van, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaplan</LastName><ForeName>&#x15e;eyhmus</ForeName><Initials>&#x15e;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Van Yuzuncu Yil University, Van, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Running</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054459" MajorTopicYN="Y">Elasticity Imaging Techniques</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005205" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fascia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057185" MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plantar fascia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">runner</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shear-wave elastography</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41790681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12975240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000047970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202603060-00061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McNally EG, Shetty S. Plantar fascia: imaging diagnosis and guided treatment. Semin Musculoskelet Radiol. 2010;14:334&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20539958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stecco C, Corradin M, Macchi V, et al. Plantar fascia anatomy and its relationship with Achilles tendon and paratenon. J Anat. 2013;223:665&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3842207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24028383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks JH. The mechanics of the foot. II. The plantar aponeurosis and the arch. J Anat. 1954;88:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1244640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13129168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natali AN, Pavan PG, Stecco C. A constitutive model for the mechanical characterization of the plantar fascia. Connect Tissue Res. 2010;51:337&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20175692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavan PG, Stecco C, Darwish S, Natali AN, De Caro R. Investigation of the mechanical properties of the plantar aponeurosis. Surg Radiol Anat. 2011;33:905&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolf C, Guntner P, Ericsater J, Turan I. Plantar fascia rupture: diagnosis and treatment. J Foot Ankle Surg. 1997;36:112&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9127213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt KJ, Anderson RB. Heel pain in the athlete. Sports Health. 2009;1:427&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petraglia F, Ramazzina I, Costantino C. Plantar fasciitis in athletes: diagnostic and treatment strategies. A systematic review. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2017;7:107&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5505577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28717618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjaer M, Langberg H, Heinemeier K, et al. From mechanical loading to collagen synthesis, structural changes and function in human tendon. Scandinavian J Med Sci Sports. 2009;19:500&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19706001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bojsen-Moller J, Kalliokoski KK, Seppanen M, Kjaer M, Magnusson SP. Low-intensity tensile loading increases intratendinous glucose uptake in the Achilles tendon. J Appl Physiol (Bethesda, MD: 1985). 2006;101:196&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16565354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klauser AS, Miyamoto H, Bellmann-Weiler R, Feuchtner GM, Wick MC, Jaschke WR. Sonoelastography: musculoskeletal applications. Radiology. 2014;272:622&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25153273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiina T, Nitta N, Ueno E, Bamber JC. Real time tissue elasticity imaging using the combined autocorrelation method. J Med Ultrason (2001). 2002;29:119&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27277886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schillizzi G, Alviti F, D&#x2019;Ercole C, et al. Evaluation of plantar fasciopathy shear wave elastography: a comparison between patients and healthy subjects. J Ultrasound. 2021;24:417&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8572281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32418168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domenichini R, Pialat JB, Podda A, Aubry S. Ultrasound elastography in tendon pathology: state of the art. Skeletal Radiol. 2017;46:1643&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28765991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arda K, Ciledag N, Aktas E, Aribas BK, Kose K. Quantitative assessment of normal soft-tissue elasticity using shear-wave ultrasound elastography. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2011;197:532&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taljanovic MS, Gimber LH, Becker GW, et al. Shear-wave elastography: basic physics and musculoskeletal applications. Radiographics . 2017;37:855&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5452887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28493799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatz M, Bejder L, Quack V, et al. Shear wave elastography (SWE) for the evaluation of patients with plantar fasciitis. Acad Radiol. 2020;27:363&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31153782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ta&#x15f; S. Effect of gender on mechanical properties of the plantar fascia and heel fat pad. Foot Ankle Spec. 2018;11:403&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29029575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiotani H, Yamashita R, Mizokuchi T, Naito M, Kawakami Y. Site- and gender-differences in morphological and mechanical properties of the plantar fascia: a supersonic shear imaging study. J Biomech. 2019;85:198&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30665708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baur D, Schwabl C, Kremser C, et al. Shear wave elastography of the plantar fascia: comparison between patients with plantar fasciitis and healthy control subjects. J Clin Med. 2021;10:2351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8199455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34072045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha DK, Wongkaewpotong J, Chuckpaiwong B. Effect of age and BMI on sonographic findings of plantar fascia. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2023;62:125&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanda G, Knechtle B. Marathon performance in relation to body fat percentage and training indices in recreational male runners. Open Access J Sports Med. 2013;4:141&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3871414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24379719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen KD, Rogers J, Winzenberg T, van Middelkoop M. Higher body mass index is associated with plantar fasciopathy/&#x201c;plantar fasciitis&#x201d;: systematic review and meta-analysis of various clinical and imaging risk factors. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:972&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26644427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual Huerta J, Garc&#xed;a JM, Matamoros EC, Matamoros JC, Mart&#xed;nez TD. Relationship of body mass index, ankle dorsiflexion, and foot pronation on plantar fascia thickness in healthy, asymptomatic subjects. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc. 2008;98:379&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18820041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ta&#x15f; S, Bek N, Onur MR, Korkusuz F. Effects of body mass index on mechanical properties of the plantar fascia and heel pad in asymptomatic participants. Foot Ankle Int. 2017;38:779&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28535692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzel M, Cetinus E, Ekerbicer HC, Karaoguz A. The influence of athletic activity on the plantar fascia in healthy young adults. J Clin Ultrasound. 2006;34:17&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16353229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabau-Dasi R, Nieto-Gil P, Ortega-Avila AB, Gijon-Nogueron G. Variations in the thickness of the plantar fascia after training based in training race. A pilot study. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2022;61:1230&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35370051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello C, Chatzistergos P, Branthwaite H, Chockalingam N. The importance of preconditioning for the sonographic assessment of plantar fascia thickness and shear wave velocity. Sensors (Basel). 2024;24:4552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11280931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39065950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiotani H, Mizokuchi T, Yamashita R, Naito M, Kawakami Y. Influence of body mass on running-induced changes in mechanical properties of plantar fascia. J Strength Cond Res. 2023;37:e588&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10599803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37099441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiotani H, Yamashita R, Mizokuchi T, Sado N, Naito M, Kawakami Y. Track distance runners exhibit bilateral differences in the plantar fascia stiffness. Sci Rep. 2021;11:9260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8085187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33927340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albano D, Messina C, Gitto S, et al. Shear-wave elastography of the plantar fascia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Ultrasound. 2023;26:59&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10063692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36662404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>