<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41468029</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1948-8270</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of bronchology &amp; interventional pulmonology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Role of Artificial Intelligence in Interventional Pulmonology.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e01051</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/LBR.0000000000001051</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Artificial intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing interventional pulmonology (IP) by enhancing diagnostics, procedural precision, and patient outcomes. AI-powered tools improve lung nodule detection, radiomics-based risk stratification, and bronchoscopic navigation. Machine learning (ML) algorithms aid in lung cancer screening by analyzing imaging data, reducing false positives, and improving early diagnosis. AI-driven robotic-assisted bronchoscopy enhances navigation and biopsy accuracy, particularly for peripheral lung lesions. Endobronchial ultrasound (EBUS) and cytopathology benefit from AI's ability to assess lymph node malignancy and optimize rapid on-site evaluation (ROSE). AI applications extend to phenotyping chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and identifying candidates for bronchoscopic lung volume reduction (BLVR). Deep learning (DL) models analyze computed tomography (CT) imaging and spirometry data to optimize patient selection. AI-driven algorithms are also advancing pleural effusion detection, differentiation, and classification, supporting clinical decision-making. Education and research in IP are also transforming with AI-driven simulation, virtual reality, and automated assessment tools that enhance procedural training and competency evaluation. The integration of AI into clinical work and procedural training accelerates advancements while presenting challenges in ethical AI implementation, data security, and bias mitigation. As AI continues to evolve, its role in IP will expand, improving procedural efficiency, personalizing treatment plans, and optimizing patient selection for interventions. Future developments will focus on refining AI-driven predictive analytics, enhancing robotic-assisted procedures, and integrating AI seamlessly into clinical workflows. The responsible implementation of AI in IP holds the potential to transform patient care, reduce complications, and advance precision medicine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kornafeld</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Little</LastName><ForeName>Greg</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Grodivo, Park City, UT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frye</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Bronchology Interv Pulmonol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101496866</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1948-8270</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="N">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015272" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pulmonary Medicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="N">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001999" MajorTopicYN="N">Bronchoscopy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014057" MajorTopicYN="N">Tomography, X-Ray Computed</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029424" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ChatGPT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GenAI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OpenEvidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bronchoscopic lung volume reduction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiomics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">robotic bronchoscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">robotics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure: There is no conflict of interest or other disclosures.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41468029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/LBR.0000000000001051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01436970-202601010-00018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Deasy K, C H, Kennedy M. AI in Respirology and Bronchoscopy, in AI in clinical medicine : a practical guide for healthcare professionals Byrne, N MFP, Greenhill AT, Chahal , D, Ahmad O, Bagci U. Editor 2023 Wiley Blackwell, Hoboken, NJ.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baloescu C, Bailitz J, Cheema B, et al. Artificial intelligence-guided lung ultrasound by nonexperts. JAMA Cardiol. 2025;10:245&#x2013;253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massion PP, Antic S, Ather S, et al. Assessing the accuracy of a deep learning method to risk stratify indeterminate pulmonary nodules. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202:241&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao J, Feng J, Li J, et al. Novel tools for early diagnosis and precision treatment based on artificial intelligence. Chin Med J Pulm Crit Care Med. 2023;1:148&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennani S, Regnard NE, Ventre J, et al. Using AI to improve radiologist performance in detection of abnormalities on chest radiographs. Radiology. 2023;309:e230860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H, Hwang EJ, Goo JM. Deep learning-based kernel adaptation enhances quantification of emphysema on low-dose chest CT for predicting long-term mortality. Invest Radiol. 2024;59:278&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Hwang EJ, Yoon SH, Park CM, Goo JM. Emerging trends and innovations in radiologic diagnosis of thoracic diseases. Investigative Radiology. 2024;13:10&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiwata T, Yasufuku K. Artificial intelligence in interventional pulmonology. Curr Opin Pulm Med. 2024;30:92&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiwata T, Gregor A, Inage T, Yasufuku K. Bronchoscopic navigation and tissue diagnosis. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2020;68:672&#x2013;678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bera K, Braman N, Gupta A, et al. Predicting cancer outcomes with radiomics and artificial intelligence in radiology. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2022;19:132&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuhmann M, Raffy P, Yin Y, et al. Computed tomography predictors of response to endobronchial valve lung reduction treatment. Comparison with Chartis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2015;191:767&#x2013;774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranschaert E, Topff L, Pianykh O. Optimization of radiology workflow with artificial intelligence. Radiol Clin North Am. 2021;59:955&#x2013;966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thoracic Key: Introduction to Lung CT AI 2023 2/11/2025]. https://thoracickey.com/introduction-to-lung-ct-ai/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diddams MJ, Lee HJ. Robotic bronchoscopy: review of three systems. Life (Basel). 2023;13:354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshpajooh V, Ahmad D, Toth J, et al. Automatic lesion detection for narrow-band imaging bronchoscopy. J Med Imaging (Bellingham). 2024;11:036002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team, SP Understanding the Theory of Mind AI: All You Need To Know. 2024 2/11/2025]. https://surveypoint.ai/blog/2024/02/24/understanding-the-theory-of-mind-ai-all-you-need-to-know/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali S, Byrne MF. An Introduction to AI for Non-Experts, in AI in clinical medicine: a practical guide for healthcare professionals Byrne MF, et al. 2023 Wiley Blackwell, Hoboken, NJ.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warner HR, Toronto AF, Veasy LG. Experience with Baye&#x2019;s theorem for computer diagnosis of congenital heart disease. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1964;115:558&#x2013;567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalaiyarasan K, R S. Artificial intelligence in respiratory medicine: the journey so far - A review. J Assoc Pulmonol Tamil Nadu. 2023;6:53&#x2013;68; May&#x2013;Aug 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manickavasagam R, Selvan S. Automatic detection and classification of lung nodules in CT image using optimized neuro fuzzy classifier with cuckoo search algorithm. J Med Syst. 2019;43:77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wei Q, Wang T, et al. Narrative review of the application of artificial intelligence-related technologies in the diagnosis of pulmonary nodules with recommendations for clinical practice and future research. J Thorac Dis. 2025;17:6326&#x2013;6338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warkentin MT, Al-Sawaihey H, Lam S, et al. Radiomics analysis to predict pulmonary nodule malignancy using machine learning approaches. Thorax. 2024;79:307&#x2013;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Sun H, Chen B, et al. Developing of risk models for small solid and subsolid pulmonary nodules based on clinical and quantitative radiomics features. J Thorac Dis. 2021;13:4156&#x2013;4168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan MY, Gustad LT, Nytro O. Sepsis prediction, early detection, and identification using clinical text for machine learning: a systematic review. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2022;29:559&#x2013;575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Kamel Boulos MN. Generative AI in medicine and healthcare: promises, opportunities and challenges. Future Internet. 2023;15:286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel D, Patel D. and Elsevier, Digital Health : Telemedicine and Beyond 1st edition Chapter 12 - Robot-assisted surgery: Past, present, and future. 2025. London, England: Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results (SEER) Program Populations (1969-2022) 2024. www.seer.cancer.gov/popdata.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster HL, Jiang B, Gratama JW, et al. AI can greatly reduce radiologist workload if used as a first read filter to rule-out negative cases in lung cancer screening. J Thorac Oncol. 2023;18:S172&#x2013;S173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Chi J, Liu J, et al. A survey of computer-aided diagnosis of lung nodules from CT scans using deep learning. Comput Biol Med. 2021;137:104806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Mohammad B, Hillis SL, Reed W, et al. Radiologist performance in the detection of lung cancer using CT. Clin Radiol. 2019;74:67&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin GD, Roos JE, Tall M, et al. Characterizing search, recognition, and decision in the detection of lung nodules on CT scans: elucidation with eye tracking. Radiology. 2015;274:276&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinsky PF, Gierada DS, Nath PH, et al. National lung screening trial: variability in nodule detection rates in chest CT studies. Radiology. 2013;268:865&#x2013;873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeshita Y, Onozawa S, Katase S, et al. Evaluation of an artificial intelligence U-net algorithm for pulmonary nodule tracking on chest computed tomography images. J Int Med Res. 2024;52:3000605241230033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamberlin J, Kocher MR, Waltz J, et al. Automated detection of lung nodules and coronary artery calcium using artificial intelligence on low-dose CT scans for lung cancer screening: accuracy and prognostic value. BMC Med. 2021;19:55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avanzo M, Stancanello J, Pirrone G, et al. Radiomics and deep learning in lung cancer. Strahlenther Onkol. 2020;196:879&#x2013;887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvam M, Chandrasekharan A, Sadanandan A, et al. Radiomics as a non-invasive adjunct to Chest CT in distinguishing benign and malignant lung nodules. Sci Rep. 2023;13:19062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Lung Screening Trial Research T, et al. Reduced lung-cancer mortality with low-dose computed tomographic screening. N Engl J Med. 2011;365:395&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Koning HJ, van der Aalst CM, de Jong PA, et al. Reduced lung-cancer mortality with volume CT screening in a randomized trial. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:503&#x2013;513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkadesh KV, Setio AAA, Schreuder A, et al. Deep learning for malignancy risk estimation of pulmonary nodules detected at low-dose screening CT. Radiology. 2021;300:438&#x2013;447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladbury C, Amini A, Govindarajan A, et al. Integration of artificial intelligence in lung cancer: rise of the machine. Cell Rep Med. 2023;4:100933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu FZ, Wu YJ, Chen CS, et al. Prediction of interval growth of lung adenocarcinomas manifesting as persistent subsolid nodules &lt;/=3 cm based on radiomic features. Acad Radiol. 2023;30:2856&#x2013;2869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo JY, Kang SY, Park JS, et al. Deep learning for anatomical interpretation of video bronchoscopy images. Sci Rep. 2021;11:23765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruionu LG, Udri&#x219;toiu AL, Iacob AV, et al. Feasibility of a lung airway navigation system using fiber-Bragg shape sensing and artificial intelligence for early diagnosis of lung cancer. PLoS ONE. 2022;17:e0277938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saghaie T, Williamson JP, Phillips M, et al. First-in-human use of a new robotic electromagnetic navigation bronchoscopic platform with integrated Tool-in-Lesion Tomosynthesis (TiLT) technology for peripheral pulmonary lesions: The FRONTIER study. Respirology. 2024;29:969&#x2013;975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secinaro S, Calandra D, Secinaro A, et al. The role of artificial intelligence in healthcare: a structured literature review. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2021;21:125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intuitive Announces AI and Advanced Imaging Integration in Ion Endoluminal System. 2025. https://www.surgicalroboticstechnology.com/news/intuitive-announces-ai-and-advanced-imaging-integration-in-ion-endoluminal-system/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel YS, Gatti AA, Farrokhyar F, et al. Artificial intelligence algorithm can predict lymph node malignancy from endobronchial ultrasound transbronchial needle aspiration images for non-small cell lung cancer. Respiration. 2024;103:741&#x2013;751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito Y, Nakajima T, Inage T, et al. Prediction of nodal metastasis in lung cancer using deep learning of endobronchial ultrasound images. Cancers (Basel). 2022;14:3334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M, Chen J, Li J, et al. Automatic representative frame selection and intrathoracic lymph node diagnosis with endobronchial ultrasound elastography videos. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2023;27:29&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi X, Li J, Chen J, et al. Automatic image selection model based on machine learning for endobronchial ultrasound strain elastography videos. Front Oncol. 2021;11:673775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Thrall MJ, Michelow P, et al. The current state of digital cytology and artificial intelligence (AI): global survey results from the American Society of Cytopathology Digital Cytology Task Force. J Am Soc Cytopathol. 2024;13:319&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CC, Lu SC, Chang YK, et al. Diagnostic performance of rapid on-site evaluation during bronchoscopy for lung cancer: a comprehensive meta-analysis. Cancer Cytopathol. 2025;133:e22908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan S, Li Y, Pan L, et al. The application of artificial intelligence for Rapid On-Site Evaluation during flexible bronchoscopy. Front Oncol. 2024;14:1360831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai D, Hu Q, Chao YC, et al. Artificial intelligence-based rapid on-site cytopathological evaluation for bronchoscopy examinations. Intelligence-Based Medicine. 2022;6:100069.62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teramoto A, Tsukamoto T, Kiriyama Y, et al. Automated classification of lung cancer types from cytological images using deep convolutional neural networks. Biomed Res Int. 2017;2017:4067832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemeh CN, Podder S, Mueller J, Wagh AA. Mueller J, Wagh AA. Use of the Vangogh System to Assess for Intra-operative Tissue Adequacy: Initial Experience. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine. 2025;211(Abstracts):A2723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coudray N, Ocampo PS, Sakellaropoulos T, et al. Classification and mutation prediction from non-small cell lung cancer histopathology images using deep learning. Nat Med. 2018;24:1559&#x2013;1567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomita N, Tafe LJ, Suriawinata AA, et al. Predicting oncogene mutations of lung cancer using deep learning and histopathologic features on whole-slide images. Transl Oncol. 2022;24:101494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Wang W, Xu Y, et al. Prediction of epidermal growth factor receptor mutation subtypes in non-small cell lung cancer from hematoxylin and eosin-stained slides using deep learning. Lab Invest. 2024;104:102094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Xiong S, Ren Q, et al. Deep learning using histological images for gene mutation prediction in lung cancer: a multicentre retrospective study. Lancet Oncol. 2025;26:136&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang LYW, Coxson HO, Lam S, et al. Towards large-scale case-finding: training and validation of residual networks for detection of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease using low-dose CT. Lancet Digit Health. 2020;2:e259&#x2013;e267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodduluri S, Nakhmani A, Reinhardt JM, et al. Deep neural network analyses of spirometry for structural phenotyping of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. JCI Insight. 2020;5:e132781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Xia S, Liang Z, et al. Artificial intelligence in COPD CT images: identification, staging, and quantitation. Respir Res. 2024;25:319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Jiang B, Wisselink HJ, et al. COPD identification and grading based on deep learning of lung parenchyma and bronchial wall in chest CT images. Br J Radiol. 2022;95:20210637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogarth DK, B T. Integrated artificial intelligence screening to optimize patient identification for bronchoscopic lung volume reduction therapy: redefining patient selection with select CT screening from MDedge. MDedge. 2024. Available from https://medauth2.mdedge.com/content/integrated-artificial-intelligence-screening-optimize-patient-identification-bronchoscopic-lung-volume-reduction-therapy-redefining-patient-selection-selecttm-screening</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian K, Muench B, Shostak E, et al. Lobar quantification of pulmonary perfusion prior to minimally invasive lung reduction improves prediction of postprocedure outcomes: a pilot study. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2024;44:44&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lind Plesner L, M&#xfc;ller FC, Brejneb&#xf8;l MW, et al. Commercially available chest radiograph AI tools for detecting airspace disease, pneumothorax, and pleural effusion. Radiology. 2023;308:e231236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niehoff JH, Kalaitzidis J, Kroeger JR, et al. Evaluation of the clinical performance of an AI-based application for the automated analysis of chest X-rays. Sci Rep. 2023;13:3680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sexauer R, Yang S, Weikert T, et al. Automated detection, segmentation, and classification of pleural effusion from computed tomography scans using machine learning. Invest Radiol. 2022;57:552&#x2013;559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Tan X, Li P, et al. Differentiation of malignant from benign pleural effusions based on artificial intelligence. Thorax. 2023;78:376&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai CH, van der Burgt J, Vukovic D, et al. Automatic deep learning-based pleural effusion classification in lung ultrasound images for respiratory pathology diagnosis. Phys Med. 2021;83:38&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association, AM Advancing AI in medical education through ethics, evidence and equity 2023 2/12/2025]. https://www.ama-assn.org/practice-management/digital/advancing-ai-medical-education-through-ethics-evidence-and-equity#:~:text=The%20AMA%20has%20created%20a%20framework%20for%20the,AMA%20promotes%20Trustworthy%20Augmented%20Intelligence%20in%20Health%20Care</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dave M, Patel N. Artificial intelligence in healthcare and education. Br Dent J. 2023;234:761&#x2013;764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cold KM, Xie S, Nielsen AO, et al. Artificial intelligence improves Novices&#x2019; bronchoscopy performance: a randomized controlled trial in a simulated setting. Chest. 2024;165:405&#x2013;413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okachi S, Sakurai M, Matsui T, et al. The application of mixed reality in bronchoscopy simulation training: a feasibility study. Surg Innov. 2023;30:685&#x2013;686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cold KM, Agbontaen K, Nielsen AO, et al. Artificial intelligence for automatic and objective assessment of competencies in flexible bronchoscopy. J Thorac Dis. 2024;16:5718&#x2013;5726.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>