<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41794945</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A pipeline leakage detection method for boiler energy operation system using enhanced SVM-based acoustic emission technology.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42769-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pipeline leakage detection in boiler energy systems is essential for operational safety and efficiency, yet conventional techniques such as pressure-based and mass-balance methods often lack real-time performance and sensitivity to small leaks. Although acoustic emission (AE) technology offers dynamic, non-destructive monitoring, its practical application is hindered by noise interference and limited training samples under industrial conditions. This paper introduces an enhanced support vector machine (SVM) framework designed for robust AE-based leakage detection. The proposed approach integrates three key contributions: first, a multi-domain feature fusion strategy that combines time-domain and frequency-domain parameters for enhanced signal separability; second, a spectral sparsity-guided dynamic kernel selection mechanism that adaptively optimizes the model for varying signal characteristics; and third, a margin-based boundary sample weighting strategy that mitigates the influence of noise near the hyperplane. Experiments involving three leakage types-spot, fracture, and explosion tube-were conducted under both low-noise (40 dB) and high-noise (70 dB) conditions. The model achieved perfect classification (100% accuracy) under quiet settings, and maintained accuracies of 92.3%, 88.1%, and 85.4% for the respective leak types under noisy conditions, outperforming conventional SVM by 12-15%. These results demonstrate that the proposed framework significantly improves detection reliability in noisy, data-scarce environments, providing a practical tool for early leakage identification in industrial boiler systems. Future work will focus on adaptive noise modeling and online threshold learning to further enhance the framework's robustness and adaptability in dynamic industrial settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Tianlong</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Engineering Research Center for High-Value Utilization of Magnesite, Yingkou, 115014, China. yuantianlong@yku.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Energy Storage and Utilization, Yingkou Institute of Technology, Yingkou, China. yuantianlong@yku.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaofei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Yingkou Electric Power Supply Company, Yingkou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Yingkou Electric Power Supply Company, Yingkou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Minghang</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Engineering Research Center for High-Value Utilization of Magnesite, Yingkou, 115014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Energy Storage and Utilization, Yingkou Institute of Technology, Yingkou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Grant No.LMNK2025020223</GrantID><Agency>the foundation of Liaoning Provincial Engineering Research Center for High-Value Utilization of Magnesite</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant No. 2023-MSLH-314</GrantID><Agency>the Natural Science Foundation of Liaoning Province of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant No.FDL202408</GrantID><Agency>Yingkou Institute of Technology campus level scientific research project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant No.HX202427</GrantID><Agency>Yingkou Institute of Technology campus level research project-Development of food additive supercritical extraction equipment and fluid transmission system research</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant No.CNNK202516</GrantID><Agency>the Foundation of Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Energy Storage and Utilization</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acoustic emission</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leakage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pipeline</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Support vector machine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41794945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42769-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42769-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. An adaptive grid generation approach to pipeline leakage rapid localization based on time reversal. Sensors 25, 1753 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Y. et al. Research on leak detection and localization algorithm for oil and gas pipelines using wavelet denoising integrated with long short-term memory (LSTM)&#x2013;transformer models. Sensors 25, 2411 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y., Yang, L., Duan, Q., Zhao, Z. &amp; Wang, Z. Research on detection methods for gas pipeline networks under small-hole leakage conditions. Sensors 25, 755 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, D. T., Nguyen, T. K., Ahmad, Z. &amp; Kim, J. M. A reliable pipeline leak detection method using acoustic emission with time difference of arrival and Kolmogorov&#x2013;Smirnov test. Sensors 23, 9296 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, D. et al. Edge intelligence: Empowering intelligence to the edge of network. Proc. IEEE 109, 1778&#x2013;1837 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, W., Ren, L. &amp; Tian, G. A novel defect quantification method utilizing multi-sensor magnetic flux leakage signal fusion. Sensors 24, 6623 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cirtautas, D., Samaitis, V., Ma&#x17e;eika, L. &amp; Rai&#x161;utis, R. Detection and classification of uniform and concentrated wall-thinning defects using high-order circumferential guided waves and artificial neural networks. Sensors 23, 6505 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Learning Filter Pruning Criteria for Deep Convolutional Neural Networks Acceleration. In: Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition. 2009&#x2013;2018. (Seattle, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J. et al. Memory-Friendly Scalable Super-Resolution via Rewinding Lottery Ticket Hypothesis. In: Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition.&#xa0;14398&#x2013;14407. (Vancouver, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, L. &amp; Li, S. Acoustic emission (AE) based small leak detection of galvanized steel pipe due to loosening of screw thread connection. Appl. Acoust. 120, 85&#x2013;89 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, C., Wen, Y., Li, P. &amp; Wen, J. Pipeline leakage acoustic signal enhancement using EMD. Chin. J. Sci. Instrum. 36, 1397&#x2013;1405 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, T., Zeng, Z., Huang, X., Li, J. &amp; Feng, H. Pipeline leak detection based on variational mode decomposition and support vector machine using an interior spherical detector. Process Saf. Environ. Prot. 153, 167&#x2013;177 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah, S., Ullah, N., Siddique, M. F., Ahmad, Z. &amp; Kim, J. M. Spatio-Temporal Feature Extraction for Pipeline Leak Detection in Smart Cities Using Acoustic Emission Signals: A One-Dimensional Hybrid Convolutional Neural Network&#x2013;Long Short-Term Memory Approach. Appl. Sci. 14, 10339 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gigih, P. &amp; Ghazali, M. F. Leak detection in pipelines using wavelet transform and cepstrum analysis methods. International Journal of Electrical, Energy and Power System Engineering 4, 159&#x2013;162 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, Y., Li, D., Song, Y., Xia, S. &amp; Wu, J. Novel deep learning framework for evaporator tube leakage estimation in supercharged boiler. Energies 18, 3986 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia, J., Rios-Colque, L., Pe&#xf1;a, A. &amp; Rojas, L. Condition Monitoring and Predictive Maintenance in Industrial Equipment: An NLP-Assisted Review of Signal Processing, Hybrid Models, and Implementation Challenges. Appl. Sci. 15, 5465 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. et al. Advanced Thermal Fluid Leakage Detection System with Machine Learning Algorithm for Pipe-In-Pipe Structure. Case Stud. Therm. Eng. 42, 102747 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luong, T. T. N. &amp; Kim, J. M. The enhancement of leak detection performance for water pipelines through the renovation of training data. Sensors 20, 2542 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang, K. W., Choi, J. H., Jeon, J. H. &amp; Kim, H. S. Combustible gas classification modeling using support vector machine and pairing plot scheme. Sensors 19, 5018 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem, F., Ahmad, Z., Siddique, M. F., Umar, M. &amp; Kim, J. M. Acoustic emission-based pipeline leak detection and size identification using a customized one-dimensional DenseNet. Sensors 25, 1112 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, Z., Nguyen, T. K. &amp; Kim, J. M. Leak detection and size identification in fluid pipelines using a novel vulnerability index and 1-D convolutional neural network. Eng. Appl. Comput. Fluid Mech. 17, 2165159 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. et al. Experimental research on in-pipe leaks detection of acoustic signature in gas pipelines based on the artificial neural network. Measurement 183, 109875 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umar, M., Siddique, M. F., Ullah, N. &amp; Kim, J. M. Milling Machine Fault Diagnosis Using Acoustic Emission and Hybrid Deep Learning with Feature Optimization. Appl. Sci. 14, 10404 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah, N., Siddique, M. F., Ullah, S., Ahmad, Z. &amp; Kim, J.-M. Pipeline leak detection system for a smart city: Leveraging acoustic emission sensing and sequential deep learning. Smart Cities 7, 2318&#x2013;2338 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, J., Park, Y. J., Lee, J., Wang, S. H. &amp; Eom, D. S. Novel leakage detection by ensemble CNN-SVM and graph-based localization in water distribution systems. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 65, 4279&#x2013;4289 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, W. et al. An Improved Convolutional Neural Network for Pipe Leakage Identification Based on Acoustic Emission.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>