<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41764278</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex-specific influence of maturity status on jumping performance in adolescents: a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41094-1</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bchini</LastName><ForeName>Souhail</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, 7100, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdellaoui</LastName><ForeName>Saber</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dergaa</LastName><ForeName>Ismail</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, 7100, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Activity, Sport and Health Research Unit, UR18JS01, National Observatory of Sport, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ceylan</LastName><ForeName>Halil &#x130;brahim</ForeName><Initials>H&#x130;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education of Sports Teaching Department, Faculty of Sports Sciences, Ataturk University, Erzurum, Turkey. halil.ibrahimceylan60@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Triki</LastName><ForeName>Raoua</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farhani</LastName><ForeName>Zouhaier</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, 7100, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moussaoui</LastName><ForeName>Dhouha</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muntean</LastName><ForeName>Raul Ioan</ForeName><Initials>RI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Faculty of Law and Social Sciences, University "1 Decembrie 1918" of Alba Iulia, Alba Iulia, Romania. muntean.raul@uab.ro.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abderrahman</LastName><ForeName>Abderraouf Ben</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Ksar Said, University of Manouba, 2010, Manouba, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Height</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Horizontal jump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plyometrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Puberty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tanner</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vertical jump</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval and consent to participate: All procedures were conducted following the Declaration of Helsinki. Informed consent was obtained from all participants&#x2019; parents or legal guardians. The study protocol was approved by the local research ethics committee of the High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba (approval code: c11-2024, January 18, 2024). It also complied with the ethical and procedural requirements for conducting sports medicine and exercise science research26.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41764278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41094-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41094-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lloyd, R. S. et al. Long-term athletic development, part 2: Barriers to success and potential solutions. J. Strength Cond. Res. 29, 1451&#x2013;1464 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic, G., Dizdar, D., Jukic, I. &amp; Cardinale, M. Reliability and factorial validity of squat and countermovement jump tests. J. Strength Cond. Res. 18, 551&#x2013;555 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagaduan, J., Schoenfeld, B. &amp; Pojski&#x107;, H. Systematic review and meta-analysis on the effect of contrast training on vertical jump performance. Strength Cond. J. 41, 63 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryman Augustsson, S., Arvidsson, J. &amp; Haglund, E. Jump height as performance indicator for the selection of youth football players to national teams. J. Sports Med. Phys. Fitness 59, 1669&#x2013;1675 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicol, C., Avela, J. &amp; Komi, P. V. The stretch-shortening cycle&#x202f;: A model to study naturally occurring neuromuscular fatigue. Sports Med. 36, 977&#x2013;999 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anicic, Z. et al. Assessment of countermovement jump: What should we report?. Life 13, 190 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedley, J. S. et al. A novel method to categorize stretch-shortening cycle performance across maturity in youth soccer players. J. Strength Cond. Res. 36, 2573&#x2013;2580 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focke, A. et al. Effects of age, sex and activity level on counter-movement jump performance in children and adolescents. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 13, 518&#x2013;526 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malina, R. M., Bouchard, C. &amp; Bar-Or, O. Growth, Maturation, and Physical Activity. (Human Kinetics, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortona, E., Pagano, M. T., Capossela, L. &amp; Malorni, W. The role of sex differences in bone health and healing. Biology (Basel). 12, 993 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillen, Z. M. et al. Influences of the stretch-shortening cycle and arm swing on vertical jump performance in children and adolescents. J. Strength Cond. Res. 36, 1245&#x2013;1256 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haischer, M. H. Influence of Maximal Strength on Joint-Specific Function and Coordination Across Stretch-Shortening Cycle Task Demands. https://epublications.marquette.edu/dissertations_mu/3195/ (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouguezzi, R. et al. Effects of jump exercises with and without stretch-shortening cycle actions on components of physical fitness in prepubertal male soccer players. Sport Sci. Health 16, 297&#x2013;304 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Fernandez, J., Can&#xf3;s-Portal&#xe9;s, J., Martinez-Gallego, R., Corbi, F. &amp; Baiget, E. Effects of maturation on lower-body neuromuscular performance in youth tennis players. J. Strength Cond. Res. 37, 167&#x2013;173 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niespodzi&#x144;ski, B. et al. The neuromuscular characteristics of gymnasts&#x2019; jumps and landings at particular stages of sports training. J. Hum. Kinet. 78, 15&#x2013;28 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bchini, S., Hammami, N., Selmi, T., Zalleg, D. &amp; Bouassida, A. Influence of muscle volume on jumping performance in healthy male and female youth and young adults. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabil. 15, 26 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylvester, R., Lehnert, M., Hanzl&#xed;kov&#xe1;, I. &amp; Krej&#x10d;&#xed;, J. The effect of plyometric training and moderating variables on stretch-shortening cycle function and physical qualities in female post peak height velocity volleyball players. Front. Physiol. 15, 1346624 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, N. T. A. et al. The influence of maturity status on drop jump kinetics in male youth. J. Strength Cond. Res. 38, 38&#x2013;46 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radnor, J. M., Oliver, J. L., Waugh, C. M., Myer, G. D. &amp; Lloyd, R. S. The influence of maturity status on muscle architecture in school-aged boys. Pediatr. Exerc. Sci. 32, 89&#x2013;96 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, T. et al. Longitudinal development of sprint performance and force-velocity-power characteristics: Influence of biological maturation. J. Strength Cond. Res. 37, 2178&#x2013;2184 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kite, R. J. The influence of maturity status on jumping performance of inner London secondary school students. (University of East London, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Mansour, G., Kacem, A., Ishak, M., Gr&#xe9;lot, L. &amp; Ftaiti, F. The effect of body composition on strength and power in male and female students. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabil. 13, 150 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birat, A. et al. Effect of drop height on vertical jumping performance in pre-, circa-, and post-pubertal boys and girls. Pediatr. Exerc. Sci. 32, 23&#x2013;29 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, T. et al. Influence of age and maturation status on sprint acceleration characteristics in junior Australian football. J. Sports Sci. 39, 1585&#x2013;1593 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozie&#x142;, S. M. &amp; Malina, R. M. Modified maturity offset prediction equations: Validation in independent longitudinal samples of boys and girls. Sports Med. 48, 221&#x2013;236 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guelmami, N. et al. The ethical compass: Establishing ethical guidelines for research practices in sports medicine and exercise science. Int. J. Sport Stud. Health 7, 31&#x2013;46 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serhier, Z., Bendahhou, K., Ben Abdelaziz, A. &amp; Bennani, M. O. Methodological sheet n&#xb0;1: How to calculate the size of a sample for an observational study?. Tunis. Med. 98, 1&#x2013;7 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammami, M. et al. The effect of a sand surface on physical performance responses of junior male handball players to plyometric training. BMC Sports Sci. Med. Rehabil. 12, 26 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methnani, J., Latiri, I., Dergaa, I., Chamari, K. &amp; Ben Saad, H. ChatGPT for sample-size calculation in sports medicine and exercise sciences: A cautionary note. Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 18, 1219&#x2013;1223 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souid, I., Fargier, P., Alin, C., Driss, T. &amp; Liotard, P. Curricular vulnerability of young physical education teachers in Tunisia through the prism of innovation. Tunis. J. Sports Sci. Med. 2, 25&#x2013;35 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souissi, M. A. et al. Impact of evening blue light exposure timing on sleep, motor, and cognitive performance in young athletes with intermediate chronotype. Biol. Sport 42, 61&#x2013;68 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirwald, R. L., Baxter-Jones, A. D., Bailey, D. A. &amp; Beunen, G. P. An assessment of maturity from anthropometric measurements. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 34, 689&#x2013;694 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez-Campillo, R. et al. Effects of in-season low-volume high-intensity plyometric training on explosive actions and endurance of young soccer players. J. Strength Cond. Res. 28, 1335&#x2013;1342 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo, T. K. &amp; Li, M. Y. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J. Chiropr. Med. 15, 155&#x2013;163 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins, W. G. A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics. New View Stat. 502, 321 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins, W. G. A new view of statistics: A scale of magnitudes for effect sizes. Retrieved January 9, 2014 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schabort, E.-J., Hopkins, W. G. &amp; Hawley, J. A. Reproducibility of self-paced treadmill performance of trained endurance runners. Int. J. Sports Med. 19, 48&#x2013;51 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulbricht, A., Fernandez-Fernandez, J., Mendez-Villanueva, A. &amp; Ferrauti, A. Impact of fitness characteristics on tennis performance in elite junior tennis players. J. Strength Cond. Res. 30, 989&#x2013;998 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bchini, S. et al. Relationship between muscle power, muscle volume and limb length in healthy male and female adolescents. Front. Sports Act Living 6, 1457948 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa, I. et al. Moving beyond the stigma: Understanding and overcoming the resistance to the acceptance and adoption of artificial intelligence Chatbots. New Asian J. Med. 1, 29&#x2013;36 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa, I. et al. A thorough examination of ChatGPT-3.5 potential applications in medical writing: A preliminary study. Medicine (Baltimore) 103, e39757 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>