<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41917983</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-2974</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of eating disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Eat Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute response and neurophysiological mechanisms of mindfulness meditation in emotional eating.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40337-026-01591-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Emotional eating often leads to adverse health outcomes. Understanding how mindfulness influences emotional eating is crucial for developing strategies to promote healthier eating behaviors and well-being. This study aims to investigate the mechanism and acute response to a mindfulness meditation practice on emotional eating by examining immediate post-intervention effects on brain activity and neurophysiological differences between individuals with and without emotional eating.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty-nine adults were recruited and allocated into two groups based on the emotional eating subscale score of the Dutch Eating Behavior Questionnaire: emotional eating (EE group) and non-emotional eating (comparison group). EEG was captured from three 14-min audio-guided mindfulness practices (MPs; each comprising three consecutive phases: mindful breathing [MPbreathing], emotion evocation [MPevocation], and meditation [MPmeditation]) and 5-min resting periods before and after each mindfulness practice. We compared between-group and between-condition differences in the EEG band power and examined potential correlations between EEG data and other participant characteristics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Following three MPs, the EE group exhibited a higher frontal midline theta power (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.051) and a lower frontal midline alpha power (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.059) compared with the comparison group. These effects primarily originated from the MPmeditation (theta band: corrected ps&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.03; alpha band: corrected ps&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.08). Two negative correlations were specifically found in the EE group: one between changes in frontal midline delta power and emotional eating behaviors, and another between beta-1 power and cognitive reappraisal that emerged in the MPmeditation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that the modulation of frontal midline theta and alpha activity may contribute to the immediate effects of mindfulness meditation in remediating emotional eating. The clinical significance of the correlation between delta activity and emotional eating severity warrants further investigation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Roy Rongyue</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Rangchun</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Hiu Yin</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Hei Yuen</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lau</LastName><ForeName>Ka Siu</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hung</LastName><ForeName>Ka Yan</ForeName><Initials>KY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwok</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guasch</LastName><ForeName>Nestor Vinas</ForeName><Initials>NV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahorsu</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Kwasi</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Special Education and Counselling, The Education University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>Tiev</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Yushen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cruz-Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Pablo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Research Institute of Singapore, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lau</LastName><ForeName>Benson Wui-Man</ForeName><Initials>BW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR. benson.lau@polyu.edu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jack Jiaqi</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR. jack-jiaqi.zhang@polyu.edu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanchez Vidana</LastName><ForeName>Dalinda Isabel</ForeName><Initials>DI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR. dalinda.sanchezvidana@connect.polyu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mindfulness Training Centre, Kowloon, Hong Kong SAR. dalinda.sanchezvidana@connect.polyu.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Eat Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610672</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-2974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>We compared two groups of adults: those who often eat emotionally and those who do not. Both groups took part in three mindfulness practice sessions, and we measured their brain activity before, during, and after each session. We found that people who struggle with emotional eating showed different patterns of brain activity during meditation compared to those who do not eat emotionally. Specifically, certain brain signals linked to emotional processing were stronger in the emotional eating group during meditation. However, these brain changes did not directly relate to how much people reported emotional eating. Our findings suggest that mindfulness may affect the way the brain processes emotions in people who eat emotionally. This could help guide new ways to support people in managing emotional eating and improving their overall well-being.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disordered eating behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emotional regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesh</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mindfulness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurophysiology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was registered at the Hong Kong University Clinical Trial Registry (HKUCTR-3034) and obtained ethical approval from the Hong Kong Polytechnic University (HSEARS20240507003). Informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to conducting the study in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki principles. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41917983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40337-026-01591-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40337-026-01591-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Godet A, Fortier A, Bannier E, Coquery N, Val-Laillet D. Interactions between emotions and eating behaviors: main issues, neuroimaging contributions, and innovative preventive or corrective strategies. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2022;23(4):807&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew HSJ, Soong RY, Ang WHD, Ngooi JW, Park J, Yong JQYO, et al. The global prevalence of emotional eating in overweight and obese populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychol. 2025;116(2):484&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madal&#x131; B, Alkan &#x15e;B, &#xd6;rs ED, Ayranc&#x131; M, Ta&#x15f;k&#x131;n H, Kara HH. Emotional eating behaviors during the COVID-19 pandemic: a cross-sectional study. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;46:264&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabat-Zinn J. Mindfulness-based interventions in context: past, present, and future. Clin Psychol Sci Pract. 2003;10(2):144&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker KK. Mindfulness meditation: do-it-yourself medicalization of every moment. Soc Sci Med. 2014;1(106):168&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katterman SN, Kleinman BM, Hood MM, Nackers LM, Corsica JA. Mindfulness meditation as an intervention for binge eating, emotional eating, and weight loss: a systematic review. Eat Behav. 2014;15(2):197&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett J, Greene G, Schwartz-Barcott D. Perceptions of emotional eating behavior. A qualitative study of college students. Appetite. 2013;60:187&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, She Z, Siu AFY, Zeng X, Liu X. Effectiveness of online mindfulness-based interventions on psychological distress and the mediating role of emotion regulation. Front Psychol. 2018;9:2090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalen J, Smith BW, Shelley BM, Sloan AL, Leahigh L, Begay D. Pilot study: mindful eating and living (MEAL): weight, eating behavior, and psychological outcomes associated with a mindfulness-based intervention for people with obesity. Complement Ther Med. 2010;18(6):260&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahne E, Rosselli M. The impact of a single, brief mindfulness intervention on cognitive and emotional reactivity: an EEG study. Mindfulness. 2024;15(8):1940&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R, Liu L. Eight-week mindfulness training enhances left frontal EEG asymmetry during emotional challenge: a randomized controlled trial. Mindfulness. 2017;8(1):181&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blechert J, Goltsche JE, Herbert BM, Wilhelm FH. Eat your troubles away: electrocortical and experiential correlates of food image processing are related to emotional eating style and emotional state. Biol Psychol. 2014;1(96):94&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denke G, Rawls E, Lamm C. Attentional conflict moderates the association between anxiety and emotional eating behavior: an ERP study. Front Hum Neurosci. 2018;12:194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertl M, Hildebrandt M, Ourina K, Leicht G, Mulert C. Emotion regulation by cognitive reappraisal&#x2014;the role of frontal theta oscillations. Neuroimage. 2013;1(81):412&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan WH, Yeh WT. How to define obesity? Evidence-based multiple action points for public awareness, screening, and treatment: an extension of Asian-Pacific recommendations. Asia Pac J Clin Nutr. 2008;17(3):370&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattimore P. Mindfulness-based emotional eating awareness training: taking the emotional out of eating. Eat Weight Disord. 2020;25(3):649&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhart WR, Kalantzis MA, Braden AL. Mindfulness facets differentially relate to self-reported negative and positive emotional eating types in treatment-seeking adults with overweight/obesity. Eat Weight Disord. 2023;28(1):54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macht M. Reduction of emotional eating with a mindfulness-based group training: a randomized controlled experience-sampling study [Internet]. Research Square; 2022 [cited 2025 Apr 29]. Available from: https://www.researchsquare.com/article/rs-1834873/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagl M, Hilbert A, de Zwaan M, Braehler E, Kersting A. The German version of the Dutch eating behavior questionnaire: psychometric properties, measurement invariance, and population-based norms. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(9):e0162510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnepper R, Richard A, Wilhelm FH, Blechert J. A combined mindfulness-prolonged chewing intervention reduces body weight, food craving, and emotional eating. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2019;87(1):106&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duane A, Casimir AE, Mims LC, Kaler-Jones C, Simmons D. Beyond deep breathing: a new vision for equitable, culturally responsive, and trauma-informed mindfulness practice. Middle School J [Internet]. 2021 May 27 [cited 2025 Apr 29]; Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/00940771.2021.1893593</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrill EP, Kramer FM, Cardello A, Schutz H. A comparison of satiety measures. Appetite. 2002;39(2):181&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meule A, Reichenberger J, Blechert J. Development and preliminary validation of the Salzburg emotional eating scale. Front Psychol. 2018;6(9):88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meule A, Reichenberger J, Blechert J. Development and preliminary validation of the Salzburg stress eating scale. Appetite. 2018;1(120):442&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meule A, Hermann T, K&#xfc;bler A. A short version of the food cravings questionnaire&#x2014;trait: the FCQ-T-reduced. Front Psychol [Internet]. 2014 Mar 4 [cited 2025 May 7];5. Available from: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00190/full</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hormes JM, Meule A. Psychometric properties of the English food cravings questionnaire-trait-reduced (FCQ-T-r). Eat Behav. 2016;1(20):34&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross JJ, John OP. Individual differences in two emotion regulation processes: implications for affect, relationships, and well-being. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2003;85(2):348&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson D, Clark LA, Tellegen A. Development and validation of brief measures of positive and negative affect: the PANAS scales. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1988;54(6):1063&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JJ, Bai Z, Fong KNK. Resting-state cortical electroencephalogram rhythms and network in patients after chronic stroke. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2024;21(1):32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aftanas LI, Golocheikine SA. Human anterior and frontal midline theta and lower alpha reflect emotionally positive state and internalized attention: high-resolution EEG investigation of meditation. Neurosci Lett. 2001;310(1):57&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao G, Zhang Y, Ge Y. Frontal EEG asymmetry and middle line power difference in discrete emotions. Front Behav Neurosci. 2018;12:225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhang PA, Gawali BW, Mehrotra SC. Introduction to EEG- and speech-based emotion recognition. 1st Edition. Academic Press; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fingelkurts AA, Fingelkurts AA, Kallio-Tamminen T. EEG-guided meditation: a personalized approach. Journal of Physiology-Paris. 2015;109(4):180&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlet I, Guillery M, Weyl L, Hammal M, Maliia M, Maliia S, et al. EEG changes induced by meditative practices: state and trait effects in healthy subjects and in patients with epilepsy. Revue Neurologique. 2024;180(4):326&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekkedal MYV, Rossi J, Panksepp J. Human brain EEG indices of emotions: delineating responses to affective vocalizations by measuring frontal theta event-related synchronization. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2011;35(9):1959&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ntekin B, Ba&#x15f;ar E. A review of brain oscillations in perception of faces and emotional pictures. Neuropsychologia. 2014;1(58):33&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DJ, Kulubya E, Goldin P, Goodarzi A, Girgis F. Review of the neural oscillations underlying meditation. Front Neurosci. 2018;26(12):178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Larios J, Bracho Montes de Oca EA, Alaerts K. The EEG spectral properties of meditation and mind wandering differ between experienced meditators and novices. NeuroImage. 2021;245:118669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amihai I, Kozhevnikov M. Arousal vs. Relaxation: A comparison of the neurophysiological and cognitive correlates of Vajrayana and Theravada meditative practices. PLOS ONE. 2014;9(7):e102990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy J, Devue C, Corballis PM, Grimshaw GM. Proactive control of emotional distraction: evidence from EEG alpha suppression. Front Hum Neurosci. 2020;18(14):318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmony T. The functional significance of delta oscillations in cognitive processing. Front Integr Neurosci. [Internet]. 2013 Dec 5 [cited 2025 Apr 28];7. Available from: https://doi.org/10.3389/fnint.2013.00083/full</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knyazev GG, Slobodskoj-Plusnin JY, Bocharov AV. Event-related delta and theta synchronization during explicit and implicit emotion processing. Neuroscience. 2009;164(4):1588&#x2013;600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duda AT, Clarke AR, Barry RJ, De Blasio FM. Mindfulness meditation is associated with global EEG spectral changes in theta, alpha, and beta amplitudes. Int J Psychophysiol. 2024;1(206):112465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakumanu RJ, Nair AK, Venugopal R, Sasidharan A, Ghosh PK, John JP, et al. Dissociating meditation proficiency and experience dependent EEG changes during traditional Vipassana meditation practice. Biol Psychol. 2018;1(135):65&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomas T, Ivtzan I, Fu CHY. A systematic review of the neurophysiology of mindfulness on EEG oscillations. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2015;1(57):401&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tei S, Faber PL, Lehmann D, Tsujiuchi T, Kumano H, Pascual-Marqui RD, et al. Meditators and non-meditators: EEG source imaging during resting. Brain Topogr. 2009;22(3):158&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quoidbach J, Berry EV, Hansenne M, Mikolajczak M. Positive emotion regulation and well-being: comparing the impact of eight savoring and dampening strategies. Personality Individ Differ. 2010;49(5):368&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Ban Y, Pan G, Yao M, Liu L, Chen T, et al. Effects of online mindfulness-based stress reduction training on depression and anxiety symptoms among psychiatric healthcare workers in a randomized controlled trial: the mediating role of emotional suppression. BMC Psychiatry. 2025;25(1):577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greeson JM, Zarrin H, Smoski MJ, Brantley JG, Lynch TR, Webber DM, et al. Mindfulness meditation targets transdiagnostic symptoms implicated in stress-related disorders: understanding relationships between changes in mindfulness, sleep quality, and physical symptoms. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2018;2018(1):4505191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abid A, Hamrick HC, Mach RJ, Hager NM, Judah MR. Emotion regulation strategies explain associations of theta and Beta with positive affect. Psychophysiology. 2025;62(1):e14745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domic-Siede M, S&#xe1;nchez-Corzo A, Guzm&#xe1;n-Gonz&#xe1;lez M. Brain oscillations during emotion regulation and the two-dimensional model of adult attachment. Biol Psychol. 2024;1(189):108793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy-Moore E, Watson JC. How and when does emotional expression help? Rev Gen Psychol. 2001;5(3):187&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi R, Honda T, Hashimoto J, Kashihara S, Iwasa Y, Yamamoto K, et al. Resting-state theta/beta ratio is associated with distraction but not with reappraisal. Biol Psychol. 2020;1(155):107942.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>