<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41884406</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2155-5435</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS catalysis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Catal</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Slowdown of Enzymatic Cellulose Conversion Emerges from Cellulase Mode of Action.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5603</StartPage><EndPage>5615</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5603-5615</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acscatal.5c08098</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The problem of early slowing of the conversion rate in cellulose hydrolysis, and the resulting large amounts of cellulase enzymes required to achieve just useful conversion efficiencies, remains a major obstacle in the development of cellulosic biofuels. While numerous studies have implicated both substrate and enzyme factors, the underlying mechanism of this rate limitation has remained unresolved. Here, using bacterial cellulose as a well-defined model substrate, we demonstrate that the reaction slowdown emerges from the specific mode of substrate degradation imposed by the cellulolytic enzyme system. We introduce nanomechanical mapping by time-lapse in situ atomic force microscopy to characterize at nanometer spatial resolution the change in surface material organization of cellulose due to enzymatic degradation. The layer-by-layer ablation of surface material utilized by fungal cellulases results in the gradual exposure of the nanomechanically stiffer (i.e., more densely organized and hence more resistant) inner core of the cellulose fibrils, which leads to a rapid decline in the conversion rate by these enzymes. Cellulases assembled into stable complexes (the cellulosome) bind almost irreversibly to cellulose. Low dynamics of their adsorption causes stalling of the cellulose degradation as the portion of unproductively bound enzymes increases during the conversion. Together, these findings reveal distinct, system-specific slowdown mechanisms and uncover a functional interplay between substrate nanomechanics and enzyme adsorption dynamics that dictates overall conversion efficiency. By disentangling these coupled rate-limiting factors, this work establishes previously unrecognized molecular design principles for engineering cellulase systems capable of overcoming the intrinsic substrate recalcitrance of crystalline cellulose.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eibinger</LastName><ForeName>Manuel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3139-5394</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biotechnology and Biochemical Engineering, Graz University of Technology, NAWI Graz, A-8010 Graz, Austria.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">27253</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaira</LastName><ForeName>Gaurav Singh</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2337-1456</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biotechnology and Biochemical Engineering, Graz University of Technology, NAWI Graz, A-8010 Graz, Austria.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">27253</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Austrian Centre of Industrial Biotechnology (acib), A-8010 Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nidetzky</LastName><ForeName>Bernd</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5030-2643</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biotechnology and Biochemical Engineering, Graz University of Technology, NAWI Graz, A-8010 Graz, Austria.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">27253</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Austrian Centre of Industrial Biotechnology (acib), A-8010 Graz, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Catal</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101562209</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AFM nanomechanical mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellulase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellulose degradation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellulose recalcitrance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellulosome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enzymatic rate retardation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrolysis slowdown</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41884406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13010264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscatal.5c08098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Robertson G. P., Hamilton S. K., Barham B. L., Dale B. E., Izaurralde R. C., Jackson R. D., Landis D. A., Swinton S. M., Thelen K. D., Tiedje J. M.. Cellulosic Biofuel Contributions to a Sustainable Energy Future: Choices and Outcomes. Science. 2017;356(6345):eaal2324. doi: 10.1126/science.aal2324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aal2324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28663443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field J. L., Richard T. L., Smithwick E. A. H., Cai H., Laser M. S., LeBauer D. S., Long S. P., Paustian K., Qin Z., Sheehan J. J., Smith P., Wang M. Q., Lynd L. R.. Robust Paths to Net Greenhouse Gas Mitigation and Negative Emissions via Advanced Biofuels. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2020;117(36):21968&#x2013;21977. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1920877117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1920877117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso D. M., Hakim S. H., Zhou S., Won W., Hosseinaei O., Tao J., Garcia-Negron V., Motagamwala A. H., Mellmer M. A., Huang K., Houtman C. J., Labb&#xe9; N., Harper D. P., Maravelias C. T., Runge T., Dumesic J. A.. Increasing the Revenue from Lignocellulosic Biomass: Maximizing Feedstock Utilization. Sci. Adv. 2017;3(5):e1603301. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.1603301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.1603301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5438221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28560350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Wang Y., Liu J., Yu H., Liu P., Yang Y., Sun D., Kang H., Wang Y., Tang J., Fu C., Peng L.. Integration of Advanced Biotechnology for Green Carbon. Green Carbon. 2024;2(2):164&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1016/j.greenca.2024.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.greenca.2024.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Gao H., Wang Y., He B., Lu J., Zhu W., Peng L., Wang Y.. Challenges and Perspectives of Green-like Lignocellulose Pretreatments Selectable for Low-Cost Biofuels and High-Value Bioproduction. Bioresour. Technol. 2023;369:128315. doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2022.128315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2022.128315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36414143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holwerda E. K., Worthen R. S., Kothari N., Lasky R. C., Davison B. H., Fu C., Wang Z.-Y., Dixon R. A., Biswal A. K., Mohnen D., Nelson R. S., Baxter H. L., Mazarei M., Stewart C. N., Muchero W., Tuskan G. A., Cai C. M., Gjersing E. E., Davis M. F., Himmel M. E., Wyman C. E., Gilna P., Lynd L. R.. Multiple Levers for Overcoming the Recalcitrance of Lignocellulosic Biomass. Biotechnol. Biofuels. 2019;12(1):15. doi: 10.1186/s13068-019-1353-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13068-019-1353-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6335785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30675183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Himmel M. E., Ding S.-Y., Johnson D. K., Adney W. S., Nimlos M. R., Brady J. W., Foust T. D.. Biomass Recalcitrance: Engineering Plants and Enzymes for Biofuels Production. Science. 2007;315(5813):804&#x2013;807. doi: 10.1126/science.1137016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1137016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17289988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCann M. C., Carpita N. C.. Biomass Recalcitrance: A Multi-Scale, Multi-Factor, and Conversion-Specific Property. J. Exp. Bot. 2015;66(14):4109&#x2013;4118. doi: 10.1093/jxb/erv267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/erv267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26060266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrett O. M., Lyczakowski J. J., Yu L., Iuga D., Franks W. T., Brown S. P., Dupree R., Dupree P.. Molecular Architecture of Softwood Revealed by Solid-State NMR. Nat. Commun. 2019;10(1):4978. doi: 10.1038/s41467-019-12979-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-12979-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6823442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31673042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes A. N., Thomas L. H., Altaner C. M., Callow P., Forsyth V. T., Apperley D. C., Kennedy C. J., Jarvis M. C.. Nanostructure of Cellulose Microfibrils in Spruce Wood. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2011;108(47):1195&#x2013;1203. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1108942108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1108942108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3223458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22065760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yurtsever A., Wang P.-X., Priante F., Morais Jaques Y., Miyazawa K., MacLachlan M. J., Foster A. S., Fukuma T.. Molecular Insights on the Crystalline Cellulose-Water Interfaces via Three-Dimensional Atomic Force Microscopy. Sci. Adv. 2022;8(41):160. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.abq0160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abq0160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9565791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36240279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chundawat S. P. S., Beckham G. T., Himmel M. E., Dale B. E.. Deconstruction of Lignocellulosic Biomass to Fuels and Chemicals. Annu. Rev. Chem. Biomol. Eng. 2011;2(1):121&#x2013;145. doi: 10.1146/annurev-chembioeng-061010-114205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-chembioeng-061010-114205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22432613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne C. M., Knott B. C., Mayes H. B., Hansson H., Himmel M. E., Sandgren M., St&#xe5;hlberg J., Beckham G. T.. Fungal Cellulases. Chem. Rev. 2015;115(3):1308&#x2013;1448. doi: 10.1021/cr500351c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/cr500351c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25629559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis C. E. R., Libardi Junior N., Bento H. B. S., Carvalho A. K. F. de, Vandenberghe L. P. de S., Soccol C. R., Aminabhavi T. M., Chandel A. K.. Process Strategies to Reduce Cellulase Enzyme Loading for Renewable Sugar Production in Biorefineries. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;451:138690. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.138690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.138690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckham G. T., Matthews J. F., Peters B., Bomble Y. J., Himmel M. E., Crowley M. F.. Molecular-Level Origins of Biomass Recalcitrance: Decrystallization Free Energies for Four Common Cellulose Polymorphs. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2011;115(14):4118&#x2013;4127. doi: 10.1021/jp1106394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp1106394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21425804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arantes V., Saddler J. N.. Access to Cellulose Limits the Efficiency of Enzymatic Hydrolysis: The Role of Amorphogenesis. Biotechnol. Biofuels. 2010;3:4. doi: 10.1186/1754-6834-3-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1754-6834-3-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2844368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20178562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng X., Ragauskas A. J.. Recent Advances in Understanding the Role of Cellulose Accessibility in Enzymatic Hydrolysis of Lignocellulosic Substrates. Curr. Opin. Biotechnol. 2014;27:150&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1016/j.copbio.2014.01.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.copbio.2014.01.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24549148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y.-H. P., Lynd L. R.. Toward an Aggregated Understanding of Enzymatic Hydrolysis of Cellulose: Noncomplexed Cellulase Systems. Biotechnol. Bioeng. 2004;88(7):797&#x2013;824. doi: 10.1002/bit.20282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bit.20282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15538721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciesielski P. N., Wagner R., Bharadwaj V. S., Killgore J., Mittal A., Beckham G. T., Decker S. R., Himmel M. E., Crowley M. F.. Nanomechanics of Cellulose Deformation Reveal Molecular Defects That Facilitate Natural Deconstruction. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2019;116(20):201900161. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1900161116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1900161116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6525519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31036649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Y., de Beeck B. O., Thielemans K., Ennaert T., Snelders J., Dusselier M., Courtin C. M., Sels B. F.. The Role of Pretreatment in the Catalytic Valorization of Cellulose. Mol. Catal. 2020;487:110883. doi: 10.1016/j.mcat.2020.110883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcat.2020.110883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novy V., A&#xef;ssa K., Nielsen F., Straus S. K., Ciesielski P., Hunt C. G., Saddler J.. Quantifying Cellulose Accessibility during Enzyme-Mediated Deconstruction Using 2 Fluorescence-Tagged Carbohydrate-Binding Modules. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2019;116(45):22545&#x2013;22551. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1912354116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1912354116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6842628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31636211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chundawat S. P. S., Donohoe B. S., da Costa Sousa L., Elder T., Agarwal U. P., Lu F., Ralph J., Himmel M. E., Balan V., Dale B. E.. Multi-Scale Visualization and Characterization of Lignocellulosic Plant Cell Wall Deconstruction during Thermochemical Pretreatment. Energy Environ. Sci. 2011;4(3):973. doi: 10.1039/c0ee00574f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c0ee00574f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Hu Z., Peng H., Liu P., Wang Y., Li J., Lu J., Wang Y., Xia T., Peng L.. High Density Cellulose Nanofibril Assembly Leads to Upgraded Enzymatic and Chemical Catalysis of Fermentable Sugars, Cellulose Nanocrystals and Cellulase Production by Precisely Engineering Cellulose Synthase Complexes. Green Chem. 2023;25(3):1096&#x2013;1106. doi: 10.1039/D2GC03744K.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2GC03744K</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeoh T., Cardona M. J., Karuna N., Mudinoor A. R., Nill J.. Mechanistic Kinetic Models of Enzymatic Cellulose Hydrolysis-A Review. Biotechnol. Bioeng. 2017;114(7):1369&#x2013;1385. doi: 10.1002/bit.26277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bit.26277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28244589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall M., Bansal P., Lee J. H., Realff M. J., Bommarius A. S.. Cellulose Crystallinity-a Key Predictor of the Enzymatic Hydrolysis Rate. FEBS J. 2010;277(6):1571&#x2013;1582. doi: 10.1111/j.1742-4658.2010.07585.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1742-4658.2010.07585.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20148968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Hu Z., Wang Y., Hu H., Li F., Li M., Ragauskas A., Xia T., Han H., Tang J., Yu H., Xu B., Peng L.. Single-Molecular Insights into the Breakpoint of Cellulose Nanofibers Assembly during Saccharification. Nat. Commun. 2023;14(1):1100. doi: 10.1038/s41467-023-36856-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-36856-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9968341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36841862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen J. P., Donohoe B. S., Borch K., Westh P., Resch M. G.. Interrelationships between Cellulase Activity and Cellulose Particle Morphology. Cellulose. 2016;23(4):2349&#x2013;2361. doi: 10.1007/s10570-016-0979-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-016-0979-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L. T., Lee Y., Beardmore D. H.. Mechanism of the Enzymatic Hydrolysis of Cellulose: Effects of Major Structural Features of Cellulose on Enzymatic Hydrolysis. Biotechnol. Bioeng. 1980;22(1):177&#x2013;199. doi: 10.1002/bit.260220113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bit.260220113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grethlein H. E.. The Effect of Pore Size Distribution on the Rate of Enzymatic Hydrolysis of Cellulosic Substrates. Nat. Biotechnol. 1985;3(2):155&#x2013;160. doi: 10.1038/nbt0285-155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nbt0285-155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J., Dong Y., Zhang H., Liu J., Renneckar S., Saddler J.. Reduced Cellulose Accessibility Slows down Enzyme-Mediated Hydrolysis of Cellulose. Bioresour. Technol. 2023;371:128647. doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2023.128647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2023.128647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36681353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezaki T., Nishinari K., Samejima M., Igarashi K.. Bridging the Micro-Macro Gap between Single-Molecular Behavior and Bulk Hydrolysis Properties of Cellulase. Phys. Rev. Lett. 2019;122(9):098102. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.122.098102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.122.098102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30932525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igarashi K., Uchihashi T., Koivula A., Wada M., Kimura S., Okamoto T., Penttila M., Ando T., Samejima M.. Traffic Jams Reduce Hydrolytic Efficiency of Cellulase on Cellulose Surface. Science. 2011;333(6047):1279&#x2013;1282. doi: 10.1126/science.1208386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1208386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21885779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson T., Karlsson J., Tjerneld F.. A Model Explaining Declining Rate in Hydrolysis of Lignocellulose Substrates with Cellobiohydrolase I (Cel7A) and Endoglucanase I (Cel7B) of Trichoderma Reesei . Appl. Biochem. Biotechnol. 2002;101(1):41&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1385/ABAB:101:1:41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1385/ABAB:101:1:41</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12008866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nill J. D., Jeoh T.. The Role of Evolving Interfacial Substrate Properties on Heterogeneous Cellulose Hydrolysis Kinetics. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2020;8(17):6722&#x2013;6733. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.0c00779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.0c00779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooshima H., Kurakake M., Kato J., Harano Y.. Enzymatic Activity of Cellulase Adsorbed on Cellulose and Its Change during Hydrolysis. Appl. Biochem. Biotechnol. 1991;31(3):253&#x2013;266. doi: 10.1007/BF02921752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02921752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1818538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafle K., Shin H., Lee C. M., Park S., Kim S. H.. Progressive Structural Changes of Avicel, Bleached Softwood and Bacterial Cellulose during Enzymatic Hydrolysis. Sci. Rep. 2015;5(1):15102. doi: 10.1038/srep15102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep15102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4604514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinitsyn A. P., Mitkevich O. V., Gusakov A. V., Klyosov A. A.. Decrease in Reactivity and Change of Physico-Chemical Parameters of Cellulose in the Course of Enzymatic Hydrolysis. Carbohydr. Polym. 1989;10(1):1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/0144-8617(89)90028-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0144-8617(89)90028-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansfield S., Mooney C., Saddler J.. Substrate and Enzyme Characteristics That Limit Cellulose Hydrolysis. Biotechnol. Prog. 1999;15(5):804&#x2013;816. doi: 10.1021/bp9900864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bp9900864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10514250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nill J., Karuna N., Jeoh T.. The Impact of Kinetic Parameters on Cellulose Hydrolysis Rates. Proc. Biochem. 2018;74:108&#x2013;117. doi: 10.1016/j.procbio.2018.07.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procbio.2018.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe4;ljam&#xe4;e P., Sild V., Pettersson G., Johansson G.. The Initial Kinetics of Hydrolysis by Cellobiohydrolases I and II Is Consistent with a Cellulose Surface-Erosion Model. Eur. J. Biochem. 1998;253(2):469&#x2013;475. doi: 10.1046/j.1432-1327.1998.2530469.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1432-1327.1998.2530469.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9654098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeoh T., Nill J. D., Zhao W., Narayanasamy S. R., Chen L., Holman H.-Y. N.. Spatiotemporal Dynamics of Cellulose during Enzymatic Hydrolysis Studied by Infrared Spectromicroscopy. Green Chem. 2024;26(1):396&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1039/D3GC03279E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3GC03279E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajki-Zechmeister K., Kaira G. S., Eibinger M., Seelich K., Nidetzky B.. Processive Enzymes Kept on a Leash: How Cellulase Activity in Multienzyme Complexes Directs Nanoscale Deconstruction of Cellulose. ACS Catal. 2021;11(21):13530&#x2013;13542. doi: 10.1021/acscatal.1c03465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscatal.1c03465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34777910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artzi L., Bayer E. A., Mora&#xef;s S.. Cellulosomes: Bacterial Nanomachines for Dismantling Plant Polysaccharides. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2017;15(2):83&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1038/nrmicro.2016.164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrmicro.2016.164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27941816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora&#xef;s S., Winkler S., Zorea A., Levin L., Nagies F. S. P., Kapust N., Lamed E., Artan-Furman A., Bolam D. N., Yadav M. P., Bayer E. A., Martin W. F., Mizrahi I.. Cryptic Diversity of Cellulose-Degrading Gut Bacteria in Industrialized Humans. Science. 2024;383(6688):eadj9223. doi: 10.1126/science.adj9223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.adj9223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38484069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajki-Zechmeister K., Eibinger M., Kaira G. S., Nidetzky B.. Mechanochemical Coupling of Catalysis and Motion in a Cellulose-Degrading Multienzyme Nanomachine. ACS Catal. 2024;14(4):2656&#x2013;2663. doi: 10.1021/acscatal.3c05653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscatal.3c05653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10877591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38384941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatoon Z., Anandharaj M., Chen T.-H., Wu C.-C., Cheng J.-F., Hsu T.-L., Lin H.-C., Chang J.-J., Li W.-H.. Creating a Large Designer Cellulosome in Yeast to Boost Ethanol Production. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2025;122(45):e2517490122. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2517490122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2517490122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12625909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41201822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babi M., Williams A., Reid M., Grandfield K., Bassim N. D., Moran-Mirabal J. M.. Unraveling the Supramolecular Structure and Nanoscale Dislocations of Bacterial Cellulose Ribbons Using Correlative Super-Resolution Light and Electron Microscopy. Biomacromolecules. 2023;24(1):258&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1021/acs.biomac.2c01108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.biomac.2c01108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36577132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown R. M.. Cellulose Structure and Biosynthesis: What Is in Store for the 21st Century? J. Polym. Sci. A Polym. Chem. 2004;42(3):487&#x2013;495. doi: 10.1002/pola.10877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pola.10877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemm D., Heublein B., Fink H.-P., Bohn A.. Cellulose: Fascinating Biopolymer and Sustainable Raw Material. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. Engl. 2005;44(22):3358&#x2013;3393. doi: 10.1002/anie.200460587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.200460587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15861454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haigler C. H., Brown R. M., Benziman M.. Calcofluor White ST Alters the in Vivo Assembly of Cellulose Microfibrils. Science. 1980;210(4472):903&#x2013;906. doi: 10.1126/science.7434003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.7434003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7434003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye D., Rongpipi S., Kiemle S. N., Barnes W. J., Chaves A. M., Zhu C., Norman V. A., Liebman-Pel&#xe1;ez A., Hexemer A., Toney M. F., Roberts A. W., Anderson C. T., Cosgrove D. J., Gomez E. W., Gomez E. D.. Preferred Crystallographic Orientation of Cellulose in Plant Primary Cell Walls. Nat. Commun. 2020;11(1):1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-18449-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-18449-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32948753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung J., Sethi A., Gaiotto T., Han J. J., Jeoh T., Gnanakaran S., Goodwin P. M.. Binding and Movement of Individual Cel7A Cellobiohydrolases on Crystalline Cellulose Surfaces Revealed by Single-Molecule Fluorescence Imaging. J. Biol. Chem. 2013;288:24164&#x2013;24172. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M113.455758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M113.455758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3745362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23818525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igarashi K., Wada M., Hori R., Samejima M.. Surface Density of Cellobiohydrolase on Crystalline Celluloses. A Critical Parameter to Evaluate Enzymatic Kinetics at a Solid-Liquid Interface. FEBS J. 2006;273(13):2869&#x2013;2878. doi: 10.1111/j.1742-4658.2006.05299.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1742-4658.2006.05299.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16759230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura A., Tasaki T., Ishiwata D., Yamamoto M., Okuni Y., Visootsat A., Maximilien M., Noji H., Uchiyama T., Samejima M., Igarashi K., Iino R.. Single-Molecule Imaging Analysis of Binding, Processive Movement, and Dissociation of Cellobiohydrolase Trichoderma Reesei Cel6A and Its Domains on Crystalline Cellulose. J. Biol. Chem. 2016;291(43):22404&#x2013;22413. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M116.752048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M116.752048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5077181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27609516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nong D., Haviland Z. K., Zexer N., Pfaff S. A., Cosgrove D. J., Tien M., Anderson C. T., Hancock W. O.. Single-Molecule Tracking Reveals Dual Front Door/Back Door Inhibition of Cel7A Cellulase by Its Product Cellobiose. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2024;121(18):e2322567121. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2322567121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2322567121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11067010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38648472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morag E., Yaron S., Lamed R., Kenig R., Shoham Y., Bayer E. A.. Dissociation of the Cellulosome of Clostridium Thermocellum under Nondenaturing Conditions. J. Biotechnol. 1996;51(3):235&#x2013;242. doi: 10.1016/S0168-1656(96)01601-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0168-1656(96)01601-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8988649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kont R., Kari J., Borch K., Westh P., V&#xe4;ljam&#xe4;e P.. Inter-Domain Synergism Is Required for Efficient Feeding of Cellulose Chain into Active Site of Cellobiohydrolase Cel7A. J. Biol. Chem. 2016;291(50):26013&#x2013;26023. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M116.756007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M116.756007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5207072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27780868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalak J., Kura&#x161;in M., Teugjas H., V&#xe4;ljam&#xe4;e P.. Endo-Exo Synergism in Cellulose Hydrolysis Revisited. J. Biol. Chem. 2012;287(34):28802&#x2013;28815. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M112.381624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M112.381624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3436550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22733813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalak J., V&#xe4;ljam&#xe4;e P.. Multi-Mode Binding of Cellobiohydrolase Cel7A from Trichoderma Reesei to Cellulose. PLoS One. 2014;9(9):e108181. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0108181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0108181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4180464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25265511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruys-Bagger N., Tatsumi H., Ren G. R., Borch K., Westh P.. Transient Kinetics and Rate-Limiting Steps for the Processive Cellobiohydrolase Cel7A: Effects of Substrate Structure and Carbohydrate Binding Domain. Biochem. 2013;52(49):8938&#x2013;8948. doi: 10.1021/bi401210n.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bi401210n</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24228828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurasin M., V&#xe4;ljam&#xe4;e P.. Processivity of Cellobiohydrolases Is Limited by the Substrate. J. Biol. Chem. 2011;286(1):169&#x2013;177. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M110.161059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M110.161059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21051539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westh P., Kari J., Badino S., So&#x337;rensen T., Christensen S., Ro&#x337;jel N., Schiano-di-Cola C., Borch K.. Are Cellulases Slow? Kinetic and Thermodynamic Limitations for Enzymatic Breakdown of Cellulose. BBA Adv. 2025;7:100128. doi: 10.1016/j.bbadva.2024.100128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadva.2024.100128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11699605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39758504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masud N., Tang J., Hasib H. H., Jubery T. Z., Lee X. X., Guo H., Sarkar A.. Correlating Macroscopic Plant Growth Parameters to Nanomechanical Properties of Cellulose Microfibrils. Curr. Plant Biol. 2024;38:100345. doi: 10.1016/j.cpb.2024.100345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpb.2024.100345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhagia S., &#x10e;urkovi&#x10d; J., Laga&#x148;a R., Kardo&#x161;ov&#xe1; M., Ka&#x10d;&#xed;k F., Cernescu A., Sch&#xe4;fer P., Yoo C. G., Ragauskas A. J.. Nanoscale FTIR and Mechanical Mapping of Plant Cell Walls for Understanding Biomass Deconstruction. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2022;10(9):3016&#x2013;3026. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.1c08163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.1c08163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu S., Omadjela O., Gaddes D., Tadigadapa S., Zimmer J., Catchmark J. M.. Cellulose Microfibril Formation by Surface-Tethered Cellulose Synthase Enzymes. ACS Nano. 2016;10(2):1896&#x2013;1907. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.5b05648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.5b05648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26799780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert E., Agui&#xe9;-B&#xe9;ghin V., Dessaint D., Foulon L., Chabbert B., Pa&#xeb;s G., Molinari M.. Real Time and Quantitative Imaging of Lignocellulosic Films Hydrolysis by Atomic Force Microscopy Reveals Lignin Recalcitrance at Nanoscale. Biomacromolecules. 2019;20(1):515&#x2013;527. doi: 10.1021/acs.biomac.8b01539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.biomac.8b01539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30532964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajki-Zechmeister K., Eibinger M., Nidetzky B.. Enzyme Synergy in Transient Clusters of Endo- and Exocellulase Enables a Multilayer Mode of Processive Depolymerization of Cellulose. ACS Catal. 2022;12(17):10984&#x2013;10994. doi: 10.1021/acscatal.2c02377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscatal.2c02377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9442579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36082050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willhammar T., Daicho K., Johnstone D. N., Kobayashi K., Liu Y., Midgley P. A., Bergstr&#xf6;m L., Saito T.. Local Crystallinity in Twisted Cellulose Nanofibers. ACS Nano. 2021;15(2):2730&#x2013;2737. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.0c08295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.0c08295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33464042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igarashi K., Koivula A., Wada M., Kimura S., Penttil&#xe4; M., Samejima M.. High Speed Atomic Force Microscopy Visualizes Processive Movement of Trichoderma Reesei Cellobiohydrolase I on Crystalline Cellulose. J. Biol. Chem. 2009;284(52):36186&#x2013;36190. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M109.034611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M109.034611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2794734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19858200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persson B. N. J., Ganser C., Schmied F., Teichert C., Schennach R., Gilli E., Hirn U.. Adhesion of Cellulose Fibers in Paper. J. Phys.: Condens. Matter. 2013;25(4):045002. doi: 10.1088/0953-8984/25/4/045002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0953-8984/25/4/045002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlert M., Benselfelt T., W&#xe5;gberg L., Fur&#xf3; I., Berglund L. A., Wohlert J.. Cellulose and the Role of Hydrogen Bonds: Not in Charge of Everything. Cellulose. 2022;29(1):1&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1007/s10570-021-04325-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-021-04325-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman H. V., Perrino A. P., Garcia R.. Peak Forces in High-Resolution Imaging of Soft Matter in Liquid. ACS Nano. 2013;7(4):3198&#x2013;3204. doi: 10.1021/nn4012835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nn4012835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23521043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eibinger M., Ganner T., Plank H., Nidetzky B.. A Biological Nanomachine at Work: Watching the Cellulosome Degrade Crystalline Cellulose. ACS Cent. Sci. 2020;6(5):739&#x2013;746. doi: 10.1021/acscentsci.0c00050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscentsci.0c00050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32490190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X., Cheng G.. From Cellulose Fibrils to Single Chains: Understanding Cellulose Dissolution in Ionic Liquids. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2015;17(47):31592&#x2013;31607. doi: 10.1039/C5CP05744B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5CP05744B</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodayari A., Van Vuure A. W., Hirn U., Seveno D.. Tensile Behaviour of Dislocated/Crystalline Cellulose Fibrils at the Nano Scale. Carbohydr. Polym. 2020;235:115946. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2020.115946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2020.115946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32122482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cresswell R., Deralia P. K., Yoshimi Y., Kuga T., Echevarr&#xed;a-Poza A., Franks W. T., Brown S. P., Dupree R., Dupree P.. Using Solid-State NMR to Understand the Structure of Plant Cellulose. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2025;147(51):47223&#x2013;47236. doi: 10.1021/jacs.5c14452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5c14452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12752684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41381423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove D. J., Dupree P., Gomez E. D., Haigler C. H., Kubicki J. D., Zimmer J.. How Many Glucan Chains Form Plant Cellulose Microfibrils? A Mini Review. Biomacromolecules. 2024;25(10):6357&#x2013;6366. doi: 10.1021/acs.biomac.4c00995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.biomac.4c00995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11480985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39207939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding S.-Y., Himmel M. E.. The Maize Primary Cell Wall Microfibril: A New Model Derived from Direct Visualization. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2006;54(3):597&#x2013;606. doi: 10.1021/jf051851z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf051851z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson P. T., Wickholm K., Iversen T.. A CP/MAS13C NMR Investigation of Molecular Ordering in Celluloses. Carbohydr. Res. 1997;302(1&#x2013;2):19&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/S0008-6215(97)00130-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-6215(97)00130-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T., Hong M.. Solid-State NMR Investigations of Cellulose Structure and Interactions with Matrix Polysaccharides in Plant Primary Cell Walls. J. Exp. Bot. 2016;67(2):503&#x2013;514. doi: 10.1093/jxb/erv416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/erv416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6280985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26355148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foston M.. Advances in Solid-State NMR of Cellulose. Curr. Opin. Biotechnol. 2014;27:176&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/j.copbio.2014.02.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.copbio.2014.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24590189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding S.-Y., Himmel M. E.. The Maize Primary Cell Wall Microfibril: A New Model Derived from Direct Visualization. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2006;54(3):597&#x2013;606. doi: 10.1021/jf051851z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf051851z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard V., Chauss&#xe9; J., Vermette P.. Bacterial Cellulose: A Comprehensive Review. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2024;141(15):e55163. doi: 10.1002/app.55163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.55163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iguchi M., Yamanaka S., Budhiono A.. Bacterial Cellulose &#xe5f8; a Masterpiece of Nature &#x2019; s Arts. J. Mater. Sci. 2000;35:261&#x2013;270. doi: 10.1023/A:1004775229149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1004775229149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove D. J.. Structure and Growth of Plant Cell Walls. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 2024;25(5):340&#x2013;358. doi: 10.1038/s41580-023-00691-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41580-023-00691-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38102449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Shklyaev O. E., Nili A., Mohamed M. N. A., Kubicki J. D., Crespi V. H., Zhong L.. Cellulose Microfibril Twist, Mechanics, and Implication for Cellulose Biosynthesis. J. Phys. Chem. A. 2013;117(12):2580&#x2013;2589. doi: 10.1021/jp3089929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp3089929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23418823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeoh T., Santa-Maria M. C., O&#x2019;Dell P. J.. Assessing Cellulose Microfibrillar Structure Changes Due to Cellulase Action. Carbohydr. Polym. 2013;97(2):581&#x2013;586. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2013.05.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2013.05.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23911488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazeau K., Heux L.. Molecular Dynamics Simulations of Bulk Native Crystalline and Amorphous Structures of Cellulose. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2003;107(10):2394&#x2013;2403. doi: 10.1021/jp0219395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp0219395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne C. M., Himmel M. E., Crowley M. F., Beckham G. T.. Decrystallization of Oligosaccharides from the Cellulose I&#x3b2; Surface with Molecular Simulation. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2011;2(13):1546&#x2013;1550. doi: 10.1021/jz2005122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jz2005122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tewari Y. B., Lang B. E., Decker S. R., Goldberg R. N.. Thermodynamics of the Hydrolysis Reactions of 1,4-&#x3b2;-d-Xylobiose, 1,4-&#x3b2;-d-Xylotriose, d-Cellobiose, and d-Maltose. J. Chem. Thermodyn. 2008;40(10):1517&#x2013;1526. doi: 10.1016/j.jct.2008.05.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jct.2008.05.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>French A. D., Miller D. P., Aabloo A.. Miniature Crystal Models of Cellulose Polymorphs and Other Carbohydrates. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 1993;15(1):30&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/S0141-8130(05)80085-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0141-8130(05)80085-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8443130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vi&#xeb;tor R. J., Mazeau K., Lakin M., P&#xe9;rez S.. A Priori Crystal Structure Prediction of Native Celluloses. Biopolymers. 2000;54(5):342&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1002/1097-0282(20001015)54:5&lt;342::AID-BIP50&gt;3.0.CO;2-O.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1097-0282(20001015)54:5&lt;342::AID-BIP50&gt;3.0.CO;2-O</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10935974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho G. O., Deleris I., Champion D., Wallecan J., Debon S., Roudaut G.. Multiscale Dynamics and Molecular Mobility in Cellulose-Rich Materials. Carbohydr. Polym. 2024;344:122490. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2024.122490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2024.122490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39218537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petridis L., O&#x2019;Neill H. M., Johnsen M., Fan B., Schulz R., Mamontov E., Maranas J., Langan P., Smith J. C.. Hydration Control of the Mechanical and Dynamical Properties of Cellulose. Biomacromolecules. 2014;15(11):4152&#x2013;4159. doi: 10.1021/bm5011849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bm5011849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25325376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y.-S., Baker J. O., Zeng Y., Himmel M. E., Haas T., Ding S.-Y.. Cellobiohydrolase Hydrolyzes Crystalline Cellulose on Hydrophobic Faces. J. Biol. Chem. 2011;286(13):11195&#x2013;11201. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M110.216556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M110.216556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimlos M. R., Beckham G. T., Matthews J. F., Bu L., Himmel M. E., Crowley M. F.. Binding Preferences, Surface Attachment, Diffusivity, and Orientation of a Family 1 Carbohydrate-Binding Module on Cellulose. J. Biol. Chem. 2012;287(24):20603&#x2013;20612. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M112.358184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M112.358184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3370244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22496371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eibinger M., Zahel T., Ganner T., Plank H., Nidetzky B.. Cellular Automata Modeling Depicts Degradation of Cellulosic Material by a Cellulase System with Single-Molecule Resolution. Biotechnol. Biofuels. 2016;9(1):56. doi: 10.1186/s13068-016-0463-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13068-016-0463-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4784381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26962329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto H., Schnupf U., Brady J. W.. Water Structuring over the Hydrophobic Surface of Cellulose. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2014;62(46):11017&#x2013;11023. doi: 10.1021/jf501763r.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf501763r</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25365241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felby C., Thygesen L. G., Kristensen J. B., Jo&#x337;rgensen H., Elder T.. Cellulose&#x2013;Water Interactions during Enzymatic Hydrolysis as Studied by Time Domain NMR. Cellulose. 2008;15(5):703&#x2013;710. doi: 10.1007/s10570-008-9222-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-008-9222-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selig M. J., Thygesen L. G., Johnson D. K., Himmel M. E., Felby C., Mittal A.. Hydration and Saccharification of Cellulose I&#x3b2;, II and IIII at Increasing Dry Solids Loadings. Biotechnol. Lett. 2013;35(10):1599&#x2013;1607. doi: 10.1007/s10529-013-1258-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10529-013-1258-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23881312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selig M. J., Hsieh C. W. C., Thygesen L. G., Himmel M. E., Felby C., Decker S. R.. Considering Water Availability and the Effect of Solute Concentration on High Solids Saccharification of Lignocellulosic Biomass. Biotechnol. Prog. 2012;28(6):1478&#x2013;1490. doi: 10.1002/btpr.1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/btpr.1617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22915470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chundawat S. P. S., Bellesia G., Uppugundla N., da Costa Sousa L., Gao D., Cheh A. M., Agarwal U. P., Bianchetti C. M., Phillips G. N., Langan P., Balan V., Gnanakaran S., Dale B. E.. Restructuring the Crystalline Cellulose Hydrogen Bond Network Enhances Its Depolymerization Rate. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2011;133(29):11163&#x2013;11174. doi: 10.1021/ja2011115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja2011115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21661764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petridis L., Smith J. C.. Molecular-Level Driving Forces in Lignocellulosic Biomass Deconstruction for Bioenergy. Nat. Rev. Chem. 2018;2(11):382&#x2013;389. doi: 10.1038/s41570-018-0050-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41570-018-0050-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turon X., Rojas O. J., Deinhammer R. S.. Enzymatic Kinetics of Cellulose Hydrolysis: A QCM-D Study. Langmuir. 2008;24(8):3880&#x2013;3887. doi: 10.1021/la7032753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la7032753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18324851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews J. F., Skopec C. E., Mason P. E., Zuccato P., Torget R. W., Sugiyama J., Himmel M. E., Brady J. W.. Computer Simulation Studies of Microcrystalline Cellulose I&#x3b2;. Carbohydr. Res. 2006;341(1):138&#x2013;152. doi: 10.1016/j.carres.2005.09.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carres.2005.09.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16297893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross A. S., Chu J.-W.. On the Molecular Origins of Biomass Recalcitrance: The Interaction Network and Solvation Structures of Cellulose Microfibrils. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2010;114(42):13333&#x2013;13341. doi: 10.1021/jp106452m.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp106452m</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20883004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paajanen A., Ceccherini S., Maloney T., Ketoja J. A.. Chirality and Bound Water in the Hierarchical Cellulose Structure. Cellulose. 2019;26(10):5877&#x2013;5892. doi: 10.1007/s10570-019-02525-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-019-02525-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resch M. G., Donohoe B. S., Baker J. O., Decker S. R., Bayer E. A., Beckham G. T., Himmel M. E.. Fungal Cellulases and Complexed Cellulosomal Enzymes Exhibit Synergistic Mechanisms in Cellulose Deconstruction. Energy Environ. Sci. 2013;6(6):1858. doi: 10.1039/c3ee00019b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c3ee00019b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resch M. G., Donohoe B. S., Ciesielski P. N., Nill J. E., Magnusson L., Himmel M. E., Mittal A., Katahira R., Biddy M. J., Beckham G. T.. Clean Fractionation Pretreatment Reduces Enzyme Loadings for Biomass Saccharification and Reveals the Mechanism of Free and Cellulosomal Enzyme Synergy. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2014;2(6):1377&#x2013;1387. doi: 10.1021/sc500210w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/sc500210w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juturu V., Wu J. C.. Microbial Cellulases: Engineering, Production and Applications. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2014;33:188&#x2013;203. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2014.01.077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2014.01.077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamote B., da Fonseca M. J. M., Vanderstraeten J., Meert K., Elias M., Briers Y.. Current Challenges in Designer Cellulosome Engineering. Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 2023;107(9):2755&#x2013;2770. doi: 10.1007/s00253-023-12474-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00253-023-12474-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36941434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David H., Vita N., Pag&#xe8;s S., &#x160;travs P., Berlec A., Fierobe H.-P., Perret S.. Synergies between Cellulosomal and Non-Cellulosomal Bacterial Cellulases Complexed in Designer Cellulosomes. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;309:142819. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.142819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.142819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40187463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vodovnik M., Lindi&#x10d; N.. Towards the Application of Nature&#x2019;s Catalytic Nanomachines: Cellulosomes in 2nd Generation Biofuel Production. Biotechnol. Adv. 2025;79:108523. doi: 10.1016/j.biotechadv.2025.108523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2025.108523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39892314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ne&#x10d;as D., Klapetek P.. Gwyddion: An Open-Source Software for SPM Data Analysis. Open Phys. 2012;10(1):181&#x2013;188. doi: 10.2478/s11534-011-0096-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/s11534-011-0096-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>