<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41479730</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1948-9366</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastrointestinal surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastrointest Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dexmedetomidine enhances recovery after gastrointestinal cancer surgery by protecting the endothelial glycocalyx: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>114628</StartPage><MedlinePgn>114628</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">114628</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4240/wjgs.v17.i12.114628</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The vascular endothelial glycocalyx (VEG) plays a critical role in maintaining vascular barrier integrity, regulating inflammation, and ensuring microcirculatory homeostasis. Surgical stress and systemic inflammation can disrupt the glycocalyx, leading to endothelial dysfunction, impaired microcirculation, and adverse postoperative outcomes. dexmedetomidine (DEX), an &#x3b1;2-adrenergic agonist with anti-inflammatory and organ-protective properties, has been suggested in preclinical and clinical studies to mitigate glycocalyx degradation, yet evidence in gastrointestinal cancer surgery remains limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine whether perioperative DEX attenuates surgical inflammation-induced VEG degradation and preserves endothelial barrier function in patients undergoing gastrointestinal cancer resection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a prospective, single-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial conducted at the First Affiliated Hospital of University of Science and Technology of China. A total of 110 patients undergoing elective gastric or colorectal tumor resection were randomly assigned (1:1) to receive intraoperative DEX or saline placebo. Anesthesia and analgesia were standardized across groups. The primary outcome was plasma syndecan-1 concentration, a marker of endothelial glycocalyx injury, measured at four perioperative timepoints (T0-T3). Secondary outcomes included inflammatory biomarkers [interleukin-6 (IL-6), tumor necrosis factor-alpha, C-reactive protein, heparan sulfate], microcirculatory parameters [perfused vessel density (PVD), flow index, P(v-a)CO<sub>2</sub>, lactate], and clinical endpoints [extubation time, opioid use, Visual Analog Scale (VAS) scores, Quality of Recovery-15 Questionnaire (QoR-15), length of stay, and 30-day complications]. Postoperative complications were defined by Clavien-Dindo criteria and adjudicated by blinded investigators. The trial was registered prospectively (ChiCTR2500109633) and powered to detect a clinically meaningful difference in syndecan-1 levels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 110 patients were randomized equally to the DEX or control group, with well-balanced baseline characteristics. Compared with controls, DEX significantly reduced postoperative infections (7% <i>vs</i> 16%) and intensive care unit admissions (7% <i>vs</i> 13%), shortened extubation time (13.1 &#xb1; 3.0 minutes <i>vs</i> 18.4 &#xb1; 4.0 minutes; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001), and decreased opioid use (23.1 &#xb1; 5.0 mg <i>vs</i> 27.3 &#xb1; 6.0 mg; <i>P</i> = 0.004) and VAS pain scores (<i>P</i> = 0.002). At abdominal closure, DEX attenuated endothelial glycocalyx injury, as evidenced by lower plasma syndecan-1 (44.72 &#xb1; 7.10 ng/mL <i>vs</i> 48.73 &#xb1; 6.26 ng/mL; <i>P</i> = 0.002) and heparan sulfate levels (<i>P</i> = 0.001). IL-6 was significantly reduced at 24 hours (110.77 &#xb1; 29.72 pg/mL <i>vs</i> 138.86 &#xb1; 35.95 pg/mL; <i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001) and positively correlated with syndecan-1 (<i>r</i> = 0.71). Microcirculatory function improved with DEX, including higher PVD (21.40 &#xb1; 3.50 mm/mm&#xb2; <i>vs</i> 19.94 &#xb1; 2.93 mm/mm&#xb2;; <i>P</i> = 0.019), increased flow index, lower P(v-a)CO<sub>2</sub> (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.001), and reduced lactate (<i>P</i> = 0.003). DEX also improved recovery outcomes, with higher QoR-15 scores (<i>P</i> = 0.001), shorter hospital stays (6.49 &#xb1; 1.29 days <i>vs</i> 7.29 &#xb1; 1.59 days; <i>P</i> = 0.005), and fewer overall 30-day complications (12.7% <i>vs</i> 30.9%; <i>P</i> = 0.036). Receiver operating characteristic analysis identified syndecan-1 &gt; 45 ng/mL at abdominal closure as a potential predictor of postoperative complications (area under the curve = 0.68, 95%CI: 0.59-0.76), and multivariable analysis showed a near-significant association (OR = 2.88, <i>P</i> = 0.057). Subgroup analyses demonstrated consistent anti-inflammatory and endothelial-protective effects of DEX across age and surgical approach strata.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Perioperative administration of DEX confers significant endothelial-protective effects by mitigating glycocalyx degradation, suppressing systemic inflammation, and promoting enhanced postoperative recovery. These findings support its clinical utility as a valuable adjunctive therapy in the perioperative management of patients undergoing oncologic gastrointestinal surgery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Rong</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Anhui Provincial Cancer Hospital, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Chao-Liang</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of USTC, Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Life Sciences and Medicine, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Anhui Provincial Cancer Hospital, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Rui-Xiang</ForeName><Initials>RX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Anhui Provincial Cancer Hospital, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Anhui Provincial Cancer Hospital, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xian-Wen</ForeName><Initials>XW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei 230031, Anhui Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine of Anhui Higher Education Institutes, Anhui Medical University, Hefei 230601, Anhui Province, China. huxianwen001@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastrointest Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532473</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dexmedetomidine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal neoplasms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Syndecan-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular endothelial glycocalyx</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41479730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12754488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4240/wjgs.v17.i12.114628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Weinbaum S, Cancel LM, Fu BM, Tarbell JM. The Glycocalyx and Its Role in Vascular Physiology and Vascular Related Diseases. Cardiovasc Eng Technol. 2021;12:37&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32959164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reitsma S, Slaaf DW, Vink H, van Zandvoort MA, oude Egbrink MG. The endothelial glycocalyx: composition, functions, and visualization. Pflugers Arch. 2007;454:345&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1915585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17256154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg BM, Vink H, Spaan JA. The endothelial glycocalyx protects against myocardial edema. Circ Res. 2003;92:592&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12637366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarbell JM, Cancel LM. The glycocalyx and its significance in human medicine. J Intern Med. 2016;280:97&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26749537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteside TL. Exosome and mesenchymal stem cell cross-talk in the tumor microenvironment. Semin Immunol. 2018;35:69&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29289420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai X, Chen W, Qiao Y, Chen X, Chen Y, Zhang K, Zhang Q, Duan X, Li X, Zhao J, Tian F, Liu K, Dong Z, Lu J. Dihydroartemisinin inhibits the development of colorectal cancer by GSK-3&#x3b2;/TCF7/MMP9 pathway and synergies with capecitabine. Cancer Lett. 2024;582:216596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38101610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koide R, Hirane N, Kambe D, Yokoi Y, Otaki M, Nishimura SI. Antiadhesive nanosome elicits role of glycocalyx of tumor cell-derived exosomes in the organotropic cancer metastasis. Biomaterials. 2022;280:121314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang FQ, Sun JH, Wu QL, Feng LY, Fan YX, Ye JX, Gao W, He GL, Wang WJ. Protective effect of sevoflurane on vascular endothelial glycocalyx in patients undergoing heart valve surgery: A randomised controlled trial. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2021;38:477&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33399382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda ML, Balarini MM, Bouskela E. Dexmedetomidine attenuates the microcirculatory derangements evoked by experimental sepsis. Anesthesiology. 2015;122:619&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25313879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker BF, Jacob M, Leipert S, Salmon AH, Chappell D. Degradation of the endothelial glycocalyx in clinical settings: searching for the sheddases. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2015;80:389&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4574825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25778676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khwaja A. KDIGO clinical practice guidelines for acute kidney injury. Nephron Clin Pract. 2012;120:c179&#x2013;c184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22890468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch J, Idzerda NMA, Ettema EM, Kuipers J, Dam W, van den Born J, Franssen CFM. An acute rise of plasma Na(+) concentration associates with syndecan-1 shedding during hemodialysis. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol. 2020;319:F171&#x2013;F177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32538148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weerink MAS, Struys MMRF, Hannivoort LN, Barends CRM, Absalom AR, Colin P. Clinical Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Dexmedetomidine. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2017;56:893&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5511603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou Z, Li L, Sch&#xe4;fer N, Huang Q, Maegele M, Gu Z. Endothelial glycocalyx in traumatic brain injury associated coagulopathy: potential mechanisms and impact. J Neuroinflammation. 2021;18:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8204552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34126995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi A, Mimuro S, Katoh T, Kobayashi K, Sato T, Kien TS, Nakajima Y. Dexmedetomidine suppresses serum syndecan-1 elevation and improves survival in a rat hemorrhagic shock model. Exp Anim. 2022;71:281&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9388338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35110424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JS, Shim JK, Soh S, Kim MK, Kwak YL. Perioperative dexmedetomidine reduces the incidence and severity of acute kidney injury following valvular heart surgery. Kidney Int. 2016;89:693&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26444030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi T, Kidani Y, Kanakura H, Takemoto Y, Yamamoto K. Effects of dexmedetomidine on mortality rate and inflammatory responses to endotoxin-induced shock in rats. Crit Care Med. 2004;32:1322&#x2013;1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15187514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed H, Hosny H, Tawadros Md P, Elayashy Md Desa Fcai M, El-Ashmawi Md H. Effect of Dexmedetomidine Infusion on Sublingual Microcirculation in Patients Undergoing On-Pump Coronary Artery Bypass Graft Surgery: A Prospective Randomized Trial. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2019;33:334&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30075898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Zhao G, Zang X, Lu F, Liu P, Chen W. Effect of dexmedetomidine on opioid consumption and pain control after laparoscopic cholecystectomy: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Wideochir Inne Tech Maloinwazyjne. 2021;16:491&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8512507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34691300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirani R, Podder D, Stala O, Mohebpour R, Tiwari RK, Etienne M. Strategies to Reduce Hospital Length of Stay: Evidence and Challenges. Medicina (Kaunas) 2025;61:922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12112870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40428880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J, Lei Y, Wan Y, Dong P, Wang Y, Liu K, Zhang X. Enhanced recovery after surgery from 1997 to 2022: a bibliometric and visual analysis. Updates Surg. 2024;76:1131&#x2013;1150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38446378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt EP, Yang Y, Janssen WJ, Gandjeva A, Perez MJ, Barthel L, Zemans RL, Bowman JC, Koyanagi DE, Yunt ZX, Smith LP, Cheng SS, Overdier KH, Thompson KR, Geraci MW, Douglas IS, Pearse DB, Tuder RM. The pulmonary endothelial glycocalyx regulates neutrophil adhesion and lung injury during experimental sepsis. Nat Med. 2012;18:1217&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3723751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22820644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>