<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41764277</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Formation tracking control of multiple USVs using ADRC with prescribed performance.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-37252-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper investigates the formation tracking control problem for multiple unmanned surface vehicles (USVs) under prescribed performance constraints in the presence of model uncertainties and unknown disturbances. A decentralized formation control strategy is developed based on a modified active disturbance rejection control (ADRC) framework, where a model-compensation extended state observer (ESO) is designed to estimate the total disturbance and enhance robustness. To avoid the "explosion of complexity", a tracking differentiator (TD) is employed to approximate virtual control derivatives, while a universal barrier function (UBF) is incorporated into the Lyapunov-based synthesis to guarantee both transient and steady-state performance bounds. Rigorous Lyapunov analysis proves that all closed-loop signals remain uniformly ultimately bounded, prescribed performance constraints are strictly satisfied, and inter-agent collision avoidance and communication connectivity are maintained. Comprehensive simulations further demonstrate significant performance advantages over representative baseline methods. In particular, the proposed controller achieves a 57.4% reduction in IAE and a 42.6% reduction in RMSE compared with a PID controller, and a further 49.4% and 36.7% reduction relative to a backstepping controller. These quantitative results confirm the superior accuracy and robustness of the proposed approach.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huo</LastName><ForeName>Mingen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unmanned Systems Research Center, China People's Police University, Guangzhou, 510000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Automation Science and Engineering, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510641, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mao</LastName><ForeName>Wenlong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unmanned Systems Research Center, China People's Police University, Guangzhou, 510000, China. WenlMao@Foxmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Automation Science and Engineering, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510641, China. WenlMao@Foxmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Low Altitude Economy Development Co., Ltd., Guangzhou, 510335, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20250001</GrantID><Agency>the Research on Safety Separation for Integrated Helicopter and Logistics UAV Operations in Urban Inter-Building Airspace</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GZYL24FG122919</GrantID><Agency>the Regulatory and Safeguard System for Low-Altitude Security in Guangdong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomous UAV landing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Field-of-view constraint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prescribed performance control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Velocity estimation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Visual servo control</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41764277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-37252-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-37252-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Zhang, Y., Yu, X. &amp; Yuan, C. Unmanned surface vehicles: An overview of developments and challenges. Ann. Rev. Control 41, 71&#x2013;93 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Zhang, G., Jiang, C. &amp; Zhang, W. A survey of maritime unmanned search system: theory, applications and future directions. Ocean Eng. 285, 115359 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, S., Dai, S.-L., Zhao, Z. &amp; Zou, T. Uncertainty and disturbance estimator-based distributed synchronization control for multiple marine surface vehicles with prescribed performance. Ocean Eng. 261, 111867 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Feng, K. &amp; Li, K. Finite-time fuzzy adaptive dynamic event-triggered formation tracking control for usvs with actuator faults and multiple constraints. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inf. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashrafiuon, H., Nersesov, S. &amp; Clayton, G. Trajectory tracking control of planar underactuated vehicles. IEEE Trans. Autom. Control 62, 1959&#x2013;1965 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Y., Zhang, X., Im, N., Zhang, G. &amp; Zhang, Q. Adaptive fuzzy tracking control for underactuated surface vessels with unmodeled dynamics and input saturation. ISA Trans. 103, 52&#x2013;62 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, S. P. &amp; Cheah, C. C. Can a simple control scheme work for a formation control of multiple autonomous underwater vehicles?. IEEE Trans. Control Syst. Technol. 19, 1090&#x2013;1101 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, L., Xu, C., Hao, L., Yao, J. &amp; Guo, R. Research on pid parameter tuning and optimization based on sac-auto for usv path following. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 10, 1847 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, X., Wei, X., Kao, Y. &amp; Han, J. Robust synchronization for under-actuated vessels based on disturbance observer. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 23, 5470&#x2013;5479 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y., Wu, D., Yin, Z. &amp; Yuan, Z.-M. Design of ude-based dynamic surface control for dynamic positioning of vessels with complex disturbances and input constraints. Ocean Eng. 220, 108487 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, L., Pan, Y., Liang, H. &amp; Huang, T. Observer-based dynamic event-triggered control for multiagent systems with time-varying delay. IEEE Trans. Cybernet. 53, 3376&#x2013;3387 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Z. et al. Autonomous cooperative formation control of underactuated usvs based on improved mpc in complex ocean environment. Ocean Eng. 270, 113633 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinsen, A. B., Lekkas, A. M. &amp; Gros, S. Reinforcement learning-based nmpc for tracking control of asvs: Theory and experiments. Control Eng. Pract. 120, 105024 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, N., Gao, Y. &amp; Zhang, X. Data-driven performance-prescribed reinforcement learning control of an unmanned surface vehicle. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 32, 5456&#x2013;5467 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Luo, Q., Li, N. &amp; Zheng, W. Data-driven model free formation control for multi-usv system in complex marine environments. Int. J. Control, Autom. Syst. 20, 3666&#x2013;3677 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Z. et al. Heading control of unmanned marine vehicles based on an improved robust adaptive fuzzy neural network control algorithm. IEEE Access 7, 9704&#x2013;9713 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, W., Wang, Y., Ahn, C. K., Cheng, J. &amp; Chen, C. Adaptive fuzzy backstepping-based formation control of unmanned surface vehicles with unknown model nonlinearity and actuator saturation. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 69, 14749&#x2013;14764 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, J., Ge, Y., Zhou, X., Liu, S. &amp; Wu, J. Research on the course control of usv based on improved ADRC. Syst. Sci. Control Eng. 9, 44&#x2013;51 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, D., Yuan, K., Huang, Y., Yuan, Z.-M. &amp; Hua, L. Design and test of an improved active disturbance rejection control system for water sampling unmanned surface vehicle. Ocean Eng. 245, 110367 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamraoui, H. C., Qidan, Z. &amp; Bouzid, Y. Improved active disturbance rejecter control for trajectory tracking of unmanned surface vessel. Mar. Syst. Ocean Technol. 17, 18&#x2013;26 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, Y., Shao, X., Li, J., Liu, J. &amp; Zhang, Q. Concurrent-learning-based adaptive critic formation for multirobots under safety constraints. IEEE Internet Things J. 12, 7610&#x2013;7621 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Shao, X., Wang, H., Liu, J. &amp; Zhang, Q. Adaptive critic attitude learning control for hypersonic morphing vehicles without backstepping. IEEE Trans. Aerospace Electron. Syst. 61, 8787&#x2013;8803 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, X. et al. Efficient path-following for urban logistics: A fuzzy control strategy for consumer uavs under disturbance constraints. IEEE Trans. Consum. Electron. 71, 7117&#x2013;7128 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q., He, D., Liu, H. &amp; Shao, X. Adaptive sliding mode security control for rotary inverted pendulum against randomly occurring false data injection attacks. IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng. 22, 17988&#x2013;17999 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei, Z., Shao, X., Xia, Y. &amp; Liu, J. Enhanced fixed-time collision-free elliptical circumnavigation coordination for uavs. IEEE Trans. Aerospace Electron. Syst. 60, 4257&#x2013;4270 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, B. S., Kwon, J.-W. &amp; Kim, H. Neural network-based output feedback control for reference tracking of underactuated surface vessels. Automatica 77, 353&#x2013;359 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo, M., Wu, Z., He, T. &amp; Li, D. Thermodynamic modeling and control of hybrid solar-fossil fuel power generation and storage system. Appl. Therm. Eng. 229, 120593 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z., Shi, G., Li, D., Liu, Y. &amp; Chen, Y. Active disturbance rejection control design for high-order integral systems. ISA Trans. 125, 560&#x2013;570 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z.-H., Deng, F., Guo, B.-Z., Wu, C. &amp; Xiang, Q. Backstepping active disturbance rejection control for lower triangular nonlinear systems with mismatched stochastic disturbances. IEEE Trans. Syst. Man Cybernet.: Syst. 52, 2688&#x2013;2702 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doostdar, F. &amp; Mojallali, H. An adrc-based backstepping control design for a class of fractional-order systems. ISA Trans. 121, 140&#x2013;146 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J. From pid to active disturbance rejection control. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 56, 900&#x2013;906 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humaidi, A.&#xa0;J. et al. State estimation of rotary inverted pendulum: A comparative study of observers performance. In 2020 IEEE Congreso Bienal de Argentina (ARGENCON), 1&#x2013;7 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmood, N. S., Humaidi, A. J., Al-Azzawi, R. S. &amp; Al-Jodah, A. Extended state observer design for uncertainty estimation in electronic throttle valve system. Int. Rev. Appl. Sci. Eng. 15, 107&#x2013;115 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alawad, N. A., Humaidi, A. J. &amp; Muslim, M. M. Modified adrc for position lower-knee exoskeleton system: Rehabilitation case. Int. Rev. Appl. Sci. Eng. 16, 314&#x2013;323 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechlioulis, C. P. &amp; Rovithakis, G. A. Robust adaptive control of feedback linearizable mimo nonlinear systems with prescribed performance. IEEE Trans. Autom. Control 53, 2090&#x2013;2099 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, S.-L., He, S., Lin, H. &amp; Wang, C. Platoon formation control with prescribed performance guarantees for usvs. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 65, 4237&#x2013;4246 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, X. Adaptive fixed-time control for mimo nonlinear systems with asymmetric output constraints using universal barrier functions. IEEE Trans. Autom. Control 64, 3046&#x2013;3053 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan, B., Zhang, L., Liu, Y. &amp; Gao, J. Model predictive and compensated adrc for permanent magnet synchronous linear motors. ISA Trans. 136, 605&#x2013;621 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Z. et al. Scaling and bandwidth-parameterization based controller tuning. In ACC, 4989&#x2013;4996 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, B.-Z. &amp; Zhao, Z.-L. On convergence of tracking differentiator. Int. J. Control 84, 693&#x2013;701 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, T., Wu, Z., Li, D. &amp; Wang, J. A tuning method of active disturbance rejection control for a class of high-order processes. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 67, 3191&#x2013;3201 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. &amp; Xue, W. Active disturbance rejection control: Methodology and theoretical analysis. ISA Trans. 53, 963&#x2013;976 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skjetne, R., Fossen, T. I. &amp; Kokotovi&#x107;, P. V. Adaptive maneuvering, with experiments, for a model ship in a marine control laboratory. Automatica 41, 289&#x2013;298 (2005).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>