<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41892908</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2313-433X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of imaging</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Imaging</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vision-Language Models for Transmission Line Fault Detection: A New Approach for Grid Reliability and Optimization.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/jimaging12030106</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Reliable fault detection along transmission corridors is essential for preventing small defects from developing into long outages and costly emergency operations. This study aims to improve the field reliability of an open vocabulary vision language backbone without retraining the large model in an end-to-end manner. The work focuses on four operational fault classes in multi-region corridor imagery collected during routine inspections and uses a Florence-2 vision language model as the base recognizer. On top of this backbone, three domain-specific components are introduced. A subclass-aware fusion scheme keeps probability mass within the active parent concept so that insulator icing and conductor icing produce stable, action-oriented decisions. A Power-Line Focus Then Crop normalization uses an attention-guided corridor window together with isotropic resizing so that thin conductors and small fittings remain visible in the processed image. A corridor geo prior reduces scores as the distance from the mapped centerline increases and in this way suppresses detections that lie outside the corridor. All methods are evaluated under a shared preprocessing and scoring pipeline in training-free and parameter-efficient tuning modes. Experiments on unseen regions show higher accuracy for skinny and low-contrast faults, fewer false alarms outside the right-of-way, and improved score calibration in the confidence range used for triage, while keeping throughput and memory usage suitable for unmanned aerial vehicles and substation edge devices.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Runle</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mai</LastName><ForeName>Lihao</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical, Computer and Energy Engineering, Arizona State University, 551 East Tyler Mall, Tempe, AZ 85281, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weng</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5267-1303</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical, Computer and Energy Engineering, Arizona State University, 551 East Tyler Mall, Tempe, AZ 85281, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Qiushi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3471-3936</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Guochang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Henan Electric Power Company, Zhengzhou 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Pengliang</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Jiuyu EPRI Electric Power Technology Co., Ltd., Zhengzhou 450052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Imaging</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101698819</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2313-433X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calibration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fault detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">geo prior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">geometry preserving normalization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subclass aware fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transmission corridor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vision language model</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Guochang Xu is employed by State Grid Henan Electric Power Company. Author Pengliang Ren is employed by Henan Jiuyu EPRI Electric Power Technology Co. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41892908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13028582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging12030106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jimaging12030106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Li X., Sun M., Wang J. Automatic Power Line Inspection Using UAV Images. Remote Sens. 2017;9:824&#x2013;839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos T., Cunha T., Dias A., Moreira A.P., Almeida J. UAV Visual and Thermographic Power Line Detection Using Deep Learning. Sensors. 2024;24:5678. doi: 10.3390/s24175678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24175678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11397857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39275590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne J., Dorrian M., McCarthy T., Laefer D.F. 3D Reconstructions Using Unstabilized Video Footage from an Unmanned Aerial Vehicle. J. Imaging. 2017;3:15. doi: 10.3390/jimaging3020015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging3020015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan H., Li J., Yu Y., Wang C., Chapman M. UAV&#x2013;LiDAR Aids Automatic Intelligent Powerline Inspection. Eng. Struct. 2021;229:111595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song G., Du H., Zhang X., Bao F., Zhang Y. Small Object Detection in Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Images Using Multi-Scale Hybrid Attention. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 2024;128:107455. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Miao X., Jiang H., Chen J., Wu M., Chen Z. Component Detection for Power Line Inspection Using a Graph-Based Relation Guiding Network. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2023;19:9280&#x2013;9290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germanese D., Leone G., Moroni D., Petracca M. Long-Term Monitoring of Crack Patterns with UAV Imagery: Calibration and SLAM with Planar Markers. J. Imaging. 2018;4:98&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santagata T. Monitoring of the Nirano Mud Volcanoes Regional Natural Reserve (North Italy) Using Unmanned Aerial Vehicles and Terrestrial Laser Scanning. J. Imaging. 2017;3:42. doi: 10.3390/jimaging3040042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging3040042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni J., Zhao Y., Chen L., Zhang Y. A Small-Object Detection Model Based on Improved YOLOv8s. Remote Sens. 2024;16:4121&#x2013;4139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan B., Wang T., Lu W., Zhen X., Guan W., Zheng F. Knowledge-Aware Prompt Tuning for Generalizable Vision-Language Models. arXiv. 2023 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2308.11186.2308.11186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2308.11186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvez C., Abur A. Fault Location in Power Networks Using a Sparse Set of Digital Fault Recorders. IEEE Trans. Smart Grid. 2022;13:3468&#x2013;3480. doi: 10.1109/TSG.2022.3168904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSG.2022.3168904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Fang R., Zhang W., Gao P., Li K., Dai J., Qiao Y., Li H. Tip-Adapter: Training-Free CLIP-Adapter for Better Vision&#x2013;Language Modeling. arXiv. 20212111.03930</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao B., Wang H., Xu W., Dai X., Lu H., Lu Y., Zeng M., Liu C., Yuan L. Florence-2: Advancing a Unified Representation for a Variety of Vision Tasks. arXiv. 2023 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2311.06242.2311.06242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2311.06242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou K., Yang J., Loy C.C., Liu Z. Learning to Prompt for Vision-Language Models. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.1007/s11263-022-01653-1.2109.01134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11263-022-01653-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao P., Geng S., Zhang R., Ma T., Fang R., Zhang Y., Li H., Qiao Y. CLIP-Adapter: Better Vision-Language Models with Feature Adapters. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.1007/s11263-023-01891-x.2110.04544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11263-023-01891-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook E., Luo S., Weng Y. Solar Panel Identification via Deep Semi-Supervised Learning and Deep One-Class Classification. IEEE Trans. Power Syst. 2022;37:2516&#x2013;2526. doi: 10.1109/TPWRS.2021.3125613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRS.2021.3125613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z., Chen K., Chen J., Chen Z., Zhang M. CACS-YOLO: A Lightweight Model for Insulator Defect Detection Based on Improved YOLOv8m. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2024;73:3530710. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2024.3453332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2024.3453332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S., He K., Girshick R., Sun J. Faster R-CNN: Towards Real-Time Object Detection with Region Proposal Networks. arXiv. 2015 doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031.1506.01497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Liu G., Wang B. CapS-Adapter: Caption-Based MultiModal Adapter in Zero-Shot Classification. arXiv. 2024 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2405.16591.2405.16591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2405.16591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H., Wang Z., Wang J., Huang Z., Carrington N., Liao J. Data-Driven Power Outage Detection by Social Sensors. IEEE Trans. Smart Grid. 2016;7:2516&#x2013;2526. doi: 10.1109/TSG.2016.2546181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSG.2016.2546181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva K.M., Souza B.A., Brito N.S.D. Fault Detection and Classification in Transmission Lines Based on Wavelet Transform and ANN. IEEE Trans. Power Deliv. 2006;21:2058&#x2013;2063. doi: 10.1109/TPWRD.2006.876659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2006.876659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N., Kezunovic M. Transmission Line Boundary Protection Using Wavelet Transform and Neural Network. IEEE Trans. Power Deliv. 2007;22:859&#x2013;869. doi: 10.1109/TPWRD.2007.893596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2007.893596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen V.N., Jenssen R., Roverso D. Intelligent Monitoring and Inspection of Power Line Components Powered by UAVs and Deep Learning. IEEE Power Energy Technol. Syst. J. 2019;6:11&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1109/JPETS.2018.2881429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPETS.2018.2881429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das L., Saadat M.H., Gjorgiev B., Auger E., Sansavini G. Object Detection-Based Inspection of Power Line Insulators: Incipient Fault Detection in the Low Data-Regime. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2212.11017.2212.11017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2212.11017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sbaihema A., Noghabi A.S., Mazlum K. Evaluation of Power System Reliability Incorporating Protection System Miscoordination. Azerbaijan J. Electr. Eng. 2024;26:291&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Tong Y., Shang X., Zhang Z. Hierarchical Viewpoint Planning for Complex Surfaces in Industrial Product Inspection. IEEE/ASME Trans. Mechatron. 2024;29:3289&#x2013;3299. doi: 10.1109/TMECH.2023.3340312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMECH.2023.3340312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Wang Y., Zhou J., Zhang C., Zhang Y., Guan J., Bian Y., Zhou S. Hierarchical Few-Shot Object Detection: Problem, Benchmark and Method; Proceedings of the 30th ACM International Conference on Multimedia; Lisbon, Portugal. 10&#x2013;14 October 2022;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3503161.3548428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamali M., Davidsson P., Khoshkangini R., Ljungqvist M.G., Mihailescu R.-C. Context in Object Detection: A Systematic Literature Review. Artif. Intell. Rev. 2025;58:175. doi: 10.1007/s10462-025-11186-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-025-11186-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoefler M.A., Mueller K., Samek W. XAI-Guided Insulator Anomaly Detection for Imbalanced Datasets. arXiv. 2024 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2409.16821.2409.16821</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2409.16821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang R., Liu Z., Chen J., Shi Y., Xiao G. Geometric Prior-Assisted Feature Presentation Enhancement for Object Detection in Aerial Images; Proceedings of the 2023 IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP); Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. 8&#x2013;11 October 2023; pp. 1095&#x2013;1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICIP49359.2023.10222806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>