<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41454406</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-7283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the intrinsic mechanism of growth mindset on the academic performance of female art majors in China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>128</StartPage><MedlinePgn>128</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">128</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40359-025-03910-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The growth mindset proposes that intelligence comprises expandable, malleable, and controllable attributes, and those who embrace this mindset are inclined to view challenges and failures through a more optimistic lens. As a result, it can propel female college art majors towards greater achievements in both academic and professional settings. This study employed empirical analysis on 398 questionnaire responses, utilising Mplus 8.0 software. The research findings reveal the following: (1) There is a positive correlation between the academic performance of college female art majors and their growth mindset; (2) Grit serves as a mediator in the relationship between growth mindset and the academic performance of college female art majors; (3) Learning adaptability mediates the association between growth mindset and the academic performance of college female art majors; (4) Personal growth initiative serves as a moderator in the relationship between growth mindset and the academic performance of college female art majors. These findings not only enrich learning theories but also provide practical insights for improving students&#x2019; academic outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ouyang</LastName><ForeName>Linxia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Textile and Fashion &amp; Intelligent Textile Institute of Innovation, Hunan Institute of Engineering, No. 88 Fuxingdong Road, Xiangtan City, Hunan Province, 411104, China. linxiaouyang2023@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Humanities and Art, Jiangxi University of Water Resources and Electric Power, No. 289, Tianxiang Road, Nanchang, Jiangxi, 330099, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Student Affairs, Hubei Normal University, No.11 Cihu Road, Huangshi City, Hubei Province, 435002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Libo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Textile and Fashion &amp; Intelligent Textile Institute of Innovation, Hunan Institute of Engineering, No. 88 Fuxingdong Road, Xiangtan City, Hunan Province, 411104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Education Science, Nanyang Normal University, No. 1638 Wolong Road, Nanyang City, Henan Province, 473061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Textile and Fashion &amp; Intelligent Textile Institute of Innovation, Hunan Institute of Engineering, No. 88 Fuxingdong Road, Xiangtan City, Hunan Province, 411104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>S202511342138</GrantID><Agency>Innovation Training Project of Hunan Province: Research on Employment Countermeasures for College Students Majoring in Art at Universities Based on Artificial Intelligence Methods</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-7283</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Academic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Grit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Growth mindset</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Learning adaptability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Personal growth initiative</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Before commencing data collection, the study was thoroughly reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of the College of Textile and Fashion at Hunan Institute of Engineering (Approval No. EA2023052). It strictly complied with the Declaration of Helsinki and the &#x201c;Ethical Review Measures for Scientific and Medical Research Involving Humans&#x201d; promulgated by the Chinese government. During the entire data collection process, informed consent was duly obtained from all participants and/or their legal guardians. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41454406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12853709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-025-03910-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40359-025-03910-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang R. Artificial intelligence-based strategies for improving the teaching effect of Art major courses in colleges. Int J Emerg Technol Learn 2020, 15(22).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Zhang H, Zhou Y. The inquiry report of the innovation abilities of female university students. Journalof Hebei University(Philosophy Social Science) (Chinese). 2009;34(4):134&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gralewski J, Gajda A. Girls&#x2019; creativity less visible: mathematics and Language teachers&#x2019; ratings of male and female students&#x2019; creativity. Learn Individual Differences. 2024;116:102560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lindif.2024.102560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao M, Huang A, Mukhopadhyay A, Shon J. Divergent effects of mindsets on performance trajectories. NPJ Sci Learn. 2025;10(1):64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41539-025-00355-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12394573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linklater-Steele A, Colthorpe K, Ainscough L. Mindset matters: exploring the link between mindsets, learning intentions, and performance in biomedical science students. Adv Physiol Educ. 2025;49(3):780&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/advan.00012.2025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40516929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao M, Zhou N, Duan H, Wu H, Li F, Xiang T. Growth mindset mediates the effect of core self-evaluation on professional self-efficacy for nursing interns: A cross-sectional study. Nurse Educ Today. 2025;147:106591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2025.106591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39889459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Zhang H, Shang K, Huang Z. What matters for students&#x2019; social and emotional skills: the associations with student, parent, and teacher growth mindsets? Learn Individual Differences. 2025;124:102799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lindif.2025.102799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackwell LS, Trzesniewski KH, Dweck CS. Implicit theories of intelligence predict achievement across an adoles cent transition: A longitudinal study and an intervention. Child Dev. 2007;78(1):246&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-8624.2007.00995.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17328703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murry LT, Boyer JG, Catledge K, Gettig JP, Travlos DV, Zarembski D, Kiersma ME. The intersection of growth mindset and accreditation in pharmacy education. Am J Pharm Educ. 2024;88(6):100711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpe.2024.100711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38723896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milad M, Katherine G, Marie K. N: beware false growth mindset: Building growth mindset in medical education is essential but complicated. Acad Medicine: J Association Am Med Colleges. 2024;99(3):261&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0000000000005448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37643577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronson J, Fried CB, Good C. Reducing the effects of stereotype threat on African American college students by shaping theories of intelligence. J Exp Soc Psychol. 2002;38(2):113&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jesp.2001.1491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton E, Bryan C, Murray J, McDaniel M, Schneider B, Yeager DS. Why meta-analyses of growth mindset and other interventions should follow best practices for examining heterogeneity. Psychol Bull. 2022;149(3&#x2013;4):229&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10495100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37701627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Bates TC. You can&#x2019;t change your basic ability, but you work at things, and that&#x2019;s how we get hard things done: testing the role of growth mindset on response to setbacks, educational attainment, and cognitive ability. J Experimental Psychol Gen. 2019;148(9):1640&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/xge0000669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31464486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macnamara BN, Burgoyne AP. Do growth mindset interventions impact students&#x2019; academic achievement? A systematic review and meta-analysis with recommendations for best practices. Psychol Bull. 2022;10(3):32&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36326645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dommett EJ, Devonshire IM, Sewter E, Greenfield SA. The impact of participation in a neuroscience course on motivational measures and academic performance. Trends Neurosci Educ. 2013;2:122&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tine.2013.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duckworth AL, Peterson C, Matthews MD, Kelly DR. Grit: perseverance and passion for long-term goals. J Personal Soc Psychol. 2007;92:1087&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.92.6.1087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17547490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Zhai X, Zhang G, Liang X, Xin S. The relationship between growth mindset and grit: serial mediation effects of the future time perspective and achievement motivation. Psychol Dev Educ (Chinese). 2022;38(2):216&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei H, Gao K, Wang W. Understanding the relationship between grit and foreign Language performance among middle school students: the roles of foreign Language enjoyment and classroom environment. Front Psychol. 2019;10:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6624730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khajavy GH, MacIntyre PD, Hariri J. A closer look at grit and Language mindset as predictors of foreign Language achievement. Stud Second Lang Acquisition. 2021;43(2):379&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0272263120000480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collie RJ, Martin AJ. Students&#x2019; adaptability in mathematics: examining self-reports and teachers&#x2019; reports and links with engagement and achievement outcomes. Contemp Educ Psychol. 2017;49:355&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2017.04.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holliman AJ, Sheriston L, Martin AJ, Collie RJ, Sayer D. Adaptability: does students&#x2019; adjustment to university predict their mid-course academic achievement and satisfaction? J Furth High Educ. 2018;43(10):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shek DTL. Family functioning and psychological well-being, school adjustment, and problem behavior in Chinese adolescents with and without economic disadvantage. J Genet Psychol. 2002;163(4):497&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00221320209598698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12495233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker RW, Siryk B. Measuring adjustment to college. J Couns Psychol. 1984;31(2):179&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0167.31.2.179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robitschek C. Life/career renewal: an intervention for vocational and other life transitions. J Career Dev. 1997;24(2):133&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/089484539702400205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsusaki R, Mullassery D, Ramaswamy P. Stress, grit, satisfaction with life, and remediation of prelicensure nursing students. Nurs Educ. 2024;49(1):19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NNE.0000000000001481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37442120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robitschck C, Ashton MW, Spering CC, Geiger N, Byers D, Schotts GC, Thoen MA. Development and psychometric evaluation of the personal growth initiative Scale-II. J Couns Psychol. 2012;59(2):274&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0027310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22352950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weigold IK, Robitschek C. Agentic personality characteristics and coping: their relation to trait anxiety in college students. Am J Orthopsychiatry. 2011;81(2):255&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1939-0025.2011.01094.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21486267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robitschek C, Hershberger AR. Predicting expectations about counseling: psychological factors and gender implications. J Couns &#xf06; Dev. 2005;83(4):457&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.1556-6678.2005.tb00367.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robitschek C. Personal growth initiative: the construct and its measure. Meas Evaluation Couns Dev. 1998;30(4):183&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07481756.1998.12068941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Himmelberger ZM, Tibbetts Y, Barron KE, Hulleman CS, Harootunian G, Speicher MR. How can a growth mindset-supportive learning environment in medical school promote student well-being? Families Syst Health. 2024;42(3):343&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/fsh0000915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39418421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demird&#xf6;gen B, Lewis SE. Investigating how chemistry students&#x2019; reported challenges inform the relationship between mindset and academic performance. J Chem Educ. 2023;100(9):3252&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jchemed.3c00452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel JE. Online PLC based on growth mindset theory for developing science teachers&#x2019; technology use and academic motivation in Egypt. J Sci Edu Technol 2025:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnette JL, Russell MV, Hoyt CL, Orvidas K, Widman L. An online growth mindset intervention in a sample of rural adolescent girls. Br J Educ Psychol. 2017;88(3):428&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjep.12192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28960257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeager DS, Trzesniewski KH, Dweck CS. An implicit theories of personality intervention reduces adolescent aggression in response to victimization and exclusion. Child Dev. 2013;84(5):970&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cdev.12003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3660787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23106262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haimovitz K, Dweck CS. What predicts children&#x2019;s fixed and growth intelligence mindsets? Not their parents&#x2019; views of intelligence but their parents&#x2019; views of failure. Psychol Sci. 2016;27(6):859&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0956797616639727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27113733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park D, Tsukayama E, Yu A, Duckworth AL. The development of grit and growth mindset during adolescence. J Exp Child Psychol 2020, 198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8747892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32629233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker-Drob EM, Briley DA, Engelhardt LE, Mann FD, Harden KP. Genetically-mediated associations between measures of childhood character and academic achievement. J Personal Soc Psychol. 2016;111(5):790&#x2013;815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pspp0000098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5073013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27337136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West MR, Kraft MA, Finn AS, Martin RE, Duckworth AL, Gabrieli CFO, Gabrieli JDE. Promise and paradox: measuring students&#x2019; non-cognitive skills and the impact of schooling. Educational Evaluation Policy Anal. 2016;38(1):148&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/0162373715597298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Liu H, Zhang P. Study on the relationship between growth mindset, grit and subjective well-being of adolescents. J Jimei Univ (Chinese) 2021, 22(4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park D, Yu A, Baelen RN, Tsukayama E, Duckworth AL. Fostering grit:perceived school goal-structure predicts growth in grit and grades. Contemp Educ Psychol. 2018;55:120&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2018.09.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32831457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duckworth AL, Quinn PD. Development and validation of the short grit scale(Grit-S). J Pers Assess. 2009;91(2):166&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00223890802634290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19205937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casali N, Feraco T, Meneghetti C. Keep going, keep growing: A longitudinal analysis of grit, posttraumatic growth, and life satisfaction in school students under COVID-19. Learn Individual Differences. 2023;105:102320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lindif.2023.102320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10288321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37366479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duckworth A, Gross JJ. Self-control and grit:&#xf32;elated but separable determinants of success. Curr Dir Psychol Sci. 2014;23(5):319&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0963721414541462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26855479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddi S&#xf32;, Erwin LM, Carmody CL, Vil-Larreal BJ, White M, Gundersen KK. Relationship of hardiness grit and e motional intelligence to internet addiction, excessive Con sumer, spending and gambling. J Posit Psychol 2013, 8(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teimouri Y, Plonsky Y, Tabandeh F. L2 grit: passion and perseverance for second Language learning. Lang Teach Res. 2022;26(5):893&#x2013;918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362168820921895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paunesku D, Walton G, Romero C, Smith E, Yeager D, Dweck C. Mind-set interventions are a scalable treatment for academic underachievement. Psychol Sci. 2015;26(6):784&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0956797615571017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25862544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin AJ, Nejad H, Colmar S, Liem GAD. Adaptability: conceptual and empirical perspectives on responses to change, novelty and uncertainty. Australian J Guidance Counselling. 2012;22(1):58&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/jgc.2012.8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou N, Noels K. Mindsets matter for linguistic minority students: growth mindsets foster greater perceived proficiency, especially for newcomers. Mod Lang J. 2020;104(4):739&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/modl.12669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarrinabadi N, Rezazadeh M, Karimi M, Lou NM. Why do growth mindsets make you feel better about learning and your selves? The mediating role of adaptability. Innov Lang Learn Teach. 2021;16(3):249&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17501229.2021.1962888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boo S, Wang C, Kim M. Career adaptability, future time perspective, and career anxiety among undergraduate students: A cross-national comparison. J Hospitality Leisure Sport Tourism Educ 2021, 29(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera M, Shapoval V, Medeiros M. The relationship between career adaptability, hope, resilience, and life satisfaction for hospitality students in times of Covid-19. J Hospitality Leisure Sport Tourism Educ 2021, 29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8528733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34703387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collie RJ, Granziera H, Martin AJ, Burns EC, Holliman AJ. Adaptability among science teachers in schools: A multi-nation examination of its role in school outcomes. Teach Teacher Educ. 2020;95(10):103&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holliman AJ, Martin AJ, Collie RJ. Adaptability, engagement, and degree completion: A longitudinal investigation of university students. Educational Psychol. 2018;38(6):785&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01443410.2018.1426835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockinger K, Rinas R, Daumiller M. Student adaptability, emotions, and achievement: navigating new academic terrains in a global crisis. Learn Individual Differences 2021, 90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9759342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36569365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin AJ, Nejad HG, Colmar S, Liem GAD. Adaptability: how students&#x2019; responses to uncertainty and novelty predict their academic and non-academic outcomes. J Educ Psychol. 2013;105(3):728&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0032794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Chang EC. Examining the structure, reliability, and validity of the Chinese personal growth initiative scale-II: evidence for the importance of intentional self-change among Chinese. J Pers Assess. 2014;96(5):559&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00223891.2014.886256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24579722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walburg V. Burnout among high school students: A literature review. Child Youth Serv Rev. 2014;42:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.childyouth.2014.03.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patanapu SK, Doshi D, Kulkarni S, Reddy P, Adepu S, Reddy S. Does academic performance influence personal growth initiative? An institutional-based study among undergraduate dental students. J Educ Health Promotion. 2018;7(1):83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_204_17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6052781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30079354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong Z, Jiao X, Zhang M, Qu Q, Sun B. Effects of personal growth initiative on occupational engagement of college students in the uncertain social context: A cross-lagged model and a moderated mediation model. Front Psychol 2022, 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9533056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricky H, Monty PS, Linda W. The influence of personal growth initiative on student grit during the pandemic. Int J Application Social Sci Humanit. 2023;1(1):595&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celik E. Mediating and moderating role of academic self-efficacy in the relationship between student academic support and personal growth initiative. Australian J Career Dev. 2015;24(2):105&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1038416215583563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brianna RS, Xu J. Personal growth initiative as a protective factor between the relation of practical stress and life satisfaction. J Am Coll Health 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38039412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oksenberg L, Cannell C, Kalton G. New strategies for pretesting survey questions. J Official Stat. 1991;7(3):349&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dweck CS. Mindset: the new psychology of success. New York: NY: Random House; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng T, Su T, Hu X, Li H. The development of a test about learning adjustment of undergraduates. Acta Physiol Sinica (Chinese). 2006;38(05):762&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J, Fan Y, He J, Dai H. How does a good leader-member relationship motivate employees&#x2019; innovative behaviour? Leadersh Organ Dev J. 2023;44(5):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J, He J, Dai H, Jing Y, Shang G. The impact of perceived overqualification on employees&#x2019; innovation behaviour: role of psychological contract breach, psychological distance and employment relationship atmosphere. Leadersh Organ Dev J. 2023;44(3):407&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/LODJ-04-2022-0200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Zhao L, Xia Y, Dai L. Unveiling the dual impacts of the aesthetic deficiency of foods on consumers&#x2019; purchase intentions. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):11218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-92352-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11965373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40175417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsakoff PM, Mackenzie SB, Lee JY, Podsakoff NP. Common method biases in behavioral research: A critical review of the literature and recommended remedies. J Appl Psychol. 2003;88(5):879&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.88.5.879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14516251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112(1):155&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.112.1.155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. 2nd ed. Hillsdale: NJ: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates.; 1988.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>