<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41867972</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-1078</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing deep learning in AI-enhanced education: a dual mediation model of cognitive load and learning motivation through interaction quality.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1768822</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1768822</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1768822</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyg.2026.1768822</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This research develops and validates a dual mediation framework examining the pathways through which interaction quality in artificial intelligence educational systems is positively associated with deep learning outcomes via cognitive load reduction and motivational enhancement. Utilizing covariance-based structural equation modeling (CB-SEM), we analyzed survey data from 570 university teachers engaged with AI-powered learning platforms. Findings demonstrate that high-quality human-AI interaction significantly reduces cognitive burden, which in turn is positively related to learning motivation and shows pathways to deep learning approaches. Bootstrap procedures confirmed robust sequential mediation effects, with this pathway accounting for 53% of the total variance. The model achieved excellent fit indices and explained 31.5% of variance in deep learning outcomes. By synthesizing Cognitive Load Theory with Self-Determination Theory, this study contributes to educational technology scholarship by elucidating the psychological mechanisms linking interface design to learning depth. The empirical evidence provides actionable insights for developing AI educational systems that strategically minimize cognitive demands, foster motivational engagement, and support meaningful learning experiences.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Dong.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Childhood Education College, Ningbo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550902</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-1078</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive load theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">covariance-based structural equation modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning strategies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intelligent educational systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interaction quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">learning motivation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41867972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12999455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2026.1768822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akram H., Li S. (2024). Understanding the role of teacher-student relationships in students' online learning engagement: mediating role of academic motivation. Percept. Mot. Skills 131, 1415&#x2013;1438. doi: 10.1177/00315125241248709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00315125241248709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38647390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An F., Yu J., Xi L. (2022). Relationship between perceived teacher support and learning engagement among adolescents: mediation role of technology acceptance and learning motivation. Front. Psychol. 13:992464. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.992464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.992464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9562933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36248506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey D., Almusharraf N., Hatcher R. (2021). Finding satisfaction: intrinsic motivation for synchronous and asynchronous communication in the online language learning context. Educ. Inf. Technol. 26, 2563&#x2013;2583. doi: 10.1007/s10639-020-10369-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-020-10369-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7641871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33169066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaidir C., Majid M. S. A., Ibrahim M., Djalil M. A., Agustina M. (2025). The role of digital leadership in technology-driven learning in Indonesian senior high schools. Int. J. Dist. Educ. Technol. 23:391898. doi: 10.4018/IJDET.391898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/IJDET.391898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong D. (2025). Self-determination theory perspectives on the influence of digital learning engagement on motivation in extracurricular learning activities: considering the mediating role of digital self-efficacy. Learn. Motiv. 90:102135. doi: 10.1016/j.lmot.2025.102135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lmot.2025.102135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu P., Gao C., Chen X., Zhang Z., Chen J., Yang D. (2024). Proactive personality and its impact on online learning engagement through positive emotions and learning motivation. Sci. Rep. 14:28144. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-79776-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-79776-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11568340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39548208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grozev V. H., Easterbrook M. J., Jessop D. C. (2024). Discipline identification, identity incompatibility, belonging and their association with deep approaches to learning and academic self-efficacy during COVID-19 in the UK. Eur. J. Psychol. Educ. 39, 785&#x2013;812. doi: 10.1007/s10212-023-00735-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10212-023-00735-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajian S., Chang D. H., Wang Q., Lin M. P. (2025). Motivational theories in action: a guide for teaching artificial intelligence prompts to support student learning motivation. Int. J. Instruct. 18, 601&#x2013;626. doi: 10.29333/iji.2025.18433a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29333/iji.2025.18433a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homyamyen P., Kulachai W., Kurniawati L., Khaowisade T., Thaiposri W. (2025). Key drivers of success in online learning for undergraduate students in logistics and supply chain management. Cogent Education, 12(1), Article 2500000. doi: 10.1080/2331186X.2025.2500000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2331186X.2025.2500000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F., Zhang H. (2025). Enhancing willingness to communicate in the second language through technology: the effects of community of practice, enjoyment, and boredom in online classes. Comput. Assis. Lang. Learn. Advance online publication. doi: 10.1080/09588221.2025.2497496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09588221.2025.2497496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X., Zhang C., Wang Y., Huo T. (2025). Affective computing-driven optimization methods for adaptive foreign language learning systems research and empirical validation. Int. J. Hum. Comput. Interact. Advance online publication. doi: 10.1080/10447318.2025.2551048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10447318.2025.2551048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jose B., Cherian J., Verghis A. M., Varghise S. M., Mumthas S., Joseph S. (2025). The cognitive paradox of AI in education: between enhancement and erosion. Front. Psychol. 16:1550621. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1550621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1550621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12036037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40297599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyuga S., Liu T. (2015). Guest editorial: Managing cognitive load in technology-based learning environments. Educ. Technol. Soc. 18, 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamparia A., Pandey B. (2018). Effects of visual map embedded approach on students learning performance using Briggs-Myers learning style in word puzzle gaming course. Comput. Elect. Eng. 66, 531&#x2013;540. doi: 10.1016/j.compeleceng.2017.12.041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2017.12.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamparia A., Pandey B. (2020). Effects of microworld game-based approach on neuromuscular disabled students learning performance in elementary basic science courses. Educ. Inf. Technol. 25, 3881&#x2013;3896. doi: 10.1007/s10639-020-10142-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-020-10142-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D., Lee M. (2019). &#x201c;The structural relationship among smartphone dependency, teaching presence, deep approach to learning and satisfaction in online deeper learning,&#x201d; in Technology (New York, NY: Association for Computing Machinery; ), 27&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1145/3318396.3318416</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3318396.3318416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kio S. I., Lau M. C. (2017). Utilization of online educational resources in teaching: a moderated mediation perspective. Educ. Inf. Technol. 22, 1327&#x2013;1346. doi: 10.1007/s10639-016-9495-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10639-016-9495-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C., Hsu Y. (2021). Sustainable education using augmented reality in vocational certification courses. Sustainability 13:6434. doi: 10.3390/su13116434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13116434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Zhan Z., Ji Y., Li T. (2025). Exploring human and AI collaboration in inclusive STEM teacher training: a synergistic approach based on self-determination theory. Int. High. Educ. 65:101003. doi: 10.1016/j.iheduc.2025.101003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iheduc.2025.101003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Jiang J. (2025). How time pressure intensifies artificial intelligence addiction among graduate students: Exploring the role of academic control deprivation and self-reflexivity across engagement profiles. High. Educ. Advance online publication. doi: 10.1007/s10734-025-01559-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10734-025-01559-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L., Atkinson R. K., Christopherson R. M., Joseph S. S., Harrison C. J. (2013). Animated agents and learning: does the type of verbal feedback they provide matter? Comput. Educ. 67, 239&#x2013;249. doi: 10.1016/j.compedu.2013.04.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compedu.2013.04.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Wang D., Gu X., Hwang G., Tu Y., Wang Y. (2025). Facilitating pre-service teachers' instructional design and higher-order thinking with generative AI: an integrated approach with the peer assessment and concept map. J. Res. Technol. Educ. Advance online publication. doi: 10.1080/15391523.2025.2474528</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15391523.2025.2474528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng J., Wang Z., Li Z. (2016). &#x201c;Application of cognitive load theory in mobile micro-learning,&#x201d; in Proceedings of the 2016 International Conference on Management Science and Innovative Education eds. L. Liu and D. Zhao (Paris: Atlantis Press), 295&#x2013;298. doi: 10.2991/msie-16.2016.110</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2991/msie-16.2016.110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mphahlele L. (2022). Students' perception of the use of a rubric and peer reviews in an online learning environment. J. Risk Fin. Manag. 15:503. doi: 10.3390/jrfm15110503</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jrfm15110503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namaziandost E. (2025). Academic motivation, academic buoyancy, and language development in AI-supported learning environments: a SEM analysis of the roles of digital informal learning and digital competence. Innov. Lang. Learn. Teach. Advance online publication. doi: 10.1080/17501229.2025.2570836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17501229.2025.2570836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngandoh S. T., Riandi R., Rahmat A., Muslim M., Haris A., Khaeruddin K., Friyanto A. (2025). Enhancing interactive media design using cognitive load theory approach: integrating artificial intelligence (AI) chatbot. J. Eng. Sci. Technol. 20, 71&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguar K. D. A., Appolloni A. (2024). The impact of digital learning and capacity building on employees' performance in humanitarian organizations. Knowl. Manag. Res. Practice 23, 119&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1080/14778238.2024.2328177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14778238.2024.2328177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni K., Dai H. M., Brown C. (2024). Secondary school students' learning persistence in human-AI hybrid learning: the supplementary role of parental mediation. Br. J. Educ. Technol. 56, 2227&#x2013;2250. doi: 10.1111/bjet.13563</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjet.13563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan X. (2023). Online learning environments, learners' empowerment, and learning behavioral engagement: the mediating role of learning motivation. SAGE Open, 13:21582440231205098. doi: 10.1177/21582440231205098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21582440231205098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purnama S., Ulfah M., Machali I., Wibowo A., Narmaditya B. S. (2021). Does digital literacy influence students' online risk? Evidence from Covid-19. Heliyon 7:e07406. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2021.e07406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2021.e07406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8258846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34258460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qasrawi A., VicunaPolo S., Qasrawi R. (2021). &#x201c;User experience and performance evaluation of Palestinian universities websites,&#x201d; in 2021 International Conference on Promising Electronic Technologies (New York, NY: IEEE; ), 73&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1109/ICPET53277.2021.00019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICPET53277.2021.00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salas J., Chang A., Montalvo L., N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez A., Vilcapoma M., Moquillaza A., Murillo B., Paz F. (2019). &#x201c;Guidelines to evaluate the usability and user experience of learning support platforms: a systematic review,&#x201d; in Human-computer interaction, HCI-COLLAB 2019, eds. V. Agredo-Delgado and P. H. Ruiz (Berlin: Springer; ), 238&#x2013;254. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-37386-3_18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-37386-3_18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana R., Rodr&#xed;guez A., Rybarczyk Y., M&#xe9;ndez G., Vera F., Rossi G. (2022). &#x201c;A study on user experience of smart glasses for higher education students,&#x201d; in 2022 17th Iberian Conference on Information Systems and Technologies, eds. A. Rocha, B. Bordel, F. G. Penalvo, and R. Goncalves (New York, NY: IEEE), 197&#x2013;202. doi: 10.23919/CISTI54924.2022.9820326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23919/CISTI54924.2022.9820326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz T., Knierim M. T., Weinhardt C. (2025). &#x201c;How generative-AI-assistance impacts cognitive load during knowledge work: a study proposal,&#x201d; in Information systems and neuroscience, NeuroIS Retreat 2024, eds. F. D. Davis, R. Riedl, J. VomBrocke, P. M. Leger, A. B. Randolph, and G. R. Muller-Putz (Berlin: Springer; ), 357&#x2013;365. doi: 10.1007/978-3-031-71385-9_31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-031-71385-9_31</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaari R., Mahmud N., Wahab S. R. A., Rahim K. A., Rajab A., Panatik S. A. (2012). &#x2018;Deep' as a learning approach in inspiring creative and innovative minds among postgraduate students in research university. Proced. Soc. Behav. Sci. 40, 152&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1016/j.sbspro.2012.03.175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sbspro.2012.03.175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skulmowski A., Xu K. M. (2022). Understanding cognitive load in digital and online learning: a new perspective on extraneous cognitive load. Educ. Psychol. Rev. 34, 171&#x2013;196. doi: 10.1007/s10648-021-09624-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10648-021-09624-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H., Tang X., Jiang Y. (2025). Dual-channel conduction modulated by digital literacy: Examining technology shock awareness and informal digital learning through an AI-enabled human-computer interaction lens. Disabil. Rehabil. Assist. Technol. Advance online publication. doi: 10.1080/17483107.2025.2573221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2025.2573221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41075300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syamala S., Shrivastava A., Karmakar S. (2025). Enhancing user experience in digital design learning environments through user interface improvements: a comprehensive approach. IEEE Access 13, 182960&#x2013;182976. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3624267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3624267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan K., Loganathan S. R., Pidani R. R., Yeap P., Ng D. W. L., Chong N. T. S., et al. (2024). Embracing imperfections: a predictive analysis of factors alleviating adult leaders' digital learning stress on Singapore's lifelong learning journey. Hum. Resour. Dev. Int. 28, 371&#x2013;392. doi: 10.1080/13678868.2024.2389029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13678868.2024.2389029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfik A., Payne L., Ketter H., James J. (2024a). What instruments do researchers use to evaluate LXD? A systematic review study. Technol. Knowl. Learn. 30, 47&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1007/s10758-024-09763-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10758-024-09763-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfik A., Schmidt M., Payne L., Huang R. (2024b). Advancing understanding of learning experience design: refining and clarifying definitions using an eDelphi study approach. ETRandD&#x2014;Educ. Technol. Res. Dev. 72, 1539&#x2013;1561. doi: 10.1007/s11423-024-10355-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11423-024-10355-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., McWatt S. C. (2023). Visuospatial ability and student approach to learning as predictors of academic performance on written versus laboratory-based assessments in human anatomy. Anat. Sci. Educ. 16, 1187&#x2013;1199. doi: 10.1002/ase.2317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ase.2317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37483065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan N., Yu Q., Liu W. (2025). The impact of digital literacy on learning outcomes among college students: the mediating effect of digital atmosphere, self-efficacy for digital technology and digital learning. Front. Educ. 10:1641687. doi: 10.3389/feduc.2025.1641687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feduc.2025.1641687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>