<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41584666</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-462X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in plant science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Plant Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing multiclass plant disease classification using GAN-boosted vision transformer with XAI insights.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1649399</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1649399</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1649399</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpls.2025.1649399</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Agriculture is one of the major backbones of the Indian economy, where rice is the most prominent staple crop across the country. However, rice production has been significantly affected due to the occurrence of various plant diseases. Deep learning and machine learning have emerged as powerful solutions for computer vision-based problems.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This work identifies some of the key diseases and addresses these prominent ones using a state-of-the-art deep learning model. It proposes a novel multiclass rice leaf disease recognition model named GRG-ViT, which integrates Vision Transformer (ViT), Generative Artificial Intelligence (GenAI), and Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) techniques for better outcomes. The Vision Transformer-based framework is designed to capture long-range spatial dependencies in leaf images, which enhances the model's ability to identify the subtle disease patterns. Since the dataset portrayed considerable class imbalance, a GenAI-based synthetic data generation approach is equipped in this model to create balanced training samples, which in turn improves the model's robustness. This model also proposes a hybrid Rectified Linear Unit (ReLU)-Gaussian Error Linear Unit (GELU)-based activation mechanism to attain effective feature representation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS AND DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The obtained experimental results exhibit that the proposed GRG-ViT model reaches close to an overall accuracy of 96%, which outperforms conventional approaches. The incorporation of XAI methods like Gradient-weighted Class Activation Mapping (Grad-CAM) provides both interpretability and transparency by emphasizing the regions impacting the model's actions. This research showcases the blended power of ViT, GenAI, and XAI in producing reliable and high-performing results for rice disease detection in precision agriculture.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 S. A. M. and B. R..</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S A M</LastName><ForeName>Felicita</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science Engineering and Information Systems, Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B R</LastName><ForeName>Kavitha</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science Engineering and Information Systems, Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Plant Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101568200</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-462X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">class imbalance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">explainable AI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">generative adversarial networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rice disease detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vision transformer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41584666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12827657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2025.1649399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbas A., Jain S., Gour M., Vankudothu S. (2021). Tomato plant disease detection using transfer learning with C-GAN synthetic images. Comput. Electron. Agric. 187, 106279. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.compag.2021.106279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2021.106279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akilan T., Baalamurugan K. M. (2024). Automated weather forecasting and field monitoring using GRU-CNN model along with IoT to support precision agriculture. Expert Syst. Appl 249, 123468. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhammad S. M., Khafaga D. S., El-Hady W. M., Samy F. M., Hosny K. M. (2025). Deep learning and explainable AI for classification of potato leaf diseases. Front. Artif. Intell 7, 1449329. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/frai.2024.1449329, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frai.2024.1449329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11830750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39963448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashish V., Noam S., Niki P., Jakob U., Llion J., Gomez A. N., et al. (2017). &#x201c; Attention is all you need,&#x201d; in Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems. (California: ) 5998&#x2013;6008. doi:&#xa0; 10.48550/arXiv.1706.03762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1706.03762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhakta I., Phadikar S., Majumder K., Mukherjee H., Sau A. (2023). A novel plant disease prediction model based on thermal images using modified deep convolutional neural network. Precis. Agric. 24, 23&#x2013;39. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s11119-022-09927-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11119-022-09927-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borhani Y., Khoramdel J., Najafi E. (2022). A deep learning based approach for automated plant disease classification using vision transformer. Sci. Rep. 12, 11554. doi:&#xa0; 10.1038/s41598-022-15163-0, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-15163-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9262884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35798775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budhkar A., Song Q., Su J., Zhang X. (2025). Demystifying the black box: A survey on explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) in bioinformatics. Comput. Struct. Biotechnol. J. 27, 346&#x2013;359. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.csbj.2024.12.027, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csbj.2024.12.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11782883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39897059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrabarty A., Ahmed S. T., Islam M. F. U., Aziz S. M., Maidin S. S. (2024). An interpretable fusion model integrating lightweight CNN and transformer architectures for rice leaf disease identification. Ecol. Inf. 82, 102718. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.ecoinf.2024.102718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2024.102718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheemaladinne V., Reddy S. (2024). Tomato leaf disease detection and management using VARMAx-CNN-GAN integration. J. King Saud University-Science. 36, 103340. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jksus.2024.103340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2024.103340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chefer H., Gur S., Wolf L. (2021). &#x201c; Transformer interpretability beyond attention visualization,&#x201d; in Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF conference on computer vision and pattern recognition. (Tennessee: ) 782&#x2013;791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chettri K., Sen B., Ghosal P. (2024). &#x201c; ViT-PlantNet: Enhancing plant disease classification with encoder-decoder architecture,&#x201d; in Proceedings of the 2024 OITS International Conference on Information Technology (OCIT). (Guntur: ) 86&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniya T., Vigneshwari S. (2023). Rice plant leaf disease detection and classification using optimization enabled deep learning. J. Environ. Inf. 42, 25. doi:&#xa0; 10.3808/jei.202300492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3808/jei.202300492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng R., Tao M., Xing H., Yang X., Liu C., Liao K., et al. (2021). Automatic diagnosis of rice diseases using deep learning. Front. Plant Sci. 12, 701038. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fpls.2021.701038, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2021.701038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8416767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34490004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogra R., Rani S., Singh A., Albahar M. A., Barrera A. E., Alkhayyat A. (2023). Deep learning model for detection of brown spot rice leaf disease with smart agriculture. Comput. Electrical Eng 109, 108659. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.compeleceng.2023.108659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2023.108659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy A., Beyer L., Kolesnikov A., Weissenborn D., Zhai X., Unterthiner T., et al. (2020). An image is worth 16x16 words: Transformers for image recognition at scale. arXiv preprint arXiv:2010.11929. doi:&#xa0; 10.48550/arXiv.2010.11929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2010.11929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmitwally N. S., Tariq M., Khan M. A., Ahmad M., Abbas S., Alotaibi F. M. (2022). Rice leaves disease diagnose empowered with transfer learning. Comput. Syst. Sci. Eng. 42, 1001&#x2013;1014. doi:&#xa0; 10.32604/csse.2022.022017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/csse.2022.022017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felicita S. A. M., Kavitha B. R. (2024). &#x201c; Advancing plant disease prediction accuracy with viT based deep learning model,&#x201d; in 2024 International Conference on Computing, Semiconductor, Mechatronics, Intelligent ystems and Communications (COSMIC). (Manglore: ) 60&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg V., Agarwal S., Sharma S. (2023). &#x201c; Deep learning-based paddy doctor for sustainable agriculture,&#x201d; in 2023 Seventh International Conference on Image Information Processing (ICIIP). (Solan: ) 485&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow I. J., Pouget-Abadie J., Mirza M., Xu B., Warde-Farley D., Ozair S., et al. (2014). Generative adversarial nets. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst 27. doi:&#xa0; 10.48550/arXiv.2010.11929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2010.11929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haridasan A., Thomas J., Raj E. D. (2023). Deep learning system for paddy plant disease detection and classification. Environ. Monit. Assess. 195, 120. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s10661-022-10656-x, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-022-10656-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36399232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrycks D., Gimpel K. (2016). Gaussian error linear units (gelus). arXiv preprint arXiv:1606.08415. doi:&#xa0; 10.48550/arXiv.2010.11929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2010.11929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jannat N., Hasan S. M., Zibran M. F. (2025). A novel ensemble approach for crop disease detection by leveraging customized EfficientNets and interpretability. Pattern Recognition Lett. 197, 370&#x2013;377. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.patrec.2025.07.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patrec.2025.07.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kas M., Chahi A., Kajo I., Ruichek Y. (2024). EigenGAN: An SVD subspace-based learning for image generation using Conditional GAN. Knowledge-Based Syst. 293, 111691. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.knosys.2024.111691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2024.111691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klair Y. S., Agrawal K., Kumar A. (2024). &#x201c; Impact of generative ai in diagnosing diseases in agriculture,&#x201d; in 2024 2nd International Conference on Disruptive Technologies (ICDT). (Greater Noida: ) 870&#x2013;875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B., Zheng C., Sun F., Wang X., Pan L. (2025). CDCGAN: Class Distribution-aware Conditional GAN-based minority augmentation for imbalanced node classification. Neural Networks. 183, 106933. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.neunet.2024.106933, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neunet.2024.106933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39637823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Min W., Mei S., Wang L., Jiang S. (2021). Plant disease recognition: A large-scale benchmark dataset and a visual region and loss reweighting approach. IEEE Trans. Image Process. 30, 2003&#x2013;2015. doi:&#xa0; 10.1109/TIP.2021.3049334, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2021.3049334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longo L., Brcic M., Cabitza F., Choi J., Confalonieri R., Del Ser J., et al. (2024). Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) 2.0: A manifesto of open challenges and interdisciplinary research directions. Inf. Fusion. 106, 102301. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.inffus.2024.102301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2024.102301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Wu X., Liu P., Li H., Liu W. (2023). Rice disease identification method based on improved CNN-BiGRU. Artif. Intell. Agric. 9, 100&#x2013;109. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.aiia.2023.08.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aiia.2023.08.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahadevan K., Punitha A., Suresh J. (2024). A novel rice plant leaf diseases detection using deep spectral generative adversarial neural network. Int. J. Cogn. Computing Eng. 5, 237&#x2013;249. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.ijcce.2024.05.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcce.2024.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahim S. M., Ali M. S., Hasan M. O., Nafi A. A. N., Sadat A., Al Hasan S., et al. (2024). Unlocking the potential of XAI for improved Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease detection and classification using a ViT-GRU model. IEEE Access. 12, 8390&#x2013;8412. doi:&#xa0; 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3351809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3351809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maur&#xed;cio J., Domingues I., Bernardino J. (2023). Comparing vision transformers and convolutional neural networks for image classification: A literature review. Appl. Sci. 13, 5521. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/app13095521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13095521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigar N., Faisal H. M., Umer M., Oki O., Lukose J. (2024). Improving plant disease classification with deep learning based prediction model using explainable artificial intelligence. IEEE Access. 12, 100005&#x2013;100014. doi:&#xa0; 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3428553</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3428553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacal I. (2024). Enhancing crop productivity and sustainability through disease identification in maize leaves: Exploiting a large dataset with an advanced vision transformer model. Expert Syst. Appl. 238, 122099. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parez S., Dilshad N., Alghamdi N. S., Alanazi T. M., Lee J. W. (2023). Visual intelligence in precision agriculture: Exploring plant disease detection via efficient vision transformers. Sensors. 23, 6949. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/s23156949, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23156949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10422257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37571732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng M., Liu Y., Qadri I. A., Bhatti U. A., Ahmed B., Sarhan N. M., et al. (2024). Advanced image segmentation for precision agriculture using CNN-GAT fusion and fuzzy C-means clustering. Comput. Electron. Agric. 226, 109431. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.compag.2024.109431</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2024.109431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petchiammal A., Briskline Kiruba S., Murugan D., Arjunan P. (2024). Design a classifier to classify diseases in paddy based on leaf color. IEEE Dataport. doi:&#xa0; 10.21227/3emp-zs52.s</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21227/3emp-zs52.s</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan T. H. M., Hoa N. T. (2024). &#x201c; Rice leaf diseases classification based on riceNet,&#x201d; in International conference on From Smart City to Smart Factory for Sustainable Future. 359&#x2013;368 (Cham: Springer Nature Switzerland; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajpoot V., Tiwari A., Jalal A. S. (2023). Automatic early detection of rice leaf diseases using hybrid deep learning and machine learning methods. Multimedia Tools Appl. 82, 36091&#x2013;36117. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s11042-023-14969-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-023-14969-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis H. C., Turk V. (2024). Potato leaf disease detection with a novel deep learning model based on depthwise separable convolution and transformer networks. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell 133, 108307. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.engappai.2024.108307</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2024.108307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma V., Ashish Kumar Tripathi P., Daga, Nidhi M., Mittal H. (2024). ClGanNet: A novel method for maize leaf disease identification using ClGan and deep CNN,&#x201d; Signal processing. Image communication. 120, 117074&#x2013;117074. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.image.2023.117074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.image.2023.117074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivastava G., Patidar H. (2022). RICE PLANT DISEASE IDENTIFICATION DECISION SUPPORT MODEL USING MACHINE LEARNING. ICTACT J. Soft Computing. 12, 2619&#x2013;2627. doi:&#xa0; 10.21917/ijsc.2022.0375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21917/ijsc.2022.0375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A. K., Rao A., Chattopadhyay P., Maurya R., Singh L. (2024). Effective plant disease diagnosis using Vision Transformer trained with leafy-generative adversarial network-generated images. Expert Syst. Appl. 254, 124387. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.eswa.2024.124387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.124387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultana S., Tasir M. A. M., Nobel S. N., Kabir M. M., Mridha M. F. (2024). XAI-FruitNet: An explainable deep model for accurate fruit classification. J. Agric. Food Res. 18, 101474. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jafr.2024.101474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jafr.2024.101474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tasnim F., Habib I. B., Symon N. K., Arefin M. S., Reza A. W. (2025). &#x201c; Integrating machine learning with association rule mining for enhanced crop disease classification,&#x201d; in 2025 International Conference on Quantum Photonics, Artificial Intelligence, and Networking (QPAIN). (Saidpur: ) 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umar M., Altaf S., Ahmad S., Mahmoud H., Mohamed A. S. N., Ayub R. (2024). Precision agriculture through deep learning: Tomato plant multiple diseases recognition with cnn and improved yolov7. IEEE Access. 12, 49167&#x2013;49183. doi:&#xa0; 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3383154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3383154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay S. K., Kumar A. (2022). A novel approach for rice plant diseases classification with deep convolutional neural network. Int. J. Inf. Technol. 14, 185&#x2013;199. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s41870-021-00817-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41870-021-00817-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallabhajosyula S., Sistla V., Kishore K. (2024). A Novel Hierarchical framework for Plant Leaf Disease Detection using Residual Vision Transformer. Heliyon. 10, e29912. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e29912, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e29912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11064133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38699004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villegas-Cubas, Elias J., David B. H. (2024). Disease detection system in rice leaves, using Deep Learning models. 22nd LACCEI International Multi-Conference for Engineering, Education, and Technology. (Costa Rica: ). doi:&#xa0; 10.18687/LACCEI2024.1.1.479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18687/LACCEI2024.1.1.479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin C., Liu Z., Zhao K., Miao L., Ma Y., Zhu X., et al. (2022). An improved transformer network for skin cancer classification. Comput. Biol. Med 149, 105939. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2022.105939, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2022.105939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36037629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Yang M., Wang H., Qiu Y. (2025). A strategy for improving GAN generation: Contrastive self-adversarial training. Neurocomputing 637, 129864. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.neucom.2025.129864</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2025.129864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C., Zhong Y., Zhou S., Song J., Xiang W. (2023). Rice leaf disease identification by residual-distilled transformer. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 121, 106020. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.engappai.2023.106020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2023.106020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>