<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41667531</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hybrid meta heuristic and fuzzy impedance method for fast fault location in power system lines.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8019</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-33182-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study discusses a new and accurate fault location method for power system lines in power networks. The exact location of the fault and the distance of the line from one end are determined by training the proposed positioning system with experimental reference data. Phasor measurement units (PMUs) at one end of the power line effectively monitor the entire system. First, the types of problems are identified and categorized using the PMU measurement signals. The fault location was then diagnosed using a nonlinear modeling technique to locate the fault based on the impedance of one end. Two non-linear fault locating estimation methods are described based on the fuzzy logic system and the fifth-order Taylor expansion polynomial fitting system. The samples have been used to train the parameters of the proposed positioning systems using the Fire Hawk Optimizer (FHO) algorithm. Therefore, the objective is to determine the distance at which the fault occurs, locate the fault spot precisely, and determine the distance from the PMU at the end of the line. The three-bus system for a 200&#xa0;km long, 220&#xa0;kV power line has been assessed and verified using the Simulink environment of MATLAB software. The results show how effective the proposed method is at locating the exact location of the power line issue with the least amount of error in a PMU. Finally, with an execution duration of less than 0.16&#xa0;s, the method has shown a high search speed on a case study model.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Najafzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Masoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Shab.C, Islamic Azad University, Shabestar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pouladi</LastName><ForeName>Jaber</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Shab.C, Islamic Azad University, Shabestar, Iran. Pouladi.jaber@iau.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daghigh</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Shab.C, Islamic Azad University, Shabestar, Iran. a_daghigh@iau.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beiza</LastName><ForeName>Jamal</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Shab.C, Islamic Azad University, Shabestar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abedinzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Taher</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Shab.C, Islamic Azad University, Shabestar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fault location</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fire hawk optimizer (FHO) algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid fuzzy-impedance method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PMUs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power system lines</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41667531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12957327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-33182-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-33182-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hossain-McKenzie, S., Piesciorovsky, E. C., Reno, M. J. &amp; Hambrick, J. C. <i>Microgrid Fault Location: Challenges and Solutions</i> (Sandia National Laboratories, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu,Y. et al. Region of attraction estimation for power systems with multiple integrated DFIG-based wind turbines. <i>IEEE Trans. Sustain. Energy</i>. <b>16</b>, 1&#x2013;15. 10.1109/TSTE.2025.3579018 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSTE.2025.3579018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, H., Chen, Y., Li, M. &amp; Li, J. Fault-tolerant control design for nonlinear multilateral teleoperation system with unreliable communication channels and actuator constraints. <i>Int. J. Mach. Learn. Cybernet.</i><b>16</b>, 1991&#x2013;2007. 10.1007/s13042-024-02373-3 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13042-024-02373-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M., Chen, Y. &amp; Li, J. Event-Triggered Fault-Tolerant control for nonlinear multilateral teleoperation system with unknown environmental forces. <i>Int. J. Robust Nonlinear Control</i>. <b>35</b>, 1831&#x2013;1847. 10.1002/rnc.7759 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rnc.7759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W., Zong, G., Niu, B., Zhao, X. &amp; Xu, N. Adaptive fuzzy dynamic event-triggered control for PDE-ODE cascaded systems with actuator failures. <i>Fuzzy Sets Syst.</i><b>519</b>(1), 109514. 10.1016/j.fss.2025.109514 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fss.2025.109514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, Z., Yan, S., Ahn, C. K., Yue, D. &amp; Xie, X. Event-Triggered dissipative tracking control of networked control systems with distributed communication delay. <i>IEEE Syst. J.</i><b>16</b>(2), 3320&#x2013;3330. 10.1109/JSYST.2021.3079460 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSYST.2021.3079460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning Xu, T. et al. Zero-sum game-based dynamic self-triggered sliding mode control for unknown nonlinear systems with asymmetric input constraints. <i>ISA Trans.</i>. 10.1016/j.isatra.2025.11.014 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isatra.2025.11.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41266234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X. et al. Security assessment of cascading failures in cyber-physical power systems with wind power penetration. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Syst.</i><b>40</b>, 1&#x2013;13. (2025). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRS.2025.3561125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiahou, K. et al. Resilience assessment for hybrid AC/DC cyber-physical power systems under cascading failures. <i>IEEE Trans. Reliab.</i><b>74</b>, 1&#x2013;12. (2025). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TR.2025.3550523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q. et al. Elevator fault diagnosis based on digital twin and PINNs-e-RGCN. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>(1), 30713. (2024). 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-78784-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11680868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39730406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z., Xu, N., Zhang, L., Zhao, N. &amp; Song, G. Privacy preservation-based dynamic event-triggered bipartite consensus strategy for nonlinear multi-agent systems with unknown mismatched disturbances. <i>Appl. Math. Comput.</i>10.1016/j.amc.2025.129846 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amc.2025.129846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S., Xu, N., Li, L., Alharbi, K. H. &amp; Zhao, X. Zero-sum games-based optimal fault tolerant control for control-constrained multiplayer systems with external disturbances via adaptive dynamic programming. <i>Commun. Nonlinear Sci. Numer. Simul.</i>10.1016/j.cnsns.2025.108804 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cnsns.2025.108804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, H., Zhang, F. &amp; Li, J. Event-Triggered disturbance rejection Fault-Tolerant constrained consensus against agents&#x2019; number changing. <i>J. Syst. Sci. Complexity</i>. 10.1007/s11424-025-4455-2 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11424-025-4455-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, J., Guo, D., Chen, G., Cai, J. &amp; Li, J. Event-triggered inverse control for parametric feedback systems with asymmetric dead-zone input. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>13</b>, 129359&#x2013;129371. 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3590439 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3590439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yumeng Cao, B. et al. Adaptive neural event-triggered secure control for nonlinear mass against actuator faults and FDI attacks. <i>Int. J. Syst. Sci.</i>10.1080/00207721.2025.2530186 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00207721.2025.2530186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. Observer-based adaptive secure control for networked switched nonlinear systems under DoS attacks. <i>Int. J. Gener. Syst.</i>10.1080/03081079.2025.2540300 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03081079.2025.2540300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J., Niu, H. R. K. B. &amp; Zhao, X. Safe optimal control for multiplayer Stackelberg&#x2013;Nash games of nonlinear time-delay systems via adaptive dynamic programming. <i>Neurocomputing</i><b>654</b>, 131203. 10.1016/j.neucom.2025.131203 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2025.131203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hang, J., Qiu, G., Hao, M. &amp; Ding, S. Improved fault diagnosis method for permanent magnet synchronous machine system based on lightweight multisource information data layer fusion. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>39</b>(10), 13808&#x2013;13817 10.1109/TPEL.2024.3432163 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2024.3432163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, S., Nayak, P. K., Panigrahi, B. K. &amp; Pradhan, G. An intelligent fault detection and classification technique based on variational mode decomposition-CNN for transmission lines installed with UPFC and wind farm. <i>Electr. Power Syst. Res.</i><b>223</b>, 109526 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2023.109526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, W., Hang, J., Ding, S., Sun, L. &amp; Hua, W. Robust diagnosis of partial demagnetization fault in PMSMs using radial Air-Gap flux density under complex working conditions. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr. Electron.</i><b>71</b>(10), 12001&#x2013;12010. 10.1109/TIE.2024.3349520 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2024.3349520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, Z., Zhu, C. &amp; Goetz, S. M. Fault-tolerant multiparallel three-phase two-level converters with adaptive hardware reconfiguration. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>39</b>(4), 3925&#x2013;3930. 10.1109/TPEL.2024.3350186 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2024.3350186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, X. et al. Identification of thermal fault states in cable insulation sheaths based on gas sensor arrays. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i>10.1109/TDEI.2025.3572332 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2025.3572332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abeid, A. M., Abd el Ghany, H. A. &amp; Azmy, A. M. An advanced travelling wave fault location algorithm for simultaneous faults. in <i>Nineteenth International Middle East Power Systems Conference (MEPCON)</i> 747&#x2013;752 (2017). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei, W., Wang, X., Lu, Y., Yu, K. &amp; Li, S. Learning and current prediction of PMSM drive via differential neural networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Circuits Syst. II Express Briefs</i>. <b>72</b>(3), 489&#x2013;493. 10.1109/TCSII.2025.3527024 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCSII.2025.3527024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi, S., Su, K., Yu, J., Li, X. &amp; Shen, H. An unsupervised transfer learning bearing fault diagnosis method based on multi-channel calibrated transformer with shiftable window. <i>Struct. Health Monit.</i>10.1177/14759217251324671 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14759217251324671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, S., Liu, C., Fan, Z. &amp; Hang, J. Lumped parameter Adaptation-Based automatic MTPA control for IPMSM drives by using stator current impulse response. <i>IEEE Trans. Energy Convers.</i><b>40</b>(3), 2108&#x2013;2118. 10.1109/TEC.2025.3550193 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEC.2025.3550193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voutsinas, S., Karolidis, D., Voyiatzis, I. &amp; Samarakou, M. Development of a machine-learning-based method for early fault detection in photovoltaic systems. <i>J. Eng. Appl. Sci.</i><b>70</b>, 27 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44147-023-00200-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y. et al. A dynamic imperfect inspection-based maintenance optimization considering dependent competing failure. <i>Measurement</i><b>253</b>, 117470. 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.117470 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.117470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geneid, A., Atia, M. &amp; Badawy A multi-objective optimization of vertical axis wind turbine&#x2019;s blade structure using genetic algorithm. <i>J. Eng. Appl. Sci.</i><b>69</b>, 90 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44147-022-00150-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, N., Zhao, T., Cao, J. &amp; Shi, H. Fault diagnosis of dual-network recursive interval type-2 fuzzy neural network based on SVD-TLS optimization. <i>Comput. Ind. Eng.</i><b>207</b>, 111280. 10.1016/j.cie.2025.111280 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cie.2025.111280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, D., Yuan, X., Gao, H., Ma, J. &amp; Chen, Z. FFRLS-based data-driven voltage security assessment for active distribution networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Smart Grid</i>. <b>16</b>(6), 5685&#x2013;5688 10.1109/TSG.2025.3596779 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSG.2025.3596779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Feasibility study of mechanical stress wave detection in power semiconductor devices using bare FBG sensors. <i>IEEE Sens. J.</i><b>25</b>(21), 39849&#x2013;39857. (2025). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2025.3615108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Bai, H., Yao, R., Wang, Y. &amp; Liu, T. Causes identification and sources localization method for multistage voltage Sag under the influence of high penetration of renewable energy sources. <i>Appl. Energy</i>. <b>402</b>, 126891. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126891 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. et al. UAV based defect detection and fault diagnosis for static and rotating wind turbine blade: A review. <i>Nondestruct. Test. Eval</i>. <b>40</b>(4), 1691&#x2013;1729. 10.1080/10589759.2024.2395363 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10589759.2024.2395363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. Transient stability analysis for hybrid parallel-connected converters by two-dimensional phase portrait. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>40</b>(6), 7765&#x2013;7776. 10.1109/TPEL.2025.3532938 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2025.3532938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, H. et al. Dynamical Analysis, feedback control circuit implementation, and fixed-time sliding mode synchronization of a novel 4D chaotic system. <i>Symmetry</i><b>17</b>(8), 1252. 10.3390/sym17081252 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym17081252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafzadeh, M., Pouladi, J., Daghigh, A., Beiza, J. &amp; Shahmohamadi, S. A new method for fault detection and location in a low-resistance grounded power distribution network using voltage phasor of D&#x2010;PMUs data. <i>Int. Trans. Electr. Energy Syst.</i><b>2023</b>(1), 1754305 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafzadeh, M., Pouladi, J., Daghigh, A., Beiza, J. &amp; Abedinzade, T. Fault Detection, classification and localization along the power grid line using optimized machine learning algorithms. <i>Int. J. Comput. Intell. Syst.</i><b>17</b>(1), 49 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44196-024-00434-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, S., Roy, P. K., Mandal, B. &amp; Mukherjee, I. Artificial hummingbird Algorithm-based fault location optimization for transmission line. <i>J. Eng. Appl. Sci.</i><b>71</b>(1), 149 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s44147-024-00475-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, G. et al. Fault location of high voltage overhead transmission line based on ACO-ENN algorithm. <i>Int. J. Crit. Infrastruct.</i><b>19</b>(6), 544&#x2013;557 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJCIS.2023.134619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lak, P. Y., Ha, K. M. &amp; Nam, S. R. A fault location algorithm for Multi-Section combined transmission lines considering unsynchronized sampling. <i>Energies</i><b>17</b>, 703. 10.3390/en17030703 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17030703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Y. et al. A mechanism-guided intelligent enhancement method for early aging information of winding insulation. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr. Inf.</i><b>21</b>(7), 5440&#x2013;5450. 10.1109/TII.2025.3555990 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2025.3555990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Li, Y., Men, T. &amp; Li, L. Physically interpretable Wavelet-Guided networks with dynamic frequency decomposition for machine intelligence fault prediction. <i>IEEE Trans. Syst. Man. Cybernetics: Syst.</i><b>54</b>(8), 4863&#x2013;4875. 10.1109/TSMC.2024.3389068 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSMC.2024.3389068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, A. et al. A Novel GA-PSO-SVM model for compound fault diagnosis in gearboxes with limited data. <i>IEEE Sens. J.</i><b>25</b>(16), 30431&#x2013;30443. 10.1109/JSEN.2025.3576761 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2025.3576761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, J., Liang, F., Feng, H. &amp; Ran, L. Condition monitoring of discrete power devices: A data-driven approach with stress quantification and mold temperature sensing. <i>IEEE J. Emerg. Sel. Top. Power Electron.</i><b>12</b>(3), 2569&#x2013;2579 10.1109/JESTPE.2024.3387652 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JESTPE.2024.3387652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, N., Luo, L., Sheng, G. &amp; Jiang, X. Scheduling the imperfect maintenance and replacement of power substation equipment: A Risk-Based optimization model. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Delivery</i>. <b>40</b>(4), 2154&#x2013;2166. 10.1109/TPWRD.2025.3572076 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2025.3572076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. A Novel optimal power flow method considering interval uncertainties under high renewable penetration based on security limits definition. <i>IEEE Trans. Sustain. Energy</i>. 10.1109/TSTE.2025.3602456 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSTE.2025.3602456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin, P. &amp; Liu, P. Study on vibration characteristics of stator core during Inter-Turn short circuit of field winding in Hydro-Generator. <i>J. Electr. Eng. Technol.</i>10.1007/s42835-025-02381-5 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42835-025-02381-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, S. &amp; Panigrahi, B. K. An improved fault detection and phase identification for collector system of DFIG-wind farms using least square transient detector coefficient. <i>Electr. Power Syst. Res.</i><b>226</b>, 109961 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2023.109961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, S., Panigrahi, B. K., Nayak, P. K., Pradhan, G. &amp; Padmanaban, S. A single-pole filter-assisted improved protection scheme for the TCSC-compensated transmission line connecting large-scale wind farms. <i>IEEE J. Emerg. Sel. Top. Industrial Electron.</i><b>5</b>(2), 346&#x2013;358 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JESTIE.2023.3345791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, T., Yao, L. &amp; Yang, G. A new fault location method for high-voltage transmission lines based on ICEEMDAN&#x2010;MSA&#x2010;ConvGRU model. <i>IET Gener. Trans. Distrib</i>. <b>18</b>(16), 2650&#x2013;2668 (2024). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/gtd2.13225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir, &#xd6;., K&#xf6;ker, R. &amp; Pamuk, N. Fault classification and precise fault location detection in 400&#xa0;kV High-Voltage power transmission lines using machinelearning algorithms. <i>Processes</i><b>13</b>, 527. 10.3390/pr13020527 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr13020527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi, M., Trik, M. &amp; Ansari, A. Diagnosis and classification of disturbances in the power distribution network by phasor measurement unit based on fuzzy intelligent system. <i>J. Eng.</i><b>2024</b>(1), e12322 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ghannam, S. H. et al. Development of open (broken) conductor detection system for high resistivity areas. in <i>2017 Saudi Arabia Smart Grid</i> 1&#x2013;8 (IEEE, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, 2017). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuthalapati, B. &amp; Sinha, U. K. Fault detection and location of broken power line not touching the ground. <i>Int. J. Emerg. Electr. Power Syst.</i><b>20</b>(3), 1&#x2013;10 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, A., Tong, X., Al-Bukhaiti, K., Zhou, Z., Su, Y., Cheng, X.,... Ji, X. (2025). Vibration prediction for abnormal elevator door system faults based on attention mechanism and neural networks with time-frequency domain features. <i>Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. Part. C J. Mechan. Eng. Sci.</i><b>239</b>(18), 7358&#x2013;7372. 10.1177/09544062251347475</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Q., Song, Y., Mu, J., Lv, Y., Yang, J., Xu, L.,... Meng, Q. (2023). Electric power audit text classification with multi-grained pre-trained language model. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>11</b>, 13510&#x2013;13518. 10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3240162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Ding, T. &amp; Xu, W. An open conductor condition monitoring scheme using natural voltage and current disturbances. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Delivery</i>. <b>34</b>(3), 1193&#x2013;1202 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2019.2906313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. &amp; Xu, W. A 3rd harmonic power based open conductor detection scheme. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Deliv.</i><b>36</b>(2), 1041&#x2013;1050 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2020.3001075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Aziz, A. M., Hasaneen, B. M. &amp; Dawood, A. A. Detection and classification of one conductor open faults in parallel transmission line using artificial neural network. <i>Int. J. Sci. Res. Eng. Trends</i>. <b>2</b>(6), 139&#x2013;146 (2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>