<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41528683</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1613-9674</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Oral radiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Oral Radiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Web-based AI application for enhanced dental disease diagnosis using advanced object detection integrated with transformer-based attention mechanism.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11282-025-00886-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The accurate and timely diagnosis of dental diseases is critical for effective treatment and improved patient outcomes. However, traditional methods of analyzing panoramic X-ray images rely heavily on the expertise of oral and maxillofacial radiologists and dentists, making the process time-consuming, labor-intensive, and prone to human error. To address these challenges, this study introduces a novel web-based AI application powered by the YOLOv11-TAM model designed to automate the detection and diagnosis of dental diseases from panoramic X-ray images.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The proposed system integrates a user-friendly interface, a robust PostgreSQL database, and an advanced AI engine based on the YOLOv11-TAM architecture. The AI engine was trained and validated using the publicly available DENTEX dataset, which includes 705 annotated panoramic X-ray images categorized into four disease classes: caries, deep caries, impacted teeth, and periapical lesions. The YOLOv11-TAM model incorporates architectural innovations, including the C3k2 block, Spatial Pyramid Pooling Fast (SPPF) layer, and Transformer-based attention mechanisms, to enhance feature extraction, localization accuracy, and adaptability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The customized YOLOv11-TAM model demonstrated significant improvements over YOLOv11, achieving about a 15% increase in precision, a high specificity of 0.92, and over 12% improvement in localization accuracy for periapical lesions. Class-specific evaluations revealed superior performance in detecting deep caries and periapical lesions, although challenges remain in diagnosing caries due to class imbalance. The usability study also yielded high satisfaction scores, with an average exceeding 8 across all dimensions, highlighting the application's intuitive design and seamless integration into clinical workflows.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study presents a transformative web-based AI application that leverages advanced deep learning techniques to enhance the accuracy, efficiency, and accessibility of dental diagnostics. By reducing radiologists' workload and enabling early disease detection, the proposed solution has the potential to revolutionize dental healthcare, particularly in underserved regions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s) under exclusive licence to Japanese Society for Oral and Maxillofacial Radiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadr</LastName><ForeName>Hossein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Research Center, Trauma Institute, Guilan University of Medical Sciences, Rasht, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Artificial Intelligence in Medicine, Faculty of Advanced Technologies in Medicine, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nazari</LastName><ForeName>Mojdeh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Disease Research Center, Department of Cardiology, School of Medicine, Heshmat Hospital, Guilan University of Medical Sciences, Rasht, Iran. Mojdeh.nazari@sbmu.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Information Technology and Management, School of Allied Medical Sciences, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran. Mojdeh.nazari@sbmu.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koochaki</LastName><ForeName>Mahsa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dental Sciences Research Center, Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Medicine, School of Dentistry, Guilan University of Medical Sciences, Rasht, Iran. mahsakoochaki18@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hendi</LastName><ForeName>Amirreza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dental Sciences Research Center, Department of Prosthodontics, School of Dentistry, Guilan University of Medical Sciences, Rasht, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Oral Radiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8806621</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0911-6028</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dental disease diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Panoramic X-ray images</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transformer-based attention mechanisms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Web-based AI application</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">YOLOv11</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval: It was found to be in accordance with the ethical principles and the national norms and standards for conducting Medical Research in Iran (IR.GUMS.REC.1403.276).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41528683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11282-025-00886-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11282-025-00886-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, Yu X, Wang F, Xu C. Application of artificial intelligence in dental implant prognosis: a scoping review. J Dent. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdent.2024.104924 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdent.2024.104924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding H, Wu J, Zhao W, Matinlinna JP, Burrow MF, Tsoi JK. Artificial intelligence in dentistry&#x2014;a review. Frontiers in Dental Medicine. 2023;4:1085251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdmed.2023.1085251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11811754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeili M, et al. Hierarchical attention mechanism combined with deep neural networks for accurate semantic segmentation of dental structures in panoramic radiographs. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):38725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-22560-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12589480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari M, Emami H, Rabiei R, Hosseini A, Rahmatizadeh S. Detection of cardiovascular diseases using data mining approaches: application of an ensemble-based model. Cogn Comput. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12559-024-10306-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12559-024-10306-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeeda MH, Ahmedb BT. Web-based dental patient education and management application. Acta Informatica Malaysia (AIM). 2021;5(1):12&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26480/aim.01.2021.12.15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burbano R, Est&#xe9;vez E, Llerena L, Rodr&#xed;guez N. OralDentalSoft: Open-Source Web Application for Dental Office Management. In:&#xa0;World Conference on Information Systems and Technologies, 2024: Springer, pp. 97&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harini M. Telemedicine and health care accessibility: AI-powered remote diagnostics. Bull Nexus: J Multidisciplinary Int Res Stud. 2024;1(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadr H, Nazari M, Yousefzade-Chabok S, Emami H, Rabiei R, Ashraf A. Enhancing brain tumor classification in MRI images: A deep learning-based approach for accurate classification and diagnosis. Image Vis Comput. 2025;159:105555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imavis.2025.105555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad-Rahimi H, Rokhshad R, Bencharit S, Krois J, Schwendicke F. Deep learning: a primer for dentists and dental researchers. J Dent. 2023;130:104430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdent.2023.104430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Wang J, Wang S, Zhang Y. A review of deep learning in dentistry. Neurocomputing. 2023;554:126629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2023.126629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari M, Emami H, Rabiei R, Rabiee HR, Salari A, Sadr H. Enhancing cardiac function assessment: developing and validating a domain adaptive framework for automating the segmentation of echocardiogram videos. Comput Med Imaging Graph. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compmedimag.2025.102627 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compmedimag.2025.102627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari M, Sadr H, Emami H, Rabiei R. A Telemonitoring System for High-Risk Pregnancies: a Novel Approach to Enhancing Prenatal Care and Reducing Maternal and Fetal Complications. In: 2025 11th International Conference on Web Research (ICWR), 2025: IEEE, pp. 431&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haramshahi SMA, et al. Biomaterials for CNS disorders: a review of development from traditional methods to AI-assisted optimization. J Mater Sci Mater Med. 2025;36(1):85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10856-025-06947-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12521308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohades Deilami F, Sadr H, Nazari M. Using machine learning-based models for personality recognition. Big Data Comput Visions. 2021;1(3):128&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panahi O, Dadkhah S. Transforming dental care: a comprehensive review of AI technologies. J Stoma Dent Res. 2025;3(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitaras S, et al. Applications of artificial intelligence in dental medicine: a critical review. Int Dent J. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.identj.2024.11.009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.identj.2024.11.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11976566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadr H, Khodaverdian Z, Nazari M, Yamaghani MR. A shallow convolutional neural network for cerebral neoplasm detection from magnetic resonance imaging. Big Data Comput Visions. 2024;4(2):95&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravifard N, et al. Introducing a new auto edge detection technique capable of revealing cervical root resorption in CBCT scans with pronounced metallic artifacts. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):4245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54974-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10879123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasin ET, Erturk M, Tassoker M, Koklu M. Deep learning applications in dentistry: a bibliometric review analysis and mapping (2014&#x2013;2024). Iran J Comput Sci. 2025;8:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42044-024-00226-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shujaat S. Automated machine learning in dentistry: a narrative review of applications, challenges, and future directions. Diagnostics. 2025;15(3):273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics15030273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11817062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahrami M, Saleh Saber F, Hendi A. Comprehensive treatments for congenitally missing teeth and generalized diastema. Case Rep Dent. 2017;2017(1):3254873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5523549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodda S, Narne S, Chintala S, Kanungo S, Adedoja T, Sharma D. Exploring AI-driven innovations in image communication systems for enhanced medical imaging applications. J Electr Syst. 2024;20(3):949&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terven J, C&#xf3;rdova-Esparza D-M, Romero-Gonz&#xe1;lez J-A. A comprehensive review of Yolo architectures in computer vision: from YOLOv1 to YOLOv8 and YOLO-NAS. Mach Learn Knowl Extr. 2023;5(4):1680&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/make5040083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x17d;, Bizjak, Robi&#x10d; T. Advancing Dental Caries Detection in Panoramic X-rays: A Two-Step Deep Learning Approach. In:&#xa0;Informatica Medica Slovenica, 2024, vol. 29, no. 1: Slovenian Medical Informatics Association (SIMIA), pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, Liu Y, Wang L. Integrated segmentation and detection models for dentex challenge 2023, arXiv preprint arXiv:2308.14161, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razaghi M, Komleh HE, Dehghani F, Shahidi Z. Innovative Diagnosis of Dental Diseases Using YOLO V8 Deep Learning Model. In: 2024 13th Iranian/3rd International Machine Vision and Image Processing Conference (MVIP), 2024: IEEE, pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanam R, Hussain M. Yolov11: An overview of the key architectural enhancements, arXiv preprint arXiv:2410.17725, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;k DB, et al. Hybrid CNN-Transformer model for accurate impacted tooth detection in panoramic radiographs. Diagnostics. 2025;15(3):244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics15030244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11817329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohrabniya F, et al. Exploring a decade of deep learning in dentistry: a comprehensive mapping review. Clin Oral Invest. 2025;29(2):1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00784-025-06216-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamamci IE et al. Dentex: An abnormal tooth detection with dental enumeration and diagnosis benchmark for panoramic x-rays. arXiv preprint arXiv:2305.19112, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H et al. Dino: Detr with improved denoising anchor boxes for end-to-end object detection. arXiv preprint arXiv:2203.03605, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain M. Yolov1 to v8: unveiling each variant&#x2013;a comprehensive review of Yolo. IEEE Access. 2024;12:42816&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3378568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>