<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41838491</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-3231</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthroscopy : the journal of arthroscopic &amp; related surgery : official publication of the Arthroscopy Association of North America and the International Arthroscopy Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthroscopy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Editorial Commentary: Anteriorizing Tibial Tubercle Osteotomies Re-emerge Without Wound Complications of the Past, but Where Do They Fit in the Evolving State of Patellofemoral Pain Management?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>216</StartPage><EndPage>218</EndPage><MedlinePgn>216-218</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/arj.70039</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A more posteriorly located tibial tubercle relative to the trochlear groove-conceptualized as a greater sagittal tibial tubercle-trochlear groove magnitude-has been associated with patellofemoral chondral defects and is considered a potential proxy for patellofemoral contact pressures. Thus, it stands to reason that a pure anteriorizing tibial tubercle osteotomy (aTTO) could be utilized in the treatment of patellofemoral compartment pathology in patients without coronal or axial plane mal-alignment. However, pure anteriorizing osteotomies have historically been associated with an unacceptably high wound complication rate. The wound complications that have plagued this procedure appear to be avoidable with technical modifications such as utilizing laterally based incisions over a more robust tissue envelope and limiting anteriorization to 10-15mm, an amount which has previously been shown to reduce patellofemoral contract forces 30% to 60%. Several important questions remain. The authors have showed the safety of aTTO in treatment of select patellofemoral patients without coronal or axial malalignment, but how effective is it? Would the reduction of patellofemoral contact forces from an aTTO alone be enough to provide a meaningful reduction of symptoms, or would an aTTO most impactful when coupled with restorative procedures? We have not yet defined what "normal" and "abnormal" sagittal tibial tubercle-trochlear groove values are to help guide decision making. We must also develop a more thorough understanding of how tibial tubercle and trochlear morphology influence sagittal plane mechanics. The aTTO is a promising new tool with a seemingly lower complication rate than historic predecessors, though its precise role in patellofemoral pain management remains to be determined.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 the Arthroscopy Association of North America.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tansey</LastName><ForeName>Patrick J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1063-5849</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Editorial Board, MacDill Air Force Base, Tampa, Florida, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthroscopy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506498</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0749-8063</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013977" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tibia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010027" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteotomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D046788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patellofemoral Pain Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057071" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patellofemoral Joint</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41838491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/arj.70039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Collins NJ, Barton CJ, van Middelkoop M, et al. 2018 consensus statement on exercise therapy and physical interventions (orthoses, taping and manual therapy) to treat patellofemoral pain: Recommendations from the 5th international patellofemoral pain research retreat, gold coast, Australia, 2017. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:1170&#x2010;1178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson VR, Boden BP, Shen A, Jackson JN, Yao L, Sheehan FT. The tibial tubercle&#x2010;trochlear groove distance is greater in patients with patellofemoral pain: Implications for the origin of pain and clinical interventions. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45:1110&#x2010;1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langhans MT, Strickland SM, Gomoll AH. Management of chondral defects associated with patella instability. Clin Sports Med. 2022;41:137&#x2010;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansdown DA, Christian D, Madden B, et al. The sagittal tibial tubercle&#x2010;trochlear groove distance as a measurement of sagittal imbalance in patients with symptomatic patellofemoral chondral lesions. Cartilage. 2021;13(suppl 1):449S&#x2010;455S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan DJ, Mojica ES, Ortega PF, et al. Posterior tibial tubercle measured by the sagittal TT&#x2010;TG distance correlates with increased risk for patellofemoral chondral lesions. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2022;30:3733&#x2010;3741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namiri NK, C&#xe0;liva F, Martinez AM, Pedoia V, Lansdown DA. A more posterior tibial tubercle (decreased sagittal tibial tubercle&#x2010;trochlear groove distance) is significantly associated with patellofemoral joint degenerative cartilage change: A deep learning analysis. Arthroscopy. 2023;39:1493&#x2010;1501.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka MJ, D&#x2019;Amore T, Elias JJ, Thawait G, Demehri S, Cosgarea AJ. Anteroposterior distance between the tibial tuberosity and trochlear groove in patients with patellar instability. Knee. 2019;26:1278&#x2010;1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka MJ. Editorial commentary: Sagittal tibial tuberosity to trochlear groove distance measurements may reflect patellofemoral contact pressures. Arthroscopy. 2025;41:1009&#x2010;1010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson AB Jr, Brown TD, Fu FH, Rutkowski R. Relief of patellofemoral contact stress by anterior displacement of the tibial tubercle. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1979;61:159&#x2010;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbari S, Raugstad TS, Lichtenberg N, Refvem D. The Hauser operation for patellar dislocation. 3&#x2010;32&#x2010;year results in 63 knees. Acta Orthop Scand. 1990;61:32&#x2010;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varady NH, Khorana A, Williams RJ. Low complication rate following contemporary pure anteriorization tibial tubercle osteotomy for patellofemoral chondral wear in patients aged less than 50&#x2009;years. Arthroscopy. 2026;42:209&#x2010;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadambande SS, Auyeung J, Ghandour A, Mintowt&#x2010;Czyz W. A review of wound healing following Maquet osteotomy. Knee. 2004;11:463&#x2010;467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rue JP, Colton A, Zare SM, et al. Trochlear contact pressures after straight anteriorization of the tibial tuberosity. Am J Sports Med. 2008;36:1953&#x2010;1959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahla J, Hinckel BB, Yanke AB, et al. An expert consensus statement on the management of large chondral and osteochondral defects in the patellofemoral joint. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8:2325967120907343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackermann J, Bergheim N, Hartmann M, Vlachopoulos L, Fucentese SF. Trochlear dysplasia is associated with increased sagittal tibial tubercle trochlear&#x2010;groove distance in patients with patellar instability. Arthroscopy. 2025;41:1002&#x2010;1008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leclerc JT, Dartus J, Labreuche J, et al. Complications and outcomes of trochleoplasty for patellofemoral instability: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of 1000 trochleoplasties. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2021;107:103035.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>