<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41692787</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of exercise on cognitive performance and ERP (P3, N2) in overweight and obese populations: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">151</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01593-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Individuals with overweight/obesity often show cognitive-control deficits, reflected in slower reaction times, lower accuracy, attenuated P3, and altered N2. We meta-analysed randomized controlled and within-subject crossover studies comparing exercise versus non-exercise controls during standard cognitive-control tasks. Primary outcomes were reaction time (RT), reaction accuracy (RA), P3 amplitude, and N2 amplitude; risk of bias was assessed with Cochrane RoB 2, and ERP reporting was evaluated with a checklist aligned to RoB-2 D4/D5.Across 14 studies, exercise was associated with faster RT and larger P3 amplitude. RA and N2 showed directionally favorable but lower-certainty effects, reflecting substantial heterogeneity, small samples, and limitations in ERP quality reporting (e.g., sparse SNR/QC metrics; infrequent assessor blinding). Exploratory subgroup/meta-regression analyses offered limited explanatory power overall but suggested potential contributions of task paradigm, exercise mode, and design/comparator features-effects appeared larger in Stroop/Flanker than Go/No-Go and tended to be more pronounced for higher-arousal modes and under baseline/assessment-only controls and in designs incorporating baseline assessments-though these patterns should be interpreted cautiously given residual heterogeneity, sparse strata, and multiple comparisons.Exercise thus confers measurable behavioral and electrophysiological gains in individuals with elevated BMI, consistent with cerebral blood-flow/neuroplasticity and catecholaminergic arousal mechanisms. Improved prespecification/multiplicity control and transparent ERP reporting are needed to strengthen future evidence and clarify dose-response and timing effects.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Chengcheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Educational Sciences and Technology, Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, Johor, 81310, Malaysia. zhuchengcheng@graduate.utm.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Halijah Binti</ForeName><Initials>HB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Educational Sciences and Technology, Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, Johor, 81310, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chi</LastName><ForeName>Puyan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Maritime University, Shanghai, 200240, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yilin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Physical Education University, Xi'an, 710068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Xiangyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Siyuan University, Xi'an, 710038, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sports, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi'an, 710100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chi</LastName><ForeName>Aiping</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sports, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi'an, 710100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>BLA230107</GrantID><Agency>National Education Science Planning Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ERP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">N2 amplitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Overweight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">P3 amplitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reaction accuracy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reaction time</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41692787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13011643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01593-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01593-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Apo E, Mondrag&#xf3;n&#x2010;Maya A, Ferrari-D&#xed;az M, Silva&#x2010;Pereyra J. Structural brain changes associated with overweight and obesity. J Obes. 2021;2021:6613385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8302366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Obesity and overweight: key facts. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favieri F, Forte G, Casagrande M. The executive functions in overweight and obesity: A systematic review of neuropsychological cross-sectional and longitudinal studies. Front Psychol. 2019;10:2126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6764464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31616340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a, Jurado M, Garolera M, et al. Functional network centrality in obesity: A resting-state and task Fmri study. Psychiatry Res. 2015;233:331&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26145769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prickett C, Brennan L, Stolwyk R. Examining the relationship between obesity and cognitive function: A systematic literature review. Obes Res Clin Pract. 2015;9:93&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25890426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein JR, Van Petten C. Influence of cognitive control and mismatch on the n2 component of the erp: A review. Psychophysiology. 2008;45:152&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2365910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17850238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polich J. Updating p300: an integrative theory of p3a and p3b. Clin Neurophysiology: Official J Int Federation Clin Neurophysiol. 2007;118:2128&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2715154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17573239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly HC, Fau - Castelli D, Castelli D, Fau - Etnier JL et al. Physical activity, fitness, cognitive function, and academic achievement in children: a systematic review. 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4874515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27182986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamijo K, Pontifex MB, Khan NA et al. The negative association of childhood obesity to cognitive control of action monitoring. Cerebral cortex (New York, NY: 1991). 2014;24:654&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3920765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23146965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, De Meirleir K. Exercise and brain neurotransmission. Sports Med (Auckland NZ). 1995;20:160&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8571000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bherer L, Erickson KI, Liu-Ambrose T. A review of the effects of physical activity and exercise on cognitive and brain functions in older adults. J Aging Res. 2013;2013:657508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3786463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24102028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Hillman C, Stillman CM, et al. Physical activity, cognition, and brain outcomes: A review of the 2018 physical activity guidelines. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:1242&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31095081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Min L, Liu R, et al. The effect of exercise on cerebral blood flow and executive function among young adults: A double-blinded randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2023;13:8269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10203129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37217511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Labban JD, Gapin JI, Etnier JL. The effects of acute exercise on cognitive performance: A meta-analysis. Brain Res. 2012;1453:87&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22480735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreau D, Chou E. The acute effect of high-intensity exercise on executive function: A meta-analysis. Perspect Psychol Science: J Association Psychol Sci. 2019;14:734&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31365839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Y, Yang Y, Huang T. Effects of chronic exercise interventions on executive function among children and adolescents: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1397&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30737201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosang L, Mouchlianitis E, Gu&#xe9;rin SMR, Karageorghis CI. Effects of exercise on electroencephalography-recorded neural oscillations: A systematic review. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2024;17:926&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao, Chen F, Moreau D, et al. Acute effects of exercise engagement on neurocognitive function: A systematic review and meta-analysis on p3 amplitude and latency. Int Rev Sport Exerc Psychol. 2025;18:111&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao, Cadenas-Sanchez C, Shigeta TT, et al. A systematic review of physical activity and cardiorespiratory fitness on p3b. Psychophysiology. 2020;57:e13425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31228362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludyga S, Gerber M, Brand S, Holsboer-Trachsler E, P&#xfc;hse U. Acute effects of moderate aerobic exercise on specific aspects of executive function in different age and fitness groups: A meta-analysis. Psychophysiology. 2016;53:1611&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27556572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijer A, K&#xf6;nigs M, Vermeulen GT, et al. The effects of physical activity on brain structure and neurophysiological functioning in children: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Dev Cogn Neurosci. 2020;45:100828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7451819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32805531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boa Sorte Silva NC, Barha CK, Erickson KI, Kramer AF, Liu-Ambrose T. Physical exercise, cognition, and brain health in aging. Trends Neurosci. 2024;47:402&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38811309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keil A, Debener S, Gratton G, et al. Committee report: publication guidelines and recommendations for studies using electroencephalography and magnetoencephalography. Psychophysiology. 2014;51:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24147581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luck SJ, Gaspelin N. How to get statistically significant effects in any erp experiment (and why you shouldn&#x2019;t). Psychophysiology. 2017;54:146&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5178877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28000253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernet, Garrido MI, Gramfort A, et al. Issues and recommendations from the Ohbm Cobidas Meeg committee for reproducible Eeg and Meg research. Nat Neurosci. 2020;23:1473&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32958924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, et al. Rob 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2019;366:l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T. Developing the catecholamines hypothesis for the acute exercise-cognition interaction in humans: lessons from animal studies. Physiol Behav. 2016;165:291&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27526999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The Prisma 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2021;372:n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas et al. august. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions (version 6.5, 2024). Cochrane. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO, Obesity. Preventing and managing the global epidemic : report of a who consulation. World Health Organ eBooks. 2000;894:1&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11234459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WGOC A. Body mass index reference for Chinese adults. Biomed Environ Sci. 2004;17:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MoHW T. Guidelines for overweight and obesity in adults (chinese/taiwan bmi criteria). 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onis M, Onyango AW, Borghi E, Siyam A, Nishida C, Siekmann J. Development of a who growth reference for school-aged children and adolescents. Bull World Health Organ. 2007;85:660&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2636412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18026621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuczmarski RJ, Ogden CL, Guo SS et al. 2000 CDC growth charts for the united states: methods and development. Vital Health Stat 11. Data from the National Health Survey. 2002:1-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12043359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole TJ, Lobstein T. Extended international (iotf) body mass index cut-offs for thinness, overweight and obesity. Pediatr Obes. 2012;7:284&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22715120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozemek C, Bonikowske et al. Acsm&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pontifex M, McGowan A, Chandler M, et al. A primer on investigating the after effects of acute bouts of physical activity on cognition. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2019;40:1&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbourne DR, Altman DG, Higgins JP, Curtin F, Worthington HV, Vail A. Meta-analyses involving cross-over trials: methodological issues. Int J Epidemiol. 2002;31:140&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11914310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan X, Wang W, Liu J, Tong T. Estimating the sample mean and standard deviation from the sample size, median, range and/or interquartile range. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25524443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo D, Wan X, Liu J, Tong T. Optimally estimating the sample mean from the sample size, median, mid-range, and/or mid-quartile range. Stat Methods Med Res. 2018;27:1785&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27683581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luck. An introduction to the event-related potential technique. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett J, Chak C, Bullock T, Giesbrecht B. A systematic review and bayesian meta-analysis provide evidence for an effect of acute physical activity on cognition in young adults. Commun Psychol. 2024;2:82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11358546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39242965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambourne K, Tomporowski P. The effect of exercise-induced arousal on cognitive task performance: A meta-regression analysis. Brain Res. 2010;1341:12&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV. Distribution theory for glass&#x2019;s estimator of effect size and related estimators. J Educational Stat. 1981;6:107&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB, DeShon RPJP. Combining effect size estimates in meta-analysis with repeated measures and independent-groups designs. Psychol methods. 2002;7:105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11928886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>StataCorp. Stata statistical software: Release 11. 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2003;327:557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson SG, Higgins JP. How should meta-regression analyses be undertaken and interpreted? Stat Med. 2002;21:1559&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IntHout J, Ioannidis JP, Rovers MM, Goeman JJ. Plea for routinely presenting prediction intervals in meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2016;6:e010247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4947751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27406637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges L, Higgins J, Rothstein H, Den A. Introduction to meta-analysis. Int Coaching Psychol Rev. 2021;15:121&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 1997;315:629&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: A simple funnel-plot&#x2013;based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56:455&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balshem H, Helfand M, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, et al. Grade guidelines: 3. Rating the quality of evidence. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64:401&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21208779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, et al. Grade guidelines: 1. Introduction-grade evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64:383&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey BW, Muir AM, Bartholomew CL et al. The impact of exercise intensity on neurophysiological indices of food-related inhibitory control and cognitive control: a randomized crossover event-related potential (erp) study. NeuroImage. 2021;237:118162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbine KA, LeCheminant JD, Kelley TA, et al. The impact of exercise on food-related inhibitory control&#x2014; do calories, time of day, and Bmi matter? Evidence from an event-related potential (erp) study. Appetite. 2024;200:107514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38838592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanlon N. The effect of an acute bout of exercise on food motivation, energy intake, and total physical activity in normal-weight and obese woman: an event-related potential study. ScholarsArchive. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang J, Lloyd K, Ligeza T, et al. Interrupting sitting with moderate-intensity physical activity breaks improves inhibitory control in adults with overweight and obesity: findings from the sitless pilot randomized crossover trial. Ment Health Phys Act. 2025;28:100671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39880212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan N, Raine L, Drollette E, et al. The differential relationship of an afterschool physical activity intervention on brain function and cognition in children with obesity and their normal weight peers. Pediatr Obes. 2021;16:e12708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33249759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Y, Dong X, Sun T, et al. Acute effects of different physical activity on executive function and regulation role of beta Oscillation in sedentary youth frontal region. Sci Rep. 2024;14:30939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11681212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39730640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Ren J. Effects of different modalities of acute exercise on inhibitory function in overweight individuals a behavioral and event-related potential-based study. Chin J Sports Med. 2024;43:537&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Cai S, Huang T, et al. Unveiling the neural mechanisms of acute aerobic exercise on inhibitory control among young adults with obesity: insights from an erp study. Acta Psychol. 2024;250:104506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39353340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie C, Alderman BL, Meng F, Ai J, Chang YK, Li A. Acute high-intensity interval exercise improves inhibitory control among young adult males with obesity. Front Psychol. 2020;11:1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7330122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32670154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie C, Alderman BL, Meng F, Chen YC, Chang YK, Wang K. Acute high-intensity interval exercise improves food-related cognition in young adults with obesity: an erp study. Int J Clin Health Psychology: IJCHP. 2024;24:100430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10753058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38155877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie C, Huang T, Wang Y et al. The impact of acute aerobic exercise on general and food-related inhibitory function among young adults with obesity: an event-related potential (erp) study. Brain Sci. 2025;15:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11763633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39851427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai CL, Pan CY, Chen FC, Huang TH, Tsai MC, Chuang CY. Differences in neurocognitive performance and metabolic and inflammatory indices in male adults with obesity as a function of regular exercise. Exp Physiol. 2019;104:1650&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31609518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen HJ, Liu SH, Tsai CL. Effects of 12 weeks of aerobic exercise combined with resistance training on neurocognitive performance in obese women. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2022;20:291&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35892114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen HJ, Tsai CL. Effects of acute aerobic exercise combined with resistance exercise on neurocognitive performance in obese women. Brain Sci. 2020;10:767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33105799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara T, Drollette ES, Ludyga S, Hillman CH, Kamijo K. The effects of acute aerobic exercise on executive function: A systematic review and meta-analysis of individual participant data. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2021;128:258&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34147558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AS, Saliasi E, van den Berg V, et al. Effects of physical activity interventions on cognitive and academic performance in children and adolescents: A novel combination of a systematic review and recommendations from an expert panel. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:640&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30061304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F-T, Etnier JL, Chan K-H, Chiu P-K, Hung T-M, Chang Y-K. Effects of exercise training interventions on executive function in older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2020;50:1451&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7376513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32447717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillman CM, Esteban-Cornejo I, Brown B, Bender CM, Erickson KI. Effects of exercise on brain and cognition across age groups and health States. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43:533&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Jia J, Yang Y, Zhang L, Wang X. Effects of exercise interventions on cognitive functions in healthy populations: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev. 2023;92:102116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37924980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Keye SA, Pascual-Abreu M, Khan NA. Effects of an acute bout of cycling on different domains of cognitive function. Prog Brain Res. 2024;283:21&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38538189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gusatovic J, Gramkow MH, Hasselbalch SG, Frederiksen KS. Effects of aerobic exercise on event-related potentials related to cognitive performance: A systematic review. PeerJ. 2022;10:e13604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9281596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35846877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z, Shi L, Wu W, Meng L, Ru Y, Wu M. A scoping review of effects of acute exercise on executive function: evidence from event-related potentials. Front Psychol. 2025;16:1599861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12079670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40376491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudo M, Costello JT, McMorris T, Ando S. The effects of acute high-intensity aerobic exercise on cognitive performance: A structured narrative review. Front Behav Neurosci. 2022;16:957677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9538359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36212191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Li Y, Cai L, Wang Y. Effects of physical activity interventions on cognitive performance of overweight or obese children and adolescents: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pediatr Res. 2021;89:46&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32388536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwenhuis S, Aston-Jones G, Cohen JD. Decision making, the p3, and the locus coeruleus-norepinephrine system. Psychol Bull. 2005;131:510&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16060800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aston-Jones G, Cohen JD. An integrative theory of locus coeruleus-norepinephrine function: adaptive gain and optimal performance. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2005;28:403&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16022602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botvinick MM, Cohen JD, Carter CS. Conflict monitoring and anterior cingulate cortex: an update. Trends Cogn Sci. 2004;8:539&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15556023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Hale BJ. Differential effects of differing intensities of acute exercise on speed and accuracy of cognition: A meta-analytical investigation. Brain Cogn. 2012;80:338&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillman CM, Cohen J, Lehman ME, Erickson KI. Mediators of physical activity on neurocognitive function: A review at multiple levels of analysis. Front Hum Neurosci. 2016;10:626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5161022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28018195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinoff A, Herrmann N, Swardfager W, et al. The effect of exercise training on resting concentrations of peripheral brain-derived neurotrophic factor (bdnf): A meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2016;11:e0163037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5033477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27658238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang RF-F, Li R-H, Ai J-Y, Kao S-C, Etnier JL. Effects of acute exercise on cognitive function: A meta-review of 30 systematic reviews with meta-analyses. Psychol Bull. 2025;151:240&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39883421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris S. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organizational Res Methods. 2008;11:364&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers A, Altman A. Analysing controlled trials with baseline and follow up measurements. BMJ. 2001;323:1123&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1121605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11701584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn S. Cross-over trials in clinical research. Technometrics. 2002;36:233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Shields GS, Guo C, Liu Y. Executive function performance in obesity and overweight individuals: A meta-analysis and review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2018;84:225&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29203421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barha CK, Davis JC, Falck RS, Nagamatsu LS, Liu-Ambrose T. Sex differences in exercise efficacy to improve cognition: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials in older humans. Front Neuroendocr. 2017;46:71&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28442274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boot, Blakely DP, Simons DJ. Do action video games improve perception and cognition? Front Psychol. 2011;2:226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3171788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21949513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boot, Simons DJ, Stothart C, Stutts C. The pervasive problem with placebos in psychology: why active control groups are not sufficient to rule out placebo effects. Perspect Psychol Sci. 2013;8:445&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26173122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, G&#xf8;tzsche PC. Placebo interventions for all clinical conditions. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2004;2:CD003974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15266510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T. Exercise-cognition interaction: Neuroscience perspectives. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridderinkhof KR, Ullsperger M, Crone EA, Nieuwenhuis S. The role of the medial frontal cortex in cognitive control. Sci (New York NY). 2004;306:443&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15486290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLeod CM. Half a century of research on the Stroop effect: an integrative review. Psychol Bull. 1991;109:163&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2034749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayson PE, Brush CJ, Hajcak G. Data quality and reliability metrics for event-related potentials (erps): the utility of subject-level reliability. Int J Psychophysiol. 2021;165:121&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernet AS, Gorgolewski KJ, et al. Eeg-bids, an extension to the brain imaging data structure for electroencephalography. Sci Data. 2019;6:103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6592877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maris E, Oostenveld R. Nonparametric statistical testing of eeg- and meg-data. J Neurosci Methods. 2007;164:177&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17517438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye M, Song T, Xia H, Hou Y, Chen A. Effects of aerobic exercise on executive function of healthy middle-aged and older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Stud. 2024;160:104912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39326271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino F, Puhl RM, Cummings DE, et al. Joint international consensus statement for ending stigma of obesity. Nat Med. 2020;26:485&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7154011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32127716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for H, Care E. Obesity: Identification, assessment and management (ng246). 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36719951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USPSTF. Behavioral counseling interventions to promote a healthy diet and physical activity for cardiovascular disease prevention in adults with cardiovascular risk factors: Us preventive services task force recommendation statement. JAMA. 2020;324:2069&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33231670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, et al. World health organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54:1451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7719906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhl RM, Heuer CA. The stigma of obesity: A review and update. Obes (Silver Spring Md). 2009;17:941&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19165161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>