<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600405</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>End-Edge-Cloud Collaborative Monitoring System with an Intelligent Multi-Parameter Sensor for Impact Anomaly Detection in GIL Pipelines.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">606</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020606</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Gas-insulated transmission lines (GILs) are increasingly deployed in dense urban power networks, where complex construction activities may introduce external mechanical impacts and pose risks to pipeline structural integrity. However, existing GIL monitoring approaches mainly emphasize electrical and gas-state parameters, while lightweight solutions capable of rapidly detecting and localizing impact-induced structural anomalies remain limited. To address this gap, this paper proposes an intelligent end-edge-cloud monitoring system for impact anomaly detection in GIL pipelines. Numerical simulations are first conducted to analyze the dynamic response characteristics of the pipeline under impacts of varying magnitudes, orientations, and locations, revealing the relationship between impact scenarios and vibration mode evolution. An end-tier multi-parameter intelligent sensor is then developed, integrating triaxial acceleration and angular velocity measurement with embedded lightweight computing. Laboratory impact experiments are performed to acquire sensor data, which are used to train and validate a multi-class extreme gradient boosting (XGBoost) model deployed at the edge tier for accurate impact-location identification. Results show that, even with a single sensor positioned at the pipeline midpoint, fusing acceleration and angular velocity features enables reliable discrimination of impact regions. Finally, a lightweight cloud platform is implemented for visualizing structural responses and environmental parameters with downsampled edge-side data. The proposed system achieves rapid sensor-level anomaly detection, precise edge-level localization, and unified cloud-level monitoring, offering a low-cost and easily deployable solution for GIL structural health assessment.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-2823-1296</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geotechnical Engineering, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geotechnical and Underground Engineering of Ministry of Education, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Kun</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4116-6176</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geotechnical Engineering, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geotechnical and Underground Engineering of Ministry of Education, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yaojun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Shanghai Municipal Electric Power Company, Shanghai 200072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Xiongyao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5357-4003</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geotechnical Engineering, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geotechnical and Underground Engineering of Ministry of Education, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Genji</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geotechnical Engineering, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geotechnical and Underground Engineering of Ministry of Education, School of Civil Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>5200-202417104A-1-1-ZN</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project of State Grid Company Headquarters</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">end-edge-cloud monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extreme gradient boosting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gas-insulated transmission line</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impact-location identification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intelligent multi-parameter sensor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structural health monitoring</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Yaojun Zhou was employed by State Grid Shanghai Municipal Electric Power Company, Shanghai, China. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12845587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hillers T., Koch H. Gas insulated transmission lines for high power transmission over long distances; Proceedings of the EMPD&#x2019;98, 1998 International Conference on Energy Management and Power Delivery (Cat. No. 98EX137); Singapore. 3&#x2013;5 March 1998; pp. 613&#x2013;618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Wang C., Zhao Y., Zhu H., Shi W., Li H., Luo M., Zhu D., Du J. Investigation into In Situ Computed Tomography Inspection Technology for Conductor Connection Structure of Ultra-High Voltage Gas-Insulated Transmission Lines. Russ. J. Nondestruct. Test. 2025;61:353&#x2013;365. doi: 10.1134/S1061830925600133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S1061830925600133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G., Tu Y., Wang C., Cheng Y., Jiang H., Zhou H., Jin H. Analysis on temperature distribution and current-carrying capacity of GIL filled with fluoronitriles-CO2 gas mixture. J. Electr. Eng. Technol. 2018;13:2402&#x2013;2411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Tang S., Liu Q., Wang H., Li X., Chen P., Liu H. Key technology for the construction and inspection of long-distance underwater tunnel for 1000 kV gas-insulated transmission line. Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ. 2023;82:7. doi: 10.1007/s10064-022-02991-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-022-02991-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu T., Ma H., Duan D., Ge W. Novel GIL mechanical fault diagnosis method based on multi-sensor data feature fusion and TDEAVOA-ELM. Comput. Electr. Eng. 2024;119:109573. doi: 10.1016/j.compeleceng.2024.109573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2024.109573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch H., Imamovic D. Applications of underground transmission lines for high power AC transmission; Proceedings of the 2015 International Conference on Condition Assessment Techniques in Electrical Systems (CATCON); Bangalore, India. 10&#x2013;12 December 2015; pp. 139&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C., Yang H., Chen M., Tian Z., Gao C., Zhou F. Optimization of vibration reduction in damping materials for GIL equipment subjected to subway-induced vibrations.  [(accessed on 12 January 2026)];South. Power Syst. Technol. 2025 :1&#x2013;9. Available online:  https://link.cnki.net/urlid/44.1643.TK.20250811.1450.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan W., Shafiq M., Hussain G.A., Choudhary M., Palu I. Investigating the progression of insulation degradation in power cable based on partial discharge measurements. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 2023;221:109452. doi: 10.1016/j.epsr.2023.109452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2023.109452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan J.Q., Raymond W.J.K., Illias H.A., Othman M. Partial Discharge Localization Techniques: A Review of Recent Progress. Energies. 2023;16:2863. doi: 10.3390/en16062863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en16062863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J., Wang K., Zhang C., Chen M., Zheng H., Albarrac&#xed;n R. Improving the Error of Time Differences of Arrival on Partial Discharges Measurement in Gas-Insulated Switchgear. Sensors. 2018;18:4078. doi: 10.3390/s18114078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s18114078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6263400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30469445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodaveisi F., Karami H., Karimpour M.Z., Rubinstein M., Rachidi F. Partial discharge localization in power transformer tanks using machine learning methods. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:11785. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-62527-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-62527-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11116502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38782982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan U., Lazaridis P., Mohamed H., Albarrac&#xed;n R., Zaharis Z., Atkinson R., Tachtatzis C., Glover I. An Efficient Algorithm for Partial Discharge Localization in High-Voltage Systems Using Received Signal Strength. Sensors. 2018;18:4000. doi: 10.3390/s18114000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s18114000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6263643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30453570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia C., Zhao W., Zhu Y., Lu W., Tang Z. A Numerical Study on the Decomposition and Diffusion Characteristics of SF6 in Gas-Insulated Switchgear with Consideration of the Temperature Rising Effect. Energies. 2022;15:7834. doi: 10.3390/en15217834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15217834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Zheng Y., Zhang P., Han X., Zhou W. Effect of Temperature on Insulation Properties of SF6/N2 Mixed Gas Under AC Voltage. IEEE Trans. Plasma Sci. 2020;48:914&#x2013;920. doi: 10.1109/TPS.2020.2979805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPS.2020.2979805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang M., Son J., Lee B., Nam H. Reconstruction of the Chemical Gas Concentration Distribution Using Partial Convolution-Based Image Inpainting. Sensors. 2024;24:4470. doi: 10.3390/s24144470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24144470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11280514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39065868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doukas D.I., Papadopoulos T.A., Chrysochos A.I., Labridis D.P., Papagiannis G.K. Multiphysics Modeling for Transient Analysis of Gas-Insulated Lines. IEEE Trans. Power Deliv. 2018;33:2786&#x2013;2793. doi: 10.1109/TPWRD.2018.2820022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2018.2820022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Yao Y., Zhao R., Zhang Z., Jing R. SF6 Research on the Key Technology of the Gas Integrated Online Monitoring System in the Fault Early Warning and Diagnosis of GIS Equipment; Proceedings of the 2024 Boao New Power System International Forum-Power System and New Energy Technology Innovation Forum (NPSIF); Qionghai, China. 8&#x2013;10 December 2024; pp. 163&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Zhen G., Liu Y., Song H., Liang Y., Liu X., Meng S., Liu Y., Li S. Effect of temperature on partial discharges activity and electrical trees propagation in XLPE. IET Sci. Meas. Technol. 2024;18:300&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1049/smt2.12199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/smt2.12199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiqing M., Kexin W., Xinyu W., Xing H. Deep learning empowering gas monitoring in GIL pipeline corridor: Super-resolution reconstruction of gas leakage distribution data and optimization of sensor placement. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 2025;248:111956. doi: 10.1016/j.epsr.2025.111956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2025.111956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toh G., Park J. Review of Vibration-Based Structural Health Monitoring Using Deep Learning. Appl. Sci. 2020;10:1680. doi: 10.3390/app10051680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10051680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Zhou J., Wang Z., Li B., Ma Y. Gas Insulated Metal Enclosed Transmission Line (GIL) Seismic Response Analysis. J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 2024;2731:12021. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/2731/1/012021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/2731/1/012021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Xie Q., Wen J. Seismic Performance Evaluation and Retrofit Strategy of Overhead Gas-Insulated Transmission Lines. Buildings. 2023;13:2968. doi: 10.3390/buildings13122968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13122968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Chen J., Wei X., Zhang B., Liu Y., Wang X., Chen Q., Zhang M., Zhou T. Research and application of long-distance high-drop GIL multiparameter integrated monitoring. Infrared Laser Eng. 2024;53:176&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Ma H., Dai F. Research on GIL Mechanical Fault Diagnosis and Early Warning Technology. Electr. Mach. Control Appl. 2021;48:106&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L., Zang C., Hu X., Liu Y., Gong Y., Liu C. Research on the diagnosis of GIL mechanical fault by low frequency vibration signal. J. Electr. Power Sci. Technol. 2019;34:86&#x2013;91+100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu A., Zang C., Li Y., Hu H., Xu H., Xu S., Guo H. Research on GIL Mechanical Fault Detection System Based on Combined Vibration and Acoustic Location Technology. High Volt. Appar. 2025;61:52&#x2013;58, 67. doi: 10.13296/j.1001-1609.hva.2025.06.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13296/j.1001-1609.hva.2025.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stajanca P., Chruscicki S., Homann T., Seifert S., Schmidt D., Habib A. Detection of Leak-Induced Pipeline Vibrations Using Fiber-Optic Distributed Acoustic Sensing. Sensors. 2018;18:2841. doi: 10.3390/s18092841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s18092841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6164018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30154358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussels M., Chruscicki S., Arndt D., Scheider S., Prager J., Homann T., Habib A.K. Localization of Transient Events Threatening Pipeline Integrity by Fiber-Optic Distributed Acoustic Sensing. Sensors. 2019;19:3322. doi: 10.3390/s19153322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s19153322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6696037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31362352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Xu S., Zhang Y., Tu Y., Peng M. A Method for the Pattern Recognition of Acoustic Emission Signals Using Blind Source Separation and a CNN for Online Corrosion Monitoring in Pipelines with Interference from Flow-Induced Noise. Sensors. 2024;24:5991. doi: 10.3390/s24185991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24185991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11435983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39338735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J., Du J. Investigation into acoustic emission-based methodology for precise localization of pipeline leakage sources. Measurement. 2025;250:117194. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2025.117194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.117194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T., Guestrin C. XGBoost: A Scalable Tree Boosting System; Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD&#x2019;16), Association for Computing Machinery; New York, NY, USA. 13&#x2013;17 August 2016; pp. 785&#x2013;794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z., Zhou M., Lin Z., Chen X., Huang Y. Improved Genetic Algorithm and XGBoost Classifier for Power Transformer Fault Diagnosis. Front. Energy Res. 2021;9:745744. doi: 10.3389/fenrg.2021.745744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2021.745744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z., Wang X., Jiang B. Fault Diagnosis for Wind Turbines Based on ReliefF and eXtreme Gradient Boosting. Appl. Sci. 2020;10:3258. doi: 10.3390/app10093258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10093258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szmigiel A., Apel D.B., Pourrahimian Y., Dehghanpour H., Pu Y. Exploring machine learning techniques for open stope stability prediction: A comparative study and feature importance analysis. Rock Mech. Bull. 2025;4:100146. doi: 10.1016/j.rockmb.2024.100146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rockmb.2024.100146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fissha Y., Ragam P., Ikeda H., Kushal Kumar N., Adachi T., Paul P.S., Kawamura Y. Data-driven machine learning approaches for simultaneous prediction of peak particle velocity and frequency induced by rock blasting in mining. Rock Mech. Bull. 2025;4:100166. doi: 10.1016/j.rockmb.2024.100166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rockmb.2024.100166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhams A., Abdelhadi A., Badri Y., Sassi S., Renno J. Enhanced Bearing Fault Diagnosis Through Trees Ensemble Method and Feature Importance Analysis. J. Vib. Eng. Technol. 2024;12:109&#x2013;125. doi: 10.1007/s42417-024-01405-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42417-024-01405-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan C., Li C., Peng Y., Shen Y., Cao G., Li S. Fault Diagnosis of Vibration Sensors Based on Triage Loss Function-Improved XGBoost. Electronics. 2023;12:4442. doi: 10.3390/electronics12214442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics12214442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T., Li Q., Yang J., Xie T., Wu P., Liang J. Transformer Fault Diagnosis Method Based on Incomplete Data and TPE-XGBoost. Appl. Sci. 2023;13:7539. doi: 10.3390/app13137539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13137539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali W., El-Thalji I., Giljarhus K.E.T., Delimitis A. Classification Analytics for Wind Turbine Blade Faults: Integrated Signal Analysis and Machine Learning Approach. Energies. 2024;17:5856. doi: 10.3390/en17235856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17235856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>