<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41535810</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-244X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of smartphone-based behavioral activation, assertiveness training, and problem-solving therapy for parenting stress in parents raising autistic children: a multicenter, randomized, open-label, parallel-group trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>138</StartPage><MedlinePgn>138</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">138</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12888-025-07746-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Parents of autistic children often experience high levels of stress and depressive symptoms. Although cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) is effective in alleviating depression and reducing stress, its delivery requires trained personnel and considerable time, limiting accessibility. Smartphone applications may provide a feasible alternative. This study evaluated the efficacy of smartphone-delivered behavioral activation, assertiveness training, and problem-solving therapy in improving depressive symptoms and reducing stress among parents of autistic children.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This was an individually randomized, parallel-group, multicenter trial. Eligible participants were parents aged 24 to &lt;&#x2009;60 years caring for biological children aged 6 to &lt;&#x2009;16 years diagnosed with autism by child psychiatrists. Participants were randomly assigned (1:1) to a smartphone-based intervention or a control group that received psychoeducation only. Both groups continued treatment as usual. The intervention consisted of an 8-week smartphone application program delivering behavioral activation, assertiveness training, and problem-solving therapy. The primary endpoint was the Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) score at Week 8. Secondary outcomes included Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7) scores at Weeks 4 and 8, Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Skills Scale scores, presenteeism assessed with the Health and Work Performance Questionnaire (HPQ) at Week 8, and app usage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 63 parents were randomized to the intervention group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;31) or control group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;32). Changes in PHQ-9 scores from baseline to Week 8 did not differ significantly between groups. No significant between-group differences were observed for GAD-7, CBT Skills, or HPQ presenteeism at Week 8.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The smartphone-based intervention did not demonstrate additional benefits over psychoeducation alone in reducing depressive symptoms. Although symptoms improved in both groups, no significant between-group differences were observed, and the findings should be interpreted cautiously given the limited statistical power.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">This study was retrospectively registered in UMINCTR (ID UMIN000052319) on October 1, 2023.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamada</LastName><ForeName>Atsurou</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurodevelopmental Disorders, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan. atsurou@med.nagoya-cu.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Neurodevelopmental Disorders, Nagoya City University Hospital, Nagoya, Japan. atsurou@med.nagoya-cu.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakanishi</LastName><ForeName>Daisuke</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mie Prefectural Medical Center for Child Growth, Development and Disability, Mie, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nogimura</LastName><ForeName>Akane</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurodevelopmental Disorders, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Neurodevelopmental Disorders, Nagoya City University Hospital, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Promotion and Human Behavior, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine/School of Public Health, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katsuki</LastName><ForeName>Fujika</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing, Nagoya City University School of Nursing, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ito</LastName><ForeName>Yoshinori</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Psychology Department, Nagoya City University Hospital, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imai</LastName><ForeName>Fuminobu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Toyota Kokoro Clinic, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Cognitive-Behavioral Medicine, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences Department of Psychiatry, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanabe</LastName><ForeName>Norio</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Soseikai General Hospital, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakata</LastName><ForeName>Msatsugu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurodevelopmental Disorders, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Neurodevelopmental Disorders, Nagoya City University Hospital, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akechi</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Cognitive-Behavioral Medicine, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences Department of Psychiatry, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horikoshi</LastName><ForeName>Masaru</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Furukawa</LastName><ForeName>Toshi A</ForeName><Initials>TA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Office of Institutional Advancement and Communications, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>18K03104</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968559</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-244X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Assertiveness training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autism spectrum disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Behavioral activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Problem-solving therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Raising</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smartphone</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Ethics Review Committee of Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medicine, Japan (46-18-0016), and the Ethics Committees of the participating clinics and hospitals. This study was conducted in accordance with the principles stated in the Helsinki Declaration. Written and oral informed consent were obtained from each participant prior to this study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41535810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12888233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-025-07746-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12888-025-07746-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maenner MJ, Warren Z, Williams AR, Amoakohene E, Bakian AV, Bilder DA, et al. Prevalence and characteristics of autism spectrum disorder among children aged 8 years &#x2013; autism and developmental disabilities monitoring network, 11 sites, united States, 2020. MMWR Surveill Summ. 2023;72(2):1&#x2013;14. 10.15585/mmwr.ss7202a1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.ss7202a1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10042614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36952288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bristol MM, Gallagher JJ, Schopler E. Mothers and fathers of young developmentally disabled and nondisabled boys: adaptation and spousal support. Dev Psychol. 1988;24(3):441&#x2013;51. 10.1037/0012-1649.24.3.441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0012-1649.24.3.441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray DE, Holden WJ. Psycho-social well-being among the parents of children with autism. Aust N Z J Dev Disabil. 1992;18(2):83&#x2013;93. 10.1080/07263869200034841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07263869200034841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastings RP, Kovshoff H, Ward NJ, degli Espinosa F, Brown T, Remington B. Systems analysis of stress and positive perceptions in mothers and fathers of pre-school children with autism. J Autism Dev Disord. 2005;35(5):635&#x2013;44. 10.1007/s10803-005-0007-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-005-0007-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16177837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsson MB, Hwang CP. Depression in mothers and fathers of children with intellectual disability. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2001;45(Pt 6):535&#x2013;43. 10.1046/j.1365-2788.2001.00372.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2788.2001.00372.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11737541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnabel A, Youssef GJ, Hallford DJ, Hartley EJ, McGillivray JA, Stewart M, et al. Psychopathology in parents of children with autism spectrum disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis of prevalence. Autism. 2020;24(1):26&#x2013;40. 10.1177/1362361319844636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361319844636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31070044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohrs AC, Leslie DL. Depression in parents of children diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder: A claims-based analysis. J Autism Dev Disord. 2017;47(5):1416&#x2013;22. 10.1007/s10803-017-3063-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-017-3063-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28214978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karra SV, Krause TM, Yamal JM, Ogle NT, Tanner R, Revere L. Autism spectrum disorder and parental depression. J Dev Phys Disabil. 2024;36(3):575&#x2013;89. 10.1007/s10882-023-09924-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10882-023-09924-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Yong Y, Li Y, Li J, Xie J. Cognitive-based interventions for improving psychological health and well-being for parents of children with developmental disabilities: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Autism Dev Disord. 2024;54(9):3316&#x2013;35. 10.1007/s10803-023-06063-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-023-06063-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11362495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37668850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie KT, Eack SM. Interventions to improve outcomes for parents of children with autism spectrum disorder: A meta-analysis. J Autism Dev Disord. 2022;52(7):2859&#x2013;83. 10.1007/s10803-021-05164-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-021-05164-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34189683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uwatoko T, Luo Y, Sakata M, Kobayashi D, Sakagami Y, Takemoto K, et al. Healthy campus trial: a multiphase optimization strategy (MOST) fully factorial trial to optimize the smartphone cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) app for mental health promotion among university students: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2018;19(1):353. 10.1186/s13063-018-2719-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-018-2719-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6032568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29973252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, van Straten A, Warmerdam L. Behavioral activation treatments of depression: a meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Rev. 2007;27(3):318&#x2013;26. 10.1016/j.cpr.2006.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2006.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17184887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekers D, Webster L, Van Straten A, Cuijpers P, Richards D, Gilbody S. Behavioural activation for depression; an update of meta-analysis of effectiveness and sub group analysis. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(6):e100100. 10.1371/journal.pone.0100100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0100100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4061095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24936656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni&#x2019;matuzahroh SMW, Suen MW, Ningrum V, Widayat N, Yuniardi MS, Hasanati N, et al. The association between parenting stress, positive reappraisal coping, and quality of life in parents with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) children: A systematic review. Healthc (Basel). 2021;10(1):52. 10.3390/healthcare10010052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10010052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8775364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35052216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai WW, Oei TP. Coping in parents and caregivers of children with autism spectrum disorders (ASD): a review. Rev J Autism Dev Disord. 2014;1(3):207&#x2013;24. 10.1007/s40489-014-0021-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40489-014-0021-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25800867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbeduto L, Seltzer MM, Shattuck P, Krauss MW, Orsmond G, Murphy MM. Psychological well-being and coping in mothers of youths with autism, down syndrome, or fragile X syndrome. Am J Ment Retard. 2004;109(3):237&#x2013;54. 10.1352/0895-8017(2004)109%3C237:PWACIM%3E2.0.CO;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1352/0895-8017(2004)109&lt;237:PWACIM&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15072518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai RY, Uljarevi&#x107; M, Leekam SR. Predicting mental health and psychological wellbeing in mothers of children with autism spectrum disorder: roles of intolerance of uncertainty and coping. Autism Res. 2020;13(10):1797&#x2013;801. 10.1002/aur.2341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aur.2341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32618140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feinberg E, Augustyn M, Fitzgerald E, Sandler J, Ferreira-Cesar Suarez Z, Chen N, et al. Improving maternal mental health after a child&#x2019;s diagnosis of autism spectrum disorder: results from a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Pediatr. 2014;168(1):40&#x2013;6. 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2013.3445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2013.3445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24217336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen CT, Fairclough DL, Noll RB. Problem-solving skills training for mothers of children recently diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder: A pilot feasibility study. Autism. 2016;20(1):55&#x2013;64. 10.1177/1362361314567134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361314567134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25896269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nezu AM, Nezu CM, Felgoise SH, McClure KS, Houts PS. Project genesis: assessing the efficacy of problem-solving therapy for distressed adult cancer patients. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2003;71(6):1036&#x2013;48. 10.1037/0022-006X.71.6.1036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-006X.71.6.1036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14622079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews G, Cuijpers P, Craske MG, McEvoy P, Titov N. Computer therapy for the anxiety and depressive disorders is effective, acceptable and practical health care: a meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2010;5(10):e13196. 10.1371/journal.pone.0013196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0013196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20967242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So M, Yamaguchi S, Hashimoto S, Sado M, Furukawa TA, McCrone P. Is computerised CBT really helpful for adult depression?-A meta-analytic re-evaluation of CCBT for adult depression in terms of clinical implementation and methodological validity. BMC Psychiatry. 2013;13:113. 10.1186/1471-244X-13-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-13-113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23587347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akechi T, Hirai K, Motooka H, Shiozaki M, Chen J, Momino K, et al. Problem-solving therapy for psychological distress in Japanese cancer patients: preliminary clinical experience from psychiatric consultations. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2008;38(12):867&#x2013;70. 10.1093/jjco/hyn115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jjco/hyn115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19008215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akechi T, Yamaguchi T, Uchida M, Imai F, Momino K, Katsuki F, et al. Smartphone psychotherapy reduces fear of cancer recurrence among breast cancer survivors: A fully decentralized randomized controlled clinical trial (J-SUPPORT 1703 study). J Clin Oncol. 2023;41(5):1069&#x2013;78. 10.1200/JCO.22.00699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.22.00699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9928623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36322882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakata M, Toyomoto R, Yoshida K, Luo Y, Nakagami Y, Uwatoko T, et al. Components of smartphone cognitive-behavioural therapy for subthreshold depression among 1093 university students: a factorial trial. Evid Based Ment Health. 2022;25(e1):e18&#x2013;25. 10.1136/ebmental-2022-300455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ebmental-2022-300455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9811098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35577537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantani A, Kato T, Furukawa TA, Horikoshi M, Imai H, Hiroe T, et al. Smartphone cognitive behavioral therapy as an adjunct to pharmacotherapy for refractory depression: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2017;19(11):e373. 10.2196/jmir.8602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.8602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5695656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29101095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai F, Momino K, Katsuki F, Horikoshi M, Furukawa TA, Kondo N, et al. Smartphone problem-solving therapy to reduce fear of cancer recurrence among breast cancer survivors: an open single-arm pilot study. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2019;49(6):537&#x2013;44. 10.1093/jjco/hyz005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jjco/hyz005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30793156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai H, Yamada M, Inagaki M, Watanabe N, Chino B, Mantani A, et al. Behavioral activation contributed to the total reduction of depression symptoms in the smartphone-based cognitive behavioral therapy: A secondary analysis of a randomized, controlled trial. Innov Clin Neurosci. 2020;17(7&#x2013;9):21&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7839653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33520400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada S. Construction of the big five scales of personality trait terms and concurrent validity with NPI. Jpn J Psychol. 1996;67(1):61&#x2013;7. 10.4992/jjpsy.67.61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4992/jjpsy.67.61</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Namikawa T, Tani I, Wakita T, Kumagai R, Nakane A, Noguchi H. [Development of a short form of the Japanese big-five scale, and a test of its reliability and validity]. Shinrigaku Kenkyu. 2012;83(2):91&#x2013;9. 10.4992/jjpsy.83.91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4992/jjpsy.83.91</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22834085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron-Cohen S, Wheelwright S, Skinner R, Martin J, Clubley E. The Autism-Spectrum quotient (AQ): evidence from asperger syndrome/high-functioning autism, males and females, scientists and mathematicians. J Autism Dev Disord. 2001;31(1):5&#x2013;17. 10.1023/a:1005653411471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/a:1005653411471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11439754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurita H, Koyama T, Osada H. Autism-Spectrum Quotient-Japanese version and its short forms for screening normally intelligent persons with pervasive developmental disorders. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2005;59(4):490&#x2013;6. 10.1111/j.1440-1819.2005.01403.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1819.2005.01403.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16048456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarason IG, Sarason BR, Shearin EN, Pierce GR. A brief measure of social support: practical and theoretical implications. J Soc Personal Relat. 1987;4(4):497&#x2013;510. 10.1177/0265407587044007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0265407587044007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa TA, Harai H, Hirai T, Kitamura T, Takahashi K. Social support questionnaire among psychiatric patients with various diagnoses and normal controls. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 1999;34(4):216&#x2013;22. 10.1007/s001270050136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s001270050136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10365628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakata M, Toyomoto R, Yoshida K, Luo Y, Nakagami Y, Aoki S, et al. Development and validation of the cognitive behavioural therapy skills scale among college students. Evid Based Ment Health. 2021;24(2):70&#x2013;6. 10.1136/ebmental-2020-300217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ebmental-2020-300217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33402377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heppner PP, Petersen CH. The development and implications of a personal Problem-Solving inventory. J Couns Psychol. 1982;29(1):66&#x2013;75. 10.1037/0022-0167.29.1.66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0167.29.1.66</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto T, Shudo Y, Sakai M. Development of the Japanese version of behavioral activation for depression Scale-Short form (BADS-SF) and examination of its reliability and validity. Jpn J Cogn Ther. 2015;8:96&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchida T, Fukushima O. The development of the cognitive behavioral self-monitoring scale. Mejiro J Psychol. 2007;3(1):85&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strunk DR, Hollars SN, Adler AD, Goldstein LA, Braun JD. Assessing patients&#x2019; cognitive therapy skills: initial evaluation of the competencies of cognitive therapy scale. Cognit Ther Res. 2014;38(5):559&#x2013;69. 10.1007/s10608-014-9617-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10608-014-9617-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4232848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25408560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manos RC, Kanter JW, Luo W. The behavioral activation for depression scale-short form: development and validation. Behav Ther. 2011;42(4):726&#x2013;39. 10.1016/j.beth.2011.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beth.2011.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa TA. Assessment of mood: guides for clinicians. J Psychosom Res. 2010;68(6):581&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2009.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2009.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20488276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muramatsu K, Miyaoka H, Kamijima K, Muramatsu Y, Tanaka Y, Hosaka M, et al. Performance of the Japanese version of the patient health Questionnaire-9 (J-PHQ-9) for depression in primary care. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2018;52:64&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2018.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2018.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29698880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(10):1092&#x2013;7. 10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obbarius A, van Maasakkers L, Baer L, Clark DM, Crocker AG, de Beurs E, et al. Standardization of health outcomes assessment for depression and anxiety: recommendations from the ICHOM depression and anxiety working group. Qual Life Res. 2017;26(12):3211&#x2013;25. 10.1007/s11136-017-1659-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-017-1659-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5681977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28786017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Ames M, Hymel PA, Loeppke R, McKenas DK, Richling DE, et al. Using the world health organization health and work performance questionnaire (HPQ) to evaluate the indirect workplace costs of illness. J Occup Environ Med. 2004;46(6 Suppl):S23&#x2013;37. 10.1097/01.jom.0000126683.75201.c5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.jom.0000126683.75201.c5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15194893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Barker PR, Colpe LJ, Epstein JF, Gfroerer JC, Hiripi E, et al. Screening for serious mental illness in the general population. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2003;60(2):184&#x2013;9. 10.1001/archpsyc.60.2.184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.60.2.184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12578436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami N, Takeshima T, Ono Y, Uda H, Hata Y, Nakane Y, et al. Twelve-month prevalence, severity, and treatment of common mental disorders in communities in japan: preliminary finding from the world mental health Japan survey 2002&#x2013;2003. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2005;59(4):441&#x2013;52. 10.1111/j.1440-1819.2005.01397.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1819.2005.01397.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16048450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>