<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41760911</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2398-6352</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NPJ digital medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>NPJ Digit Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advancing medical AI through benchmarking and competition for specialty triage.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41746-026-02433-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Artificial intelligence holds transformative potential for clinical triage, yet challenges in accuracy, generalization, and interpretability persist. To address these gaps, we introduce MedTriage, a benchmark designed to evaluate large-scale models across diverse clinical scenarios rigorously. Leveraging this framework, we launched the Large-Model-Based Medical Triage Evaluation Competition, utilizing real-world clinician-patient dialogues from general hospitals and four specialized domains. The competition engaged numerous research teams, spurring advancements in large-model-driven triage algorithms. Building on the competition insights, we developed an enhanced model (MedGPT-Guide) employing a "10 Relevant + 10 Random + Ensemble" strategy, achieving superior accuracy on the MedTriage benchmark. Our results underscore the power of "evaluation-driven training" to improve model performance and lay the groundwork for standardized, deployable intelligent triage systems. Moving forward, priorities include enhancing data security, model generalization, and addressing legal and regulatory frameworks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Putuo Hospital, Shanghai University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Bian</LastName><ForeName>Mouxiao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Minjia</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Laboratory of Biomedical Artificial Intelligence, Shanghai East Hospital, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Luyi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Infectious Disease and Biosecurity, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Health Development Research Center(Shanghai Medical Information Center), Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Kaiyi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Pengcheng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yuanye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Putuo Hospital, Shanghai University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shanghai, China. yuanye1014@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Shanghai, China. xujie@pjlab.org.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>NPJ Digit Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101731738</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2398-6352</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41760911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-026-02433-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41746-026-02433-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hsia, R. Y., Thind, A., Zakariah, A., Hicks, E. R. &amp; Mock, C. Prehospital and emergency care: updates from the disease control priorities, version 3. World J. Surg. 39, 2161&#x2013;2167 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollberg, B., Dahlgaard, J. &amp; Brehmer, P.-O. Measuring lean initiatives in health care services: Issues and findings. J. Prod. Perform. Manag 56, 7&#x2013;24 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton, W. Diagnosis: cancer diagnosis in UK primary care. Nat. Rev. Clin. Oncol. 9, 251&#x2013;252 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iserson, K. V. &amp; Moskop, J. C. Triage in medicine, part I: concept, history, and types. Ann. Emerg. Med. 49, 275&#x2013;281 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, H. et al. Analysis of factors affecting medical personnel seeking employment at primary health care institutions: developing human resources for primary health care. Int. J. Equity Health 21, 37 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachariasse, J. M. et al. Validity of the Manchester Triage System in emergency care: a prospective observational study. PloS one 12, e0170811 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman, A. B., Delgado, M. K. &amp; Weissman, G. E. Artificial intelligence for emergency care triage-much promise, but still much to learn. JAMA Netw. open 7, e248857 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bierer, B. E. &amp; Truog, R. D. The unresolved challenge of triage. JAMA Netw. open 6, e2329676 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knitza, J. et al. Comparison of two symptom checkers (ada and symptoma) in the emergency department: randomized, crossover, head-to-head, double-blinded study. J. Med. Internet Res. 26, e56514 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawoodbhoy, F. M. et al. AI in patient flow: applications of artificial intelligence to improve patient flow in NHS acute mental health inpatient units. Heliyon 7, e06993 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siira, E., Tyskbo, D. &amp; Nygren, J. Healthcare leaders&#x2019; experiences of implementing artificial intelligence for medical history-taking and triage in Swedish primary care: an interview study. BMC Prim. Care 25, 268 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser, H. et al. Comparison of diagnostic and triage accuracy of Ada Health and WebMD symptom checkers, ChatGPT, and physicians for patients in an emergency department: clinical data analysis study. JMIR mHealth uHealth 11, e49995 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mika, A. P., Martin, J. R., Engstrom, S. M., Polkowski, G. G. &amp; Wilson, J. M. Assessing ChatGPT responses to common patient questions regarding total hip arthroplasty. J. bone Jt. Surg. Am. Vol. 105, 1519&#x2013;1526 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, M. &amp; Decary, M. Artificial intelligence in healthcare: an essential guide for health leaders. Healthc. Manag. forum 33, 10&#x2013;18 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masanneck, L. et al. Triage performance across large language models, ChatGPT, and untrained doctors in emergency medicine: comparative study. J. Med. Internet Res. 26, e53297 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, D. M. et al. The diagnostic and triage accuracy of the GPT-3 artificial intelligence model: an observational study. Lancet Digital Health 6, e555&#x2013;e561 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griot, M., Hemptinne, C., Vanderdonckt, J. &amp; Yuksel, D. Large Language Models lack essential metacognition for reliable medical reasoning. Nat. Commun. 16, 642 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. et al. Meddialog: a large-scale medical dialogue dataset. 3 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. Bianque: Balancing the questioning and suggestion ability of health llms with multi-turn health conversations polished by ChatGPT. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, J. et al. Chain-of-thought prompting elicits reasoning in large language models. 35, 24824-24837 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, L. et al. Evaluating large language models on medical evidence summarization. NPJ Digital Med. 6, 158 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, R. et al. Development and interpretation of a pathomics-based model for the prediction of microsatellite instability in colorectal cancer. Theranostics 10, 11080&#x2013;11091 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmieding, M. L., M&#xf6;rgeli, R., Schmieding, M. A. L., Feufel, M. A. &amp; Balzer, F. Correction: benchmarking triage capability of symptom checkers against that of medical laypersons: survey study. J. Med. Internet Res. 23, e30215 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes, M. et al. Clinical decision support systems for triage in the emergency department using intelligent systems: a review. Artif. Intell. Med. 102, 101762 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, H., Meczner, A., Burslam-Dawe, K. &amp; Hayhoe, B. Triage errors in primary and pre-primary care. J. Med. Internet Res. 24, e37209 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, M. et al. Artificial intelligence applications in health care practice: scoping review. J. Med. Internet Res. 24, e40238 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend, B. A., Plant, K. L., Hodge, V. J., Ashaolu, O. &amp; Calinescu, R. Medical practitioner perspectives on AI in emergency triage. Front. Digital health 5, 1297073 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahun, E. et al. Perceptions and concerns of emergency medicine practitioners about artificial intelligence in emergency triage management during the pandemic: a national survey-based study. Front. Public Health 11, 1285390 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnell, R. et al. Rethink reporting of evaluation results in AI. Science 380, 136&#x2013;138 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, A., Hertzmann, A. &amp; Russakovsky, O. Benchmark suites instead of leaderboards for evaluating AI fairness. Patterns 5, 101080 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algorithms of Oppression: How Search Engines Reinforce RacismAlgorithms of Oppression: How Search Engines Reinforce Racism Safiya Umoja Noble NYU Press, 2018. 256 Science. 374, 542 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed, S. A. &amp; Masters, R. M. Disparities in Health Care and the Digital Divide. Curr. Psychiatry Rep. 23, 61 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermeyer, Z., Powers, B., Vogeli, C. &amp; Mullainathan, S. Dissecting racial bias in an algorithm used to manage the health of populations. Science 366, 447-453 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, N. et al. Data privacy in healthcare: in the era of artificial intelligence. Indian Dermatol. online J. 14, 788&#x2013;792 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles, G. &amp; Quinlan, A. HIPAA and video recordings in the clinical setting. Nursing 53, 15&#x2013;19 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orel, A. &amp; Bernik, I. GDPR and health personal data; tricks and traps of compliance. Stud. Health Technol. Inform. 255, 155&#x2013;159 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y. &amp; Yang, F. Overcoming personal information protection challenges involving real-world data to support public health efforts in China. Front. public health 11, 1265050 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Kuwaiti, A. et al. A review of the role of artificial intelligence in healthcare. J. Personal. Med. 13, 951 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>