<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41675512</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2095-4697</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Quantitative biology (Beijing, China)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Quant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying early warning signals of cancer formation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e81</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e81</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e81</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/qub2.81</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It is increasingly clear that cancer is a complex systemic disease and one of the most fatal diseases in humans. Complex systems, including cancer, exhibit critical transitions in which the system abruptly shifts from one state to another. However, predicting these critical transitions is difficult as the system may show little change before the tipping point is reached. Models for predicting cancer are generally not accurate enough to reliably predict where these critical transitions will occur. Additionally, there is often a gap between theoretical results and clinical practice. To address these issues, we conducted a study using gastric cancer as a representative to reveal the tipping point of cancer and develop a feasible method for clinical monitoring. We used gene regulatory networks and a landscape framework to quantify the formation of gastric cancer. Since the dissipation cost of cancer cells is different from that of normal cells, we calculated the entropy product rate (EPR) and mean flux to quantify the thermodynamic cost and dynamical driving force in predicting critical transitions of cancer, which can serve as early warning signals. Both the EPR and mean flux change sharply near the point when the cancer state is about to emerge and/or the normal state is about to disappear. Moreover, the peak or sharp upward trends of the signals occur much earlier than critical slowdown and flickering frequency. These significant variations can be used as early warning signals for cancer. To further explore early warning signals in clinical and experimental trials, we calculated the difference in cross correlations (&#x394;<i>C</i>) forward and backward in time for the stochastic gene expression time series. This time-irreversible measure gives a rise to peak before the bifurcation points, which can help detect precancerous and metastatic early warning signals in clinical practice rather than just theoretical calculation. This study is crucial for effectively identifying early warning signals for cancer in clinical and experimental settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Quantitative Biology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd on behalf of Higher Education Press.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Chong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1289-8578</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Electroanalytical Chemistry Changchun Institute of Applied Chemistry Chinese Academy of Sciences Changchun China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics Jilin University of Finance and Economics Changchun China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Wenbo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Electroanalytical Chemistry Changchun Institute of Applied Chemistry Chinese Academy of Sciences Changchun China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaona</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry Northeast Normal University Changchun China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint Research Centre on Medicine the Affiliated Xiangshan Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University Ningbo China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Theoretical Interdisciplinary Sciences Wenzhou Institute University of Chinese Academy of Sciences Wenzhou China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and of Physics and Astronomy State University of New York at Stony Brook Stony Brook New York USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Quant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101639642</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2095-4689</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer early warning signals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">entropy production rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flux</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gene regulatory network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">landscape</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">time irreversibility</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41675512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12806070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/qub2.81</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">QUB281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Luo M, Li L. Clinical utility of miniprobe endoscopic ultrasonography for prediction of invasion depth of early gastric cancer: a meta&#x2010;analysis of diagnostic test from PRISMA guideline. Medicine. 2019;98(6):e14430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6380697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30732202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo C, Zhang X, Gu Y, Wang D, Zhang S, Liu T, et&#xa0;al. Organoids: construction and application in gastric cancer. Biomolecules. 2023;13(5):875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10216466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37238742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauren P. The two histological main types of gastric carcinoma: diffuse and so&#x2010;called intestinal&#x2010;type carcinoma: diffuse and so&#x2010;called intestinal&#x2010;type carcinoma. Acta Pathol Microbiol Scand. 1965;64(1):31&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14320675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cis&#x142;o M, Filip AA, Offerhaus GJA, Cise&#x142; B, Rawicz&#x2010;Pruszy&#x144;ski K, Skierucha M, et&#xa0;al. Oncotarget. 2018;9:19427&#x2013;19442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5922408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29721214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnakenberg J. Network theory of microscopic and macroscopic behavior of master equation systems. Rev Mod Phys. 1976;48(4):571&#x2013;585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Xu L, Wang E. Potential landscape and flux framework of nonequilibrium networks: robustness, dissipation, and coherence of biochemical oscillations. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2008;105(34):12271&#x2013;12276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2527901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18719111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu M, Jolly MK, Gomoto R, Huang B, Ben&#x2010;Jacob JOandE. Tristability in cancer&#x2010;associated MicroRNA&#x2010;TF chimera toggle switch. J Phys Chem B. 2013;117(42):13164&#x2013;13174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23679052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu M, Jolly MK, Onuchic J, Ben&#x2010;Jacob E. Toward decoding the principles of cancer metastasis circuits. Cancer Res. 2014;74(17):4574&#x2013;4587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25183783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C, Wang J, Li S, Guo D, He J. Acetyl&#x2010;CoA carboxylases and diseases. Front Oncol. 2022;12:836058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8963101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35359351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C, Xu H, Wang J. A global and physical mechanism of gastric cancer formation and progression. J Theor Biol. 2021;520:110643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33636204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Lu M, Jia D, Ma J, Ben&#x2010;Jacob E, Levine H, et&#xa0;al. Modeling the genetic regulation of cancer metabolism: interplay between glycolysis and oxidative phosphorylation. Cancer Res. 2017;77(7):1564&#x2013;1574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5380541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li C, Wang E. Potential and flux landscapes quantify the stability and robustness of budding yeast cell cycle network. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2010;107(18):8195&#x2013;8200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2889591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20393126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhang K, Xu L, Wang E. Quantifying the Waddington landscape and biological paths for development and differentiation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2011;108(20):8257&#x2013;8262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21536909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Wang E, Wang J. Landscape topography determines global stability and robustness of a metabolic network. ACS Synth Biol. 2012;1(6):229&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23651205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhter MH, Madhav NS, Ahmad J. Epidermal growth factor receptor based active targeting: a paradigm shift towards advance tumor therapy. Artif Cell Nanomed Biotechnol. 2018;46(Suppl 2):1188&#x2013;1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29991287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bure IV, Nemtsova MV, Zaletaev DV. Roles of E&#x2010;cadherin and noncoding RNAs in the epithelial&#x2013;mesenchymal transition and progression in gastric cancer. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(12):2870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6627057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31212809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuzhalin A. The role of interleukin DNA polymorphisms in gastric cancer. Hum Immunol. 2011;72(11):1128&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21871937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozengurt E, Walsh JH. Gastrin, CCK, signaling, and cancer. Annu Rev Physiol. 2001;63(1):49&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11181948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Terashima M, Kitada K, Ochiai A, Ichikawa W, Kurahashi I, Sakuramoto S, et&#xa0;al. Impact of expression of human epidermal growth factor receptors <i>EGFR</i> and ERBB2 on survival in stage II/III gastric cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2012;18(21):5992&#x2013;6000.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22977193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Wang J. Quantifying cell fate decisions for differentiation and reprogramming of a human stem cell network: landscape and biological paths. PLoS Comput Biol. 2013;9(8):e1003165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3731225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23935477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier RS, Stein DL. Escape problem for irreversible systems. Phys Rev. 1993;48(2):931&#x2013;938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9960675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheffer M, Bascompte J, Brock WA, Brovkin V, Carpenter SR, Dakos V, et&#xa0;al. Early&#x2010;warning signals for critical transitions. Nature. 2009;461(7260):53&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19727193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto E, Suzuki H, Takamaru H, Yamamoto H, Toyota M, Shinomura Y. Role of DNA methylation in the development of diffuse&#x2010;type gastric cancer. Digestion. 2011;83(4):241&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21273772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goud HK, Mehkari Z, Mohammed L, Javed M, Althwanay A, Ahsan F, et&#xa0;al. Significance of E&#x2010;cadherin gene mutations in patients with hereditary diffuse gastric cancer syndrome: a systematic review. Cureus. 2020;12(9):e10406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7550226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33062523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian H. Open&#x2010;system nonequilibrium steady State: statistical thermodynamics, fluctuations, and chemical oscillations. J Phys Chem B. 2006;110(31):15063&#x2013;15074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16884217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Wang J. Uncovering the underlying mechanisms of cancer metabolism through the landscapes and probability flux quantifications. iScience. 2020;23(4):101002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7150521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32276228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanahan D, Weinberg RA. Hallmarks of cancer: the next generation. Cell. 2011;144(5):646&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21376230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David CJ, Massagu&#xe8; J. Contextual determinants of TGF&#x3b2; action in development, immunity and cancer. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2018;19(7):419&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7457231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29643418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang S, Zhu G, Ouyang L, Luo Y, Zhou R, Pan C, et&#xa0;al. Bapx1 mediates transforming growth factor&#x2010;&#x3b2;&#x2010; induced epithelial&#x2010;mesenchymal transition and promotes a malignancy phenotype of gastric cancer cells. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2017;486(2):285&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28315334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rami FEE, Barsoumian HB, Khneizer GW. Therapeutic Advances in Medical Oncology. 2020;12:175883592096723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Li Q, Chen J, Liu Y, Zhao X, Tan B, et&#xa0;al. Prevalence of Th17 and Treg cells in gastric cancer patients and its correlation with clinical parameters. Oncol Rep. 2013;30(3):1215&#x2013;1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23807713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dakos V, Matthews B, Hendry AP, Levine J, Loeuille N, Norberg J, et&#xa0;al. Ecosystem tipping points in an evolving world. Nature Ecology and Evolution. 2019;3:355&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30778190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arani BMS, Carpenter SR, Lahti L, van Nes EH, Scheffer M. Exit time as a measure of ecological resilience. Science. 2021;372(6547):eaay4895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34112667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brock WA, Carpenter SR. Interacting regime shifts in ecosystems: implication for early warnings. Ecol Monogr. 2010;80(3):353&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijesundera I, Halgamuge MN, Nirmalathas A, Nanayakkara T. MFPT calculation for random walks in inhomogeneous networks. Phys Stat Mech Appl. 2016;462:986&#x2013;1002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Zhang K, Wang J. Exploring the underlying mechanisms of the <i>Xenopus laevis</i> embryonic cell cycle. J Phys Chem B. 2018;122(21):5487&#x2013;5499.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian H, Elson EL. Fluorescence correlation spectroscopy with&#xa0;high&#x2010;order and dual&#x2010;color correlation to probe nonequilibrium steady states. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2004;101(9):2828&#x2013;2833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC365705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14970342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J, Cao Z, Wang J, Jiang H, Hou Z. Dynamical and thermodynamical origins of motility&#x2010;induced phase separation. Cell Reports Physical Science. 2024;5(2):101817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Xu L, Wang EK. Potential landscape and flux framework of nonequilibrium networks: robustness, dissipation, and coherence of biochemical oscillations. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2008;105(34):12271&#x2013;12276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2527901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18719111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasai M, Wolynes PG. Stochastic gene expression as a many&#x2010;body problem. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2003;100(5):2374&#x2013;2379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC151348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12606710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Wang E, Wang J. Landscape, flux, correlation, resonance, coherence, stability, and key network wirings of stochastic circadian oscillation. Biophys J. 2011;101(6):1335&#x2013;1344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3177066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21943414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>