<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41642269</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1076-836X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Systematic biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Syst Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synergizing Bayesian and Heuristic Approaches: D-BPP Uncovers Ghost Introgression in Panthera and Thuja.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">syag012</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/sysbio/syag012</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hybridization involving extinct or unsampled ("ghost") lineages profoundly influences species' evolutionary histories, but detecting such introgression remains methodologically challenging. We introduce D-BPP, a framework that integrates the heuristic D-statistic (or ABBA-BABA test) with Bayesian phylogenomic inference (implemented in BPP) to efficiently infer phylogenetic networks. In D-BPP, we first employ the D-statistic to rapidly identify candidate introgression events on a predefined bifurcating species tree; then we leverage the Bayesian test in BPP to rigorously validate these candidates and sequentially add them to the species tree, retaining only those events with strong statistical support. When the species tree is ambiguous, D-BPP identifies the most probable topology by comparing introgression models in a Bayesian framework. Through dedicated simulation analyses, we show that the D-BPP workflow has high power: the D-statistic reliably detects the presence of introgression, BPP accurately discriminates among alternative introgression scenarios, and the key procedural steps of the pipeline are empirically well-justified. Critically, our framework excels at detecting ghost introgression, which is often unidentifiable or overlooked by existing methods-whether heuristic or full-likelihood. Applied to genomic datasets from Panthera (big cats) and Thuja (conifers), D-BPP uncovered previously undetected ghost introgression events in both clades, underscoring the pervasive role ghost lineages have played across diverse taxa. By combining the computational efficiency of heuristic D-statistics with the robust statistical rigor of full-likelihood Bayesian inference, D-BPP provides a practical and powerful approach for reconstructing complex reticulate evolutionary histories.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Society of Systematic Biologists. All rights reserved. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site-for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Facility Preservation Bank for Forestry and Grassland Germplasm Resources (Xiong'an), College of Biological Sciences and Technology, Beijing Forestry University, Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory for Biodiversity Science and Ecological Engineering, College of Life Sciences, Beijing Normal University, Beijing 100875, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Xu</ForeName><Initials>XX</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8279-8113</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Herbage Improvement and Grassland Agro-Ecosystems, College of Ecology, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Mei</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South China Botanical Garden, the Chinese Academy of Sciences, Guangdong 510520, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Bo-Wen</ForeName><Initials>BW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory for Biodiversity Science and Ecological Engineering, College of Life Sciences, Beijing Normal University, Beijing 100875, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Wei-Ning</ForeName><Initials>WN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory for Biodiversity Science and Ecological Engineering, College of Life Sciences, Beijing Normal University, Beijing 100875, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Da-Yong</ForeName><Initials>DY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1056-8735</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory for Biodiversity Science and Ecological Engineering, College of Life Sciences, Beijing Normal University, Beijing 100875, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Syst Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9302532</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1063-5157</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">D-statistic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BPP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bayesian test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Introgression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogenetic networks</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41642269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sysbio/syag012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">8465372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>