<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41796195</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-Time stability enhancement of DDPMSG-based tidal hybrid power systems using heuristic optimization.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42638-1</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhutto</LastName><ForeName>Javed Khan</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, King Khalid University, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohanty</LastName><ForeName>Asit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Power Engineering, National Energy University, Kualalumpur, 43000, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Promotion of Research, Graphic Era (Deemed to be University), Clementtown, Dehradun, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohanty</LastName><ForeName>Pragyan P</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, VSSUT, Burla, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Satpathy</LastName><ForeName>Abhaya S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of management studies, Sri Sri University, Cuttack, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Soumya Ranjan</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, India. soumya.das@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DDPMSG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DEA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid FA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reactive power compensation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UPFC</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41796195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42638-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42638-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Millar, D. L. Wave and tidal power [Internet]. Energy&#x2026; beyond oil. Oxford University Press; (2007). Available from: https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780199209965.003.0006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidal-current and tidal-range power [Internet]. Renewable Energy Resources. Routledge. pp. 477&#x2013;507. (2015). Available from: https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315766416-20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elghali, S. E., Ben, Benbouzid, M. E. H. &amp; Charpentier, J. F. Marine Tidal Current Electric Power Generation Technology: State of the Art and Current Status [Internet]. 2007 IEEE International Electric Machines &amp; Drives Conference. IEEE; (2007). Available from: https://doi.org/10.1109/iemdc.2007.383635</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Elghali, S. E., Benbouzid, M. E. H. &amp; Charpentier, J. F. Modelling and control of a marine current turbine-driven doubly fed induction generator. IET Renew. Power Gener. 4(1), 1&#x2013;11 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Elghali, S. E., Benbouzid, M. E. H. &amp; Charpentier, J. F. Modelling and control of a marine current turbine-driven doubly fed induction generator. IET Renew. Power Gener. 4(1), 1. https://doi.org/10.1049/iet-rpg.2008.0118 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim, B., Gheisarnejad, M. &amp; Khooban, M. H. Delay-dependent stability analysis of modern shipboard microgrids. IEEE Trans. Circuits Syst. I Regul. Pap. 68(4), 1693&#x2013;705 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. et al. Fractional-order PI control of DFIG-based tidal stream turbine. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse8050309 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam, D. &amp; Vittal, V. Impact of DFIG based wind turbine generators on transient and small signal stability of power systems. 2009 IEEE Power Energy Soc Gen Meet PES &#x2019;09. ;6551. (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasa, Y. &amp; Mese, E. Design and analysis of generator and converters for outer rotor direct drive gearless small-scale wind turbines. 3rd Int. Conf. Renew. Energy Res. Appl. ICRERA 2014 ;689&#x2013;694. (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, R. N. et al. Dynamical analysis of a novel hybrid oceanic tidal-wave energy converter system. Energy 263(January), 1&#x2013;8 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R., Singh, R. &amp; Ashfaq, H. Stability enhancement of induction generator&#x2013;based series compensated wind power plants by alleviating subsynchronous torsional oscillations using BFOA-optimal controller tuned STATCOM. Wind Energy 23(9), 1846&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1002/we.2521 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghefiri, K., Bouall&#xe8;gue, S., Garrido, I., Garrido, A. J. &amp; Hagg&#xe8;ge, J. Complementary power control for doubly fed induction generator-based tidal stream turbine generation plants. Energies https://doi.org/10.3390/en10070862 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polinder, H., Van Der Pijl, F. F. A., De Vilder, G. J. &amp; Tavner, P. J. Comparison of direct-drive and geared generator concepts for wind turbines. IEEE Trans. Energy Convers. 21(3), 725&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1109/tec.2006.875476 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly, H. H., Alhaddad, F. M. &amp; El-Hawary, M. E. A proposed adaptive intelligent controllers for tidal currents turbine driving DDPMSG for improving the output power generated. 2019 IEEE Electr Power Energy Conf EPEC. 2019;3. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noman, M., Li, G., Wang, K. &amp; Han, B. Electrical control strategy for an ocean energy conversion system. Prot. Control Mod. Power Syst. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41601-021-00186-y (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafi, S. H. &amp; Sheikh, M. R. I. Optimization of a Direct-Drive Wind Power Generation System by using PMSG Pgrid (dgrid) (I dgrid) Qgrid - (Vdgrid) (Idgrid). ;(May):21&#x2013;3. (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghefiri, K., Bouall&#xe8;gue, S., Garrido, I., Garrido, A. J. &amp; Hagg&#xe8;ge, J. Multi-layer artificial neural networks based MPPT-pitch angle control of a tidal stream generator. Sensors https://doi.org/10.3390/s18051317 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghefiri, K., Bouall&#xe8;gue, S., Hagg&#xe8;ge, J., Garrido, I. &amp; GarridoAJ Firefly algorithm based-pitch angle control of a tidal stream generator for power limitation mode. 2018 Int. Conf. Adv. Syst. Electr. Technol. IC_ASET 2018. 1 (1), 387&#x2013;392 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkhier, Y. &amp; Achour, A. Fuzzy passivity-based linear feedback current controller approach for PMSG-based tidal turbine. Ocean Eng. 218(August), 108156. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oceaneng.2020.108156 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghefiri, K., Garrido, I., Bouall&#xe8;gue, S., Hagg&#xe8;ge, J. &amp; Garrido, A. J. Hybrid neural fuzzy design-based rotational speed control of a tidal stream generator plant. Sustain 10(10), 1&#x2013;26 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanty, A., Viswavandya, M., Ray, P. K., Panigrahi, T. K. &amp; Mohanty, S. Stability and optimisation of direct drive permanent magnet synchronous generator based tidal turbine. Vacuum 166(October), 341&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2018.10.052 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanty, A., Viswavandya, M., Ray, P. K. &amp; Mohanty, S. Reactive power control and optimisation of hybrid off shore tidal turbine with system uncertainties. J. Ocean Eng. Sci. 1(4), 256&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joes.2016.06.005 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusco, F. &amp; Ringwood, J. V. A simple and effective real-time controller for wave energy converters. IEEE Trans. Sustain. Energy 4(1), 21&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1109/tste.2012.2196717 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraiman, G., Nichita, C., M&#xee;nzu, V., Dakyio, B. &amp; Jo, C. H. Concept study of offshore wind and tidal hybrid conversion based on real time simulation. Renew Energy Power Qual J [Internet]. ;812&#x2013;7. (2011). Available from: https://doi.org/10.24084/repqj09.459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghefiri, K., Bouallegue, S., Haggege, J. &amp; Modeling and SIL simulation of a Tidal Stream device for marine energy conversion [Internet]. IREC2015 The Sixth International Renewable Energy Congress. IEEE; (2015). Available from: https://doi.org/10.1109/irec.2015.7110882</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sah, S. V., Prakash, V., Pathak, P. K. &amp; Yadav, A. K. Intelligent Frequency Control Mechanism of Renewable Shared Interconnected Power System with Communication Delay [Internet]. 2024 IEEE 11th Power India International Conference (PIICON). IEEE; pp. 1&#x2013;6. (2024). Available from: https://doi.org/10.1109/piicon63519.2024.10995151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R., Khetrapal, P., Badoni, M. &amp; Diwania, S. Evaluating the relative operational performance of wind power plants in Indian electricity generation sector using two-stage model. Energy Environ. 33(7), 1441&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1177/0958305x211043531 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, N., Kumar, N. &amp; Kumar, R. Battery energy storage-based system damping controller for alleviating sub-synchronous oscillations in a DFIG-based wind power plant. Prot. Control Mod. Power Syst. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41601-023-00309-7 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., Saini, S., Gupta, S. K. &amp; Kumar, R. Solar-PV inverter for the overall stability of power systems with intelligent MPPT control of DC-link capacitor voltage. Prot. Control Mod. Power Syst. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41601-023-00285-y (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, J., Zou, R., Pathak, P. K., Karni, A. &amp; Akhtar, S. Design of a novel cascade PI-(1&#x2009;+&#x2009;FOPID) controller to enhance load frequency control performance in diverse electric power systems. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 243, 111488. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.epsr.2025.111488 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, J., Zou, R., Wu, Z., Pathak, P. K. &amp; Akhtar, S. Design and performance analysis of Walrus Optimization Algorithm (&lt;scp&gt;WaOA&lt;/scp&gt;)-based cascade controller for load frequency control of a multi&#x2010;area power system with renewable sources. Int. J. Numer. Model. Electron. Netw. Devices Fields https://doi.org/10.1002/jnm.70046 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh, M., Yadav, A. K., Pathak, P. K. &amp; Hussaian Basha, C. H. A novel fuzzy assisted sliding mode control approach for frequency regulation of wind-supported autonomous microgrid. Sci. Rep. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-83202-z (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R., Singh, R., Ashfaq, H., Singh, S. K. &amp; Badoni, M. Power system stability enhancement by damping and control of sub-synchronous torsional oscillations using whale optimization algorithm based Type-2 wind turbines. ISA Trans. 108, 240&#x2013;56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isatra.2020.08.037 (2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>