<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41574210</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2197-1153</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of experimental orthopaedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exp Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Current concepts and future perspective of muscle function tests to inform return to sport decision-making after ACLR: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70643</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70643</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70643</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jeo2.70643</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">An injury to the anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) can be sustained in sports participation during situations such as offensive cutting, landing from a jump, or defensive pressing. Despite treatment with surgical reconstruction and/or rehabilitation, only 55%-84% of patients return to sport (RTS) after treatment, and second ACL injury rates remain as high as 25% in young athletes. To reduce the risk of second ACL injury, clinicians commonly use muscle strength tests, hop tests, and patient-reported outcomes (PROs) to evaluate readiness for RTS. These tools have become central in clinical decision-making, yet significant challenges remain. Current tests typically rely on limb symmetry index (LSI) thresholds, with &#x2265;90% LSI commonly recommended as a clearance criterion for RTS. However, these cut-offs have shown poor predictive value for second ACL injury risk and may be misleading. The LSI also fails to account for pre-injury strength, bilateral deficits, or compensatory movement strategies. Hop tests provide additional insights into explosiveness and load absorption but emphasise distance or repetitions rather than movement quality, missing key biomechanical risk factors. Similarly, while PROs aim to capture the psychological dimension of recovery, they cannot be used in isolation to determine readiness for RTS. Collectively, these evaluation tools provide only snapshots of recovery and do not adequately reflect the chaotic, multidimensional demands of sport. The research gap lies not in the absence of tests, but in their limited transferability, standardisation, and contextual relevance. Current tests should not be viewed as a simple pass-or-fail clearance point, but as guidance for informed decision-making in rehabilitation. Continuous evaluation across physical and psychological domains can help clinicians tailor progression, motivate patients, and support safer transitions toward sport. This narrative review explores the current state, limitations, and future directions of RTS testing in order the bridge the gap between clinical measures and the chaotic, high-demand realities of sport.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Level III.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Journal of Experimental Orthopaedics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamrin Senorski</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7025-7619</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Physiotherapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy University of Gothenburg Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piussi</LastName><ForeName>Ramana</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7586-5293</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Physiotherapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy University of Gothenburg Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xf6;gberg</LastName><ForeName>Johan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Physiotherapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy University of Gothenburg Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sundberg</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-9543-3188</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Physiotherapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy University of Gothenburg Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lindskog</LastName><ForeName>Jakob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-9146-0073</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Physiotherapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy University of Gothenburg Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prill</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4916-1206</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Orthopaedics and Traumatology University Hospital, Brandenburg/Havel, Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane Brandenburg an der Havel Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences Brandenburg Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane Brandenburg an der Havel Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamrin Senorski</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9340-0147</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Physiotherapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy University of Gothenburg Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center Gothenburg Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Swedish Olympic Committee Stockholm Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Exp Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653750</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2197-1153</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hop performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle function test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return to sport</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Eric Hamrin Senorski is the associate editor of Journal of Orthopeadic and Sports Physical Therapy. Authors Rebecca Hamrin Senorski, Ramana Piussi, Johan H&#xf6;gberg, Jakob Lindskog, Axel Sundberg or Robert Prill has no conflict of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41574210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12820797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jeo2.70643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JEO270643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ageberg E, Roos EM. The association between knee confidence and muscle power, hop performance, and postural orientation in people with anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2016;46(6):477&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27117728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al&#x2010;Gburi M, Kristiansen JB, Christensen KB, Krogsgaard MR. Functional performance tests, clinical measurements, and patient&#x2010;reported outcome measures do not correlate as outcomes 1 year after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(12):5905&#x2013;5912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10719130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37947829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida GPL, Albano TR, Rodrigues CAS, Tavares MLA, de Paula Lima PO. Combining return to sport, psychological readiness, body mass, hamstring strength symmetry, and hamstring/quadriceps ratio increases the risk of a second anterior cruciate ligament injury. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(11):5087&#x2013;5095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37728760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen LL, Aagaard P. Influence of maximal muscle strength and intrinsic muscle contractile properties on contractile rate of force development. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;96(1):46&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16249918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Webster KE. Fifty&#x2010;five per cent return to competitive sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: an updated systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis including aspects of physical functioning and contextual factors. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(21):1543&#x2013;1552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Whitehead TS, Webster KE. Psychological responses matter in returning to preinjury level of sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(7):1549&#x2013;1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23733635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Glasgow P, Schneiders A, Witvrouw E, Clarsen B, Cools A, et al. 2016 Consensus statement on return to sport from the First World Congress in Sports Physical Therapy, Bern. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(14):853&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arp K, Nedermark J, Ingwersen KG, Ageberg E, Varnum C, Viberg B. Which patients need anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction after initial treatment with rehabilitation? A scoping review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(2):500&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11792103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39045722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashnai F, Thome&#xe9; R, Hamrin Senorski E, Beischer S. Higher isokinetic quadriceps peak force is associated with a patient&#x2010;acceptable symptom&#x2010;state 1 and 3 years after ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(8):2847&#x2013;2865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12310089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39564974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni BM, Ruas CV, Ribeiro&#x2010;Alvares JB, Pinto RS. Hamstring&#x2010;to&#x2010;quadriceps torque ratios of professional male soccer players: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34(1):281&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29794893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beischer S, Gustavsson L, Senorski EH, Karlsson J, Thome&#xe9; C, Samuelsson K, et al. Young athletes who return to sport before 9 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction have a rate of new injury 7 times that of those who delay return. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2020;50(2):83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32005095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloch H, Krutsch W, Klein C, Achenbach L, Reinsberger C. ACL injuries in professional football (soccer): women face higher risk, later surgical care and longer time loss compared to men. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;1:ksa.70160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41182134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M. Optimising the late&#x2010;stage rehabilitation and return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport training and testing process after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):1043&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31004279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Wang L, Dong S, Ding Y, Jia S, Zheng C. Can symmetry of single&#x2010;leg vertical jump height represent normal lower limb biomechanics of athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Sports Health. 2024;16(4):596&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11195865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37554095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Villa F, Buckthorpe M, Grassi A, Nabiuzzi A, Tosarelli F, Zaffagnini S, et al. Systematic video analysis of ACL injuries in professional male football (soccer): injury mechanisms, situational patterns and biomechanics study on 134 consecutive cases. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(23):1423&#x2013;1432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Paolo S, Zaffagnini S, Tosarelli F, Grassi A, Della Villa F. Beyond distance: a simple qualitative assessment of the single&#x2010;leg hop test in return&#x2010;to&#x2010;play testing. Sports Health. 2022;14(6):906&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9631045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35081839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos'Santos T, McBurnie A, Donelon T, Thomas C, Comfort P, Jones PA. A qualitative screening tool to identify athletes with &#x2018;high&#x2010;risk&#x2019; movement mechanics during cutting: the cutting movement assessment score (CMAS). Physical Therapy in Sport. 2019;38:152&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31153108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draper JM. The 505 test: a test for agility in horizontal plane. 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert JR, Calvert ND, Radic R. Females demonstrate lower levels of activity, psychological readiness and strength symmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction than males, and also recovery of quadriceps strength and hop symmetry is delayed in females undergoing reconstruction with a quadriceps tendon autograft. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(10):2688&#x2013;2698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39126259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eppinga P, Welling W, Dekker R, Zwerver H. Return to performance criteria in soccer after musculoskeletal injury: a scoping review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;1:ksa.70180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41324447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faleide AGH, Inderhaug E. It is time to target psychological readiness (or lack of readiness) in return to sports after Anterior Cruciate Ligament tears. J Exp Orthop. 2023;10(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10511393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37728618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faleide AGH, Magnussen LH, Strand T, Bogen BE, Moe&#x2010;Nilssen R, Mo IF, et al. The role of psychological readiness in return to sport assessment after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(5):1236&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faleide AGH, Magnussen LH, Bogen BE, Strand T, Mo IF, Vervaat W, et al. Association between psychological readiness and knee laxity and their predictive value for return to sport in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(10):2599&#x2013;2606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34251870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xe4;ltstr&#xf6;m A, Kvist J, H&#xe4;gglund M. High risk of new knee injuries in female soccer players after primary anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction at 5&#x2010; to 10&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(13):3479&#x2013;3487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34623936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xe4;ltstr&#xf6;m A, Kvist J, H&#xe4;gglund M. Are we jumping to the wrong conclusions? Longer jumps and more hops in female football players who went on to sustain a primary or secondary ACL injury compared to those who did not. Sports Med Open. 2023;9(1):105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10638330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37947959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnier JJ, Shen Y, Huang H. Psychometric properties of patient&#x2010;reported outcome measures for use in patients with anterior cruciate ligament injuries: a systematic review. JBJS Reviews. 2018;6(4):e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29634589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geeslin AG, Moatshe G, Engebretsen L, Lind M, Hansson F, Stalman A, et al. Functional anterior cruciate ligament braces may have a role in select patient groups although there is presently limited evidence supporting or refuting their routine use: A scoping review of clinical practice guidelines and an updated bracing classification. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(7):1690&#x2013;1699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38651562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girdwood MA, Crossley KM, Patterson BE, Rio EK, Whitehead TS, Morris HG, et al. People are more variable than their hop test would suggest: hop performance and self&#x2010;reported outcomes over 11&#x2009;years following ACL reconstruction. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34(9):e14727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39289174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girdwood MA, Crossley KM, Rio EK, Patterson BE, Haberfield MJ, Couch JL, et al. Hop to it! A systematic review and longitudinal meta&#x2010;analysis of hop performance after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2025;55(1):101&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11787245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39414723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Dingenen B, Hewett TE. Rehabilitation and return to sport testing after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: where are we in 2022? Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(1):e77&#x2013;e82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Tosarelli F, Buckthorpe M, Della Villa F. Neurocognitive errors and noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries in professional male soccer players. J Athl Train. 2024;59(3):262&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10976343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Welling W, Benjaminse A, Lemmink K, Seil R, Zaffagnini S. A critical analysis of limb symmetry indices of hop tests in athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a case control study. Orthop Traumatol: Surg Res. 2017;103(6):947&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28428033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokeler A, Zandbergen MA, Hoogeslag RAG, Houten A, Nijmeijer EM, Heuvelmans P. Neurocognitive demands reduce jump distance and coordination variability of the injured leg in athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(4):1321&#x2013;1332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39189158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, Moksnes H, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after ACL reconstruction: the Delaware&#x2010;Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):804&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4912389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27162233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Logerstedt D, Eitzen I, Moksnes H, Axe MJ, Snyder&#x2010;Mackler L, et al. Single&#x2010;legged hop tests as predictors of self&#x2010;reported knee function in nonoperatively treated individuals with anterior cruciate ligament injury. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39(11):2347&#x2013;2354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3582365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grondin J, Crenn V, Gernigon M, Quinette Y, Louguet B, Menu P, et al. Relevant strength parameters to allow return to running after primary anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with hamstring tendon autograft. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(14):8245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35886096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grooms DR, Chaput M, Simon JE, Criss CR, Myer GD, Diekfuss JA. Combining neurocognitive and functional tests to improve return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport decisions following ACL reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2023;1(8):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10847844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37186672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustavsson A, Neeter C, Thome&#xe9; P, Gr&#xe4;vare Silbernagel K, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R, et al. A test battery for evaluating hop performance in patients with an ACL injury and patients who have undergone ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2006;14(8):778&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16525796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harbo T, Brincks J, Andersen H. Maximal isokinetic and isometric muscle strength of major muscle groups related to age, body mass, height, and sex in 178 healthy subjects. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(1):267&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21537927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper DJ, McBurnie AJ, Santos TD, Eriksrud O, Evans M, Cohen DD, et al. Biomechanical and neuromuscular performance requirements of horizontal deceleration: a review with implications for random intermittent multi&#x2010;directional sports. Sports Med. 2022;52(10):2321&#x2013;2354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9474351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35643876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;gberg J, Bergentoft E, Piussi R, Wernbom M, Beischer S, Simonson R, et al. Persistent knee flexor strength deficits identified through the NordBord eccentric test not seen with &#x201c;gold standard&#x201d; isokinetic concentric testing during the first year after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with a hamstring tendon autograft. Phys Ther Sport. 2022;55:119&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35339867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;gberg J, Piussi R, Wernbom M, Della Villa F, Simonsson R, Samuelsson K, et al. No association between hamstrings&#x2010;to&#x2010;quadriceps strength ratio and second ACL injuries after accounting for prognostic factors: a cohort study of 574 patients after ACL&#x2010;reconstruction. Sports Med Open. 2024;10(1):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10784243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38212594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang YL, Mulligan CMS, Johnson ST, Pollard CD, Hannigan K, Stutzenberger L, et al. Differential influence of quadriceps rate of torque development on single&#x2010; and double&#x2010;leg landing mechanics in anterior cruciate ligament reconstructed and control females. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(8):2013&#x2013;2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38686590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob G, Lim YP, Brito CA, Parker DA. Lateral extra&#x2010;articular tenodesis does not enhance ACL graft healing, however, does reduce graft tunnel widening. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(11):2885&#x2013;2894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38860740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaldau NC, Andersen FF, Barfod KW, Hersnaes PN, H&#xf6;lmich P. Return to badminton play following an ACL injury is common, but only a few return to previous performance. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(6):1507&#x2013;1515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keays SL, Mellifont DB, Keays AC, Stuelcken MC, Lovell DI, Sayers MGL. Long&#x2010;term return to sports after anterior cruciate ligament injury: reconstruction vs no reconstruction&#x2010;a comparison of 2 case series. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(4):912&#x2013;921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35148249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E, Blazevich AJ. Hamstrings force&#x2010;length relationships and their implications for angle&#x2010;specific joint torques: a narrative review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2022;14(1):166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9446565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36064431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellis E, Sahinis C, Baltzopoulos V. Is hamstrings&#x2010;to&#x2010;quadriceps torque ratio useful for predicting anterior cruciate ligament and hamstring injuries? A systematic and critical review. J Sport Health Sci. 2023;12(3):343&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10199143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Burland JP. Lower knee self&#x2010;efficacy is associated with greater asymmetries in quadriceps neuromuscular function and jump&#x2010;landing biomechanics post&#x2010;ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;1:ksa.70192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41235457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koga H, Nakamae A, Shima Y, Iwasa J, Myklebust G, Engebretsen L, et al. Mechanisms for noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries: knee joint kinematics in 10 injury situations from female team handball and basketball. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38(11):2218&#x2013;2225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20595545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrath JM, Vertullo CJ, Kennedy BA, Bush HS, Barrett RS, Lloyd DG. Morphologic characteristics and strength of the hamstring muscles remain altered at 2 years after use of a hamstring tendon graft in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(10):2589&#x2013;2598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27432052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Whiteley R, Van Rossom S, Korakakis V, Bahr R, Sideris V, et al. Single leg hop for distance symmetry masks lower limb biomechanics: time to discuss hop distance as decision criterion for return to sport after ACL reconstruction? Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(5):249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33687928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Van Rossom S, Whiteley R, Korakakis V, Bahr R, Sideris V, et al. Single leg vertical jump performance identifies knee function deficits at return to sport after ACL reconstruction in male athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(9):490&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9016240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Korakakis V, King E, Barbosa O, Maree D, Pantouveris M, et al. Aspetar clinical practice guideline on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(9):500&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krosshaug T, Slauterbeck JR, Engebretsen L, Bahr R. Biomechanical analysis of anterior cruciate ligament injury mechanisms: three&#x2010;dimensional motion reconstruction from video sequences. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2007;17(5):508&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17181770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krosshaug T, Nakamae A, Boden BP, Engebretsen L, Smith G, Slauterbeck JR, et al. Mechanisms of anterior cruciate ligament injury in basketball: video analysis of 39 cases. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(3):359&#x2013;367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17092928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvist J, Ek A, Sporrstedt K, Good L. Fear of re&#x2010;injury: a hindrance for returning to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2005;13(5):393&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15703963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyritsis P, Bahr R, Landreau P, Miladi R, Witvrouw E. Likelihood of ACL graft rupture: not meeting six clinical discharge criteria before return to sport is associated with a four times greater risk of rupture. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(15):946&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27215935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labban W, Manaseer T, Golberg E, Sommerfeldt M, Nathanail S, Dennett L, et al. Jumping into recovery: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of discriminatory and responsive force plate parameters in individuals following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction during countermovement and drop jumps. J Exp Orthop. 2024;11(2):e12018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10986632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logerstedt D, Grindem H, Lynch A, Eitzen I, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA, et al. Single&#x2010;legged hop tests as predictors of self&#x2010;reported knee function after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: the Delaware&#x2010;Oslo ACL cohort study. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(10):2348&#x2013;2356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundgaard&#x2010;Nielsen M, Herzog RB, Warming S, Rathcke MW, Magnusson SP, Krogsgaard MR. Good physical function but reduced quality of life in children 3 years after ACL reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(7):1725&#x2013;1733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38666741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch AD, Logerstedt DS, Grindem H, Eitzen I, Hicks GE, Axe MJ, et al. Consensus criteria for defining &#x2018;successful outcome&#x2019; after ACL injury and reconstruction: a Delaware&#x2010;Oslo ACL cohort investigation. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(5):335&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23881894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macri EM, Young JJ, Ingelsrud LH, Khan KM, Terluin B, Juhl CB, et al. Meaningful thresholds for patient&#x2010;reported outcomes following interventions for anterior cruciate ligament tear or traumatic meniscus injury: a systematic review for the OPTIKNEE consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(24):1432&#x2013;1444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35973755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, Folland J, Tillin N, Duchateau J. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(6):1091&#x2013;1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4875063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26941023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marieswaran M, Jain I, Garg B, Sharma V, Kalyanasundaram D. A review on biomechanics of anterior cruciate ligament and materials for reconstruction. Appl Bionics Biomech. 2018;2018(1):4657824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5971278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29861784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormick E, Gao Y, Geiger K, Glass NA, Leary S, Wolf BR, et al. Associations between graft choice and return to sports after primary anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction in athletes. Orthop J Sports Med. 2025;13(10):23259671251369005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12536117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41122276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherson AL, Feller JA, Hewett TE, Webster KE. Psychological readiness to return to sport is associated with second anterior cruciate ligament injuries. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(4):857&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30753794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van der Weegen W, van der Horst N. Quadriceps and hamstrings strength reference values for athletes with and without anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction who play popular pivoting sports, including soccer, basketball, and handball: a scoping review. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2022;52(3):142&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34972481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, Senorski EH, Kr&#xf3;likowska A, Prill R. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation: decades of change. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(4):1178&#x2013;1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39925169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messer DJ, Shield AJ, Williams MD, Timmins RG, Bourne MN. Hamstring muscle activation and morphology are significantly altered 1&#x2010;6 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with semitendinosus graft. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2020;28(3):733&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31030253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller B, Yabroudi MA, Lynch A, Lai CL, van Dijk CN, Fu FH, et al. Defining thresholds for the patient acceptable symptom state for the IKDC subjective knee form and KOOS for patients who underwent ACL reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(11):2820&#x2013;2826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27474383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderi A, Fallah Mohammadi M, Dehghan A, Baker JS. Psychosocial interventions seem redact kinesiophobia after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction but higher level of evidence is needed: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(12):5848&#x2013;5855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37973676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederer D, Keller M, Petersen W, Sch&#xfc;ttler KF, Efe T, Engeroff T, et al. Jump performance and hop function, kinesiophobia and return to sports are important prognostic factors for a subsequent injury after an anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a 2&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up cohort study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;34(1):338&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12747599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41144697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwachukwu BU, Adjei J, Rauck RC, Chahla J, Okoroha KR, Verma NN, et al. How much do psychological factors affect lack of return to play after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? A systematic review. Orthop J Sports Med. 2019;7(5):2325967119845313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31205965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogborn D, McRae S, Larose G, Leiter J, Brown H, MacDonald P. Knee flexor strength and symmetry vary by device, body position and angle of assessment following ACL reconstruction with hamstring grafts at long&#x2010;term follow&#x2010;up. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(5):1658&#x2013;1664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34477895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic M, Winkler PW, Karlsson J, Becker R, Prill R. Minimal clinically important difference: don&#x2032;t just look at the &#x201c;p&#x2010;value. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(10):4077&#x2013;4079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37460662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picinini F, Della Villa F, Tallent J, Patterson SD, Galassi L, Parigino M, et al. High return to competition rate after on&#x2010;field rehabilitation in competitive male soccer players after ACL reconstruction: GPS tracking in 100 consecutive cases. Orthop J Sports Med. 2025;13(3):23259671251320093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11881939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40052178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piussi R, Beischer S, Thome&#xe9; R, Hamrin Senorski E. Hop tests and psychological PROs provide a demanding and clinician&#x2010;friendly RTS assessment of patients after ACL reconstruction, a registry study. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2020;12:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7218571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32426142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piussi R, Beischer S, Thome&#xe9; R, Thome&#xe9; C, Sansone M, Samuelsson K, et al. Greater psychological readiness to return to sport, as well as greater present and future knee&#x2010;related self&#x2010;efficacy, can increase the risk for an anterior cruciate ligament re&#x2010;rupture: a matched cohort study. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(4):1267&#x2013;1276.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34571186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piussi R, Simonson R, Zsidai B, Grassi A, Karlsson J, Della Villa F, et al. Better safe than sorry? A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis on time to return to sport after ACL reconstruction as a risk factor for second ACL injury. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2023;54(3):161&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38032099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piussi R, Lindskog J, Hamrin Senorski R, Thome&#xe9; R, Samuelsson K, Hamrin Senorski E. Thresholds for minimum clinically important difference, minimal important change and patient acceptable symptom state for the ACL&#x2010;RSI and the K&#x2010;SES in patients after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;1:ksa.70044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40905284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill R, Janosky J, Bode L, van Melick N, Villa FD, Becker R, et al. Prevention of ACL injury is better than repair or reconstruction&#x2014;Implementing the ESSKA&#x2010;ESMA &#x2018;Prevention for All&#x2032; ACL programme. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1954&#x2013;1958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40260666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randsborg PH, Cepeda N, Adamec D, Rodeo SA, Ranawat A, Pearle AD. Patient&#x2010;reported outcome, return to sport, and revision rates 7&#x2010;9 years after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: results from a cohort of 2042 patients. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(2):423&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8829731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35040694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeqi M, Klouche S, Bohu Y, Herman S, Lefevre N, Gerometta A. Progression of the Psychological ACL&#x2010;RSI Score and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a prospective 2&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up study from the French Prospective Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Cohort Study (FAST). Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6(12):2325967118812819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30574516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senorski RH, Piussi R, H&#xf6;gberg R, Thome&#xe9; J, Samuelsson R, et al. Rehabilitation alone after ACL injury yields greater limb symmetry but lower knee related self&#x2010;efficacy without limiting return to preinjury activity level. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33(12):4435&#x2013;4445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12684339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40878596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi H, Huang H, Li H, Yu Y, Ren S, Liu H, et al. Angle&#x2010;specific analysis of isokinetic quadriceps and hamstring strength at 6 and 12 months after unilateral ACL reconstruction. Sports Health. 2025;17(4):792&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11569700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39108063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonson R, Piussi R, H&#xf6;gberg J, Senorski C, Thome&#xe9; R, Samuelsson K, et al. Effect of quadriceps and hamstring strength relative to body weight on risk of a second ACL injury: a cohort study of 835 patients who returned to sport after ACL reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2023;11(4):23259671231157386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10155024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37152619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonsson R, H&#xf6;gberg J, Lindskog J, Piussi R, Sundberg A, Sansone M, et al. A comparison between physical therapy clinics with high and low rehabilitation volumes of patients with ACL reconstruction. J Orthop Surg. 2023;18(1):842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10629052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37936163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonsson R, Sundberg A, Piussi R, H&#xf6;gberg J, Senorski C, Thome&#xe9; R, et al. Questioning the rules of engagement: a critical analysis of the use of limb symmetry index for safe return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2025;59(6):376&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11874420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinacore JA, Evans AM, Lynch BN, Joreitz RE, Irrgang JJ, Lynch AD. Diagnostic accuracy of handheld dynamometry and 1&#x2010;repetition&#x2010;maximum tests for identifying meaningful quadriceps strength asymmetries. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47(2):97&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28142362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater D, Kvist J, Ardern CL. Biopsychosocial factors associated with return to preinjury sport after ACL injury treated without reconstruction: NACOX cohort study 12&#x2010;month follow&#x2010;up. Sports Health. 2023;15(2):176&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9950991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35633030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AM. Psychological impact of injuries in athletes. Sports Med. 1996;22(6):391&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8969016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun B, Vivekanantha P, Khalik HA, Slawaska&#x2010;Eng D, Kay J, Johnson J, et al. Approximately half of pediatric or adolescent patients undergoing revision anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction return to the same level of sport or higher: a systematic review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(1):181&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38226741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki M, Ishida T, Matsumoto H, Kaneko S, Inoue C, Aoki Y, et al. Association of psychological readiness to return to sports with subjective level of return at 12 months after ACL reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2023;11(9):23259671231195030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10492488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37693806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szymski D, Achenbach L, Weber J, Huber L, Memmel C, Kerschbaum M, et al. Reduced performance after return to competition in ACL injuries: an analysis on return to competition in the &#x2018;ACL registry in German Football&#x2019;. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(1):133&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9859836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35819462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Y, Kaldau NC, Lumban&#x2010;Gaol I, Budhiparama NC, Peers K. Anterior cruciate ligament injuries in elite badminton athletes: 84% Return to sport, half return to performance. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(11):2978&#x2013;2998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38984858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thome&#xe9; P, W&#xe4;hrborg P, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Thome&#xe9; R, Eriksson BI, Karlsson J. Self&#x2010;efficacy of knee function as a pre&#x2010;operative predictor of outcome 1 year after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2008;16(2):118&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18034333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turpeinen JT, Freitas TT, Rubio&#x2010;Arias J&#xc1;, Jordan MJ, Aagaard P. Contractile rate of force development after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction&#x2010;a comprehensive review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(9):1572&#x2013;1585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32478931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Undheim MB, Cosgrave C, King E, Strike S, Marshall B, Falvey &#xc9;, et al. Isokinetic muscle strength and readiness to return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: is there an association? A systematic review and a protocol recommendation. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(20):1305&#x2013;1310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26105017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urhausen AP, Berg B, &#xd8;iestad BE, Whittaker JL, Culvenor AG, Crossley KM, et al. Measurement properties for muscle strength tests following anterior cruciate ligament and/or meniscus injury: what tests to use and where do we need to go? A systematic review with meta&#x2010;analyses for the OPTIKNEE consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(24):1422&#x2013;1431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36113973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vos FH, Meuffels DE, Baart SJ, van Es EM, Reijman M. Externally validated treatment algorithm acceptably predicts nonoperative treatment success in patients with anterior cruciate ligament rupture. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32(9):2228&#x2013;2238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38738823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wackerle AM, Joreitz R, Sprague A, Senorski EH, Halilaj E, Rabuck SJ, et al. Freddie Fu Panther Symposium Expert Group 2024: rehabilitation and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction Part 2: Concepts and emerging technology in return to sport. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;1:ksa.70110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41169247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wald&#xe9;n M, Krosshaug T, Bj&#xf8;rneboe J, Andersen TE, Faul O, H&#xe4;gglund M. Three distinct mechanisms predominate in non&#x2010;contact anterior cruciate ligament injuries in male professional football players: a systematic video analysis of 39 cases. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(22):1452&#x2013;1460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4680158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25907183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber M, M&#xfc;ller M, Mathieu&#x2010;K&#xe4;lin M, Caminada S, H&#xe4;berli M, Baur H. Evaluation of hop test movement quality to enhance return to sport testing. a cross&#x2010;sectional study. Front Sports Active Living. 2024;6:1305817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10944867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38500546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Hewett TE. What is the evidence for and validity of return&#x2010;to&#x2010;sport testing after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery? A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49(6):917&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30905035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West TJ, Bruder AM, Crossley KM, Culvenor AG. Unilateral tests of lower&#x2010;limb function as prognostic indicators of future knee&#x2010;related outcomes following anterior cruciate ligament injury: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of 13 150 adolescents and adults. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(13):855&#x2013;863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36669871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitworth N, Webster KE, Klemm HJ, McClelland JA, Batty LM, Kirby JC, et al. Impact of change in contralateral knee extensor strength on achieving limb symmetry index targets following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;1:ksa.70182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41235526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk KE, Arrigo CA, Davies GJ. Isokinetic testing: why it is more important today than ever. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19(4):374&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10987309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38576833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>