<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41392955</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-6848</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Soft matter</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Soft Matter</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Measurement of tissue viscosity to relate force and motion in collective cell migration.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>458</StartPage><EndPage>473</EndPage><MedlinePgn>458-473</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5sm01139f</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In tissue development, wound healing, and cancer invasion, coordinated cell motion arises from active forces produced by the cells. The relationship between force and motion remains unclear, however, because the forces result from a sum of contributions from activity and the constitutive response of the cell collective. Here, we develop a method to decouple the forces due to activity from those due to constitutive response. As a model of an epithelial tissue, we use a monolayer of epithelial cells in the fluid state, for which the constitutive behavior is that of a viscous fluid. By careful study of the distribution of the ratio between shear stress and strain rate, we show that the order of magnitude of viscosity within the epithelial tissue is 100 Pa h and that increasing (decreasing) the actomyosin cytoskeleton and cell-cell adhesions increase (decrease) the magnitude of tissue viscosity. These results establish tissue viscosity as a meaningful way to describe the mechanical behavior of epithelial tissues, and demonstrate a direct relationship between tissue microstructure and material properties. By providing the first experimental measurement of tissue viscosity, our study is a step toward separating the active and constitutive components of stress, in turn clarifying the relationship between force and motion and providing a new means of identifying how active cell forces evolve in space and time.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCord</LastName><ForeName>Molly</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA. jknotbohm@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biophysics Program, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Notbohm</LastName><ForeName>Jacob</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9836-4982</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA. jknotbohm@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biophysics Program, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R35 GM151171</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Soft Matter</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101295070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1744-683X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9013-26-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000205">Actomyosin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>ArXiv. 2025 Aug 15:arXiv:2508.11518v1.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">40832046</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014783" MajorTopicYN="N">Viscosity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cell Movement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004847" MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelial Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013314" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Mechanical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002448" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Adhesion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000205" MajorTopicYN="N">Actomyosin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003599" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytoskeleton</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Biological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest. There are no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41392955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2130553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12771545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5sm01139f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Friedl P and Gilmour D Collective cell migration in morphogenesis, regeneration and cancer. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol, 10(7):445&#x2013;457, 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19546857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, He Y, Zhao M, and Jiang J Collective cell migration: Implications for wound healing and cancer invasion. Burns &amp; Trauma, 1(1):21&#x2013;26, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J-A, Atia L, Mitchel JA, Fredberg JJ, and Butler JP Collective migration and cell jamming in asthma, cancer and development. J Cell Sci, 129(18):3375&#x2013;3383, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5047682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27550520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpa E and Mayor R Collective cell migration in development. J Cell Biol, 212(2):143&#x2013;155, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4738384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26783298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poujade M, Grasland-Mongrain E, Hertzog A, Jouanneau J, Chavrier P, Ladoux B, Buguin A, and Silberzan P Collective migration of an epithelial monolayer in response to a model wound. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 104(41):15988&#x2013;15993, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Picamal X, Conte V, Vincent R, Anon E, Tambe DT, Bazellieres E, Butler JP, Fredberg JJ, and Trepat X Mechanical waves during tissue expansion. Nat Phys, 8(8):628&#x2013;634, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J-A, Kim JH, Bi D, Mitchel JA, Qazvini NT, Tantisira K, Park CY, McGill M, Kim S-H, Gweon B, Notbohm J, Steward R Jr., Burger S, Randell SH, Kho AT, Tambe DT, Hardin C, Shore SA, Israel E, Weitz DA, Tschumperlin DJ, Henske EP, Weiss ST, Manning ML, Butler JP, Drazen JM, and Fredberg JJ Unjamming and cell shape in the asthmatic airway epithelium. Nat Mater, 14(10):1040&#x2013;1048, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26237129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notbohm J, Banerjee S, Utuje KJ, Gweon B, Jang H, Park Y, Shin J, Butler JP, Fredberg JJ, and Marchetti MC Cellular contraction and polarization drive collective cellular motion. Biophys J, 110(12):2729&#x2013;2738, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4919426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27332131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malinverno C, Corallino S, Giavazzi F, Bergert M, Li Q, Leoni M, and Disanza A Endocytic reawakening of motility in jammed epithelia. Nat Mater, 16(5):587&#x2013;596, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mongera A, Rowghanian P, Gustafson HJ, Shelton E, Kealhofer DA, Carn EK, Serwane F, Lucio AA, Giammona J, and Camp&#xe0;s O A fluid-to-solid jamming transition underlies vertebrate body axis elongation. Nature, 561(7723):401&#x2013;405, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6148385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30185907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe5;ng E, L&#xe5;ng A, Blicher P, Rognes T, Dommersnes PG, and B&#xf8;e SO Topology-guided polar ordering of collective cell migration. Sci Adv, 10(16):eadk4825, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11023523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38630812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, O&#x2019;Byrne J, Schoenit A, Maitra A, M&#xe8;ge R-M, Voituriez R, and Ladoux B Flocking and giant fluctuations in epithelial active solids. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 122(16):e2421327122, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel V and Sheetz M Local force and geometry sensing regulate cell functions. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol, 7(4):265&#x2013;275, 2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16607289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladoux B and M&#xe8;ge R-M Mechanobiology of collective cell behaviours. Nat Rev Mol Cell Bio, 18(12):743&#x2013;757, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29115298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dembo M and Wang YL Stresses at the cell-to-substrate interface during locomotion of fibroblasts. Biophys J, 76(4):2307&#x2013;2316, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler JP, Tolic-Norrelykke IM, Fabry B, and Fredberg JJ Traction fields, moments, and strain energy that cells exert on their surroundings. Am J Physiol Cell Ph, 282(3):C595&#x2013;C605, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trepat X, Wasserman MR, Angelini TE, Millet E, Weitz DA, Butler JP, and Fredberg JJ Physical forces during collective cell migration. Nat Phys, 5(6):426&#x2013;430, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tambe DT, Hardin CC, Angelini TE, Rajendran K, Park CY, Serra-Picamal X, Zhou EH, Zaman MH, Butler JP, Weitz DA, Fredberg JJ, and Trepat X Collective cell guidance by cooperative intercellular forces. Nat Mater, 10(6):469&#x2013;475, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3135682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21602808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tambe DT, Croutelle U, Trepat X, Park CY, Kim JH, Millet E, Butler JP, and Fredberg JJ Monolayer stress microscopy: limitations, artifacts, and accuracy of recovered intercellular stresses. Plos One, 8(2):e55172, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3585344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alert R and Trepat X Physical models of collective cell migration. Annu Rev Condens Matter Phys, 11(1):77&#x2013;101, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia S, Hannezo E, Elgeti J, Joanny J-F, Silberzan P, and Gov NS Physics of active jamming during collective cellular motion in a monolayer. Proc Natl Acad Sci, 112(50):15314&#x2013;15319, 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4687586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26627719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann J, Camley BA, Rappel W-J, and Levine H Contact inhibition of locomotion determines cell&#x2013;cell and cell&#x2013;substrate forces in tissues. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 113(10):2660&#x2013;2665, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi D, Yang X, Marchetti MC, and Manning ML Motility-driven glass and jamming transitions in biological tissues. Phys Rev X, 6(2):021011, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5619672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28966874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton DL, Henkes S, Weijer CJ, and Sknepnek R Active Vertex Model for cell-resolution description of epithelial tissue mechanics. Plos Comput Biol, 13(6):e1005569, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5493290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28665934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalilgharibi N, Fouchard J, Asadipour N, Barrientos R, Duda M, Bonfanti A, Yonis A, Harris A, Mosaffa P, Fujita Y, Kabla A, Mao Y, Baum B, Mu&#xf1;oz JJ, Miodownik M, and Charras G Stress relaxation in epithelial monolayers is controlled by the actomyosin cortex. Nature Physics, 15(8):839&#x2013;847, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Beco S, Gueudry C, Amblard F, and Coscoy S Endocytosis is required for E-cadherin redistribution at mature adherens junctions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 106(17):7010&#x2013;7015, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris AR, Peter L, Bellis J, Baum B, Kabla AJ, and Charras GT Characterizing the mechanics of cultured cell monolayers. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 109(41):16449&#x2013;16454, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oriola D, Alert R, and Casademunt J Fluidization and Active Thinning by Molecular Kinetics in Active Gels. Physical Review Letters, 118(8):088002, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28282157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishwakarma M, Di Russo J, Probst D, Schwarz US, Das T, and Spatz JP Mechanical interactions among followers determine the emergence of leaders in migrating epithelial cell collectives. Nat Commun, 9(1):3469, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6110746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30150695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathibhatla A, Henkes S, Galles EE, Sknepnek R, and Notbohm J Coordinated tractions increase the size of a collectively moving pack in a cell monolayer. Extreme Mech Lett, 48:101438, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Russo J, Young JL, Wegner JW, Steins T, Kessler H, and Spatz JP
Integrin <i>&#x3b1;</i>5<i>&#x3b2;</i>1 nano-presentation regulates collective keratinocyte migration independent of substrate rigidity. elife, 10:e69861, 2021.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8460267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez K, Saraswathibhatla A, and Notbohm J Effect of substrate stiffness on friction in collective cell migration. Sci Rep, 12(1):2436, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35136184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alert R, Blanch-Mercader C, and Casademunt J Active fingering instability in tissue spreading. Phys Rev Lett, 122(8):088104, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30932560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Serra-Picamal X, Tambe DT, Zhou EH, Park CY, Sadati M, Park J-A, Krishnan R, Gweon B, Millet E, Butler JP, Trepat X, and Fredberg JJ Propulsion and navigation within the advancing monolayer sheet. Nat Mater, 12(9):856&#x2013;863, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23793160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bera PK, McCord M, Zhang J, and Notbohm J Traction and stress control formation and motion of +1/2 topological defects in epithelial cell monolayers. Newton, page 100231, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12416539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40926784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCord M and Notbohm J Energy injection in an epithelial cell monolayer via negative viscosity. arXiv preprint arXiv:2501.03401, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sep&#xfa;lveda N, Petitjean L, Cochet O, Grasland-Mongrain E, Silberzan P, and Hakim V Collective cell motion in an epithelial sheet can be quantitatively described by a stochastic interacting particle model. Plos Comput Biol, 9(3):e1002944, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3591275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23505356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mark S, Shlomovitz R, Gov NS, Poujade M, Grasland-Mongrain E, and Silberzan P Physical model of the dynamic instability in an expanding cell culture. Biophys J, 98(3):361&#x2013;370, 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2814206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20141748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y and Levine H Leader-cell-driven epithelial sheet fingering. Phys Biol, 17(4):046003, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kammeraat SC, Keta Y-E, Appleton P, Newton IP, Liverpool TB, Sknepnek R, N&#xe4;thke I, and Henkes S Correlated cell movements drive epithelial finger formation. arXiv preprint arXiv:2508.01046, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reffay M, Parrini M-C, Cochet-Escartin O, Ladoux B, Buguin A, Coscoy S, Amblard F, Camonis J, and Silberzan P Interplay of RhoA and mechanical forces in collective cell migration driven by leader cells. Nat Cell Biol, 16(3):217&#x2013;223, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24561621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petitjean L, Reffay M, Grasland-Mongrain E, Poujade M, Ladoux B, Buguin A, and Silberzan P Velocity fields in a collectively migrating epithelium. Biophys J, 98(9):1790&#x2013;1800, 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2862185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20441742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravasio A, Le AP, Saw TB, Tarle V, Ong HT, Bertocchi C, M&#xe8;ge R-M, Lim CT, Gov NS, and Ladoux B Regulation of epithelial cell organization by tuning cell-substrate adhesion. Integr Biol, 7(10):1228&#x2013;1241, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathibhatla A and Notbohm J Tractions and stress fibers control cell shape and rearrangements in collective cell migration. Phys Rev X, 10(1):011016, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathibhatla A, Zhang J, and Notbohm J Coordination of contractile tension and cell area changes in an epithelial cell monolayer. Phys Rev E, 105(2):024404, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35291100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi D, Lopez J, Schwarz JM, and Manning ML A density-independent rigidity transition in biological tissues. Nat Phys, 11(12):1074&#x2013;1079, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabry B, Maksym GN, Butler JP, Glogauer M, Navajas D, and Fredberg JJ Scaling the Microrheology of Living Cells. Physical Review Letters, 87(14):148102, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11580676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabry B, Maksym GN, Butler JP, Glogauer M, Navajas D, Taback NA, Millet EJ, and Fredberg JJ Time scale and other invariants of integrative mechanical behavior in living cells. Physical Review E, 68(4):041914, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno D, Tardin C, Schmidt CF, and MacKintosh FC Nonequilibrium Mechanics of Active Cytoskeletal Networks. Science, 315(5810):370&#x2013;373, 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17234946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanch-Mercader C, Vincent R, Bazelli&#xe8;res E, Serra-Picamal X, Trepat X, and Casademunt J Effective viscosity and dynamics of spreading epithelia: a solvable model. Soft Matter, 13(6):1235&#x2013;1243, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28098306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton TA, Mang HE, and Atkinson SJ Rho-kinase regulates myosin II activation in MDCK cells during recovery after ATP depletion. American Journal of Physiology-Renal Physiology, 281(5):F810&#x2013;F818, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11592938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Tolic-N&#xf8;rrelykke IM, Chen J, Mijailovich SM, Butler JP, Fredberg JJ, and Stamenovic D Cell prestress. I. Stiffness and prestress are closely associated in adherent contractile cells. Am J Physiol Cell Phiol, 282(3):C606&#x2013;C616, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goeckeler Z, Bridgman P, and Wysolmerski R Nonmuscle myosin II is responsible for maintaining endothelial cell basal tone and stress fiber integrity. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol, 295(4):C994&#x2013;C1006, 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2575828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18701651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi D, Gonzalez Z, Ho SY, Bermudez A, and Lin NY Cell-cell adhesion impacts epithelia response to substrate stiffness: Morphology and gene expression. Biophys J, 121(2):336&#x2013;346, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8790207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34864047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchetti MC, Joanny J-F, Ramaswamy S, Liverpool TB, Prost J, Rao M, and Simha RA Hydrodynamics of soft active matter. Rev Mod Phys, 85(3):1143, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclos G, Erlenk&#xe4;mper C, Joanny J-F, and Silberzan P Topological defects in confined populations of spindle-shaped cells. Nat Phys, 13(1):58&#x2013;62, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez C, Alert R, Blanch-Mercader C, G&#xf3;mez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Kolodziej T, Bazellieres E, Casademunt J, and Trepat X Active wetting of epithelial tissues. Nat Phys, 15(1):79&#x2013;88, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6753015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmottant P, Mgharbel A, K&#xe4;fer J, Audren B, Rieu J-P, Vial J-C, van der Sanden B, Mar&#xe9;e AFM, Graner F, and Delano&#xeb;-Ayari H The role of fluctuations and stress on the effective viscosity of cell aggregates. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 106(41):17271&#x2013;17275, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guevorkian K, Colbert M-J, Durth M, Dufour S, and Brochard-Wyart F Aspiration of biological viscoelastic drops. Phys Rev Lett, 104(21):218101, 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20867138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochet-Escartin O, Ranft J, Silberzan P, and Marcq P Border forces and friction control epithelial closure dynamics. Biophys J, 106(1):65&#x2013;73, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3907253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24411238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duclos G, Blanch-Mercader C, Yashunsky V, Salbreux G, Joanny J-F, Prost J, and Silberzan P Spontaneous shear flow in confined cellular nematics. Nat Phys, 14(7):728&#x2013;732, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6071846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30079095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alert R and Casademunt J Role of substrate stiffness in tissue spreading: Wetting transition and tissue durotaxis. Langmuir, 35(23):7571&#x2013;7577, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30281318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez C, Alert R, Blanch-Mercader C, G&#xf3;mez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Kolodziej T, Bazellieres E, Casademunt J, and Trepat X Active wetting of epithelial tissues. Nat Phys, 15(1):79&#x2013;88, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6753015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31537984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraswathibhatla A, Galles EE, and Notbohm J Spatiotemporal force and motion in collective cell migration. Sci Data, 7(1):197, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7314837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32581285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begnaud S, Chen T, Delacour D, M&#xe8;ge R-M, and Ladoux B Mechanics of epithelial tissues during gap closure. Curr Opin Cell Biol, 42:52&#x2013;62, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5428743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27131272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treloar KK and Simpson MJ Sensitivity of Edge Detection Methods for Quantifying Cell Migration Assays. Plos One, 8(6):e67389, 2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3691172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23826283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo CW, Chueh D-Y, and Chen P Investigation of size&#x2013;dependent cell adhesion on nanostructured interfaces. J Nanobiotechnology, 12:54, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4265325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25477150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stringer C, Wang T, Michaelos M, and Pachitariu M Cellpose: A generalist algorithm for cellular segmentation. Nat Methods, 18(1):100&#x2013;106, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33318659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mashburn DN, Lynch HE, Ma X, and Hutson MS Enabling user-guided segmentation and tracking of surface-labeled cells in time-lapse image sets of living tissues. Cytometry Part A, 81A(5):409&#x2013;418, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Kochba E, Toyjanova J, Andrews E, Kim K-S, and Franck C A fast iterative digital volume correlation algorithm for large deformations. Exp Mech, 55(1):261&#x2013;274, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Alamo JC, Meili R, Alonso-Latorre B, Rodriguez-Rodriguez J, Aliseda A, Firtel RA, and Lasheras JC Spatio-temporal analysis of eukaryotic cell motility by improved force cytometry. P Natl Acad Sci USA, 104(33):13343&#x2013;13348, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelling J, Sauer U, Szallasi Z, Doyle FJ, and Doyle J Robustness of cellular functions. Cell, 118(6):675&#x2013;685, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15369668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron S, Caplanusi A, van de Ven M, Radu M, Despa S, Lambrichts I, Ameloot M, Steels P, and Smets I Role of mitochondrial Na+ concentration, measured by CoroNa red, in the protection of metabolically inhibited MDCK cells. J Am Soc Nephrol, 16(12):3490, 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16221870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>