<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41656937</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>98</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Global, Regional, and National Time Trends in Incidence for Hepatitis A, 1990-2021: A Systematic Analysis for the Global Burden of Disease 2021 Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70838</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70838</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.70838</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hepatitis A is the most common form of acute viral hepatitis, and its control is critical to achieving the 2030 viral hepatitis elimination target. We conducted a comprehensive assessment of hepatitis A incidence across 204 countries and regions from 1990 to 2021. Annual incident cases and age-standardized incidence rates (ASIR) of hepatitis A were obtained from the Global Burden of Disease (GBD) study 2021. Joinpoint regression analysis evaluated long-term trends in ASIR, while Age-Period-Cohort (APC) analysis assessed the independent effects of age, period, and cohort. Decomposition analysis determined the drivers behind temporal changes in disease incidence. The Slope Index of Inequality (SII) and Concentration Index (CI) were employed to quantify cross-national inequalities in incidence. From 1990 to 2021, global hepatitis A cases declined by 7.25%, with age-standardized incidence rates (ASIR) demonstrating a universal downward trend. The most substantial ASIR reductions occurred in low-middle socio-demographic index (SDI) quintiles, whereas low-SDI quintiles showed paradoxical ASIR declines (AAPC: -1.56 95% CI: -1.71 to -1.40) alongside a 39.44% (95%UI: 28.04 to 50.48) case surge. Cases remained concentrated in children under 5. The age-period-cohort analysis confirmed highest risk in young children, with period and cohort risks declining over time. Decomposition analysis identified population growth as the primary driver of case increases. Health inequality analysis showed persistent absolute disparities despite relative improvements. Although global hepatitis A incidence has declined over three decades, trends are highly heterogeneous and significant inequalities persist. Achieving equitable burden reduction requires differentiated strategies and enhanced international collaboration, particularly for low-resource settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Aodi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0900-8570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute of Infectious Disease and Biosecurity, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Xia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Municipal Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peoples Armed Police Force Wuhan Special Service Recuperation Center, Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006506" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hepatitis A</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071219" MajorTopicYN="Y">Global Burden of Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="N">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014943" MajorTopicYN="N">Global Health</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012959" MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatitis A</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">age&#x2010;period&#x2010;cohort</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">age&#x2010;standardized incidence rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decomposition analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health inequities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trend</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41656937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.70838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>R. S. Koff, &#x201c;Hepatitis A,&#x201d; Lancet 351, no. 9116 (1998): 1643&#x2013;1649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Franco, &#x201c;Hepatitis A: Epidemiology and Prevention in Developing Countries,&#x201d; World Journal of Hepatology 4, no. 3 (2012): 68&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Lemon, J. J. Ott, P. Van Damme, and D. Shouval, &#x201c;Type A Viral Hepatitis: A Summary and Update on the Molecular Virology, Epidemiology, Pathogenesis and Prevention,&#x201d; Journal of Hepatology 68 (2018): 167&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. B. Keeffe, &#x201c;Hepatitis A and B Superimposed on Chronic Liver Disease: Vaccine&#x2010;Preventable Diseases,&#x201d; Transactions of the American Clinical and Climatological Association 117 (2006): 227&#x2013;237; discussion 37&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Cao, W. Jing, J. Liu, and M. Liu, &#x201c;The Global Trends and Regional Differences in Incidence and Mortality of Hepatitis A From 1990 to 2019 and Implications for Its Prevention,&#x201d; Hepatology International 15, no. 5 (2021): 1068&#x2013;1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Van Damme, R. M. Pint&#xf3;, Z. Feng, F. Cui, A. Gentile, and D. Shouval, &#x201c;Hepatitis A Virus Infection,&#x201d; Nature Reviews Disease Primers 9, no. 1 (2023): 51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, &#x201c;Introduction of Hepatitis A Vaccine,&#x201d; accessed March 5, 2025, https://immunizationdata.who.int/global/wiise-detail-page/introduction-of-hepatitis-a-vaccine?ISO_3_CODE=&amp;YEAR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. H. Jacobsen, &#x201c;Globalization and the Changing Epidemiology of Hepatitis A Virus,&#x201d; Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine 8, no. 10 (2018): a031716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. H. Jacobsen and S. T. Wiersma, &#x201c;Hepatitis A Virus Seroprevalence by Age and World Region, 1990 and 2005,&#x201d; Vaccine 28, no. 41 (2010): 6653&#x2013;6657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Beaute, T. Westrell, D. Schmid, et al., &#x201c;Travel&#x2010;Associated Hepatitis A in Europe, 2009 to 2015,&#x201d; Euro Surveillance 23, no. 22 (2018): 1700583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. Wenzel and F. Allerberger, &#x201c;Hepatitis A as a Foodborne Infection,&#x201d; Lancet Infectious Diseases 14, no. 10 (2014): 907&#x2013;908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. B. D. Diseases and C. Injuries, &#x201c;Global Incidence, Prevalence, Years Lived With Disability (YLDs), Disability&#x2010;Adjusted Life&#x2010;Years (DALYs), and Healthy Life Expectancy (HALE) for 371 Diseases and Injuries in 204 Countries and Territories and 811 Subnational Locations, 1990&#x2010;2021: A Systematic Analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021,&#x201d; Lancet (London, England) 403, no. 10440 (2024): 2133&#x2013;2161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Naghavi, K. L. Ong, A. Aali, et al., Collaborators GBDCoD., &#x201c;Global Burden of 288 Causes of Death and Life Expectancy Decomposition in 204 Countries and Territories and 811 Subnational Locations, 1990&#x2010;2021: a Systematic Analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021,&#x201d; Lancet 403, no. 10440 (2024): 2100&#x2013;2132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, X. Cao, S. Xu, et al., &#x201c;Global, Regional, and National Burden of Retinoblastoma in Infants and Young Children: Findings From the Global Burden of Disease Study 1990&#x2013;2021,&#x201d; EClinicalMedicine 76 (2024): 102860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Bai, J. Han, J. An, et al., &#x201c;The Global, Regional, and National Patterns of Change in the Burden of Congenital Birth Defects, 1990&#x2013;2021: An Analysis of the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021 and Forecast to 2040,&#x201d; EClinicalMedicine 77 (2024): 102873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zou, G. Liu, S. I. Hay, et al., &#x201c;Time Trends in Tuberculosis Mortality Across the BRICS: An Age&#x2010;Period&#x2010;Cohort Analysis for the GBD 2019,&#x201d; EClinicalMedicine 53 (2022): 101646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. S. Rosenberg, D. P. Check, and W. F. Anderson, &#x201c;A Web Tool for Age&#x2013;Period&#x2013;Cohort Analysis of Cancer Incidence and Mortality Rates,&#x201d; Cancer Epidemiology, Biomarkers &amp; Prevention 23, no. 11 (2014): 2296&#x2013;2302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Liu, M. Luo, Y. Huang, Y. Tan, F. Cheng, and Y. Wu, &#x201c;Time Trends in Anxiety Disorders Incidence Across the BRICS: An Age&#x2010;Period&#x2010;Cohort Analysis for the GBD 2021,&#x201d; Frontiers in Public Health 12 (2024): 1467385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Cheng, L. Tan, Y. Gao, Y. Yang, D. C. Schwebel, and G. Hu, &#x201c;A New Method to Attribute Differences in Total Deaths Between Groups to Population Size, Age Structure and Age&#x2010;Specific Mortality Rate,&#x201d; PLoS One 14, no. 5 (2019): e0216613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhu, S. Li, X. Li, L. Wang, L. Du, and Y. Qiu, &#x201c;Impact of Population Ageing on Cancer&#x2010;Related Disability&#x2010;Adjusted Life Years: A Global Decomposition Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Global Health 14 (2024): 04144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. H. Organization, Handbook on Health Inequality Monitoring: With A Special Focus on Low&#x2010;and Middle&#x2010;Income Countries (World Health Organization, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Liang, S. Z. Xi, J. Y. Liu, et al., &#x201c;Global Burden and Cross&#x2010;Country Inequalities of Nutritional Deficiencies in Adults Aged 65 Years and Older, 1990&#x2010;2021: Population&#x2010;Based Study Using the GBD 2021,&#x201d; BMC Geriatrics 25, no. 1 (2025): 74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. S. Cooke, I. Andrieux&#x2010;Meyer, T. L. Applegate, et al., &#x201c;Accelerating the Elimination of Viral Hepatitis: A Lancet Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology Commission,&#x201d; Lancet Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology 4, no. 2 (2019): 135&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wu, P. Wang, Y. Huang, et al., &#x201c;Assessing the Effectiveness of the Expanded Hepatitis A Vaccination Program in China: An Interrupted Time Series Design,&#x201d; BMJ Global Health 9, no. 2 (2024): e013444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Wang, X. Sun, F. Wang, et al., &#x201c;Changing Epidemiology of Hepatitis A in China: Evidence From Three National Serological Surveys and the National Notifiable Disease Reporting System,&#x201d; Hepatology 73, no. 4 (2021): 1251&#x2013;1260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. H. Jacobsen and J. S. Koopman, &#x201c;Declining Hepatitis A Seroprevalence: A Global Review and Analysis,&#x201d; Epidemiology and Infection 132, no. 6 (2004): 1005&#x2013;1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. V. Murphy, M. M. Denniston, H. A. Hill, et al., &#x201c;Progress Toward Eliminating Hepatitis A Disease in the United States,&#x201d; MMWR Supplements 65, no. 1 (2016): 29&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Doshani, M. Weng, K. L. Moore, J. R. Romero, and N. P. Nelson, &#x201c;Recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices for Use of Hepatitis A Vaccine for Persons Experiencing Homelessness,&#x201d; MMWR: Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report 68, no. 6 (2019): 153&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. G. Regan, J. G. Wood, C. Benevent, et al., &#x201c;Estimating the Critical Immunity Threshold for Preventing Hepatitis A Outbreaks in Men Who Have Sex With Men,&#x201d; Epidemiology and Infection 144, no. 7 (2016): 1528&#x2013;1537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Steffen, &#x201c;Epidemiology and Prevention of Hepatitis A in Travelers,&#x201d; JAMA: The Journal of the American Medical Association 272, no. 11 (1994): 885&#x2013;889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. P. Nelson, M. K. Weng, M. G. Hofmeister, et al., &#x201c;Prevention of Hepatitis A Virus Infection in the United States: Recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, 2020,&#x201d; MMWR: Recommendations and Reports 69, no. 5 (2020): 1&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. G. Hofmeister, J. Xing, M. A. Foster, et al., &#x201c;Factors Associated With Hepatitis A Mortality During Person&#x2010;To&#x2010;Person Outbreaks: A Matched Case&#x2010;Control Study&#x2010;United States, 2016&#x2010;2019,&#x201d; Hepatology 74, no. 1 (2021): 28&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Ruscher, M. Faber, D. Werber, et al., &#x201c;Resurgence of An International Hepatitis A Outbreak Linked to Imported Frozen Strawberries, Germany, 2018 to 2020,&#x201d; Eurosurveillance 25, no. 37 (2020): 1900670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. G. Hofmeister, M. A. Foster, and E. H. Teshale, &#x201c;Epidemiology and Transmission of Hepatitis A Virus and Hepatitis E Virus Infections in the United States,&#x201d; Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine 9, no. 4 (2019): a033431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Dureab, M. Al&#x2010;Sakkaf, O. Ismail, et al., &#x201c;Diphtheria Outbreak in Yemen: The Impact of Conflict on a Fragile Health System,&#x201d; Conflict and Health 13 (2019): 19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Franco, &#x201c;Hepatitis B: Epidemiology and Prevention in Developing Countries,&#x201d; World Journal of Hepatology 4, no. 3 (2012): 74&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. A. Tay and R. T. A. Ocansey, &#x201c;Impact of Urbanization on Health and Well&#x2010;Being in Ghana. Status of Research, Intervention Strategies and Future Directions: A Rapid Review,&#x201d; Frontiers in Public Health 10 (2022): 877920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. E. Re, E. Ridruejo, A. C. Fantilli, B. D. Moutinho, M. B. Pisano, and M. G. Pessoa, &#x201c;Hepatitis A in Latin America: The Current Scenario,&#x201d; Reviews in Medical Virology 34, no. 4 (2024): e2566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McMichael, &#x201c;Water, Sanitation and Hygiene (WASH) in Schools in Low&#x2010;Income Countries: A Review of Evidence of Impact,&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 16, no. 3 (2019): 359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. W. Ming, Z. Yang, Z. L. Yan, et al., &#x201c;Impact of Urbanization on Morbidity of Hepatitis A: A National Panel Study in China During 2005&#x2013;2018,&#x201d; Infectious Diseases of Poverty 12, no. 1 (2023): 56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Devakumar, M. Birch, D. Osrin, E. Sondorp, and J. C. Wells, &#x201c;The Intergenerational Effects of War on the Health of Children,&#x201d; BMC Medicine 12 (2014): 57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations, Transforming our World: The 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, accessed August 26, 2015, https://sdgs.un.org/2030agenda.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Cui, S. C. Hadler, H. Zheng, et al., &#x201c;Hepatitis A Surveillance and Vaccine Use in China From 1990 Through 2007,&#x201d; Journal of Epidemiology 19, no. 4 (2009): 189&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Vizzotti, J. Gonz&#xe1;lez, A. Gentile, et al., &#x201c;Impact of the Single&#x2010;Dose Immunization Strategy Against Hepatitis A in Argentina,&#x201d; Pediatric Infectious Disease Journal 33, no. 1 (2014): 84&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Estripeaut, R. Contreras, O. Tinajeros, et al., &#x201c;Impact of Hepatitis A Vaccination With a Two&#x2010;Dose Schedule in Panama: Results of Epidemiological Surveillance and Time Trend Analysis,&#x201d; Vaccine 33, no. 28 (2015): 3200&#x2013;3207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. R. Behera, H. S. Pradhan, D. Behera, D. Jena, and S. K. Satpathy, &#x201c;Achievements and Challenges of India's Sanitation Campaign Under Clean India Mission: A Commentary,&#x201d; Journal of Education and Health Promotion 10 (2021): 350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Ayanore, N. Amuna, M. Aviisah, et al., &#x201c;Towards Resilient Health Systems in Sub&#x2010;Saharan Africa: A Systematic Review of the English Language Literature on Health Workforce, Surveillance, and Health Governance Issues for Health Systems Strengthening,&#x201d; Annals of Global Health 85, no. 1 (2019): 113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Y. Zeng, J. M. Li, S. Lin, et al., &#x201c;Global Burden of Acute Viral Hepatitis and Its Association With Socioeconomic Development Status, 1990&#x2010;2019,&#x201d; Journal of Hepatology 75, no. 3 (2021): 547&#x2013;556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Vos, S. S. Lim, C. Abbafati, et al., &#x201c;Global Burden of 369 Diseases and Injuries in 204 Countries and Territories, 1990&#x2010;2019: A Systematic Analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019,&#x201d; Lancet 396, no. 10258 (2020): 1204&#x2013;1222.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>