<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41536390</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Distinguishing Between AI-Generated and Human-Written Electronic Residency Application Service (ERAS) Personal Statements in Otolaryngology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e99202</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e99202</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e99202</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.99202</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Generative AI tools, such as ChatGPT, raise concerns about authenticity and fairness in residency applications. Since the transition of USMLE Step 1 to pass/fail, residency programs have placed greater emphasis on qualitative components such as the personal statement. The integrity of this document is critical, as it informs interview invitations and final rank decisions. However, it remains unclear whether reviewers can reliably distinguish AI-generated from human-written content and how this may affect the residency selection process. Objective In this small pilot study, we evaluated the ability of generative AI, specifically ChatGPT 4.0 (OpenAI, Inc., San Francisco, CA, USA), to produce convincing personal statements for otolaryngology residency applications and explored whether a limited sample of expert reviewers could distinguish AI-generated from human-written content. We used 2019 applicant-written statements because they predated the widespread availability of generative AI, ensuring a true "human-only" comparison group. Methods In 2024, ChatGPT was given a sophisticated and detailed prompt to generate five otolaryngology residency personal statements. These were combined with five de-identified, applicant-written statements submitted in 2019. Four otolaryngologists from a single academic medical center and four attorneys, blinded to the origin of the statements, rated them using a standardized rubric for readability, originality, persuasiveness, and interview desirability. An AI detection tool (Scribbr, Amsterdam, The Netherlands) also analyzed each statement. Statistical analyses included paired t-tests and inter-rater reliability assessment. Results Eight blinded reviewers (four otolaryngologists and four attorneys) evaluated 10 personal statements (five AI-generated and five human-written). Mean ratings for readability (AI 3.63 &#xb1; 0.22 vs. human 3.53 &#xb1; 0.40), originality (3.65 &#xb1; 0.16 vs. 3.53 &#xb1; 0.39), persuasiveness (3.35 &#xb1; 0.76 vs. 3.43 &#xb1; 0.36), and interview desirability (3.40 &#xb1; 0.51 vs. 3.30 &#xb1; 0.58) showed no significant differences (all P &gt; 0.05), but given the small sample size, the study was underpowered (post hoc estimated power 14.1% for medium effect size), limiting the ability to detect statistically significant differences. Inter-rater reliability was moderate (intraclass correlation coefficient = 0.66), indicating consistent scoring trends across reviewers. The AI detection tool correctly flagged 93.6% of ChatGPT-generated text and had an AI probability rating ranging from 0% to 20% with a mean of 4% in the human-written text. Reviewer profession (medical vs. legal) did not significantly influence scoring patterns. Although underpowered due to a small sample size, the findings suggest that ChatGPT-generated personal statements are comparable in quality and perceived authenticity to those written by applicants, yet remain largely detectable by current AI-detection algorithms. Conclusions These findings suggest that ChatGPT can generate statements that may be difficult to distinguish from applicant-written work, but AI detection tools remain effective in identifying synthetic text. For residency programs, these results highlight the need for clear guidelines on AI use, integration of detection strategies, and ongoing research to understand how AI may affect perceptions of authenticity in applicant evaluation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Menon et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menon</LastName><ForeName>Rahul</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, Cooper Medical School of Rowan University, Camden, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Donald</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery, Cooper University Hospital, Camden, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berenson</LastName><ForeName>Mia</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School - Graduate Medical Education, Rowan-Virtua School of Osteopathic Medicine, Stratford, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kushnir</LastName><ForeName>Vlad</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Law, Cooper University Hospital, Camden, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shapiro</LastName><ForeName>Yekaterina</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery, Cooper University Hospital, Camden, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chatgpt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">otolaryngology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personal statements</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">residency applications</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41536390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12799199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.99202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ten steps for writing an exceptional personal statement. Jones D, Pittman JR Jr, Manning KD. J Grad Med Educ. 2022;14:522&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36274771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How do we choose? A review of residency application scoring systems. Naides AI, Ayyala HS, Lee ES. J Surg Educ. 2021;78:1461&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33744118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COVID-19 and the otolaryngology match: an increase in applicants remaining close to home. Whisonant CT, Shahriari SR, McDonald CD, Moya AN, Ederle A, Borah G. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9053550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35505731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial intelligence in healthcare: review and prediction case studies. Rong G, Mendez A, Bou Assi E, Zhao B, Sawan M. Engineering. 2020;6:291&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utilization of ChatGPT-4 in plastic and reconstructive surgery: a narrative review. Aljindan FK, Shawosh MH, Altamimi L, Arif S, Mortada H. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2023;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10602496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37900984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing scientific abstracts generated by ChatGPT to real abstracts with detectors and blinded human reviewers. Gao CA, Howard FM, Markov NS, Dyer EC, Ramesh S, Luo Y, Pearson AT. NPJ Digit Med. 2023;6:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10133283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37100871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distinguishing authentic voices in the age of ChatGPT: comparing AI-generated and applicant-written personal statements for plastic surgery residency application. Patel V, Deleonibus A, Wells MW, Bernard SL, Schwarz GS. Ann Plast Surg. 2023;91:324&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37566815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial intelligence software can generate residency application personal statements that program directors find acceptable and difficult to distinguish from applicant compositions. Johnstone RE, Neely G, Sizemore DC. J Clin Anesth. 2023;89:111185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37336139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative analysis of artificial intelligence-generated and human-written personal statements in emergency medicine applications. Steele E, Steratore A, Dilcher BZ, Bandi K. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12305746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40735658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Death of the personal statement: a qualitative comparison between human-authored and artificial intelligence-generated medical school admissions essays. Vaccaro MJ, Sharma I, Espina Rey AP, et al. J Am Coll Surg. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41051105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial intelligence-generated writing in the ERAS personal statement: an emerging quandary for post-graduate medical education. Burke H, Kazinka R, Gandhi R, Murray A. Acad Psychiatry. 2025;49:13&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39505810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can residency programs detect artificial intelligence use in personal statements? Cumbo N, Williams W, Canterino JC, Aikman N, Baum JD. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12392696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40895899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Will ChatGPT match to your program? Zumsteg JM, Junn C. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2023;102:545&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36912286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Journals take up arms against AI-written text. Brainard J. Science. 2023;379:740&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36821673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>