<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41527546</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2251-6581</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes and metabolic disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Metab Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanistic insights into propolis in targeting adipokines including leptin, resistin, and adiponectin: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>31</StartPage><MedlinePgn>31</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">31</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40200-026-01855-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Propolis is a bioactive bee product that may influence adipokines involved in metabolic and inflammatory disorders; however, findings on leptin, adiponectin, and resistin are inconsistent across models and human studies. Current study aimed to systematically synthesize preclinical and clinical evidence on the effects of propolis and propolis-derived compounds on leptin, adiponectin, and resistin, and to summarize proposed mechanistic pathways.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study protocol was registered in PROSPERO (CRD42024593198). We searched PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus, and Google Scholar to find related articles published between 1900 and 2025. We screened reference lists, and used alert services after the primary search. We included <i>in vitro</i>, animal, and human studies that were published in English language and evaluated propolis/propolis-derived compounds versus a comparator and reporting leptin, adiponectin, and resistin outcomes. Risk of bias was assessed using the CRIS guideline (<i>in vitro</i>), SYRCLE tool (animal), and Cochrane risk-of-bias tool (clinical trials). Findings were synthesized narratively due to heterogeneity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-six studies were included (9 <i>in vitro</i>, 11 animals, 6 human). <i>In vitro</i> studies generally reported decreased leptin and resistin expression and increased adiponectin expression following propolis-derived phenolics; one study reported increased leptin mRNA with a Brazilian propolis extract. In animal studies, leptin decreased in 5/8 studies and adiponectin increased in 5/9 studies, while remaining studies reported no change or opposite directions. Human trials showed mixed results: leptin decreased in 1/2 trials and adiponectin increased in 2/5 trials, whereas other trials reported no significant change. Substantial heterogeneity in propolis type/origin, formulation, dose, duration, and participant health status limited comparability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Preclinical evidence suggests that propolis and selected constituents can modulate adipokines (often lowering leptin/resistin and increasing adiponectin), but clinical evidence is limited and inconsistent. Well-designed, adequately powered trials using standardized propolis preparations are required to clarify efficacy and translational relevance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s40200-026-01855-1.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Tehran University of Medical Sciences 2026. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Malek Mahdavi</LastName><ForeName>Aida</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Connective Tissue Diseases Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04krpx645</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412888.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2174 8913</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Javadivala</LastName><ForeName>Zeinab</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Education &amp; Promotion, Faculty of Health, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04krpx645</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412888.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2174 8913</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilkay</LastName><ForeName>Hatice Ozcaliskan</ForeName><Initials>HO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health Sciences, Erciyes University, Kayseri, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/047g8vk19</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411739.9</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2331 2603</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ansarin</LastName><ForeName>Atefeh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tuberculosis and Lung Disease Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04krpx645</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412888.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2174 8913</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Metab Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2251-6581</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adiponectin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leptin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Propolis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41527546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12790545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-026-01855-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clemente-Su&#xe1;rez VJ, Redondo-Fl&#xf3;rez L, Beltr&#xe1;n-Velasco AI, Mart&#xed;n-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Mart&#xed;nez-Guardado I, Navarro-Jim&#xe9;nez E, et al. The role of adipokines in health and disease. Biomedicines. 2023;11(5):1290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines11051290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10216288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37238961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xfc;rfel M, Bl&#xfc;her M, Stumvoll M, Ebert T, Kovacs P, T&#xf6;njes A, et al. Adipokines as clinically relevant therapeutic targets in obesity. Biomedicines. 2023;11(5):1427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines11051427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10216759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turpin T, Thouvenot K, Gonthier MP. Adipokines and bacterial metabolites: a pivotal molecular bridge linking obesity and gut microbiota dysbiosis to target. Biomolecules. 2023;13(12):1692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom13121692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10742113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38136564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-P&#xe9;rez A, S&#xe1;nchez-Jim&#xe9;nez F, Vilari&#xf1;o-Garc&#xed;a T, S&#xe1;nchez-Margalet V. Role of leptin in inflammation and vice versa. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(16):5887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms21165887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32824322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhang S, Li Z. Adipokines in glucose and lipid metabolism. Adipocyte. 2023;12(1):2202976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21623945.2023.2202976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10120571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy PK, Islam J, Lalhlenmawia H. Prospects of potential adipokines as therapeutic agents in obesity-linked atherogenic dyslipidemia and insulin resistance. Egypt Heart J. 2023;75(1):24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43044-023-00352-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10073393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37014444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimian J, Hadi A, Pourmasoumi M, Najafgholizadeh A, Ghavami A. The efficacy of propolis on markers of glycemic control in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Phytother Res. 2019;33(6):1616&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30950136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Zhang J, Yang H, Li G, Li H, Deng Z, et al. Propolis polyphenols: a review on the composition and anti-obesity mechanism of different types of propolis polyphenols. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1066789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1066789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10102383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37063322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nattagh-Eshtivani E, Pahlavani N, Ranjbar G, Gholizadeh Navashenaq J, Salehi-Sahlabadi A, Mahmudiono T, Nader Shalaby M, Jokar M, Nematy M, Barghchi H, Havakhah S, Maddahi M, Rashidmayvan M, Khosravi M. Does propolis have any effect on rheumatoid arthritis? A review study. Food Sci Nutr. 2022;10(4):1003&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/fsn3.2684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9007309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35432965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitamura H. Effects of propolis extract and propolis-derived compounds on obesity and diabetes: knowledge from cellular and animal models. Molecules. 2019;24(23):4394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24234394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6930477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31805752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera-Ya&#xf1;ez N, Rivera-Ya&#xf1;ez CR, Pozo-Molina G, M&#xe9;ndez-Catal&#xe1; CF, M&#xe9;ndez-Cruz AR, Nieto-Ya&#xf1;ez O. Biomedical properties of propolis on diverse chronic diseases and its potential applications and health benefits. Nutrients. 2021;13(1):78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13010078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7823938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33383693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghallab D, Shawky E, Mohyeldin M, Metwally AM, Ibrahim RS. Propolis: an update on its chemical diversity, botanical origin and biological activities. J Adv Pharm Sci. 2025;2(1):76&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sani L, Cardinault N, Astier J, Darmon P, Landrier JF. Poplar propolis improves insulin homeostasis in non-diabetic insulin-resistant volunteers with obesity: a crossover randomized controlled trial. Antioxidants. 2023;12(8):1481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox12081481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10451960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37627476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moayedi F, Taghian F, Jalali Dehkordi K, Hosseini SA. Cumulative effects of exercise training and consumption of propolis on managing diabetic dyslipidemia in adult women: a single-blind, randomized, controlled trial with pre-post-intervention assessments. J Physiol Sci. 2023;73(1):17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12576-023-00872-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10717816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37542207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanazashi M, Iida T, Nakanishi R, Tanaka M, Ikeda H, Takamiya N, et al. Brazilian propolis intake decreases body fat mass and oxidative stress in community-dwelling elderly females: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Nutrients. 2023;15(2):364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15020364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9861743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36678234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natsir R, Usman AN, Ardyansyah BD, Fendi F. Propolis and honey trigona decrease leptin levels of central obesity patients. Enferm Clin. 2020;30:96&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enfcli.2019.07.043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao W, Pu L, Wei J, Yao Z, Wang Y, Shi T, et al. Serum antioxidant parameters are significantly increased in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus after consumption of Chinese propolis: a randomized controlled trial based on fasting serum glucose level. Diabetes Ther. 2018;9(1):101&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13300-017-0341-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5801227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Pu L, Wei J, Li J, Wu J, Xin Z, et al. Brazilian Green Propolis Improves Antioxidant Function in Patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2016;13(5):498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph13050498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4881123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oriquat G, Masoud IM, Kamel MA, Aboudeya HM, Bakir MB, Shaker SA. The anti-obesity and anti-steatotic effects of Chrysin in a rat model of obesity mediated through modulating the hepatic AMPK/mTOR/lipogenesis pathways. Molecules. 2023;28(4):1734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules28041734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9962978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36838721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Wang J, Wang Y, Wang P, Zhou Z, Wu R, et al. A propolis-derived small molecule ameliorates metabolic syndrome in obese mice by targeting the CREB/CRTC2 transcriptional complex. Nat Commun. 2022;13:246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-27533-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35017472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinault N, Tourniaire F, Astier J, Couturier C, Bonnet L, Seipelt E, et al. Botanic origin of propolis extract powder drives contrasted impact on diabesity in High-Fat-Fed mice. Antioxid Basel. 2021;10(3):411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox10030411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8000394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe A, de Almeida MO, Deguchi Y, Kozuka R, Arruda C, Berreta AA, et al. Effects of Baccharin Isolated from Brazilian Green Propolis on Adipocyte Differentiation and Hyperglycemia in ob/ob Diabetic Mice. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(13):6954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22136954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34203569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisbona-Gonz&#xe1;lez MJ, Reyes-Botella C, Mu&#xf1;oz-Soto E, Olmedo-Gaya MV, Moreno-Fernandez J, Diaz-Castro J. Effect of propolis-supplemented diet on body composition and endocrine function of adipose tissue. Curr Top Nutraceutical Res. 2021;19(2):217&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardinault N, Tourniaire F, Astier J, Couturier C, Perrin E, Dalifard J, et al. Poplar Propolis Ethanolic Extract Reduces Body Weight Gain and Glucose Metabolism Disruption in High-Fat Diet-Fed Mice. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2020;64(18):e2000275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mnfr.202000275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SM, Imm JY. The effect of Chrysin-loaded phytosomes on insulin resistance and blood sugar control in type 2 diabetic db/db mice. Molecules. 2020;25(23):5503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25235503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33255372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farkhondeh T, Abedi F, Samarghandian S. Chrysin attenuates inflammatory and metabolic disorder indices in aged male rat. Biomed Pharmacother. 2019;109:1120&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2018.10.059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30551362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LH, Chien YW, Chang ML, Hou CC, Chan CH, Tang HW, et al. Taiwanese green propolis ethanol extract delays the progression of type 2 diabetes mellitus in rats treated with streptozotocin/high-fat diet. Nutrients. 2018;10(4):503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10040503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5946288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29670038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elissa LA, Elsherbiny NM, Magmomah AO. Propolis restored adiponectin level in type 2 diabetes through PPAR&#x3b3; activation. Egypt J Basic Appl Sci. 2015;2(4):318&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezerra RM, Veiga LF, Caetano AC, Rosalen PL, Amaral ME, Palanch AC, et al. Caffeic acid phenethyl ester reduces the activation of the nuclear factor &#x3ba;B pathway by high-fat diet-induced obesity in mice. Metabolism. 2012;61(11):1606&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2012.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22575582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong L, Zhang Y, Feng Z, Dong J, Zhang H. Phenolic compounds of propolis alleviate lipid metabolism disorder. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2021;2021:7615830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/7615830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7914084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33688365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YW, Chien Y-H. Taiwanese green propolis ethanol extract promotes adipocyte differentiation and alleviates TNF-&#x3b1;-mediated downregulation of adiponectin expression. J Funct Foods. 2020;73:104135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2020.104135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn S, Kim J, An S, Pyo JJ, Jung D, Lee J, et al. 2-phenyl-8-(1-phenylallyl)-chromenone compounds have a pan-PPAR modulator pharmacophore. Bioorg Med Chem. 2019;27(13):2948&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmc.2019.05.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31128991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washio K, Shimamoto Y, Kitamura H. Brazilian propolis extract increases leptin expression in mouse adipocytes. Biomed Res. 2015;36(5):343&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2220/biomedres.36.343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26522151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanella L, Tibullo D, Godos J, Pluchinotta FR, Di Giacomo C, Sorrenti V, et al. Caffeic acid phenethyl ester regulates PPAR&#x2019;s levels in stem cells-derived adipocytes. PPAR Res. 2016;2016:7359521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/7359521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4745343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26904104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juman S, Yasui N, Okuda H, Ueda A, Negishi H, Miki T, Ikeda K. Caffeic acid phenethyl ester suppresses the production of adipocytokines, leptin, tumor necrosis factor -alpha and resistin, during differentiation to adipocytes in 3T3-L1 cells. Biol Pharm Bull. 2011;34(4):490&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.34.490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21467634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SS, Cha BY, Iida K, Lee YS, Yonezawa T, Teruya T, et al. Artepillin C, as a PPAR&#x3b3; ligand, enhances adipocyte differentiation and glucose uptake in 3T3-L1 cells. Biochem Pharmacol. 2011;81(7):925&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcp.2011.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21219874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda R, Yanagisawa M, Takahashi N, Kawada T, Kumazawa S, Yamaotsu N, Nakagome I, Hirono S, Tsuda T. Brazilian propolis-derived components inhibit TNF-&#x3b1;-mediated downregulation of adiponectin expression via different mechanisms in 3T3-L1 adipocytes. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2011;1810(7):695&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbagen.2011.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21554928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iio A, Ohguchi K, Inoue H, Maruyama H, Araki Y, Nozawa Y, Ito M. Ethanolic extracts of Brazilian red propolis promote adipocyte differentiation through PPAR&#x3b3; activation. Phytomedicine. 2010;17(12):974&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2010.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20382515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, Ghersi D, Liberati A, Petticrew M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2046-4053-4-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25554246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krithikadatta J, Gopikrishna V, Datta M. CRIS guidelines (checklist for reporting <i>in vitro</i> studies): a concept note on the need for standardized guidelines for improving quality and transparency in reporting <i>in-vitro</i> studies in experimental dental research. J Conserv Dent. 2014;17(4):301&#x2013;4.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0972-0707.136338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4127685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25125839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooijmans CR, Rovers MM, de Vries RB, Leenaars M, Ritskes-Hoitinga M, Langendam MW. SYRCLE&#x2bc;s risk of bias tool for animal studies. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-14-43</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4230647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24667063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane collaboration&#x2bc;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;43:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lettieri-Barbato D, Giovannetti E, Aquilano K. Effects of dietary restriction on adipose mass and biomarkers of healthy aging in human. Aging. 2016;8(12):3341&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.101122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5270672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koya-Miyata S, Arai N, Mizote A, Taniguchi Y, Ushio S, Iwaki K, Fukuda S. Propolis prevents diet-induced hyperlipidemia and mitigates weight gain in diet-induced obesity in mice. Biol Pharm Bull. 2009;32(12):2022&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.32.2022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen EL, Rissanen A, Bruun JM, Skogstrand K, Tonstad S, Hougaard DM, et al. Weight loss larger than 10% is needed for general improvement of levels of circulating adiponectin and markers of inflammation in obese subjects: a 3-year weight loss study. Eur J Endocrinol. 2008;158(2):179&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/EJE-07-0721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18230824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Mal K, Razaq MK, Magsi M, Memon MK, Memon S, Afroz MN, Siddiqui HF, Rizwan A. Association of leptin with obesity and insulin resistance. Cureus. 2020;12(12):e12178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7815269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33489589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pahlavani N, Malekahmadi M, Firouzi S, Rostami D, Sedaghat A, Moghaddam AB, Ferns GA, Navashenaq JG, Reazvani R, Safarian M, Ghayour-Mobarhan M. Molecular and cellular mechanisms of the effects of propolis in inflammation, oxidative stress and glycemic control in chronic diseases. Nutr Metab (Lond). 2020;17:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-020-00485-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwase M, Yamamoto T, Nishimura K, Takahashi H, Mohri S, Li Y, et al. Suksdorfin promotes adipocyte differentiation and improves abnormalities in glucose metabolism via PPAR&#x3b3; activation. Lipids. 2017;52(7):657&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11745-017-4269-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28601955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olefsky JM. Treatment of insulin resistance with peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma agonists. J Clin Invest. 2000;106(4):467&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI10843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC380259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10953021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day EA, Ford RJ, Steinberg GR. AMPK as a therapeutic target for treating metabolic diseases. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2017;28(8):545&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2017.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28647324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products N Allergies. Scientific opinion on the substantiation of health claims related to propolis (ID 1242, 1245, 1246, 1247, 1248, 3184) and flavonoids in propolis (ID 1244, 1644, 1645, 3526, 3527, 3798, 3799) pursuant to Article 13 (1) of regulation (EC) 1924/2006. EFSA J. 2010;8(10):1810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>