<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41696857</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2702-3648</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of osteopathic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Osteopath Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Challenging hierarchies and fostering collaboration: a critical discourse analysis of interprofessional education in healthcare training.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/jom-2024-0244</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Interprofessional education (IPE) in health professions training strives to create a future collaborative healthcare workforce for the betterment of patient care. One of the aims of IPE experiences is to challenge healthcare hierarchies, with a focus on fluid leadership among healthcare team members. This promotes improved patient-care experience, as well as addressing patient well-being in a more holistic manner.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to critically analyze the discourse of an interprofessional team of healthcare students following a simulated patient encounter to assess the power dynamic among the professions present.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Researchers critically analyzed the discourse from student Interprofessional Team Immersion (IPTI) simulation debrief sessions. Sessions were transcribed and the discourse was coded utilizing Interprofessional Education Collaborative (IPEC) core competencies. A critical discourse analysis (CDA) was employed as a methodology to identify the prevalence of utilitarian and emancipatory discourse among students in diverse health professions and how collaborative interprofessional teamwork and patient health outcomes are impacted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Student teams modeled emancipatory and utilitarian discourses to structure team debriefs. The first debrief session operated through utilitarian discursivity, demonstrating instances of individual insecurity, slow team growth, and less coordinated patient care. Analysis of the second debrief session demonstrated the use of emancipatory discourse through the presence of greater team cohesiveness, less focus on self, and greater collaborative focus on patient care. Furthermore, analysis suggests the presence of fluid leadership with no dominant, healthcare profession (HCP)-specific hierarchy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Employing a critical discursive lens in healthcare education can help students challenge power imbalances and shift toward fluid leadership and increase team cohesion between HCPs. These findings highlight how IPE can lead to greater collaboration between interprofessional student team members, challenge hierarchy, and&#xa0;empower the healthcare team to provide improved patient&#xa0;care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 the author(s), published by De Gruyter, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zorda</LastName><ForeName>Emma M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Osteopathic Medicine, University of New England, Biddeford, ME, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sargent</LastName><ForeName>Mikayla A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Osteopathic Medicine, University of New England, Biddeford, ME, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gose</LastName><ForeName>Cara E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Osteopathic Medicine, University of New England, Biddeford, ME, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becker</LastName><ForeName>Mitchell T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Osteopathic Medicine, University of New England, Biddeford, ME, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garber</LastName><ForeName>Sarah S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Pharmacy, 283505 Rosalind Franklin University of Medicine and Science , North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DePrimo</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Beaver College of Health Sciences, Appalachian State University, Boone, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Batteson</LastName><ForeName>Tamzin</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baldwin Institute for Interprofessional Education, Rosalind Franklin University of Medicine and Science, North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>J Osteopath Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101776472</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2702-3648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical discourse analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interprofessional education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">simulation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41696857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jom-2024-0244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jom-2024-0244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haddara, W, Lingard, L. Are we all on the same page? A discourse analysis of interprofessional collaboration. Acad Med 2013;88:1509&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1097/ACM.0b013e3182a31893 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0b013e3182a31893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, B, Oeppen, RS, Smith, DW, Brennan, PA. Challenging hierarchy in healthcare teams&#xa0;&#x2013;&#xa0;ways to flatten gradients to improve teamwork and patient care. BJOMS 2017;55:449&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j/bjoms/2017/02/010 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j/bjoms/2017/02/010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves, S. Why we need interprofessional education to improve the delivery of safe and effective care. Interface Comun Saude, Educ 2016;20:185&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1590/1807-57622014.0092 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1807-57622014.0092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milligan, RA, Gilroy, J, Katz, KS, Rodan, MF, Subramanian, KN. Developing a shared language: interdisciplinary communication among diverse health care professionals. Holist Nurs Pract 1999;13:47&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1097/00004650-199901000-00008 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004650-199901000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, JHV, Yan, J, Hoffman, SJ. A WHO report: framework for action on interprofessional education and collaborative practice. J&#xa0;Allied Health 2010;39:196&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins, K, Salih, R, Garber, SS, Batteson, TJ. Interprofessional healthcare themes derived through critical discourse analysis. JESMA 2023;3:96&#x2013;116. https://doi.org/10.51383/jesma.2023.80 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51383/jesma.2023.80</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawlinson, C, Carron, T, Cohidon, C, Arditi, C, Hong, QN, Pluye, P, et al.. An overview of reviews on interprofessional collaboration in primary care: barriers and facilitators. Int J Integrated Care 2021;21:32. https://doi.org/10.5334/ijic.5589 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/ijic.5589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlke, S, Hunter, KF, Reshef Kalogirou, M, Negrin, K, Fox, M, Wagg, A. Perspectives about interprofessional collaboration and patient-centered care. Can J Aging 2020;39:443&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0714980819000539 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0714980819000539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, R, Kitto, S, Whitehead, C. Other ways of knowing: using critical discourse analysis to reexamine intraprofessional collaboration. Can Fam Physician 2016;62:701&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wodak, R. Chapter 3: Critical discourse analysis. In: Hyland, K, editor. Continuum companion to discourse analysis . Bloomsbury Publishing Plc; 2011:39&#x2013;40 pp. ProQuest Ebook Central https://ebookcentral.proquest.com/lib/uneedu/detail.action?docID=661030 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schot, E, Tummers, L, Noordegraaf, M. Working on working together. A systematic review on how healthcare professionals contribute to interprofessional collaboration. J&#xa0;Interprof Care 2019;34:332&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1080/13561820.2019.1636007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820.2019.1636007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters, MJ, Sexton, M, Metz, AE, Hasbrouck, CS. A team-based interprofessional education course for first-year health professions students. Curr Pharm Teach Learn 2017;9:1099&#x2013;110. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cptl.2017.07.006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cptl.2017.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konrad, SC, Cavanaugh, JT, Rodriguez, K, Hall, K, Pardue, K. A five-session interprofessional team immersion program for health professions students. J&#xa0;Interprofessional Educ Pract 2017;6:49&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xjep.2016.12.007 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xjep.2016.12.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interprofessional Education Collaborative . IPEC core competencies for interprofessional collaborative practice: version 3 . Washington, DC: Interprofessional Education Collaborative; 2023. https://ipec.memberclicks.net/assets/core-competencies/IPEC_Core_Competencies_Version_3_2023.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interprofessional Education Collaborative . Core competencies for interprofessional collaborative practice: 2016 update . Washington, DC: Interprofessional Education Collaborative; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricci, E, Konrad, SC, Muntifering, A, Nadeau, J, Takatsuki, J, Williams, E, et al.. The effect of a transdisciplinary early intervention playgroup experience on interprofessional student attitudes. Am J Occup Ther 2015;69:6911510216p1. https://doi.org/10.5014/ajot.2015.69S1-PO6098 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5014/ajot.2015.69S1-PO6098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macfarlane, M, Kelley, S, Carver, C, Cacic, Q, Castle, A, Horne, E. Interprofessional team immersion: team resilience. Poster presented at: CECE spring poster session. Portland, ME: University of New England; 2022. https://dune.une.edu/cecespring2022/14 .</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>