<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41667989</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development and validation of a prediction model for predicting invasive Klebsiella pneumoniae liver abscess syndrome in patients with pyogenic liver abscess.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">562</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-12727-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Invasive Klebsiella pneumoniae liver abscess syndrome (IKLAS) increases the risk of mortality and length of hospital stay in patients with pyogenic liver abscess (PLA). This study aimed to construct a nomogram capable of accurately predicting the occurrence of IKLAS in PLA patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This study retrospectively analyzed data from pyogenic liver abscess (PLA) patients admitted to Tianjin Medical University General Hospital between January 2022 and May 2024. We aimed to develop a nomogram predicting IKLAS, which defines as a liver abscess with metastatic Klebsiella pneumoniae infections at other sites. Data were collected from the inpatient management system. To address class imbalance, the dataset was augmented using Synthetic Minority Over-sampling Technique (SMOTE) and Random Over-Sampling Examples (ROSE). The enhanced dataset was split into a training set and validation set using R software. To improve the model&#x2019;s explanatory power and stability, Least Absolute Shrinkage and Selection Operator (LASSO) regression was used. A logistic regression-based nomogram was developed. It was evaluated using receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves, calibration diagrams, and decision curve analysis (DCA). Internal validation was performed on the holdout dataset.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">This study included 160 PLA patients, 24 with IKLAS and 136 with non-IKLAS. Using SMOTE and ROSE, IKLAS cases were augmented to 120. Patients were divided into training (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;180) and validation (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;76) sets. Statistical analysis identified 12 significant factors, such as diabetes mellitus (DM), septic shock (SS), white blood cell (WBC), neutrophil percentage (N%), lymphocyte percentage (L%), N%: L% ratio, C-reactive protein (CRP), alkaline phosphatase (ALKP), blood urea nitrogen (BUN), total cholesterol (TC), and lipoproteins (HDL, LDL). LASSO regression selected eight parameters for nomogram: SS, WBC, L%, CRP, ALKP, BUN, and LDL. TC was excluded due to its compositional relationship with LDL. The model demonstrated excellent predictive performance. It achieved an AUC of 0.813 (95% CI: 0.752&#x2013;0.834) in the training set and 0.853 (95% CI: 0.769&#x2013;0.937) in the validation set. Calibration curves and DCA confirmed accuracy and strong clinical utility, proving its reliability for predicting IKLAS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">We developed a risk prediction model for IKLAS in patients with PLA. The influencing factors include SS, WBC, L%, CRP, ALKP, BUN and LDL. This model provides preliminary evidence for IKLAS risk stratification.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12879-026-12727-7.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Tianjin Medical University General Hospital, Tianjin, 300052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Chenguang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Tianjin Medical University General Hospital, Tianjin, 300052, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chai</LastName><ForeName>Yanfen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Tianjin Medical University General Hospital, Tianjin, 300052, China. chaiyanfen2012@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Klebsiella pneumoniae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nomogram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pyogenic liver abscess (PLA)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki (2013 revision) and was approved by the Institutional Review Board of Tianjin Medical University General Hospital (Full IRB name: &#x201c;Research Ethics Committee of Tianjin Medical University General Hospital&#x201d;; Approval No. IRB2025-YX-010&#x2013;01). The requirement for written informed consent was formally waived by the IRB under Article 32 of China&#x2019;s &#x201c;Ethical Review Measures for Life Sciences and Medical Research Involving Humans&#x201d; (National Health Commission Order No. 2, 2023), which permits retrospective studies using anonymized clinical data to proceed without individual consent. All patient data were de-identified prior to analysis to ensure confidentiality. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41667989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12990508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-12727-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-12727-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akhondi H, Sabih DE. Liver Abscess. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2024 Jan; 2023 Jul 3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30855818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendt S, Ba&#x10d;&#xe1;k M, Petroff D, et al. Clinical management, pathogen spectrum and outcomes in patients with pyogenic liver abscess in a German tertiary-care hospital. Sci Rep. 2024, Jun, 5;14(1):12972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-63819-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11153614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38839980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JQ, Liu Y, Li CH, et al. Characteristics of Klebsiella pneumoniae pyogenic liver abscess from 2010&#x2013;2021 in a tertiary teaching hospital of South China. J Glob Antimicrob Resist. 2024, Mar;36:210&#x2013;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgar.2023.12.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38154752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Gong Y, Song B, et al. Pyogenic liver abscess complicated with endogenous endophthalmitis caused by <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i>: a case report and literature Review. Immun Inflamm Dis. 2023, Jul;11(7):e943
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/iid3.943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10373569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37506152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CH, Chuah SK, Tai WC, et al. Platelet reactivity in diabetic patients with invasive Klebsiella pneumoniae liver abscess syndrome. Infect Drug Resist. 2018, Oct, 9;11:1669&#x2013;76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S174913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6183545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang CG, Wang Y, Duan M, et al. <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> invasion syndrome: a case of liver abscess combined with lung abscess, endophthalmitis, and brain abscess. J Int Med Res. 2022, Mar;50(3):3000605221084881
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03000605221084881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8969510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35345919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oduncu AF, K&#x131;yan GS, Yal&#xe7;&#x131;nl&#x131; S. Comparison of qSOFA, SIRS, and NEWS scoring systems for diagnosis, mortality, and morbidity of sepsis in emergency department. Am J Emerg Med. 2021, Oct;48:54&#x2013;59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2021.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33839632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Wu J, Tian Y, et al. Predictive value of peripheral lymphocyte subsets for the disease progression in patients with sepsis. Int Immunopharmacol. 2023, Apr;117:109922</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2023.109922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37012888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JGH, Genga KR, Pisitsak C, et al. Survival benefit of a low ratio of visceral to subcutaneous adipose tissue depends on LDL clearance versus production in sepsis. Crit Care. 2018;22(1):58</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-018-1985-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29510719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Eckardstein A, Nordestgaard BG, Remaley AT, et al. High-density lipoproteinrevisited: biological functions and clinical relevance. Eur Heart J. 2023, Apr, 21;44(16):1394&#x2013;1407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehac605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10119031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36337032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Geest B, Mishra M. Impact of high-density lipoproteins on sepsis. Int J Mol Sci. 2022, Oct, 26;23(21):12965</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms232112965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9655469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36361756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Wang JY, Jiang W. An increasing prominent disease of <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> liver abscess: etiology, diagnosis, and treatment. Gastroenterol Res Pract. 2013;2013:258514
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/258514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3806164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24194749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harazim M, Tan K, Nalos M, et al. Blood urea nitrogen-independent marker of mortality in sepsis. Biomed Pap Med Fac Univ Palacky Olomouc Czech Repub. 2023, Mar;167(1):24&#x2013;29</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5507/bp.2022.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35373784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S, Archuleta S, Pang J. Risk factors of septic metastatic infection among patients with <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> liver abscess in Singapore: a case-control study. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2022;106:805&#x2013;08
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.21-0623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35073511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu L, Wang Y, Wang H, et al. Analysis of clinical and microbiological characteristics of invasive <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> liver abscess syndrome. BMC Infect Dis. 2025, Apr, 29;25(1):626
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-025-10981-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12039297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40301787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivrak M, Avci U, Uzun H, et al. The impact of the SMOTE method on machine Learning and ensemble Learning performance results in addressing class imbalance in data used for predicting total testosterone deficiency in type 2 diabetes patients. Diagn (Basel). 2024 Nov 22;14(23):2634</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11640355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39682541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Zhang H, Xu Y, et al. Clinical and CT comparative study of invasive and non-invasive <i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> liver abscesses. Clin Radiol. 2023, Jan;78(1):40&#x2013;46
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crad.2022.08.145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36198513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>