<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41501159</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2150-5551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nano-micro letters</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nanomicro Lett</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coordination Thermodynamic Control of Magnetic Domain Configuration Evolution toward Low-Frequency Electromagnetic Attenuation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>104</StartPage><MedlinePgn>104</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">104</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40820-025-01948-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The precise tuning of magnetic nanoparticle size and spacing directly influences the alignment of intrinsic magnetic moments and magnetic domains, thereby shaping magnetic properties. However, the dynamic evolution mechanisms of magnetic domain configurations in relation to electromagnetic (EM) attenuation behavior remain poorly understood. To address this gap, a thermodynamically controlled periodic coordination strategy is proposed to achieve precise modulation of magnetic nanoparticle spacing. This approach unveils the evolution of magnetic domain configurations, progressing from individual to coupled and ultimately to crosslinked domain configurations. A unique magnetic coupling phenomenon surpasses the Snoek limit in low-frequency range, which is observed through micromagnetic simulation. The crosslinked magnetic configuration achieves effective low-frequency EM wave absorption at 3.68 GHz, encompassing nearly the entire C-band. This exceptional magnetic interaction significantly enhances radar camouflage and thermal insulation properties. Additionally, a robust gradient metamaterial design extends coverage across the full band (2-40 GHz), effectively mitigating the impact of EM pollution on human health and environment. This comprehensive study elucidates the evolution mechanisms of magnetic domain configurations, addresses gaps in dynamic magnetic modulation, and provides novel insights for the development of high-performance, low-frequency EM wave absorption materials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Tong</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Jiangxi Province for Persistent Pollutants Control and Resources Recycle, School of Environmental and Chemical Engineering, Nanchang Hangkong University, Nanchang, 330063, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Jiangxi Province for Persistent Pollutants Control and Resources Recycle, School of Environmental and Chemical Engineering, Nanchang Hangkong University, Nanchang, 330063, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Xue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Environmental Risk Assessment and Control On Chemical Process, School of Mechanical and Power Engineering, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai, 200237, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Zhaobo</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Jiangxi Province for Persistent Pollutants Control and Resources Recycle, School of Environmental and Chemical Engineering, Nanchang Hangkong University, Nanchang, 330063, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Zhiqiang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Jiangxi Province for Persistent Pollutants Control and Resources Recycle, School of Environmental and Chemical Engineering, Nanchang Hangkong University, Nanchang, 330063, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yuqi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Jiangxi Province for Persistent Pollutants Control and Resources Recycle, School of Environmental and Chemical Engineering, Nanchang Hangkong University, Nanchang, 330063, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Yuhui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Nondestructive Testing, Ministry of Education, School of Instrument Science and Optoelectronic Engineering, Nanchang Hangkong University, Nanchang, 330063, People's Republic of China. pengyuhui@nchu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Guangsheng</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Materials, Nanchang University, Nanchang, 330031, People's Republic of China. luoguangsheng@ncu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Xuliang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry &amp; Materials, Jiangxi Agricultural University, Nanchang, 330045, People's Republic of China. xuliangnie123@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Mingyue</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Advanced Materials, Shanghai Key Lab of Molecular Catalysis and Innovative Materials, Academy for Engineering &amp; Technology, Fudan University, Shanghai, 200438, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chongbo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Jiangxi Province for Persistent Pollutants Control and Resources Recycle, School of Environmental and Chemical Engineering, Nanchang Hangkong University, Nanchang, 330063, People's Republic of China. cbliu2002@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Che</LastName><ForeName>Renchao</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Advanced Materials, Shanghai Key Lab of Molecular Catalysis and Innovative Materials, Academy for Engineering &amp; Technology, Fudan University, Shanghai, 200438, People's Republic of China. rcche@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Nanomicro Lett</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101727940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2150-5551</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrical/magnetic coupling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Low-frequency electromagnetic wave absorption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic domain configuration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multifunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thermodynamically controlled coordination strategy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests. They have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41501159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12779889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-025-01948-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40820-025-01948-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>M. He, X. Zhong, X. Lu, J. Hu, K. Ruan et al., Excellent low-frequency microwave absorption and high thermal conductivity in polydimethylsiloxane composites endowed by <i>Hydrangea</i>-like CoNi@BN heterostructure fillers. Adv. Mater. <b>36</b>(48), 2410186 (2024). 10.1002/adma.202410186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202410186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39380425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Gu, Z. Luo, J. Wang, X. Tan, Z. Tao et al., Multifunctional lightweight rGO/polyimide hybrid aerogels for highly efficient infrared-radar-acoustic compatibility <i>via</i> heterogeneous interface engineering strategies. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. <b>243</b>, 102&#x2013;114 (2026). 10.1016/j.jmst.2025.04.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2025.04.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y.-Y. Wang, J. Li, L.-C. Jia, J. Lei, D.-X. Yan et al., Recent progress on segregated polymer composites for functional applications. Prog. Mater. Sci. <b>155</b>, 101524 (2026). 10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101524</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zheng, D. Lan, S. Zhang, F. Wei, T. Liu et al., Zeolite imidazolate framework derived efficient absorbers: From morphology modulation to component regulation. J. Alloys Compd. <b>1010</b>, 177092 (2025). 10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Xue, X. Liu, X. Lu, Hierarchically three-dimensional ZrO<sub>2</sub>/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>/C nanocomposites with Janus structure for high-efficiency electromagnetic wave absorption. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. <b>195</b>, 126&#x2013;135 (2024). 10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Xue, X. Liu, X. Cui, Y. Zhao, X. Lu, Precise magnetic tailoring in ZrO<sub>2</sub>/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>-Fe/C nanocomposites <i>via</i> electron transfer modulation for enhanced electromagnetic wave absorption. Nano Res. <b>18</b>(6), 94907387 (2025). 10.26599/nr.2025.94907387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/nr.2025.94907387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Yang, W. You, X. Xiong, R. Zhang, Z. Wu et al., Morphology-evolved succulent-like FeCo microarchitectures with magnetic configuration regulation for enhanced microwave absorption. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces <b>14</b>(28), 32369&#x2013;32378 (2022). 10.1021/acsami.2c06767
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c06767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Li, Z. Zong, F. Zhang, J.-F. Shi, Z.-Y. Li et al., Barium ferrite with high anisotropy for ultra-broadband microwave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(5), 2414694 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202414694</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202414694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Yuan, B. Zhao, C. Yang, K. Pei, L. Wang et al., Remarkable magnetic exchange coupling <i>via</i> constructing bi-magnetic interface for broadband lower-frequency microwave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>32</b>(33), 2203161 (2022). 10.1002/adfm.202203161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202203161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Ding, C. Shao, Z. Li, X. Ren, S. Wu et al., High anisotropy 2D large-size iron-based coral for C-band ultra-wide microwave absorption. Chem. Eng. J. <b>500</b>, 156973 (2024). 10.1016/j.cej.2024.156973</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.156973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Chen, R. Zhang, M. Yuan, S. Xue, Y. Liu et al., Visualizing nanoscale interlayer magnetic interactions and unconventional low-frequency behaviors in ferromagnetic multishelled structures. Adv. Mater. <b>36</b>(24), 2313411 (2024). 10.1002/adma.202313411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202313411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38469974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Jiang, P. Zhang, X. Wang, Y. Gong, Synthesis of magnetic two-dimensional materials by chemical vapor deposition. Nano Res. <b>14</b>(6), 1789&#x2013;1801 (2021). 10.1007/s12274-020-3020-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12274-020-3020-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Hu, C. Ye, X. Wang, X. Zhao, L. Kang et al., Chemical vapor deposition of superconducting FeTe<sub>1&#x2013;</sub><sub>x</sub>Se<sub>x</sub> nanosheets. Nano Lett. <b>21</b>(12), 5338&#x2013;5344 (2021). 10.1021/acs.nanolett.1c01577
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.1c01577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34105969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Pan, M. Ning, Z. Li, D. Batalu, H. Guo et al., Sequential architecture induced strange dielectric-magnetic behaviors in ferromagnetic microwave absorber. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>33</b>(27), 2300374 (2023). 10.1002/adfm.202300374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202300374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yang, Z. Xiu, F. Pan, H. Liang, H. Jiang et al., Tuning the multilevel hierarchical microarchitecture of MXene/rGO-based aerogels through a magnetic field-guided strategy toward stepwise enhanced electromagnetic wave dissipation. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(18), 2406133 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202406133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202406133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Jin, Z. Wu, C. Yang, L. Wang, R. Zhang et al., Impedance amelioration of coaxial-electrospun TiO<sub>2</sub>@Fe/C@TiO<sub>2</sub> vesicular carbon microtubes with dielectric-magnetic synergy toward highly efficient microwave absorption. Chem. Eng. J. <b>433</b>, 133640 (2022). 10.1016/j.cej.2021.133640</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.133640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Yang, J. Fang, C. Xu, H. Cao, R. Zhang et al., One-dimensional magnetic FeCoNi alloy toward low-frequency electromagnetic wave absorption. Nano-Micro Lett. <b>14</b>(1), 170 (2022). 10.1007/s40820-022-00920-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-022-00920-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9392832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35987921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Chai, Y. Wang, Z. Jia, Z. Liu, S. Zhou et al., Tunable defects and interfaces of hierarchical dandelion-like NiCo<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub><i>via</i> Ostwald ripening process for high-efficiency electromagnetic wave absorption. Chem. Eng. J. <b>429</b>, 132547 (2022). 10.1016/j.cej.2021.132547</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.132547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Ma, F. Zhao, M. Li, P. Wang, Y. Fu et al., Construction of hollow binary oxide heterostructures by Ostwald ripening for superior photoelectrochemical removal of reactive brilliant blue KNR dye. Adv Powder Mater <b>2</b>(3), 100117 (2023). 10.1016/j.apmate.2023.100117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmate.2023.100117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Liu, J. Zhou, Y. Xue, X. Lu, Structural engineering of hierarchical magnetic/carbon nanocomposites <i>via in situ</i> growth for high-efficient electromagnetic wave absorption. Nano-Micro Lett. <b>16</b>(1), 174 (2024). 10.1007/s40820-024-01396-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-024-01396-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11018581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38619635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Huang, L. Wang, K. Pei, B. Li, W. You et al., Heterogeneous interface engineering of bi-metal MOFs-derived ZnFe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;ZnO-Fe@C microspheres <i>via</i> confined growth strategy toward superior electromagnetic wave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>34</b>(3), 2308898 (2024). 10.1002/adfm.202308898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202308898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhang, J. Zheng, D. Lan, Z. Gao, X. Liang et al., Hierarchical engineering on built-in electric field of bimetallic zeolitic imidazolate derivatives towards amplified dielectric loss. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(3), 2413884 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202413884</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202413884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhang, J. Zheng, Z. Zhao, S. Du, D. Lan et al., New prospects in built-In electric fields for electromagnetic wave absorption: from fundamentals to interdisciplinary applications. Adv. Funct. Mater. (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202513762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202513762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhao, Z. Wang, H. Wang, P. Liu, R. Che, Controllable design of &#x201c;nested doll&#x201d; MoS<sub>2</sub>/V<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> heterostructures promotes polarization effects for high-efficiency microwave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(14), 2418282 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202418282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202418282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Liu, P. Zhu, J. Teng, R. Xi, X. Wang et al., Optimizing MOF-derived electromagnetic wave absorbers through gradient pore regulation for Pareto improvement. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(18), 2413048 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202413048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202413048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Fang, C. Liu, X. Wei, Q. Cai, C. Chen et al., Determining the preferable polarization loss for magnetoelectric microwave absorbers by strategy of controllably regulating defects. Chem. Eng. J. <b>463</b>, 142440 (2023). 10.1016/j.cej.2023.142440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.142440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Stankovi&#x107;, D. Jovanovi&#x107;, D. Krsti&#x107;, V. Markovi&#x107;, N. Cvetkovi&#x107;, Temperature distribution and specific absorption rate inside a child&#x2019;s head. Int. J. Heat Mass Transf. <b>104</b>, 559&#x2013;565 (2017). 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2016.08.094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2016.08.094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Rao, Z. Liu, L. Wang, W. You, C. Yang et al., Dimensional engineering of hierarchical nanopagodas for customizing cross-scale magnetic coupling networks to enhance electromagnetic wave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>33</b>(47), 2306984 (2023). 10.1002/adfm.202306984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202306984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C.-H. Li, J.-L. Zuo, Self-healing polymers based on coordination bonds. Adv. Mater. <b>32</b>(27), 1903762 (2020). 10.1002/adma.201903762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201903762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31599045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Wang, Y. Ni, X. Hou, L. Chen, F. Li et al., A two-dimensional metal&#x2013;organic polymer enabled by robust nickel&#x2013;nitrogen and hydrogen bonds for exceptional sodium-ion storage. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>59</b>(49), 22126&#x2013;22131 (2020). 10.1002/anie.202008726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202008726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32812334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Kr&#xe1;l, A. Chesalkin, J. Cermak, P. Roupcova, E. Prusov, Influence of Fe on the hydrogen storage properties of LaCeNi alloys. Langmuir <b>39</b>(17), 6061&#x2013;6068 (2023). 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00093
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37079632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Qiu, X. Liu, T. Yang, J. Wang, Y. Wang et al., Synergistic enhancement of electromagnetic wave absorption and corrosion resistance properties of high entropy alloy through lattice distortion engineering. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>34</b>(33), 2400220 (2024). 10.1002/adfm.202400220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202400220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Zhao, Z. Yan, Y. Du, L. Rao, G. Chen et al., High-entropy enhanced microwave attenuation in titanate perovskites. Adv. Mater. <b>35</b>(11), e2210243 (2023). 10.1002/adma.202210243
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202210243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36606342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, X. Zhang, H. Yuan, K. Li, Q. Ouyang et al., CoNi nanoparticles encapsulated by nitrogen-doped carbon nanotube arrays on reduced graphene oxide sheets for electromagnetic wave absorption. Chem. Eng. J. <b>383</b>, 123208 (2020). 10.1016/j.cej.2019.123208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2019.123208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Shi, Z. Jia, D. Lan, Z. Gao, S. Zhang et al., Enhanced polarization relaxation of multidimensional bimetallic selenide nanocomposites for electromagnetic wave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202502261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202502261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Liu, X. Wang, X. Lu, L. Jiang, Localized morphological modulation of ultrathin magnetic nanosheets <i>via</i> a strategically designed reduction approach. Small <b>21</b>(6), 2409657 (2025). 10.1002/smll.202409657</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202409657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39707672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Zhang, N. Li, J.-F. Shi, L. Xu, L.-C. Jia et al., Recent progress on carbon-based microwave absorption materials for multifunctional applications: a review. Compos. B Eng. <b>283</b>, 111646 (2024). 10.1016/j.compositesb.2024.111646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2024.111646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Feng, C. Liu, X. Li, G. Luo, N. Zhai et al., Designing electronic structures of multiscale helical converters for tailored ultrabroad electromagnetic absorption. Nano-Micro Lett. <b>17</b>(1), 20 (2024). 10.1007/s40820-024-01513-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-024-01513-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11448510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39325236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Li, F. Pan, H. Guo, H. Jiang, X. Wang et al., Tailored magnetic spatial confinement with enhanced polarization and magnetic response for electromagnetic wave absorption. Small <b>20</b>(46), 2402564 (2024). 10.1002/smll.202402564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202402564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39087370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lin, Y. Peng, J. Luo, Z. Xiong, J. Huang et al., One-click to 3D: helical carbon nanotube-mediated MXene hierarchical aerogel with layer spacing engineering for broadband electromagnetic wave absorption. Small Methods <b>9</b>(5), 2401665 (2025). 10.1002/smtd.202401665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smtd.202401665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39610167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Wang, H. Wang, S. Zhang, N. Ren, Y. Wu et al., Manipulating the electronic structure of nickel <i>via</i> alloying with iron: toward high-kinetics sulfur cathode for Na&#x2013;S batteries. ACS Nano <b>15</b>(9), 15218&#x2013;15228 (2021). 10.1021/acsnano.1c05778
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.1c05778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34423643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Yao, F. Pan, H. Liang, X. Zhang, L. Li et al., Shifting d-band center: an overlooked factor in broadening electromagnetic wave absorption bandwidth. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(3), 2413639 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202413639</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202413639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Wang, W. Wei, F. Huang, F. Liu, S. Li et al., Orbital hybridization induced dipole polarization and room temperature magnetism of atomic Co-N<sub>4</sub>-C toward electromagnetic energy attenuation. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>34</b>(45), 2404484 (2024). 10.1002/adfm.202404484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202404484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, X. Wang, M. Li, W. Zhu, H. Luo et al., Built-in electric field enhancement strategy induced by cross-dimensional nano-heterointerface design for electromagnetic wave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(18), 2407217 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202407217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202407217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Cai, L. Zhou, P.-Y. Zhao, H.-L. Peng, Z.-L. Hou et al., Interface-induced dual-pinning mechanism enhances low-frequency electromagnetic wave loss. Nat. Commun. <b>15</b>(1), 3299 (2024). 10.1038/s41467-024-47537-5
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-47537-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11024160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38632245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Liu, Y. Li, H. Xu, L. Shi, J. Kong et al., Hierarchical Fe-Co@TiO<sub>2</sub> with incoherent heterointerfaces and gradient magnetic domains for electromagnetic wave absorption. ACS Nano <b>18</b>(1), 560&#x2013;570 (2024). 10.1021/acsnano.3c08569
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.3c08569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38109426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Huang, L. Wang, K. Pei, W. You, X. Yu et al., Multidimension-controllable synthesis of MOF-derived Co@N-doped carbon composite with magnetic-dielectric synergy toward strong microwave absorption. Small <b>16</b>(14), 2000158 (2020). 10.1002/smll.202000158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202000158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32182407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhang, C. Sun, Y. Jiang, Z. Fan, R. Che et al., Construction of chiral-magnetic-dielectric trinity structures with different magnetic systems for efficient low-frequency microwave absorption. Small <b>20</b>(50), 2407176 (2024). 10.1002/smll.202407176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202407176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39328032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J.-C. Shu, M.-S. Cao, M. Zhang, X.-X. Wang, W.-Q. Cao et al., Molecular patching engineering to drive energy conversion as efficient and environment-friendly cell toward wireless power transmission. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>30</b>(10), 1908299 (2020). 10.1002/adfm.201908299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.201908299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Hu, J. Luo, H. Wen, C. Liu, J. Peng et al., Enhanced electromagnetic energy conversion in an entropy-driven dual-magnetic system for superior electromagnetic wave absorption. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(14), 2418304 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202418304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202418304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Pan, L. Cheng, D. Lan, S. Zhang, M. He et al., Conductor-semiconductor heterointerface polarization enhancement for superior electromagnetic wave absorption. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. <b>244</b>, 129&#x2013;141 (2026). 10.1016/j.jmst.2025.05.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2025.05.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R.-Y. Ma, S.-Q. Yi, Z.-X. Wang, Y.-F. Lin, R.-P. Nie et al., Highly stretchable liquid metal/poly(urethane-urea) composite with self-healing ability for electromagnetic interference shielding. Compos. B Eng. <b>306</b>, 112808 (2025). 10.1016/j.compositesb.2025.112808</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2025.112808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Qu, H. Sun, Y. Sun, M. He, R. Xing et al., 2D/2D coupled MOF/Fe composite metamaterials enable robust ultra-broadband microwave absorption. Nat. Commun. <b>15</b>(1), 5642 (2024). 10.1038/s41467-024-49762-4
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-49762-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11226717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38969643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Zhou, S. Tan, J. Wang, Y. Wu, L. Liang et al., &#x201c;Three-in-one&#x201d; multi-scale structural design of carbon fiber-based composites for personal electromagnetic protection and thermal management. Nano-Micro Lett. <b>15</b>(1), 176 (2023). 10.1007/s40820-023-01144-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-023-01144-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10333170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37428269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>