<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41766041</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1348-4214</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hypertension research : official journal of the Japanese Society of Hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hypertens Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differential cardiovascular and autonomic responses to structurally distinct intermittent hypoxia paradigms in rats.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41440-026-02588-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Intermittent hypoxia (IH), the key physiological stressor in obstructive sleep apnea, is commonly quantified by respiratory event frequency. However, clinical heterogeneity in hypertension among patients with comparable apnea-hypopnea index (AHI) suggests that episode timing, including the duration and frequency of desaturation-reoxygenation cycles, may exert distinct biological effects even under equal cumulative burden. To test this, male Wistar-Kyoto rats were exposed for 21 days (8&#x2009;h/day) to IH with either 10-s hypoxia duration at 30 cycles/h (10s-30c) or 5-s hypoxia duration at 60 cycles/h (5s-60c), while room air served as a control. Cardiovascular regulation was evaluated by continuous measurement of mean arterial pressure, heart-rate variability, and baroreflex sensitivity, and broader systemic effects were assessed through sleep-wake architecture, EEG activity, spatial memory, and cortical/hippocampal protein markers. Both IH groups had elevated blood pressure and disrupted autonomic balance compared with controls. The 5s-60c group produced more sustained hypertension, blunted nocturnal dipping, greater baroreflex impairment, and enhanced beta power during sleep, indicating persistent sympathetic drive. By contrast, the 10s-30c group was associated with increased paradoxical sleep, impaired spatial memory, reduced NeuN expression, and stronger upregulation of IBA-1 and NF-&#x3ba;B. These findings demonstrate that equivalent cumulative hypoxic exposure with different temporal structures yields divergent cardiovascular and neurocognitive outcomes. High-frequency, short-duration episodes preferentially promoted cardiovascular dysregulation, whereas longer episodes were linked to neurocognitive vulnerability. Consideration of hypoxic episode duration may improve the mechanistic interpretation of cardiovascular heterogeneity associated with sleep-disordered breathing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>She</LastName><ForeName>Sheng-Chieh</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Chi-Wei</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chieh-Wen</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience, National Chengchi University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Mind, Brain and Learning, National Chengchi University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Han</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Management, National Taipei University of Nursing and Health Sciences, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shiang-Suo</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Institute of Medicine, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Jung</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Master Program in Biomedical Science, School of Medicine, Tzu Chi University, Hualien, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Tzu Chi University, Hualien, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>Terry B J</ForeName><Initials>TBJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Education and Research, Taipei City Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tsaotun Psychiatric Center, Ministry of Health and Welfare, Nantou, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Ding-I</ForeName><Initials>DI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsie</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Heng</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Liang</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1554-1307</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Taipei City Hospital Renai Branch, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC. DAA87@tpech.gov.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Informatics, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC. DAA87@tpech.gov.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Cheryl C H</ForeName><Initials>CCH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1053-997X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC. cchyang@nycu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sleep Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC. cchyang@nycu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Education and Research, Taipei City Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC. cchyang@nycu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan, ROC. cchyang@nycu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hypertens Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9307690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0916-9636</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Implemental hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intermittent hypoxia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Compliance with ethical standards. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests. Declaration of generative AI and AI-assisted technologies in the writing process: During the preparation of this work, the authors used ChatGPT (OpenAI) to assist with language refinement and improvement of clarity in English writing. After using this tool, the authors reviewed and edited the content as needed and take full responsibility for the content of the publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41766041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41440-026-02588-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41440-026-02588-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yeghiazarians Y, Jneid H, Tietjens JR, Redline S, Brown DL, El-Sherif N, et al. Obstructive sleep apnea and cardiovascular disease: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2021;144:e56&#x2013;e67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34148375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JG, Ramar K, Olson EJ. Updates on definition, consequences, and management of obstructive sleep apnea. Mayo Clin Proc. 2011;86:549&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21628617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3104914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4065/mcp.2010.0810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-de-la-Torre M, Campos-Rodriguez F, Barb&#xe9; F. Obstructive sleep apnoea and cardiovascular disease. Lancet Respir Med. 2013;1:61&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24321805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(12)70051-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenzweig I, Glasser M, Polsek D, Leschziner GD, Williams SC, Morrell MJ. Sleep apnoea and the brain: a complex relationship. Lancet Respir Med. 2015;3:404&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25887982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(15)00090-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapur VK, Auckley DH, Chowdhuri S, Kuhlmann DC, Mehra R, Ramar K, et al. Clinical practice guideline for diagnostic testing for adult obstructive sleep apnea: an American Academy of Sleep Medicine clinical practice guideline. Clin Sleep Med. 2017;13:479&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.6506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarbarzin A, Sands SA, Stone KL, Taranto-Montemurro L, Messineo L, Terrill PI, et al. The hypoxic burden of sleep apnoea predicts cardiovascular disease-related mortality: the osteoporotic fractures in men study and the sleep heart health study. Eur Heart J. 2019;40:1149&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30376054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6451769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehy624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaffe K, Laffan AM, Harrison SL, Redline S, Spira AP, Ensrud KE, et al. Sleep-disordered breathing, hypoxia, and risk of mild cognitive impairment and dementia in older women. JAMA. 2011;306:613&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3600944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie L. Oxidative stress in obstructive sleep apnea and intermittent hypoxia-revisited-the bad, ugly and good: implications to the heart and brain. Sleep Med Rev. 2015;20:27&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25155182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2014.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin M, Liu R, Gozal D, Wead WB, Chapleau MW, Wurster R, et al. Chronic intermittent hypoxia impairs baroreflex control of heart rate but enhances heart rate responses to vagal efferent stimulation in anesthetized mice. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2007;293:H997&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17384123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.01124.2006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Amine B, Fournier J, Minoves M, Baillieul S, Roche F, Perek N, et al. Cerebral oxidative stress, inflammation and apoptosis induced by intermittent hypoxia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of rodent data. Eur Respir Rev 2024;33:240162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polotsky VY, Rubin AE, Balbir A, Dean T, Smith PL, Schwartz AR, et al. Intermittent hypoxia causes REM sleep deficits and decreases EEG delta power in NREM sleep in the C57BL/6J mouse. Sleep Med. 2006;7:7&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16309961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2005.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam CS, Tipoe GL, So KF, Fung ML. Neuroprotective mechanism of Lycium barbarum polysaccharides against hippocampal-dependent spatial memory deficits in a rat model of obstructive sleep apnea. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0117990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25714473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0117990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blekic N, Bold I, Mettay T, Bruyneel M. Impact of desaturation patterns versus apnea-hypopnea index in the development of cardiovascular comorbidities in obstructive sleep apnea patients. Nat Sci Sleep. 2022;14:1457&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo TB, Shaw FZ, Lai CJ, Lai CW, Yang CC. Changes in sleep patterns in spontaneously hypertensive rats. Sleep. 2004;27:406&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo TB, Lai CJ, Shaw FZ, Lai CW, Yang CC. Sleep-related sympathovagal imbalance in SHR. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2004;286:H1170&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14630638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00418.2003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JY, Kuo TB, Hsieh SS, Yang CC. Changes in electroencephalogram and heart rate during treadmill exercise in the rat. Neurosci Lett. 2008;434:175&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18325668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neulet.2008.01.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo TB, Lai CJ, Huang YT, Yang CC. Regression analysis between heart rate variability and baroreflex-related vagus nerve activity in rats. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2005;16:864&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16101628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1540-8167.2005.40656.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang CC, Shaw FZ, Lai CJ, Lai CW, Kuo TB. Relationship between electroencephalogram slow-wave magnitude and heart rate variability during sleep in rats. Neurosci Lett. 2003;336:21&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12493593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0304-3940(02)01200-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo TB, Yien HW, Hseu SS, Yang CC, Lin YY, Lee LC, et al. Diminished vasomotor component of systemic arterial pressure signals and baroreflex in brain death. Am J Physiol. 1997;273:H1291&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9321818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher EC, Lesske J, Qian W, Miller CC, Unger T. Repetitive, episodic hypoxia causes diurnal elevation of blood pressure in rats. Hypertension. 1992;19:555&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1592450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.HYP.19.6.555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao H, Han Z, Huang S, Bai R, Ge X, Chen F, et al. Intermittent hypoxia caused cognitive dysfunction relate to miRNAs dysregulation in hippocampus. Behav Brain Res. 2017;335:80&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28647595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2017.06.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji ES, Kim YM, Shin MS, Kim CJ, Lee KS, Kim K, et al. Treadmill exercise enhances spatial learning ability through suppressing hippocampal apoptosis in Huntington&#x2019;s disease rats. J Exerc Rehabil. 2015;11:133&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26171378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4492422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.150212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippone EJ, Foy AJ, Naccarelli GV. Controversies in hypertension III: dipping, nocturnal hypertension, and the morning surge. Am J Med. 2023;136:629&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36893831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2023.02.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ili&#x107; A, Stoj&#x161;i&#x107;-Milosavljevi&#x107; A, Miljkovi&#x107; T, Bjelobrk M, Stoj&#x161;i&#x107; S, Tadi&#x107; S, et al. The Influence of non-dipping pattern of blood pressure in gestational hypertension on early onset of hypertension later in life, single-center experience in a very-high-risk southeast and central European country. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:11324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshide S, Kario K, Hoshide Y, Umeda Y, Hashimoto T, Kunii O, et al. Associations between nondipping of nocturnal blood pressure decrease and cardiovascular target organ damage in strictly selected community-dwelling normotensives. Am J Hypertens. 2003;16:434&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12799090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0895-7061(03)00567-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkat P, Chopp M, Chen J. Models and mechanisms of vascular dementia. Exp Neurol. 2015;272:97&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25987538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4631710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2015.05.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billman GE, Schwartz PJ, Stone HL. Baroreceptor reflex control of heart rate: a predictor of sudden cardiac death. Circulation. 1982;66:874&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7116603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.66.4.874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ferrari GM, Landolina M, Mantica M, Manfredini R, Schwartz PJ, Lotto A. Baroreflex sensitivity, but not heart rate variability, is reduced in patients with life-threatening ventricular arrhythmias long after myocardial infarction. Am Heart J. 1995;130:473&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7661063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0002-8703(95)90354-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Rovere MT, Pinna GD, Hohnloser SH, Marcus FI, Mortara A, Nohara R, et al. Baroreflex sensitivity and heart rate variability in the identification of patients at risk for life-threatening arrhythmias: implications for clinical trials. Circulation. 2001;103:2072&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11319197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.103.16.2072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freet CS, Stoner JF, Tang X. Baroreflex and chemoreflex controls of sympathetic activity following intermittent hypoxia. Auton Neurosci. 2013;174:8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23305890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2012.12.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Rio R, Andrade DC, Lucero C, Arias P, Iturriaga R. Carotid body ablation abrogates hypertension and autonomic alterations induced by intermittent hypoxia in rats. Hypertension. 2016;68:436&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27381902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.116.07255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalacheva P, Thum J, Yokoe T, O'Donnell CP, Khoo MC. Development of autonomic dysfunction with intermittent hypoxia in a lean murine model. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2013;188:143&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23774144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3729633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2013.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugniaux JV, Pialoux V, Foster GE, Duggan CT, Eliasziw M, Hanly PJ, et al. Effects of intermittent hypoxia on erythropoietin, soluble erythropoietin receptor and ventilation in humans. Eur Respir J. 2011;37:880&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00156009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam SY, Tipoe GL, Fung ML. Upregulation of erythropoietin and its receptor expression in the rat carotid body during chronic and intermittent hypoxia. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2009;648:207&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19536483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-90-481-2259-2_24</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun P, Kumar N, Tin A, Zhao J, Brown MR, Lin Z, et al. Epidemiologic and genetic associations of erythropoietin with blood pressure, hypertension, and coronary artery disease. Hypertension. 2021;78:1555&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34488438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8516734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.121.17597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Z, Ruan Z, Li M, Ren R, Ma Y, Zeng J, et al. Intermittent hypoxia inhibits anti-tumor immune response via regulating PD-L1 expression in lung cancer cells and tumor-associated macrophages. Int Immunopharmacol. 2023;122:110652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37478668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2023.110652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K Dolu A, Korkmaz A, Kundi H, Guray U. Whole blood viscosity predicts nondipping circadian pattern in essential hypertension. Biomark Med. 2020;14:1307&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huart J, Persu A, Lengel&#xe9; JP, Krzesinski JM, Jouret F, Stergiou GS. Pathophysiology of the nondipping blood pressure pattern. Hypertension. 2023;80:719&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36606502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.122.19996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Bue A, Salvaggio A, Insalaco G, Marrone O. Extreme REM rebound during continuous positive airway pressure titration for obstructive sleep apnea in a depressed patient. Case Rep Med. 2014;2014:292181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24876843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4024427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahr K, Geisler V, Huppertz T, Groppa S, Matthias C, Gouveris H, et al. Intensity of respiratory cortical arousals is a distinct pathophysiologic feature and is associated with disease severity in obstructive sleep apnea patients. Brain Sci. 2021;11:282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franken P. Long-term vs. short-term processes regulating REM sleep. J Sleep Res. 2002;11:17&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11869422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2869.2002.00275.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitka T, Katai Z, Pap D, Molnar E, Adori C, Bagdy G. Small platform sleep deprivation selectively increases the average duration of rapid eye movement sleep episodes during sleep rebound. Behav Brain Res. 2009;205:482&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19665493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2009.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnet MH, Arand DL. Hyperarousal and insomnia: state of the science. Sleep Med Rev. 2010;14:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19640748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2009.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlis ML, Smith MT, Andrews PJ, Orff H, Giles DE. Beta/Gamma EEG activity in patients with primary and secondary insomnia and good sleeper controls. Sleep. 2001;24:110&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11204046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/24.1.110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnbull CD. Intermittent hypoxia, cardiovascular disease and obstructive sleep apnoea. J Thorac Dis. 2018;10:S33&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29445526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5803045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jtd.2017.10.33</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seravalle G, Mancia G, Grassi G. Role of the sympathetic nervous system in hypertension and hypertension-related cardiovascular disease. High Blood Press Cardiovasc Prev. 2014;21:89&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24789091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40292-014-0056-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf J, Hering D, Narkiewicz K. Non-dipping pattern of hypertension and obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Hypertens Res. 2010;33:867&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20818398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/hr.2010.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiina K. Obstructive sleep apnea -related hypertension: a review of the literature and clinical management strategy. Hypertens Res. 2024;47:3085&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39210083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11534699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41440-024-01852-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges JG, Ginani GE, Hachul H, Cintra FD, Tufik S, Pomp&#xe9;ia S. Executive functioning in obstructive sleep apnea syndrome patients without comorbidities: focus on the fractionation of executive functions. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol. 2013;35:1094&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24295424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13803395.2013.858661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goussakov I, Synowiec S, Yarnykh V, Drobyshevsky A. Immediate and delayed decrease of long-term potentiation and memory deficits after neonatal intermittent hypoxia. Int J Dev Neurosci. 2019;74:27&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30858028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6461389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijdevneu.2019.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khuu MA, Pagan CM, Nallamothu T, Hevner RF, Hodge RD, Ramirez JM, et al. Intermittent hypoxia disrupts adult neurogenesis and synaptic plasticity in the dentate gyrus. J Neurosci. 2019;39:1320&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30587544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1359-18.2018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Yang T, Sun J, Zhang S, Liu S. SENP1 modulates microglia-mediated neuroinflammation toward intermittent hypoxia-induced cognitive decline through the de-SUMOylation of NEMO. J Cell Mol Med. 2021;25:6841&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34120412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8278079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcmm.16689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei RM, Zhang MY, Fang SK, Liu GX, Hu F, Li XY, et al. Melatonin attenuates intermittent hypoxia-induced cognitive impairment in aged mice: The role of inflammation and synaptic plasticity. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2025;171:107210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39378690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2024.107210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun F. The impact of blood pressure variability on cognition: current limitations and new advances. J Hypertens. 2023;41:888&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37016905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10158606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouhamida E, Morciano G, Perrone M, Kahsay AE, Della Sala M, Wieckowski MR, et al. The interplay of hypoxia signaling on mitochondrial dysfunction and inflammation in cardiovascular diseases and cancer: from molecular mechanisms to therapeutic approaches. Biology. 2022;11:282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Ma D, Wu Y, Xu Z. Impact of chronic intermittent hypoxia on cognitive function and hippocampal neurons in mice: a study of inflammatory and oxidative stress pathways. Nat Sci Sleep. 2024;16:2029&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39712883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11660659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NSS.S489232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia NN, Yao MF, Zhu CX, He MJ, Zhu HF, Chen ZY, et al. Chronic intermittent hypoxia-induced neural injury: pathophysiology, neurodegenerative implications, and therapeutic insights. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2025;31:e70384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40260643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12012570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cns.70384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarbarzin A, Sands SA, Taranto-Montemurro L, Vena D, Sofer T, Kim SW, et al. The sleep apnea-specific hypoxic burden predicts incident heart failure. Chest. 2020;158:739&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7417383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2020.03.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Wei DH, Zhang J, Cao J. Time under 90% oxygen saturation and systemic hypertension in patients with obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Nat Sci Sleep. 2022;14:2123&#x2013;2132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9719713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NSS.S388238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>