<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41476134</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Socioeconomic and climatic factors influencing desertification in Saudi Arabia through an ARDL approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3990</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3990</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3990</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34168-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In&#x2002;this study, based on the sample covering 1990-2023, we use ARDL methods to test potential driving forces of Desertification (DS), including key socioeconomic and climatic determinants in Saudi Arabia: renewable energy consumption (RE) , economic growth (EG) , CO&#x2082; emissions(CO2E), temperature anomaly(TA) and vegetation index(VI). To address the lack of time-series-integrated data studies in Saudi Arabia, this article uses ARDL and VECM models to capture short-run dynamics and long-run equilibrium. The findings indicate that a 1% increase in renewable energy results in an average reduction of 0.1003% in desertification . In contrast, improvements in the vegetation index have been more effective and could reduce desertification by up to 8.7%.Conversely, improved economic growth and increased CO2 emissions significantly aggravate land degradation. These results illustrate the need to reconcile Vision 2030's development aims with environmental protection. Recommendations on policy: Increase the proportion of renewable energy to 50% of total energy consumption by 2030; expand afforestation to restore 10% of degraded land per year; work toward universal environmental protection for major development projects at a rate commensurate with the scale and potential impact. .</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derouez</LastName><ForeName>Faten</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quantitative Method Department, School of Business, King Faisal University, Hofouf, 31982, Saudi Arabia. fderouez@kfu.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ifa</LastName><ForeName>Adel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Economics and Management, Mahdia, University of Monastir, Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shammre</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah Al</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Economics Department, School of Business, King Faisal University, Hofouf, 31982, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zayed</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, College of Science, Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University (IMSIU), Riyadh, SA, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alrawad</LastName><ForeName>Mahmaod</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quantitative Method Department, School of Business, King Faisal University, Hofouf, 31982, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>KFU252943</GrantID><Agency>King Faisal University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CO2 emissions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Desertification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic growth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renewable energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Temperature anomaly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vegetation index</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41476134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12856010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34168-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34168-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Derouez, F. Technological advancements and economic growth as key drivers of renewable energy production in Saudi arabia: an ARDL and VECM analysis. <i>Energies</i><b>18</b> (2177). 10.3390/en18092177 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faten, F. et al. Energy, Technology, and Economic Growth in Saudi Arabia: An ARDL and VECM Analysis Approach. <i>Heliyon </i><b>10</b>, (2024). 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10878952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38384577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, Z., Gui, D., Abd-Elmabod, S. K., Murtaza, G. &amp; Ali, S. An overview of global desertification control efforts: key challenges and overarching solutions. <i>Soil. Use Management</i>. <b>40</b>, 13154 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sum.13154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla, K., Mutema, M., Chivenge, P., Everson, C. &amp; Chaplot, V. Grassland rehabilitation significantly increases soil carbon stocks by reducing net soil CO2 emissions. <i>Soil. Use Management</i>. <b>38</b>, 1250&#x2013;1265 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sum.12790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, Y., Li, Y., Liu, W., Wang, X. &amp; Chen, Y. Effects of environment factors on the carbon fluxes of Semi-Fixed sandy land recovering from degradation. <i>Front. Ecol. Evol.</i><b>11</b>, 1178660 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fevo.2023.1178660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Blooshi, L. S., Issa, S. &amp; Ksiksi, T. Assessing the environmental impact of climate change on desert ecosystems: A review. <i>Adv. Ecol. Environ. Res.</i><b>5</b>, 27&#x2013;52 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B. et al. Desertification reversion alters soil greenhouse gas emissions in the Eastern Hobq Desert, China. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollution Research</i>. <b>27</b>, 15624&#x2013;15634 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-08117-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Global Research Trends on the Role of Soil Erosion in Carbon Cycling Under Climate Change: A Bibliometric Analysis (1994&#x2013;2024. <i>Atmosphere </i><b>16</b>, 934. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, J. et al. Temporal variability of temperature, precipitation and drought indices in Hyper-Arid region of Northwest China for the past 60 years. <i>Atmosphere</i><b>13</b>, 1561 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/atmos13101561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yisehak, B. et al. Spatio-temporal characteristics of meteorological drought under changing climate in Semi&#x2010;arid region of Northern Ethiopia. <i>Environ. Syst. Res.</i><b>10</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40068-021-00226-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seifu, T. K. &amp; Demessie Eshetu, K. Characterizing the aridity indices and potential evapotranspiration using CMIP6-GCMs in two distinct regions of Ethiopia. <i>J. Water Climate Change</i>. <b>15</b>, 1507&#x2013;1531 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wcc.2024.394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Ma, L., Liu, T., Qiao, Z. &amp; Chen, Y. Influence of Key Climate Factors on Desertification in Inner Mongolia. <i>Atmosphere </i>14<i>,</i> 1404. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, S., Wang, J., Altansukh, O. &amp; Chuluun, T. Spatiotemporal evolution and driving mechanisms of desertification on the Mongolian plateau. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>941</b>, 173566 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.173566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38823694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chouari, W. Assessment of Vegetation Cover Changes and the Contributing Factors in the Al- Ahsa Oasis Using Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI. <i>Regional Sustainability </i>5, 100111. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbdelRahman, M. A. E. An overview of land Degradation, desertification and sustainable land management using GIS and remote sensing applications. <i>Rend. Lincei Scienze Fis. E</i>. <b> Naturali</b>, 767&#x2013;808 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12210-023-01155-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A&#x15f;&#x131;k, &#x15e;. Agricultural Drought Monitoring Using Surface Temperature and Vegetation Indices from Satellite Images. In <i>Ege &#xdc;niversitesi Ziraat Fak&#xfc;ltesi Dergisi</i>; 151&#x2013;160. (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarahmadi, H., Desille, Y., Goold, J. &amp; Pietracaprina, F. Identifying vegetation patterns for a qualitative assessment of land degradation using a cellular automata model and satellite imagery. <i>Phys. Rev. E</i>. <b>110</b>, 024136 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.110.024136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39294942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL-Dulliami; A, A. Using normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) and some of vegetation indicators for the monitoring desertification and sand dunes in the Baiji/Iraq. <i>Tikrit J. of Pure Sci.</i><b>20</b>, 109&#x2013;120 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, A. A., Ouhassan, Y., Abouyaakoub, M., Chahboun, M. &amp; Hihi, H. The impact of desert regions on solar energy production with the evaluation of groundwater for maintenance: A case study in Morocco. <i>Sustainability</i><b>16</b>, 5476 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16135476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, J. et al. Ecological Dichotomies of Solar Energy expansion: Resilience in Arid Regions versus Fragility in Humid Ecosystems. <i>Frontiers in Plant Science </i>16, 1549519. (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40104031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Pastor, R., Liu, Y., Wang, H. &amp; Zhang, L. Positive impacts of typical desert photovoltaic scenarios in China on the growth and physiology of Sand-Adapted plants. <i> Environmental Sci. Pollution Res.</i><b>30</b>, 12345&#x2013;12356 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClung, M. R., Smith, J. A. &amp; Thompson, L. M. Minimizing impacts of future renewable energy development on the world&#x2019;s desert ecosystems. <i>Front. Sustain.</i><b>3</b>, 900468 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frsus.2022.900468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaliq, A. &amp; Mamkhezri, J. The impact of renewable portfolio standards and Land-Use governance on CO2 and gross total emissions in four US regions. <i>Appl. Energy</i>. <b>372</b>, 123832 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.123832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaliq, A. &amp; Mamkhezri, J. Asymmetrical analysis of economic complexity and economic freedom on environment in South asia: A NARDL approach. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i><b>30</b>, 89049&#x2013;89070 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-023-28481-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37450190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaliq, A., Atique, A., Hina, H. &amp; Bilal, A. Impact of electricity Generation, Consumption, energy Trade, and ICT on the environment in pakistan: A NARDL and ARDL analysis. <i>Int. J. Sustainable Dev. World Ecol.</i><b>31</b>, 279&#x2013;297 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13504509.2023.2277918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhini, M. et al. The Land Degradation and Desertification-Socioeconomic Nexus in Egypt&#x2019;s Delta Region: A Case Study on Alexandria and Beheira. <i>Heliyon </i><b>10</b>, e31165, (2024). 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11133725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38813219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balogun, F. B., Dhakir, A. A. &amp; Rozaini, R. From Desert to Oasis: Empowering Sahel&#x2019;s Prosperity Through Green Finance. <i>African Journal of Business and Economic Research </i><b>19</b><i>,</i> (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweidan, O. D. &amp; Elbargathi, K. Does environmental stress affect economic growth: evidence from the Gulf Cooperation Council countries? <i>Clean. Technol. Environ.</i><b> Policy</b>, 2561&#x2013;2574 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10098-021-02169-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8325413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34366762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hissan, R. U., Shafiq, H. &amp; Nassani, A. A. Assessment of Spatio-Temporal dynamics of land degradation and desertification in Pakistan and its impact on agriculture productivity. <i> Environment Dev. Sustain.</i><b>26</b>, 32337&#x2013;32357 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10668-024-05224-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldegheishem, A. Factors affecting ecological footprint in Saudi arabia: A panel data analysis. <i> Frontiers Environ. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 1384451 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2024.1384451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derouez, F. &amp; Ifa, A. Sustainable Food Security: Balancing Desalination, Climate Change, and Population Growth in Five Arab Countries Using ARDL and VECM. <i> Sustainability </i><b>16</b>(6), 2302. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darwez, F. et al. Assessing the impact of oil price Vol-Atility on food prices in Saudi arabia: insights from nonlinear autoregressive distributed lags (NARDL) analysis. <i>ECO-NOMICS-Innovative Econ. Res. J.</i><b>11</b>, 5&#x2013;23 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesaran, M. H., Shin, Y. &amp; Smith, R. J. Bounds testing approaches to the analysis of cointegrated variables. <i> Journal Appl. Econometrics</i>. <b>16</b>, 289&#x2013;326 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jae.616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesaran, M. H. &amp; Pesaran, B. <i>Working with Microfit 4.0: Interactive Econometric Analysis</i> 29 (Oxford University Press, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newey, W. K., West, K. D. A. &amp; Simple Positive Semi-Definite, Heteroskedasticity and Autocorrelationconsistent Covariance Matrix (1986).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engle, R. F. &amp; Granger, C. W. J. Co-Integration and Error-Correction: Representation, Estimation, and testing. <i>EconomIetrica</i><b>55</b>, 251&#x2013;276 (1987).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1913236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesaran, M. H. &amp; Shin, Y. An Autoregressive Distributed Lag Modelling Approach to Cointegration Analysis. In Proceedings of the Proceedings of the Econometrics and Economic Theory in the 20th Century: The Ragnar Frisch Centennial Symposium; Strom, S., Ed.; Cambridge University Press: Cambridge, UK, 371&#x2013;413. (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen, S. &amp; Juselius, K. Maximum likelihood Estimation and inference on Cointegration&#x2014;with appucations to the demand for money. <i>Oxf. Bull. Econ. Stat.</i><b>52</b>, 169&#x2013;210 (1990).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-0084.1990.mp52002003.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ifa, A. &amp; Al Shammre, A. Energy transition and poverty alleviation in light of environmental and economic challenges: A comparative study in China and the European union region. <i>Sustain. (Switzerland)</i>. <b>16</b>10.3390/su16114468 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granger, C. W. J. &amp; Engle, R. F. Econometric forecasting: A brief survey of current and future techniques. <i>Clim. Change</i>. <b>11</b>, 117&#x2013;139 (1987).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00138798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ifa, A. &amp; Guetat, I. Does public expenditure on education promote Tunisian and Moroccan GDP per capita? ARDL approach. <i>J. Finance Data Sci.</i><b>4</b>, 234&#x2013;246 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfds.2018.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharbi, F., Mathlouthi, N., Ifa, A., Alrawad, M. &amp; Ahmed, N. How does the stock market development React to energy consumption? Evidence from the ARDL panel approach. <i>ECONOMICS - Innovative Econ. Res. Journal</i><b>13</b> (1), 247-265 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derouez, F. &amp; Ifa, A. Desalination for food security in Tunisia: Harnessing renewable energy to address water scarcity and climate change by using ARDL approach and VECM technical. <i>Sustainability</i><b>17</b>, 1046 (2025). 10.3390/su17031046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derouez, F. &amp; Ifa, A. Assessing the sustainability of Southeast Asia&#x2019;s energy transition: A comparative analysis. <i>Energies</i><b>18</b>, 287 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>