<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41768429</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1538-1927</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Hispanic higher education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hispanic High Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing for Change: Principles for STEM Programs That Foster Organizational Transformation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>137</StartPage><EndPage>155</EndPage><MedlinePgn>137-155</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15381927261418040</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study examines how STEM programs can be intentionally designed to serve as mechanisms for organizational transformation. Grounded in organizational change theory and findings from a multi-site qualitative case study of the Meyerhoff Adaptation Project, the study presents four design principles that illustrate how intentional choices can reconfigure structures, cultures, and power dynamics, which enable inequity within higher education. The principles offer guidance for developing sustainable, equity-centered STEM initiatives that advance institutional change.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perez</LastName><ForeName>Edwin Jose</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-3515-1260</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Texas at El Paso, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Hispanic High Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535831</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1538-1927</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa"><AbstractText>Este estudio examina c&#xf3;mo los programas de STEM pueden dise&#xf1;arse intencionadamente para servir como mecanismos de transformaci&#xf3;n organizativa. Bas&#xe1;ndose en la teor&#xed;a del cambio organizativo y en los resultados de un estudio de caso cualitativo realizado en m&#xfa;ltiples centros sobre el Proyecto de Adaptaci&#xf3;n Meyerhoff, el estudio presenta cuatro principios de dise&#xf1;o que ilustran c&#xf3;mo las decisiones intencionadas pueden reconfigurar las estructuras, las culturas y las din&#xe1;micas de poder que permiten la desigualdad en la educaci&#xf3;n superior. Los principios ofrecen orientaci&#xf3;n para desarrollar iniciativas STEM sostenibles y centradas en la equidad que promuevan el cambio institucional.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STEM equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STEM intervention programs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organizational change</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41768429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12944547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15381927261418040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_15381927261418040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrica E. J., Lane T. B., Zobac S., Collins E. (2022). Sense of belonging and community building within a STEM intervention program: A focus on Latino male undergraduates&#x2019; experiences. Journal of Hispanic Higher Education, 21(2), 228&#x2013;242. 10.1177/1538192720974884</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1538192720974884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asai D. J. (2020). Race matters. Cell, 181(4), 754&#x2013;757. 10.1016/j.cell.2020.03.044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2020.03.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32413295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battey D., Leyva L. A. (2016). A framework for understanding whiteness in mathematics education. Journal of Urban Mathematics Education, 9(2), 49&#x2013;80. 10.21423/jume-v9i2a294</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21423/jume-v9i2a294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beasley M. A., Fischer M. J. (2012). Why they leave: The impact of stereotype threat on the attrition of women and minorities from science, math and engineering majors. Social Psychology of Education, 15(4), 427&#x2013;448. 10.1007/s11218-012-9185-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11218-012-9185-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Calabrese Barton A., Menezes S., Mayas R., Ambrogio O., Ballard M. (2018). What are the cultural norms of STEM and why do they matter?
Center for Advancement of Informal Science Education. https://informalscience.org/research/what-are-cultural-norms-stem-and-why-do-they-matter/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlone H. B., Johnson A. (2007). Understanding the science experiences of successful women of color: Science identity as an analytic lens. Journal of Research in Science Teaching, 44(8), 1187&#x2013;1218. 10.1002/tea.20237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tea.20237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpi A., Ronan D. M., Falconer H. M., Boyd H. H., Lents N. H. (2013). Development and implementation of targeted STEM retention strategies at a Hispanic-serving institution. Journal of Hispanic Higher Education, 12(3), 280&#x2013;299. 10.1177/1538192713486279</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1538192713486279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro E. L. (2014). &#x201c;Underprepared&#x201d; and &#x201c;at-risk&#x201d;: Disrupting deficit discourses in undergraduate STEM recruitment and retention programming. Journal of Student Affairs Research and Practice, 51(4), 407&#x2013;419. 10.1515/jsarp-2014-0041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jsarp-2014-0041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobian K. P., Ramos H. V. (2021). A cross-case analysis of developing program sustainability and institutionalization in early stages of a multisite biomedical student diversity initiative. BMC Medical Education, 21(1), 254. 10.1186/s12909-021-02663-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-021-02663-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8091701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33934702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crimmins M. T., Fisher C., Summers M. F., Williams M. E. (2017). The Meyerhoff adaptation partnership: Mid-term report. Howard Hughes Medical Institute. (Unpublished internal document).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia G. A., N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez A.M., Sansone V. A. (2019). Toward a multidimensional conceptual framework for understanding &#x201c;servingness&#x201d; in Hispanic-serving institutions: A synthesis of the research. Review of Educational Research, 89(5), 745&#x2013;784. 10.3102/0034654319864591</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/0034654319864591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George C. E., Castro E. L., Rinc&#xf3;n B. (2019). Investigating the origins of STEM intervention programs: An isomorphic analysis. Studies in Higher Education, 44(9), 1645&#x2013;1661. 10.1080/03075079.2018.1458224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03075079.2018.1458224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez A. K., Cobian K. P., Hurtado S. (2021). The role of STEM program directors in broadening the impact of STEM interventions. Education Sciences, 11(11), 742. 10.3390/educsci11110742 Article 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci11110742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson C., Beach A., Finkelstein N. (2011). Facilitating change in undergraduate STEM instructional practices: An analytic review of the literature. Journal of Research in Science Teaching, 48(8), 952&#x2013;984. 10.1002/tea.20439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tea.20439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera F., Kovats S&#xe1;nchez G. (2022). Curando la comunidad (Healing the community): Community-centered STEM identity. Journal of Hispanic Higher Education, 21(2), 135&#x2013;150. 10.1177/15381927211069543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15381927211069543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrabowski F. A., Rous P. J., Henderson P. H. (2019). The empowered university: Shared leadership, culture change, and academic success. John Hopkins University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtado S., Eagan M. K., Tran M. C., Newman C. B., Chang M. J., Velasco P. (2011). &#x201c;We do science here&#x201d;: Underrepresented students&#x2019; interactions with faculty in different college contexts. Journal of Social Issues, 67(3), 553&#x2013;579. 10.1111/j.1540-4560.2011.01714.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1540-4560.2011.01714.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3596161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23503924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kezar A. (2019). Creating a diverse student success infrastructure: The key to catalyzing cultural change for today&#x2019;s student. Pullias Center for Higher Education. https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED600559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kezar A., Holcombe E. (2017). Creating a unified community of support: Increasing success for underrepresented students in STEM (A final report on the CSU STEM collaboratives project). Pullias Center for Higher Education. https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED591453.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kezar A., Holcombe E. (2020). The role of collaboration in integrated programs aimed at supporting underrepresented student success in STEM. American Behavioral Scientist, 64(3), 325&#x2013;348. 10.1177/0002764219869421</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0002764219869421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kezar A., Holcombe E., Vigil D., Dizon J. P. M. (2021). Shared equity leadership: Making equity everyone&#x2019;s work. On shared equity leadership series. Pullias Center for Higher Education. https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED619517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kezar A., Kitchen J. A. (2020). Supporting first-generation, low-income, and underrepresented students&#x2019; transitions to college through comprehensive and integrated programs. American Behavioral Scientist, 64(3), 223&#x2013;229. 10.1177/0002764219869397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0002764219869397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Laursen S. (2019). Levers for change: An assessment of progress on changing STEM instruction. American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS). https://aaas-iuse.org/resource/levers-for-change-an-assessment-of-progress-on-changing-stem-instruction/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M. J., Collins J. D., Harwood S. A., Mendenhall R., Huntt M. B. (2020). &#x201c;If you aren&#x2019;t White, Asian or Indian, you aren&#x2019;t an engineer&#x201d;: Racial microaggressions in STEM education. International Journal of STEM Education, 7(48), 1&#x2013;16. 10.1186/s40594-020-00241-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40594-020-00241-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leyva L. A. (2021). Black women&#x2019;s counter-stories of resilience and within-group tensions in the white, patriarchal space of mathematics education. Journal for Research in Mathematics Education, 52(2), 117&#x2013;151. 10.5951/jresematheduc-2020-0027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5951/jresematheduc-2020-0027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linley J. L., George-Jackson C. E. (2013). Addressing underrepresentation in STEM fields through undergraduate interventions. In Watt S. K., Linley J. L. (Eds.), Creating successful multicultural initiatives in higher education and student affairs Vol. 2013 (Vol. 144, pp. 97&#x2013;102). New Directions for Student Services.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez N., Morgan D. L., Hutchings Q. R., Davis K. (2022). Revisiting critical STEM interventions: A literature review of STEM organizational learning. International Journal of STEM Education, 9(39), 1&#x2013;14. 10.1186/s40594-022-00357-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40594-022-00357-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9204364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35729935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Malcom S. M., Hall P. Q., Brown J. W. (1976). The double bind: The price of being a minority woman in science. American Association for the Advancement of Science. https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED130851</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maton K. I., Pollard S. A., McDougall Weise T. V., Hrabowski Fa., III(2012). The Meyerhoff scholars program: A strengths-based, institution-wide approach to increasing diversity in science, technology, engineering and mathematics. The Mount Sinai Journal of Medicine, 79(5), 610&#x2013;623. 10.1002/msj.21341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/msj.21341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3444508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22976367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoy D. L., Luedke C. L., Winkle-Wagner R. (2017). Encouraged or weeded out: Perspectives of students of color in the STEM disciplines on faculty interactions. Journal of College Student Development, 58(5), 657&#x2013;673. 10.1353/csd.2017.0052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/csd.2017.0052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee E. O. (2016). Devalued Black and Latino racial identities: A by-product of STEM college culture? American Educational Research Journal, 53(6), 1626&#x2013;1662. 10.3102/0002831216676572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/0002831216676572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee E. O. (2020). Interrogating structural racism in STEM higher education. Educational Researcher, 49(9), 633&#x2013;644. 10.3102/0013189x20972718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/0013189x20972718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee E. O., Martin D. B. (2011). &#x201c;You would not believe what I have to go through to prove my intellectual value!&#x201d; Stereotype management among academically successful Black mathematics and engineering students. American Educational Research Journal, 48(6), 1347&#x2013;1389. 10.3102/0002831211423972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/0002831211423972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Mervis J. (2025). NSF&#x2019;s grant cuts fall heaviest on scientists from underrepresented groups. Science. https://www.science.org/content/article/nsf-s-grant-cuts-fall-heaviest-scientists-underrepresented-groups</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (NASEM). (2016). Barriers and opportunities for 2-year and 4-year STEM degrees: Systemic change to support students&#x2019; diverse pathways. The National Academies Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27336114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (NASEM). (2018). Sexual harassment of women: Climate, culture, and consequences in academic sciences, engineering, and medicine. The National Academies Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29894119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (NASEM). (2023). Advancing antiracism, diversity, equity, and inclusion in STEM organizations: Beyond broadening participation. The National Academies Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36787395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (NASEM). (n.d). About the National Academies. https://www.nationalacademies.org/about</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academy of Sciences, National Academy of Engineering, &amp; Institute of Medicine. (2011). Expanding underrepresented minority participation: America&#x2019;s science and technology talent at the crossroads. National Academies Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22379652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez A.-M. (2025). Toward opportunity-centered institutional logics: Evidence from Hispanic-serving institutions and science equity efforts. Journal of Higher Education, 96(4), 678&#x2013;703. 10.1080/00221546.2024.2344531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00221546.2024.2344531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez A. M., Hurtado S., Galdeano E. C. (2015). Why study Hispanic-serving institutions? In N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez A. M., Hurtado S., Galdeano E. C. (Eds.), Hispanic-serving institutions: Advancing research and transformative practice (pp. 1&#x2013;24). Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palid O., Cashdollar S., Deangelo S., Chu C., Bates M. (2023). Inclusion in practice: A systematic review of diversity-focused STEM programming in the United States. International Journal of STEM Education, 10(2), 1&#x2013;16. 10.1186/s40594-022-00387-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40594-022-00387-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson J., Giacumo L. A., Farid A., Sadegh M. (2022). A systematic multiple studies review of low-income, first-generation, and underrepresented, STEM-degree support programs: Emerging evidence-based models and recommendations. Education Sciences, 12(5), 333, Article 5. 10.3390/educsci12050333</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci12050333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Perez E. J. (2023). The life cycle of STEM intervention programs: From adoption to institutionalization [Doctoral dissertation]. University of California. https://www.proquest.com/docview/2866297364/abstract/D75B2B9F2FCA4966PQ/1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray V. (2019). A theory of racialized organizations. American Sociological Review, 84(1), 26&#x2013;53. 10.1177/0003122418822335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0003122418822335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinholz D. L., Apkarian N. (2018). Four frames for systemic change in STEM departments. International Journal of STEM Education, 5(3), 1&#x2013;10. 10.1186/s40594-018-0103-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40594-018-0103-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6310387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30631693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinholz D. L., White I., Andrews T. (2021). Change theory in STEM higher education: A systematic review. International Journal of STEM Education, 8(37), 1&#x2013;22. 10.1186/s40594-021-00291-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40594-021-00291-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinc&#xf3;n B. E., George-Jackson C. E. (2016). STEM intervention programs: Funding practices and challenges. Studies in Higher Education, 41(3), 429&#x2013;444. 10.1080/03075079.2014.927845</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03075079.2014.927845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson T. N. (2022). The myths and misconceptions of change for STEM reform: From fixing students to fixing institutions. New Directions for Higher Education, 2022(197), 79&#x2013;89. 10.1002/he.20429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/he.20429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez J. E., Campbell K. M., Pololi L. H. (2015). Addressing disparities in academic medicine: What of the minority tax? BMC Medical Education, 15(6), 1&#x2013;5. 10.1186/s12909-015-0290-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-015-0290-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4331175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25638211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shortlidge E. E., Gray M. J., Estes S., Goodwin E. C. (2024). The value of support: STEM intervention programs impact student persistence and belonging. CBE Life Sciences Education, 23(2), Article 23. 10.1187/cbe.23-04-0059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1187/cbe.23-04-0059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11235113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38728228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stake R. E. (2006). Multiple case study analysis. Guilford Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sto. Domingo M. R., Sharp S., Freeman A., Freeman T., Harmon K., Wiggs M., Sathy V., Panter A. T., Oseguera L., Sun S., Williams M. E., Templeton J., Folt C. L., Barron E. J., Hrabowski I. I. I., F A., Maton K. I., Crimmins M., Fisher C. R., Summers M. F. (2019). Replicating Meyerhoff for inclusive excellence in STEM. Science, 364(6438), 335&#x2013;337. 10.1126/science.aar5540</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aar5540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Tsui L. (2007). Effective strategies to increase diversity in STEM fields: A review of the research literature. Journal of Negro Education, 76(4), 555&#x2013;581. https://www.jstor.org/stable/40037228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin R. K. (Ed.). (2018). Case study research and applications: Design and methods (6th ed.). Sage Publications, Inc.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>