<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41585303</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2055-2076</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A cross-sectional study on the quality of cervical cancer health information across multiple short video platforms: Analysis of content, quality, and dissemination characteristics.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20552076261415927</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20552076261415927</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20552076261415927</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20552076261415927</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cervical cancer remains a serious global threat to women's health, with rising incidence and younger demographic impact, challenging reproductive health. Short-video platforms have become key public sources for health information due to digital health communication advances, yet the scientific accuracy and reliability of their cervical cancer content are widely questioned. A systematic evaluation of its quality and dissemination patterns is lacking.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This cross-sectional study assessed cervical cancer-related videos on YouTube, TikTok, and Bilibili, examining content breadth, information quality, and dissemination impact.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Videos were systematically retrieved in July 2025 using "cervical cancer" keywords across the three platforms. After applying inclusion/exclusion criteria, 201 videos were analyzed. Quality, reliability, and educational value were evaluated using the Global Quality Score (GQS), modified DISCERN, Patient Education Materials Assessment Tool (PEMAT-assessing understandability and actionability), and Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA) benchmark criteria. Platform differences were compared using the Kruskal-Wallis H test (significance p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Platform differences emerged: YouTube videos demonstrated the highest quality (GQS mean 3.47&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.06 vs. Bilibili 2.85&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.89, TikTok 3.09&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.75; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001) and significantly higher PEMAT understandability (76.94&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;10.43 vs. TikTok 70.14&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;11.07; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). TikTok had the strongest dissemination power. Content coverage was inadequate: only 50.2% mentioned screening, 33.3% covered human papillomavirus vaccination, and a mere 8.0% recommended male vaccination. Creator expertise significantly influenced outcomes: Professionals (doctors/researchers) had higher JAMA authority scores and PEMAT actionability. Patient-created videos generated the highest interaction but scored lowest on quality metrics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cervical cancer information quality on short-video platforms is uneven. YouTube offers the highest overall quality, while TikTok achieves the widest reach but lacks content depth. Critical prevention information (e.g. male vaccination) has low coverage. Professional creators provide more reliable content but have limited reach. Platforms should enhance promotion of authoritative content and implement quality review mechanisms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-0135-5882</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Teaching Hospital of Tianjin University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74770</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Traditional Chinese Medicine Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Ren</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-0906-6382</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Wuhan, China Authors Yu Liu and Ren Wu make equal contributions to this work.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">240515</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Longyao</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5363-8575</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The First Teaching Hospital of Tianjin University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74770</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Traditional Chinese Medicine Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101690863</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-2076</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bilibili</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cervical cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HPV vaccine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TikTok</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">YouTube</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-sectional study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">information quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">screening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">short videos</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41585303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12830547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076261415927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20552076261415927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin 2021; 71: 209&#x2013;249. 20210204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D, Vignat J, Lorenzoni V, et al. Global estimates of incidence and mortality of cervical cancer in 2020: a baseline analysis of the WHO global cervical cancer elimination initiative. Lancet Glob Health 2023; 11: e197&#x2013;e206. 20221214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9848409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36528031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han B, Zheng R, Zeng H, et al. Cancer incidence and mortality in China, 2022. J Natl Cancer Cent 2024; 4: 47&#x2013;53. 20240202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11256708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39036382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Jin Q, Zhang Y, et al. Global burden of cervical cancer: current estimates, temporal trend and future projections based on the GLOBOCAN 2022. J Natl Cancer Cent 2025; 5: 322&#x2013;329. 20250123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12276544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40693230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human papillomavirus vaccines: WHO position paper, May 2017. Wkly Epidemiol Rec 2017; 92: 241&#x2013;268. 20170512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28530369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castle PE, Faupel-Badger JM, Umar A, et al. A proposed framework and lexicon for cancer prevention. Cancer Discov 2024; 14: 594&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38571411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei J, Ploner A, Elfstr&#xf6;m KM, et al. HPV vaccination and the risk of invasive cervical cancer. N Engl J Med 2020; 383: 1340&#x2013;1348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32997908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simms KT, Steinberg J, Caruana M, et al. Impact of scaled up human papillomavirus vaccination and cervical screening and the potential for global elimination of cervical cancer in 181 countries, 2020-99: a modelling study. Lancet Oncol 2019; 20: 394&#x2013;407. 20190219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30795950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Chen H, Wong MCS, et al. Effects of screening coverage and screening quality assurance on cervical cancer mortality: implication for integrated framework to monitor global implementation of cervical cancer screening programmes. J Glob Health 2024; 14: 04189. 20241025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11503509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39450607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Wang L, Zhang X, et al. Cervical cancer screening rates among Chinese women - China, 2023-2024. China CDC Wkly 2025; 7: 321&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11982917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40225781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed F, Shoufan A. Users&#x2019; experience with health-related content on YouTube: an exploratory study. BMC Public Health 2024; 24: 86. 20240103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38172765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haroon M, Wojcieszak M, Chhabra A, et al. Auditing YouTube's recommendation system for ideologically congenial, extreme, and problematic recommendations. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2023; 120: e2213020120. 20231205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10723127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38051772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannella L, Grelloni C, Natalini L, et al. The role of internet information on anti-HPV vaccines: a comprehensive overview of a double-edged sword. Vaccines (Basel) 2025 Apr 23; 13: 445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12116087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40432056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Yuan J, Zhang D, et al. Short video platforms as sources of health information about cervical cancer: a content and quality analysis. PLoS One 2024; 19: e0300180. 20240308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10923403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38457419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhong Z, Deng X, et al. Assessment of information quality and reliability on ankle sprains in short videos from Douyin and Bilibili. Sci Rep 2025; 15: 22654. 20250702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12218369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40596304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Zhang H, Cao J, et al. Quality and content evaluation of thyroid eye disease treatment information on TikTok and Bilibili. Sci Rep 2025; 15: 25134. 20250711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12254225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40646154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, He B, Wang X, et al. Information quality of videos related to esophageal cancer on Tiktok, Kwai, and Bilibili: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health 2025; 25: 2245. 20250702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12220660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40604838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnock D, Shepperd S, Needham G, et al. DISCERN: an instrument for judging the quality of written consumer health information on treatment choices. J Epidemiol Community Health 1999; 53: 105&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10396471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoemaker SJ, Wolf MS, Brach C. Development of the patient education materials assessment tool (PEMAT): a new measure of understandability and actionability for print and audiovisual patient information. Patient Educ Couns 2014; 96: 395&#x2013;403. 20140612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5085258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24973195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang S, Zhou Y, Qiu J, et al. Search engines and short video apps as sources of information on acute pancreatitis in China: quality assessment and content assessment. Front Public Health 2025; 13: 1578076. 20250604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12174125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40535445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Liu B, Yang G, et al. Assessing the content and quality of GI bleeding information on Bilibili, TikTok, and YouTube: a cross-sectional study. Sci Rep 2025; 15: 14856. 20250428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12038001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40295710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang G, Duan Li X. X. Assessment of health information in Chinese atopic dermatitis-related videos: a cross-sectional study. Digit Health 2025; 11: 20552076251346579. 20250602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12130654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40463986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lydersen S. Cohen's kappa &#x2013; a measure of agreement between observers. Tidsskr Nor Laegeforen 2018 Mar 5; 138. DOI: 10.4045/tidsskr.17.0962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4045/tidsskr.17.0962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29513468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x130;lhan S, Evran T. The quality and reliability of YouTube and TikTok videos on epidural blood patch: a cross-sectional analysis. Medicine (Baltimore) 2025; 104: e43628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12324023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40760581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Shi W. Accessing the impact of TikTok's algorithm on regional inequality in health information. Health Commun 2025; 40: 1636&#x2013;1644. 20241014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39397594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe S, Lukowiak T, Mackenzie E, et al. Mohs and social media: a cross-sectional analysis of the quality of TikTok videos regarding Mohs micrographic surgery. Dermatol Surg 2025 Dec 1; 51: 1168&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40762374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia L, Bao J, Yao K, et al. Evaluation of the quality and reliability of Chinese content about orthognathic surgery on BiliBili and TikTok: a cross-sectional study. Sci Rep 2025; 15: 28967. 20250807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12332024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40775506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y, Liao F, Li X, et al. Quality and reliability evaluation of pancreatic cancer-related video content on social short video platforms: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health 2025; 25: 1919. 20250524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12102813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40413453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Condoy JS, Arias-Intriago M, Mosquera-Qui&#xf1;&#xf3;nez M, et al. Assessing the educational impact and quality of medical microvideos on TikTok: the case of Latin America. Med Educ Online 2025; 30: 2474129. 20250308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11892066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40055918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X, Xu Y, Yang Y, et al. Assessment of non-small cell lung cancer online videos in China: a cross-sectional study on quality, content, understandability, actionability, and reliability. Health Informatics J 2025; 31: 14604582251328930. 20250403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40181503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Tang D, Jin Y, et al. Quality of cerebral palsy videos on Chinese social media platforms. Sci Rep 2025; 15: 13323. 20250417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12006377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40246856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai QY, Tang J, Meng SZ, et al. Quality assessment of videos on social media platforms related to gestational diabetes mellitus in China: a cross-section study. Heliyon 2024; 10: e29020. 20240331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11015130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38617917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He F, Yang M, Liu J, et al. Quality and reliability of pediatric pneumonia related short videos on mainstream platforms: cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health 2025; 25: 1896. 20250523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12101000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40410758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes AB, Sultan A. Problematizing content moderation by social media platforms and its impact on digital harm reduction. Harm Reduct J 2024; 21: 194. 20241109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11549828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39516798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath A, Chaffin K, Ahmad S, et al. The discourse surrounding polycystic ovary syndrome on TikTok: a social media analysis. Healthcare (Basel) 2024; 12: 2253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11593613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39595451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfender EJ, Kuijpers KL, Wanzer CV, et al. Cycle syncing and TikTok's digital landscape: a reasoned action elicitation through a critical feminist Lens. Qual Health Res 2024; 35: 10497323241297683. 20241122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12308043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39576887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diakite I, Kyle J, Situ S, et al. Assessing the influence of male vaccination on cervical cancer elimination in China under different vaccination coverage scenarios: a modeling study. Hum Vaccin Immunother 2025; 21: 2528426. 20250714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12269654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40658038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels V, Prabhu VS, Palmer C, et al. Public health impact and cost-effectiveness of catch-up 9-valent HPV vaccination of individuals through age 45 years in the United States. Hum Vaccin Immunother 2021; 17: 1943&#x2013;1951. 20210110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8189092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33427033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikoloudi M, Galanis P, Tsatsou I, et al. Demoralization, pain, and hope as predictors of desire for death in cancer patients: a cross-sectional study. J Pain Symptom Manage 2025; 70: 295&#x2013;301. 20250605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40482786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Huang L, Wang F, et al. Alexithymia and its influence on perceived social support, stress, and help-seeking attitudes in men undergoing radical prostatectomy. J Affect Disord 2025; 389: 119676. 20250612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40516627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi X, Chen J, Yang L, et al. Knowledge, attitudes, and practices toward nutritional management among patients with gastrointestinal cancer: a cross-sectional study. Asia Pac J Oncol Nurs 2025; 12: 100688. 20250311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12049811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40321361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>