<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41394246</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Role of YouTube in Patient Education on Renal Oncocytoma: A Quality Assessment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e98880</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e98880</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e98880</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.98880</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction The increasing use of advanced imaging techniques has led to more frequent detection of renal masses, including benign tumours like renal oncocytomas. Although typically asymptomatic, these tumours can complicate diagnosis due to their resemblance to renal cell carcinoma (RCC) on imaging studies. Treatment strategies for renal oncocytomas depend on tumour size, symptoms, and imaging features. As patients increasingly turn to online platforms for health information, YouTube has become a popular source for educational videos. However, the quality and reliability of such videos vary. This study evaluates YouTube videos on renal oncocytoma to assess their role in patient education. Materials and methods A systematic search of YouTube was conducted on September 5, 2025, using the keyword "renal oncocytoma." A total of 60 videos were screened, and 10 met the inclusion criteria. The educational quality and reliability of the selected videos were assessed using the Global Quality Score (GQS) and the DISCERN instrument. Video popularity was assessed with the Video Power Index (VPI). A one-sample t-test was used to compare the average GQS and DISCERN scores with predefined benchmarks. Spearman's rank correlation coefficient (&#x3c1;) was used to evaluate associations between these metrics. Results The videos analysed had a mean GQS of 3.7 &#xb1; 0.90, significantly higher than the midpoint score of 3 (p = 0.037), indicating moderate educational quality. DISCERN scores revealed that while the videos clearly stated their aims (mean score 4.8 &#xb1; 0.98, p = 0.0003), they often fell short in providing detailed, patient-centered information. The mean score for describing treatment options was 2.1 &#xb1; 1.81 (p = 0.15), and there was a notable lack of transparency regarding information sources, with a mean score of 1.7 &#xb1; 1.23 (p = 0.008). Although the videos provided current information (mean score 4.4 &#xb1; 0.94, p = 0.001), they did not adequately address uncertainties (mean score 2.0 &#xb1; 1.00, p = 0.011) or support shared decision-making (mean score 2.3 &#xb1; 1.65, p = 0.207). The VPI revealed no significant correlation with the quality metrics, with a moderate negative correlation between GQS and VPI (&#x3c1; = -0.424, p = 0.299) and a weak negative correlation between DISCERN and VPI (&#x3c1; = -0.141, p = 0.757). Conclusion This study highlights the potential of YouTube as an educational tool for renal oncocytoma, but it also underscores significant gaps in the quality and reliability of the information provided. The videos often lack comprehensive discussions on treatment options, transparency, and addressing uncertainties, which are essential for informed patient decision-making. Although YouTube can serve as a starting point for general information, patients should consult healthcare professionals for accurate, personalised advice. Efforts to improve the quality of health-related content on YouTube are needed to better support patient education.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Saad et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saad</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urology, Barts Health NHS Trust, London, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamed</LastName><ForeName>Mujahid Abuagla Dafalla</ForeName><Initials>MAD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Al Neelain University, Khartoum, SDN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">benign renal mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renal neoplasm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renal oncocytoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">youtube study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">youtube videos</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41394246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12696757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.98880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asymptomatic giant right renal oncocytoma: a case report. &#xc7;evik G, Tozsin A, Erdo&#x11f;an EG, &#xc7;ak&#x131;c&#x131; H, Akdere H. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9947728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36843740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renal oncocytoma. Pearse HD, Houghton DC. Urology. 1979;13:74&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">442326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renal oncocytoma--are there sufficient grounds to consider surveillance following prenephrectomy histologic diagnosis. Haifler M, Copel L, Sandbank J, et al. Urol Oncol. 2012;30:362&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20171908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giant renal oncocytoma. Stojanovi&#x107; N, Ignjatovic I, Kostov M, et al. Vojnosanit Pregl. 2013;70:68&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23401933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giant asymptomatic left renal oncocytoma in a 40-year-old man: a case report. Qaid S, Ghaleb R, Ahmed F, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36187032/ Pan Afr Med J. 2022;42:177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9482213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36187032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oncocitoma renal gigante: giant renal oncocytoma. Alvarez Ardura M, Hern&#xe1;ndez Ca&#xf1;as V, et al. Actas Urol Esp. 2005;29:791&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16304913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metastatic oncocytic renal neoplasm presenting as gastrointestinal bleeding. Sqour H, Shilbayeh AR, Gerais Y, et al. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12146448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40491617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renal oncocytoma: a systematic review of its metastatic features. Rajagopal R, Yoztyurk E, Ravendran K. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11483153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39417067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>[Diagnosis and treatment of renal oncocytoma of 6 cases and literature review] Li S, Wu H, Zhao X, Zhong Z, Li Y. Zhong Nan Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. 2012;37:208&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22561440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilateral renal oncocytoma: active surveillance versus partial nephrectomy. Sathe A, Lindars D, Sathe P, et al. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8933140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35350482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renal oncocytoma treated with stereotactic body radiation therapy in a patient with prior pancoast tumor. Gould N, Brower B, Maree M, Dar AR. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11870772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40027059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>YouTube videos: a learning tool for periodontology education. Singh S, Suragimath G, Varma S, et al.  http://10.7759/cureus.76049 Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11743747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39834979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Student perceptions towards the use of YouTube as an educational tool for learning and tutorials. Maziriri ET, Gapa P, Chuchu T. Int J Instr. 2020;13:119&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeking mental health support among college students in video-based social media: content and statistical analysis of YouTube videos. Choi B, Kim H, Huh-Yoo J. JMIR Form Res. 2021;5:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34762060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>YouTube as a source of information on fibromyalgia. Ozsoy-Unubol T, Alanbay-Yagci E. Int J Rheum Dis. 2021;24:197&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33355406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DISCERN: an instrument for judging the quality of written consumer health information on treatment choices. Charnock D, Shepperd S, Needham G, Gann R. J Epidemiol Community Health. 1999;53:105&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10396471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enteral nutrition: goody or good-for-nothing in acute pancreatitis? Petrov MS. https://journals.lww.com/ajg/fulltext/2007/08000/enteral_nutrition__goody_or_good_for_nothing_in.40.aspx. Am J Gastroenterol. 2007;102:1828&#x2013;1829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17686077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the quality of patient information to support informed shared decision-making. Godolphin W, Towle A, McKendry R. Health Expect. 2001;4:235&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5060084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11703497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quality assessment of YouTube videos as an information source for testicular torsion. Bai G, Pan X, Zhao T, et al. Front Public Health. 2022;10:905609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9157819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35664123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating the reliability of DISCERN: a tool for assessing the quality of written patient information on treatment choices. Rees CE, Ford JE, Sheard CE. Patient Educ Couns. 2002;47:273&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>YouTube as a patient-information source for hypothyroidism. Du&#x142;ak NA, Anuszkiewicz K, Trzci&#x144;ski R, et al. Minerva Endocrinol (Torino) 2023;48:371&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35166471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of the quality and reliability of YouTube videos on rotator cuff tears. Kuru T, Erken HY. Cureus. 2020;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32181087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of YouTube Videos as a source of information on hepatosteatosis. Tutan D, Kaya M. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10566639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37829652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>YouTube: Homepage.  [
Dec;
2025 
]. 2025. http://www.youtube.com http://www.youtube.com</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>