<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41501655</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2288</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical research methodology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Res Methodol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Innovative statistical method for longitudinal and hierarchical data modeling: the GMEXGBoost method.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>24</StartPage><MedlinePgn>24</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">24</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12874-025-02751-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Over recent decades, the exponential growth of data, especially in healthcare, has necessitated advanced analytical methods. Conventional machine learning algorithms often assume independence among data points, limiting their effectiveness with longitudinal and hierarchical data. This study introduces a novel algorithm called GMEXGBoost, a methodological extension of generalized mixed-effects models that leverages the boosting framework of XGBoost for estimating fixed effects while simultaneously accounting for random effects. The innovation lies in GMEXGBoost's ability to explicitly incorporate data correlations while retaining the predictive power of boosted trees.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The GMEXGBoost model was evaluated through extensive simulations and a real-world cohort study, benchmarking against GLMM, GLMMTree, GMERF, and XGBoost. Also, its performance was assessed using predictive mean absolute deviation (PMAD), predictive misclassification rate (PMCR), sensitivity, specificity, accuracy, and AUC. Simulation analyses were conducted using multiple synthetic datasets, each comprising training and testing groups with varying effect structures, including random intercepts and slopes. All computations were performed in RStudio(version 2023.06.0).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Our results indicate that while XGBoost achieved the lowest average errors across most scenarios, GMEXGBoost consistently demonstrated superior stability and accuracy when random-effect variance was large or correlations were strong. Also, in real data, GMEXGBoost outperformed other models in terms of the performance metrics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The GMEXGBoost algorithm, by combining the estimates of the GLMM and XGBoost models, leverages the capabilities of both and delivers improved performance in complex problems. Although it is not universally superior, but demonstrates clear advantages in the analysis of hierarchical and longitudinal datasets with strong correlations. These properties make it a valuable tool for decision-making in healthcare and other domains that involve complex, structured data.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asadi</LastName><ForeName>Fariba</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ferdows Faculty of Medical Sciences, Birjand University of Medical Sciences, Birjand, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, School of Allied Medical Sciences, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Homayounfar</LastName><ForeName>Reza</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Noncommunicable Diseases Research Center, Fasa University of Medical Sciences, Fasa, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food Technology Research Institute, Faculty of Nutrition Sciences and Food Technology, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehrali</LastName><ForeName>Yaser</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistical Center of Iran, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masci</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Economics, Management and Quantitative Methods, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zayeri</LastName><ForeName>Farid</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Proteomics Research Center and Department of Biostatistics, School of Allied Medical Sciences, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Qods Square, Darband Street, Tehran, Iran. fzayeri@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Res Methodol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968545</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2288</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015233" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Statistical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003627" MajorTopicYN="N">Data Interpretation, Statistical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Boosted tree</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Generalized linear mixed model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal and hierarchical data</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted as part of a PhD dissertation in Biostatistics approved by the Ethics Committee of Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences (approval number: IR.SBMU.RETECH.REC.1402.137). The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. The data were derived from a previously approved human cohort study, and ethical approval and informed consent were obtained in the original study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41501655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12874673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-025-02751-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12874-025-02751-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Reinsel D, Gantz J, Rydning J. The digitization of the world from edge to core, vol. 16. Framingham: International Data Corporation; 2018. p. 1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BashariRad B, Akbarzadeh N, Ataei P, Khakbiz Y. Security and privacy challenges in big data era. Int J Control Theory Appl. 2016;9(43):437&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta MK, Chandra P. A comprehensive survey of data mining. Int J Inf Technol. 2020;12(4):1243&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razzak MI, Imran M, Xu G. Big data analytics for preventive medicine. Neural Comput Appl. 2020;32(9):4417&#x2013;51. 10.1007/s00521-019-04095-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-019-04095-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7088441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaoling S, Yiwan Y. Knowledge discovery: methods from data mining and machine learning. Soc Sci Res. 2023;110(102817):1&#x2013;16. 10.1016/j.ssresearch.2022.102817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssresearch.2022.102817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36796993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young DS. Handbook of Regression Methods. 1st ed. Chapman and Hall/CRC; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DK. Data transformation: a focus on the interpretation. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2020;73(6):503&#x2013;8. 10.4097/kja.20137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4097/kja.20137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33271009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCullagh P, Nelder J. Generalized linear models. 2nd ed. Boca Raton: Chapman and Hall/CRC; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood S. Generalized additive models: an introduction with R. 2nd ed. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie T, Tibshirani R, Friedman JH. The elements of statistical learning: data mining, inference, and prediction. Statistics SSi, editor. New York: Springer; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elith J, Leathwick JR, Hastie T. A working guide to boosted regression trees. J Anim Ecol. 2008;77(4):802&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2656.2008.01390.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18397250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovel J, Greiner R. An introduction to machine learning approaches for biomedical research. Front Med. 2021;8:771607. 10.3389/fmed.2021.771607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.771607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8716730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34977072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fokkema M, Edbrooke-Childs J, Wolpert M. Generalized linear mixed-model (GLMM) trees: a flexible decision-tree method for multilevel and longitudinal data. Psychother Res. 2021;31(3):329&#x2013;41. 10.1080/10503307.2020.1785037.&#xa0;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10503307.2020.1785037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10503307.2020.1785037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32602811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianchang H, Silke S. A review on longitudinal data analysis with random forest. Briefings in Bioinformatics. 2023;24(2). 10.1093/bib/bbad00210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10025446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36653905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangino AA, Finch WH. Prediction with mixed effects models: a Monte Carlo simulation study. Educ Psychol Meas. 2021;81(6):1118&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0013164421992818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8451021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34565818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S, Wang Y-G, Drovandi C, Cao T. Predictions of machine learning with mixed-effects in analyzing longitudinal data under model misspecification. Stat Methods Appl. 2023;32(2):681&#x2013;711. 10.1007/s10260-022-00658-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10260-022-00658-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascarano A, Mur-Petit J, Hernandez-Gonzalez J, Camacho M, de Toro Eadie N, Gkontra P, et al. Machine and deep learning for longitudinal biomedical data: a review of methods and applications. Artif Intell Rev. 2023;56(Suppl 2):1711&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-023-10561-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salditt M, Humberg S, Nestler S. Gradient tree boosting for hierarchical data. Multivar Behav Res. 2023;58(5):911&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00273171.2022.2146638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36602080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y-W, Yang H-C, Chen Y-H, Guo C-Y. Generalized estimating equations boosting (GEEB) machine for correlated data. J Big Data. 2024;11(1):20. 10.1186/s40537-023-00875-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-023-00875-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascarano A, Mur-Petit J, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Camacho M, de Toro EN, Gkontra P, et al. Machine and deep learning for longitudinal biomedical data: a review of methods and applications. Artif Intell Rev. 2023;56(2):1711&#x2013;71. 10.1007/s10462-023-10561-w10.1007/s10462-023-10561-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-023-10561-w10.1007/s10462-023-10561-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajjem A, Larocque D, Bellavance F. Generalized mixed effects regression trees. Stat Probability Lett. 2017;126:114&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.spl.2017.02.033. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0167715217300895?via%3Dihub.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spl.2017.02.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellagatti M, Masci C, Ieva F, Paganoni AM. Generalized mixed-effects random forest: a flexible approach to predict university student dropout. Stat Anal Data Min ASA Data Sci J. 2021;14(3):241&#x2013;57. 10.1002/sam.11505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sam.11505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigrist F, Gyger T, Kuendig P. gpboost: combining tree-boosting with Gaussian process and mixed effects models. CRAN: Contributed Packages. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofner B, Mayr A, Robinzonov N, Schmid M. Model-based boosting in R: a hands-on tutorial using the R package mboost. Comput Stat. 2014;29(1):3&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00180-012-0382-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olaniran OR, Olaniran SF, Allohibi J, Alharbi AA, Alharbi NM. Mixed effect gradient boosting for high-dimensional longitudinal data. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):30927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-16526-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12373843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40847064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong T, Oronti IB, Sinha S, Freitas A, Zhai B, Chan J, et al. Enhancing cardiovascular risk prediction: development of an advanced xgboost model with hospital-level random effects. Bioengineering. 2024;11(10):1039.&#xa0;https://www.mdpi.com/2306-5354/11/10/1039.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering11101039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11505330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39451414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song YY, Lu Y. Decision tree methods: applications for classification and prediction. Shanghai Arch Psychiatry. 2015;27(2):130&#x2013;5. 10.11919/j.issn.1002-0829.215044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11919/j.issn.1002-0829.215044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4466856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26120265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman L, Friedman J, Stone CJ, Olshen RA. Classification and regression trees. Cambridge, MA: CRC Press; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallahzadeh H, Asadi F. Generalized linear mixed models: Introduction, Estimation method and Application in medical studies. Paramed Sci Military Health. 2019;14(1):33&#x2013;8.&#xa0;http://jps.ajaums.ac.ir/article-1-176-fa.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolker BM, Brooks ME, Clark CJ, Geange SW, Poulsen JR, Stevens MHH, et al. Generalized linear mixed models: a practical guide for ecology and evolution. Trends Ecol Evol. 2009;24(3):127&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.tree.2008.10.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tree.2008.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19185386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carty DM. An analysis of boosted regression trees to predict the strength properties of wood composites. Master's Thesis, The University of Tennessee; 2011. https://trace.tennessee.edu/utk_gradthes/954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C, Wu D, Huang J, Yuan Y, Zhang H-T, Peng R, et al. BoostTree and BoostForest for ensemble learning. IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell. 2022;45(7):8110&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37015516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahad P, Saxena P. Study of AdaBoost and Gradient Boosting Algorithms for Predictive Analytics. International Conference on Intelligent Computing and Smart Communication 2019. Algorithms for Intelligent Systems. Springer: Singapore; 2020:235-44. 10.1007/978-981-15-0633-8_22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Cui B, Zhang C. Distributed machine learning and gradient optimization. Singapore: Springer; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Guestrin C. Xgboost: a scalable tree boosting system. Proceedings of the 22nd acm sigkdd international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining. New York; 2016. p. 785&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Deng C, Wang S. Imbalance-XGBoost: leveraging weighted and focal losses for binary label-imbalanced classification with XGBoost. Pattern Recogn Lett. 2020;136:190&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patrec.2020.05.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhaliwal SS, Nahid A-A, Abbas R. Effective intrusion detection system using XGBoost. Information. 2018;9(7):149. 10.3390/info9070149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info9070149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafarian F, Wieland R, L&#xfc;ttschwager D, Nendel C. Application of extreme gradient boosting and Shapley Additive explanations to predict temperature regimes inside forests from standard open-field meteorological data. Environ Model Softw. 2022;156:105466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envsoft.2022.105466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker B, Walker S. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. J Stat Softw. 2015;67(1):1&#x2013;48. 10.18637/jss.v067.i01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaw A, Wiener M. Classification and regression by randomForest. R News. 2002;2(3):18&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, He T, Benesty M, Khotilovich V, Tang Y, Cho H, et al. Xgboost: extreme gradient boosting. R package version 04&#x2013;2. 2015;1(4):1&#x2013;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therneau T, Atkinson B, Ripley B, Ripley MB. Package &#x2018;rpart&#x2019;. 2015;2:5&#x2013;32. Available online: cranmaicacuk/web/packages/rpart/rpart.pdf. Accessed on 20 Apr 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fokkema M, Zeileis A, Fokkema MM. Package &#x2018;glmertree&#x2019;. 2019. Retrived from: https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/glmertree/glmertree.pdf. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farjam M, Bahrami H, Bahramali E, Jamshidi J, Askari A, Zakeri H, et al. A cohort study protocol to analyze the predisposing factors to common chronic non-communicable diseases in rural areas: Fasa Cohort Study. BMC Public Health. 2016;16(1):1&#x2013;8. 10.1186/s12889-016-3760-z.&#xa0;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-016-3760-z.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3760-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5069851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27756262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X, Zhiwen Y, Wenming C, Yifan S, Qianli M. A survey on ensemble learning. Front Comp Sci. 2020;14:241&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11704-019-8208-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehra A, Tripathy P, Faridi A, Chinmay A. Ensemble learning approach to improve existing models. Int J Innov Sci Res Technol. 2019;4(12):25&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabiraj S, Raihan M, Alvi N, Afrin M, Akter L, Sohagi SA, et al. Breast cancer risk prediction using XGBoost and random forest algorithm. 11th international conference on computing, communication and networking technologies (ICCCNT). IEEE; Kharagpur, India, 2020, pp. 1&#x2013;4. 10.1109/ICCCNT49239.2020.9225451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamani Joharestani M, Cao C, Ni X, Bashir B, Talebiesfandarani S. PM2. 5 prediction based on random forest, XGBoost, and deep learning using multisource remote sensing data. Atmosphere. 2019;10(7):373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/atmos10070373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nghiem N, Wilson N, Krebs J, Tran T. Predicting the risk of diabetes complications using machine learning and social administrative data in a country with ethnic inequities in health: Aotearoa New Zealand. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2024;24(1):274. 10.1186/s12911-024-02678-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-024-02678-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11438423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39334279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi F, Homayounfar R, Mehrali Y, Masci C, Talebi S, Zayeri F. Detection of cardiovascular disease cases using advanced tree-based machine learning algorithms. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):22230. 10.1038/s41598-024-72819-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-72819-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11437204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39333550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>