<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41353182</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-0003</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuroengineering and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroeng Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exhalation-synchronous robotic abdominal compression for user-centered respiratory assistance and training in neurological patients.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>50</StartPage><MedlinePgn>50</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">50</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12984-025-01798-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Patients with respiratory weaknesses due to neurological disorders or aging often face usability challenges with conventional mechanical ventilators, which directly move air in and out of the lungs via the ventilation mask. To address these challenges, Exo-Abs was developed to support a wide range of respiratory functions through synchronous abdominal compression. Its control previously relied on continuous full-phase measurements from multiple sensors to ensure control performance across a wide dynamic range. However, accommodating long-term usage scenarios remained challenging, as practical features such as allowing breaks between breaths or adapting to different installation environments were limited. Here, we present a user-centered solution designed to address these real-world usage conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Although consecutive compression-and-recoil cycles are commonly considered essential for this type of assistance, we found that well-synchronized abdominal compression with Exo-Abs can immediately augment the corresponding breath, when applied above a certain intensity. Based on this finding, we proposed an exhalation-synchronous control strategy for the system that involves strict control policy over the exhalation phase (compression) and sparse control policy over the inhalation phase (release). A streamlined sensor configuration was also implemented to improve use scenarios, allowing users to take breaks freely and supporting long-term use. To evaluate the improved practicality of Exo-Abs, we conducted an experimnt in which the device was used in place of a conventional mechanical ventilator during prescribed respiratory therapy sessions for hospitalized patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Notably, all participants were able to use the system for up to approximately two hours, demonstrating the feasibility of the proposed control scheme for long-term usage. The efficacy of assistance was evaluated by utilizing the mathematical model individualized to each participant. Results for primary respiratory performances showed an average 23.25% increase in the peak volumetric flow rate per breath (ranging from 13.99 to 57.81% depending on the user) and an average 19.46% increase in the maximal volume of air moved in and out per breath (ranging from 7.23 to 45.60% depending on the user). During assistance, Exo-Abs applied between 76 and 91&#xa0;N of compressive force synchronously to each breath. Secondary analysis based on individualized mathematical models showed an average increase of 1.80&#xa0;cmH[Formula: see text]O in mean pleural pressure per breath (23.44% of their spontaneous pleural pressure; ranging from 7.99 to 43.93% depending on the user) and an average 0.07&#xa0;J increase of the mechanical work per breath (23.49% of their spontaneous work; ranging from 8.22 to 45.35% depending on the user).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates that Exo-Abs can enhance respiratory performance in patients with weakened respiratory muscles, even in long-term usage scenarios. Along with the simplifications in the control policy and user interface, Exo-Abs has been shown to provide effective respiratory assistance over various breathing patterns and respiratory training contexts. The contribution of this study extends beyond demonstrating a user-centered system with improved usability and practicality, as it also establishes an objective evaluation framework for respiratory biomechanics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sang-Yoep</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, 02139, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bio-Max Institute, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Soft Robotics Research Center, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Institute of Advanced Machines and Design, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beom</LastName><ForeName>Jaewon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Soft Robotics Research Center, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, 13620, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hahn</LastName><ForeName>Jin-Oh</ForeName><Initials>JO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, University of Maryland, College Park, MD, 20742, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Jae-Young</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Soft Robotics Research Center, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seongnam, 13620, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Aging, College of Medicine, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Kyu-Jin</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Soft Robotics Research Center, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea. kjcho@snu.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Institute of Advanced Machines and Design, Seoul National University, Seoul, 08826, South Korea. kjcho@snu.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NRF-2016R1A5A1938472</GrantID><Agency>National Research Foundation of Korea</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>HI19C1352</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Health and Welfare,South Korea</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>N00014-19-1-2402 and N00014-23-1-2828</GrantID><Agency>Office of Naval Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuroeng Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101232233</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-0003</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical ventilation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurological disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation engineering</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory assistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soft wearable robotics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: All experimental procedures were conducted following approved guidelines and regulations and proceeded under the supervision of therapists. Ethical approval for the experimental protocols (B01908/561-002) was obtained from the Institutional Review Board of Seoul National University Hospital Biomedical Research Institute, Seoul, Republic of Korea. Informed consents were obtained from all the participants after explaining the possible consequences of the study. Consent for publication: All participants provided written and informed consent for the publication of the included data, video, and images. Competing interests: The authors declare no Conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41353182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12859905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-025-01798-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12984-025-01798-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roussos C. Function and fatigue of respiratory muscles. Chest. 1985;88(2):124S-132S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.88.2_Supplement.124S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3160552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas BM, Trew M, Castle PC. Effects of respiratory muscle weakness on daily living function, quality of life, activity levels, and exercise capacity in mild to moderate Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;83(8):601&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.PHM.0000133436.61009.02</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15277961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poddighe D, Van Hollebeke M, Rodrigues A, Hermans G, Testelmans D, Kalkanis A, et al. Respiratory muscle dysfunction in acute and chronic respiratory failure: How to diagnose and how to treat? Eur Respir Rev. 2024;33(174):240150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/16000617.0150-2024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11615664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39631928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polkey MI, Lyall RA, Moxham J, Leigh PN. Respiratory aspects of neurological disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1999;66(1):5&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.66.1.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1736177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah NM, Kaltsakas G, Steier J. Assessment of respiratory muscle weakness. In: ERS Handbook of respiratory sleep medicine. European Respiratory Society; 2024. p. 269&#x2013;272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AD, Bianchi AL, Bishop BP. Neural control of the respiratory muscles. CRC Press; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley RC, Ferreira LF. Diaphragm abnormalities in heart failure and aging: mechanisms and integration of cardiovascular and respiratory pathophysiology. Heart Fail Rev. 2017;22:191&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10741-016-9549-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4827708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27000754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsentsevitsky AN, Sibgatullina GV, Odoshivkina YG, Khuzakhmetova VF, Tokmakova AR, Ponomareva AA, et al. Functional and structural changes in diaphragm neuromuscular junctions in early aging. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(16):8959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25168959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11354816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39201644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pingleton SK. Complications of acute respiratory failure. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1988;137(6):1463&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/ajrccm/137.6.1463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3059862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagina M, Valley TS. Diagnosis and management of acute respiratory failure. Crit Care Clin. 2024;40(2):235&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccc.2024.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10910131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38432694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrosino N, Carpene N, Gherardi M. Chronic respiratory care for neuromuscular diseases in adults. Eur Respir J. 2009;34(2):444&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00182208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19648521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faverio P, De Giacomi F, Bonaiti G, Stainer A, Sardella L, Pellegrino G, et al. Management of chronic respiratory failure in interstitial lung diseases: overview and clinical insights. Int J Med Sci. 2019;16(7):967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.32752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6643124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31341410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xf6;yh&#xf6;nen M, Syv&#xe4;oja S, Hartikainen J, Ruokonen E, Takala J. The effect of carbon dioxide, respiratory rate and tidal volume on human heart rate variability. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2004;48(1):93&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-6576.2004.00272.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14674979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoller O, de Bruin ED, Schindelholz M, Schuster-Amft C, de Bie RA, Hunt KJ. Cardiopulmonary exercise testing early after stroke using feedback-controlled robotics-assisted treadmill exercise: test-retest reliability and repeatability. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2014;11:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-0003-11-145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4271449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25306061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiles C. Neurological complications of severe illness and prolonged mechanical ventilation. Thorax. 1996;51(Suppl 2):S40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.51.Suppl_2.S40</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1090705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8869351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrin C, Unterborn JN, Ambrosio CD, Hill NS. Pulmonary complications of chronic neuromuscular diseases and their management. Muscle Nerve Off J Am Assoc Electrodiagn Med. 2004;29(1):5&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.10487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14694494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White J, Drinnan M, Smithson A, Griffiths C, Gibson G. Respiratory muscle activity and oxygenation during sleep in patients with muscle weakness. Eur Respir J. 1995;8(5):807&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.95.08050807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7656954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitriadis Z, Kapreli E, Strimpakos N, Oldham J. Respiratory weakness in patients with chronic neck pain. Man Ther. 2013;18(3):248&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.math.2012.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23199797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windisch W, et al. Impact of home mechanical ventilation on health-related quality of life. Eur Respir J. 2008;32(5):1328&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00066407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18579546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang XN, Zong HY, Ou Y, Yu X, Cheng H, Du CP, et al. Exoskeleton-assisted walking improves pulmonary function and walking parameters among individuals with spinal cord injury: a randomized controlled pilot study. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2021;18(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-021-00880-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8146689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34030720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troosters T, Casaburi R, Gosselink R, Decramer M. Pulmonary rehabilitation in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005;172(1):19&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200408-1109SO</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15778487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr&#xe9; R, Navajas D, Prats E, Marti S, Guell R, Montserrat JM, et al. Performance of mechanical ventilators at the patient&#x2019;s home: a multicentre quality control study. Thorax. 2006;61(5):400&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2005.052647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2111198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16467068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess DR, Kacmarek RM. Essentials of mechanical ventilation. McGraw Hill Education; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishigaki Y, Mizuguchi H, Takeda E, Koike T, Ando T, Kawamura K, et al. Development of new measurement system of thoracic excursion with biofeedback: reliability and validity. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2013;10:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-0003-10-45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3669041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23687911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissett B, Gosselink R, Van Haren FM. Respiratory muscle rehabilitation in patients with prolonged mechanical ventilation: a targeted approach. Ann Update Intensive Care Emerg Med. 2020;2020:595&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-37323-8_45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32204719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YH, Lin HL, Hsiao HF, Chou LT, Kao KC, Huang CC, et al. Effects of exercise training on pulmonary mechanics and functional status in patients with prolonged mechanical ventilation. Respir Care. 2012;57(5):727&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.01341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22152978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess DR. The growing role of noninvasive ventilation in patients requiring prolonged mechanical ventilation. Respir Care. 2012;57(6):900&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.01692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22663966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de&#xa0;Souza&#xa0;Coutinho L, Santana Alves&#xa0;do Nascimento J, de&#xa0;Oliveira&#xa0;de Macedo P, Moura&#xa0;Braga ME, de&#xa0;Almeida&#xa0;Karam M, Ara&#xfa;jo&#xa0;de Oliveira J, et&#xa0;al. The usability of mechanical ventilation and its interface with nursing care: an integrative review. Sa&#xfa;de Coletiva. 2025;15(93).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J, Tasota FJ, Hoffman LA. Mobility interventions to improve outcomes in patients undergoing prolonged mechanical ventilation: a review of the literature. Biol Res Nurs. 2008;10(1):21&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1099800408319055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2724770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18647758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visscher MO, White CC, Jones JM, Cahill T, Jones DC, Pan BS. Face masks for noninvasive ventilation: fit, excess skin hydration, and pressure ulcers. Respir Care. 2015;60(11):1536&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.04036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jablonski RS. The experience of being mechanically ventilated. Qual Health Res. 1994;4(2):186&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/104973239400400204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Hahn JO, Beom J, Park JH, Cho HE, Kang SW, et al. Exo-Abs: a wearable robotic system inspired by human abdominal muscles for noninvasive and effort-synchronized respiratory assistance. IEEE Trans Rob. 2022;38(5):2994&#x2013;3014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2022.3167399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho KJ, Lee SY, Brown MG. Acupressure device. Google Patents; 2018. US Patent 10,117,805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Cho KJ. A study on the cough augmentation using a belt-driven assistive. In: 2017 international conference on rehabilitation robotics (ICORR). IEEE; 2017. p. 1654&#x2013;1659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Jeong U, Cho KJ. An application of user-friendly control for a respiratory rehabilitation and assistance robot. In: 2015 IEEE international conference on advanced intelligent mechatronics (AIM). IEEE; 2015. p. 441&#x2013;446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei P, Lee SY, Cho K, Hahn JO. Robust control of Exo-Abs, a wearable platform for ubiquitous respiratory assistance. J Dyn Syst Meas Contr. 2025;147(2):021005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4066266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham T, Brochard LJ, Slutsky AS. Mechanical ventilation: state of the art. In: Mayo clinic proceedings. vol.&#xa0;92. Elsevier; 2017. p. 1382&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28870355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quevedo-Moreno D, Lee SY, Tagoe J, Emani V, Bonnemain J, Roche ET. Design, modeling, and control of a soft robotic diaphragm-assist device in a respiratory simulator. Adv Intell Syst. 2025. 10.1002/aisy.202401087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aisy.202401087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exovent Development Group. Exovent: a study of a new negative-pressure ventilatory support device in healthy adults. Anaesthesia. 2021;76(5):623&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33465816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Ge Q, Wang Z, Qin Y, Wu Y, Wang M, et al. Extracorporeal closed-loop respiratory regulation for patients with respiratory difficulty using a soft bionic robot. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 2024;71(10):2923&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2024.3401713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38753478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan S, Zhou S, Wang Y, Hou M, Fei Y. Design, modeling, and control of a soft abdominal compression robot for respiratory assistance. Soft Robot. 2025. 10.1089/soro.2024.0088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/soro.2024.0088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40147041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Pu Z, Yuan S, Fei Y. Bidirectional asymmetric accordion-type soft robot for respiratory assistance. J Mech Robot. 2025;17(7):075003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4068019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Troyer A, Estenne M, Ninane V, Van Gansbeke D, Gorini M. Transversus abdominis muscle function in humans. J Appl Physiol. 1990;68(3):1010&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1990.68.3.1010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2140344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strohl KP, Mead J, Banzett RB, Loring SH, Kosch PC. Regional differences in abdominal muscle activity during various maneuvers in humans. J Appl Physiol. 1981;51(6):1471&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1981.51.6.1471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6459311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratnovsky A, Elad D, Halpern P. Mechanics of respiratory muscles. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2008;163(1&#x2013;3):82&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2008.04.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18583200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranu H, Wilde M, Madden B. Pulmonary function tests. Ulst Med J. 2011;80(2):84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3229853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crapo RO. Pulmonary-function testing. N Engl J Med. 1994;331(1):25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199407073310107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8202099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyatt RE, Scanlon PD, Nakamura M. Interpretation of pulmonary function tests. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates JH, Irvin CG, Farr&#xe9; R, Hantos Z. Oscillation mechanics of the respiratory system. Compr Physiol. 2011;1(3):1233&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.2040-4603.2011.tb00366.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23733641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marini JJ, Crooke PS. A general mathematical model for respiratory dynamics relevant to the clinical setting. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1993;147:14&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/ajrccm/147.1.14</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8420408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum P, Reinkensmeyer D, Mahoney R, Rymer WZ, Burgar C. Robotic devices for movement therapy after stroke: current status and challenges to clinical acceptance. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2002;8(4):40&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1310/9KFM-KF81-P9A4-5WW0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14523729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blank AA, French JA, Pehlivan AU, O&#x2019;Malley MK. Current trends in robot-assisted upper-limb stroke rehabilitation: promoting patient engagement in therapy. Curr Phys Med Rehabil Rep. 2014;2:184&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40141-014-0056-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26005600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolbrecht ET, Chan V, Reinkensmeyer DJ, Bobrow JE. Optimizing compliant, model-based robotic assistance to promote neurorehabilitation. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2008;16(3):286&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSRE.2008.918389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18586608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schranz C, Kn&#xf6;bel C, Kretschmer J, Zhao Z, M&#xf6;ller K. Hierarchical parameter identification in models of respiratory mechanics. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 2011;58(11):3234&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2011.2166398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21880567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schranz C, Docherty PD, Chiew YS, M&#xf6;ller K, Chase JG. Iterative integral parameter identification of a respiratory mechanics model. Biomed Eng Online. 2012;11(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-925X-11-38</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3460758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22809585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major V, Corbett S, Redmond D, Beatson A, Glassenbury D, Chiew YS, et al. Respiratory mechanics assessment for reverse-triggered breathing cycles using pressure reconstruction. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2016;23:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2015.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucangelo U, Bernab&#xe9; F, Blanch L. Respiratory mechanics derived from signals in the ventilator circuit. Respir Care. 2005;50(1):55&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15636645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou M, Patton RJ. Input observability and input reconstruction. Automatica. 1998;34(6):789&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0005-1098(98)00021-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavan RA, Fitch K, Palanthandalam-Madapusi HJ, Recursive input reconstruction with a delay. In: American Control Conference. IEEE. 2014;2014:628&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fridman L, Shtessel Y, Edwards C, Yan XG. Higher-order sliding-mode observer for state estimation and input reconstruction in nonlinear systems. Int J Robust Nonlinear Control IFAC-Affil J. 2008;18(4&#x2013;5):399&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rnc.1198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bejarano FJ. Partial unknown input reconstruction for linear systems. Automatica. 2011;47(8):1751&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.automatica.2011.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelmayer A, Bokor J, Szab&#xf3; Z, Szigeti F. Input reconstruction by means of system inversion: a geometric approach to fault detection and isolation in nonlinear systems. Int J Appl Math Comput Sci. 2004;14(2):189&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifflin MD, St Jeor ST, Hill LA, Scott BJ, Daugherty SA, Koh YO. A new predictive equation for resting energy expenditure in healthy individuals. Am J Clin Nutr. 1990;51(2):241&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/51.2.241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2305711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong MS, Lee YS, Lee HY. Effects of breathing exercises on resting metabolic rate and maximal oxygen uptake. J Phys Ther Sci. 2018;30(9):1173&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.30.1173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6127488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30214120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill MB, Pugh L. Basal metabolism and respiration in men living at 5,800 m (19,000 ft). J Appl Physiol. 1964;19(5):949&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1964.19.5.949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14207750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabello B, Mancebo J. Work of breathing. Intensive Care Med. 2006;32:1311&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-006-0278-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16838150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancebo J, Isabey D, Lorino H, Lofaso F, Lemaire F, Brochard L. Comparative effects of pressure support ventilation and intermittent positive pressure breathing (IPPB) in non-intubated healthy subjects. Eur Respir J. 1995;8(11):1901&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.95.08111901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8620960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladjal H, Azencot J, Beuve M, Giraud P, Moreau JM, Shariat B. Biomechanical modeling of the respiratory system: Human diaphragm and thorax. In: Computational biomechanics for medicine: new approaches and new applications. Springer; 2015. p. 101&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wall WA, Wiechert L, Comerford A, Rausch S. Towards a comprehensive computational model for the respiratory system. Int J Numer Methods Biomed Eng. 2010;26(7):807&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cnm.1378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boles JM, Bion J, Connors A, Herridge M, Marsh B, Melot C, et al. Weaning from mechanical ventilation. Eur Respir J. 2007;29(5):1033&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00010206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17470624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteban A, Frutos F, Tobin MJ, Al&#xed;a I, Solsona JF, Valverdu V, et al. A comparison of four methods of weaning patients from mechanical ventilation. N Engl J Med. 1995;332(6):345&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199502093320601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7823995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stafinski T, Nagase FI, Avdagovska M, Stickland MK, Menon D. Effectiveness of home-based pulmonary rehabilitation programs for patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD): systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-07779-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9039605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35473597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Maitinuer A, Lian Z, Li Y, Ding W, Wang W, et al. Home based pulmonary tele-rehabilitation under telemedicine system for COPD: a cohort study. BMC Pulm Med. 2022;22(1):284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-022-02077-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35871652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawthorne G, Greening N, Esliger D, Briggs-Price S, Richardson M, Chaplin E, et al. Usability of wearable multiparameter technology to continuously monitor free-living vital signs in people living with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: prospective observational study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2022;9(1):e30091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/30091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35171101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuBois AB, Brody AW, Lewis DH, Burgess BF Jr. Oscillation mechanics of lungs and chest in man. J Appl Physiol. 1956;8(6):587&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1956.8.6.587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13331841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates JH. Lung mechanics: an inverse modeling approach. Cambridge University Press; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Tal A. Simplified models for gas exchange in the human lungs. J Theor Biol. 2006;238(2):474&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtbi.2005.06.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16038941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>