<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41355241</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ITO Nanoparticles to Stabilize the Self-Assembly of Hole Transport Layer in Inverted Perovskite Solar Cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e17573</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e17573</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202517573</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recently, inverted perovskite solar cells (PSCs) show rapidly improved efficiency with the use of self-assembled molecules (SAM). However, device stability remains a challenge due to the easy desorption of the SAM molecule. Here, functionalized indium tin oxide nanoparticles (INPs) are introduced to promote and reinforce the self-assembly of SAM on the substrate. INPs contain abundant &#x2500;OH groups to uniformly anchor SAM molecules. Importantly, different from traditional physically absorbed and easy-desorbed &#x2500;OH in ITO substrate, the &#x2500;OH groups on INPs are stably bonded, resistant to solvent rinsing and long-term aging, thus inhibiting SAM desorption during device aging. As a result, PSCs with INPs exhibit high efficiency of 26.44% with good operational stability under ISOS-L-2 protocol, retaining &#x223c;&#x2248;91% of initial efficiency after maximum power point (MPP) tracking with continuous illumination at 85&#xa0;&#xb0;C.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Wen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Zhengbo</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yunfei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Wentao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Sheng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wenxiao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaodong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0184-008X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Institute of East China Normal University, Chongqing, 401123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Junfeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics and Electronic Science, Engineering Research Center of Nanophotonics &amp; Advanced Instrument, Ministry of Education, East China Normal University, Shanghai, 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023YFA1407500</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62274062</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62374058</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62104070</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24DZ3001202</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai Science and Technology Innovation Action Plan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022NSCQ-MSX2058</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Chongqing</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ITO nanoparticles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SAM desorption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hole transport layer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inverted perovskite solar cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stability</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41355241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202517573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>D. He, D. Ma, J. Zhang, Y. Yang, J. Ding, C. Liu, X. Liu, Y. Yu, T. Liu, C. Chen, M. Li, J. Chen, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2505115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Luo, Q. Zhou, K. Wang, X. Wang, J. He, P. Gao, C. Zhan, Z. Bi, W. Li, Y. Ma, W. Chen, Y. Hou, Z. Liu, Q. Zhao, Nat. Mater. 2025, 10,1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Du, J. Chen, B. Ouyang, A. Sun, C. Tian, R. Zhuang, C. Chen, S. Liu, Q. Chen, Z. Li, X. Wu, J. Cai, Y. Zhao, R. Li, T. Xue, T. Cen, K. Zhao, C.&#x2010;C. Chen, Energy Environ. Sci. 2025, 18, 3196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Fu, D. Yang, Y. Chen, R. Lu, M. A. Haque, Y. Liu, Y. Han, H. Li, R. Chen, J. Liu, W. Qin, L. H. Hernandez, F. Fan, K. Wu, D. Baran, H. Zhou, C. Li, Energy Environ. Sci. 2025, 10, 1039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Guo, H. Q. Du, Y. C. Wang, X. Gao, Y. Q. Lan, Y. S. Xiao, W. Jiang, Y. C. Zhou, Q. B. Yuan, Z. Y. Qiang, J. H. Zheng, L. H. Yang, C. X. Wang, N. Yang, R. Lin, G. J. Liang, M. U. Rothmann, X. Ouyang, Y. B. Cheng, W. Li, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2504520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Cao, S. Luo, T. Zheng, Z. Bi, J. Mo, L. G. Gutsev, N. A. Emelianov, V. V. Ozerova, N. A. Slesarenko, G. L. Gutsev, S. M. Aldoshin, F. Sun, Y. Tian, B. R. Ramachandran, P. A. Troshin, X. Xu, Adv. Energy Mater. 2025, 15, 2405376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, Y. Wang, K. Zhang, M. Tao, H. Guo, L. Guo, Z. Song, J. Wen, Y. Yang, Y. Hou, Y. Song, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 08, 782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Xu, X. Sun, W. Hui, Q. Wang, P. Xu, W. Tang, H. Hu, L. Song, X. Xu, Y. Wu, Q. Peng, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 64, 202503008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhang, X. Wang, Y. Wu, X. Li, T. Hou, D. Li, W. Chen, J. Li, R. Lv, Y. Zhang, Z. Xiao, T. Chen, S. Chen, Z. Fang, S. Liu, S. Yang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 63, 202412409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wu, J. Wu, Z. Zhang, X. Guan, L. Wang, L. Deng, G. Li, A. Abate, M. Li, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2025, 147, 8004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Qu, L. Zhang, Y. Qiao, S. Gong, Y. Ding, Y. Tao, S. Cai, X.&#x2010;Y. Chang, Q. Chen, P. Xie, J. Feng, C. Gao, G. Li, H. Xiao, F. Wang, H. Hu, J. Yang, S. Chen, A. K. Y. Jen, X. Chen, Z.&#x2010;X. Xu, Nat. Commun. 2025, 16, 86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Park, M. Wei, N. Lempesis, W. Yu, T. Hossain, L. Agosta, V. Carnevali, H. R. Atapattu, P. Serles, F. T. Eickemeyer, H. Shin, M. Vafaie, D. Choi, K. Darabi, E. D. Jung, Y. Yang, D. B. Kim, S. M. Zakeeruddin, B. Chen, A. Amassian, T. Filleter, M. G. Kanatzidis, K. R. Graham, L. Xiao, U. Rothlisberger, M. Gr&#xe4;tzel, E. H. Sargent, Nature 2023, 624, 289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Ansari, L. Zheng, L. Pfeifer, F. T. Eickemeyer, S. M. Zakeeruddin, N. Lempesis, V. Carnevali, A. Vezzosi, V. Sl&#xe1;ma, T. Georges, U. Gunes, L. Emsley, M. K. Nazeeruddin, U. Rothlisberger, P. J. Dyson, M. Gr&#xe4;tzel, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2501075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. H. Isikgor, R. R. Pradhan, S. Zhumagali, T. Maksudov, D. Naphade, C. E. Petoukhoff, J. I. Khan, V. Hnapovskyi, G. T. Harrison, C. Combe, J. Liu, A. Marsh, E. A. Alharbi, M. Heeney, F. Laquai, U. Schwingenschl&#xf6;gl, T. D. Anthopoulos, S. De Wolf, Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 15, 2402630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, Y.&#x2010;C. Wang, L. Zhu, W. Zhang, H.&#x2010;Q. Wang, J. Fang, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2017, 9, 31357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, J. Li, R. Guo, X. Yin, R. Luo, D. Guo, K. Ji, L. Dai, H. Liang, X. Jia, J. Chen, Z. Jia, Z. Shi, S. Liu, Y. Wang, Q. Zhou, T. Wang, G. Pan, P. M&#xfc;ller&#x2010;Buschbaum, S. D. Stranks, Y. Hou, Nat. Photon. 2024, 18, 1269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, X. Liu, X. Wang, L. Zhao, T. Jiu, J. Fang, J. Mate. Chem. A 2015, 3, 15024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Xiao, X. Xu, J. Zhao, C. Wang, Z. Lu, L. Li, L. He, Y. Chen, G. Zou, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2408684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Yu, X. Sun, Z. Zhu, Z. Li, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 64, 202419608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Peng, H. Huang, W. Liu, Z. Zhang, Y. Xu, S. Chen, S. Li, S. Du, S. Wang, Z. He, B. Zou, Z. Yu, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2025, 17, 10745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, B. Jiao, R. Tian, K. Sun, Y. Meng, Y. Bai, X. Lu, B. Han, M. Yang, Y. Wang, S. Zhou, H. Pan, Z. Song, C. Xiao, C. Liu, Z. Ge, Nat. Commun. 2025, 16, 4148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Luo, Y. Tian, K. Zhao, W. Mao, C. Liu, J. Shen, Z. Cheng, C. De&#x11f;er, X. Miao, Z. Zhang, X. Sun, L. Yao, X. Zhang, P. Shi, D. Jin, J. Deng, M. Tian, I. Yavuz, N. Dong, R. Liu, R. Wang, D. Yang, J. Xue, Nat. Commun. 2025, 16, 4516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, B. Li, S. Zhang, Z. Lin, M. Han, X. Liu, J. Chen, W. Du, G. Rahim, Y. Zhou, P. Shi, R. Wang, P. Wu, T. Alshahrani, W. Alqahtani, N. Alahmad, Q. Wang, B. Ding, S. Dai, M. K. Nazeeruddin, Y. Ding, Energy Environ. Sci. 2025, 18, 468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Duan, K. Chen, B. Pi, S. Li, Z. Lin, C. Liu, Y. Pan, H. Ling, D. Li, L. Zhou, T. Liu, F. Wu, X. Guo, B. Zou, X. Hu, Energy Environ. Sci. 2025, 18, 7231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Liu, Z. Ren, Y. Liu, Y. Zhang, J. Liang, F. Cheng, Y. Li, X. Shi, Y. Dou, X. Hu, L. Wang, S. Luo, F. Wang, X. Peng, Y. Zhao, W. Wang, Y. Cao, F. Gao, S. Chen, Sci. Adv. 2025, 11, 3493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. He, X. Liu, T. Liu, T. Zhao, Y. Chen, Q. Song, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2506386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Xu, S. Li, C. Shan, W. Peng, Y. Chen, S. Li, H. Peng, T. Dai, E. Zhou, Y. Bai, L. Qiu, P. Sun, B. Xu, A. K. K. Kyaw, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2505745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Li, D. Regaldo, C.&#x2010;S. J. Wu, M. Prato, A. Treglia, H. Wang, W. Hempel, M. Sessolo, Y. Zhou, A. Olivati, A. Petrozza, Energy Environ. Sci. 2025, 18, 6618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Tang, Z. Shen, Y. Shen, G. Yan, Q. H. Y. Wang, L. Han, Science 2024, 383, 1236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. H. Chen, G. W. Liu, X. Chen, C. Deger, R. J. Jin, K. L. Wang, J. Chen, Y. Xia, L. Huang, I. Yavuz, J. Fan, Z. K. Wang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 64, 202419375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Feng, Y. Wang, H. Yang, S. Li, J. Luo, X. Han, T. Alshahrani, B. Mai, D. Wang, Z. Ding, W. Sun, C. Sun, Q. Chen, K. Wei, Y. Feng, L. Song, X. Li, X. Y. Wang, W. D. Li, Q. An, Y. Jiang, M. Yuan, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 137, 202505876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Fu, N. Sun, H. Chen, Y. Li, Y. Li, X. Zhu, B. Feng, X. Guo, C. Yao, W. Zhang, X. Li, J. Fang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2025, 18, 3305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Peng, K. Mao, F. Cai, H. Meng, Z. Zhu, T. Li, S. Yuan, Z. Xu, X. Feng, J. Xu, M. D. McGehee, J. Xu, Science 2023, 379, 683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Yu, Z. Xiong, H. Zhou, Q. Zhang, Z. Wang, F. Ma, Z. Qu, Y. Zhao, X. Chu, X. Zhang, J. You, Science 2023, 382, 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. H. Chen, G. W. Liu, X. Chen, C. Deger, R. J. Jin, K. L. Wang, J. Chen, Y. Xia, L. Huang, I. Yavuz, J. Fan, Z. K. Wang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 64, 202419375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Cui, W. Li, B. Feng, Y. Li, N. Sun, W. Zhang, S. Fu, X. Li, J. Fang, Joule 2025, 9, 102011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, W. Zhang, X. Guo, C. Lu, J. Wei, J. Fang, Science 2022, 375, 434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, H. Yang, A. Liu, C. Lu, H. Yuan, W. Zhang, J. Fang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 6071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Cui, W. Li, B. Feng, Y. Li, X. Guo, H. Yuan, Q. Weng, T. You, W. Zhang, X. Li, J. Fang, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2410273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Feng, W. Li, Z. Cui, Y. Li, Q. Weng, J. Xu, Y. Mao, T. You, T. Shu, W. Zhang, X. Li, J. Fang, J. Mater. Chem. C 2025, 13, 11608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Landgraf, Y. Gupta, A. Prasetio, S. Lange, C. Messmer, C. Schwarz, O. Fischer, S. Chanthalavong, O. Er&#x2010;raji, M. Camarada, S. Wolf, P. Schulze, A. Fischer, S. Glunz, J. Borchert, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 08186.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>