<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41398270</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6947</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical informatics and decision making</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Inform Decis Mak</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predictive machine learning for postoperative pain using biosignals: a retrospective observational study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12911-025-03305-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">Accurate prediction of postoperative pain can improve recovery quality and guide personalized pain management. This study aimed to develop and validate a machine learning (ML) model that predicts the presence of postoperative pain using biosignals recorded in the post-anesthesia care unit (PACU).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Adult patients who underwent surgery between January 2021 and December 2022 at Chungnam National University Hospital (CNUH) (<i>n</i> = 21,855) and Chungnam National University Sejong Hospital (CNUSH) (<i>n</i> = 2,356) in South Korea were included. Electrocardiography (ECG) and photoplethysmography (PPG) signals were continuously recorded during the postoperative period in the PACU. From these signals, heart rate variability (HRV) and surgical pleth index (SPI) features were extracted. These biosignal features, together with demographic variables, were used as input features for training the ML models, including logistic regression, support vector machine, multilayer perceptron, random forest, and XGBoost. The model was developed and internally validated using the CNUH dataset, while external validation was performed using the independent CNUSH dataset to assess generalizability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">In the test dataset of 1068 patients, 961 reported postoperative pain. The best-performing model achieved an accuracy of 85.2%, an AUROC of 0.77, and average precision of 0.95, while external validation yielded an accuracy of 83.2% and an AUROC of 0.78. Feature importance analysis using SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) indicated that the most influential predictors were the proportion of SPI values exceeding 50, the mean SPI, and the low-to-high frequency power ratio of HRV. Incorporating demographic features, such as age and sex, improved prediction accuracy by up to 5.91%. This improvement may be attributed to the mitigation of inter- and intra-individual variability inherent in biosignals, thereby enhancing the model&#x2019;s stability and generalizability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">ML models incorporating ECG- and PPG-derived features demonstrated reliable prediction of postoperative pain across independent hospital cohorts, highlighting the potential of biosignal-based approaches for objective pain assessment in clinical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12911-025-03305-z.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Jieun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of artificial intelligence, College of smart interdisciplinary engineering, Hannam University, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Dongheon</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Seoul National University College of Medicine, and Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Minwoong</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Chungnam National University Hospital, Chungnam National University School of Medicine, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Chahyun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Pain Medicine, Chungnam National University Hospital, Chungnam National University College of Medicine, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Seyeon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Nursing, Chungnam National University, Daejeon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Jiho</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Pain Medicine, Sejoung Chungnam National University Hospital, Chungnam National University College of Medicine, Sejoung, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Kyungsang</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. kkim24@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Boohwi</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Pain Medicine, Chungnam National University Hospital, Chungnam National University College of Medicine, Daejeon, Republic of Korea. koho0127@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Inform Decis Mak</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088682</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6947</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical pleth index</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: This study was performed in line with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and in accordance with the Transparent Reporting of a multivariable prediction model for Individual Prognosis or Diagnosis (TRIPOD) guidelines. The completed TRIPOD checklist is provided in Online Resource 3. Approval was granted by the Institutional Review Boards of Chungnam National University Hospital (2024.05.07/No. 2024-03-051) and Chungnam National University Sejong Hospital (2024.08.27/No. 2024-07-014001). Human ethics and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent to participate: The requirement for informed consent was waived by both institutions. Consent to publish: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors have no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41398270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12822141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-025-03305-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12911-025-03305-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Berning V, Laupheimer M, N&#xfc;bling M, Heidegger T. Influence of quality of recovery on patient satisfaction with anaesthesia and surgery: a prospective observational cohort study. Anaesthesia. 2017;72:1088&#x2013;96. 10.1111/anae.13906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.13906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28510285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddi D. Preventing chronic postoperative pain. Anaesthesia. 2016;71:64&#x2013;71. 10.1111/anae.13306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.13306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26620149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou R, Gordon DB, de Leon-casasola OA, Rosenberg JM, Bickler S, Brennan T, et al. Management of postoperative pain: a clinical practice guideline from the American Pain Society, the American Society of Regional Anesthesia and Pain Medicine, and the American Society of Anesthesiologists&#x2019; Committee on Regional Anesthesia, Executive Committee, and Administrative Council. J Pain. 2016;17:131&#x2013;57. 10.1016/j.jpain.2015.12.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpain.2015.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan TJ. Poorly controlled postoperative pain: prevalence, consequences, and prevention. J Pain Res. 2017;10:2287&#x2013;98. 10.2147/JPR.S144066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JPR.S144066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5626380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29026331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apfelbaum JL, Chen C, Mehta SS, Gan TJ. Postoperative pain experience: results from a national survey suggest postoperative pain continues to be undermanaged. Anesth Analg. 2003;97:534&#x2013;40. 10.1213/01.ANE.0000068822.10113.9E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/01.ANE.0000068822.10113.9E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12873949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CL, Raja SN. Treatment of acute postoperative pain. Lancet. 2011;377:2215&#x2013;25. 10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60245-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60245-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21704871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson A, Hoggart B. Pain: a review of three commonly used pain rating scales. J Clin Nurs. 2005;14:798&#x2013;804. 10.1111/j.1365-2702.2005.01121.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2702.2005.01121.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinson JN, Kavanagh T, Yamada J, Gill N, Stevens B. Systematic review of the psychometric properties, interpretability and feasibility of self-report pain intensity measures for use in clinical trials in children and adolescents. Pain. 2006;125:143&#x2013;57. 10.1016/j.pain.2006.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pain.2006.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16777328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DB, O&#x2019;Callaghan JP. Neuroendocrine aspects of the response to stress. Metabolism. 2002;51:5&#x2013;10. 10.1053/meta.2002.33184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2002.33184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12040534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mischkowski D, Palacios-Barrios EE, Banker L, Dildine TC, Atlas LY. Pain or nociception? Subjective experience mediates the effects of acute noxious heat on autonomic responses-corrected and republished. Pain. 2019;160:1469&#x2013;81. 10.1097/j.pain.0000000000001573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000001573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6553960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31107415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benarroch EE (2006) Pain-autonomic interactions. Neurol Sci. 27:S130&#x2013;S133 10.1007/s10072-006-0587-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16688616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greisen J, Juhl CB, Gr&#xf8;fte T, Vilstrup H, Jensen TS, Schmitz O. Acute pain induces insulin resistance in humans. Anesthesiology. 2001;95:578&#x2013;84. 10.1097/00000542-200109000-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000542-200109000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11575527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuji H, Shirasaka C, Asoh T, Uchida I. Effects of epidural administration of local anaesthetics or morphine on postoperative nitrogen loss and catabolic hormones. Br J Surg. 1987;74:421&#x2013;25. 10.1002/bjs.1800740536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bjs.1800740536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3594144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasylak TJ, Abbott FV, English MJM, Jeans ME. Reduction of post-operative morbidity following patient-controlled morphine. Can J Anaesth. 1990;37:726&#x2013;31. 10.1007/BF03006529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03006529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2225288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehlet H. Surgical stress: the role of pain and analgesia. Br J Anaesth. 1989;63:189&#x2013;95. 10.1093/bja/63.2.189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/63.2.189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2669908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charier D, Vogler MC, Zantour D, Pichot V, Martins-Baltar A, Courbon M, Roche F, Vassal F, Molliex S. Assessing pain in the postoperative period: analgesia nociception IndexTM versus pupillometry. Br J Anaesth. 2019;123:e322&#x2013;e327. 10.1016/j.bja.2018.09.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2018.09.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6676014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30915996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowen R, Stasiowska MK, Laycock H, Bantel C. Assessing pain objectively: the use of physiological markers. Anaesthesia. 2015;70:828&#x2013;47. 10.1111/anae.13018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.13018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25772783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huiku M, Uutela K, Van Gils M, Korhonen I, Kym&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen M, Meril&#xe4;inen P, et al. Assessment of surgical stress during general anaesthesia. Br J Anaesth. 2007;98:447&#x2013;55. 10.1093/bja/aem004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aem004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17329347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeanne M, Logier R, De Jonckheere J, Tavernier B. Heart rate variability during total intravenous anesthesia: effects of nociception and analgesia. Auton Neurosci. 2009;147:91&#x2013;96. 10.1016/j.autneu.2009.01.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autneu.2009.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19201661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabourdin N, Barrois J, Louvet N, Rigouzzo A, Guye ML, Dadure C, Constant I. Pupillometry-guided intraoperative remifentanil administration versus standard practice influences opioid use: a randomized study. Anesthesiology. 2017;127:284&#x2013;92. 10.1097/ALN.0000000000001705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000001705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28719527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Thee C, Gruenewald M, Wnent J, Illies C, Hoecker J, Hanss R, Steinfath M, Bein B. Comparison of surgical stress index-guided analgesia with standard clinical practice during routine general anesthesia: a pilot study. Anesthesiology. 2010;112:1175&#x2013;83. 10.1097/ALN.0b013e3181d3d641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0b013e3181d3d641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20418698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledowski T, Ang B, Schmarbeck T, Rhodes J. Monitoring of sympathetic tone to assess postoperative pain: skin conductance vs surgical stress index. Anaesthesia. 2009;64:727&#x2013;31. 10.1111/j.1365-2044.2008.05834.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2044.2008.05834.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19183409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boselli E, Bouvet L, B&#xe9;gou G, Dabouz R, Davidson J, Deloste JY, et al. Prediction of immediate postoperative pain using the analgesia/nociception index: a prospective observational study. Br J Anaesth. 2014;112:715&#x2013;21. 10.1093/bja/aet407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aet407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24322571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Task Force of the European Society of Cardiology the North American Society of Pacing Electrophysiology. Heart rate variability: standards of measurement, physiological interpretation, and clinical use. Circulation. 1996;93:1043&#x2013;65. doi:10.1161/01.CIR.93.5.1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8598068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi BM, Park C, Lee YH, Shin H, Lee SH, Jeong S, et al. Development of a new analgesic index using nasal photoplethysmography. Anaesthesia. 2018;73:1123&#x2013;30. 10.1111/anae.14327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.14327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29790159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhang DF, Chu YS, Cai JH, Tai YY, Chuang CC. Pain monitoring using heart rate variability and photoplethysmograph-derived parameters by binary logistic regression. J Med Biol Eng. 2021;41:669&#x2013;77. 10.1007/s40846-021-00651-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40846-021-00651-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasaeyan Naeini E, Subramanian A, Calderon MD, Zheng K, Dutt N, Liljeberg P, Salantera S, Nelson AM, Rahmani AM. Pain recognition with electrocardiographic features in postoperative patients: method validation study. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23:e25079. 10.2196/25079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/25079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8196363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34047710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok HS, Choi BM, Noh GJ, Shin H. Postoperative pain assessment model based on pulse contour characteristics analysis. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2019;23:2317&#x2013;24. 10.1109/JBHI.2018.2890482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2018.2890482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30605112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisson L, Nadeau-Vall&#xe9;e M, Espitalier F, Laferri&#xe8;re-Langlois P, Idrissi M, Lahrichi N, et al. Prediction of acute postoperative pain based on intraoperative nociception level (NOL) index values: the impact of machine learning-based analysis. J Clin Monit Comput. 2023;37:337&#x2013;44. 10.1007/s10877-022-00897-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10877-022-00897-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35925430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jean WH, Sutikno P, Fan SZ, Abbod MF, Shieh JS. Comparison of deep learning algorithms in predicting expert assessments of pain scores during surgical operations using analgesia nociception index. Sensors (Basel). 2022;22:5496. 10.3390/s22155496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22155496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9330343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35897999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salekin MS, Zamzmi G, Goldgof D, Kasturi R, Ho T, Sun Y. Multimodal spatio-temporal deep learning approach for neonatal postoperative pain assessment. Comput Biol Med. 2021;129:104150. 10.1016/j.compbiomed.2020.104150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2020.104150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33348218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi BM, Yim JY, Shin H, Noh G. Novel analgesic index for postoperative pain assessment based on a photoplethysmographic spectrogram and convolutional neural network: observational study. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23:e23920. 10.2196/23920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/23920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7889419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33533723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledowski T. Objective monitoring of nociception: a review of current commercial solutions. Br J Anaesth. 2019;123:e312&#x2013;e321. 10.1016/j.bja.2019.03.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2019.03.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6676047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31047645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arg&#xfc;ello-Prada EJ, Molano Valencia RDM. On the use of indexes derived from photoplethysmographic (PPG) signals for postoperative pain assessment: a narrative review. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2023;80:104335. 10.1016/j.bspc.2022.104335</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So V, Balanaser M, Klar G, Leitch J, McGillion M, Devereaux PJ, et al. Scoping review of the association between postsurgical pain and heart rate variability parameters. PAIN Rep. 2021;6:e977. 10.1097/PR9.0000000000000977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8824397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35155967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan A, Pantelopoulos A, Emir-Farinas H, Natarajan P. Heart rate variability with photoplethysmography in 8 million individuals: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Digit Health. 2020;2:e650&#x2013;e657. 10.1016/S2589-7500(20)30246-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2589-7500(20)30246-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33328029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kachuee M, Kiani MM, Mohammadzade H, Shabany M. Cuffless blood pressure estimation algorithms for continuous health-care monitoring. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 2017;64:859&#x2013;69. 10.1109/TBME.2016.2580904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBME.2016.2580904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27323356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Moons KGM, Dhiman P, Riley RD, Beam AL, van Calster B, Ghassemi M. TRIPOD+AI statement: updated guidance for reporting clinical prediction models that use regression or machine learning methods. BMJ. 2024;e078378. 10.1136/bmj-2023-078378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11019967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38626948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HC, Jung CW. Vital Recorder-a free research tool for automatic recording of high-resolution time-synchronised physiological data from multiple anaesthesia devices. Sci Rep. 2018;8:1527. 10.1038/s41598-018-20062-4, Available at http://vitaldb.net
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-20062-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5784161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29367620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung K, Park MH, Kim DK, Kim BJ. Prediction of postoperative pain and opioid consumption using intraoperative surgical pleth index after surgical incision: an observational study. J Pain Res. 2020;13:2815&#x2013;24. 10.2147/JPR.S264101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JPR.S264101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruenewald M, Willms S, Broch O, Kott M, Steinfath M, Bein B. Sufentanil administration guided by surgical pleth index vs standard practice during sevoflurane anaesthesia: a randomized controlled pilot study. Br J Anaesth. 2014;112:898&#x2013;905. 10.1093/bja/aet485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aet485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24535604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledowski T, Burke J, Hruby J. Surgical pleth index: prediction of postoperative pain and influence of arousal. Br J Anaesth. 2016;117:371&#x2013;74. 10.1093/bja/aew226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aew226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27543532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struys MM, Vanpeteghem C, Huiku M, Uutela K, Blyaert NB, Mortier EP. Changes in a surgical stress index in response to standardized pain stimuli during propofol&#x2014;remifentanil infusion. Br J Anaesth. 2007;99:359&#x2013;67. 10.1093/bja/aem173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aem173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung KC, Huang YT, Kuo JR, Hsu CW, Yew M, Chen JY, et al. Elevated surgical pleth index at the end of surgery is associated with postoperative moderate-to-severe pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Diagnostics. 2022;12:2167. 10.3390/diagnostics12092167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics12092167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9498235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36140567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh C, Chung W, Hong B. Optimizing patient-controlled analgesia: a narrative review based on a single center audit process. Anesth Pain Med (Seoul). 2024;19:171&#x2013;84. 10.17085/apm.24075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17085/apm.24075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11317320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39118331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldheiser A, Aziz O, Baldini G, Cox BP, Fearon KCH, Feldman LS, et al. Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) for gastrointestinal surgery, part 2: consensus statement for anaesthesia practice. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2016;60:289&#x2013;334. 10.1111/aas.12651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aas.12651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5061107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26514824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs A, Lemoine A, Joshi GP, Van de Velde M, Bonnet F, PROSPECT Working Group collaborators#, et al. PROSPECT guideline for oncological breast surgery: a systematic review and procedure-specific postoperative pain management recommendations. Anaesthesia. 2020;75:664&#x2013;73.10.1111/anae.14964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31984479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feray S, Lubach J, Joshi GP, Bonnet F, Van de Velde M, PROSPECT Working Group* of the European Society of Regional Anaesthesia and Pain Therapy, et al. PROSPECT guidelines for video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery: a systematic review and procedure-specific postoperative pain management recommendations. Anaesthesia. 2022;77:311&#x2013;25.10.1111/anae.15609</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anae.15609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9297998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34739134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>