<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41530242</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multi-agent coordination and uncertainty adaptation in deep learning-assisted hierarchical optimization for renewable-dominated distribution networks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5176</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5176</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5176</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35945-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid proliferation of renewable energy sources has introduced multi-layered uncertainty into modern power system operation, challenging conventional deterministic and stochastic optimization frameworks. To address this complexity, this study proposes a deep learning-assisted distributionally robust optimization (Deep-DRO) framework designed to enhance both economic efficiency and operational reliability under uncertainty. The model integrates a hierarchical coordination architecture, wherein deep learning modules infer the probabilistic structure of uncertain variables-such as solar irradiance, wind availability, and load fluctuation-while the DRO layer enforces system-wide robustness through an adaptively reshaped ambiguity set. The learning-assisted ambiguity reconstruction enables the optimization to dynamically adjust conservativeness, improving the tradeoff between cost, reliability, and renewable utilization. Methodologically, the proposed framework employs a multi-agent dispatch structure consisting of three decision layers-county, feeder, and distributed energy resource (DER)-each learning distinct policy mappings through reinforcement-guided coordination. Deep networks trained on high-resolution meteorological and operational data estimate scenario distributions, while the robust optimization core minimizes expected cost and reliability penalties under distributional ambiguity. The resulting hybrid system seamlessly couples data-driven forecasting and model-based optimization, bridging the gap between predictive intelligence and operational robustness. To ensure scalability and interpretability, convergence diagnostics, sensitivity analyses, and cost decomposition studies are performed across multiple test systems and uncertainty scenarios. Simulation results on a benchmark multi-region distribution network demonstrate substantial performance gains. Compared to conventional DRO, the Deep-DRO model reduces total operational cost by 11.0-13.5%, improves reliability indices from 0.864 to 0.911, and raises renewable utilization from 85.6% to 89.7%. The integrated deep learning mechanism effectively captures latent correlations among stochastic parameters, enabling the system to maintain resilience even under 30% higher uncertainty variance. Furthermore, carbon emissions decline by 28.6% relative to baseline, confirming that the proposed method achieves an intrinsic balance between economic optimization and environmental sustainability. The analysis reveals that hierarchical learning fosters adaptive coordination among agents, while the robust layer guarantees performance consistency across uncertain conditions. The study thus advances a generalizable paradigm for intelligent, risk-aware energy management, offering theoretical and practical implications for future power system restoration, smart grid autonomy, and sustainable dispatch design.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Yongle</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Henan Electric Power Company Economic and Technology Research Institute, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Huixuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Henan Electric Power Company Economic and Technology Research Institute, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shiqian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Henan Electric Power Company Economic and Technology Research Institute, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Zhongfu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>North China Electric Power University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoliang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Henan Electric Power Company Economic and Technology Research Institute, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Henan Electric Power Company Economic and Technology Research Institute, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yijun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>North China Electric Power University, Beijing, China. 18231753079@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hongkai</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Henan Electric Power Company Economic and Technology Research Institute, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>5217L0250006</GrantID><Agency>2025 Science and Technology Project of State Grid Henan Electric Power Company</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41530242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12881368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35945-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35945-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Holmes, H. E., Realff, M. J. &amp; Lively, R. P. Water management and heat integration in direct air capture systems. <i>Nat. Chem. Eng.</i><b>1</b>(3), 208&#x2013;215 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44286-024-00032-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, Q., Zhang, Z., Wang, Y. &amp; Zhang, L. A review of distributed energy systems: technologies, classification, and applications. <i>Sustainability</i><b>17</b>(4), 1346 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17041346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. &amp; Zhen, J. Evaluating the economic and environmental impacts of distributed photovoltaic policy: Insights from county-level data in China. <i>Energy Policy</i><b>198</b>, 114509 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enpol.2025.114509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, L., Geng, Y., Zhang, Y., Zhang, Y. &amp; Wang, H. Testing the effectiveness of deploying distributed photovoltaic power systems in residential buildings: evidence from rural China. <i>Environ. Impact Assess. Rev.</i><b>104</b>, 107300 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eiar.2023.107300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T. T., Zhao, A. P., Wang, Y. &amp; Alhazmi, M. Hybrid energy storage for dairy farms: enhancing energy efficiency and operational resilience. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>114</b>, 115811 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.115811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, A. P. et al. Hydrogen as the nexus of future sustainable transport and energy systems. <i>Nat. Rev. Electr. Eng.</i><b>2025</b>, 1&#x2013;20 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, H., Zhang, Z., Hu, C., Gong, Y. &amp; Cheng, D. A survey on spatio-temporal big data analytics ecosystem: resource management, processing platform, and applications. <i>IEEE Trans. Big Data</i><b>10</b>(2), 174&#x2013;193 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBDATA.2023.3342619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hady, M. A., Hu, S., Pratama, M., Cao, Z. &amp; Kowalczyk, R. Multi-agent reinforcement learning for resources allocation optimization: a survey. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>58</b>(11), 354 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-025-11340-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choppara, P. &amp; Mangalampalli, S. S. Resource adaptive automated task scheduling using deep deterministic policy gradient in fog computing. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>2025</b>, 256 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T. T. et al. Integrating solar-powered electric vehicles into sustainable energy systems. <i>Nat. Rev. Electr. Eng.</i><b>2025</b>, 256. 10.1038/s44287-025-00181-7 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44287-025-00181-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, A. P. et al. AI for science: covert cyberattacks on energy storage systems. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>99</b>, 112835. 10.1016/j.est.2024.112835 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.112835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Maghraoui, A. et al. Revolutionizing smart grid-ready management systems: a holistic framework for optimal grid reliability. <i>Sustain. Energy Grids Netw.</i><b>39</b>, 101452 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.segan.2024.101452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi, M. &amp; Mohammadi, A. Empowering distributed solutions in renewable energy systems and grid optimization. In <i>Distributed Machine Learning and Computing: Theory and Applications</i> 141&#x2013;155 (Springer, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michailidis, P., Michailidis, I. &amp; Kosmatopoulos, E. Reinforcement learning for optimizing renewable energy utilization in buildings: a review on applications and innovations. <i>Energies</i><b>18</b>(7), 1724 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18071724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P., Gu, C., Cheng, X., Li, J. &amp; Alhazmi, M. Integrated energy-water systems for community-level flexibility: a hybrid deep Q-network and multi-objective optimization framework. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 4813&#x2013;4826. 10.1016/j.egyr.2025.03.059 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2025.03.059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurbuz, F. B., Karaki, A., Karaki, A., Demirbas, S. &amp; Bayhan, S. Model-free reinforcement learning in microgrid control: a review. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>2025</b>, 256 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fose, N., Singh, A. R., Krishnamurthy, S., Ratshitanga, M. &amp; Moodley, P. Empowering distribution system operators: a review of distributed energy resource forecasting techniques. <i>Heliyon</i><b>10</b>, 15 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e34800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11327517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39157304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannan, M. et al. Recent development of grid-connected microgrid scheduling controllers for sustainable energy: a bibliometric analysis and future directions. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>12</b>, 90606&#x2013;90628 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3419443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juma, S. A., Ayeng&#x2019;o, S. P. &amp; Kimambo, C. Z. A review of control strategies for optimized microgrid operations. <i>IET Renew. Power Gener.</i><b>18</b>(14), 2785&#x2013;2818 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/rpg2.13056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, X., Dong, X., Wang, C., Yang, M. &amp; Lu, T. Decentralized power transfer limit calculation method considering spatial and seasonal differences of ambient factors. <i>J. Modern Power Syst. Clean Energy</i><b>13</b>(6), 1955&#x2013;1965 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manogna, R., Dharmaji, V. &amp; Sarang, S. Enhancing agricultural commodity price forecasting with deep learning. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>(1), 20903 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-05103-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12215695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40595985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haq, I. U., Kumar, A. &amp; Rathore, P. S. Machine learning approaches for wind power forecasting: a comprehensive review. <i>Discover Appl. Sci.</i><b>7</b>(10), 1139 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-025-07675-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P., Shen, Y., Shang, Y. &amp; Alhazmi, M. Innovative distribution network design using GAN-based distributionally robust optimization for DG planning. <i>IET Gener. Transm. Distrib.</i><b>19</b>(1), e13350 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/gtd2.13350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M. et al. Enhancing cyber-resiliency of der-based smart grid: a survey. <i>IEEE Trans. Smart Grid</i><b>15</b>(5), 4998&#x2013;5030 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSG.2024.3373008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thallapally, P. &amp; Panda, D. An aggregator-based market modelling with an impact of risk under uncertainty. <i>IEEE Lat. Am. Trans.</i><b>23</b>(5), 415&#x2013;426 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TLA.2025.10974375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J., Shi, X., Guo, L., Wan, Y. &amp; Wen, G. Distributed proximal alternating direction method of multipliers for constrained composite optimization over directed networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Signal Inf. Process. Netw.</i><b>10</b>, 539&#x2013;551 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, X. et al. Coordinated operation of multi-energy microgrids considering green hydrogen and congestion management via a safe policy learning approach. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>401</b>, 126611 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.126611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>