<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41565773</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A proposed reinforcement learning approach via discrete control reformulation and multi-step double DQN for adaptive cruise control in electric vehicles.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3041</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3041</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3041</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-33218-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Adaptive cruise control (ACC) plays a critical role in enhancing road safety and energy efficiency in electric vehicles (EVs). Traditional ACC approaches often face challenges in adapting to complex, dynamic driving environments. AI-driven reinforcement learning (RL) has emerged as a promising solution; however, its real-world adoption faces key challenges, including training stability, convergence speed, and robustness in diverse scenarios. This work reformulates the ACC control structure using a simplified action abstraction that unifies throttle and brake into a single scalar variable within a discrete action space. This design enables smooth, human-like driving behavior while allowing the use of simpler and more stable Deep Q-Network (DQN) variants. To address this, we integrate multi-step returns with Double DQN architecture (Double-MS DQN) to accelerate convergence and enhance policy stability. A stochastic scenario generator is also implemented to expose the agent to varied and unpredictable lead-vehicle behaviors during training and evaluation. The results conducted in the CARLA simulator show that the proposed approach achieves significantly faster convergence (up to 73% reduction in training episodes) and reduces headway errors by over 40% compared to standard DQN, Dueling DQN, and Double DQN. The proposed Double-MS DQN demonstrates that adapting the RL control formulation enables high-performance learning with lightweight, scalable algorithms delivering safer and smoother control in practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meghawer</LastName><ForeName>Assem</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department Arab Academy for Science and Technology and Maritime Transport (AASTMT) Smart-Village Branch , 12577, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Power Engineering and Mechatronics , Tallinn University of Technology, Tallinn, Estonia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Shaer</LastName><ForeName>Yasser</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department Arab Academy for Science and Technology and Maritime Transport (AASTMT) Smart-Village Branch , 12577, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Sebah</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed I Abu</ForeName><Initials>MIA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power Electronics and Energy Conversion Department , Electronics Research Institute , Cairo, 11843, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Khatib</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed Fawzy</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechatronics and Robotics Engineering Department Faculty of Engineering , Egyptian Russian University , Cairo, 11829, Egypt. muhamed.fawzy@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive cruise control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep Q-Network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Double deep Q-Network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electric vehicles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-Scenario testing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reinforcement learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41565773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12828003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-33218-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-33218-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. An intelligent adaptive cruise control using deep reinforcement learning and multi-objective reward shaping. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>111</b>, 104852 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, H. et al. Convergence-aware DRL for adaptive cruise with uncertain traffic patterns. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>116</b>, 105728 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Wei, M., Li &amp; Chen, H. Deep reinforcement learning for adaptive cruise control in complex driving scenarios. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>23</b> (2), 789&#x2013;801 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ploeg, J. et al. Nathanand Design and experimental evaluation of cooperative adaptive cruise control. <i>IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems</i>, vol. 19, no. 3, pp. 939&#x2013;950, (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fridman, L., Brown, D. E., Lake, B. M. &amp; Cox, D. D. Active learning for adaptive cruise control with electric vehicle energy optimization. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh.</i><b>5</b> (4), 591&#x2013;602 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalmers University of Technology. A comparison between MPC and PID controllers for education and research. Master&#x2019;s Thesis, Department of Signals and Systems, (2014). Available: https://publications.lib.chalmers.se/records/fulltext/204637/204637.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Khatib, M. F., Khater, F. M., Hendawi, E. &amp; El-Sebah M I A 2025 simplified and intelligent controllers for multi-input multi-output processes eng. <i>Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>141</b> 109816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integra Sources. Basics of PID controllers: Working principles, pros &amp; cons. 2023. Available: https://www.integrasources.com/blog/basics-of-pid-controllers-design-applications/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falcone, P., Borrelli, F., Eric Tseng, H., Asgari, J. &amp; Hrovat, D. Predictive active steering control for autonomous vehicle systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Control Syst. Technol.</i><b>15</b> (3), 566&#x2013;580 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCST.2007.894653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kural, E., Hacibekir, T. &amp; Aksun-Guvenc, B. State of the art of adaptive cruise control and stop and go systems. <i>arXiv preprint</i> arXiv:2012.12438, 2020. Available: https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.12438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boddupalli, S., Rao, A. S. &amp; Ray, S. Resilient cooperative adaptive cruise control for autonomous vehicles using machine learning. <i>arXiv preprint</i> arXiv:2103.10533, 2021. Available: https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.10533</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Zhao, L. &amp; Li, H. Scenario-based reinforcement learning for autonomous vehicle control in uncertain environments. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>119</b>, 105791 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2022.105791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z., Wang, D. &amp; Li, R. Sim-to-real transfer in reinforcement learning-based driving policies using probabilistic disturbance models. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>115</b>, 105697 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mnih, V. et al. <i>Human-level Control Through Deep Reinforcement Learn. Nature</i>, <b>518</b>, 7540, 529&#x2013;533, (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25719670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hasselt, Hado, A., Guez &amp; Silver, D. Deep reinforcement learning with double Q-learning. In <i>Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</i>, vol. 30, no. 1, pp. 2094&#x2013;2100, (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Khatib, M., Fawzy, M. N., Sabry, Mohamed, I., Abu El-Sebah &amp; Maged, S. A. Hardware-in-the-loop testing of simple and intelligent MPPT control algorithm for an electric vehicle charging power by photovoltaic system. <i>ISA Trans.</i>, (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36725414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiran, B. et al. Senthil Yogamani, and Patrick Perez. Deep reinforcement learning for autonomous driving: A survey. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>23</b> (6), 4909&#x2013;4926 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2021.3054625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Zhang, Q. &amp; Yang, R. Safety-First reinforcement learning for adaptive cruise control. <i>Sens. (Basel)</i>. <b>24</b> (8), 2657 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24082657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11055141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38676274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Q., Zhang, X., Zhao, P. &amp; Sun, L. Large Language Model Guided Deep Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Driving, <i>arXiv preprint arXiv:2412.18511</i>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Zhang, K. &amp; Zhang, C. Vision-Language Model Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Vehicle Decision-Making, <i>arXiv preprint arXiv:2412.15544</i>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marc, G., Bellemare, W., Dabney, R. &amp; Munos A Distributional Perspective on Reinforcement Learning, ICML, (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, X., Vemula, A., Scherer, S. &amp; Sycara, K. Multi-scenario reinforcement learning for safe and efficient autonomous driving. <i>IEEE Trans. Neural Networks Learn. Syst.</i><b>32</b> (7), 3153&#x2013;3167 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. E. et al. Real-time energy management for HEV combining naturalistic driving data and deep reinforcement learning with high generalization, Applied Energy, vol. 377, p. 124350, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. E. et al. Deep reinforcement Learning-Based energy management for heavy duty HEV considering Discrete-Continuous hybrid action space. <i>IEEE Trans. Transp. Electrification</i>. 10.1109/TTE.2024.3363650 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TTE.2024.3363650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, M. et al. Multi-Agent reinforcement learning for connected and automated vehicles control: recent advancements and future prospects. <i>IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng.</i>10.1109/TASE.2025.3574280 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2025.3574280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. E., Zhou, Q., Li, Y., Shuai, S. &amp; Xu, H. Safe deep reinforcement Learning-Based constrained optimal control scheme for HEV energy management. <i>IEEE Trans. Transp. Electrification</i>. <b>9</b> (3), 3866&#x2013;3880 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TTE.2023.3240430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy, A., Ros, G., Codevilla, F., Lopez, A. &amp; Koltun, V. CARLA: An open urban driving simulator. In <i>Proceedings of the 1st Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL)</i>, PMLR, pp. 1&#x2013;16, (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajamani, R. Vehicle Dynamics and Control, Springer, 2nd Edition, (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard, S., Sutton, A. G. &amp; Barto Reinforcement Learning: An Introduction, MIT, (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Organization for Standardization. ISO 15622: Intelligent transport systems &#x2013; Adaptive Cruise Control systems &#x2013; Performance requirements and test procedures. ISO Standard No. 15622, 2018. Available: https://www.iso.org/standard/73764.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery, D. C. <i>Design and Analysis of Experiments</i>, 8th Edition, Wiley, (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall, A. et al. Learning to drive in a day. In <i>Proceedings of the 2019 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)</i>, pp. 8248&#x2013;8254, (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. S. et al., Safe and Energy-Efficient Jerk-Controlled speed profiling for On-Road autonomous vehicles. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Vehicles</i>, pp. 1&#x2013;16, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hitachi Astemo Development of an Anti-Jerk control to improve ride comfort of electrified vehicles. <i>Hitachi News Release</i>, (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haarnoja, T., Zhou, A., Abbeel, P. &amp; Levine, S. Soft Actor-Critic: Off-Policy Maximum Entropy Deep Reinforcement Learning with a Stochastic Actor, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto, S., Hoof, H. &amp; Meger, D. Addressing Function Approximation Error in Actor-Critic Methods, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), (2018).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>