<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41347955</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relationship Between Hip and Knee Muscle Volume and Neuromuscular Function in Women With Patellofemoral Pain.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001396</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the relationship between hip and knee muscle volume and neuromuscular function (isokinetic strength, rate of torque development, and torque variability) in women with patellofemoral pain (PFP).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Cross-sectional study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">University research laboratory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty women with PFP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Isokinetic strength (60 degrees/second and 180 degrees/second), rate of torque development, and torque variability were assessed with an isokinetic dynamometer for hip extension, hip abduction, knee extension, and knee flexion. Muscle volume of the lower extremity muscles (cm3/kg&#xb7;m) was quantified through magnetic resonance imaging. Pearson r correlation or Spearman &#x3c1; coefficients were calculated to evaluate the relationship between muscle volume and neuromuscular function, with significance set at P &lt; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Muscle volume for all muscle groups was moderately correlated with isokinetic strength at 60 degrees/second, r &#x2265; 0.452, P &#x2264; 0.046. Hip abduction and extension were moderately correlated with isokinetic strength at 180 degrees/second, r &#x2265; 0.485, P &#x2264; 0.030; however, no significant correlations were identified between muscle volume and rate of force development or torque variability, P &lt; 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results suggest that isokinetic strength is associated with hip and knee muscle volume in women with PFP; however, additional measures of neuromuscular function (rate of torque development and torque variability) are not associated with muscle volume in lower extremity muscles.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Rutvi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rivera</LastName><ForeName>Hector</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Diana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sungwan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Sports Medicine, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glaviano</LastName><ForeName>Neal R</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4515-8015</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Sports Medicine, University of Connecticut, Storrs, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior knee pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isokinetic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rate of torque development</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41347955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-990000000-00354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Crossley KM, Stefanik JJ, Selfe J, et al. 2016 patellofemoral pain consensus statement from the 4th international patellofemoral pain research retreat, Manchester. Part 1: terminology, definitions, clinical examination, natural history, patellofemoral osteoarthritis and patient-reported outcome measures. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:839&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BE, Selfe J, Thacker D, et al. Incidence and prevalence of patellofemoral pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0190892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boling M, Padua D, Marshall S, et al. Gender differences in the incidence and prevalence of patellofemoral pain syndrome. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:725&#x2013;730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers CM, Witvrouw E, Davis IS, et al. Evidence-based framework for a pathomechanical model of patellofemoral pain: 2017 patellofemoral pain consensus statement from the 4th international patellofemoral pain research retreat, Manchester, UK: part 3. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1713&#x2013;1723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stathopulu E, Baildam E. Anterior knee pain: a long-term follow-up. Rheumatology 2003;42:380&#x2013;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathleff CR, Olesen JL, Roos EM, et al. Half of 12-15-year-olds with knee pain still have pain after one year. Danish Med J. 2013;60:A4725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaviano NR, Baellow A, Saliba S. Physical activity levels in individuals with and without patellofemoral pain. Phys Ther Sport. 2017;27:12&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coburn SL, Barton CJ, Filbay SR, et al. Quality of life in individuals with patellofemoral pain: a systematic review including meta-analysis. Phys Ther Sport. 2018;33:96&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles LS, Webster KE, McClelland JA, et al. Does quadriceps atrophy exist in individuals with patellofemoral pain? A systematic literature review with meta-analysis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2013;43:766&#x2013;776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins NJ, Barton CJ, van Middelkoop M, et al. 2018 2018 Consensus statement on exercise therapy and physical interventions (orthoses, taping and manual therapy) to treat patellofemoral pain: recommendations from the 5th International Patellofemoral Pain Research Retreat, Gold Coast, Australia, 2017. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:1170&#x2013;1178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaviano NR, Kim S. Lower extremity muscle volume in females with patellofemoral pain and its relationships to hip and knee torque: a cross-sectional study. Phys Ther Sport. 2023;63:50&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Park J, Boling MC, et al. Lower extremity muscle volume in unilateral and bilateral patellofemoral pain: a cross-sectional exploratory study including superficial and deep muscles authors. J Athl Train. 2024;59(9):915&#x2013;924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Zuk EF, DiStefano LJ, et al. Lower extremity strength has weak or no associations with clinical outcomes in individuals with patellofemoral pain: a systematic review with evidence gap map and meta-analysis. JOSPT Open. 2024;2:179&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SEK, Lira CAB, Nouailhetas VLA, et al. Do isometric, isotonic and/or isokinetic strength trainings produce different strength outcomes? J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2018;22:430&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briani RV, de Oliveira Silva D, Ducatti MHM, et al. Knee flexor strength and rate of torque development deficits in women with patellofemoral pain are related to poor objective function. Gait Posture. 2021;83:100&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira AS, de Oliveira Silva D, Ferrari D, et al. Knee and hip isometric force steadiness are impaired in women with patellofemoral pain. J Strength Cond Res, 35. 2878, 2885, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan CM, Kim S, Glaviano NR. Hip rate of torque development, but not strength, is associated with single-leg squat kinematics in individuals with patellofemoral pain. Physiother Theor Pract, 41. 2025:695&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lankhorst NE, van Middelkoop M, Crossley KM, et al. Factors that predict a poor outcome 5-8 years after the diagnosis of patellofemoral pain: a multicentre observational analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:881&#x2013;886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, et al. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Int J Surg (London, England). 2014;12:1495&#x2013;1499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton CJ, De Oliveira Silva D, Morton S, et al. REPORT-PFP: a consensus from the International Patellofemoral Research Network to improve REPORTing of quantitative PatelloFemoral Pain studies. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:1135&#x2013;1143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crossley KM, Bennell KL, Cowan SM, et al. Analysis of outcome measures for persons with patellofemoral pain: which are reliable and valid? Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004;85:815&#x2013;822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoglund LT, Scalzitti DA, Jayaseelan DJ, et al. Patient-reported outcome measures for adults and adolescents with patellofemoral pain: a systematic review of construct validity, reliability, responsiveness, and interpretability using the COSMIN methodology. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2023;53:460&#x2013;479&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boling MC, Padua DA, Alexander Creighton R. Concentric and eccentric torque of the hip musculature in individuals with and without patellofemoral pain. J Athl Train. 2009;44:7&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetschius J, Hart JM. Knee-extension torque variability and subjective knee function in patients with A history of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train, 51. 22, 27, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Park J. Patients with chronic unilateral anterior knee pain experience bilateral deficits in quadriceps function and lower quarter flexibility: a cross-sectional study. Physiother Theor Pract. 2022;38:2531&#x2013;2543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handsfield GG, Meyer CH, Hart JM, et al. Relationships of 35 lower limb muscles to height and body mass quantified using MRI. J Biomech. 2014;47:631&#x2013;638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffiuletti NA, Aagaard P, Blazevich AJ, et al. Rate of force development: physiological and methodological considerations. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:1091&#x2013;1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J, Malter H, Fehilly C, et al. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2 ed. 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenze CM, Blemker SS, Hart JM. Quadriceps function relates to muscle size following ACL reconstruction. J Orthop Res. 2016;34:1656&#x2013;1662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukunaga T, Miyatani M, Tachi M, et al. Muscle volume is a major determinant of joint torque in humans. Acta Physiol Scand. 2001;172:249&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya D, Citaker S, Kerimoglu U, et al. Women with patellofemoral pain syndrome have quadriceps femoris volume and strength deficiency. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2011;19:242&#x2013;247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison MJ, Maly MR, Keir PJ, et al. Lean muscle volume of the thigh has a stronger relationship with muscle power than muscle strength in women with knee osteoarthritis. Clin Biomech. 2017;41:92&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Negro F, Gazzoni M, et al. Detecting the unique representation of motor-unit action potentials in the surface electromyogram. J Neurophysiol. 2008;100:1223&#x2013;1233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Valdes E, Laine CM, Falla D, et al. High-density surface electromyography provides reliable estimates of motor unit behavior. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127:2534&#x2013;2541.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>