<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600379</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Attention-Based Bidirectional Feature Fusion Algorithm for Insulator Detection.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">584</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020584</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To maintain reliability, safety, and sustainability in power transmission, insulator defect detection has become a critical task in power line inspection. Due to the complex backgrounds and small defect sizes encountered in insulator defect images, issues such as false detections and missed detections often occur. The existing You Only Look Once (YOLO) object detection algorithm is currently the mainstream method for image-based insulator defect detection in power lines. However, existing models suffer from low detection accuracy. To address this issue, this paper presents an improved YOLOv5-based MC-YOLO insulator detection algorithm. To effectively extract multi-scale information and enhance the model's ability to represent feature information, a multi-scale attention convolutional fusion (MACF) module incorporating an attention mechanism is proposed. This module utilises parallel convolutions with different kernel sizes to effectively extract features at various scales and highlights the feature representation of key targets through the attention mechanism, thereby improving the detection accuracy. Additionally, a cross-context feature fusion module (CCFM) is designed, where shallow features gain partial deep semantic supplementation and deep features absorb shallow spatial information, achieving bidirectional information flow. Furthermore, the Spatial-Channel Dual Attention Module (SCDAM) is introduced into CCFM. By incorporating a dynamic attention-guided bidirectional cross-fusion mechanism, it effectively resolves the feature deviation between shallow details and deep semantics during multi-scale feature fusion. The experimental results show that the MC-YOLO algorithm achieves an mAP@0.5 of 67.4% on the dataset used in this study, which is a 4.1% improvement over the original YOLOv5. Although the FPS is slightly reduced compared to the original model, it remains practical and capable of rapidly and accurately detecting insulator defects.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Binghao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-6637-1190</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Information Engineering, Inner Mongolia University of Technology, Hohhot 010080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Jinyu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-7518-4653</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Information Engineering, Inner Mongolia University of Technology, Hohhot 010080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yongyue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-0399-7553</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Information Engineering, Inner Mongolia University of Technology, Hohhot 010080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Dong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6312-0438</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Information Engineering, Inner Mongolia University of Technology, Hohhot 010080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inner Mongolia Key Laboratory of Intelligent Perception and System Engineering, Hohhot 010080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Information Engineering, Inner Mongolia University of Technology, Hohhot 010080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inner Mongolia Key Laboratory of Intelligent Perception and System Engineering, Hohhot 010080, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>S202510128018</GrantID><Agency>Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region College Students' Innovation and Entrepreneurship Training Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025YFHH0035</GrantID><Agency>Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Key Scientific and Technological R&amp;D and Achievement Transformation Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JY20250087</GrantID><Agency>Basic Scientific Research Business Fee Project for Universities Directly under the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feature fusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulator detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-scale features</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12845999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li B., Zhang J., Bu X. Insulator Detection from Arbitrary Angles in Aerial Photography Based on Neighborhood Information Interaction. Electron. Meas. Technol. 2023;46:117&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long Y., Wei W., Shu Y., Zhang Z., Wang D., Li F. Defect Detection Method for Rotating Insulators Based on Adaptive Keypoints. Comput. Eng. 2023;49:272&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L., Hu J., Wang W., He L., Zhou K., Su Z., Yan L., Liu R., Wang B., Tu Y. Study on the Effect of Environmental Conditions on the Zero-Value Insulator Detection Criterion Based on UAV Infrared Inspection. Electr. Porcelain Arresters. 2023:171&#x2013;177. doi: 10.16188/j.isa.1003-8337.2023.05.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16188/j.isa.1003-8337.2023.05.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Zhang Z., Huang Y. Welding Fixture and Welding Method for High-Voltage Power Transmission and Transformation Insulators: CN202310870871.8. Patent CN116586881A. 2024 February 27;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang W., Yang Q. Transformative Impact of Industrial Intelligence Based on Deep Learning on Economic Development. J. Yulin Univ. 2023;33:62&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross G. Fast R-CNN; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV); Santiago, Chile. 7&#x2013;13 December 2015; pp. 1440&#x2013;1448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICCV.2015.169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren S., He K., Girshick R., Sun J. Faster R-CNN: Towards Real-Time Object Detection with Region Proposal Networks. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2017;39:1137&#x2013;1149. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2016.2577031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z., Vasconcelos N. Cascade R-CNN: Delving into high quality object detection; Proceedings of the 2018 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;23 June 2018; pp. 6154&#x2013;6162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmon J., Divvala S., Girshick R., Farhadi A. You Only Look Once: Unified, Real-Time Object Detection; Proceedings of the 2016 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Las Vegas, NV, USA. 27&#x2013;30 June 2016;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/CVPR.2016.91</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Z., Liu S., Wang F., Li Z., Sun J. Yolox: Exceeding yolo series in 2021. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2107.08430.2107.08430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2107.08430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long X., Deng K., Wang G., Zhang Y., Dang Q., Gao Y., Shen H., Ren J., Han S., Ding E., et al. PP-YOLO: An Effective and Efficient Implementation of Object Detector. arXiv. 2020 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2007.12099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2007.12099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C.Y., Bochkovskiy A., Liao H.Y.M. YOLOv7: Trainable bag-of-freebies sets new state-of-the-art for real-time object detectors. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2207.02696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2207.02696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W., Dragomir A., Erhn D., Szegedy C., Reed S., Fu C.-Y. SSD: Single Shot MultiBox Detector; Proceedings of the 14th European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV); Amsterdam, The Netherlands. 11&#x2013;14 October 2016; pp. 21&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., Li Y. Hybrid Insulator Fault Detection Based on Improved Faster R-CNN and U-net. Telev. Technol. 2021;45:6. doi: 10.16280/j.videoe.2021.05.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16280/j.videoe.2021.05.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y., Ma M., Li D. Lightweight Insulator Surface Defect Detection Based on Improved YOLOv5. Laser Optoelectron. Prog. 2023;60:2412007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Wu H., Zhao J. Study on Dynamic Differential Defect Detection Method for Glass Insulators. J. China Jiliang Univ. 2014;25:6. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1004-1540.2014.01.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1004-1540.2014.01.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J., Bai Y. Lightweight YOLOv4 for Insulator Defect Detection. Electron. Meas. Technol. 2022;45:123&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia X., Yu Y., Guo Y., Huang Y., Zhao B. Lightweight Detection Method for Self-Explosion Defects of Insulators in Aerial Photography. High Volt. Eng. 2023;49:294&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo S., Park J., Lee J.Y., Kweon I.S. CBAM: Convolutional Block Attention Module; Proceedings of the 15th European Conference; Munich, Germany. 8&#x2013;14 September 2018; Cham, Switzerland: Springer; 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-01234-2_1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang D., He S., Zhang G., Luo M., Guo H., Zhan J., Huang Z. Efficient Multi-Scale Attention Module with Cross-Spatial Learning. arXiv. 20232305.13563</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J., Shen L., Sun G. Squeeze-and-Excitation Networks; Proceedings of the 2018 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;23 June 2018; pp. 7132&#x2013;7141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Q., Zhou D., Feng J. Coordinate Attention for Efficient Mobile Network Design. arXiv. 2021 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2103.02907.2103.02907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2103.02907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Li L., Jiang H., Weng K., Geng Y., Li L., Ke Z., Li Q., Cheng M., Nie W., et al. YOLOv6:a single-stage object detection framework for industrial applications. arXiv. 20222209.02976</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Wu Y., Liu J., Sun Z., Xu H. Insulator faults detection in aerial images from high-voltage transmission lines based on deep learning model. Appl. Sci. 2021;11:4647. doi: 10.3390/app11104647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11104647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akdo&#x11f;an C., &#xd6;zer T., O&#x11f;uz Y. PP-YOLO: Deep learning based detection model to detect apple and cherry trees in orchard based on Histogram and Wavelet preprocessing techniques. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2025;232:110052. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2025.110052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2025.110052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S., Hu Z., Liu L., Zhang K., Cao Z. Object detection YOLO algorithms and their industrial applications: Overview and comparative analysis. Electronics. 2025;14:1104. doi: 10.3390/electronics14061104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14061104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Q., Su C., Tian Y., Zhao S., Yang K., Hao W., Feng X., Xie M. YOLO-SS: Optimizing YOLO for enhanced small object detection in remote sensing imagery. J. Supercomput. 2025;81:303. doi: 10.1007/s11227-024-06765-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-024-06765-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Chen L., Huang T., Yang A., Liu W. YOLO-edge: Real-time vehicle detection for edge devices. Clust. Comput. 2025;28:289. doi: 10.1007/s10586-024-04963-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10586-024-04963-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priadana A., Nguyen D.-L., Vo X.-T., Choi J., Ashraf R., Jo K. HFD-YOLO: Improved YOLO Network Using Efficient Attention Modules for Real-Time One-Stage Human Fall Detection. IEEE Access. 2025;13:41248&#x2013;41258. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3547360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3547360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y., Jiang X., Guo S., Xian R., Zong C., Yang Z., Han X. Influence of snow accretion on arc flashover gradient for various types of insulators. IET Gener. Transm. Distrib. 2020;14:2361&#x2013;2367. doi: 10.1049/iet-gtd.2020.0012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-gtd.2020.0012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Wu Y., Liu J., Han J. MTI-YOLO: A light-weight and real-time deep neural network for insulator detection in complex aerial images. Energies. 2021;14:1426. doi: 10.3390/en14051426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en14051426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Li D., Li D., Li X., Gao Q., Yu X. A lightweight insulator defect detection model based on drone images. Drones. 2024;8:431. doi: 10.3390/drones8090431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones8090431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>