<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41767533</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-858X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med (Lausanne)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An interpretable machine-learning model for predicting in-hospital mortality in patients with sepsis-associated acute kidney injury.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1756831</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1756831</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1756831</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmed.2026.1756831</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sepsis-associated acute kidney injury (S-AKI) is a severe complication in critically ill patients, linked to increased short-term mortality and chronic kidney disease. Existing prognostic tools like SOFA and SAPS II lack full representation of intricate clinical variable interactions. Machine learning (ML) models have potential in intensive care, but few validated and interpretable models focus on the in-hospital mortality rate of patients with S-AKI. This study aims to create and validate ML models for forecasting in-hospital mortality in S-AKI patients, identifying the most effective predictive model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We conducted a retrospective analysis of data from the MIMIC-IV 3.0 database to identify adult ICU patients who met theSepsis-3.0(Sepsis-3 was defined as suspected infection with an acute increase in SOFA score &#x2265;2) and KDIGO criteria for S-AKI. Additionally, a prospective cohort study from the General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University spanning 2023 to 2025 was included. Predictors recorded within 24 h of ICU admission included demographic information, comorbidities, vital signs, laboratory results, treatments, and severity scores. Variables with more than 20% missing data were excluded, and the remaining data were processed using interpolation. Feature selection was performed using the Boruta algorithm, and five machine learning models were trained (XGBoost, Random Forest, LightGBM, Decision tree, logistic regression). Model performance evaluation was based on metrics such as AUC, accuracy, sensitivity, specificity, F1 score, and clinical efficacy assessed through decision curve analysis. To enhance model interpretability, the SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) method was employed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among 16,800 patients with S-AKI, non-survivors(in-hospital mortality) exhibited older age, higher disease severity scores, more pronounced fluid overload, poorer renal function, metabolic acidosis, coagulation disorders, and heightened inflammatory responses. The XGBoost model demonstrated superior discriminative power (AUC 0.8799 ) in internal validation, surpassing other ML models, with exceptional sensitivity, accuracy, and F1 score. Decision curve analysis revealed that LightGBM offered the most significant net clinical benefit across various threshold probabilities. SHAP analysis consistently identified SAPS II score, AKI stage, oxygenation index, and key biochemical markers (e.g., serum sodium and blood urea nitrogen) as primary contributors to mortality risk, while the added value of basic demographic variables was limited. External validation confirmed that the XGBoost model has potential discrimination and robustness, highlighting the robustness and wide applicability of the machine learning-based prognostic framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study established an externally validated and interpretable ML model for riskstratification in S-AKI, enabling early identification of high-risk patients, personalized management strategies, and enhanced clinical outcomes in sepsis care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wang, Zhang, Ma, Yang, Chen and Zhou.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jian-Zhong</ForeName><Initials>JZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Clinical Medicine, Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Nan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Rong-Rong</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Clinical Medicine, Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Mei</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Clinical Medicine, Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yao-Geng</ForeName><Initials>YG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Jie</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med (Lausanne)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648047</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-858X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MIMIC-IV database</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute kidney injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sepsis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41767533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12946044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2026.1756831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Singer M, Deutschman CS, Seymour CW, Shankar-Hari M, Annane D, Bauer M, et al. The third international consensus definitions for Sepsis and septic shock (Sepsis-3). JAMA. (2016) 315:801&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1001/jama.2016.0287,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2016.0287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4968574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudd KE, Johnson SC, Agesa KM, Shackelford KA, Tsoi D, Kievlan DR, et al. Global, regional, and national sepsis incidence and mortality, 1990&#x2013;2017: analysis for the global burden of disease study. Lancet. (2020) 395:200&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32989-7,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32989-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6970225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31954465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Ji X, Wang AY, Wu PK, Liu Z, Dong L, et al. Epidemiology of Sepsis-associated acute kidney injury in Beijing, China: a descriptive analysis. Int J Gen Med. (2021) 14:5631&#x2013;49. doi: 10.2147/IJGM.S320768,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S320768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8449640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34548815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellomo R, Kellum JA, Ronco C, Wald R, Martensson J, Maiden M, et al. Acute kidney injury in sepsis. Intensive Care Med. (2017) 43:816&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1007/s00134-017-4755-7,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-017-4755-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28364303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbock A, Nadim MK, Pickkers P, Gomez H, Bellomo R, Joannidis M, et al. Sepsis-associated acute kidney injury: consensus report of the 28th acute disease quality initiative workgroup. Nat Rev Nephrol. (2023) 19:401&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1038/s41581-023-00683-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41581-023-00683-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36823168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Wang M, Jiang L, Du B, Zhu B, Xi X. The predictive value of the Oxford acute severity of illness score for clinical outcomes in patients with acute kidney injury. Ren Fail. (2022) 44:15&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1080/0886022x.2022.2027247,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0886022x.2022.2027247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8856098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35168501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mlodzinski E, Stone DJ, Celi LA. Machine learning for pulmonary and critical care medicine: a narrative review. Pulm Ther. (2020) 6:67&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1007/s41030-020-00110-z,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41030-020-00110-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7229087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32048244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue S, Li S, Huang X, Liu J, Hou X, Zhao Y, et al. Machine learning for the prediction of acute kidney injury in patients with sepsis. J Transl Med. (2022) 20:11&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1186/s12967-022-03364-0,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03364-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9101823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35562803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertsimas D, Wiberg H. Machine learning in oncology: methods, applications, and challenges. JCO Clin Cancer Inform. 4:885&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1200/cci.20.00072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/cci.20.00072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7608565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33058693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Feng J, He Z. Machine learning models for predicting acute kidney injury in patients with sepsis-associated acute respiratory distress syndrome. Shock. (2023) 59. doi: 10.1097/shk.0000000000002065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/shk.0000000000002065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36625493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) CKD Work Group . KDIGO 2024 clinical practice guideline for the evaluation and management of chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int. (2024) 105:S117&#x2013;314. doi: 10.1016/j.kint.2023.10.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kint.2023.10.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38490803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Wang X, Gao Y, Yu S, Zhao L, Zhang Z, et al. Efficacy and safety of corticosteroids for septic shock in immunocompromised patients: a cohort study from MIMIC. Am J Emerg Med. (2021) 42:121&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.ajem.2020.02.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2020.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32037125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang R, Huang T, Shen L, Feng A, Li L, Li S, et al. The use of antibiotics for ventilator-associated pneumonia in the MIMIC-IV database. Front Pharmacol. (2022) 13:869499. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.869499,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.869499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35770093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oweira H, Schmidt J, Mehrabi A, Kulaksiz H, Schneider P, Schob O, et al. Comparison of three prognostic models for predicting cancer-specific survival among patients with gastrointestinal stromal tumors. Future Oncol. (2018) 14:379&#x2013;89. doi: 10.2217/fon-2017-0450,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/fon-2017-0450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29318911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. Multiple imputation with multivariate imputation by chained equation (MICE) package. Ann Transl Med. (2016) 4:30. doi: 10.3978/j.issn.2305-5839.2015.12.63,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3978/j.issn.2305-5839.2015.12.63</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26889483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KJ, Simpson JA. Introduction to multiple imputation for dealing with missing data. Respirology. (2014) 19:162&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24372814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, White IR, Carlin JB, Spratt M, Royston P, Kenward MG, et al. Multiple imputation for missing data in epidemiological and clinical research: potential and pitfalls. BMJ. (2009) 338:b2393. doi: 10.1136/bmj.b2393,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.b2393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19564179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, et al. Scikit-learn: machine learning in python. J Mach Learn Res. (2011) 12:2825&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nohara Y, Matsumoto K, Soejima H, Nakashima N. Explanation of machine learning models using shapley additive expla- nation and application for real data in hospital. Comput Methods Prog Biomed. (2022) 214:106584. doi: 10.1016/j.cmpb.2021.106584,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2021.106584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34942412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahraman F, Y&#x131;lmaz AS, Ersoy &#x130;, Demir M, Orhan H. Predictive outcomes of APACHE II and expanded SAPS II mortality scoring systems in coronary care unit. Int J Cardiol. 371:427&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2022.09.065,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2022.09.065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36181949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao X, Chen C, Luo W, Zhou J, Tian J, Yang X, et al. Combining renal cell arrest and damage biomarkers to predict progressive AKI in patient with sepsis. BMC Nephrol. (2021) 22:415. doi: 10.1186/s12882-021-02611-8,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12882-021-02611-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34906098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyal S. Tuning Sodium Channel blockers to the near-atomic level. Epilepsy Curr. (2024) 24:123&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1177/15357597231225065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15357597231225065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11394411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39280048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu H, Wang L, Wang Y, Xie Y, Xie H, Hou X, et al. Sepsis-extracorporeal membrane oxygenation score in patients receiving extracorporeal membrane oxygenation support for sepsis. ASAIO J. (2025) 71:644&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1097/MAT.0000000000002409,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MAT.0000000000002409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12303247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40053063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramires MLV, Leite MFB, Lo DZY, da Silveira LB, Ferraz LJR, Pardini A, et al. Relation between red blood cell distribution width and acute kidney injury in patients with sepsis. Einstein (Sao Paulo). (2022) 20:eAO6828. doi: 10.31744/einstein_journal/2022AO6828,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31744/einstein_journal/2022AO6828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9071258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35544897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan P, Liu Y, Xie F, Duan Z, Li L, Gu H, et al. Significance of platelets in the early warning of new-onset AKI in the ICU by using supervise learning: a retrospective analysis. Ren Fail. (2025) 45:2194433. doi: 10.1080/0886022X.2023.2194433,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0886022X.2023.2194433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10075490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37013397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y, Zhang H, Yu X, Pan J, Xiao D, Miao H, et al. Decoding the epigenetic-immune nexus in hepatocellular carcinoma: a Mendelian randomization study reveals BTN3A2, S100A12 and TRIM27 as white blood cell regulators. BMC Cancer. (2025) 25:1282. doi: 10.1186/s12885-025-14693-w,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-025-14693-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12333189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40775620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pikula J, Heger T, Bandouchova H, Kovacova V, Nemcova M, Papezikova I, et al. Phagocyte activity reflects mammalian homeo- and hetero-thermic physiological states. BMC Vet Res. (2020) 16:232. doi: 10.1186/s12917-020-02450-z,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-020-02450-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7339577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berton MP, da Silva RP, Banchero G, Mour&#xe3;o GB, Ferraz JBS, Schenkel FS, et al. Genomic integration to identify molecular biomarkers associated with indicator traits of gastrointestinal nematode resistance in sheep. J Anim Breed Genet. (2022) 139:502&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1111/jbg.12682,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jbg.12682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng P, Zhang Y, Shi J, et al. Platelet and IL-33 count as biomarkers for lung function impairment: an 11-year follow-up study on populations exposed to hexavalent chromium. Environ Toxicol Pharmacol. 114:104660. doi: 10.1016/j.etap.2025.104660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.etap.2025.104660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39978742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;rensen NV, Frandsen BH, Orlovska-Waast S, Buus TB, &#xd8;dum N, Christensen RH, et al. Immune cell composition in unipolar depression: a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis. Mol Psychiatry. (2023) 28:391&#x2013;401. doi: 10.1038/s41380-022-01905-z,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-022-01905-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36517638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker N, Cheng W, Hindley GFL, O'Connell KS, Karthikeyan S, Holen B, et al. Genetic overlap between global cortical brain structure, C-reactive protein, and white blood cell counts. Biol Psychiatry. (2024) 95:62&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2023.06.008,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2023.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11684752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37348803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CH, Kayano M, Kusaba N. Pathogen and severity-dependent immune responses in bovine mastitis: highlight the dynamics of differential somatic cell count. J Vet Med Sci. (2024) 86:7&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1292/jvms.23-0261,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1292/jvms.23-0261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10849865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37981317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberger AL, Amaral LA, Glass L, Hausdorff JM, Ivanov PC, Mark RG, et al. PhysioBank, PhysioToolkit, and PhysioNet: components of a new research resource for complex physiologic signals. Circulation. (2000) 101:e215. doi: 10.1161/01.cir.101.23,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.101.23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10851218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>