<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41709223</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unveiling patriarchy: a systematic review of economic violence against women.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">988</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-026-26655-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Globally, women are subjected not only to physical and sexual violence but also to economic violence, an insidious and frequently overlooked form of abuse. Economic violence manifests through the control of women's income, restrictions on access to education or employment, and the denial of property ownership or inheritance rights. Beyond its financial implications, this form of violence embodies entrenched systems of power, control, and patriarchal inequality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This literature review examines how patriarchal structures sustain economic violence against women across diverse cultural and regional contexts. It synthesizes evidence from 42 peer-reviewed studies published between 2001 and 2024 to explore the forms of economic violence, how intersecting identities influence vulnerability, and which interventions show promise in disrupting this abuse.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive search across Scopus, Web of Science, PubMed, and Google Scholar. Eligible studies were screened using pre-defined inclusion criteria. A thematic synthesis approach was employed to analyze patterns and contextualize findings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Three recurrent forms of economic violence were identified: (1) direct financial control, such as withholding money or bank access (2), economic isolation, such as preventing work or education, and (3) structural exclusion, such as discriminatory inheritance laws. These practices were reinforced by cultural norms portraying men as providers and women as dependents. Women facing multiple forms of marginalization, such as migrants, ethnic minorities, and those with disabilities, experienced compounded risks. While some empowerment programs showed impact, those that failed to address gendered power dynamics often triggered backlash.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Economic violence is not incidental; it is systemic and rooted in patriarchal norms and institutions. Addressing it requires more than financial interventions; it demands transformative, intersectional approaches that center women's autonomy, justice, and dignity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hani</LastName><ForeName>Salam Bani</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0848-5615</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Faculty of Nursing, Irbid National University Irbid, Irbid, Jordan. banihani.salam@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obeisat</LastName><ForeName>Salwa Al</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Maternal-Child Health Nursing Department, Faculty of Nursing, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, 22110, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hweidi</LastName><ForeName>Lama I</ForeName><Initials>LI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Health, Irbid, 22110, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014754" MajorTopicYN="Y">Violence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000092822" MajorTopicYN="N">Family Structure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic justice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic violence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Financial abuse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gender-based violence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intersectionality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patriarchy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women's rights</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41709223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13019730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-026-26655-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-026-26655-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Krah&#xe9; B. Violence against women. Curr Opin Psychol. 2018;19:6&#x2013;10. 10.1016/j.copsyc.2017.03.017. Epub 2017 Mar 31.PMID:29279224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29279224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkan &#xd6;, &#xd6;zar &#x15e;, &#xdc;nver &#x15e;. Economic violence against women: A case in Turkey. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(3):e0248630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0248630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7959383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33720990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitchett NV. Overcoming barriers: the experiences of female survivors of domestic violence in Nigeria and the mechanisms which aided in leaving abusive relationships. Doctoral dissertation. University of Sussex; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong JS, Kim DH, Narvey C, Piquero AR, deLara E, Padilla YC. Understanding the link between family economic hardship and children&#x2019;s bullying behavior. Youth Soc. 2021;53(7):1066&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0044118X20932594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postmus JL, Hoge GL, Breckenridge J, Sharp-Jeffs N, Chung D. Economic abuse as an invisible form of domestic violence: A multicountry review. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2020;21(2):261&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524838018764160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29587598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poratibaha Roka. Patriarchy and Sexual Dynamics: Advancing Women&#x2019;s Liberation. 2025. Vol. 5, issue (01).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Chami R, Youssef MH. Challenging patriarchy: The transformation of women&#x2019;s roles. Impact of Patriarchy and Gender Stereotypes on Working Women: Exploring its Past, Present and Future. 2024:121&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan W, Wells M. It&#x2019;s deemed unmanly&#x2019;: men&#x2019;s experiences of intimate partner violence (IPV). J Forensic Psychiatr Psychol. 2016;27(3):404&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14789949.2015.1127986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monahan K. Intimate partner violence (IPV) and neurological outcomes: A review for practitioners. J Aggress Maltreatment Trauma. 2019;28(7):807&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10926771.2019.1628154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal B. A field of one&#x2019;s own: Gender and land rights in South Asia. South Asian Studies. Cambridge University Press; 1994.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duvvury N, Callan A, Carney P, Raghavendra S. Intimate partner violence: Economic costs and implications for growth and development.&#xa0;Details are complete. 2013.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulu E, Miedema S. Violence against women: globalizing the integrated ecological model. Violence against Women. 2015;21(12):1431&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077801215596244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4638316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26215287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarac E, Odabas D. Gender-based economic violence and the exploitation of women: A deep dive. World J Psychiatry. 2025;15(3):103725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v15.i3.103725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11886345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40109990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briones L. Empowering migrant women: why agency and rights. are not enough: Routledge; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas J, Harden A. Methods for the thematic synthesis of qualitative research in systematic reviews. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2008;8(1):45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-8-45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2478656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18616818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davila AL, Johnson L, Postmus JL. Examining the relationship between economic abuse and mental health among Latina intimate partner violence survivors in the united States. J Interpers Violence. 2021;36(1&#x2013;2):NP287&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260517731311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinert JI, Boehret I, Vasumati Satish R, Sharma S, Chatterji S. &#x2018;We don&#x2019;t get money in our own hands&#x2019;: evidence from focus group discussions on economic abuse against women in two states of India. BMJ Global Health. 2023;8:e012576. 10.1136/bmjgh-2023-012576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10565156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37798047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahu PR, Behera DK. Barriers to women&#x2019;s empowerment in india&#x2019;s informal sector: structural and socio-economic constraints. Discover Sustain. 2025;6(1):514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43621-025-01398-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler SR, Lenzi R, Badal SH, Nazneen S. Men&#x2019;s perspectives on women&#x2019;s empowerment and intimate partner violence in rural Bangladesh. Cult Health Sex. 2018;20(1):113&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13691058.2017.1332391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5718933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28594292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilgallen JA, Ishungisa AM, Charles P, Chizi TM, John A, Nicholaus I, et al. A snake with no teeth: urbanization shifts perceptions of men who support women&#x2019;s empowerment in Northwestern Tanzania. World Dev. 2026;199:107239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2025.107239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosimbei GK, Omolo JO, Rono GJ, Musyoka PK, Onono PA. Gendered Socioeconomic and Health Effects of COVID-19 in Informal Settlements in Kenya. 2022. https://publication.aercafricalibrary.org/handle/123456789/3462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabeer N. Gender equality, economic growth, and women&#x2019;s agency: the endless variety and monotonous similarity of patriarchal constraints. Fem Econ. 2016;22(1):295&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13545701.2015.1090009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schraiber LB, Latorre MRDO, Fran&#xe7;a I Jr, Segri NJ, d&#x2019;Oliveira AFPL. Validity of the WHO VAW study instrument for estimating gender-based violence against women. Rev Saude Publica. 2010;44:658&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0034-89102010000400009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20676557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan M, Knight L, Abramsky T, Muvhango L, Polzer Ngwato T, Mbobelatsi M, et al. Associations between women&#x2019;s economic and social empowerment and intimate partner violence: findings from a microfinance plus program in rural North West Province, South Africa. J Interpers Violence. 2021;36(15&#x2013;16):7747&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260519836952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8276343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30913954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellyer P. Intimate partner violence: intimate partner violence. London; Nature Publishing Group: 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFadden P, Ross J, Moriarty J, Mallett J, Schroder H, Ravalier J, et al. The role of coping in the wellbeing and work-related quality of life of UK health and social care workers during COVID-19. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(2):815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18020815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33477880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group WB. Global economic prospects, January 2022.&#xa0;World Bank Publication. World Bank; 2022.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group WB. Women, business and the law 2018. World Bank Publication. World Bank; 2018.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valera HGA, Yamano T, Puskur R, Veettil PC, Gupta I, Ricarte P, Mohan RR. Women's land title ownership and empowerment: evidence from India (No. 559). ADB economics working paper series. 2018.&#x200f;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posey BM. The Labor of Survival: Homicide Victims and the Black Women They Leave Behind. Homicide Studies. 2024;0(0). 10.1177/10887679241305356.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahangir R, Bulut M. Rejuvenating the practice of Mahr for Muslim women&#x2019;s financial empowerment through an interest-free savings-based finance model. J Islamic Acc Bus Res. 2025;16(3):506&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JIABR-11-2022-0298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirshekari A, Ghasemi R. The study of justice in determining women&#x2019;s rights in the family according to the Islamic legal system. J Shariah Law Res. 2019;4(2):201&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22452/jslr.vol4no2.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagneja S. Conceptualising the rights of Muslim women in context of Islamic personal law. Indian JL Just. 2019;10:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crenshaw KW. Mapping the margins: Intersectionality, identity politics, and violence against women of color. The public nature of private violence. Routledge; 2013. p.93&#x2013;118.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadambuka C, Namyalo PK, Raghunauth R, Arora N, Kouyoumdjian F, Essue BM. Precarious employment and gender-based violence against migrant women: A scoping review mapping the intersections. PLoS ONE. 2025;20(12):e0337690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0337690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12668559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41325405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Innes A, Bunce A, Manzur H, Lewis NV. Experiences of violence while in insecure migration status: a qualitative evidence synthesis. Globalization Health. 2024;20(1):83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12992-024-01085-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11585937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39580464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasil S. I came here, and it got worse day by day: examining the intersections between migrant precarity and family violence among women with insecure migration status in Australia. Violence against Women. 2024;30(10):2482&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10778012231159414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11292973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36913733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yalcinoz-Ucan B, Tastsoglou E, Dawson M. Tracing individual experiences to systemic challenges: the (re) production of GBV in migrant women&#x2019;s experiences in Canada. Front Sociol. 2025;10:1528525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsoc.2025.1528525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11915144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40103854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jewkes R, Fulu E, Tabassam Naved R, Chirwa E, Dunkle K, Haard&#xf6;rfer R, et al. Women&#x2019;s and men&#x2019;s reports of past-year prevalence of intimate partner violence and rape and women&#x2019;s risk factors for intimate partner violence: A multicountry cross-sectional study in Asia and the Pacific. PLoS Med. 2017;14(9):e1002381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1002381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5584751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28873087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heise L, Greene ME, Opper N, Stavropoulou M, Harper C, Nascimento M, et al. Gender inequality and restrictive gender norms: framing the challenges to health. Lancet. 2019;393(10189):2440&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30652-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31155275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter M. Effects of microcredit and other loans on female empowerment in bangladesh: the borrower&#x2019;s gender influences intra-household resource allocation. Agric Econ. 2016;47(2):235&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/agec.12225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj A, Johns NE, Bhan N, Silverman JG, Lundgren R. Effects of gender role beliefs on social connectivity and marital safety: findings from a cross-sectional study among married adolescent girls in India. J Adolesc Health. 2021;69(6):S65&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2021.07.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34809903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deere CD, Le&#xf3;n M. Who owns the land? Gender and land-titling programmes in Latin America. J Agrarian Change. 2001;1(3):440&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1471-0366.00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser CS. Tackling gender discriminatory inheritance law privately.&#xa0;Middle East and North Africa Region. World Bank; 2024.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuno KM, Desai M. Family, gender, and law in a globalizing middle East. and South Asia: Syracuse University; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubab I. 3 Politics around Women&#x2019;s Landed Inheritance in South Asia. South Asia from the Margins: Transformations in the Political Space. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christina Sarah Hauser, Legal Reform Versus Private Action: Experimental Evidence on Attitudes Toward Gender Equal Inheritance From Tunisia.&#xa0;J Afr Econ. 2025;34(5):541&#x2013;68. 10.1093/jae/ejaf004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede S, Van Harmelen A-L, Roman-Urrestarazu A. Wealth inequality and intimate partner violence: an individual and ecological level analysis across 20 countries. J Interpers Violence. 2022;37(17&#x2013;18):NP15568&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08862605211016337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ababsa M. Exclusion and norms: enforcing women&#x2019;s rights to property in Jordan. E. In: Al-Dahdah C, Corduneanu Huci G, Raballand, editors. EJ Sergenti, rules on paper, rules in practice: enforcing laws and policies in the middle East and North Africa direction in development. Washington, DC: World Bank Group; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain J, Jamil I. Equality in contention: exploring the debates of gender-equal inheritance rights in Bangladesh. Public Adm Policy. 2022;25(3):323&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamamra B. Unveiling hidden economic abuse: structural mechanisms of control and the erosion of women&#x2019;s financial independence. Journal of Family Studies. 2025. 1&#x2013;17. 10.1080/13229400.2025.2568017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messerschmidt JW, Bridges T. Legitimation as linchpin: on Raewyn connell&#x2019;s changing conceptualization of &#x2018;hegemonic masculinity&#x2019;. Int Rev Sociol. 2024;34(2):211&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03906701.2024.2388616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalky A, Quran TO, Abuhammad S, Al-Faraj HM, Bani Hani S, ALBashtawy M, et al. COVID-19 vaccine acceptance and associated factors among pregnant and lactating women attending maternity care clinics in refugee camps in Jordan. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(6):e0305314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0305314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11166341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38861556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>