<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41932960</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of Zn<sub>1-x</sub>Sn<sub>x</sub>O and Mg<sub>1-x</sub>Sn<sub>x</sub>O transparent conducting oxide thin films for perovskite solar cell applications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42690-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Zinc-doped tin oxide (ZTO) and magnesium-doped tin oxide (MTO) transparent conducting oxide (TCO) thin films were synthesized using the atomizer spray pyrolysis method and annealed at 450&#xa0;&#xb0;C for application as front electrodes in perovskite solar cells (PSCs). The precursor molar ratio was varied from 0.1:0.1 to 0.1:0.5 (Zn/Mg:Sn), resulting in film thicknesses ranging from 210 to 513&#xa0;nm for ZTO and 243 to 688&#xa0;nm for MTO after annealing. X-ray diffraction analysis confirmed improved crystallinity with increased crystallite size after annealing. Optical studies revealed high transmittance of&#x2009;~&#x2009;76-80% in the visible region. The optical bandgap decreased after annealing, from 3.85 to 3.67&#xa0;eV for ZTO and from 3.82 to 3.40&#xa0;eV for MTO. Hall effect measurements confirmed n-type conductivity with enhanced electrical performance at higher molar concentrations. The optimized MTO film exhibited a maximum carrier concentration of 2.78&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>20</sup>&#xa0;cm<sup>-3</sup>, mobility of 31.56&#xa0;cm<sup>2</sup>/V s, and low resistivity of 1.89&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>-4</sup>&#xa0;&#x3a9;&#xa0;cm. Photovoltaic devices fabricated using annealed ZTO and MTO substrates achieved power conversion efficiencies of 3.45% and 6.38%, respectively. The improved device performance of MTO-based PSCs is attributed to its higher conductivity and optical transparency, demonstrating its potential as an alternative cost-effective TCO material for solar cell applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiruthiga</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Science and Humanities (Physics), FOE, Karpagam Academy of Higher Education, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, 641 021, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>M Sathish</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Smart Energy Systems, Chennai Institute of Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600069, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, Tunghai University, Taichung City, 40704, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raguram</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Physical Chemistry and Solid-State Electrochemistry (LFES), Department of Materials Chemistry, Faculty of Chemistry and Biology, University of Santiago de Chile (USACH), Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murali</LastName><ForeName>Arun Prasad</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&amp;D Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ragumoorthy</LastName><ForeName>Chandini</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering and Biotechnology, National Taipei University of Technology, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Rakesh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Manipal University Jaipur, Jaipur, Rajasthan, 303007, India. kumar.rakesh@jaipur.manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giri</LastName><ForeName>Jayant</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Yeshwantrao Chavan College of Engineering, Nagpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Research and Development, Lovely Professional University, Phagwara, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research Impact and Outcome, Chitkara University Institute of Engineering and Technology, Chitkara University, Rajpura, Punjab, 140401, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammad</LastName><ForeName>Faruq</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Science, King Saud University, P.O. Box 2455, 11451, Riyadh, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soleiman</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Chemistry, College of Sciences and Engineering, Southern University, Baton Rouge, LA, 70813, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kadirov</LastName><ForeName>Islom</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Transport Systems, Urgench State University, 220100, Urgench, Uzbekistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrical and J&#x2013;V studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MgSnO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optical</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perovskite solar cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spray coating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TCO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ZnSnO</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41932960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42690-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42690-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yu, S. et al. Folding-insensitive, flexible transparent conductive electrodes based on copper nanowires. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells 231, 111323 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilatovskii, D. A. et al. Transparent conducting films based on carbon nanotubes: Rational design toward the theoretical limit. Adv. Sci. 9(24), 2201673 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun, J. S. et al. Inhibition of iodide ion migration in flexible perovskite solar cells using oxide&#x2013;metal&#x2013;oxide transparent electrode. Surf. Interfaces 27, 101546 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal, A. V. et al. Low-voltage, self-powered and broadband photodetector with ohmic, transparent and cost-effective AZO electrodes on vertical aligned MoS2 flakes. Surf. Interfaces 30, 101813 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, S. et al. Highly stable silver nanowire networks with tin oxide shells for freestanding transparent conductive nanomembranes through all&#x2010;solution processes. Chem. Eng. J. 446, 137481 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latif, H. et al. Effect of target morphology on morphological, optical and electrical properties of FTO thin film deposited by pulsed laser deposition for MAPbBr3 perovskite solar cell. Surf. Interfaces 24, 101117 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J. et al. High-temperature optical properties of indium tin oxide thin-films. Sci. Rep. 10(1), 12486 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong, H. et al. Roll-to-roll processed silver nanowire/silicon dioxide microsphere composite for high-accuracy flexible touch sensing application. Surf. Interfaces 30, 101976 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, S. et al. Degradable, ultra-flexible, transparent and conductive film made of assembling CuNWs on chitosan. Opt. Mater. 123, 111752 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. Y. Optimization of transparent amorphous oxide-metal-amorphous oxide multilayer with high figure of merit for high transmittance and low resistivity. Opt. Mater. 112, 110820 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, S. et al. Alternative transparent conducting electrode materials for flexible optoelectronic devices. Opto-Electron. Rev. 26(3), 223&#x2013;235 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L., Nam, K. &amp; Kwon, S. Effect of plasma nitriding of electroplated chromium coatings on the corrosion protection C45 mild steel. Surf. Coat. Technol. 202(2), 203&#x2013;207 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiruthiga Prabhu, G., Raguram, T. &amp; Rajni, K. S. Annealing effect of magnesium tin oxide thin films prepared by nebulizer spray pyrolysis technique for DSSC applications. IOP Conf. Ser.: Mater. Sci. Eng. 577(1), 012093 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiruthiga, G. et al. DSSCs: A facile and low-cost MgSnO<sub>3</sub>-based transparent conductive oxides via nebulized spray pyrolysis technique. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Electron. 32(18), 22780&#x2013;22791 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiruthiga, G. et al. Indium-free MgSnO3 transparent conductive oxide layer: Investigation on structural, optical and electrical properties and photovoltaic performance analysis. Appl. Nanosci. 13(5), 3421&#x2013;3434 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiruthiga, G. et al. SnO<sub>2</sub>: Investigation of optical, structural, and electrical properties of transparent conductive oxide thin films prepared by nebulized spray pyrolysis for photovoltaic applications. Inorg. Chem. Commun. 145, 109968 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altin, Y. et al. Solution-processed transparent conducting electrodes with graphene, silver nanowires and PEDOT:PSS as alternative to ITO. Surf. Coat. Technol. 302, 75&#x2013;81 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priyadharshni, L. S. &amp; Selvaraj, M. Polypyrrole sulfonate as a transparent conducting film for photovoltaic applications. Int. J. Polym. Mater. Polym. Biomater. 64(1), 47&#x2013;53 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D. et al. Cd2SnO4 transparent conductive oxide: A promising alternative candidate for highly efficient hybrid halide perovskite solar cells. RSC Adv. 7(14), 8295&#x2013;8302 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y. L. et al. Surface modification of ZnO nanocrystals. Appl. Surf. Sci. 253(12), 5473&#x2013;5479 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, S. et al. Enhanced conductivity and stability of Cu-embedded zinc tin oxide flexible transparent conductive thin films. Ceram. Int. 48(11), 15925&#x2013;15931 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. Review of ZnO transparent conducting oxides for solar applications. IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng. 423(1), 012170 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo, J. &amp; Yoo, H. Zinc&#x2013;Tin Oxide film as an earth-abundant material and its versatile applications to electronic and energy materials. Membranes https://doi.org/10.3390/membranes12050485 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. Visualized-experimental investigation on the energy storage performance of PCM infiltrated in the metal foam with varying pore densities. Energy 237, 121540 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, M. et al. Simulating the role of TCO materials, their surface texturing and band gap of amorphous silicon layers on the efficiency of amorphous silicon thin film solar cells. SILICON 9(1), 59&#x2013;68 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goje, A. A. et al. Transparent conductive oxides in flexible perovskite solar cells&#x2014;Material properties and device performance review. Sol. Energy 302, 113964 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#xed;ncipe, J. et al. Influence of the transparent conductive oxide type on the performance of inverted perovskite solar cells. ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 6(24), 12442&#x2013;12451 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, H. &amp; Srivastava, R. Solution-processed pristine metal oxides as electron-transporting materials for perovskite solar cells. Front. Electron. Mater. 3 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, A. M. et al. Synthesis of ZnO&#x2013;SnO2 nanocomposites: Impact of polyethylene glycol on morphological, luminescence and photocatalytic properties. Res. Chem. Intermed. 45(5), 3089&#x2013;3106 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ynineb, F. et al. Influence of Sn content on properties of ZnO:SnO<sub>2</sub> thin films deposited by ultrasonic spray pyrolysis. Mater. Sci. Semicond. Process. 16(6), 2021&#x2013;2027 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, P., Tang, M. &amp; Nino, J. C. In situ studies of ion irradiated inverse spinel compound magnesium stannate (Mg<sub>2</sub>SnO<sub>4</sub>). J. Nucl. Mater. 389(3), 410&#x2013;415 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visweswaran, S. et al. Characterization of MgO thin film prepared by spray pyrolysis technique using perfume atomizer. J. Mater. Sci.: Mater. Electron. 31(17), 14838&#x2013;14850 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barote, M. et al. Characterization and photoelectrochemical properties of chemical bath deposited n-PbS thin films. Digest J. Nanomater. Biostruct. 6 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthupriyal, V., Raj, M. &amp; Kumar, E. Synthesis and structural investigations of ZnO-SnO<sub>2</sub> nanocomposite by sol-gel method. 242&#x2013;244 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priyadharsini, C. et al. Effect of Mg doping on structural and optical properties of SnO<sub>2</sub> nanoparticles by chemical co-precipitation method. Int. J. Adv. Sci. Eng. 3, 428&#x2013;434 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premkumar, D. &amp; Sivakumar, G. Hydrothermally synthesized cubic magnesium stannate (Mg<sub>2</sub>SnO<sub>4</sub>) nanoparticles and its electrochemical performances. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Electron. 28, 1&#x2013;8 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raguram, T. &amp; Rajni, K. S. Synthesis and characterisation of Cu-doped TiO<sub>2</sub> nanoparticles for DSSC and photocatalytic applications. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 47(7), 4674&#x2013;4689 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharr, A. et al. Influence of pH on the structural, spectral, optical, morphological and photocatalytic properties of ZrO<sub>2</sub> nanoparticles synthesized by sol&#x2013;gel technique. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Electron. 31(18), 15718&#x2013;15730 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dangi, R. et al. Effect of oxygen vacancy on the crystallinity and optical band gap in tin oxide thin film. Energies 16, 2653. https://doi.org/10.3390/en16062653 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, Y. et al. The effect of annealing on optical transmittance and structure of ZLANI fluorozirconate glass thin films. Micron 140, 102977 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilican, S., &#xc7;a&#x11f;lar, Y. &amp; Caglar, M. Preparation and characterization of ZnO thin films deposited by sol-gel spin coating method. J. Optoelectron. Adv. Mater. 10, 2578&#x2013;2583 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atay, F. et al. Characterization of ZnO-SnO<sub>2</sub> oxide systems produced by ultrasonic spray pyrolysis. Sol. Energy 193, 666&#x2013;675 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T. &amp; Ichimura, M. Fabrication of transparent Mg(OH)<sub>2</sub> thin films by drop-dry deposition. Materials https://doi.org/10.3390/ma14040724 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhamodharan, P. et al. Preparation and characterization of spray deposited Sn-doped ZnO thin films onto ITO subtracts as photoanode in dye sensitized solar cell. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Electron. 2, 10&#x2013;28 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. Review of ZnO transparent conducting oxides for solar applications. IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng. 423, 012170 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadler, A. Transparent conducting oxides&#x2014;An up-to-date overview. Materials 5, 661&#x2013;683 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, B. &amp; Skariah, B. Spray deposited Mg-doped SnO<sub>2</sub> thin film LPG sensor: XPS and EDX analysis in relation to deposition temperature and doping. J. Alloys Compd. 625, 231&#x2013;240 (2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>