<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41567419</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2055-2076</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>What counts as care? Structural critique of digital health models.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20552076251411273</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20552076251411273</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20552076251411273</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20552076251411273</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In a world increasingly saturated with digital health technologies, the promise of empowerment through information has become almost axiomatic. Yet what if access does not equate to understanding, and what if the sleek interfaces and personalized nudges of today's tools merely simulate agency while displacing it? This presentation interrogates the epistemological and ethical limits of four dominant models underpinning digital health design: the information deficit model, the knowledge-attitude-practice (KAP) framework, health literacy strategies, and behavioral nudging. Despite their differences, each presumes a rational, autonomous user who simply needs the right data or design to act wisely. Drawing on critical public health literature and sociotechnical theory, we argue that these frameworks obscure the structural and social determinants of health (SDoH), such as time poverty, financial stress, and cultural tensions, that fundamentally constrain genuine agency. Rather than merely optimizing individual behavior, this commentary compels the field to confront fundamental questions of power: Who gets to define health? Who designs the algorithm? And who is excluded in the process? By centering these inquiries, the real frontier is not smarter apps, but fairer governance. The paper concludes that addressing the digital divide requires structural interventions, such as participatory oversight and redistributive design, ensuring that digital health systems are grounded in human understanding rather than just administrative efficiency.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7427-5427</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Community and Public Health, Faculty of Health &amp; Environmental Sciences, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Fuwen</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-1697-0914</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Social Sciences, Faculty of Arts and Education, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trafford</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7162-1053</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Community and Public Health, Faculty of Health &amp; Environmental Sciences, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Wuqi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Information, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conn</LastName><ForeName>Cath</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Community and Public Health, Faculty of Health &amp; Environmental Sciences, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101690863</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-2076</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health literacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">technology and governance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41567419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12816506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076251411273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20552076251411273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tiernan P, Costello E, Donlon E, et al. Information and media literacy in the age of AI: options for the future. Educ Sci 2023; 13: 906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai C, Chen Q, Wan T, et al. Literary runaway: increasingly more references cited per academic research article from 1980 to 2019. PLoS One 2021; 16: e0255849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8345841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larivi&#xe8;re V, Haustein S, Mongeon P. The oligopoly of academic publishers. PLoS One 2015; 10: e0127502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26061978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magee L. Computational scapegoats. Subjectivity 2025; 32: 67&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nature Editorial. AI firms must play fair when they use academic data in training. Nature 2024; 632: 953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39192111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem SM, Jan SS. Social media for health behavior change. J Nat Sci Med 2025; 8: 41&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werder O. Hashtag stay healthy: digital media for health communication. In: Werder O. (ed.) Transformational health communication. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collyer FM, Willis KF, Lewis S. Gatekeepers in the healthcare sector: knowledge and Bourdieu&#x2019;s concept of field. Soc Sci Med 2017; 186: 96&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28603078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulliford M. Access to healthcare. In: Gulliford M, Jessop E. (eds) Healthcare public health: Improving health services through population science. Oxford Univ Press, 2020, pp.69&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claridge JA, Fabian TC. History and development of evidence-based medicine. World J Surg 2005; 29: 547&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15827845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D. History of disease. London: Routledge, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt NR, Garcia Rojo E, Gauhar V, et al. The intersection of artificial intelligence and social media in shaping the new digital health frontier: powers and perils. Eur Urol 2024; 85: 183&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38092613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong JJ, Tucker JD. Digital technology and self-care in sexual health. Sex Health 2024; 21: SH24174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39270060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masrek MN, Baharuddin MF, Altaf A. Misinformation and information overload. Rec Libr J 2024; 10: 212&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento IJ, Pizarro AB, Almeida JM, et al. Infodemics and health misinformation. Bull World Health Organ 2022; 100: 544&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9421549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36062247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M, Pei Y. Linking social media overload to health misinformation dissemination: an investigation of the underlying mechanisms. SSRN. 2022. Available from: https://ssrn.com/abstract=4046798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokarski FV. Digital health equity for older populations. Lancet Digit Health 2023; 5: e395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37391262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riza E, et al. IT-based algorithm for migrant/refugee health promotion. Healthcare 2021; 9: 1284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersson L, Johansson S, Demmelmaier I, et al. Disability digital divide: survey of accessibility of eHealth services as perceived by people with and without impairment. BMC Public Health 2023; 23: 181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9880913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36707791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuford J. Contribution of artificial intelligence in improving accessibility for individuals with disabilities. J Knowl Learn Sci Technol 2023; 2: 421&#x2013;433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekbolatova M, Mayer J, Ong CW, et al. Transformative potential of AI in healthcare: definitions, applications, and navigating the ethical landscape and public perspectives. Healthcare 2024; 12: 125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10815906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38255014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal J, Cort&#xe9;s Jaimes D, et al. Reimagining healthcare: unleashing AI in medicine. Cureus 2023; 15: e44658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10549955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37799217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maleki Varnosfaderani S, Forouzanfar M. Role of AI in hospitals. Bioengineering 2024; 11: 337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11047988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38671759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lustria MLA, Smith SA, Hinnant CC. Exploring digital divides. Health Informatics J 2011; 17: 224&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21937464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mubarak F, Suomi R. Elderly forgotten? Digital exclusion in the information age and the rising grey digital divide. Inquiry 2022; 59: 469580221096272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9052810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35471138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abernethy A, Adams L, Barrett M, et al. The promise of digital health: then, now, and the future. NAM Perspect 2022: 10.31478/202206e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9499383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36177208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darioshi R, Lahav E. The impact of technology on the human decision-making process. Hum Behav Emerg Technol 2021; 3: 391&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charalambous A. Challenges and future directions: from panacea to realisation. In: Charalambous A. (ed.) Developing and utilizing digital technology in healthcare for assessment and monitoring. Cham: Springer, 2020, pp.143&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JJ, Boutet P, Serafini G, et al. Evaluation of health technology solutions. In: A Sixsmith, Sixsmith, J, Mihailidis, A . et al. (ed.) Knowledge, Innovation, and Impact. Cham: Springer, 2021, pp.251&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capraro V, Lentsch A, Acemoglu D, et al. The impact of generative artificial intelligence on socioeconomic inequalities and policy making. PNAS Nexus 2024; 3: 191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11165650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38864006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choolayil AC, Paranthaman S, Kuttiatt VS. Accessing medical care in the era of the digital revolution: arguing the case for the &#x201c;digitally marginalised&#x201d;. Front Digit Health 2024; 6: 1468633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11532061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39498099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grzybowski A, Jin K, Wu H. Challenges of artificial intelligence in medicine and dermatology. Clin Dermatol 2024; 42: 210&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38184124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed SA, Masters RM. Disparities in healthcare and digital divide. Curr Psychiatry Rep 2021; 23: 61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8300069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34297202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferryman K. Framing inequity in health technology: the digital divide, data bias, and racialization. Brooklyn, NY: Just Tech Social Science Research Council, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupton D. The quantified self. Cambridge: Polity Press, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz HA, Madani A. Evolution of the web and its uses in healthcare. Clin Lab Sci 2015; 28: 245&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko H. In science communication, why does the idea of a public deficit return? Public Underst Sci 2016; 25: 427&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27117770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zheng H, Huang CYH. Information-response model. Sci Commun 2023; 45: 724&#x2013;750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal NK. Cultural factors, social structures, and social determinants of health: the need for clarity in assessing psychopathology. Harv Rev Psychiatry 2025; 33: 54&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39787460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greyson DL, Johnson JL. The role of information in health behavior: a scoping study and discussion of major public health models. J Assoc Inf Sci Technol 2016; 67: 2831&#x2013;2844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massaro DW. Capacity limitations in auditory information processing. In: Dornic S. (ed.) Attention and performance VI: Proceedings of the Sixth International Symposium on Attention and Performance, Stockholm, Sweden, July 28&#x2013;August 1, 1975. London: Routledge, 2022, pp.213&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlov OV, Plice RK, Melville NP. A communication model with limited information-processing capacity. Syst Dyn Rev 2008; 24: 377&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo YF, Chen LC, Yang SC, et al. KAP toward COVID-19 in Taiwan. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022; 19: 2784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35270491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesaraki M, Akbarizadeh M, Ahmadidarrehsima S, et al. Knowledge, attitude, practice and clinical recommendations of healthcare workers toward COVID-19: a systematic review. Rev Environ Health 2021; 36: 345&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34469639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Kang BA, You M. KAP toward COVID-19 in South Korea. BMC Public Health 2021; 21: 295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnuaimi A, Abbas S, Zainel A, et al. Cultural and region-specific adaptation of KAP tool to capture healthy lifestyle within primary care settings. PLoS One 2024; 19: e0312852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11658580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39700224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization &amp; Stop TB Partnership. Advocacy, communication and social mobilization for TB control: a guide to KAP surveys. Geneva: WHO; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubel J, Chibanda D. The neglect of culture in global health research and practice. BMJ Glob Health 2022; 7: e009914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robeyns I. Wellbeing, freedom and social justice. Open Book Publishers, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huhta AM, Hirvonen N, Huotari ML. Health literacy in web-based health information environments. J Med Internet Res 2018; 20: e10273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30567690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Health literacy. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neter E, Brainin E, Baron-Epel O. Group differences in health literacy and eHealth literacy. Health Psychol Behav Med 2021; 9: 480&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8158255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34104571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman CD, Skinner HA. eHealth literacy. J Med Internet Res 2006; 8: e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1794004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17213046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K, Shin S, Kim S, et al. Relation between eHealth literacy and health-related behaviors: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res 2023; 25: e40778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9926349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36716080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkman ND, Sheridan SL, Donahue KE, et al. Health literacy interventions and outcomes: an updated systematic review. Evidence Report/Technology Assessment No. 199. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, 2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4781058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23126607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutbeam D. Health literacy as a public health goal. Health Promot Int 2000; 15: 259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40665800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sentell T, Pitt R, Buchthal OV. Health literacy in a social context. Health Lit Res Pract 2017; 1: e41&#x2013;e70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6607851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31294251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agner J, Bau KE, Bruland D. An introduction to health literacy and social contexts with recommendations for health professionals and researchers. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2024; 21: 240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10888032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38397728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch R, Steffen MT, Wetzel AJ, et al. Laypersons&#x2019; experiences with a symptom checker app. JMIR Form Res 2025; 9: e60647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11971579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40117573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;rensen K, et al. Health literacy definitions and models. BMC Public Health 2012; 12: 80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3292515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22276600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemian A, Hoseinzadeh M, Rad SAB, et al. Nudging oral habits. Front Public Health 2023; 11: 1243246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10739307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38145077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vande VF, Overgaard HJ, Bastien S. Nudge strategies for prevention of NTDs. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 2021; 15: e0009239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8584752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34723983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matjasko JL, Cawley JH, Baker-Goering MM, et al. Behavioral economics in public health policy. Am J Prev Med 2016; 50: S13&#x2013;S19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4871624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27102853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlaev I, King D, Dolan P, et al. Theory and practice of nudging. Public Adm Rev 2016; 76: 550&#x2013;561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MS, et al. Smartphones vs wearables after hospital discharge. JAMA Netw Open 2020; 3: e1920677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12543400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Willoughby JF. Do fitness apps need text reminders? J Health Commun 2018; 23: 379&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29601270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mols F, Haslam SA, Jetten J, et al. Why a nudge is not enough. Eur J Polit Res 2015; 54: 81&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loewenstein G, Chater N. Putting nudges in perspective. Behav Public Policy 2017; 1: 26&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver A. From nudging to budging. J Soc Policy 2013; 42: 685&#x2013;700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milne-Ives M, Homer SR, Andrade J, et al. Behavior change techniques and engagement with mHealth apps. Front Psychol 2023; 14: 1227443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10545861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37794916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidman P, Curtis R, Watson A, et al. When and why adults abandon lifestyle and mental health mobile apps: scoping review. J Med Internet Res 2024; 26: e56897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11694054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39693620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brickwood KJ, Watson G, O&#x2019;Brien J, et al. Consumer-based wearable activity trackers increase physical activity participation: systematic review and meta-analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth 2019; 7: e11819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6484266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30977740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmot M. Fair society, healthy lives: the Marmot review. London: University College London, Institute of Health Equity; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elers P, Dutta MJ, Elers S. Culturally centring digital inclusion and marginality: a case study in Aotearoa New Zealand. New Media Soc 2022; 24: 311&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson G, Cook J, Crossland N, et al. Inequities and discrimination in maternity services. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth 2022; 22: 958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9773462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36550440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollimon LA, Taylor KV, Fiegenbaum R, et al. Redefining and solving the digital divide and exclusion to improve healthcare: going beyond access to include availability, adequacy, acceptability, and affordability. Front Digit Health 2025; 7: 1508686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12052546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40330871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Lawrence K, Schoenthaler AM, et al. A framework for digital health equity. NPJ Digit Med 2022; 5: 119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9387425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35982146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veinot TC, Mitchell H, Ancker JS. Good intentions are not enough: how informatics interventions can worsen inequality. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2018; 25: 1080&#x2013;1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29788380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cresswell K, Sheikh A. Organizational issues in the implementation and adoption of health information technology innovations: an interpretative review. Int J Med Inform 2013; 82: e73&#x2013;e86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23146626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Wherton J, Papoutsi C, et al. Beyond adoption: a new framework for theorizing and evaluating nonadoption, abandonment, and challenges to the scale-up, spread, and sustainability of health and care technologies. J Med Internet Res 2017; 19: e367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5688245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29092808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domecq JP, Prutsky G, Elraiyah T, et al. Patient engagement in research: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res 2014; 14: 89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3938901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>