<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41806503</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-6283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>384</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Forensic science international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Forensic Sci Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A forensic investigation and simulation-based analysis of a chemical plant explosion accident.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>112898</StartPage><MedlinePgn>112898</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.forsciint.2026.112898</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0379-0738(26)00085-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study applies a forensic-science-based approach combined with three-dimensional CFD simulations to reconstruct a large-scale explosion at a chemical plant and to evaluate the plausibility of candidate accident scenarios. A joint on-site investigation and document review were first used to reconstruct a baseline scenario for butane leakage, vapor cloud formation, and ignition. FLACS simulations were then conducted to examine whether a range of assumed leak volumes could reproduce the observed damage pattern, with particular emphasis on overpressure at a reference building located 93&#x202f;m from the explosion center. The National Disaster Management Research Institute (NDMI) led the investigation, which included on-site inspections and document analysis. Based on physical evidence such as major structural damage, fragment distribution, and gas detector activation data, the location and dispersion range of the leak were estimated. A 3D simulation of the incident process was performed using the FLACS software. Alongside theoretical leak estimations, a reverse-engineering simulation approach considering actual damage patterns confirmed the possibility of a butane release exceeding 11,000&#x202f;kg. The simulation results quantitatively matched the measured damage radius and verified that the calculated overpressure levels met established damage thresholds. This study scientifically reconstructed the accident scenario using quantitative simulation methods, demonstrating the effectiveness and applicability of forensic-based disaster investigations. The proposed methodology may serve as foundational data not only for identifying the root causes of disasters but also for informing prevention policies, institutional reforms, and legal liability assessments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Kyung-Su</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Disaster Scientific Investigation division, National Disaster Management Research Institute(NDMI), Ministry of the Interior and Safety, Republic of Korea. Electronic address: 39lks@korea.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>An</LastName><ForeName>Su-Bin</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Disaster Scientific Investigation division, National Disaster Management Research Institute(NDMI), Ministry of the Interior and Safety, Republic of Korea. Electronic address: sb9545@korea.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>Won-Kyu</ForeName><Initials>WK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Disaster Scientific Investigation division, National Disaster Management Research Institute(NDMI), Ministry of the Interior and Safety, Republic of Korea. Electronic address: ohwjo1@korea.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Ireland</Country><MedlineTA>Forensic Sci Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7902034</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0379-0738</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Accident reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CFD simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemical accident</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FLACS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Forensic investigation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vapor cloud explosion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors are affiliated with the National Disaster Management Research Institute, Ministry of the Interior and Safety, Republic of Korea. The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41806503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.forsciint.2026.112898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0379-0738(26)00085-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>