<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41431026</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>51</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Global burden and trends of severe chest injuries from 1990 to 2021 and projections to 2045.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e46393</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e46393</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e46393</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000046393</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Severe chest injuries pose a substantial threat to human life and health, potentially leading to disability and mortality. However, comprehensive descriptions regarding the global epidemiology of this injury are rare. The incidence, prevalence and years lived with disability related to severe chest injuries were obtained from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. The age-standardized rate and estimated annual percentage change were subsequently calculated. Health disparities associated with severe chest injuries were illustrated utilizing the slope index of inequality and concentration index. Future disease trends over the next 25 years were projected using the Autoregressive Integrated Moving Average Model. Globally, the incidence of new cases of severe chest injuries have increased; however, the incidence rate has exhibited a downward trend across most countries and regions. YLD demonstrate similar patterns. The prevalence of severe chest injuries is highest in regions with a high Socio-demographic Index, particularly among individuals aged over 70, who exhibit the highest incidence rate across all age categories. The primary causes of severe chest injuries include falls, interpersonal violence, exposure to mechanical forces, and transportation injuries. Health inequality related to severe chest injuries has markedly reduced, with developed countries exhibiting a stronger potential to further reduce the disease burden associated with severe chest injuries. Despite a notable reduction in the global disease burden of severe chest injuries, disparities in health outcomes persist between countries and territories. These findings highlight the critical need for targeted public health interventions, including fall prevention programs in aging high-SDI region populations and enhanced trauma care infrastructure in conflict-affected low-SDI regions, to mitigate the burden of severe chest injuries globally.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Qingchun</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Chongqing University Cancer Hospital, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yuequan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Chenglu</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhiqiang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-3303-4197</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023SQKWLH020</GrantID><Agency>the Shapingba District Science and Health Joint Medical Research Project in Chongqing</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013898" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thoracic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014943" MajorTopicYN="N">Global Health</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071219" MajorTopicYN="N">Global Burden of Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="N">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005544" MajorTopicYN="N">Forecasting</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">global burden of disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevalence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">severe chest injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">years lived with disability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41431026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12727255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000046393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202512190-00066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adal O, Tareke AA, Bogale EK, et al. Mortality of traumatic chest injury and its predictors across Sub-Saharan Africa: systematic review and meta-analysis, 2024. BMC Emerg Med. 2024;24:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10900610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freixinet Gilart J, Ram&#xed;rez Gil ME, Gallardo Valera G, Moreno Casado P. Chest trauma. Arch Bronconeumol. 2011;47(Suppl 3):9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21640287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodhia JV, Eyre L, Smith M, Toth L, Troxler M, Milton RS. Management of thoracic trauma. Anaesthesia. 2023;78:225&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36572548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caragounis EC, Xiao Y, Granhed H. Mechanism of injury, injury patterns and associated injuries in patients operated for chest wall trauma. Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2021;47:929&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8319693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30953111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein AL, Machlouf Y, Moshe D, et al. The differences in injury patterns and outcomes of thoracic trauma between rural and urban level two trauma centers in a single country. Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2025;51:56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39856343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Huang G, Li T, et al. Insights into epidemiological trends of severe chest injuries: an analysis of age, period, and cohort from 1990 to 2019 using the Global Burden of Disease study 2019. Scand J Trauma Resusc Emerg Med. 2024;32:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11403847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39285499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray CJL; GBD 2021 Collaborators. Findings from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet. 2024;403:2259&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38762327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Risk Factors Collaborators. Global burden and strength of evidence for 88 risk factors in 204 countries and 811 subnational locations, 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet. 2024;403:2162&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11120204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38762324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Diseases and Injuries Collaborators. Global incidence, prevalence, years lived with disability (YLDs), disability-adjusted life-years (DALYs), and healthy life expectancy (HALE) for 371 diseases and injuries in 204 countries and territories and 811 subnational locations, 1990-2021: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet. 2024;403:2133&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11122111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38642570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens GA, Alkema L, Black RE, et al. ; (The GATHER Working Group). Guidelines for accurate and transparent health estimates reporting: the GATHER statement. Lancet. 2016;388:e19&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27371184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng W, Zhao L, Chen C, et al. National burden and risk factors of diabetes mellitus in China from 1990 to 2021: results from the global burden of disease study 2021. J Diabetes. 2024;16:e70012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11457207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39373380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Jiang Y, Yuan H, et al. The trends in incidence of primary liver cancer caused by specific etiologies: results from the global burden of disease study 2016 and implications for liver cancer prevention. J Hepatol. 2019;70:674&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30543829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cen J, Wang Q, Cheng L, Gao Q, Wang H, Sun F. Global, regional, and national burden and trends of migraine among women of childbearing age from 1990 to 2021: insights from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. J Headache Pain. 2024;25:96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11157953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38844846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang X, Lyu Y, Li J, Li Y, Chi C. Global, regional, and national burden of preterm birth, 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. EClinicalMedicine. 2024;76:102840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11462015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39386159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Causes of Death Collaborators. Global burden of 288 causes of death and life expectancy decomposition in 204 countries and territories and 811 subnational locations, 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet. 2024;403:2100&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11126520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38582094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H, Zhao Z, Deng Y, et al. The global, regional, and national early-onset colorectal cancer burden and trends from 1990 to 2019: results from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. BMC Public Health. 2022;22:1896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9555189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36221047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Z, Han J, An J, et al. The global, regional, and national patterns of change in the burden of congenital birth defects, 1990&#x2013;2021: an analysis of the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021 and forecast to 2040. EClinicalMedicine. 2024;77:102873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11474384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Handbook on health inequality monitoring: with a special focus on low-and middle-income countries.  https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241548632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Xia F, Chen M, et al. Disease burden and attributable risk factors of neonatal disorders and their specific causes in China from 1990 to 2019 and its prediction to 2024. BMC Public Health. 2023;23:122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36650483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M, Tang C, Shen Y, Zhang Y, Bao L. Analysis of the burden of intracerebral hemorrhage in the Asian population aged 45 and older and ARIMA model prediction trends: a systematic study based on the GBD 2021. Front Neurol. 2025;16:1526524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11869383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40027166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetzl EJ, Feeley B. Musculoskeletal disorders of the elderly. Am J Med. 2025;138:1197&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40228599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Simone B, Chouillard E, Podda M, et al. The 2023 WSES guidelines on the management of trauma in elderly and frail patients. World J Emerg Surg. 2024;19:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11140935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38816766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barq RM, Hung CS, Prather C, Lypson ML, Kartiko S. The use of a primary care provider survey to implement a fall prevention program in an urban hospital system. Surgery. 2021;170:1255&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33875254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweet AAR, de Bruin IGJ, Peek J, et al. Epidemiology and outcomes of traumatic chest injuries in children: a nationwide study in the Netherlands. Eur J Pediatr. 2023;182:1887&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10167109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36807757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zd&#xfc;lger A. Thoracic trauma in children. Turk Gogus Kalp Damar Cerrahisi Derg. 2024;32(Suppl1):S21&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10995687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38584786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coary R, Skerritt C, Carey A, Rudd S, Shipway D. New horizons in rib fracture management in the older adult. Age Ageing. 2020;49:161&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31858117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen K, Doblhammer G, Rau R, Vaupel JW. Ageing populations: the challenges ahead. Lancet. 2009;374:1196&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2810516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19801098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baffsky R, Koshiba C, Muna EL, Maua RF, Ivers R, Peden AE. Assessing violence and injury prevention plans, strategies and indicators in eighteen Pacific Islands countries: an environmental scan. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2024;44:100985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10788529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38226330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baird MD, Madha ES, Arnaouti M, et al. ; IMPACT Scoping Review Group. Global assessment of military and civilian trauma systems integration: a scoping review. Int J Surg. 2024;110:3617&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11175771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38935828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mock C, Joshipura M, Goosen J, Lormand JD, Maier R. Strengthening trauma systems globally: the essential trauma care project. J Trauma. 2005;59:1243&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16385310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin RX, Zhang G, Lim MX, et al. Assessment of essential surgical and anaesthesia care capacity: a cross-sectional study in five Pacific Island Countries. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2023;39:100830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10362349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37484709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umo I, James K, Didilemu F, et al. The direct medical cost of trauma aetiologies and injuries in a resource limited setting of Papua New Guinea: a prospective cost of illness study. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2022;20:100379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8802040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35146466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haagsma JA, Graetz N, Bolliger I, et al. The global burden of injury: incidence, mortality, disability-adjusted life years and time trends from the global burden of disease study 2013. Inj Prev. 2016;22:3&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4752630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26635210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamadeh A, El-Shamy F, Billings J, Alyafei A. The experiences of people from Arab countries in coping with trauma resulting from war and conflict in the middle east: a systematic review and meta-synthesis of qualitative studies. Trauma Violence Abuse. 2024;25:1278&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10913323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokdad AH, Forouzanfar MH, Daoud F, et al. Health in times of uncertainty in the eastern Mediterranean region, 1990&#x2013;2013: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2013. Lancet Glob Health. 2016;4:e704&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6660972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27568068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurney JM, Graf V, Staudt AM, et al. Characterization of humanitarian trauma care by US military facilities during combat operations in Afghanistan and Iraq. Ann Surg. 2022;276:732&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35837945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habboush A, Ekzayez A, Gilmore B. A framework for community health worker optimisation in conflict settings: prerequisites and possibilities from Northwest Syria. BMJ Glob Health. 2023;8:e011837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10335591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37407227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambiar D, Razzak J, Afsana K, et al. Mental illness and injuries: emerging health challenges of urbanisation in South Asia. BMJ. 2017;357:j1126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Global status report on road safety 2018.  https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241565684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19652008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>