<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41507286</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment model for multivariable fatigue performance of EA4T axles containing defects : <sup>a</sup> School of mechanical Engineering, Chengdu University, Chengdu 610,106, China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4894</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4894</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4894</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34892-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study employed a combined experimental and theoretical approach to investigate the influence of foreign object damage (FOD) on the fatigue limit of surface-strengthened EA4T axles. FOD was introduced on surface-strengthened axle specimens to generate surface defects, and finite element analysis was subsequently performed to evaluate the stress fields in the damaged regions. Fatigue tests were conducted on prefabricated defective specimens to characterize their fatigue behavior. Based on test results, an improved backward statistical inference method was used to fit the fatigue P-S-N curves for each specimen group and derive corresponding fatigue limits. The fatigue limit of full-size damaged axles was estimated by extrapolating from small-scale test results, with due consideration of geometric scale effects on mechanical performance. Considering the stochastic distribution of impact defect depths, an exponential fitting was performed to establish the quantitative relationship between defect depth and full-size axle fatigue limit. Finally, a multivariate fatigue limit prediction model was developed for surface-strengthened full-size EA4T axles based on the El-Haddad formula framework. This model enables comprehensive assessment of fatigue performance under multi-parameter coupling conditions, providing a robust theoretical basis for safety evaluation and maintenance strategies of high-speed train axles subjected to foreign object impacts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Chengdu University, Chengdu, 610106, China. luoyan636@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Gang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Zichen Technology Co., Ltd., Chengdu, 611500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Chuanqi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Chengdu University, Chengdu, 610106, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Cunhai</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Aerospace Zhongtian Power Equipment Co., Ltd., Chengdu, 610100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Rail Transit Vehicle System, Southwest Jiaotong University, Chengdu, 610031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yongxu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Chengdu University, Chengdu, 610106, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52405147</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EA4T axle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Full-scale axle, fatigue limit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multivariate model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surface defect</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41507286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12873259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34892-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34892-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huo, Y. M. et al. Prediction of microstructure and ductile damage of a high-speed railway axle steel during cross wedge rolling. <i>J. Mater. Process Tech.</i><b>239</b>, 359&#x2013;369 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2016.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klinger, C. &amp; Bettge, D. Axle fracture of an ICE3 high speed train. <i>Eng. Fail Analy.</i><b>35</b>, 66&#x2013;81 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2012.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. C., Xu, Z. W., Kang, G. Z. &amp; He, W. F. Probabilistic fatigue assessment for high-speed railway axles due to foreign object damages. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>117</b>, 90&#x2013;100 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2018.08.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X. C., Liu, D. X., Zhang, X. H., Liu, C. S. &amp; Liu, D. Mechanical and corrosion fatigue behaviors of gradient structured 7B50-T7751 aluminum alloy processed via ultrasonic surface rolling. <i>J. Mater. Sci. Technol.</i><b>40</b>, 88&#x2013;98 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2019.08.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, W. D. et al. Improving the fretting and corrosion fatigue performance of 300M ultra-high strength steel using the ultrasonic surface rolling process. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>121</b>, 30&#x2013;38 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2018.11.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. S. et al. Improving fatigue performance of Ti-6Al-4V alloy via ultrasonic surface rolling process. <i>J. Mater. Sci. Technol.</i><b>35</b>(8), 1555&#x2013;1562 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2019.03.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spanrad, S. &amp; Tong, J. Characterization of foreign object damage (FOD) and early fatigue crack growth in laser shock peened Ti-6AL-4V aerofoil specimens. <i>Procedia Eng.</i><b>2</b>(1), 1751&#x2013;1759 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.proeng.2010.03.188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Infante, V. &amp; Freitas, M. Failure analysis of compressor blades of a helicopter engine. <i>Eng. Fail Anal.</i><b>104</b>, 67&#x2013;74 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2019.05.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R., Manda, P., Singh, S. &amp; Singh, A. K. Failure analysis of variable inlet guide vane and compressor rotor blade of helicopter engine. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>5</b>(2), 5124&#x2013;5130 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2017.12.093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, J. W. et al. Fatigue and damage tolerance assessment of induction hardened S38C axles under different foreign objects. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>149</b>, 106276 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2021.106276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, J. W. et al. Fatigue assessment of EA4T railway axles under artificial surface damage. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>146</b>, 106157 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2021.106157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitagawa H, Takahashi S. Application of fracture mechanics to very small cracks or the cracks in the early stage[C]. Proc 2nd Internationl Conference of Mechnical Behavior Materials, ASME, 1976: 627&#x2013;630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad, M. H. E., Smith, K. N. &amp; Topper, T. H. Fatigue crack propagation of short cracks. <i>J. Eng. Mater. Technol. Transac. ASME</i><b>101</b>(1), 42&#x2013;46 (1979).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.3443647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. C. et al. Collaborative crack initiation mechanism of 25CrMo4 alloy steels subjected to foreign object damages. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>225</b>, 106844 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2019.106844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, J. W. et al. Foreign object damage tolerance and fatigue analysis of induction hardened S38C axles. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>202</b>, 109488 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2021.109488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. N. et al. The effect of manufacturing defects on the fatigue life of selective laser melted Ti-6Al-4V structures. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>192</b>, 108708 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2020.108708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hffern T V. Probabilistic modeling and simulation of metal fatigue life prediction[D]. California : Naval Postgraduate School, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. X., Yang, B., Feng, M. F. &amp; Wang, H. Probabilistic fatigue <i>S-N</i> curves including the super-long life regime of a railway axle steel. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>31</b>(10), 1550&#x2013;1558 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2009.04.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, L. Y., Liu, J. Z., Wu, N. X. &amp; Qian, W. X. Backwards statistical inference method for <i>P-S-N</i> curve fitting with small-sample experiment data. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>63</b>, 62&#x2013;67 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2014.01.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C. H., Wu, S. C., Zhang, J. W., Xie, L. Y. &amp; Zhang, Y. H. Determination of the fatigue P-S-N curves&#x2014;A critical review and improved backward statistical inference method. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>139</b>, 105789 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2020.105789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, Y. et al. Effect of ultrasonic rolled material layer on the corrosion fatigue resistance of railway axle EA4T alloy steel. <i>Eng. Fail Anal.</i><b>157</b>, 107895 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. N. et al. Corrosion fatigue lifetime assessment of high-speed railway axle EA4T steel with artificial scratch. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>245</b>, 107588 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2021.107588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X. et al. Experimental characterization and numerical modeling on the external impacting of high-speed railway axle EA4T steel. <i>Eng. Fail Anal.</i><b>125</b>, 105449 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2021.105449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, R., Byrne, J., Zhao, T. &amp; Tong, J. Influence of foreign object damage on fatigue crack growth of gas turbine aerofoils under complex loading conditions. <i>Fatigue Fract. Eng. M</i><b>31</b>(5), 386&#x2013;397 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1460-2695.2008.01238.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. F., Wei, C., Chen, L. J. &amp; Li, P. F. Quantitative correlation between geometric parameters and stress concentration of corrosion pit. <i>Eng. Fail. Anal.</i><b>44</b>, 168&#x2013;178 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2014.05.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerbst, U. et al. Safe life and damage tolerance aspects of railway axles-A review. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech</i><b>98</b>, 214&#x2013;271 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2012.09.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. C., Liu, Y. X., Li, C. H., Kang, G. Z. &amp; Liang, S. L. On the fatigue performance and residual life of intercity railway axles with inside axle boxes. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>197</b>, 176&#x2013;191 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2018.04.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, H. W., Wang, Z. B., Lu, J. &amp; Lu, K. Fatigue behaviors of AISI 316L stainless steel with a gradient nanostructured surface layer. <i>Acta Mater.</i><b>87</b>, 150&#x2013;160 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2014.12.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, R. H., Zhang, Z. J., Zhang, P. &amp; Zhang, Z. F. Improved fatigue properties of ultrafine- grained copper under cyclic torsion loading. <i>Acta Mater.</i><b>61</b>(15), 5857&#x2013;5868 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2013.06.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naito, T., Ueda, H. &amp; Kikuchi, M. Fatigue behavior of carburized steel with internal oxides and nonmartensitic microstructure near the surface. <i>Metall. Trans. A</i><b>15</b>(7), 1431&#x2013;1436 (1984).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02648572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duquesnay, D. L. &amp; Underhill, P. R. Fatigue life scatter in 7xxx series aluminum alloys. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>32</b>(2), 398&#x2013;402 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2009.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, Y. et al. Corrosion fatigue behavior and life prediction of railway axle EA4T alloy steel with artificial indentation. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>296</b>, 109835 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2023.109835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahani, A. R., Shakeri, I. &amp; Rans, C. D. Fatigue crack growth of Al 5083&#x2013;H111 subjected to mixed mode loading. <i>J. Braz. Soc. Mech. Sci. Eng.</i><b>42</b>, 442 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40430-020-02527-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makino, T. et al. Overview of fatigue damage evaluation rule for railway axles in Japan and fatigue property of railway axle made of medium carbon steel. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>132</b>, 105361 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2019.105361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. C., Li, C. H., Luo, Y., Zhang, H. O. &amp; Kang, G. Z. A uniaxial tensile behavior based fatigue crack growth model. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>131</b>, 105324 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2019.105324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paris, P. C. &amp; Erdogan, F. A critical analysis of crack propagation laws. <i>J. Basic. Eng.</i><b>85</b>(4), 528&#x2013;533 (1963).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.3656900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donahue, R. J., Clark, H. M., Atanmo, P., Kumble, R. &amp; McEvily, A. J. Crack opening displacement and the rate of fatigue crack growth. <i>Int. J. Fract.</i><b>8</b>(2), 209&#x2013;219 (1972).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00703882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebir, T., Correia, J., Benguediab, M. &amp; Jesus, A. M. Numerical study of fatigue damage under random loading using Rainflow cycle counting. <i>Int. J. Struct. Integr.</i><b>12</b>(3), 408&#x2013;418 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJSI-04-2020-0036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari, M. Fatigue crack growth reliability analysis under random loading. <i>Int. J. Struct. Integr.</i><b>11</b>(2), 157&#x2013;168 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJSI-06-2019-0053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, Y. L., Pan, J., Hathaway, R. &amp; Barey, M. <i>Fatigue testing and analysis: theory and practice</i> (Elsevier Butterworth-Heinemann, Burlington, 2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. H., Wang, X. Y., Hong, C., Lu, Y. H. &amp; Shoji, T. Effect of scratch depth on high cycle fatigue behavior of alloy 690TT stream generator tube. <i>J. Nucl. Mater.</i><b>558</b>, 153400 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnucmat.2021.153400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. H. et al. Fatigue life prediction of nuclear reactor main bolt based on temperature effect and size effect. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>152</b>, 106443 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2021.106443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. H. et al. Effects of foreign object damage on high-cycle fatigue behavior of Inconel Alloy 690TT steam generator tubes. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>292</b>, 109660 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2023.109660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murakami, M. E. Effects of defects, inclusions and inhomogeneities on fatigue strength. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>16</b>, 163&#x2013;182 (1994).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0142-1123(94)90001-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. N. et al. A new approach to correlate the defect population with the fatigue life of selective laser melted Ti-6Al-4V alloy. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>136</b>, 105584 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2020.105584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maierhofer, J., G&#xe4;nser, H. P. &amp; Pippan, R. Modified Kitagawa-Takahashi diagram accounting for finite notch depths. <i>Int. J. Fatigue</i><b>70</b>, 503&#x2013;509 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfatigue.2014.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>