<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41374715</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>23</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Graph-Gated Relational Reasoning for Enhanced Coordination and Safety in Distributed Multi-Robot Systems: A Decentralized Reinforcement Learning Approach.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7335</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s25237335</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The autonomous coordination of multi-robot systems in complex, environments remains a fundamental challenge. Current Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning (MARL) methods often struggle to reason effectively about the dynamic, causal relationships between agents and their surroundings. To address this, we introduce the Graph-Gated Transformer (GGT), a novel neural architecture designed to inject explicit relational priors directly into the self-attention mechanism for multi-robot coordination. The core mechanism of the GGT involves dynamically constructing a Tactical Relational Graph that encodes high-priority relationships like collision risk and cooperative intent. This graph is then used to generate an explicit attention mask, compelling the Transformer to focus its reasoning exclusively on entities rather than engaging in brute-force pattern matching across all perceived objects. Integrated into a Centralized Training with Decentralized Execution (CTDE) framework with QMIX, our approach demonstrates substantial improvements in high-fidelity simulations. In complex scenarios with dynamic obstacles and sensor noise, our GGT-based system achieves 95.3% coverage area efficiency with only 0.4 collisions per episode, a stark contrast to the 60.3% coverage and 20.7 collisions of standard QMIX. Ablation studies confirm that this structured, gated attention mechanism-not merely the presence of attention-is the key to unlocking robust collective autonomy. This work establishes that explicitly constraining the Transformer's attention space with dynamic, domain-aware relational graphs is a powerful and effective architectural solution for engineering safe and intelligent multi-robot systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Tianshun</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Merchant Shipping Academy, Shanghai Maritime University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Yiping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Merchant Shipping Academy, Shanghai Maritime University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhiqian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Merchant Shipping Academy, Shanghai Maritime University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shuai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Mechanical Engineering, Shanghai Electric Power University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Zeqi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Merchant Shipping Academy, Shanghai Maritime University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering College, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shijie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering College, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Jingbo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering College, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 62303108</GrantID><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>H20230487</GrantID><Agency>the Shanghai Maritime University Research Fund "Development and Application of New Technologies for Intelligent Shipping and Safety Management of Shipping Companies"</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Unmanned Surface Vehicle (USV)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">collision avoidance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">contextual reasoning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cooperative control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maritime robotics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maritime safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-agent reinforcement learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-modal perception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transformer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41374715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12694673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25237335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s25237335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Sun Z., Wan J., Li H., Yang D., Li Y., Fu W., Yu Z., Sun J. Hybrid Path Planning Method for USV Based on Improved A-Star and DWA. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 2025;13:934. doi: 10.3390/jmse13050934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmse13050934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shem-Tov E., Sipper M., Elyasaf A. BERT Mutation: Deep Transformer Model for Masked Uniform Mutation in Genetic Programming. Mathematics. 2025;13:779. doi: 10.3390/math13050779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math13050779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Li L., Zhu L., Zhang Z., Guo Y. Leader-Following-Based Optimal Fault-Tolerant Consensus Control for Air&#x2013;Marine&#x2013;Submarine Heterogeneous Systems. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 2025;13:878. doi: 10.3390/jmse13050878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmse13050878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashid T., Samvelyan M., de Witt C.S., Farquhar G., Foerster J., Whiteson S. Monotonic Value Function Factorisation for Deep Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning. J. Mach. Learn. Res. 2020;21:1&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzini T., Murphy R. Differentiable Boustrophedon Paths That Enable Optimization Via Gradient Descent; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA); Yokohama, Japan. 13&#x2013;17 May 2024; pp. 8778&#x2013;8783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y., Zhang K., Peng M., Mao S. Multi-Task Offloading for Digital Twin-Enabled IoT Systems: A Deep Reinforcement Learning Approach. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2023;19:840&#x2013;850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z., Chen X., Li E., Zeng L., Luo K., Zhang J. Edge Intelligence: Paving the Last Mile of Artificial Intelligence With Edge Computing. Proc. IEEE. 2019;107:1738&#x2013;1762. doi: 10.1109/JPROC.2019.2918951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2019.2918951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fossen T.I. Handbook of Marine Craft Hydrodynamics and Motion Control. John Wiley &amp; Sons; Chichester, UK: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Zhang Z., Yang Y., Du Y. STAS: Spatial-Temporal Return Decomposition for Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning; Proceedings of the 38th Annual AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Vancouver, BC, Canada. 20&#x2013;27 February 2024; pp. 17337&#x2013;17345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao B., Li R., Wang F., Peng C., Wu J., Zhao Z., Zhang H. Stochastic Graph Neural Network-Based Value Decomposition for MARL in Internet of Vehicles. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2023;73:1582&#x2013;1596. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2023.3312574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2023.3312574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramar V., Dementiev K., Kabanov A. Optimal State Estimation in Underwater Vehicle Discrete-Continuous Measurements via Augmented Hybrid Kalman Filter. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 2025;13:933. doi: 10.3390/jmse13050933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmse13050933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijelic M., Gruber T., Mannan F., Kraus F., Ritter W., Dietmayer K., Heide F. Seeing Through Fog Without Seeing Fog: Deep Multi-Modal Sensor Fusion in Unseen Adverse Weather; Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Seattle, WA, USA. 13&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 7762&#x2013;7771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunehag P., Lever G., Gruslys A., Czarnecki W.M., Zambaldi V., Jaderberg M., Lanctot M., Sonnerat N., Leibo J.Z., Tuyls K., et al. Value-Decomposition Networks for Cooperative Multi-Agent Learning; Proceedings of the 17th International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS 2018); Stockholm, Sweden. July 10&#x2013;15 2018; pp. 2085&#x2013;2087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K., Kim D., Kang W.J., Hostallero D., Yi Y. QTRAN: Learning to Factorize with Transformation for Cooperative Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning; Proceedings of the 36th International Conference on Machine Learning; Long Beach, CA, USA. 10&#x2013;15 June 2019; pp. 5887&#x2013;5896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son K., Ahn S., Reyes R.D., Kim D., Kang W.J. QTRAN++: Improved Value Transformation for Cooperative Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning. arXiv. 20202006.12010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Z., Deng K., Zhang H., Zha Z., Jobaer S. Deep Reinforcement Learning-Based Multi-Agent System with Advanced Actor&#x2013;Critic Framework for Complex Environment. Mathematics. 2025;13:754. doi: 10.3390/math13050754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math13050754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu N., Li J., Xiong J. An Integrated Design of Course-Keeping Control and Extended State Observers for Nonlinear USVs with Disturbances. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 2025;13:967. doi: 10.3390/jmse13050967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmse13050967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Y., Song S., Huang B., Li J. Distributed Edge-Event Triggered Formation Control for Multiple Unmanned Surface Vessels with Connectivity Preservation; Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE 17th International Conference on Control &amp; Automation (ICCA); Hefei, China. 27&#x2013;30 June 2022; pp. 978&#x2013;983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina R., De Silva V., Hook J., Kondoz A. Residual Q-Networks for Value Function Factorizing in Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 2024;35:4559&#x2013;4571. doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2022.3183865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2022.3183865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35737605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memarian F., Goo W., Lioutikov R., Niekum S., Topcu U. Self-Supervised Online Reward Shaping in Sparse-Reward Environments; Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS); Prague, Czech Republic. 27 September&#x2013;1 October 2021; pp. 5621&#x2013;5628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgianni L., Adami D., Giordano S., Pagano M. Enhancing Reliability in Rural Networks Using a Software-Defined Wide Area Network. Computers. 2024;13:113. doi: 10.3390/computers13050113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/computers13050113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyomoto Y., Oshima T., Oishi K., Bando M., Ishii K. Constraint-Driven Multi-USV Coverage Path Generation for Aquatic Environmental Monitoring. IEEE Trans. Control Syst. Technol. 2023;31:2792&#x2013;2799. doi: 10.1109/TCST.2025.3572776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCST.2025.3572776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni J., Gu Y., Tang G. Cooperative Coverage Path Planning for Multi-Mobile Robots Based on Improved K-Means Clustering and Deep Reinforcement Learning. Electronics. 2024;13:944. doi: 10.3390/electronics13050944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics13050944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vries J.A., Moerland T.M., Plaat A. On Credit Assignment in Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2203.03292.2203.03292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2203.03292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Zhou W., Deng X. Optimization of Adaptive Observation Strategies for Multi-AUVs in Complex Marine Environments Using Deep Reinforcement Learning. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 2025;13:865. doi: 10.3390/jmse13050865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmse13050865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaswani A., Shazeer N., Parmar N., Uszkoreit J., Jones L., Gomez A.N., Kaiser &#x141;., Polosukhin I. Attention Is All You Need; Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems; Long Beach, CA, USA. 4&#x2013;9 December 2017; pp. 5998&#x2013;6008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke H., Wang H., Sun H. Multi-Agent Deep Reinforcement Learning-Based Partial Task Offloading and Resource Allocation in Edge Computing Environment. Electronics. 2022;11:2806. doi: 10.3390/electronics11152394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics11152394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S., Zhu F., Chang X., Liang X. UPDeT: Universal Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning via Policy Decoupling with Transformers; Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Learning Representations; Virtual Event. 3&#x2013;7 May 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y., Zhang Y., Zhou X., Wang Q., Song X., Wang S. MTGNet: Multi-Agent End-to-End Motion Trajectory Prediction with Multi-Modal Panoramic Dynamic Graph. Appl. Sci. 2025;15:5244. doi: 10.3390/app15105244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15105244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z., Shen Y., Xie Z., Liu Y. Research on Autonomous Underwater Vehicle Path Optimization Using a Field Theory-Guided A Algorithm. J. Mar. Sci. Eng. 2024;12:1015. doi: 10.3390/jmse12101815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jmse12101815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>