<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41821347</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2125</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of clinical pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prescribing skills course: Three years' experience and lessons learnt through India's massive open online course.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bcp.70506</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Studies highlighting the prevalence of inappropriate prescribing and preventable harm emphasize the need to enhance prescribing competencies. This paper describes distinctive features, launch and evaluation of massive open online course (MOOC) Prescribing Skills Course (PSC) designed for medical interns and registered medical practitioners (RMPs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">PSC development funded by Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR), guided by national and international experts, with content aligned with the national medical curriculum and inputs from stakeholders, included video lectures with case scenarios, demonstration videos, assignments (pre- and post-course MCQ tests, prescription analysis) and structured feedback. Hosted on Government of India's online learning platform, course infrastructure enabled data collection for evaluation and analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">PSC having 50 modules was conducted with interns' enrolment/completion 4327/1164 (26.9%), 4098/815 (19.9%), 665/ 129 (19.4%) in 2020, 2021, 2022 and RMPs 1984/557(28.1%), 448/138 (30.8%) in 2021, 2022, respectively. Enrolment was significantly lower in regions with weaker health indices (rate ratio 0.35 with 95% CI: 0.32-0.38; P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001; Poisson regression test). Participants rated course content, relevance, quality, assignment usefulness 'excellent' to 'very good'. RMPs demonstrated higher baseline scores and greater improvement (from 60% to 73.3% p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001 in cycle 3) compared to interns.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The PSC- MOOC is convenient, accessible with experiential learning for large numbers. Performance of RMPs may suggest practical relevance and applicability. Module-wise performance analysis and enrolment variation provided insights for future strategy. Limitations include inability to assess the impact on prescribing practices. PSC-MOOC represents a promising, scalable educational strategy. Our experience would be useful to other countries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lokesh</LastName><ForeName>Shanmugam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICMR-National Institute of Epidemiology, Chennai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabu</LastName><ForeName>Sowparnika Treasa</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Studies and Trials Unit, Division of Development Research, ICMR Headquarters, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ponnaiah</LastName><ForeName>Manickam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICMR-National Institute of Epidemiology, Chennai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatnagar</LastName><ForeName>Tarun</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICMR-National Institute of Epidemiology, Chennai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandy</LastName><ForeName>Sujith J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacology, CMC, Vellore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chatterjee</LastName><ForeName>Suparna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1156-5130</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept. of Pharmacology, Institute of Postgraduate Medical Education &amp; Research, Kolkata, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raveendran</LastName><ForeName>Ramasamy</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacology, JIPMER, Puducherry, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tripathi</LastName><ForeName>Santanu K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jagannath Gupta Institute of Medical Sciences &amp; Hospital, Budge, Kolkata, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Chetna</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacology, BJMC, Ahmedabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xavier</LastName><ForeName>Denis</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacology, St Johns Medical College, Bangalore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tripathi</LastName><ForeName>Chakra Dhar</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, GIMS, Greater Noida, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaul</LastName><ForeName>Rajni</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICMR Headquarters, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chatterjee</LastName><ForeName>Nabendu Sekhar</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Previous Head, Division of Discovery Research, ICMR Headquarters, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cherian</LastName><ForeName>Jerin Jose</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Studies and Trials Unit, Division of Development Research, ICMR Headquarters, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Global Public Health, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamboj</LastName><ForeName>Ved Prakash</ForeName><Initials>VP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chairperson of Technical Advisory Group, ICMR National Task Force on Rational Use of Medical Centres, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Yogendra Kumar</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AIIMS, Bhopal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rege</LastName><ForeName>Nirmala</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2860-3378</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Seth GS Medical college &amp; KEM Hospital, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kshirsagar</LastName><ForeName>Nilima</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9195-3143</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Former National Chair, Clinical Pharmacology ICMR, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Indian Council of Medical Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7503323</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0306-5251</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">competency&#x2010;based medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">continuing medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medication errors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescribing skills</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rational drug use</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41821347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bcp.70506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ferner RE, Aronson JK. Medication errors, worse than a crime. Lancet. 2000;355(9208):947&#x2010;948. doi:10.1016/s0140&#x2010;6736(00)99025&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarn DM, Heritage J, Paterniti DA, Hays RD, Kravitz RL, Wenger NS. Physician communication when prescribing new medications. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(17):1855&#x2010;1862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panagioti M, Khan K, Keers RN, et al. Prevalence, severity, and nature of preventable patient harm across medical care settings: systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. BMJ. 2019;366:l4185. doi:10.1136/bmj.l4185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leape LL, Brennan TA, Laird N, et al. The nature of adverse events in hospitalized patients. Results of the Harvard medical practice study II. N Engl J Med. 1991;324(6):377&#x2010;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Medical Commission. Competency based under graduate curriculum. https://www.nmc.org.in/information-desk/for-colleges/ug-curriculum/ Accessed December 3, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter G, Grills N. Medication misuse in India: a major public health issue in India. J Public Health (Oxf). 2016 Jun;38(2):e150&#x2010;e157. doi:10.1093/pubmed/fdv072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subbaraman R, Thomas BE, Kumar JV, et al. Understanding nonadherence to tuberculosis medications in India using urine drug metabolite testing: a cohort study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(6):ofab190. doi:10.1093/ofid/ofab190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udwadia ZF, Pinto LM, Uplekar MW. Tuberculosis management by private practitioners in Mumbai, India: has anything changed in two decades? PLoS ONE. 2010;5(8):e12023. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0012023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walia K, Madhumathi J, Veeraraghavan B, et al. Establishing antimicrobial resistance surveillance &amp; research network in India: journey so far. Indian J Med Res. 2019;149(2):164&#x2010;179. doi:10.4103/ijmr.IJMR_226_18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modi J, Shah S, Lalwani U, Mundhava S, Singh A. A retrospective study to analyze prescription pattern and cost of anti&#x2010;malarial drugs in indoor malaria patients at a tertiary care teaching hospital. J Res Med Dent Sci. 2016;4(2):146&#x2010;149. doi:10.5455/jrmds.20164214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas J, Pandey DC, Verma A, Kumar V. Management of acute diarrhea in children: is the treatment guidelines is really implemented? Int J Res Med Sci. 2018;6(2):539&#x2010;544. doi:10.18203/2320&#x2010;6012.ijrms20180294</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel KJ, Kedia MS, Bajpai D, Mehta SS, Kshirsagar NA, Gogtay NJ. Evaluation of the prevalence and economic burden of adverse drug reactions presenting to the medical emergency department of a tertiary referral Centre: a prospective study. BMC Clin Pharmacol. 2007;7:8. doi:10.1186/1472&#x2010;6904&#x2010;7&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxwell SRJ, Coleman JJ, Bollington L, Taylor C, Webb DJ. Prescribing safety assessment 2016: delivery of a national prescribing assessment to 7343 UK final&#x2010;year medical students. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2017;83(10):2249&#x2010;2258. doi:10.1111/bcp.13319</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kshirsagar NA, Kaul R, Kumar V. ICMR National Virtual Centre for clinical pharmacology with network of rational use of Medicines &amp; Product Development Centres. Indian J Med Res. 2021;154(5):665&#x2010;668. doi:10.4103/ijmr.IJMR_1857_19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhaj R, Banerjee A, Kshirsagar NA, et al. Use of drugs not listed in the National List of essential medicines: findings from a prescription analysis by the Indian Council of Medical Research&#x2010;rational use of medicines Centres network in tertiary care hospitals across India. Indian J Pharm. 2022;54(6):407&#x2010;416. doi:10.4103/ijp.ijp_878_21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chugh PK, Gupta P, Wasan H, et al. Prescription&#x2010;based cost analysis of medicines for cardiovascular risk factors at Indian Council of Medical Research&#x2010;rational use of medicine Centre hospitals of India. Indian J Pharm. 2024;56(2):97&#x2010;104. doi:10.4103/ijp.ijp_61_23</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi R, Medhi B, Prakash A, et al. Assessment of prescribing pattern of drugs and completeness of prescriptions as per the World Health Organization prescribing indicators in various Indian tertiary care centers: a multicentric study by rational use of medicines centers&#x2010;Indian Council of Medical Research network under National Virtual Centre Clinical Pharmacology activity. Indian J Pharm. 2022;54(5):321&#x2010;328. doi:10.4103/ijp.ijp_976_21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjalkar J, Jhaj R, Chandy SJ, et al. Usage pattern of fixed&#x2010;dose combinations at ICMR network of rational use of medicine centres across India: recommendations for policymakers and prescribers. J Assoc Physicians India. 2023;71(2):11&#x2010;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witheridge A, Ferns G, Scott&#x2010;Smith W. Revisiting miller's pyramid in medical education: the gap between traditional assessment and diagnostic reasoning. Int J Med Educ. 2019;10:191&#x2010;192. doi:10.5116/ijme.5d9b.0c37</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indian Pharmacopoeia Commission. Pharmacovigilance Programme of India (PvPI). Introduction and function. https://www.ipc.gov.in/PvPI/about.html. Accessed September 30, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NITI Aayog, World Bank, Ministry of Health and Family Welfare. Healthy States, Progressive India. Report on the Ranks of States and Union Territories. Health Index&#x2010;Round IV (2019&#x2013;2020) NITI Aayog, Government of India 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathur R (Ed). National ethical guidelines for biomedical and Health Research involving human participants. Director&#x2010;General, ICMR; 2017:36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragsdale JW, Berry A, Gibson JW, Herber&#x2010;Valdez CR, Germain LJ, Engle DL. Evaluating the effectiveness of undergraduate clinical education programs. Med Educ Online. 2020;25(1):1757883. doi:10.1080/10872981.2020.1757883</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W, Qin H, Vaughan B, Ng L. Educational interventions for medical students to improve pharmacological knowledge and prescribing skills: a scoping review. Perspect Med Educ. 2023;12(1):348&#x2010;360. doi:10.5334/pme.1006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhawiti NM. The influence of active learning on the development of learner capabilities in the college of applied medical sciences: mixed&#x2010;methods study. Adv Med Educ Pract. 2023;14:87&#x2010;99. doi:10.2147/AMEP.S392875</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah N, Gupta P, Singh T. Reflection: a tool for learning and assessment in competency&#x2010;based curriculum. Indian Pediatr. 2024;61(8):771&#x2010;777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salema NE, Clement N, Hysenagolli R, et al. The evaluation of an e&#x2010;learning prescribing course for general practice. Educ Prim Care. 2021 Jul;32(4):219&#x2010;225. doi:10.1080/14739879.2021.1874250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery, T, Barber, N, Ghaleb, M, Franklin, BD, Armstrong, S, Crowe, S et al Investigating the prevalence and causes of prescribing errors in general practice: the PRACtICe study (PRevalence and causes of prescrIbing errors in general practiCe). A report for the GMC. 2012. https://www.gmc-uk.org/about/what-we-do-and-why/data-and-research/research-and-insight-archive/investigating-the-prevalence-and-causes-of-prescribing-errors-in-general-practice. Accessed December 3, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rios J. Improving test&#x2010;taking effort in low&#x2010;stakes group&#x2010;based educational testing: a meta&#x2010;analysis of interventions. Appl Meas Educ. 2021;34(2):85&#x2010;106. doi:10.1080/08957347.2021.1890741</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>