<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41410766</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>122</Volume><Issue>51</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Heavy-tailed update distributions arise from information-driven self-organization in nonequilibrium learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2523012122</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2523012122</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2523012122</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2523012122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Like human decision-making under real-world constraints, artificial neural networks may balance free exploration in parameter space with task-relevant adaptation. In this study, we identify consistent signatures of criticality during neural network training and provide theoretical evidence that such scaling behavior arises naturally from information-driven self-organization: a dynamic balance between the maximum entropy principle that promotes unbiased exploration and mutual information constraint that relates updates with task objective. We numerically demonstrate that the power-law exponent of updates remains stable throughout training, supporting the presence of self-organized criticality. Furthermore, we show that the loss landscape exhibits exponential ruggedness under small perturbations, transitioning to power-law ruggedness at larger scales, in the absence of mini-batch noise, indicating an intrinsic geometric landscape. We also observe a power-law distribution in the intervals between large updates, indicating an intermittent learning process. Together, these findings suggest that neural network learning reflects a nonequilibrium process governed by the fundamental trade-off between randomness and relevance, highlighting its dynamic nature and offering insights into the interpretability of AI systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xin-Ya</ForeName><Initials>XY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7826-3076</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Interdisciplinary Studies and Department of Physics, School of Science, Westlake University, Hangzhou 310030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Natural Sciences, Westlake Institute for Advanced Study, Hangzhou 310024, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Interdisciplinary Studies and Department of Physics, School of Science, Westlake University, Hangzhou 310030, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025M773426</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation ()</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-organization criticality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">statistical physics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41410766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12745802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2523012122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Krenn M., et al. , On scientific understanding with artificial intelligence. Nat. Rev. Phys. 4, 761&#x2013;769 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y. H., AI-driven research in pure mathematics and theoretical physics. Nat. Rev. Phys. 6, 546&#x2013;553 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jumper J., et al. , Highly accurate protein structure prediction with AlphaFold. Nature 596, 583&#x2013;589 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8371605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34265844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver D., et al. , Mastering the game of go with deep neural networks and tree search. Nature 529, 484&#x2013;489 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26819042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCun Y., et al. , Handwritten digit recognition with a back-propagation network. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2, 396&#x2013;404 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y., Zhang W., Tu Y., Activity-weight duality in feed-forward neural networks reveals two co-determinants for generalization. Nat. Mach. Intell. 5, 908&#x2013;918 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z., Huang H., Spiking mode-based neural networks. Phys. Rev. E 110, 024306 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39295018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang C., et al. , Network properties determine neural network performance. Nat. Commun. 15, 5718 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11231255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38977665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin G., et al. , How does weight correlation affect generalisation ability of deep neural networks? <i>Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst.</i>
<b>33</b>, 21346&#x2013;21356 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Achille, G. Paolini, S. Soatto, Where is the information in a deep neural network? arXiv [Preprint] (2019). http://arxiv.org/abs/1905.12213 (Accessed 29 May 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Lin P., Wang Z., Zhang Y., Xu Z. Q., Initialization is critical to whether transformers fit composite functions by reasoning or memorizing. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 37, 14093&#x2013;14126 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Kaplan et al., Scaling laws for neural language models. arXiv [Preprint] (2020). http://arxiv.org/abs/2001.08361 (Accessed 23 January 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wei et al., Emergent abilities of large language models. arXiv [Preprint] (2022). http://arxiv.org/abs/2206.07682 (Accessed 15 June 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sclocchi A., Wyart M., On the different regimes of stochastic gradient descent. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 121, e2316301121 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10907278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38377198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Metz, N. Maheswaranathan, B. Cheung, J. Sohl-Dickstein, &#x201c;Meta-learning update rules for unsupervised representation learning&#x201d; in <i>The International Conference on Learning Representations</i> (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein J., et al. , Learning compositional functions via multiplicative weight updates. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 33, 13319&#x2013;13330 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y., Cornelius S. P., Liu Y. Y., Li A., Dynamics of collective cooperation under personalised strategy updates. Nat. Commun. 15, 3125 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11006938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38600076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z., Tang Q. Y., Sun M., Li P., On the overlooked structure of stochastic gradients. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 36, 66257&#x2013;66276 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y., Tu Y., The inverse variance-flatness relation in stochastic gradient descent is critical for finding flat minima. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 118, e2015617118 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7936325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33619091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Mahoney, C. Martin, &#x201c;Traditional and heavy tailed self regularization in neural network models&#x201d; in <i>Proceedings of the 36th International Conference on Machine Learning</i>, K. Chaudhuri, R. Salakhutdinov, Eds. (PMLR, 2019), pp. 4284&#x2013;4293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahri Y., et al. , Statistical mechanics of deep learning. Annu. Rev. Condens. Matter Phys. 11, 501&#x2013;528 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Huang H., Nonequilbrium physics of generative diffusion models. Phys. Rev. E 111, 014111 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39972748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Liu J., Zhang J., Zhang P., Learning nonequilibrium statistical mechanics and dynamical phase transitions. Nat. Commun. 15, 1117 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10847122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38321012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson R. C., Geana A., White J. M., Ludvig E. A., Cohen J. D., Humans use directed and random exploration to solve the explore-exploit dilemma. J. Exp. Psychol. Gen. 143, 2074 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5635655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25347535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K., The free-energy principle: A unified brain theory? Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 11, 127&#x2013;138 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20068583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak P., Tang C., Wiesenfeld K., Self-organized criticality: An explanation of the 1/f noise. Phys. Rev. Lett. 59, 381 (1987).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10035754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsukawa T., Teramae J.-N., The cortical critical power law balances energy and information in an optimal fashion. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 122, e2418218122 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12130854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40408401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X. Y., Moore J. M., Ru X., Yan G., Geometric scaling law in real neuronal networks. Phys. Rev. Lett. 133, 138401 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39392951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X. Y., Yao Y., Han Z., Yan G., Delayed threshold and spatial diffusion in k-core percolation induced by long-range connectivity. Commun. Phys. 8, 1&#x2013;10 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruderman D. L., Origins of scaling in natural images. Vis. Res. 37, 3385&#x2013;3398 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9425551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibollahi F., Kagan B. J., Burkitt A. N., French C., Critical dynamics arise during structured information presentation within embodied in vitro neuronal networks. Nat. Commun. 14, 5287 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10469171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37648737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak P., Tang C., Earthquakes as a self-organized critical phenomenon. J. Geophys. Res. Solid Earth 94, 15635&#x2013;15637 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynn C. W., Holmes C. M., Palmer S. E., Heavy-tailed neuronal connectivity arises from Hebbian self-organization. Nat. Phys. 20, 484&#x2013;491 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Y. Zhang et al. , Adaptive stretching of representations across brain regions and deep learning model layers. <i>Nat. Commun</i>. <b>16</b>, 10302 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12638828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41271767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Kadambi, K. N. Ramamurthy, V. Berisha, &#x201c;Comparing fisher information regularization with distillation for DNN quantization&#x201d; in <i>NeurIPS Workshop on Deep Learning through Information Geometry</i> (NeurIPS Workshop, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H., Zheng L., Gaussian process parameter estimation using mini-batch stochastic gradient descent: Convergence guarantees and empirical benefits. J. Mach. Learn. Res. 23, 1&#x2013;59 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Panigrahi, R. Somani, N. Goyal, P. Netrapalli, &#x201c;Non-gaussianity of stochastic gradient noise&#x201d; in <i>NeuIPS Workshop on Science Meets Engineering of Deep Learning</i> (NeurIPS Workshop, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaynes E. T., The minimum entropy production principle. Annu. Rev. Phys. Chem. 31, 579&#x2013;601 (1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Press&#xe9; S., Ghosh K., Lee J., Dill K. A., Principles of maximum entropy and maximum caliber in statistical physics. Rev. Mod. Phys. 85, 1115&#x2013;1141 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N., Tang C., Tu Y., Stochastic gradient descent introduces an effective landscape-dependent regularization favoring flat solutions. Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 237101 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37354404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Xie, I. Sato, M. Sugiyama, &#x201c;A diffusion theory for deep learning dynamics: Stochastic gradient descent exponentially favors flat minima&#x201d; in <i>International Conference on Learning Representations</i> (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly A., Gong P., Optimization on multifractal loss landscapes explains a diverse range of geometrical and dynamical properties of deep learning. Nat. Commun. 16, 3252 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11971247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40185730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen K., Danon L., Scanlon T., Bak P., Unified scaling law for earthquakes. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 99, 2509&#x2013;2513 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC128569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11875203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corral &#xc1;., Long-term clustering, scaling, and universality in the temporal occurrence of earthquakes. Phys. Rev. Lett. 92, 108501 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15089251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plerou V., Gopikrishnan P., Amaral L. A. N., Gabaix X., Stanley H. E., Economic fluctuations and anomalous diffusion. Phys. Rev. E 62, R3023 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11088869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beggs J. M., Plenz D., Neuronal avalanches in neocortical circuits. J. Neurosci. 23, 11167&#x2013;11177 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6741045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14657176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. &#x15e;im&#x15f;ekli, M. G&#xfc;rb&#xfc;zbalaban, T. H. Nguyen, G. Richard, L. Sagun, On the heavy-tailed theory of stochastic gradient descent for deep neural networks. arXiv [Preprint] (2019). http://arxiv.org/abs/1912.00018 (Accessed 29 November 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. H. Nguyen, &#x201c;Heavy-tailed nature of stochastic gradient descent in deep learning: Theoretical and empirical analysis,&#x201d; PhD thesis, Institut Polytechnique de Paris (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. G&#xfc;rb&#xfc;zbalaban, U. Simsekli, L. Zhu, &#x201c;The heavy-tail phenomenon in SGD&#x201d; in <i>International Conference on Machine Learning</i>, N. Lawrence, Ed. (PMLR, 2021), pp. 3964&#x2013;3975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malevergne Y., Pisarenko V., Sornette D., Testing the pareto against the lognormal distributions with the uniformly most powerful unbiased test applied to the distribution of cities. Phys. Rev. E 83, 036111 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21517562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., et al. , Towards theoretically understanding why SGD generalizes better than ADAM in deep learning. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 33, 21285&#x2013;21296 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Bai R., Huang H., Spin-glass model of in-context learning. Phys. Rev. E 112, L013301 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40826530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. H. Tang, &#x201c;Collective transport and depinning&#x201d; in <i>Statistical and Nonlinear Physics</i>, R. A. Meyers, Ed. (RAMTECH LIMITED, Larkspur, CA, 2022), pp. 145&#x2013;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. He, X. Zhang, S. Ren, J. Sun, &#x201c;Delving deep into rectifiers: Surpassing human-level performance on imagenet classification&#x201d; in <i>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</i> (IEEE, 2015), pp. 1026&#x2013;1034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Glorot, Y. Bengio, &#x201c;Understanding the difficulty of training deep feedforward neural networks&#x201d; in <i>Proceedings of the Thirteenth International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics, PMLR</i>, Y. W. Teh, M. Titterington, Eds. (2010), pp. 249&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virtanen P., et al. , SciPy 1.0: Fundamental algorithms for scientific computing in Python. Nat. Methods 17, 261&#x2013;272 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7056644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X.-Y. Zhang, Heavy-tailed updates in artificial neural networks. GitHub. https://github.com/xinyacheung/Heavy-tailed-Updates-in-Artificial-Neural-Networks. Deposited 7 July 2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>