<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41509996</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1359-4338</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Virtual reality</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Virtual Real</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Towards user-centered interactive medical image segmentation in VR with an assistive AI agent.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10055-025-01284-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Crucial in disease analysis and surgical planning, manual segmentation of volumetric medical scans (e.g. MRI, CT) is laborious, error-prone, and challenging to master, while fully automatic algorithms can benefit from user feedback. Therefore, with the complementary power of the latest radiological AI foundation models and virtual reality (VR)'s intuitive data interaction, we propose SAMIRA, a novel conversational AI agent for medical VR that assists users with localizing, segmenting, and visualizing 3D medical concepts. Through speech-based interaction, the agent helps users understand radiological features, locate clinical targets, and generate segmentation masks that can be refined with just a few point prompts. The system also supports true-to-scale 3D visualization of segmented pathology to enhance patient-specific anatomical understanding. Furthermore, to determine the optimal interaction paradigm under near-far attention-switching for refining segmentation masks in an immersive, human-in-the-loop workflow, we compare VR controller pointing, head pointing, and eye tracking as input modes. With a user study, evaluations demonstrated a high usability score (SUS&#xa0;=&#xa0;90.0&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;9.0), low overall task load, as well as strong support for the proposed VR system's guidance, training potential, and integration of AI in radiological segmentation tasks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spiegler</LastName><ForeName>Pascal</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, Concordia University, Montreal, Quebec Canada.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0420zvk78</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.410319.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 8630</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harirpoush</LastName><ForeName>Arash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, Concordia University, Montreal, Quebec Canada.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0420zvk78</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.410319.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 8630</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Yiming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, Concordia University, Montreal, Quebec Canada.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0420zvk78</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.410319.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1936 8630</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Virtual Real</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518169</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1359-4338</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI agent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attention switching</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical decision support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eye tracking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Foundation model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human-in-the-loop</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical image segmentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical visualization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual reality</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41509996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12775086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10055-025-01284-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Behravan M, Gra&#x10d;anin D (2025) From voices to worlds: Developing an ai-powered framework for 3d object generation in augmented reality. In: 2025 IEEE conference on virtual reality and 3d user interfaces abstracts and workshops (VRW), pp 150&#x2013;155. IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behravan M, Haghani M, Gra&#x10d;anin D (2025) Transcending dimensions using generative ai: real-time 3d model generation in augmented reality. In: International conference on human-computer interaction, pp 13&#x2013;32. Springer</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behravan M, Matkovi&#x107; K, Gra&#x10d;anin D (2025) Generative ai for context-aware 3d object creation using vision-language models in augmented reality. In: 2025 IEEE international conference on artificial intelligence and extended and virtual reality (AIxVR), pp 73&#x2013;81. IEEE</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilic P, Christ P, Li HB, Vorontsov E, Ben-Cohen A, Kaissis G, Szeskin A, Jacobs C, Mamani GEH, Chartrand G et al (2023) The liver tumor segmentation benchmark (lits). Med Image Anal 84:102680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2022.102680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10631490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36481607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke J et al (1996) Sus-a quick and dirty usability scale. Usability Eval Ind 189(194):4&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke J (2013) Sus: a retrospective. J Usability Stud 8(2):235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno MA, Walker EA, Abujudeh HH (2015) Understanding and confronting our mistakes: the epidemiology of error in radiology and strategies for error reduction. Radiographics 35(6):1668&#x2013;1676. 10.1148/rg.2015150023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/rg.2015150023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26466178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budd S, Robinson EC, Kainz B (2021) A survey on active learning and human-in-the-loop deep learning for medical image analysis. Med Image Anal 71:102062</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2021.102062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Gutt M, Belker OA, D&#xfc;x DM, Wacker FK, Hensen B, Gutberlet M (2025) Proof of concept for voice based mri scanner control using large language models in real time guided interventions: H. chen et al. Scientific Reports 15(1):31206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-11290-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12378185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40855151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chheang V, Sharmin S, M&#xe1;rquez-Hern&#xe1;ndez R, et al. (2024) Towards anatomy education with generative ai-based virtual assistants in immersive virtual reality environments. In: Proceedings IEEE Int. Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Virtual Reality (AIVR), pp. 21&#x2013;30. 10.1109/AIxVR59861.2024.00011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douze M, Guzhva A, Deng C, Johnson J, Szilvasy G, Mazar&#xe9; P-E, Lomeli M, Hosseini L, J&#xe9;gou H (2024) The faiss library. arXiv preprint arXiv:2401.08281</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes AS, Murdison TS, Proulx M.J (2024) Looking in depth: targeting by eye and controller input for multi-depth target placement. Int J Human&#x2013;Compu Int, 1&#x2013;16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Chang C, Yu X, Pang P, Xiong N, Huang C (2022) A vr-based volumetric medical image segmentation and visualization system with natural human interaction. Virtual Real 26(2):415&#x2013;424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10055-021-00577-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez Izard S, S&#xe1;nchez Torres R, Alonso Plaza O, Juanes Mendez JA, Garc&#xed;a-Pe&#xf1;alvo FJ (2020) Nextmed: automatic imaging segmentation, 3d reconstruction, and 3d model visualization platform using augmented and virtual reality. Sensors 20(10):2962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s20102962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32456194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart SG, Staveland LE (1988) Development of nasa-tlx (task load index): results of empirical and theoretical research. In: Advances in psychology. Elsevier, pp 139&#x2013;183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellum O, Kersten-Oertel M, Xiao Y (2023) Assessment of user-interaction strategies for neurosurgical data navigation and annotation in virtual reality. Virtual Real 27(2):1345&#x2013;1355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10055-022-00740-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellum O, Steele C, Xiao Y (2024) Sonia: an immersive customizable virtual reality system for the education and exploration of brain networks. Front Virtual Real 4:1244096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frvir.2023.1244096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinson WH, Boehme JM, Choplin RH, Santago II P (1990) Voice recognition interface for a radiology information system. In: Medical imaging IV: PACS systems design and evaluation. SPIE, pp 471&#x2013;475</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X, Hao Y, Hilliard J, Zhang Z, Thomas MA, Li H, Jha AK, Hugo GD (2024) A quality assurance framework for routine monitoring of deep learning cardiac substructure computed tomography segmentation models in radiotherapy. Med Phys 51(4):2741&#x2013;2758</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mp.16846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38015793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirillov A, et al. (2024) Sam 2: Segment anything, any time, all at once. arXiv preprint arXiv:2404.07143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konenkov M, Lykov A, Trinitatova D, Tsetserukou D (2024) Vr-gpt: Visual language model for intelligent virtual reality applications. arXiv preprint arXiv:2405.11537</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai J, Vergo J (1997) Medspeak: Report creation with continuous speech recognition. In: Proceedings of the ACM SIGCHI conference on human factors in computing systems, pp 431&#x2013;438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaw SY, Tan JZ, Bin Rusli KD, Ratan R, Zhou W, Lim S, Lau TC, Seah B, Chua WL (2023) Artificial intelligence versus human-controlled doctor in virtual reality simulation for sepsis team training: randomized controlled study. J Med Internet Res 25:47748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/47748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luro FL, Sundstedt V (2019) A comparative study of eye tracking and hand controller for aiming tasks in virtual reality. In: Proceedings of the 11th ACM symposium on eye tracking research &amp; applications, pp 1&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macefield R (2009) How to specify the participant group size for usability studies: a practitioner&#x2019;s guide. J Usability Stud 5(1):34&#x2013;45</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menze BH, Jakab A, Bauer S, Kalpathy-Cramer J, Farahani K, Kirby J, Burren Y, Porz N, Slotboom J, Wiest R et al (2014) The multimodal brain tumor image segmentation benchmark (brats). IEEE trans med imaging 34(10):1993&#x2013;2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMI.2014.2377694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25494501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutasim AK, Batmaz AU, Stuerzlinger W (2021) Pinch, click, or dwell: comparing different selection techniques for eye-gaze-based pointing in virtual reality. In: Acm symposium on eye tracking research and applications, pp 1&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purkayastha S, Isaac R, Anthony S, Shukla S, Krupinski EA, Danish JA, Gichoya JW (2023) A general-purpose ai assistant embedded in an open-source radiology information system. In: International conference on artificial intelligence in medicine, pp 373&#x2013;377 Springer</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramakrishnan D, Jekel L, Chadha S, Janas A, Moy H, Maleki N, Sala M, Kaur M, Petersen GC, Merkaj S et al (2024) A large open access dataset of brain metastasis 3d segmentations on mri with clinical and imaging information. Sci Data 11(1):254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-024-03021-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10904366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38424079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashid U, Kauko J, H&#xe4;kkil&#xe4; J, Quigley A (2011) Proximal and distal selection of widgets: designing distributed ui for mobile interaction with large display. In: Proceedings of the 13th international conference on human computer interaction with mobile devices and services, pp 495&#x2013;498</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen C, Li W, Shi Y, Wang X (2025) Interactive 3D medical image segmentation with SAM 2. https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.02635</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidenmark L, Prummer F, Newn J, Gellersen H (2023) Comparing gaze, head and controller selection of dynamically revealed targets in head-mounted displays. IEEE Trans Vis Comput Grap 29(11):4740&#x2013;4750. 10.1109/TVCG.2023.3320235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVCG.2023.3320235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegler P (2025) Planification Automatique de la Trajectoire des &#xc9;lectrodes pour la Chirurgie de Stimulation C&#xe9;r&#xe9;brale Profonde Connectomique. Bourse de ma&#xee;trise en recherche, num&#xe9;ro de demande 348625, Fonds de recherche du Qu&#xe9;bec (FRQ). 10.69777/348625</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegler P, Abdelsalam H, Hellum O, Hadjinicolaou A, Weil AG, Xiao Y (2024) Previse: an efficient virtual reality system for seeg surgical planning. Virtual Real 29(1):13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10055-024-01088-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11669611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39735694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;squez-Venegas C, Sotomayor CG, Ramos B, Casta&#xf1;eda V, Pereira G, Cabrera-Vives G, H&#xe4;rtel S (2024) Human-in-the-loop-a deep learning strategy in combination with a patient-specific gaussian mixture model leads to the fast characterization of volumetric ground-glass opacity and consolidation in the computed tomography scans of covid-19 patients. J Clin Med 13(17):5231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13175231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11396404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39274444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Meng X, Yu K, Sarcar S, Liang H-N (2022) Evaluation of text selection techniques in virtual reality head-mounted displays. In: 2022 IEEE international symposium on mixed and augmented reality (ISMAR). IEEE, pp 131&#x2013;140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Sharp G, Veeraraghavan H, Van Elmpt W, Dekker A, Lustberg T, Gooding M (2017) Data from Lung CT Segmentation Challenge 2017 (LCTSC). The Cancer Imaging Archive. 10.7937/K9/TCIA.2017.3R3FVZ08. https://www.cancerimagingarchive.net/collection/lctsc/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonker SB, Korshak OO, Hedstrom T, Wu A, Atre S, Schulze JP (2019) 3d medical image segmentation in virtual reality. Electron Imaging 31:1&#x2013;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2352/ISSN.2470-1173.2019.2.ERVR-188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao T, Gu Y, Yang J et al (2025) Biomedparse: a biomedical foundation model for image parsing of everything everywhere all at once. Nat Methods 22:166&#x2013;176. 10.1038/s41592-024-02499-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41592-024-02499-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39558098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J, Hamdi A, Qi Y, Jin Y, Wu J (2024) Medical sam 2: segment medical images as video via segment anything model 2. arXiv preprint arXiv:2408.00874</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>