<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41469564</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An innovative fuzzy model control strategy for Trans-Z-Source DC-DC boost converters in satellite power systems.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>45795</StartPage><MedlinePgn>45795</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">45795</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-28748-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper investigates the critical role of Direct Current to Direct Current (DC-DC) converters in satellite power systems, emphasizing the need for efficient and reliable energy conversion under dynamic space conditions. A novel Fuzzy Model Control (FMC) strategy is proposed for a quasi-Trans-Z-Source DC-DC boost converter, addressing the inherent challenges of nonlinear power dynamics and multiport energy flow management in space applications. The proposed approach enhances mode transitions, improves solar energy extraction from photovoltaic (PV) panels, and ensures stable voltage regulation under fluctuating load conditions. A comprehensive theoretical analysis of the circuit topology highlights its advantages over conventional boost converters, including continuous input current, higher voltage gain, and reduced passive component stress. Simulation and experimental results demonstrate that the proposed FMC achieves&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.5% voltage regulation accuracy, reduces current ripple by 28%, and improves transient response time by 35% compared to a conventional Proportional-Integral (PI) controller. The overall system efficiency reaches 94.7% under nominal conditions. Furthermore, the control strategy effectively manages constraints such as duty cycle limits and dynamic disturbances, confirming its real-time applicability for spaceborne platforms such as nanosatellites and CubeSats.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lotfy</LastName><ForeName>Mostafa Wageh</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Process Control Technology, Faculty of Technology and Education, Beni-Suef University, Beni-Suef, Egypt. dr.mostafawag@techedu.bsu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussein</LastName><ForeName>Aziza I</ForeName><Initials>AI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical &amp; Computer Eng. Dept, Effat University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abo-Zahhad</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Sohag University, Sohag, New Sohag City, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mabrook</LastName><ForeName>M Mourad</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Space Communication Dept, Faculty of Navigation Science &amp; Space Technology, Beni-Suef University, Beni-Suef, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DC/DC boost converter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DC/DC converter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fuzzy model control (FMC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quasi-Trans-Z-source network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Satellite systems</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41469564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12756291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-28748-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-28748-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Q. &amp; Lee, F. C. High-efficiency, high step-up DC-DC converters. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>18</b> (1), 65&#x2013;73 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2002.807188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarzamni, H., Gohari, H. S., Sabahi, M. &amp; Kyyr&#xe4;, J. <i>Non-isolated High step-up dc-dc Converters: Comparative Review and Metrics Applicability</i> (IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics., 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh, D., Babaei, E. &amp; Mousavi, S. M. J. High conversion ratio buck&#x2013;boost DC-DC converter based on the coupled inductor. <i>IET Power Electron.</i><b>16</b> (4), 645&#x2013;658 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/pel2.12414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, Z., Abdel-Rahman, O., Al-Atrash, H. &amp; Batarseh, I. Modeling and control of three-port DC/DC converter interface for satellite applications. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>25</b> (3), 637&#x2013;649 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2009.2033926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotfy, M. W., Ramadan, H. S. &amp; Dabour, S. M. Smart EV charging via advanced ongrid MPPT-PV systems with quadratic-boost split-source inverters. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 7841. 10.1038/s41598-025-90775-w (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-90775-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11885632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40050319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehata, E. G. et al. Design and analysis of a quasi y-source impedance network dc-dc converter in Nineteenth International Middle East. Power Syst. Conference (MEPCON), IEEE, 2017, Dec., 235&#x2013;241, (2017). 10.1109/MEPCON.2017.8301189</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siwakoti, Y., Blaabjerg, F. &amp; Loh, C. New magnetically coupled impedance (Z-) source networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Electron.</i><b>31</b> (11), 7419&#x2013;7435 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2015.2459233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, F. Z. Impedance sources (Z sources) with inherent fault protection for resilient and fire-free electricity grids. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 3062. 10.1038/s41598-024-53452-y (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-53452-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10847111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38321077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wageh, M. et al. A high gain split-source inverter with reduced input current ripple. <i>22nd Int. Middle East. Power Syst. Conf. (MEPCON)</i>. <b>2021</b>, 383&#x2013;388. 10.1109/MEPCON50283.2021.9686237 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MEPCON50283.2021.9686237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forouzesh, M., Abdelhakim, A., Siwakoti, Y. &amp; Blaabjerg, F. Analysis and design of an energy regenerative snubber for magnetically coupled impedance source converters. In 2018 IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition (APEC) (2555&#x2013;2561). IEEE. (2018), March.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotfy, M. W. et al. Modulation and control of transformerless boosting inverters for three-phase photovoltaic systems: comprehensive analysis. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 14053. 10.1038/s41598-025-93902-9 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-93902-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12019217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40268987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddivari, R. &amp; Jena, D. A correlative investigation of impedance source networks: a comprehensive review. <i>IETE Tech. Rev.</i><b>39</b> (3), 506&#x2013;539 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02564602.2020.1870006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotfy, M. et al. Elmorshedy. Modeling and control of a voltage-lift cell split-source inverter with MPPT for photovoltaic systems. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>11</b>, 54699&#x2013;54712 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3280602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, Y. et al. Precipitation modeling and prediction based on fuzzy-control multi-cellular gene expression programming and wavelet transform. In Intelligent Computing Theories and Application: 15th International Conference, ICIC 2019, Nanchang, China, August 3&#x2013;6, 2019, Proceedings, Part II 15 (81&#x2013;92). Springer International Publishing. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Huang, M., Liu, S., Xiao, B. &amp; Durrani, T. S. Fuzzy multilayer clustering and fuzzy label regularization for unsupervised person reidentification. <i>IEEE Trans. Fuzzy Syst.</i><b>28</b> (7), 1356&#x2013;1368 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascoa, JC, Teixeira, O, &amp; Filipe, G. "A Review of Propulsion Systems for CubeSats." Proceedings of the ASME 2018 International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition. <b>1</b>, Advances in Aerospace Technology. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA. November 9&#x2013;15, V001T03A039. ASME. 10.1115/IMECE2018-88174. (2018)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassakeur, A., Underwood, C., Taylor, B. &amp; Duke, R. Magnetic cleanliness program on cubesats and nanosatellites for improved attitude stability. <i>J. Aeronaut. Space Technol.</i><b>13</b> (1), 25&#x2013;41 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotfy, M. W. &amp; Hussein, A. I. Hybrid energy storage system with DC-DC boost converter and MPPT P&amp;O control for optimized photovoltaic power management. In 2024 8th International Conference on Power and Energy Engineering (ICPEE) (277&#x2013;282). IEEE. (2024), December.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, X. et al. Nanosats/CubeSats adcs survey. In 2017 29th Chinese Control And Decision Conference (CCDC) (5151&#x2013;5158). IEEE. (2017), May.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem, A., Chandran, A., Srivastava, S., Varghese, J. J. &amp; Chang, J. S. <i>NanoSMAD&#x2013;A First order System Configuration Design Tool for nano and Micro Satellites</i> (Advances in Space Research, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalbins, J., Allaje, K., Ehrpais, H., Iakubivskyi, I., Ilbis, E., Janhunen, &#x2026; Slavinskis,A. (2023). Interplanetary student nanospacecraft: development of the leo demonstrator estcube-2. Aerospace, 10(6), 503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim&#xf3;n-Gonz&#xe1;lez, M., Garc&#xed;a-S&#xe1;nchez, E. R., Vargas-Mart&#xed;nez, H. S., Quiroz-Hern&#xe1;ndez, N. &amp; Maya-Rueda, S. E. Performance analysis of inter-satellite and satellite-ground communication: a report on flight data for a low Earth orbit Cubesat. <i>Aerospace</i><b>10</b> (11), 973 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/aerospace10110973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basyouni, S., Reda, R., Hussein, A. I. &amp; Lotfy, M. W. Bi-Directional DC-DC converter for enhanced power management in electric vehicle applications. In 2024 10th International Conference on Computing, Engineering and Design (ICCED) (1&#x2013;6). IEEE. (2024), December.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein, A. &amp; Lotfy, M. W. Optimizing thermo-electric generation with quasi-z-source converter in energy harvesting for wearable devices. <i>Mechatronics Autom. Technol.</i><b>64</b>, 233&#x2013;240. 10.3233/ATDE241245 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/ATDE241245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laufer, R. &amp; Pelton, J. N. The smallest classes of small satellites include femtosats, picosats, nanosats, and CubeSats. Handbook of Small Satellites: Technology, Design, Manufacture, Applications, Economics and Regulation, 1&#x2013;15. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fakhri, N. et al. Optimization of impedance-source galvanically isolated DC&#x2013;DC converters with reduced number of switches. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>10</b>, 3835&#x2013;3847 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3139948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agia, C. et al. Modeling considerations for developing deep space autonomous spacecraft and simulators, 2024 IEEE Aerospace Conference, Big Sky, MT, USA, 1&#x2013;20, (2024). 10.1109/AERO58975.2024.10521055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J., Chen, D. &amp; Jiang, J. Transformerless high step-up DC-DC converter with low voltage stress for fuel cells. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>9</b>, 10228&#x2013;10238 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3050546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komurcugil, H., Biricik, S., Bayhan, S. &amp; Zhang, Z. Sliding mode control: overview of its applications in power converters. <i>IEEE Ind. Electron. Mag.</i><b>15</b> (1), 40&#x2013;49. 10.1109/MIE.2020.2986165 (March 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almakhles, D., Ali, J. S. M., Navamani, J. D., Lavanya, A. &amp; Bhaskar, M. S. Single switch module type DC-DC converter with reduction in voltage stress. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>10</b>, 107877&#x2013;107887. 10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3212119 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3212119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathik, M. J. et al. Reliability analysis of power components in restructured DC/DC converters. <i>IEEE Trans. Device Mater. Reliab.</i><b>21</b> (4), 544&#x2013;555. 10.1109/TDMR.2021.3116941 (Dec. 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghassemi, A., Padmanaban, S., Ramachandaramurthy, V. K., Mitolo, M. &amp; Benbouzid, M. A novel solar photovoltaic fed TransZSI-DVR for power quality improvement of grid-connected PV systems. <i>IEEE access.</i><b>9</b>, 7263&#x2013;7279 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3048022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salah, I., Hussein, A. I., Lotfy, M. W. &amp; Mabrook, M. M. Enhancing 6G-satellite network integration with artificial intelligence: a future communication paradigm. In 2025 22nd International Learning and Technology Conference (L&amp;T) (22, 175&#x2013;179). IEEE. (2025), January.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y.-L., Chen, L.-H., &amp; Huang, C.-Y. FUZZY GOAL PROGRAMMING APPROACH TO SOLVE THE EQUIPMENT-PURCHASING PROBLEM OF AN FMC. <i>International Journal of Industrial Engineering: Theory, Applications and Practice</i>, <b>16</b>(4). 10.23055/ijietap.2009.16.4.72. (2009)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivakumar, S., Sathik, M. J., Manoj, S. &amp; Sundararajan, G. An assessment on performance of DC&#x2013;DC converters for renewable energy applications. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>58</b>, 1475&#x2013;1485 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2015.12.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari, A. et al. Analysing the reliability factors of a robot utilized within an FMC comprising two machines and one robot. <i>Int. J. Interact. Des. Manuf.</i><b>19</b>, 4517&#x2013;4531. 10.1007/s12008-025-02237-2 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-025-02237-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy, S. V. R., Sudhamani, D., Lavanya, B., Haritha, S. &amp; Reddy, B. N. PV fed nine-level multilevel inverter with fuzzy controller. In <i>Smart Grid Security and Protection. ICSPER 2024</i> Vol. 1307 (eds Badar, A. Q. H. et al.) (Springer, 2025). 10.1007/978-981-96-0824-9_24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagan, V., Maheshwaram, B. C., Usirikapally, M., Balachandran, K., Reddy, B. N.,Mettu, S., &#x2026; Khan, B. (2024). Analysis of different PWM techniques for enhanced ultrahigh gain z-network topology. International Transactions on Electrical Energy Systems, 2024(1), 6645798. https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/6645798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agan, V., Kumar, S., Deepika, K., Sravya, S., Mallesh, U. &amp; B, N. R A novel switched-capacitor enhanced-boost quasi z-source network. <i>Trans. Energy Syst. Eng. Appl.</i><b>4</b> (2), 1&#x2013;12. 10.32397/tesea.vol4.n2.528 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32397/tesea.vol4.n2.528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>