<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41455775</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Red-billed blue magpie optimization for training feedforward neural networks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1301</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1301</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1301</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-33719-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The input layer, hidden layer, and output layer constitute the feedforward neural networks (FNNs) with unidirectional propagation and no feedback loop connection. The FNNs exhibit pivotal properties of nonlinear fitting ability, flexible structure, multitasking adaptability, easy implementation, strong compatibility and composability. The FNNs can independently tackle classification and regression tasks and support the construction of complex networks. The red-billed blue magpie optimization (RBMO) is constructed on the collective collaborative exploration and sophisticated hunting proficiency of the red-billed blue magpies. The RBMO emulates searching for food sources, chasing and attacking prey, and hoarding superfluous food to balance extensive global exploration and meticulous local exploitation, and to ascertain the fittest solution. In this paper, the RBMO is proposed to train FNNs, the motivation is to measure the dissimilarity between anticipated and actual outputs, quantify the training efficiency and classification precision of the sample datasets, and fabricate the connection weights and biases. The RBMO exhibits the distinctive advantages of extensible adaptability and flexibility, accelerated convergence speed, heightened calculation accuracy, decreased control parameters, remarkable robustness and stability, and diminished computational complexity. Seventeen sample datasets are utilized to authenticate the applicability and practicality, the RBMO is compared with SFOA, FLO, APO, HEOA, EGO, BKA, WO, HO, IAO, NRBO, ETO and PO. The experimental results demonstrate that the RBMO can dynamically alternate between exploration and exploitation to strengthen stability and robustness, intensify training efficiency and classification precision, promote convergence speed and solution quality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jinzhong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Photoelectronic Engineering, West Anhui University, Lu'an, 237012, China. zhangjinzhongz@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hongkai</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Photoelectronic Engineering, West Anhui University, Lu'an, 237012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Gang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Photoelectronic Engineering, West Anhui University, Lu'an, 237012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Photoelectronic Engineering, West Anhui University, Lu'an, 237012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Tan</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical and Photoelectronic Engineering, West Anhui University, Lu'an, 237012, China. 42000028@wxc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Anqi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic Information and Artificial Intelligence, West Anhui University, Lu'an, 237012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024AH051989</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Key Research Project of Anhui Educational Committee</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>0045024064</GrantID><Agency>Horizontal research subject: Research on path planning technology of smart agriculture and forestry harvesting robots based on evolutionary algorithms</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>0045025108</GrantID><Agency>Horizontal research subject: Design of power supply and drive system for agricultural and forestry weeding and picking robots</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>WGKQ2022052</GrantID><Agency>Start-up Fund for Distinguished Scholars of West Anhui University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>wxxy2023079</GrantID><Agency>School-level Quality Engineering (Teaching and Research Project)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GXXT-2021-026</GrantID><Agency>University Synergy Innovation Program of Anhui Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022AH010091</GrantID><Agency>Smart Agriculture and Forestry and Smart Equipment Scientific Research and Innovation Team (Anhui Undergrowth Crop Intelligent Equipment Engineering Research Center)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>AUCIEERC-2022-01</GrantID><Agency>Open Fund of Anhui Undergrowth Crop Intelligent Equipment Engineering Research Center</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>0045025107</GrantID><Agency>Horizontal research subject: Research on Information Transmission Control Technology of Agricultural and Forestry Weeding Robot Based on Event Triggering</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CSBD2025-ZD03</GrantID><Agency>Open Research Fund of Anhui Province Engineering Laboratory for Big Data Analysis and Early Warning Technology of Coal Mine Safety</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Connection weights</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exploration and exploitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Feedforward neural networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Red-billed blue magpie optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sample datasets</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41455775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12796378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-33719-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-33719-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stecconi, T. et al. Analog resistive switching devices for training deep neural networks with the novel tiki-taka algorithm. <i>Nano Lett.</i><b>24</b>, 866&#x2013;872 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.3c03697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38205713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, R., Ma, X., Zhang, C., Ding, W. &amp; Zhan, J. GA-FCFNN: A new forecasting method combining feature selection methods and feedforward neural networks using genetic algorithms. <i>Inf. Sci.</i><b>669</b>, 120566 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ins.2024.120566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreuder, A., Bosman, A. S., Engelbrecht, A. P. &amp; Cleghorn, C. W. Training feedforward neural networks with Bayesian hyper-heuristics. <i>Inf. Sci.</i><b>686</b>, 121363 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ins.2024.121363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, C. et al. Starfish optimization algorithm (SFOA): a bio-inspired metaheuristic algorithm for global optimization compared with 100 optimizers. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>37</b>, 3641&#x2013;3683 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-024-10694-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falahah, I. A. et al. Frilled lizard optimization: A novel bio-inspired optimizer for solving engineering applications. <i>Comput. Mater. Contin.</i><b>79</b>, 3. 10.32604/cmc.2024.053189 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W., Tian, W., Xu, D. &amp; Zang, H. Arctic puffin optimization: A bio-inspired metaheuristic algorithm for solving engineering design optimization. <i>Adv. Eng. Softw.</i><b>195</b>, 103694 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.advengsoft.2024.103694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian, J. &amp; Hui, G. Human evolutionary optimization algorithm. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>241</b>, 122638 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadzadeh, A. &amp; Mirjalili, S. Eel and grouper optimizer: a nature-inspired optimization algorithm. <i>Clust. Comput.</i><b>27</b>, 12745&#x2013;12786 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10586-024-04545-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Wang, W., Hu, X., Qiu, L. &amp; Zang, H. Black-winged kite algorithm: a nature-inspired meta-heuristic for solving benchmark functions and engineering problems. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>57</b>, 98 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-024-10723-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, M. et al. Walrus optimizer: A novel nature-inspired metaheuristic algorithm. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>239</b>, 122413 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri, M. H., Mehrabi Hashjin, N., Montazeri, M., Mirjalili, S. &amp; Khodadadi, N. Hippopotamus optimization algorithm: a novel nature-inspired optimization algorithm. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 5032 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54910-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10904400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38424229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X., Li, S., Jiang, X. &amp; Zhou, Y. Information acquisition optimizer: a new efficient algorithm for solving numerical and constrained engineering optimization problems. <i>J. Supercomput.</i><b>80</b>, 25736&#x2013;25791 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-024-06384-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sowmya, R., Premkumar, M. &amp; Jangir, P. Newton-Raphson-based optimizer: A new population-based metaheuristic algorithm for continuous optimization problems. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>128</b>, 107532 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan, T. M., Khatir, S., Tran, M. T., De Baets, B. &amp; Cuong-Le, T. Exponential-trigonometric optimization algorithm for solving complicated engineering problems. <i>Comput. Methods Appl. Mech. Eng.</i><b>432</b>, 117411 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cma.2024.117411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian, J. et al. Parrot optimizer: Algorithm and applications to medical problems. <i>Comput. Biol. Med.</i><b>172</b>, 108064 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2024.108064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38452469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, S. et al. Red-billed blue magpie optimizer: a novel metaheuristic algorithm for 2D/3D UAV path planning and engineering design problems. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>57</b>, 134 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-024-10716-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W., Li, Z. &amp; Qiao, J. DEPFSWNN: A data-driven efficient pruning feedforward small-world neural network as a virtual sensor for total phosphorus in wastewater treatment process. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>296</b>, 129007. 10.1016/j.eswa.2025.129007 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S., Kim, H., Kang, N. &amp; Lee, T. H. Projected variable three-term conjugate gradient algorithm for enhancing generalization performance in deep neural network training. <i>Neurocomputing</i><b>657</b>, 131568. 10.1016/j.neucom.2025.131568 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito Iwakiri, I. et al. The relationship between diffusion coefficient and ion conductivity in solid-state electrolytes using feedforward neural networks and symbolic regression. <i>Available SSRN</i><b>656</b>, 238044 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panek-Chwastyk, E., Paradowski, K., Rutkowska, B., Szulc, W. &amp; Dzier&#x17c;anowski, I. Advancing early-stage plant phosphorus assessment for winter rye via hyperspectral data: A model-based approach harnessing feedforward neural networks. <i>Eur. J. Agron.</i><b>169</b>, 127667 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eja.2025.127667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, K. A. M. et al. Performance evaluation and prediction of optimal operational conditions for a compact date seeds milling unit using feedforward neural networks. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 4764 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-87508-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11807147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39922878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humfeld, K. D. et al. Co-training of multiple neural networks for simultaneous optimization and training of physics-informed neural networks for composite curing. <i>Compos. Part Appl. Sci. Manuf.</i><b>193</b>, 108820 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2025.108820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravichandran, N., Lansner, A. &amp; Herman, P. Unsupervised representation learning with Hebbian synaptic and structural plasticity in brain-like feedforward neural networks. <i>Neurocomputing</i><b>626</b>, 129440 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2025.129440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, C.-T., Blank, C., Schmelcher, P. &amp; Mukherjee, R. Towards arbitrary QUBO optimization: analysis of classical and quantum-activated feedforward neural networks. <i>Mach. Learn. Sci. Technol.</i><b>6</b>, 025049 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2632-2153/addb97</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrkash, M. &amp; Santini-Bell, E. Robustness analysis of multi-layer feedforward artificial neural networks for finite element model updating. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>171</b>, 112799 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2025.112799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustaffa, Z., Sulaiman, M. H. &amp; Abdul Aziz, A. An Improved Feedforward Neural Network with Barnacles Mating Optimizer for Traffic Class Prediction. <i>Eng. Res. Express</i><b>7</b>, 035218. 10.1088/2631-8695/adebe1 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;m&#xfc;&#x15f;, M. G., &#xc7;ift&#xe7;i, H. &#xc7;. &amp; G&#xfc;m&#xfc;&#x15f;, K. Determination of the performance of training algorithms and activation functions in meteorological drought index prediction with nonlinear autoregressive neural network. <i>Earth Sci. Inform.</i><b>18</b>, 197 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12145-025-01711-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, G. et al. The cascaded forward algorithm for neural network training. <i>Pattern Recognit.</i><b>161</b>, 111292 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patcog.2024.111292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, M., Tian, M. &amp; Wang, X. GA-DE: an integrated meta-heuristic approach for optimizing feedforward neural networks. <i>J. Supercomput.</i><b>81</b>, 1&#x2013;42 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11227-024-06799-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi, S. S., Salehirad, M., Emamzadeh, M. M. &amp; Yazdi, M. B. Improved equilibrium optimizer for accurate training of feedforward neural networks. <i>Opt. Mem. Neural Netw.</i><b>33</b>, 133&#x2013;143 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3103/S1060992X24700048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Bai, L., Gao, W., Xie, J. &amp; Huang, L. Many-objective coevolutionary learning algorithm with extreme learning machine auto-encoder for ensemble classifier of feedforward neural networks. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>246</b>, 123186 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood, K., Chaudhary, N. I., Khan, Z. A., Cheema, K. M. &amp; Raja, M. A. Z. Design of quantum computing-based avain navigation optimization algorithm for parameter estimation of input nonlinear output error model with key term separation. <i>Mod. Phys. Lett. A</i><b>40</b>, 2550019 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0217732325500191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood, K. et al. Design of chaos induced aquila optimizer for parameter estimation of electro-hydraulic control system. <i>Comput. Model. Eng. Sci. CMES</i><b>143</b>, 1809. 10.32604/cmes.2025.064900 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Liu, W., Zhang, G. &amp; Zhang, T. Quantum encoding whale optimization algorithm for global optimization and adaptive infinite impulse response system identification. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>58</b>, 158 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-025-11120-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. CWOA: A novel complex-valued encoding whale optimization algorithm. <i>Math. Comput. Simul.</i><b>207</b>, 151&#x2013;188 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matcom.2022.12.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>