<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41471455</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fault Diagnosis Method for Excitation Dry-Type Transformer Based on Multi-Channel Vibration Signal and Visual Feature Fusion.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7460</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s25247460</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To address the limitations of existing fault diagnosis methods for excitation dry-type transformers, such as inadequate utilization of multi-axis vibration data, low recognition accuracy under complex operational conditions, and limited computational efficiency, this paper presents a lightweight fault diagnosis approach based on the fusion of multi-channel vibration signals and visual features. Initially, a multi-physics field coupling simulation model of the excitation dry-type transformer is developed. Vibration data collected from field-installed three-axis sensors are combined to generate typical fault samples, including normal operation, winding looseness, core looseness, and winding eccentricity. Due to the high dimensionality of vibration signals, the Symmetrized Dot Pattern (ISDP) method is extended to aggregate and map time- and frequency-domain information from the x-, y-, and z-axes into a two-dimensional feature map. To optimize the inter-class separability and intra-class consistency of the map, Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) is employed to adaptively adjust the angle gain factor (&#x3b7;) and time delay coefficient (t). Keypoint descriptors are then extracted from the map using the Oriented FAST and Rotated BRIEF (ORB) feature extraction operator, which improves computational efficiency while maintaining sensitivity to local details. Finally, an efficient fault classification model is constructed using an Adaptive Boosting Support Vector Machine (Adaboost-SVM) to achieve robust fault mode recognition across multiple operating conditions. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed method achieves a fault diagnosis accuracy of 94.00%, outperforming signal-to-image techniques such as Gramian Angular Field (GAF), Recurrence Plot (RP), and Markov Transition Field (MTF), as well as deep learning models based on Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) in both training and testing time. Additionally, the method exhibits superior stability and robustness in repeated trials. This approach is well-suited for online monitoring and rapid diagnosis in resource-constrained environments, offering significant engineering value in enhancing the operational safety and reliability of excitation dry-type transformers.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baihetan Hydropower Plant, China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd., Liangshan 615400, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Mingtao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baihetan Hydropower Plant, China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd., Liangshan 615400, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jingang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4771-9456</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bao</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baihetan Hydropower Plant, China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd., Liangshan 615400, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zu</LastName><ForeName>Weiguo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baihetan Hydropower Plant, China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd., Liangshan 615400, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Yinglong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baihetan Hydropower Plant, China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd., Liangshan 615400, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Shiyi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baihetan Hydropower Plant, China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd., Liangshan 615400, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Lijiang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baihetan Hydropower Plant, China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd., Liangshan 615400, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Pengcheng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dou</LastName><ForeName>Jinyao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Z532402020</GrantID><Agency>China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ISDP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ORB</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitation dry-type transformer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fault diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-channel vibration signal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">three-axis feature aggregation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Yang Liu, Mingtao Yu, Peng Bao, Weiguo Zu, Yinglong Deng, Shiyi Chen and Lijiang Ma were employed by the company China Yangtze Power Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41471455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12736799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25247460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s25247460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>He D.S., Jia Z.D., Wang J.X., Fu J.B., He F., Dai F. Investigating temperature rise dynamics at hot-spots within dry-Type transformer windings: A comparative analysis across varied loading rates and an extrapolative computational model. Case Stud. Therm. Eng. 2024;60:104699. doi: 10.1016/j.csite.2024.104699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2024.104699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedghi M., Zolfaghari M., Mohseni A., Nosratian-Ahour J. Real-time transient stability estimation of power system considering nonlinear limiters of excitation system using deep machine learning: An actual case study in Iran. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 2024;127:107254. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virant-Doberlet M., Stritih-Peljhan N., &#x17d;uni&#x10d;-Kosi A., Polajnar J. Functional diversity of vibrational signaling systems in insects. Annu. Rev. Entomol. 2023;68:191&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1146/annurev-ento-120220-095459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-ento-120220-095459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36198397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Zhang F., Dang Y., Zhan C., Wang S., Ji S. A mechanical-electromagnetic coupling model of transformer windings and its application in the vibration-based condition monitoring. IEEE Trans. Power Deliv. 2023;38:2387&#x2013;2397. doi: 10.1109/TPWRD.2023.3242266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2023.3242266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan M., Zheng T., Gao Y., Wang G., Feng Z., Wang X. DGA-GNN: Dynamic Grouping Aggregation GNN for Fraud Detection. Proc. AAAI Conf. Artif. Intell. 2024;38:11820&#x2013;11828. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v38i10.29067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v38i10.29067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azmi P.A.R., Yusoff M., Sallehud-Din M.T.M. Improving Transformer Failure Classification on Imbalanced DGA Data Using Data-Level Techniques and Machine Learning. Energy Rep. 2025;13:264&#x2013;277. doi: 10.1016/j.egyr.2024.12.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2024.12.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mwinisin P., Mingotti A., Peretto L., Tinarelli R., Tefferi M. Electrical Diagnosis Techniques for Power Transformers: A Comprehensive Review of Methods, Instrumentation, and Research Challenges. Sensors. 2025;25:1968. doi: 10.3390/s25071968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25071968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11990981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40218480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattarai A., Adhikari A., Dhakal G., Silwal B. Partial Discharge Detection in Transformer Using Machine Learning; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE International Conference on Power System Technology (PowerCon); Kathmandu, Nepal. 4&#x2013;6 November 2024; New York, NY, USA: IEEE; 2024. pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tag A., Refaat S.S., Kameli S.M., Saleh M.A. Machine Learning Applications for Online Partial Discharge Detection, Classification, and Localization in Power Transformers: A Review; Proceedings of the 2024 4th International Conference on Smart Grid and Renewable Energy (SGRE); Doha, Qatar. 10 January 2024; New York, NY, USA: IEEE; 2024. pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeili Nezhad A., Samimi M.H. A Review of Vibration-Based Techniques for the Condition Assessment and Failure Detection of Transformers. J. Vib. Eng. Technol. 2025;13:95. doi: 10.1007/s42417-024-01616-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42417-024-01616-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., He Y., Xing Z., Wang L., Shao K., Lei L., Li Z. Vibration Signal-Based Fusion Residual Attention Model for Power Transformer Fault Diagnosis. IEEE Sens. J. 2024;24:17231&#x2013;17242. doi: 10.1109/JSEN.2024.3382811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2024.3382811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attallah O., Ibrahim R.A., Zakzouk N.E. A Lightweight Deep Learning Framework for Transformer Fault Diagnosis in Smart Grids Using Multiple Scale CNN Features. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:14505. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-96290-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-96290-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12032260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40281010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian Y., Wang J., Li Z., Liu W., Huang L., Jiang X. Residual Attention Guided Vision Transformer with Acoustic-Vibration Signal Feature Fusion for Cross-Domain Fault Diagnosis. Adv. Eng. Inform. 2025;64:103003. doi: 10.1016/j.aei.2024.103003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aei.2024.103003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Z., Yang M., Xiao J., Shen Z., Tang L., Wang J. Random vibration-based virtual fatigue test for large-scale welded structures using frequency-domain structural stress method and its application to traction transformers. Eng. Comput. 2023;40:836&#x2013;851. doi: 10.1108/EC-09-2022-0591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/EC-09-2022-0591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Li D., Chen L. Research and application of intelligent diagnosis method of mechanical fault based on transformer vibration and noise and BP neural network; Proceedings of the 2021 International Conference on Electrical Materials and Power Equipment (ICEMPE); Chongqing, China. 11&#x2013;15 April 2021; pp. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Ji S., Zhang Y., Wang S., Liu H. A novel vibration frequency response analysis method for mechanical condition detection of converter transformer windings. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 2023;71:8176&#x2013;8180. doi: 10.1109/TIE.2023.3301514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2023.3301514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao R., Zhang Z., Dan Y., Yang Y., Pan Z., Deng J. Multifeature extraction and semi-supervised deep learning scheme for state diagnosis of converter transformer. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2022;71:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2022.3168929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2022.3168929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong K., Jin M., Huang H. Transformer winding fault diagnosis using vibration image and deep learning. IEEE Trans. Power Deliv. 2020;36:676&#x2013;685. doi: 10.1109/TPWRD.2020.2988820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2020.2988820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Yu X., Xu W., Li W. Research on High-Frequency Modification Method of Industrial-Frequency Smelting Transformer Based on Parallel Connection of Multiple Windings. Energies. 2025;18:4196. doi: 10.3390/en18154196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18154196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He D.S., Jia Z.D., Yue Y.G., Wang J.X., Xiong L.R., Xia S., Fu J.B., He F.W. Simulation and experimental analysis of dynamic thermal rise relaxation characteristics for dry-type distribution transformer. Int. J. Emerg. Electr. Power Syst. 2025;26:419&#x2013;435. doi: 10.1515/ijeeps-2024-0106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ijeeps-2024-0106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eslamian M., Bigdeli M., Abu-Siada A. High frequency modeling of dry type detuned reactor for transient studies: Simulation and experimental analyses. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 2024;228:110102. doi: 10.1016/j.epsr.2023.110102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2023.110102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao C., Li Z., Wang J., Zhang J., Li Y., Wang Q. Research on Simulation Analysis and Joint Diagnosis Algorithm of Transformer Core-Loosening Faults Based on Vibration Characteristics. Energies. 2025;18:914. doi: 10.3390/en18040914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18040914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Zhao Y., Zhang J., Yang L., Liu X. Numerical Analysis of Flow-Induced Resonance in Pilot-Operated Molten Salt Control Valves. Energies. 2025;18:4631. doi: 10.3390/en18174631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18174631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#x119;drych M., Gorzkiewicz D., Deja M., Chodnicki M. Application of 3D scanning and computer simulation techniques to assess the shape accuracy of welded components. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2025;138:127&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1007/s00170-024-14498-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-024-14498-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behara R.K., Saha A.K. Comparative Performance Analysis of Deep Learning-Based Diagnostic and Predictive Models in Grid-Integrated Doubly Fed Induction Generator Wind Turbines. Energies. 2025;18:4725. doi: 10.3390/en18174725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18174725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borman R.I., Harjoko A. Improved ORB Algorithm Through Feature Point Optimization and Gaussian Pyramid. Int. J. Adv. Comput. Sci. Appl. 2024;15:268. doi: 10.14569/IJACSA.2024.0150228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14569/IJACSA.2024.0150228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q., Yao L., Xu L., Yang Y., Xu T., Yang Y., Liu Y. Horticultural image feature matching algorithm based on improved ORB and LK optical flow. Remote Sens. 2022;14:4465. doi: 10.3390/rs14184465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14184465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R., Anand R.S. Bearing fault diagnosis using multiple feature selection algorithms with SVM. Prog. Artif. Intell. 2024;13:119&#x2013;133. doi: 10.1007/s13748-024-00324-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13748-024-00324-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain S.S., Zaidi S.S.H. Adaboost ensemble approach with weak classifiers for gear fault diagnosis and prognosis in dc motors. Appl. Sci. 2024;14:3105. doi: 10.3390/app14073105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14073105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsky A.M., Greenland S. Causal directed acyclic graphs. JAMA. 2022;327:1083&#x2013;1084. doi: 10.1001/jama.2022.1816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.1816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35226050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X.T., Hu M., Wang C.R., Li D., Chen D.C., Ouyang C.L., Bai Y.Z., Qu S.B., Zhou Z.B. A method for high-precision measuring differential transformer asymmetry. Rev. Sci. Instrum. 2023;94:065006. doi: 10.1063/5.0138361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0138361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37862499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H., Wang Y., Zhou Z., Xu J. Design and simulation of micro piezoelectric fiber triaxial acceleration sensor. J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 2023;2483:012031. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/2483/1/012031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/2483/1/012031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Industrial Communication Networks&#x2014;Fieldbus Specifications&#x2014;Part 2: Physical Layer Specification and Service Definition. International Electrotechnical Commission; Geneva, Switzerland: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isari A.A., Ghaffarkhah A., Hashemi S.A., Wuttke S., Arjmand M. Structural design for EMI shielding: From underlying mechanisms to common pitfalls. Adv. Mater. 2024;36:2310683. doi: 10.1002/adma.202310683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202310683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38467559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang T., Zhang Q., Zhang J., Wei X. Variational multi-harmonic duality mode pursuit method for extracting repetitive transient components from vibration signals. Measurement. 2024;225:113987. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2023.113987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2023.113987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W., Zhang Y., Yu K., Huang C., Zhu P., Wu Q., Hao J. Hybrid DWT NLM method with NOA optimization for ECG signal denoising. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:24258. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-09663-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-09663-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12234893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40624068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L., Wen J., Yang Y., Chen L., Shen G. A Visual Fault Detection Method for Induction Motors Based on a Zero-Sequence Current and an Improved Symmetrized Dot Pattern. Entropy. 2022;24:614. doi: 10.3390/e24050614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e24050614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9141730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35626499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Xu H., Zhang Y., Qi Z., Wang D. GAF-MAE: A self-supervised automatic modulation classification method based on Gramian angular field and masked autoencoder. IEEE Trans. Cogn. Commun. Netw. 2023;10:94&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1109/TCCN.2023.3318414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCCN.2023.3318414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Wang W., Zhang X., Iu H.H.C. A new fault diagnosis of rolling bearing based on Markov transition field and CNN. Entropy. 2022;24:751. doi: 10.3390/e24060751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e24060751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9221820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35741472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Xia L., Shi J., Zhang L., Bai L., Wang S. A fault diagnosis method of rolling bearing based on improved recurrence plot and convolutional neural network. IEEE Sens. J. 2023;23:10767&#x2013;10775. doi: 10.1109/JSEN.2023.3265409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2023.3265409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>