<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41807311</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3724</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of sport medicine : official journal of the Canadian Academy of Sport Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Sport Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of the sBESS, a Pragmatic Dual-Task Balance Test in Adolescents With Acute Concussion.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001435</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Develop a clinically pragmatic dual-task balance test to identify balance problems in acutely concussed adolescents more accurately than the current standard.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Observational cohort study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Pediatric emergency department.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Adolescents aged 10 to 18 years with acute (&lt;48 hours) concussion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INDEPENDENT VARIABLES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Single tasks: balance (mBESS errors); cognitive function (Oral Trail-Making Test-B [OTMT-B] completion rate and accuracy); vestibular-oculomotor function (gaze stabilization test); and symptom change (pre-/post-test numeric pain rating scale). Dual tasks: (1) balance + cognitive function; (2) balance + vestibular-oculomotor function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Primary outcome was change in center-of-pressure (COP) on a force plate (95% ellipse sway area), during single and dual tasks. We evaluated associations between clinical outcomes and gold-standard COP sway area using Spearman correlation coefficients and P-values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eighty-three adolescents (median [IQR] age = 12.86 [11.52-15.41 years; 62.65% male; median [IQR] time from injury = 3.03 [2.08-13.37] hours) were included. Balance errors during dual-task gaze stabilization with tandem stance correlated more strongly with sway area (rs = 0.77, P &lt; 0.001) than with mBESS balance errors (double-leg stance, rs = 0.44, P &lt; 0.001; tandem stance, rs = 0.58, P &lt; 0.001; single-leg stance, rs = 0.39, P &lt; 0.001). Cognitive dual task (OTMT-B completion rate) was associated with fewer balance errors and decreased sway area in tandem stance (rs = -0.28, P = 0.02) and single-leg stance (rs = -0.21, P = 0.07). Pre-/post-test symptom change was not associated with sway area.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Dual-task gaze stabilization with tandem stance ("sharpened BESS" [sBESS]) is a new vestibular dual task that is more strongly associated with gold-standard balance performance in concussed adolescents than mBESS. Diagnostic and prognostic accuracy studies are needed to determine the clinical utility of sBESS to inform concussion diagnosis and return to sport decisions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Ierssel</LastName><ForeName>Jacqueline</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5519-8526</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Webster</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayawi</LastName><ForeName>Lamia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ledoux</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;e-Anne</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular Molecular Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Howell</LastName><ForeName>David R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine Center, Children's Hospital Colorado, Aurora, Colorado.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, University of Colorado School of Medicine, Aurora, Colorado; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zemek</LastName><ForeName>Roger</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Emergency Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ONntario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>459145</GrantID><Acronym>CAPMC</Acronym><Agency> CIHR</Agency><Country>Canada</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RFP 2019-20</GrantID><Agency>University of Ottawa Brain and Mind Post Concussion Research Group</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Sport Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9103300</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1050-642X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">center of pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual task</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vestibulo-ocular reflex</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41807311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000001435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042752-990000000-00390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>DePadilla L, Miller GF, Jones SE, et al. Self-reported concussions from playing a sport or being physically active among high school students&#x2014;United States, 2017. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2018;67:682&#x2013;685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Schneider KJ, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport: the 6th International Conference on Concussion in Sport-Amsterdam, October 2022. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:695&#x2013;711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guskiewicz KM, McCrea M, Marshall SW, et al. Cumulative effects associated with recurrent concussion in collegiate football players: the NCAA Concussion Study. JAMA. 2003;290:2549&#x2013;2555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherson AL, Nagai T, Webster KE, et al. Musculoskeletal injury risk after sport-related concussion: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47:1754&#x2013;1762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleiner M, Wong L, Dub&#xe9; A, et al. Dual-task assessment protocols in concussion assessment: a systematic literature review. J orthopaedic Sports Phys Ther. 2018;48:87&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochefort C, Walters-Stewart C, Aglipay M, et al. Balance markers in adolescents at 1 month postconcussion. Orthop J Sports Med. 2017;5:2325967117695507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider KJ, Meeuwisse WH, Nettel-Aguirre A, et al. Cervicovestibular rehabilitation in sport-related concussion: a randomised controlled trial. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1294&#x2013;1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledoux AA, Tang K, Yeates KO, et al. Natural progression of symptom change and recovery from concussion in a pediatric population. JAMA Pediatr. 2019;173:e183820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, et al. STROBE Initiative. Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. BMJ. 2007 Oct 20;335(7624):806-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osmond MH, Legace E, Gill PJ, et al. Partnering with patients, caregivers, and Clinicians to determine research priorities for concussion. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:e2316383&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed N, Zemek R, Dawson J, et al. Living guideline for pediatric concussion care. www.pedsconcussion.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrory P, Meeuwisse W, Dvorak J, et al. Consensus statement on concussion in sport&#x2014;the 5th international conference on concussion in sport held in Berlin, October 2016. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:838&#x2013;847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayr LK, Yeates KO, Taylor HG, et al. Dimensions of postconcussive symptoms in children with mild traumatic brain injuries. J Int Neuropsychol Soc. 2009;15:19&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabricant PD, Robles A, Downey-Zayas T, et al. Development and validation of a pediatric sports activity rating scale: the hospital for special surgery pediatric functional activity brief scale (HSS Pedi-FABS). Am J Sports Med. 2013;41:2421&#x2013;2429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langevin P, Fr&#xe9;mont P, Fait P, et al. Responsiveness of the post-concussion symptom scale to monitor clinical recovery after concussion or mild traumatic brain injury. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10:23259671221127049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrazik M, Millis S, Drane DL. The oral trail making test: effects of age and concurrent validity. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2010;25:236&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucha A, Collins MW, Elbin RJ, et al. A brief vestibular/ocular motor screening (VOMS) assessment to evaluate concussions: preliminary findings. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2479&#x2013;2486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guskiewicz KM, Ross SE, Marshall SW. Postural stability and neuropsychological deficits after concussion in collegiate athletes. J Athl Train. 2001;36:263&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan DP, Lafave MR, Katz L. Intra-rater and inter-rater reliability of the balance error scoring system in pre-adolescent school children. Meas Phys Educ Exerc Sci. 2011;15:234&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quatman-Yates C, Hugentobler J, Ammon R, et al. The utility of the balance error scoring system for mild brain injury assessments in children and adolescents. Phys Sportsmed. 2014;42:32&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor SM, Baweja HS, Goble DJ. Validating the BTrackS balance plate as a low cost alternative for the measurement of sway-induced center of pressure. J Biomech. 2016;49:4142&#x2013;4145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris P, Taylor R, Thielke R, et al. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)&#x2014;a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42:377&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babl FE, Dionisio D, Davenport L, et al. Accuracy of components of SCAT to identify children with concussion. Pediatrics. 2017;140:e20163258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober P, Boer C, Schwarte LA. Correlation Coefficients: Appropriate Use and Interpretation. Anesth Analg. 2018 May;126(5):1763-1768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: a language and environment for statistical computing; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis G, Anderson V, Babl F, et al. What is the difference in concussion management in children as compared with adults? A systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:949&#x2013;957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen EO, Howell DR, Stracciolini A, et al. Examination of age-related differences on clinical tests of postural stability. Sports Health. 2016;8:244&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemek R, Barrowman N, Freedman S, et al. Clinical risk score for persistent postconcussion symptoms among children with acute concussion in the ED. JAMA. 2016;315:1014&#x2013;1025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell DR, Zemek R, Brilliant AN, et al. Identifying persistent postconcussion symptom risk in a pediatric sports medicine clinic. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46:3254&#x2013;3261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peusner KD, Shao M, Reddaway R, et al. Basic concepts in understanding recovery of function in vestibular reflex networks during vestibular compensation. Front Neurol. 2012;3:17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anzalone AJ, Blueitt D, Case T, et al. A positive vestibular/ocular motor screening (VOMS) is associated with increased recovery time after sports-related concussion in youth and adolescent athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2017;45:474&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knell G, Caze T, Burkhart SO. Evaluation of the vestibular and ocular motor screening (VOMS) as a prognostic tool for protracted recovery following paediatric sports-related concussion. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2021;7:e000970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corwin DJ, Wiebe DJ, Zonfrillo MR, et al. Vestibular deficits following youth concussion. J Pediatr. 2015;166:1221&#x2013;1225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resch JE, May B, Tomporowski PD, et al. Balance performance with a cognitive task. J athletic Train. 2011;46:170&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis GA, Echemendia RJ, Ahmed OH, et al. Introducing the Child Sport Concussion Assessment Tool 6 (Child SCAT6). Br J Sports Med 2023;11:632&#x2013;635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echemendia RJ, Brett BL, Broglio S, et al. Introducing the sport concussion assessment tool 6 (SCAT6). Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:619&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubert MC, Migliaccio AA. New advances regarding adaptation of the vestibulo-ocular reflex. J Neurophysiol. 2019;122:644&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Ierssel J, Osmond M, Hamid J, et al. What is the risk of recurrent concussion in children and adolescents aged 5-18 years? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55:663&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patricios JS, Schneider GM, van Ierssel J, et al. Beyond acute concussion assessment to office management: a systematic review informing the development of a Sport Concussion Office Assessment Tool (SCOAT6) for adults and children. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:737&#x2013;748.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>