<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41794992</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interfacial engineering of aluminum powder with a tannic acid/Fe&#xb3;&#x207a; complex and fluorosilane for high-performance energetic composites.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43316-y</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Technology, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gou</LastName><ForeName>Xiaodong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Technology, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yingjun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>601 Institute, The Six Academy of China Aerospace Science and Industry Corporation, Hohhot, 010076, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Jiahao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Technology, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Shi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Technology, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Xueyong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Technology, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Jianxin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Technology, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, 100081, China. niejx@bit.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22175026</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aluminum powder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ammonium perchlorate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">combustion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual core-shell structure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interface performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41794992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43316-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43316-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Trache, D., Maggi, F., Palmucci, I. &amp; DeLuca, L. T. Thermal behavior and decomposition kinetics of composite solid propellants in the presence of amide burning rate suppressants. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 132, 1601&#x2013;1615 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, J., Liu, J., Zhou, Y., Zhang, Y. &amp; Cen, K. Thermal decomposition and combustion characteristics of Al/AP/HTPB propellant. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 143, 3935&#x2013;3944 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang, D. L., Rong, J. L. &amp; He, X. Detonation performance of four groups of aluminized explosives. Cent. Eur. J. Energ. Mater. 13 (4), 903&#x2013;915 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, K. K., Gottfried, J. L., Walck, S. D., Pantoya, M. L. &amp; Wu, C. C. Plasma surface treatment of aluminum nanoparticles for energetic material applications. Combust. Flame. 206, 211&#x2013;213 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. et al. Incorporation of high explosives into nano-aluminum based microspheres to improve reactivity. Chem. Eng. J. 383, 123110 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young, G., Wang, H. &amp; Zachariah, M. R. Application of nano-aluminum/nitrocellulose mesoparticles in composite solid rocket propellants. Propellants, Explos., Pyrotech. 40 (3), 413&#x2013;418 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, W. et al. Mussel-inspired polydopamine-directed crystal growth of core-shell n-Al@PDA@CuO metastable intermixed composites. Chem. Eng. J. 369, 1093&#x2013;1101 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, W. et al. Yan, Energetic metastable n-Al@PVDF/EMOF composite nanofibers with improved combustion performances. Chem. Eng. J. 383, 123146 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaurav, M. &amp; Ramakrishna, P. Effect of mechanical activation of high specific surface area aluminium with PTFE on composite solid propellant. Combust. Flame. 166, 203&#x2013;215 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckstead, M. W., Liang, Y. &amp; Pudduppakkam, K. Numerical simulation of single aluminum particle combustion. Combust. Explosion Shock Waves. 41, 622&#x2013;638 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, T., Ren, H., Li, Y., Wang, H. &amp; Jiao, Q. Tailoring structural energetics for enhanced reactivity of nano-Aluminum particles based microspheres. Adv. Eng. Mater. 21 (8), 1900176 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLuca, L. et al. Microstructure effects in aluminized solid rocket propellants. J. Propul. Power. 26 (4), 724&#x2013;732 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLisio, J. B. et al. Probing the reaction mechanism of aluminum/poly (vinylidene fluoride) composites. J. Phys. Chem. B. 120 (24), 5534&#x2013;5542 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, P. et al. Preparation and characterization of n-Al/FeF<sub>3</sub> nanothermite. Chem. Eng. J. 331, 850&#x2013;855 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padhye, R., Aquino, A. J., Tunega, D. &amp; Pantoya, M. L. Fluorination of an alumina surface: modeling aluminum&#x2013;fluorine reaction mechanisms. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 9 (28), 24290&#x2013;24297 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, W. et al. Tuning the reactivity of metastable intermixed composite n-Al/PTFE by polydopamine interfacial control. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 10 (38), 32849&#x2013;32858 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Core&#x2013;Shell Al-Polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) Configurations to Enhance Reaction Kinetics and Energy Performance for Nanoenergetic Materials. Chemistry&#x2013;A Eur. J. 22 (1), 279&#x2013;284 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Li, J., Wang, B., Ma, H. &amp; Han, Z. An approach to the induced reaction mechanism of the combustion of the nano-Al/PVDF composite particles. Surf. Coat. Technol. 429, 127912 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Direct writing of a 90 wt% particle loading nanothermite. Adv. Mater. 31 (23), 1806575 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, X. et al. Safe preparation, energetic performance and reaction mechanism of corrosion-resistant Al/PVDF nanocomposite films. J. Mater. Chem. A. 6 (36), 17713&#x2013;17723 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Architecture can significantly alter the energy release rate from nanocomposite energetics. ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 1 (5), 982&#x2013;989 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Qu, Y., Gong, F., Shen, J. &amp; Zhang, L. A promising strategy to obtain high energy output and combustion properties by self-activation of nano-Al. Combust. Flame. 204, 220&#x2013;226 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke, X. et al. Superhydrophobic fluorine-containing protective coating to endow Al nanoparticles with long&#x2010;term storage stability and self&#x2010;activation reaction capability. Adv. Mater. Interfaces. 6 (19), 1901025 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou, Y., Jiao, Q., Li, N., Yan, S. &amp; Yang, R. Pyrolysis of ammonium perfluorooctanoate (APFO) and its interaction with nano-aluminum. Chem. Eng. J. 403, 126367 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sippel, T. R., Son, S. F. &amp; Groven, L. J. Aluminum agglomeration reduction in a composite propellant using tailored Al/PTFE particles. Combust. Flame. 161 (1), 311&#x2013;321 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valluri, S. K., Schoenitz, M. &amp; Dreizin, E. L. Metal-rich aluminum-polytetrafluoroethylene reactive composite powders prepared by mechanical milling at different temperatures. J. Mater. Sci. 52, 7452&#x2013;7465 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi, P. M., Das, S., Schoenitz, M. &amp; Dreizin, E. L. Aluminum powders with modified morphology and enhanced reactivity prepared by emulsion-assisted milling. Combust. Flame. 275, 114116 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, N. et al. Well-dispersed ultrafine Mn3O4 nanoparticles on graphene as a promising catalyst for the thermal decomposition of ammonium perchlorate. Carbon 54, 124&#x2013;132 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salunkhe, R. R. et al. Asymmetric supercapacitors using 3D nanoporous carbon and cobalt oxide electrodes synthesized from a single metal&#x2013;organic framework. ACS nano. 9 (6), 6288&#x2013;6296 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan, G. et al. The catalytic effect of nanosized MgO on the decomposition of ammonium perchlorate. Powder Technol. 172 (1), 27&#x2013;29 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. et al. Thermal decomposition of ammonium perchlorate over perovskite catalysts: Catalytic decomposition behavior, mechanism and application. Appl. Surf. Sci. 513, 145849 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou, X. et al. Electrochemical Synthesis of the Energetic Combustion Catalyst Co (BODN)&#xb7;9H<sub>2</sub>O and Its Catalytic Effect on Ammonium Perchlorate Thermal Decomposition. Langmuir 39 (48), 17498&#x2013;17512 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou, X. et al. Preparation of AP@ ZIF-7 composite materials by chemical precipitation method: A good strategy for simultaneously improving its thermal performance, energy property and moisture absorption. Powder Technol. 433, 119230 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou, X. et al. Enhanced thermal, safety and anti-hygroscopicity performance of core-shell ammonium perchlorate with a double coating layer. Dalton Trans. 52 (46), 17324&#x2013;17339 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaodong, G. et al. In-situ synthesis of AP@Co/BIM composites with improved thermal performance and anti-hygroscopicity. Mater. Chem. Phys. 309, 128347 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, T. et al. Study on interaction between propargyl-terminated polybutadiene and plasticizers based on simulation and experiments. J. Phys. Chem. A. 123 (29), 6370&#x2013;6377 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, J., Wang, B., Chen, Y., Fu, J. &amp; Tian, X. -y. Ye, Molecular dynamics simulation of CL-20/DNDAP cocrystal-based PBXs. J. Mol. Model. 29 (7), 199 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Q. et al. Effects of fluorine-based modification on triboelectric properties of cellulose. Polymers 14 (17), 3536 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, J. et al. Engineering multifunctional capsules through the assembly of metal&#x2013;phenolic networks. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 53 (22), 5546&#x2013;5551 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie, S. et al. Enhanced performance of a cellulose nanofibrils-based triboelectric nanogenerator by tuning the surface polarizability and hydrophobicity. Chem. Eng. J. 404, 126512 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, F. et al. Enhanced combustion performance of core-shell aluminum with poly (vinylidene fluoride) interfacial layer: Constructing the combination bridge of aluminum powder and poly (vinylidene fluoride). Surf. Coat. Technol. 439, 128410 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. et al. Sponge-like Al/PVDF films with laser sensitivity and high combustion performance prepared by rapid phase inversion. Chem. Eng. J. 396, 124962 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostoglou, N. et al. Novel combustion synthesis of carbon foam&#x2013;aluminum fluoride nanocomposite materials. Mater. Design. 144, 222&#x2013;228 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, L., Liu, J., Jiao, Q., Nie, X. &amp; Ren, H. Enhance thermal response behavior of energetic composite by doping fluorinated graphene. Combust. Flame. 265, 113484 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>