<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41850016</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-2782</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>200</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neural networks : the official journal of the International Neural Network Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neural Netw</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>VISTA-3D : Training-free unfolding for vision-based 3D object detection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108790</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108790</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neunet.2026.108790</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0893-6080(26)00252-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>3D object detection from vision inputs powers autonomous driving and embodied AI but remains compute- and energy-intensive at inference. While neuromorphic (spike-driven) computation promises event-driven sparsity and efficiency, prior training-free conversions have largely focused on 2D tasks. They are not directly applicable to modern 3D detectors due to normalization-dependent inconsistencies. We present VISTA-3D, a training-free unfolding method for vision-based 3D object detection. The approach replaces all LayerNorm blocks with a calibrated Exponential Normalization (ExpNorm) and emits incremental temporal updates whose sum matches the one-shot ANN output, producing a temporally unfolded representation suitable for spike-style execution. On the KITTI benchmark, VISTA-3D preserves the original detector's accuracy, achieving the same 3D Average Precision under the standard R40 evaluation protocol for both the monocular and depth-augmented variants. Experiments on nuScenes further show that the unfolding mechanism generalizes to larger transformer-based detectors, maintaining competitive accuracy while enabling sparse spike-style computation. VISTA-3D reduces analytic latency and achieves a normalized SOP-based energy proxy of approximately 0.17, without introducing new parameters. A controlled ablation confirms that directly enabling test-time spiking without replacing LayerNorm severely degrades performance, whereas our calibrated unfolding preserves accuracy robustly. VISTA-3D provides a principled, plug-and-play route toward neuromorphic-ready 3D perception, offering a stable temporal representation that may serve as a basis for future fully spiking 3D detectors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China FAW Corporation Limited, Changchun, 130011, China; College of Communication Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun, 130012, China. Electronic address: dongxiaoyu5@faw.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Communication Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun, 130012, China. Electronic address: fangxu@jlu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lyu</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China FAW Corporation Limited, Changchun, 130011, China. Electronic address: lvying@faw.com.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Multimedia Information Processing, School of Computer Science, Peking University, Beijing, China. Electronic address: ruizhao26@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Yajing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Multimedia Information Processing, School of Computer Science, Peking University, Beijing, China. Electronic address: zyj061@pku.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neural Netw</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8805018</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0893-6080</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">3D object detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LayerNorm approximation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromorphic computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spike-inspired temporal unfolding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training-free conversion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vision-based perception</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Xiaoyu Dong reports financial support was provided by China FAW Corporation Limited. Fang Xu reports a relationship with Jilin University that includes: employment. Yajing Zheng reports a relationship with Peking University that includes: employment. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41850016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neunet.2026.108790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0893-6080(26)00252-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>