<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41722593</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-4465</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet. Neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A path to preventing cognitive impairment due to Alzheimer's disease: initiatives beginning in the USA.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>268</StartPage><EndPage>278</EndPage><MedlinePgn>268-278</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S1474-4422(25)00483-1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1474-4422(25)00483-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Antibody therapies can remove amyloid plaques from the brain and slow cognitive decline in people with Alzheimer's disease who are mildly impaired. These drugs are now being evaluated in participants who are cognitively unimpaired but positive for a biomarker of Alzheimer's disease for their safety, tolerability, disease-modifying and cognitive preserving effects, and ability to avert the onset of cognitive impairment. If these studies are successful, and the drugs get regulatory approval, they could accelerate the evaluation and approval of related Alzheimer's disease-modifying treatments in people who are unimpaired with or without a biomarker of the disease. Preclinical Alzheimer's disease therapies that modify the underlying disease in people who are unimpaired with a biomarker of Alzheimer's disease and primary prevention therapies that avert the onset of amyloid plaques in those with a negative test have the potential to substantially prevent ensuing biological and clinical manifestations of Alzheimer's disease. In this Policy View, we assess the challenges and opportunities that trials of these drug treatments will bring, and consider the blood tests, cognitive assessments, and post-marketing strategies needed to enable the approval, affordability, health-care insurance coverage, and equitable use. Our recommendations are intended for consideration in the USA, and relevant refinement in other countries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reiman</LastName><ForeName>Eric M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Banner Alzheimer's Institute, Phoenix, AZ, USA. Electronic address: eric.reiman@bannerhealth.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexander</LastName><ForeName>Robert C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Banner Alzheimer's Institute, Phoenix, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langbaum</LastName><ForeName>Jessica B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Banner Alzheimer's Institute, Phoenix, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aisen</LastName><ForeName>Paul S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alzheimer's Therapeutic Research Institute, Keck School of Medicine, University of Southern California, San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashton</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Banner Sun Health Research Institute, Sun City, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atri</LastName><ForeName>Alireza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Banner Sun Health Research Institute, Sun City, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbarino</LastName><ForeName>Paola</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alzheimer's Disease International, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Byrd</LastName><ForeName>Goldie S</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Sciences and Health Policy, Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feldman</LastName><ForeName>Howard H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosciences, University of California San Diego; Alzheimer's Disease Cooperative Study, La Jolla, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fowler</LastName><ForeName>Nicole R</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Medicine and Neurology, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghisays</LastName><ForeName>Valentina</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Banner Alzheimer's Institute, Phoenix, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grill</LastName><ForeName>Joshua D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Memory Impairments and Neurological Disorders, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hassenstab</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University in St. Louis, St Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heaton</LastName><ForeName>George R</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Durham, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herring</LastName><ForeName>William L</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RTI Health Solutions, Research Triangle Park, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jack</LastName><ForeName>Clifford R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Sterling C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wisconsin Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karlawish</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keach</LastName><ForeName>Nancy L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BrightFocus Foundation, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kivipelto</LastName><ForeName>Miia</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Geriatrics, Center for Alzheimer Research, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krumholz</LastName><ForeName>Harlan M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Infection and Immunity, Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, USA; Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation, Yale New Haven Hospital, New Haven, CT, USA; Section of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, USA; Department of Health Policy and Management, Yale School of Public Health, New Haven, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Largent</LastName><ForeName>Emily A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Ethics and Health Policy, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MaGee-Rodgers</LastName><ForeName>Tamiko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Alzheimer's Platform Foundation, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDade</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University in St. Louis, St Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mielke</LastName><ForeName>Michelle M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Prevention, Division of Public Health Sciences, Wake Forest University School of Medicine, Winston-Salem, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molina-Henry</LastName><ForeName>Doris</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alzheimer's Therapeutic Research Institute, Keck School of Medicine, University of Southern California, San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petersen</LastName><ForeName>Ronald C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rabinovici</LastName><ForeName>Gil D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Radiology, and Biomedical Imaging, Psychiatry and Neurology, University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ritchie</LastName><ForeName>Craig</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scottish Brain Sciences, Edinburgh, UK; Medical School, University of St Andrews, St Andrews, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schindler</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Washington University in St. Louis, St Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sperling</LastName><ForeName>Reisa A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brigham and Women's, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su&#xe1;rez-Calvet</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barcelona&#x3b2;eta Brain Research Center, Pasqual Maragall Foundation, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vradenburg</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UsAgainstAlzheimer's and Davos Alzheimer's Collaborative, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiner</LastName><ForeName>Michael W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Radiology, and Biomedical Imaging, Psychiatry and Neurology, University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Welsh-Bohmer</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Duke University Medical Center, Durham, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zetterberg</LastName><ForeName>Henrik</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Neurochemistry, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, M&#xf6;lndal, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuendel</LastName><ForeName>Michael T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Initiative to Change the D Word, Telluride, CO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattke</LastName><ForeName>Soeren</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The USC Brain Health Observatory, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cummings</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chambers-Grundy Center for Transformative Neuroscience, Department of Brain Health, Kirk Kerkorian School of Medicine, University of Nevada Las Vegas, Las Vegas, NV, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101139309</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1474-4422</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests EMR reports his institution received support for this Policy View from the JTMF Foundation, GHR Foundation, Banner Alzheimer's Foundation, and Arizona Department of Health Services (AZ DHS); reports institutional grants or contracts with the following entities: National Institutes of Health (NIH) Grants R01 AG058468, R01 AG086363, R01 AG055444, P30 AG072980, P30 AG019620, R01 AG069453, R01 NS 139383, OT2 D026549, OT2 OD037642, T2 HL161847, P01 AG052350, R01 AG070883, RF1 AG073424, U24 AG072122, and R01AG05467; JTMF Foundation; GHR Foundation; NOMIS Foundation; Banner Alzheimer's Foundation; Gates Ventures; and AZ DHS; reports consulting fees and/or stock options for serving as a scientific advisor to Alzheon, Beren Therapeutics, Cognition Therapeutics, Denali, Enigma, Jocasta Neuroscience, Retromer Therapeutics, and Vaxxinity; reports being the inventor of a 2005 patent issued to Banner Health for using biomarker endpoints to accelerate the evaluation Alzheimer's prevention therapies in people who are cognitively unimpaired at genetic or biomarker risk, which will not be deployed; reports serving as Board Chairman of the Flinn Foundation and the Arizona Alzheimer's Consortium; and reports having stock shares as a cofounder of ALZPath, maker of a capture antibody which has been licensed to several diagnostics companies for the performance of plasma p-tau217 assays. RCA reports that his institution received financial support for the present manuscript from the JTMF Foundation, GHR Foundation, Banner Alzheimer's Foundation, and AZ DHS; is supported by grants R01AG058468, R01AG055444, and R01 AG074983 from the National Institute on Aging (NIA); reports institutional grants or contracts from Eli Lilly and Roche; reports receiving consulting fees from Lundbeck, Vigil Neurosciences, and Novartis; reports serving as a member of the data safety monitoring board for ImmunoBrain study IBC-01&#x2013;01; and reports being a minor shareholder of Eli Lilly. JBL reports that her institution received financial support for this Policy View from the JTMF Foundation, GHR Foundation, Banner Alzheimer's Foundation, and AZ DHS; is supported by grants R01AG086363, R01AG069453, R01AG063954, R01AG058468, R33AG070604, and P30AG072980; reports institutional grants or contracts from Eli Lilly and Roche; and has received consulting fees from Biogen and Denovo Biopharma. PSA reports grants or contracts from the NIH, Alzheimer's Association, and Eli Lilly; and reports consulting fees from Merck, Roche, Genentech, AbbVie, Biogen, Checkpoint, Immunobrain, and Arrowhead. NA reports consulting fees from Athria, ImaginationLand, MapLight Therapeutics, SpearBio, Neurogen Biomarking, Quanterix, TauRx, Eli Lilly, Roche, Beckman Coulter, Janssen, and AbbVie; reports payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from Alamar Biosciences, Biogen, Eli Lilly, Quanterix, and VJDementia; reports patent application PCT/US2024/037834 (WSGR Docket No 58484&#x2013;709&#xb7;601); and reports participation on an Advisory Board for Biogen and TauRx. AA reports grants or contracts from University of Southern California, Indiana University, Johns Hopkins (site principal investigator for collaborative clinical trials sponsored or co-sponsored by Universities), Washington University St. Louis (project arm leader for international clinical trial), Gates Ventures and Michael J Fox Foundation (MJJF; grant from Foundation), AZ DHS, National Institute of Aging (NIA)/NIH (grants from state or federal agency), Foundation for NIH (principal investigator for Single Site Biomarker [SV2A-PET] study funded by FNIH), Alzheon, Athira, Biogen (Site principal investigator for biopharma-sponsored clinical trials at institution), Biohaven (with ADCS), Eisai (with ATRI/ACTC), Eli Lilly (with ATRI/ACTC), Vivoryon (with ADCS), Cognition Therapeutics (with ATRI/ACTC; site principal investigator for biopharma-AD academic consortium [ADCS, ACTC, and ATRI] collaborative sponsored clinical trials at institution), ACTC, ADCS, AZ Alzheimer's Research Consortium, and AZ DHS, ATRI, and GAP (site principal investigator for clinical trials sponsored or cosponsored or grants from Academic Research Consortia or Institutes); reports royalties or licenses from Oxford University Press for a book on dementia; reports past/completed consulting fees from Lundbeck, Prothena, Acadia, Axsome, Biogen, Lantheus, Qynapse, Merck, ONO, AriBio, and Johnson &amp; Johnson and current consulting fees from Novo Nordisk, Eisai, and Life Molecular Imaging; reports past/completed payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, or educational events from Acadia, Biogen, Eisai, and Lundbeck; and reports receiving support for attending meetings and/or travel from the Alzheimer's Association (US), Alzheimer's Disease International (ADI), American Academy of Neurology (AAN), American Heart Association (AHA), and MJJF only for workgroup, symposium, summit or consulting meetings, and scientific/medical presentations or educational programmes. PB reports she is the CEO of ADI, which receives grants from or has contracts with a variety of for-profit companies and non-profit organisations, including the following: Eli Lilly, Novo Nordisk, Helen Bader Fund, a Bader philanthropy, Biogen, Bristol Meyers Squibb (BMS), Eisai, JD Power, London School of Economics, Otsuka, Parexel, Diane and Dan Riccio, Roche, Mary Oakley Foundation, AbbVie, Acumen Pharmaceuticals, AC Immune, Acadia Pharmaceuticals, Alector, Care UK, C2N Diagnostics, GE Healthcare, GT Diagnostics, Home Instead, IFPMA, Life Molecular Imaging, Lundbeck, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis International, Danone Nutricia Advanced Medical Nutrition, PhRMA, Phastar, Prothena, Re: Cognition Health, Skylight Frame, Tunstall, ZiMAd, and de Mol van Otterloo Family foundation&#x2014;all payments from these entities have been made to the charity and not to her; reports that her institution has received modest honoraria for presentations or participation in meetings from the following: Istituto Superiore di Sanit&#xe0;, Italy, Ministry of Health, Malta, HGPI, Japan, Government of South Korea, Government of Taiwan, Eli Lilly, Roche, Novo Nordisk, and TauRx; reports support for travel has also been provided from these entities, either in-kind or reimbursed to the charity; and reports serving as a member of World Dementia Council, in an unpaid role. HHF reports payment to his institution by Banner Health for travel related expenses to participate in conference on the prevention of Alzheimer's disease in February, 2025; reports grant funding to his institution from Allyx Therapeutics, Vivoryon (Probiodrug), NIA/NIH (U19 AG079774&#x2013;01, R01 AG061146, R01 AG076634&#x2013;01, and P30 AG062429), and Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CNA-137794 and 363926); reports royalties for Detecting and Treating Dementia Serial Number 12/3&#x2013;2691 US Patent No PCT/US2007/07008; holds service agreements through his institution for consulting with LuMind Foundation, Novo Nordisk, Axon Neuroscience, Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals, and Biosplice Therapeutics; reports his institution receives travel expenses from Novo Nordisk, Royal Society of Canada, Translating Research in Elder Care, Association for Frontotemporal Dementia, Rainwater Charitable Foundation, and University of British Columbia; reports participating on a data safety monitoring board for Janssen Research &amp; Development and on a scientific advisory board for the Tau Consortium through service agreements through his institution; and reports receiving philanthropic support for Alzheimer therapeutic research from Epstein Family Alzheimer's Research Collaboration. NRF reports her institution has received grants or contracts from the NIH. JDG reports receiving grants or contracts from the NIA, Alzheimer's Association, BrightFocus Foundation, Eli Lilly, Genentech, Biogen, and Eisai; and reports receiving payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from the NIA and financial support for attending meetings and/or travel from the Alzheimer's Association. JH reports receiving consulting fees from Quanterix, Prothena, AbbVie, and AlzPath; and reports serving as data safety monitoring board chair for Caring Bridge (NIH), and WALLe (NIH). WLH is a full-time employee of RTI Health Solutions, a not-for-profit research consultancy that receives research funding through contracts with pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies&#x2014;his compensation is unrelated to the studies on which he works, and RTI Health Solutions did not receive any funding specific to this study; is affiliated to research with the Karolinska Institute but does not receive any compensation from this affiliation; and reports receiving financial support for travel and accommodations for the Alzheimer's Prevention Symposium in Arlington, VA, in February, 2025, as provided by the symposium organisers. CRJ reports institutional grants or contracts from the National Institutes of Health; and reports serving on the data safety monitoring board for Roche pro bono. SCJ reports his institution has received grants from the NIA (AG027161 and AG021155); reports receiving consulting fees from Merck, Eli Lilly, and Enigma Biomedical; and reports serving as an unpaid consultant for Alzpath. JK reports his institution received grants or contracts from the NIA (R21-AG-069805, U24-AG-057437, R01-AG-054029, R01-AG-063689, R01-AG-061848, R01-AG-058468, P30-AG-064105, R01-AG-063954, RF1-AG-069922, R01-AG-070885, P30-AG-073105, R01-AG-077111, R01-AG-081698, R21-AG-074371, P30-AG-010124, R01-AG-057501, R01-AG-070944, R21-AG-062679, RF1-AG-047866, U2C-AG-054397, U54-AG-063546; P30-AG-072979; U19-AG-024904; and R01-AG-078457), and from Pennsylvania Department of Public Health (2019NF4100087335); reports his institution received payments from Novartis for his serving as a co-investigator on the Generation Program, from Eli Lilly for serving as Site PI for the A4 Study, from Esai for serving as co-investigator on the AHEAD Study, and from Biogen for serving as co-investigator for ENGAGE, EMERGE, &amp; ADVANCE; reports receiving consulting fees from Biogen and payment or Honoria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Harvard Dementia Course 20205; reports receiving financial support for participation on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board from Linus Health; and reports receiving payments for serving as The Greenwall Foundation board of directors, and serving in an unpaid leadership or fiduciary role for Play on Philly. MK reports support from CIMED, Region Stockholm ALF, and Stockholms sjukhem Foundation; and reports participation on Scientific Advisory Boards for Combinostics, Eli Lilly, Eisai, and Nestl&#xe9;. HMK, in the past 3 years, has received options for Element Science and Identifeye and payments from F-Prime for advisory roles; was a cofounder of and held equity in Hugo Health; is a cofounder of and holds equity in Refactor Health and ENSIGHT-AI; and is associated with research contracts through Yale University from Janssen, Kenvue, Novartis, and Pfizer. EAL reports her institution has grants or contracts with the National Institute on Aging and the Greenwall Foundation; reports receiving consulting fees from Novartis and payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Eli Lilly; and reports paid participation on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for Pitt and Royball DSMB. TM-R reports participating as an unpaid executive board member for Diverse Research Now. EM reports the following grants or contracts: NIA R01AG059798 (PI: Prof Eric McDade), NIA K23AG046363 (principal investigator: Prof Eric McDade), NIA R01AG068319 (principal investigator: Randall Bateman, DIAN-TU Next Generation Tau Trial &#x2013; grant), NIA UFAG032438 (principal investigator: Randall Bateman, DIAN &#x2013; grant), NIA RF1AG079569 (principal investigator: Jasmeer Chhatwal), NIA R21AG084054 (principal investigator: Lei Liu), NIA R01AG070353 (principal investigator: Douglas Galasko), NIA T32AG058518 (principal investigators: Prof Eric McDade and B Joy Snider), National Library of Medicine (principal investigator: Fuhai Li), Alzheimer's Association DIAN-TU-OLE/ART-21&#x2013;725093 (principal investigator: Randall Bateman), AA DIAN-TU-Tau-21&#x2013;822987 (principal investigator: Randall Bateman), Alzheimer's Association DIAN-TU-PP-22&#x2013;872356 (principal investigator: Prof Eric McDade), and DIAN-TU Pharma Consortium, DIAN Expanded Registry (principal investigator: Prof Eric McDade); reports the following grants or contracts: active: Eli Lilly/Avid Radiopharmaceuticals, Hoffman-La Roche/Genentech, Biogen, Eisai, Janssen; previous: AbbVie, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Forum, Mithridion, Novartis, Pfizer, United Neuroscience, Sanofi, and Anonymous Foundation (principal investigator: Randall Bateman); reports his institution received payment for an Investigator Initiated Research grant from Eli Lilly and Company, Hoffman La Roche, and Eisai; reports receiving consulting fees from Astra Zeneca, Roche, Sanofi, and Merck; reports receiving payment or honoraria for manuscript preparation from the Alzheimer's Association, for CME from Projects in Knowledge (Kaplan) and Neurology Live, and for lecture honoraria by AAN and University of Maryland; reports receiving financial support for attending meetings and/or travel from the Alzheimer Association, Fondation Alzheimer, McGill University, University of Maryland, American Academy of Neurology, University of Massachusetts, Australian and New Zealand Association of Neurologists (ANZAN), and University of Utah Visiting Professor; reports receiving royalties from patent T-018562; reports receiving payments for participation on the following Boards: Alector Data Monitoring Committee, Alnylum, Eli Lilly Scientific Advisory Board, Fondation Alzheimer Scientific Advisory Board, Eli Lilly Data Monitoring Committee, Eli Lilly Global AD Medical Education Scientific Advisory Board, and Roche Scientific Advisory Board; and reports receiving radiopharmaceuticals and technology transfer from Avid Radiopharmaceuticals, Cerveau, and LMI, and receipt of drug and services for the DIAN-TU Primary Prevention Trial from Eli Lilly. MMM reports her institution received financial support for this Policy View from U54 AG044170; reports her institution has received the following grants or contracts: NIH: RF1 AG69052; U01 AG006786, RF1 AG077386, R01AG079397, U24 AG082930, P30 AG021332, U19 AG078109; DOD: W81XWH2110490; and Alzheimer's Association; reports receiving personal consulting fees from Althira, Beckman Coulter, Biogen, Cognito Therapuetics, Eisai, Eli Lilly, Merck, Neurogen Biomarking, Novo Nordisk, Roche, and Siemens Healthineers; and reports receiving honoraria for education events from Roche, Novo Nordisk, Eisai, and Eli Lilly. RCP is supported by NIH grants U01 AG006786, P30 AG0626, U19 AG024904, U24 AG057437, R01 AG011378, and UF1 NS125417; has consulted for Roche, Genentech, Eli Lilly, Eisai, Novartis, Novo Nordisk; receives royalties from Oxford University Press and UpToDate; and has prepared educational materials for Medscape. GDR reports support paid to his institution from a grant from American College of Radiology, with sponsorship from Alzheimer's Association, Eli Lilly, GE Healthcare and Life Molecular Imaging; reports his institution has the following grants or contracts: NIH-NIA R35AG072362, P30AG062422, U01AG057195. U01AG082350, R56-AG075744; NIH-NINDS R01NS139383, R21NS120629, Alzheimer's Association ZEN-21&#x2013;848216, SG-21&#x2013;876655, Alliance for Therapeutics in Neurodegeneration (supported by Genentech); and Rainwater Charitable Foundation; reports receiving consulting fees from Eli Lilly, Roche, Alector, C2N, Novo Norodisk, Merck, and Bristol Myers Squib; reports payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from Efficient, Associate Editor&#x2013;JAMA Neurology, Miller Medical Communications, Medscape, Peerview, and Associate Editor&#x2013;JAMA; and reports paid participation on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for Johnson &amp; Johnson. CR reports support for the present manuscript from serving as founder and CEO, and majority shareholder of Scottish Brain Sciences; reports receiving consulting fees from Biogen, Eisai, MSD, Actinogen, Roche, Eli Lilly, and Novo Nordisk; reports payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events from Roche and Eisai. SES reports receiving consulting fees for advisory boards on blood biomarkers and biomarker education for providers from Eisai and Novo Nordisk; reports receiving honorarium for presenting a lecture on biomarker testing from Eli Lilly; has received honoraria for educational content from Medscape and Peerview; reports that plasma Ab42/Ab40 data was provided to Washington University by C2N Diagnostics at no cost; reports unpaid presentations made for Eisai, Eli Lilly, Biogen, and Danaher, and unpaid scientific advising for Johnson &amp; Johnson Innovative Medicine. RAS reports her institution has received grants or contracts from the Alzheimer's Association, NIA, and GHR Foundation; reports receiving research funding to clinical trial sites from Eli Lilly and Eisai; reports receiving consulting fees from AbbVie, AC Immune, Acumen, Alector, Apellis, Biohaven, BMS, Genentech, Janssen, Nervgen, Oligomerix, Prothena, Roche, Vigil Neuroscience, Ionis, and Vaxxinity. She reports receiving financial support for attending meetings and/or travel from the Alzheimer's Association, Clinical Trials in Alzheimer's Disease, and Janssen. MS-C reports his institution has received project grants from Roche Diagnostics; reports his institution received consulting fees from Roche Diagnostics; reports his institution has received payment for lectures given in symposia from Roche Diagnostics, Almirall, Eli Lilly, Novo Nordisk, and Quanterix; reports his institution received payments for him attending advisory boards for Roche Diagnostics, Grifols, SL, Eli Lilly, and Novo Nordisk. He reports his institution received in-kind biomarker measurements from Roche Diagnostics International Ltd, Avid Radiopharmaceuticals, Inc. (Eli Lilly and company), Janssen Research &amp; Development, Alamar Biosciences, Fujirebio, Meso Scale Discovery, and ALZpath; reports his institution received in-kind antibodies from ADX Neurosciences; reports serving as a site investigator at his institution for the study A multicenter, prospective, no-interventional study to determine the cutoff and clinical performance of the Elecsys Amyloid Plasma Panel and its component assays; RD006263 from March, 2023, to March, 2024, which is associated with Roche Diagnostics. GV reports acting as chair of the board for Davos Alzheimer's, is chairman of UsAgainstAlzheimer's; is co-convener of Leaders Engaged on Alzheimer's disease coalition; and is co-convener of CEOi. MWW reports his institution has received the following grants: NIH (2 U19 AG024904&#xb7;16, 5U2CAG060426&#x2013;04, 5R01AG058676&#x2013;02, 1RF1AG059009&#x2013;01, R33 AG062867, 1R01NS119651&#x2013;01, RF1AG062196, R56AG075744&#x2013;01A1), Department of Defense, California Department of Public Health, Siemens, Biogen, Hillblom Foundation, Alzheimer's Association, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Kevin and Connie Shanahan, General Electric, VU University Medical Center Amsterdam, Australian Catholic University (Healthy Brain Initiative&#x2013;Brain Health Registry), The Stroke Foundation, and Veterans Administration; reports receiving consulting fees from Acadia Pharmaceuticals, Acumen Pharmaceuticals, Boxer Capital Payment, BrightFocus Foundation, Cerecin, Clario&#x2013;BioClinica, Dementia Society of Japan, Eisai, Guidepoint, Health and Wellness Partners, Indiana University, LCN Consulting, MSD, Duke University, North Carolina Registry for Brain Health, Owkin France, NovoNordisk, ProMIS Neurosciences, Prova Education, Sai Med Partners, T3D Therapeutics, University of Southern, WebMD, MEDA, Quantum Leap Health, REGEnLIFE, and GLG Consulting; reports receiving payment or honoria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from the China Association for Alzheimer's Disease, Taipei Medical University, Cleveland Clinic, Banner Health, AD/PD Congress, Foundation of Learning, Health Society (Japan), INSPIRE Project: University of Toulouse, Japan Society for Dementia Research, Korean Dementia Society, MSD, National Center for Geriatrics and Gerontology (NCGG; Japan), University of Southern California, and University of Madison Wisconsin; reports receiving support for attending meetings and/or travel from AD/PD Congress, Banner Health, Cleveland Clinic, CTAD Congress, Foundation of Learning; Health Society (Japan), INSPIRE Project: University of Toulouse, Japan Society for Dementia Research, Korean Dementia Society, MSD, NCGG, and University of Southern California (UCSF); reports participation on a Data Safety Monitoring Board or Advisory Board for ADNI Scientific Advisory Board (leadership), University of California San Fransisco Committee for Human Research (committee member), ProMIS Neurosciencs (clinical advisory board member), Acumen Pharmaceutical SAB (scientific advisory board member), Duke University NC Registry for Brain Health SAB (scientific advisory board member); reports serving in leadership roles for the UCSF Inclusion Diversity Equity &amp; Awareness and the Diversity Task Force of the Alzheimer's Disease Neuroimaging Initiative; and reports stock in Alzeca, ALZPath, and Anven, and stock options in Alzheon. KAW-B reports participation on the data safety monitoring board for the NIA-Alzheimer's Association Sponsored US POINTER Study-Lifestyle Intervention for Prevention of Dementia, for which no compensation was given to her or her institution. HZ is a Wallenberg Scholar and a Distinguished Professor at the Swedish Research Council supported by grants from the Swedish Research Council (#2023&#x2013;00356; #2022&#x2013;01018 and #2019&#x2013;02397), the European Union's Horizon Europe research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 101053962, Swedish State Support for Clinical Research (#ALFGBG-71320), the Alzheimer Drug Discovery Foundation (ADDF), USA (#201809&#x2013;2016862), the AD Strategic Fund and the Alzheimer's Association (#ADSF-21&#x2013;831376-C, #ADSF-21&#x2013;831381-C, #ADSF-21&#x2013;831377-C, and #ADSF-24&#x2013;1284328-C), the Bluefield Project, Cure Alzheimer's Fund, the Olav Thon Foundation, the Erling-Persson Family Foundation, Stiftelsen f&#xf6;r Gamla Tj&#xe4;narinnor, Hj&#xe4;rnfonden, Sweden (#FO2022&#x2013;0270), the EU's Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under the Marie Sk&#x142;odowska-Curie grant agreement No 860197 (MIRIADE), the European Union Joint Programme&#x2013;Neurodegenerative Disease Research (JPND2021&#x2013;00694), the National Institute for Health and Care Research University College London Hospitals Biomedical Research Centre, and the UK Dementia Research Institute at University College London (UKDRI-1003); reports payment for serving on scientific advisory boards and/or as a consultant for AbbVie, Acumen, Alector, Alzinova, ALZPath, Amylyx, Annexon, Apellis, Artery Therapeutics, AZTherapies, Cognito Therapeutics, CogRx, Denali, Eisai, Merry Life, Nervgen, Novo Nordisk, Optoceutics, Passage Bio, Pinteon Therapeutics, Prothena, Red Abbey Labs, reMYND, Roche, Samumed, Siemens Healthineers, Triplet Therapeutics, and Wave; reports payments for lectures given in symposia sponsored by Alzecure, BioArctic, Biogen, Cellectricon, Fujirebio, LabCorp, Eli Lilly, Novo Nordisk, Oy Medix Biochemica AB, Roche, and WebMD; is a co-founder of Brain Biomarker Solutions in Gothenburg AB, which is a part of the University of Gothenburg Ventures Incubator Program without any products on the market, is co-chair of the Global Biomarker Standardization Consortium and chair of the International Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine Working Group on Biomarkers for Neurodegenerative Diseases, all of which are unpaid. MTZ reports being the founder of the Initiative to Change the &#x201c;D-Word&#x201d;; and serves as a board member for Banner Alzheimer's Institute Foundation. SM reports his institution received research contracts from Biogen, C2N, Eisai, Eli Lilly, and Roche; reports receiving personal consulting fees from Biogen, C2N, Eisai, Roche&#x2013;Genentech, and Novo Nordisk, and honoraria for educational events from Roche, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Eisai, and Eli Lilly; reports receiving financial support for travel to AAIC 2023 from Roche; reports participating on Advisory Boards for Roche and serves on the board of Directors for Senscio Systems; and reports serving on the scientific advisory board for Alzpath and Boston Millennia Partners. JLC reports receiving royalties of licenses from copyright ownership of Neuropsychiatric Inventory (NPI); reports receiving consulting fees from Acadia, Acumen, ALZpath, Artery, Axsome, Biogen, Biohaven, BMS, Eisai, Fosun, GAP Foundation, Hummingbird Diagnostics, Janssen, Karuna, Kinoxis, Lighthouse, Eli Lilly, Lundbeck, LSP/eqt, Merck, Sharp &amp; Dorne, MoCA Cognition, New Amsterdam, Novo Nordisk, Optoceutics, Otsuka, Oxford Brain Diagnostics, Praxis, Prothena, ReMYND, Roche, Scottish Brain Sciences, Signant Health, Simcere, Sinaptica, TrueBinding, and Vaxxinity pharmaceutical, assessment, and investment companies; reports participation on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for Acadia, Biogen, Genentech, Grifols, Janssen, Karuna, Otsuka, reMYND, Roche, Signant Health; reports stock or stock options for Artery, Vaxxinity, Behrens, Alzheon, MedAvante-Prophase, and Acumen; and is supported by NIGMS grant P20GM109025, NIA R35AG71476, NIA R25AG083721, NINDS RO1NS139383, the Alzheimer's Disease Drug Discovery Foundation, Ted and Maria Quirk Endowment, and Joy Chambers-Grundy Endowment. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41722593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(25)00483-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1474-4422(25)00483-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>