<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41376335</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0029</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>89</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Microscopy research and technique</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Microsc Res Tech</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Accelerating Prostate Cancer Detection Through Histopathological Image Analysis Using Artificial Intelligence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>687</StartPage><EndPage>704</EndPage><MedlinePgn>687-704</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jemt.70104</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Prostate cancer is a prevalent and serious health concern, ranking among the most frequently diagnosed cancers and a leading cause of cancer-related deaths in men worldwide. Early detection and accurate diagnosis are crucial for improving patient outcomes by limiting disease progression. Histopathological image analysis remains the gold standard for prostate cancer detection; however, manual interpretation is time-consuming and requires specialized expertise. To address these challenges, this study proposes a hybrid deep learning framework that combines an ensemble of transfer-learned CNNs (VGG-16, DenseNet-121, and AlexNet) with a fine-tuned Vision Transformer (ViT). The CNN ensemble extracts rich local features, while the ViT captures global contextual dependencies through a self-attention mechanism and a multilayer perceptron (MLP). Additionally, a cross-attention fusion (CAF) module integrates local and global features, and knowledge distillation (KD) enables a lightweight student network suitable for efficient clinical deployment. The study utilizes the publicly available PANDA dataset for training and testing. Preprocessing steps, including patch generation, gamma correction, and stain deconvolution, enhance image quality and feature representation. A comprehensive evaluation was conducted using standard performance metrics such as accuracy, true positive rate (TPR), true negative rate (TNR), precision, F1-score, false negative rate (FNR), and false positive rate (FPR). An ablation study confirmed the contribution of each module, highlighting the critical role of ensemble CNNs, CAF, and ViT in improving performance. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed model outperforms conventional transfer learning models and existing state-of-the-art techniques, achieving 97.91% accuracy, along with significant improvements in TPR, TNR, and reduced FNR/FPR. The computational complexity, evaluated in terms of parameters, FLOPs, GPU memory, and inference time, indicates that the proposed model is more demanding than traditional CNNs. Nevertheless, the architecture strikes a practical balance between predictive accuracy and efficiency, making it suitable for real-world clinical applications. These findings underscore the potential of AI-powered hybrid models in expediting prostate cancer diagnosis and enabling timely intervention for improved patient outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bose</LastName><ForeName>Anandh Sam Chandra</ForeName><Initials>ASC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3020-0594</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Industrial Engineering, College of Applied Sciences, AlMaarefa University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srinivasan</LastName><ForeName>Chandran</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0841-8351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of EEE, Rajalakshmi Engineering College, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saravanakumar</LastName><ForeName>Chandrasekaran</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of ECE, SRM Valliammai Engineering College, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Microsc Res Tech</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9203012</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1059-910X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011471" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prostatic Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007091" MajorTopicYN="Y">Image Processing, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077321" MajorTopicYN="N">Deep Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">computer&#x2010;aided diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">histopathological images</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prostate cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vision transformer</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41376335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jemt.70104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Asghar, M., A. R. Shahid, A. Jamil, K. Aftab, and S. A. Enam. 2023. &#x201c;Tumor&#x2010;Centered Patching for Enhanced Medical Image Segmentation.&#x201d; arXiv Preprint arXiv:2308.12168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaha, H. M., A. O. Shaban, E. M. El&#x2010;Gendy, and M. M. Saafan. 2024. &#x201c;Prostate Cancer Grading Framework Based on Deep Transfer Learning and Aquila Optimizer.&#x201d; Neural Computing and Applications 36, no. 14: 7877&#x2013;7902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behzadi, M. M., M. Madani, H. Wang, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Weakly&#x2010;Supervised Deep Learning Model for Prostate Cancer Diagnosis and Gleason Grading of Histopathology Images.&#x201d; Biomedical Signal Processing and Control 95: 106351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bejnordi, B. E., G. Litjens, N. Timofeeva, et&#xa0;al. 2015. &#x201c;Stain Specific Standardization of Whole&#x2010;Slide Histopathological Images.&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging 35, no. 2: 404&#x2013;415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulten, W., G. Litjens, H. Pinckaers, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;The PANDA Challenge: Prostate cANcer graDe Assessment using the Gleason grading system.&#x201d; MICCAI Challenge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty, S., K. Ma, R. Gupta, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;Visual Attention Analysis of Pathologists Examining Whole Slide Images of Prostate Cancer.&#x201d; In 2022 IEEE 19th International Symposium on Biomedical Imaging (ISBI), 1&#x2013;5. IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, N., and Q. Zhou. 2016. &#x201c;The Evolving Gleason Grading System.&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Cancer Research 28, no. 1: 58&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duenweg, S. R., M. Brehler, S. A. Bobholz, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;Comparison of a Machine and I Model for Automated Tumor Annotation on Digitized Whole Slide Prostate Cancer Histology.&#x201d; PLoS One 18, no. 3: e0278084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein, J. I., W. C. Allsbrook Jr., M. B. Amin, L. L. Egevad, and ISUP Grading Committee. 2005. &#x201c;The 2005 International Society of Urological Pathology (ISUP) Consensus Conference on Gleason Grading of Prostatic Carcinoma.&#x201d; American Journal of Surgical Pathology 29, no. 9: 1228&#x2013;1242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetisov, N., L. Hall, D. Goldgof, and M. Schabath. 2023. &#x201c;Unsupervised Prostate Cancer Histopathology Image Segmentation via Meta&#x2010;Learning.&#x201d; In 2023 IEEE 36th International Symposium on Computer&#x2010;Based Medical Systems (CBMS), 838&#x2013;844. IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a, G., A. Colomer, and V. Naranjo. 2019. &#x201c;First&#x2010;Stage Prostate Cancer Identification on Histopathological Images: Hand&#x2010;Driven Versus Automatic Learning.&#x201d; Entropy 21, no. 4: 356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleason, D. F. 1992. &#x201c;Histologic Grading of Prostate Cancer: A Perspective.&#x201d; Human Pathology 23, no. 3: 273&#x2013;279. https://doi.org/10.1016/0046&#x2010;8177(92)90108&#x2010;F.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gour, M., S. Jain, and U. Shankar. 2021. &#x201c;Application of Deep Learning Techniques for Prostate Cancer Grading Using Histopathological Images.&#x201d; In International Conference on Computer Vision and Image Processing, 83&#x2013;94. Springer International Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, G., Z. Liu, L. van der Maaten, and K. Q. Weinberger. 2017. &#x201c;Densely Connected Convolutional Networks.&#x201d; In Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 4700&#x2013;4708. IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, G., C. Y. Wong, S. C. F. Lin, et&#xa0;al. 2015. &#x201c;Image Contrast Enhancement With Brightness Preservation Using an Optimal Gamma Correction and Weighted Sum Approach.&#x201d; Journal of Modern Optics 62, no. 7: 536&#x2013;547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizhevsky, A., I. Sutskever, and G. E. Hinton. 2012. &#x201c;Imagenet Classification With Deep Convolutional Neural Networks.&#x201d; Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 25: 84&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudo, M. S., V. M. G. de Souza, C. L. N. Estivallet, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;The Value of Artificial Intelligence for Detection and Grading of Prostate Cancer in Human Prostatectomy Specimens: A Validation Study.&#x201d; Patient Safety in Surgery 16, no. 1: 36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R. 2020. &#x201c;Adding Binary Search Connections to Improve Densenet Performance.&#x201d; In 5th International Conference on Next Generation Computing Technologies (NGCT&#x2010;2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W., J. Li, Z. Wang, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;PathAL: An Active Learning Framework for Histopathology Image Analysis.&#x201d; IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging 41, no. 5: 1176&#x2013;1187. https://doi.org/10.1109/TMI.2021.3135002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linkon, A. H. M., M. M. Labib, T. Hasan, and M. Hossain. 2021. &#x201c;Deep Learning in Prostate Cancer Diagnosis and Gleason Grading in Histopathology Images: An Extensive Study.&#x201d; Informatics in Medicine Unlocked 24: 100582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masoudi, S., S. A. Harmon, S. Mehralivand, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Quick Guide on Radiology Image Pre&#x2010;Processing for Deep Learning Applications in Prostate Cancer Research.&#x201d; Journal of Medical Imaging 8, no. 1: 010901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagpal, K., D. Foote, Y. Liu, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;Development and Validation of a Deep Learning Algorithm for Improving Gleason Scoring of Prostate Cancer.&#x201d; NPJ Digital Medicine 2, no. 1: 48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishio, M., H. Matsuo, Y. Kurata, O. Sugiyama, and K. Fujimoto. 2023. &#x201c;Label Distribution Learning for Automatic Cancer Grading of Histopathological Images of Prostate Cancer.&#x201d; Cancers 15, no. 5: 1535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak, M., and S. Kim. 2017. &#x201c;A Review of Deep Learning in Image Recognition.&#x201d; In 2017 4th International Conference on Computer Applications and Information Processing Technology (CAIPT), 1&#x2013;3. IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadia, H., M. Abbas, B. Wahid, et&#xa0;al. 2017. &#x201c;Developing a Deeper Insight Into Prostate Cancer.&#x201d; Bulletin of Environment, Pharmacology and Life Sciences 6: 12&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvi, M., U. R. Acharya, F. Molinari, and K. M. Meiburger. 2021. &#x201c;The Impact of Pre&#x2010;and Post&#x2010;Image Processing Techniques on Deep Learning Frameworks: A Comprehensive Review for Digital Pathology Image Analysis.&#x201d; Computers in Biology and Medicine 128: 104129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvi, M., F. Molinari, U. R. Acharya, L. Molinaro, and K. M. Meiburger. 2021. &#x201c;Impact of Stain Normalization and Patch Selection on the Performance of Convolutional Neural Networks in Histological Breast and Prostate Cancer Classification.&#x201d; Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine Update 1: 100004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel, R. L., K. D. Miller, and A. Jemal. 2019. &#x201c;Cancer Statistics, 2019.&#x201d; CA: a Cancer Journal for Clinicians 69, no. 1: 7&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonyan, K., and A. Zisserman. 2014. &#x201c;Very Deep Convolutional Networks for Large&#x2010;Scale Image Recognition.&#x201d; arXiv Preprint arXiv:1409.1556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal, N., S. Soni, S. Bonthu, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;A Deep Learning System for Prostate Cancer Diagnosis and Grading in Whole Slide Images of Core Needle Biopsies.&#x201d; Scientific Reports 12, no. 1: 3383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;berg, C., M. Lundmark, C. Granberg, S. Johansson, A. Ahnesj&#xf6;, and A. Montelius. 2013. &#x201c;Clinical Evaluation of Multi&#x2010;Atlas Based Segmentation of Lymph Node Regions in Head and Neck and Prostate Cancer Patients.&#x201d; Radiation Oncology 8, no. 1: 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stromberga, Z. 2020. The Role of the Inflammatory Mediators in Modulating Bladder Contractile Activity. PhD diss., Bond University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swiderska&#x2010;Chadaj, Z., T. de Bel, L. Blanchet, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;Impact of Rescanning and Normalization on Convolutional Neural Network Performance in Multi&#x2010;Center, Whole&#x2010;Slide Classification of Prostate Cancer.&#x201d; Scientific Reports 10, no. 1: 14398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammina, S. 2019. &#x201c;Transfer Learning Using Vgg&#x2010;16 With Deep Convolutional Neural Network for Classifying Images.&#x201d; International Journal of Scientific and Research Publications (IJSRP) 9, no. 10: 143&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, Y., M. Xu, Z. Lu, and Y. Zhong. 2018. &#x201c;DenseNet&#x2010;Based Depth&#x2010;Width Double Reinforced Deep Learning Neural Network for High&#x2010;Resolution Remote Sensing Image Per&#x2010;Pixel Classification.&#x201d; Remote Sensing 10, no. 5: 779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Y. Wang, X. Ci, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Molecular Events in Neuroendocrine Prostate Cancer Development.&#x201d; Nature Reviews Urology 18, no. 10: 581&#x2013;596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, W., K. Yang, Y. Bai, T. Xiao, H. Yao, and Y. Rui. 2016. &#x201c;Visualizing and Comparing AlexNet and VGG Using Deconvolutional Layers.&#x201d; In Proceedings of the 33 Rd International Conference on Machine Learning.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>