<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41862557</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimal fractional order PID-load frequency controller for multi-interconnected microgrids including renewable energy and storage system.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43080-z</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alshahir</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, College of Engineering, Jouf University, 72388, Sakaka, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fathy</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, College of Engineering, Jouf University, 72388, Sakaka, Saudi Arabia. afali@ju.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>A Hashim</LastName><ForeName>Fatma</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biomedical Department, Faculty of Engineering, Capital University (Formerly Helwan University), Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Science Research Center, Applied Science Private University, Amman, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Kaiguang</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Information Engineering, Ningxia University, Yinchuan, 750021, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alshahr</LastName><ForeName>Shahr</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, College of Engineering, Jouf University, 72388, Sakaka, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Hossam Hassan</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Department, Faculty of Technology and Education, Sohag University, Sohag, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>DGSSR-2025-02-01110</GrantID><Agency>Al Jouf University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interconnected area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Load frequency control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Political optimizer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Storage battery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wind power</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41862557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43080-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43080-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Elnozahy, A., Ramadan, H. S. &amp; Abo-Elyousr, F. K. Efficient metaheuristic utopia-based multi-objective solutions of optimal battery-mix storage for microgrids. J. Clean. Prod. 303, 127038 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri, A., Jabbari, A. &amp; Mobayen, S. An intelligent ABC-based terminal sliding mode controller for load-frequency control of islanded micro-grids. Sustain. Cities Soc. 64, 102544 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benmouna, A., Becherif, M., Boulon, L., D&#xe9;pature, C. &amp; Ramadan, H. S. Efficient experimental energy management operating for FC/battery/SC vehicles via hybrid Artificial Neural Networks-Passivity Based Control. Renewable Energy 178, 1291&#x2013;1302 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, C., Wang, C. &amp; Shi, D. An alternative method for mitigating impacts of communication delay on load frequency control. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 119, 105924 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dev, A., Anand, S. &amp; Sarkar, M. K. Adaptive super twisting sliding mode load frequency control for an interconnected power network with nonlinear coupling between control areas. IFAC-PapersOnLine 53(1), 350&#x2013;355 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, D., Singh, V. P. &amp; Mallick, M. A. Frequency control of interlinked microgrid system using fractional order controller. Electrica 24(2), 532&#x2013;541 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P., Chen, X., Zhang, Y., Zhang, L. &amp; Huang, Y. Fractional-order load frequency control of an interconnected power system with a hydrogen energy-storage unit. Fractal Fraction 8(3), 126 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnefaie, S. A., Alkuhayli, A. &amp; Al-Shaalan, A. M. Optimizing load frequency control of multi-area power renewable and thermal systems using advanced proportional&#x2013;integral&#x2013;derivative controllers and catch fish algorithm. Fractal Fraction 9(6), 355 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, M. et al. Power grid load frequency control based on Fractional Order PID combined with pumped storage and battery energy storage. Energy Rep. 9, 1402&#x2013;1411 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaker, H. K., Keshta, H. E., Mosa, M. A. &amp; Ali, A. A. Adaptive nonlinear controllers based approach to improve the frequency control of multi islanded interconnected microgrids. Energy Rep. 9, 5230&#x2013;5245 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davoudkhani, I. F., Zare, P., Abdelaziz, A. Y., Bajaj, M. &amp; Tuka, M. B. Robust load-frequency control of islanded urban microgrid using 1PD-3DOF-PID controller including mobile EV energy storage. Sci. Rep. 14(1), 13962 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daraz, A., Malik, S. A., Basit, A., Aslam, S. &amp; Zhang, G. Modified FOPID controller for frequency regulation of a hybrid interconnected system of conventional and renewable energy sources. Fractal Fract. 7(1), 89 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyan, C. N. S., and Salkuti, S. R. A Cascaded (1+ PI)-PID controller for the improvement in load frequency control of the diversified interconnected power system. In&#xa0;Artificial Intelligence for Integrated Smart Energy Systems in Electric Vehicles, 527&#x2013;542. (Springer Nature Switzerland, Cham, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakout, A. H. et al. A novel ultra local based-fuzzy PIDF controller for frequency regulation of a hybrid microgrid system with high renewable energy penetration and storage devices. Processes 11(4), 1093 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohmingtluanga, C. et al. Enhanced Harris hawks optimization based load frequency control of multi area microgrid based water treatment plant with consideration of 3DOF-(FO-PIDN)/(TIDN) controller. Front. Energy Res. 12, 1387780 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, I. A. et al. Load frequency control using Golden eagle optimization for multi-area power system connected through AC/HVDC transmission and supported with hybrid energy storage devices. IEEE Access 11, 44672&#x2013;44695 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K., Abualigah, L., Smerat, A., Li, J., Wu, X., Liu, H., Shao, Z. &amp; Mirjalili, S. A nature recoil mechanism-based Octopus Optimization Algorithm for solving the global and constraint optimization from engineering structural design problems. J. Comput. Design Eng. qwaf139 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barakat, M. Optimal design of fuzzy-PID controller for automatic generation control of multi-source interconnected power system. Neural Comput. Appl. 34(21), 18859&#x2013;18880 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathy, A. et al. A new fractional-order load frequency control for multi-renewable energy interconnected plants using skill optimization algorithm. Sustainability 14(22), 14999 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, M. Resilient PIDA control design based frequency regulation of interconnected time-delayed microgrid under cyber-attacks. IEEE Trans. Ind. Appl. 59(1), 492&#x2013;502 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid, J., Ramli, M. A. M., Khan, M. S. &amp; Hidayat, T. Efficient load frequency control of renewable integrated power system: A twin delayed DDPG-based deep reinforcement learning approach. IEEE Access 10, 51561&#x2013;51574 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathy, A., Yousri, D., Rezk, H., Thanikanti, S. B. &amp; Hasanien, H. M. A robust fractional-order PID controller based load frequency control using modified hunger games search optimizer. Energies 15(1), 361 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A., Khadanga, R. K. &amp; Panda, S. Reinforced modified equilibrium optimization technique-based MS-PID frequency regulator for a hybrid power system with renewable energy sources. Soft Comput. 26(11), 5437&#x2013;5455 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R. &amp; Sharma, V. K. Interconnected power control on unequal, deregulated multi-area power system using three-degree-of-freedom-based FOPID-PR controller. Electr. Eng. 106(2), 2107&#x2013;2129 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla, S., Jha, S. K. &amp; Singh, S. K. Optimizing load frequency control in diverse power generation systems using hybrid metaheuristic algorithms. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-025-10261-3 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekinci, S., Izci, D., Bajaj, M. &amp; Blazek, V. Novel application of sinh cosh optimizer for robust controller design in hybrid photovoltaic-thermal power systems. Sci. Rep. 15(1), 2825 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sah, S. V., Prakash, V., Pathak, P. K. &amp; Yadav, A. K. Resilient fractional-order fuzzy-based tilt control of renewable-dominated hybrid power system. Neural Comput. Appl. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00521-025-11015-w (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gbadega, P. A., Sun, Y. &amp; Balogun, O. A. Enhanced multi-area automatic generation control in renewable energy-based microgrids using an IPFC-SMES system and COA-optimized FOPID controller. Energy Rep. 13, 6479&#x2013;6513 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, J., Zou, R., Pathak, P. K., Karni, A. &amp; Akhtar, S. Design of a novel cascade PI-(1+ FOPID) controller to enhance load frequency control performance in diverse electric power systems. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 243, 111488 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, E. A. et al. Optimal 1+ PDDF/FOPIT frequency regulator for developing robust multi-microgrid systems with employing EV energy storage batteries. J. Energy Storage 73, 109088 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbaksawi, O., Fathy, R., Daoud, A. A. &amp; Abd El-aal, R. A. Optimized load frequency controller for microgrid with renewables and EVs based recent multi-objective Mantis search algorithm. Results Eng. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2025.105472 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi, N., Dowlatabadi, M. &amp; Sabzevari, K. A hierarchical deep learning approach to optimizing voltage and frequency control in networked microgrid systems. Appl. Energy 377, 124313 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafez, W. A., Aly, M., Mohamed, E. A. &amp; Nagem, N. A. Improved fractional order control with virtual inertia provision methodology for electric vehicle batteries in modern multi-microgrid energy systems. J. Energy Storage 106, 114582 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari, Z. A. &amp; Raja, G. L. Flow direction optimizer tuned robust FOPID-(1+ TD) cascade controller for oscillation mitigation in multi-area renewable integrated hybrid power system with hybrid electrical energy storage. J. Energy Storage 83, 110616 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palaniyappan, S. &amp; Singaravel, M. M. R. Opposition African vultures optimization based NFOPID controller for frequency stabilization of multi-microgrid network. Comput. Electr. Eng. 122, 109959 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swain, N., Sinha, N. &amp; Behera, S. Stabilized frequency response of a microgrid using a two-degree-of-freedom controller with African vultures optimization algorithm. ISA Trans. 140, 412&#x2013;425 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathy, D., Choudhury, N. D., Behera, S., &amp; Sahu, B. K. Grasshopper optimization algorithm based fuzzy PD-PI cascade controller for LFC of interconnected power system coordinate with renewable sources. In&#xa0;2020 IEEE Calcutta Conference (CALCON), 111&#x2013;116 (IEEE, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathy, D., Behera, S. &amp; Choudhury, N. B. D. Implementation of Grasshopper optimization algorithm based cascaded fuzzy PD-PI controller for frequency stability in a multi-area power system. J. Interdiscip. Math. 23(2), 335&#x2013;345 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhagat, S. K. et al. Bird swarm algorithm optimized TIDD controller for multi-area load frequency control application. SN Comput. Sci. 4(2), 138 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya, Y. &amp; Kumar, N. Optimal AGC with redox flow batteries in multi-area restructured power systems. Eng. Sci. Technol. Int. J. 19(3), 1145&#x2013;1159 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya, Y., Ahmad, R., Nasiruddin, I. &amp; Ahmer, M. F. LFC performance advancement of two-area RES penetrated multi-source power system utilizing CES and a new CFOTID controller. J. Energy Storage 87, 111366 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, K., Amir, M. &amp; Arya, Y. Optimal dynamic frequency regulation of renewable energy based hybrid power system utilizing a novel TDF-TIDF controller. Energy Sources A 44(4), 10733&#x2013;10754 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanien, H. M. &amp; El-Fergany, A. A. Salp swarm algorithm-based optimal load frequency control of hybrid renewable power systems with communication delay and excitation cross-coupling effect. Electr. Power Syst. Res. 176, 105938 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amir, M., Zaery, M., Singh, K., Hussain, S. M. S. &amp; Abido, M. A. Enhancement of frequency regulation by tfoid controller in hybrid renewable energy with battery storage system based multi area microgrids. IEEE Access 12, 110813&#x2013;110828 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshnoei, S., Oshnoei, A., Mosallanejad, A. &amp; Haghjoo, F. Novel load frequency control scheme for an interconnected two-area power system including wind turbine generation and redox flow battery. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 130, 107033 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, I. A. et al. Load frequency control in power systems with high renewable energy penetration: A strategy employing PI&#x3bb; (1+ PDF) controller, hybrid energy storage, and IPFC-FACTS. Alex. Eng. J. 106, 337&#x2013;366 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathy, A., Bouaouda, A. &amp; Hashim, F. A. A novel modified Cheetah optimizer for designing fractional-order PID-LFC placed in multi-interconnected system with renewable generation units. Sustain. Comput. 43, 101011 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulzar, M. M., Sibtain, D., Alqahtani, M., Alismail, F. &amp; Khalid, M. Load frequency control progress: A comprehensive review on recent development and challenges of modern power systems. Energy Strategy Rev. 57, 101604 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, H. H., Fathy, A. &amp; Kassem, A. M. Optimal model predictive control for LFC of multi-interconnected plants comprising renewable energy sources based on recent sooty terns approach. Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess. 42, 100844 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askari, Q., Younas, I. &amp; Saeed, M. Political optimizer: A novel socio-inspired meta-heuristic for global optimization. Knowl. Based Syst. 195, 105709 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monje, C. A., Chen, Y. Q., Vinagre, B. M., Xue, D. &amp; Feliu, V. Fractional-order Systems and Controls: Fundamentals and Applications (Springer, London, 2010).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>