<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41560182</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-0053</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>112</Volume><Issue>6-2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical review. E</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Rev E</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hybridizing multiscale and delayed reservoir computing for long-term accurate chaotic system forecasting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>065313</StartPage><MedlinePgn>065313</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1103/x6c1-3xj8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Prediction of chaotic dynamical systems remains a fundamental challenge, primarily due to their extreme sensitivity to initial conditions and the coexistence of multiscale temporal dynamics. Although traditional Reservoir Computing (RC) and its delayed-feedback extension (DRC) have demonstrated promising performance in chaotic system prediction, they often struggle to capture the complex multiscale features present in such systems. To address these limitations, a Hybrid MultiScale Delayed Reservoir Computing framework (HyMS-DRC) is proposed. This approach integrates standard RC and delayed-feedback RC in a parallel multiscale architecture, where state fusion enhances the representation of dynamics across different temporal scales and mitigates memory fading in long-horizon prediction. We systematically evaluate HyMS-DRC on three canonical chaotic systems-Double Scroll, Lorenz, and R&#xf6;ssler-and compare it against RC, DRC, MultiScale Reservoir Computing (MS-RC), and MultiScale Delayed-Feedback Reservoir Computing (MS-DRC). Experimental results demonstrate that HyMS-DRC consistently achieves superior forecasting performance, attaining the lowest normalized root-mean-square errors (NRMSEs) of 0.0089, 0.0137, and 0.0662, and the longest valid prediction times of approximately 27.85, 24.29, and 22.37 on the three systems, respectively. Furthermore, long-term statistical analyses confirm that HyMS-DRC robustly reconstructs the attractor geometry and accurately reproduces the power spectral distribution, indicating excellent generalization and modeling capability for complex nonlinear dynamics. These findings highlight that combining multiscale structures with delayed feedback significantly enhances temporal memory and feature representation in reservoirs, enabling accurate and robust long-term prediction of chaotic systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Zuo Wei</ForeName><Initials>ZW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi Normal University, Guangxi Normal University, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Brain-Inspired Computing and Intelligent Chips, College of Electronic and Information Engineering, Guilin 541004, China and Key Laboratory of Nonlinear Circuits and Optical Communications (, ), Education Department of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Guilin, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02frt9q65</Identifier><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02frt9q65</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Du Qu</ForeName><Initials>DQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangxi Normal University, Guangxi Normal University, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Brain-Inspired Computing and Intelligent Chips, College of Electronic and Information Engineering, Guilin 541004, China and Key Laboratory of Nonlinear Circuits and Optical Communications (, ), Education Department of Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Guilin, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02frt9q65</Identifier><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02frt9q65</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Rev E</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101676019</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-0045</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41560182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/x6c1-3xj8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>