<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41616004</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Graph neural networks and belief rule base collaborative modeling for automated and interpretable fault diagnosis in proton exchange membrane fuel cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0341884</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0341884</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0341884</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0341884</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFC) are critical for clean energy conversion, but their reliability is severely compromised by complex faults, creating a pressing need for accurate and interpretable diagnostic methods. While the Belief Rule Base (BRB) provides a transparent reasoning framework, its practical deployment faces two fundamental challenges: the "combinatorial explosion" of rules with increasing system complexity, and a heavy reliance on domain experts to provide precise quantitative parameters. To address these issues, this paper proposes a novel GNN-BRB framework that synergistically integrates Graph Neural Networks (GNN) with BRB. Our solution introduces two key innovations: an exponential ordered weighting operator to systematically convert qualitative expert rankings into quantitative confidence parameters, and a GNN-based mechanism that models the BRB rule base as a graph to automatically generate initial parameters through information propagation among semantically related rules. Experimental results on a real-world PEMFC fault diagnosis case demonstrate that the proposed method significantly reduces dependency on manual expert input while achieving superior diagnostic performance. Ablation studies further validate the contribution of each model component. This work establishes a new paradigm for developing automated, highly accurate, and interpretable fault diagnosis systems for complex engineering applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Zhao et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Guizhou University, Guiyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guizhou Provincial Key Laboratory of Internet plus Intelligent Manufacturing, Guiyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4335-9078</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Guizhou University, Guiyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guizhou Provincial Key Laboratory of Internet plus Intelligent Manufacturing, Guiyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Economics and Management, Guiyang University, Guiyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011522">Protons</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011522" MajorTopicYN="Y">Protons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000098422" MajorTopicYN="N">Graph Neural Networks</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41616004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12857982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0341884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-48376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Chen J, Liu J. Iron phthalocyanine coupled with Co-Nx sites in carbon nanostraws for Zn-Air batteries. Chemical Engineering Journal. 2025;503:158343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao K, Wang X, Feng W, Ponrouch A, Poizot P, Armand M, et al. Carbonyl-based organic electrode materials spanning from nonaqueous rechargeable lithium to calcium batteries. Energy Environ Sci. 2025;18(16):7756&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1039/d4ee06017b</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ee06017b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi F, Sun Y, Zhang J, Zhou J, Zhang C, Yu W, et al. Early flooding fault diagnosis method of fuel cell based on feature amplification transformer. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 2025;119:13&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.241</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.03.241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Peng L, He F, Huang R. Fault diagnosis method of PEMFC system based on ensemble learning. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 2024;69:1501&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Gao Y, Yu J, Tian L, Yin C. Data-driven fault diagnosis of PEMFC water management with segmented cell and deep learning technologies. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 2024;67:715&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ao Y, Laghrouche S, Depernet D. Diagnosis of proton exchange membrane fuel cell system based on adaptive neural fuzzy inference system and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. Energy Conversion and Management. 2022;256:115391. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2022.115391</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2022.115391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escobet T, Feroldi D, de Lira S, Puig V, Quevedo J, Riera J, et al. Model-based fault diagnosis in PEM fuel cell systems. Journal of Power Sources. 2009;192(1):216&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2008.12.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2008.12.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ming W, Sun P, Zhang Z. A systematic review of machine learning methods applied to fuel cells in performance evaluation, durability prediction, and application monitoring. Int J Hydrogen Energy. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousfi Steiner N, Hissel D, Mo&#xe7;ot&#xe9;guy P, Candusso D, Marra D, Pianese C, et al. Application of Fault Tree Analysis to Fuel Cell diagnosis. Fuel Cells. 2012;12(2):302&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1002/fuce.201100072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/fuce.201100072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B, Zhang Q, He W, Han P, Cao Y, Zhou G. A deep belief rule base-based fault diagnosis method for complex systems. ISA Trans. 2024;150:77&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1016/j.isatra.2024.05.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isatra.2024.05.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38777695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z AB, Z AY, H BG, et al. A method of automatically generating initial parameters for large-scale belief rule base. Knowl Based Syst. 2020;199:105904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahneman D, Tversky A. Prospect Theory: An Analysis of Decision under Risk. Econometrica. 1979;47(2):263. doi: 10.2307/1914185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1914185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hey JD, Lotito G, Maffioletti A. The descriptive and predictive adequacy of theories of decision making under uncertainty/ambiguity. J Risk Uncertain. 2010;41(2):81&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1007/s11166-010-9102-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11166-010-9102-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LL, Xu XB, Xu XJ. Multi-objective optimization method of variable-structured belief rule base using dominant subordinate framework. Syst Eng Theory Pract. 2022;42(2):13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Qian G, He W. A novel classification method based on an online extended belief rule base with a human-in-the-loop strategy. Appl Intell. 2025;55(7):1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim RI, Noura H, Fardoun A. A review on fault diagnosis tools of the proton exchange membrane fuel cell. Control &amp; Fault-tolerant Systems. IEEE. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang B, Na W, Lee H. Model-based fault analysis and diagnosis of PEM fuel cell control system. Appl Sci. 2022;12(24):12733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riascos LAM, Simoes MG, Miyagi PE. On-line fault diagnostic system for proton exchange membrane fuel cells. Journal of Power Sources. 2008;175(1):419&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2007.09.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2007.09.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Outbib R, Giurgea S. Online implementation of SVM based fault diagnosis strategy for PEMFC systems. In:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu X, Hou Z, Cai J. Data-based flooding fault diagnosis of proton exchange membrane fuel cell systems using LSTM networks. Energy and AI. 2021;4:100056. doi: 10.1016/j.egyai.2021.100056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyai.2021.100056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Guo X. Fault diagnosis of proton exchange membrane fuel cell system of tram based on information fusion and deep learning. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 2021;46(60):30828&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.05.137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.05.137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu X, Yi F, Zhang J, Zhou J, Wang S, Gong H, et al. An Explainable Fault Diagnosis Algorithm for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells Integrating Gramian Angular Fields and Gradient-Weighted Class Activation Mapping. Electronics. 2025;14(22):4401. doi: 10.3390/electronics14224401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14224401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jian-Bo Y, Jun L, Jin W, How-Sing S, Hong-Wei W. Belief rule-base inference methodology using the evidential reasoning Approach-RIMER. IEEE Trans Syst, Man, Cybern A. 2006;36(2):266&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1109/tsmca.2005.851270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tsmca.2005.851270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian Z, Zhou Z, Hu C, Cao Y, Tang S, Sun Y. Transparent Fault Diagnosis for Complex Equipment Considering Expert Reliability Based on Belief Rule Base and Linguistic Z-Number. IEEE Trans Automat Sci Eng. 2025;22:3887&#x2013;900. doi: 10.1109/tase.2024.3402099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tase.2024.3402099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D, Yang H, Xu K. Data and knowledge fusion-driven Bayesian networks for interpretable fault diagnosis of HVAC systems. Int J Refrig. 2024;161:101&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao-Sheng S, Chang-Hua H, Jian-Bo Y, Zhi-Jie Z. A New Prediction Model Based on Belief Rule Base for System&#x2019;s Behavior Prediction. IEEE Trans Fuzzy Syst. 2011;19(4):636&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1109/tfuzz.2011.2130527</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tfuzz.2011.2130527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren H, Xing J, Zhang Y, Wang J, Zhu Z. Feature semantic alignment network for rotating machinery domain generalization fault diagnosis with limited labeled samples. Neurocomputing. 2026;664:132085. doi: 10.1016/j.neucom.2025.132085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2025.132085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Zhou Z, Cao Y, Tang S, Ning P, Chen L. BRN: A belief rule network model for the health evaluation of complex systems. Expert Systems with Applications. 2023;214:119065. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2022.119065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2022.119065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Xu X, Sheng C. Intelligent wear mode identification system for marine diesel engines based on multi-level belief rule base methodology. Meas Sci Technol. 2018;29(1):015110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z, Zhou Z, Hu C, Yin X, Hu G, Zhao F. Fault Diagnosis Based on Belief Rule Base With Considering Attribute Correlation. IEEE Access. 2018;6:2055&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1109/access.2017.2781365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2017.2781365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian Z, Zhou Z, Hu C, Ning P, Ming Z. Interpretable large-scale belief rule base for complex industrial systems modeling with expert knowledge and limited data. Adv Eng Inform. 2024;62:102852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z-J, Hu C-H, Yang J-B, Xu D-L, Chen M-Y, Zhou D-H. A sequential learning algorithm for online constructing belief-rule-based systems. Expert Systems with Applications. 2010;37(2):1790&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2009.07.067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2009.07.067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L, Zhou Y, Jiang J, Li M, Zhang X. Structure learning for belief rule base expert system: A comparative study. Knowledge-Based Systems. 2013;39:159&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/j.knosys.2012.10.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2012.10.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian Z, Zhou ZJ, Hu CH, Wang J, Zhang CC, Zhang CL. A health assessment method with attribute importance modeling for complex systems using belief rule base. Reliab Eng Syst Saf. 2024;251:110387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G, He W, Sun C, Zhu H, Li K, Jiang L. Hierarchical belief rule-based model for imbalanced multi-classification. Expert Systems with Applications. 2023;216:119451. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2022.119451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2022.119451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, Zhou ZJ, Hu CH, Tang SW, Wang J. A new approximate belief rule base expert system for complex system modelling. Decision Support Systems. 2021;150:113558. doi: 10.1016/j.dss.2021.113558</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dss.2021.113558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L-H, Ye F-F, Wang Y-M. Ensemble belief rule base modeling with diverse attribute selection and cautious conjunctive rule for classification problems. Expert Systems with Applications. 2020;146:113161. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2019.113161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2019.113161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, Zhou Z, Hu G, Hu C, Tang S, Li G. A new multilayer belief rule base model for complex system modeling. IEEE Systems Journal. 2021;:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filev D, Yager RR. On the issue of obtaining OWA operator weights. Fuzzy Sets and Systems. 1998;94(2):157&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1016/s0165-0114(96)00254-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0165-0114(96)00254-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kipf TN, Welling M. Semi-supervised classification with graph convolutional networks. In: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jian-Bo Y, Singh MG. An evidential reasoning approach for multiple-attribute decision making with uncertainty. IEEE Trans Syst, Man, Cybern. 1994;24(1):1&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1109/21.259681</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/21.259681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen N. The CMA evolution strategy: a comparing review. Towards a New Evolutionary Computation: Advances in the Estimation of Distribution Algorithms. 2006:75&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z, Ming Z, Wang J. A novel belief rule-based fault diagnosis method with interpretability. Comput Model Eng Sci. 2023;136(2):1165&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Li K, Zhang G, Zhu H, He W. A complex system health state assessment method with reference value optimization for interpretable BRB. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):2334. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-52829-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-52829-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11291914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38282169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Outbib R, Giurgea S, Hissel D, Jemei S, Giraud A, et al. Online implementation of SVM based fault diagnosis strategy for PEMFC systems. Applied Energy. 2016;164:284&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.11.060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.11.060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganaie MA, Tanveer M, Suganthan PN, Snasel V. Oblique and rotation double random forest. Neural Netw. 2022;153:496&#x2013;517. doi: 10.1016/j.neunet.2022.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neunet.2022.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yezerska K, Dushina A, Sarabakha A, Wagner P, Dyck A, Wark M. Model-based degradation prediction on impedance data and artificial neural network for high-temperature polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells after hydrogen starvation. International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 2022;47(68):29495&#x2013;504. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.06.254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.06.254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Maaten L, Hinton G. Visualizing data using t-SNE. J Mach Learn Res. 2008;9(2605):2579&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>