<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41366748</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2393</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pregnancy and childbirth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Empowering health literacy in mothers of premature infants during the post-discharge period: a qualitative comparison of nurses' and mothers' perspectives through digital health platforms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>46</StartPage><MedlinePgn>46</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">46</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12884-025-08477-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Premature infants require complex care following hospital discharge, placing a high demand on the health literacy of mothers. The use of digital health platforms provides innovative solutions for managing post-discharge care. However, mothers' and nurses' perspectives about the role of digital literacy in fostering caregiving confidence and informed decision-making may differ. This study aimed to qualitatively compare the views of mothers and neonatal nurses regarding the empowerment of health literacy through digital health platforms following the discharge of premature infants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This qualitative research employed a conventional content analysis approach. Data were collected through semi-structured interviews with 20 mothers of premature infants, and 15 neonatal nurses at three hospitals (Imam Hossein, Shahid Beheshti, Alzahra) in Isfahan, Iran, between February and July 2025. Purposeful sampling continued until data saturation was reached. Interviews were transcribed verbatim and analyzed using MAXQDA based on Graneheim and Lundman's method. Strategies such as triangulation, audit trails, and member checking were used to ensure rigor.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Analysis identified three main themes: (1) Navigating digital information accessibility, trustworthiness, and usability challenges; (2) Digital platforms as sources of emotional and practical support; and (3) Divergent perceptions of digital literacy's impact on caregiving confidence. Mothers valued peer support and access to varied information but faced difficulties interpreting some medical content. Nurses emphasized providing evidence-based digital resources, complemented by face-to-face education. The findings showed both convergences and divergences between mothers' and nurses' perspectives, underscoring the need for co-designed, culturally appropriate digital interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Digital health platforms may enhance health literacy in mothers of premature infants during the post-discharge phase. The findings suggest that co-designed interventions integrating digital and interpersonal support may help bridge the gap between mothers' needs and nurses' expectations, thereby facilitating informed decision-making.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atefeh</LastName><ForeName>Shamsi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Care Research Center, Clinical Sciences Institute, Faculty of Nursing, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran. noor13500@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahboobeh</LastName><ForeName>Namnabati</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing and Midwifery Care Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asghar</LastName><ForeName>Ehteshami</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Information Technology Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamed</LastName><ForeName>Zandi Esfahani</ForeName><Initials>ZE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, School of Medicine, Emam Hossein Hospital Research Center, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967799</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2393</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Literacy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009035" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mothers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007234" MajorTopicYN="Y">Infant, Premature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010351" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Discharge</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007492" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Iran</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072221" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nurses, Neonatal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000079102" MajorTopicYN="Y">Empowerment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000097103" MajorTopicYN="N">Digital Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health literacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, premature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maternal care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neonatal nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postnatal care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Isfahan University of Medical Sciences (Approval Number: [IR.MUI.NUREMA.REC.1400.055]). All procedures were conducted in accordance with institutional and national research committee ethical standards and the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: All participants voluntarily agreed to participate in this research after being provided with comprehensive information regarding the study aims and procedures. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41366748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12801648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-025-08477-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12884-025-08477-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ramirez JD, Sarik DA, Matsuda Y, Ortiz J. Best practices to support maternal mental health during the transition from neonatal intensive care unit to home: A scoping review. Crit Care Nurs Clin. 2024;36(2):261&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38705693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen LWH. Post-discharge communication in orthopedic patient care: evaluation of digital team-based communication between patients and health care professionals across settings. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs RJ, Lou JQ, Ownby RL, Caballero J. A systematic review of eHealth interventions to improve health literacy. Health Inf J. 2016;22(2):81&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1460458214534092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24916567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S-H, Kim J-I. Effects of e-Health Literacy, parenting Stress, and maternal role confidence on children&#x2019;s Health-Promoting behaviors in mothers of infants and toddlers. J Korean Soc Maternal Child Health. 2023;27(2):92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21896/jksmch.2023.27.2.92</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackley A, Winter M, Guillen U, Paul DA, Locke R. Health literacy among parents of newborn infants. Adv Neonatal Care. 2016;16(4):283&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ANC.0000000000000295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4955655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27391562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briain &#xd3;, Byrne E, Dowling AO. Diuretics use in the management of bronchopulmonary dysplasia in preterm infants: a systematic review. Acta Paediatr. 2024;113(3):394&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apa.17093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38214373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talmont E. Assessing technology attitudes and telehealth readiness among New Jersey perinatal nurses. Rutgers University-School of Nursing-RBHS; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi N-C, Demiris G. A systematic review of telehealth tools and interventions to support family caregivers. J Telemed Telecare. 2015;21(1):37&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1357633X14562734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4486048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25475220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rababeh A, Paton C, Grewal G, et al. Postdischarge health information tools and information needs for mothers of vulnerable newborns in low-and middle-income countries: a scoping review. BMJ Open. 2025;15(2):e082824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2023-082824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11865766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40010811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuo J, Makkar A, Machut K, et al. Telemedicine across the continuum of neonatal-perinatal care. Elsevier; 2022. p. 101398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9623499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36333212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindgren B-M, Lundman B, Graneheim UH. Abstraction and interpretation during the qualitative content analysis process. Int J Nurs Stud. 2020;108:103632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2020.103632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32505813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. To saturate or not to saturate? Questioning data saturation as a useful concept for thematic analysis and sample-size rationales. Qualitative Res Sport Exerc Health. 2021;13(2):201&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2159676X.2019.1704846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matysek A. The use of one-on-one interviews in library and information science: A scoping review. J Inform Sci. 2023:01655515231171088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon SA, Winch PJ. Systematic debriefing after qualitative encounters: an essential analysis step in applied qualitative research. BMJ Global Health. 2018;3(5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6135453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30233833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karcher K, McCuaig J, King-Hill S. (Self-) reflection/reflexivity in sensitive, qualitative research: A scoping review. Int J Qualitative Methods. 2024;23:16094069241261860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069241261860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim WM. What is qualitative research? An overview and guidelines. Australasian Mark J. 2025;33(2):199&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14413582241264619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zysset AE, Schw&#xe4;rzler P, Dratva J. Seeking health in a digital world: exploring immigrant parents&#x2019; quest for child health Information&#x2014;A scoping review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(19):6804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20196804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10572919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37835074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaks R, Baumann I, Juvalta S, Dratva J. Parental digital health information seeking behavior in switzerland: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2019;19(1):225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-019-6524-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6385444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzpatrick PJ. Improving health literacy using the power of digital communications to achieve better health outcomes for patients and practitioners. Front Digit Health. 2023;5:1264780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2023.1264780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10693297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38046643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Causio FA, Gandolfi S, Kaur J et al. Impact of digital health interventions on health literacy: A systematic review with quality appraisal. MedRxiv. 2025:2025.02. 27.25323025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diviani N, Van Den Putte B, Giani S, van Weert JC. Low health literacy and evaluation of online health information: a systematic review of the literature. J Med Internet Res. 2015;17(5):e112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.4018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4468598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25953147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Fan G, Fan G, Liu D. Exploring nurse and patient perspectives on WeChat-based prenatal education in Chinese public hospitals: a qualitative inquiry. BMC Nurs. 2025;24(1):459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-03108-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12032743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40287699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denecke K, Kaufmann B, Reichenpfader D, Petersen C. How to Consider Health Literacy in Digital Health Interventions? Springer; 2024:259-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeHoff BA, Staten LK, Rodgers RC, Denne SC. The role of online social support in supporting and educating parents of young children with special health care needs in the united states: a scoping review. J Med Internet Res. 2016;18(12):e333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5216258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28007689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird M, Li L, Ouellette C, Hopkins K, McGillion MH, Carter N. Use of synchronous digital health technologies for the care of children with special health care needs and their families: scoping review. JMIR Pediatr Parent. 2019;2(2):e15106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6895870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31750840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall M, Spencer E, Owen H, Roberts N, Heneghan C. Characteristics and efficacy of digital health education: an overview of systematic reviews. Health Educ J. 2018;77(5):497&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0017896918762013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;helin D. Digital empowerment of patients and health providers for collaboration in chronic care. University of Zurich; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones-Esan L, Somasiri N, Lorne K. Enhancing healthcare delivery through digital health interventions: a systematic review on telemedicine and mobile health applications in Low and Middle-Income Countries (LMICs). 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crehan C. <i>Optimising and evaluating usability, acceptability and feasibility of a neonatal digital health system in a low-resource setting: the NeoTree case-study</i>. UCL (University College London); 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthymiou A, Middleton N, Charalambous A, Papastavrou E. The association of health literacy and electronic health literacy with self-efficacy, coping, and caregiving perceptions among carers of people with dementia: research protocol for a descriptive correlational study. JMIR Res Protocols. 2017;6(11):e8080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/resprot.8080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5703980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29133284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W. Self-Efficacy theory perspective: challenges and improvement strategies for elderly people in digital healthcare services. Atlantis. 2025. pp. 106&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mburu CW. Preemie Care: A Co-designed Digital Tool to Improve Communication Between Health Personnel and Parents of Preterm Infants. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antinora C, Taylor-Ducharme S, Asselin S, et al. NeoConnect: the design, implementation, and impact of a virtual family-centered NICU program. J Perinat Neonatal Nurs. 2023;37(1):61&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JPN.0000000000000698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36707750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumner J, Tan SY, Wang Y, et al. Co-designing remote patient monitoring technologies for inpatients: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e58144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/58144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11522647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39405106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietvorst E, de Vries LP, van Eijl S, et al. Effective elements of eHealth interventions for mental health and well-being in children and adolescents: A systematic review. Digit Health. 2024;10:20552076241294105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076241294105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11544686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39525561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D. Clicks, likes, and shares: How Online Health Misinformation is Undermining Healthcare and Implications for Medical Professionals. 2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>