<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41353373</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2056-7529</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research involvement and engagement</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Involv Engagem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Co-production with marginalised workers: working with homecare workers and managers caring for people approaching end-of-life.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40900-025-00814-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Co-production is important due to its effectiveness in creating relevant and meaningful outputs for use in social and healthcare practice, however, frontline staff such as homecare workers (also known as aides, personal assistants or domiciliary care workers providing paid care within the home) are a key group within the social care workforce who are under-represented in this approach. Here, we report our coproduction process engaging with this workforce to develop training resources for workers providing end-of-life homecare.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To co-produce training resources with homecare workers and their managers to support and educate workers delivering end-of-life homecare using evidence from our larger qualitative interview study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a series of 12 co-production workshops with UK-based homecare workers and managers (partners) to design training resources and recommendations for homecare providers informed by research findings. We adopted the five key principles of co-production: Sharing of power; Including all perspectives and skills; Respecting and valuing knowledge; Reciprocity; and Building and maintaining relationships. A co-production advisory group of homecare workers as well as the workshop partners gave valuable oversight throughout the workshop series.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">77 partners (31 homecare workers, 46 managers) participated in 12 workshops (one face-to-face; 11 online). Our approach enabled power-sharing, inclusivity, respect, collaboration and reciprocity, relationship-building, and identification of effective flexible approaches to co-production. Specific forms of training resources were co-created. Training recommendations (content, delivery formats, access during working hours, etc.) were also developed together. Challenges were non-attendance and lack of engagement by some partners during sessions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These workshops are the first, to our knowledge, to successfully co-produce end-of-life care training resources with homecare workers and managers, a poorly represented workforce in co-production. Challenges included inconsistent attendance and poor engagement by a minority of partners. The five key principles of co-production enabled true engagement with the process, thereby enriching the final outputs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayley</LastName><ForeName>Zana</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, The University of Hull, Hull, HU6 7RX, UK. z.bayley@sheffield.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forward</LastName><ForeName>Cat</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health and Social Care Workforce Research Unit, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elliott-Button</LastName><ForeName>Helene</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wolfson Palliative Care Research Centre, Hull York Medical School, The University of Hull, Hull, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krygier</LastName><ForeName>Justine</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wolfson Palliative Care Research Centre, Hull York Medical School, The University of Hull, Hull, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>White</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wolfson Palliative Care Research Centre, Hull York Medical School, The University of Hull, Hull, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pearson</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wolfson Palliative Care Research Centre, Hull York Medical School, The University of Hull, Hull, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker</LastName><ForeName>Liz</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, The University of Hull, Hull, HU6 7RX, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moss</LastName><ForeName>Colin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Involve Hull, Institute for Clinical and Applied Health Research, The University of Hull, Hull, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussain</LastName><ForeName>Jamilla</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bradford Teaching Hospitals Foundation Trust, Bradford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St Luke's Hospice, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Centre for Health and Related Research, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wray</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, The University of Hull, Hull, HU6 7RX, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roberts</LastName><ForeName>Helen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wolfson Palliative Care Research Centre, Hull York Medical School, The University of Hull, Hull, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Miriam J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wolfson Palliative Care Research Centre, Hull York Medical School, The University of Hull, Hull, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NIHR135128</GrantID><Agency>National Institute for Health and Care Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Res Involv Engagem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101708164</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2056-7529</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Access to personalised homecare is crucial for people wishing to remain in their own homes when approaching end-of-life. Most home-based care within the UK is provided by paid, unqualified (a standard professional qualification is not required) carers, often called homecare workers or domiciliary carers. End-of-life care addresses social, psychological, emotional, and physical needs but there is little training that is accessible or available to this workforce. In addition, this workforce is rarely, if ever, involved in the co-production of training resources.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used an approach called co-production to partner with homecare workers and their managers to co-create end-of-life care training resources. The parent study for these workshops included interviews with care recipients and their families, health professionals, and homecare workers and managers and evidenced the key areas of training needed for homecare workers when delivering this type of care. We used this knowledge to co-produce training resources and a set of recommendations for training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Several key aspects of this co-production approach were effective in engaging a workforce rarely considered in co-production activities. There were some challenges such as lack of engagement from some partners.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">As far as we know, this is the first example of successful co-production work partnered with homecare workers and managers to co-create meaningful training material for use in the workplace. Our experience may be helpful for others wishing to conduct co-production work with rarely involved partners.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-creation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Homecare</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: An ethics waiver was provided by Hull York Medical School Ethics Committee (ref.: 22&#x2013;23 38) for co-production involving user testing with researchers and partners rather than research participants. We explained confidentiality of involvement through our documentation &#x2018;Ways of Working&#x2019; and &#x2018;Ground Rules&#x2019; for stakeholders. This included: not disclosing what was discussed, individual contributions would not be identified, and all recordings would be deleted once workshop outcomes were incorporated into the resources. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41353373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12784559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40900-025-00814-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40900-025-00814-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Forward C, Bayley Z, Walker L, Krygier J, White C, Mwaba K, et al. Needs and experiences of homecare workers when supporting people to live at home at the end of life: a rapid review. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2024. 10.1136/spcare-2023-004737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/spcare-2023-004737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11671894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38490719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feliciano DR, Reis-Pina P. Enhancing end-of-life care with home-based palliative interventions: A systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manag. 2024;68:e356&#x2013;72. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39002710/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2024.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39002710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgener AM. Enhancing communication to improve patient safety and to increase patient satisfaction. Health Care Manag. 2020;39(3):128&#x2013;32. 10.1097/hcm.0000000000000165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/hcm.0000000000000165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdy H. Authentic learning in health professions education: Problem-based learning, team-based learning, task-based learning, case-based learning, and the blend. Routledge international handbook of medical education. Routledge; 2015. pp. 128&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahid S, Ekberg S, Holloway M, Jacka C, Yates P, Garvey G, et al. Experiential learning to increase palliative care competence among the Indigenous workforce: an Australian experience. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2019;9:158&#x2013;63. 10.1136/bmjspcare-2016-001296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjspcare-2016-001296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6582728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29353253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata C, Tsutsumi M, Kiyonaga A, Nogaki H. Evaluation of a training program for community-based end-of-life care of older people toward aging in place: a mixed methods study. Nurse Educ Pract. 2021.54 10.1016/j.nepr.2021.103091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34087577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disler APR, Madhuvu DA, Ly L, Pascoe DA, Hickson DH, Wright PJ, et al. Palliative care training gaps remain in chronic disease management post-COVID-19. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2025. 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2025.02.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2025.02.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39971214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masterson D, Laidlaw L. A Co-production values and principles compass to guide along the underused pathway: comment on research Co-production: an underused pathway to impact. Int J Health Policy Manag. 2024;13. 10.34172/ijhpm.8835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith H, Budworth L, Grindey C, Hague I, Hamer N, Kislov R, et al. Co-production practice and future research priorities in united Kingdom-funded applied health research: a scoping review. Health Res Policy Syst. 2022;20(1):36. 10.1186/s12961-022-00838-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12961-022-00838-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35366898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali PA, Salway S, Such E, Dearden A, Willox M. Enhancing health literacy through co-design: development of culturally appropriate materials on genetic risk and customary consanguineous marriage. Prim Health Care Res Dev. 2019;20:e2. 10.1017/S1463423618000038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1463423618000038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6476369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29642973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arblaster K, Mackenzie L, Buus N, Chen T, Gill K, Gomez L, et al. Co-design and evaluation of a multidisciplinary teaching resource on mental health recovery involving people with lived experience. Aust Occup Ther J. 2023;70(3):354&#x2013;65. 10.1111/1440-1630.12859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1440-1630.12859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36704991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janamian T, True A, Dawda P, Wentzel M, Fraser T. Co-creating education and training programs that build workforce capacity to support the implementation of integrated health care initiatives. Med J Aust. 2022;216(Suppl 10):S9&#x2013;13. 10.5694/mja2.51526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/mja2.51526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9328132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35665934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell M, Collier M, Pineda-Pinto M, Cooper C, Nulty F, Castaneda NR. Redefining co-design for social-ecological research and practice: A systematic literature review. Environ Sci Policy. 2025;164. 10.1016/j.envsci.2025.103998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staniszewska S, Brett J, Simera I, Seers K, Mackford C, Goodlad S, et al. GRIPP2 reporting checklists: tools to improve reporting of patient and public involvement in research. BMJ. 2017. 10.1136/bmj.j3453. 358J3453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j3453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28768629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beresford B, O&#x2019;Rourke G. Doing research on homecare: the views and experiences of UK homecare providers and researchers. J long Term Care. 2024;0:334&#x2013;45. 10.31389/jltc.250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31389/jltc.250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Audit Office. The Adult Social Care Market in England [Internet]. 2021 [cited 2025 May 26]. Available from: https://www.nao.org.uk/press-releases/adult-social-care-markets/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes S. Domiciliary care, self and older age [dissertation]. Anglia Ruskin University; 2023. https://hdl.handle.net/10779/aru.23760969.v1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falzarano FB, Cimarolli V, Boerner K, Siedlecki KL, Horowitz A. Use of home care services reduces care-Related strain in Long-Distance caregivers. Gerontologist. 2021;62(2):252&#x2013;61. 10.1093/geront/gnab088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/geront/gnab088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8827323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34166493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindell C, Coates E, Croot L, O&#x2019;Cathain A. The use of co-production, co-design, and co-creation to mobilise knowledge in the management of health conditions: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):877. 10.1186/s12913-022-08079-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-08079-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9264579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35799251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayley Z, Bothma J, Bravington A, Forward C, Hussain J, Manthorpe J, et al. Supported: Supporting, enabling, and sustaining homecare workers to deliver end-of-life care: A qualitative study protocol. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(12). 10.1371/journal.pone.0291525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10718427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38091299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott-Button HL, Mwaba K, Bayley Z, Bothma J, Forward C, Hussain J, Krygier J, Pearson M, Taylor P, White C, Wray J. Policy gaps regarding social homecare in the context of end-of-life; a policy document analysis. MedRxiv. 2025 Jul;15:2025&#x2013;07.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White C, Forward C, Bayley Z, Elliott-Button H, Krygier J, Bravington A, Begum S, Bothma J, Hussain J, Johnson M, Moss C. Experiences of delivering social homecare at end-of life: insights from a qualitative study drawing on multiple perspectives. MedRxiv. 2025 Jul 14:2025&#x2013;07.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayley Z, Forward C, White C, Elliott-Button HL, Krygier J, Walker L, Pearson M, Hussein J, Taylor PM, Wray J, Roberts A. Addressing barriers to interprofessional working with homecare workers in community palliative care: insights from a multi-site qualitative case study in England. MedRxiv. 2025 Aug;15:2025&#x2013;08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12779770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41277395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangill C, Buus N, Hybholt L, Berring LL. Service user&#x2019;s actual involvement in mental health research practices: a scoping review. Int J Ment Health Nurs. 2019;28(4):798&#x2013;815. 10.1111/inm.12594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/inm.12594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30938019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIHR. Guidance on co-producing a research project [Internet]. 2024 https://www.learningforinvolvement.org.uk/content/resource/nihr-guidance-on-co-producing-a-research-project/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks CF, Lund S, Kryl D, Lloyd Jones S, Myall M. We all see things through a different lens based on our life experiences: co-production of a web-based implementation toolkit with stakeholders across the health and social care system. Front Health Serv. 2024;4:1356961. 10.3389/frhs.2024.1356961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frhs.2024.1356961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11133535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38812599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beresford P. Public participation in health and social care: exploring the co-production of knowledge. Front Social. 2019;3:41. 10.3389/fsoc.2018.00041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsoc.2018.00041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gremyr A, Andersson Gare B, Thor J, Elwyn G, Batalden P, Andersson AC. The role of co-production in learning health systems. LntJ Qual Health Care. 2021;33(Suppl 2):ii26&#x2013;32. 10.1093/intqhc/mzab072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzab072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8849120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34849971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boaz A, Borst R, Kok M, O&#x2019;Shea A. How Far does an emphasis on stakeholder engagement and co&#xad; production in research present a threat to academic identity and autonomy? A prospective study across five European countries. Res EvaI. 2021;30(3):361&#x2013;9. 10.1093/reseval/rvab013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/reseval/rvab013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell J, Lim A, Williams R, Girdler S, Milbourn B, Black M. Nothing about Us without Us&#x2019;: co-production ingredients for working alongside stakeholders to develop mental health interventions. Adv Ment Health. 2023;21(1):4&#x2013;16. 10.1080/18387357.2021.2020143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/18387357.2021.2020143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filipe A, Renedo A, Marston C. The co-production of what? Knowledge, values, and social relations in health care. PLoS Biol. 2017;15(5):e2001403. 10.1371/journal.pbio.2001403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5414996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bovill C. A co-creation of learning and teaching typology: what kind of co-creation are you planning or doing? Int J Stud Partners. 2019;3(2):91&#x2013;8. 10.15173/ijsap.v3i2.3953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15173/ijsap.v3i2.3953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr M, Davies P, Andrews H, Bagnall D, Brangan E, Davies R. Co-producing knowledge in health and social care research: reflections on the challenges and ways to enable more equal relationships. Humanit Soc Sci Commun. 2021;8(1). 10.1057/s41599-021-00782-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attal B, Leeding J, van der Scheer JW, Barry Z, Crookes E, Igwe S, et al. Integrating patient and public involvement into co-design of healthcare improvement: a case study in maternity care. BMC Health Serv Res. 2025;25(1):352. 10.1186/s12913-025-12423-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-025-12423-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11889828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40055700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams 0, Robert G, Martin GP, Hanna E, O&#x2019;Hara J. Is Co-production just really good PPI? Making sense of patient and public involvement and Co-production networks. In: Bevir M, Waring J, editors. Decentring health and care Networks. Organizational behaviour in healthcare. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan; 2020. 10.1007/978-3-030-40889-3_10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahlmark N, Algren MH, Holmberg T, Norredam ML, Nielsen SS, Blom AB, et al. Survey nonresponse among ethnic minorities in a National health survey &#x2014; a mixed-method study of participation, barriers, and potentials. Ethn Health. 2015;20(6):611&#x2013;32. 10.1080/13557858.2014.979768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13557858.2014.979768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25411892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auh S, Bell SJ, McLeod CS, Shih E. When does customer participation matter? An empirical examination of perceived impact and worth. J Serv Res. 2019;22(2):169&#x2013;84. 10.1177/1094670518820197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massey M. Survey practice in Non-Survey-Literate populations: lessons learned from a cognitive interview study in Brazil. Surv Pract. 2025;19(SI). 10.29115/SP-2024-0035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11987661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40224398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyot M, Pelgrims I, Aerts R, Keune H, Remmen R, De Clercq E, et al. Non-response bias in the analysis of the association between mental health and the urban environment: a cross-sectional study in Brussels, Belgium. Arch Public Health. 2023;81:129. 10.1186/s13690-023-01118-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-023-01118-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10327324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37420293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearsley SL, Walker L, Johnson MJ, Bravington A. Ancillary hospital workers experience during COVID- 19: systematic review and narrative synthesis. BMJ Support Palliat Care. 2024;14(e2):e1635&#x2013;48. 10.1136/spcare-2024-004855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/spcare-2024-004855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39084691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>