<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851752</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1747-597X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Substance abuse treatment, prevention, and policy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Subst Abuse Treat Prev Policy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Postpartum women's motivation for substance use recovery: an exploratory qualitative study of recovery capital.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13011-026-00718-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Canada is facing a national opioid crisis, with an average of 20 opioid-related deaths reported daily. Postpartum women who use non-prescription opioids and unregulated substances are at high risk of relapse and overdose. They also face significant health and social challenges that create barriers to successful, long-term recovery. While many women reduce or stop substance use during pregnancy, sustained recovery in the postpartum period remains a challenge. Despite this, little research has explored the personal, social, and structural factors, collectively conceptualized as recovery capital, that sustain motivation for recovery after birth. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to explore the factors that influence motivation for recovery among postpartum women with a history of substance use, with particular attention to the personal, social, and structural dimensions of recovery capital.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An exploratory qualitative design was used to capture the experiences of 16 postpartum women in Saskatchewan, Canada, who had given birth within the previous two years and were in recovery from non-prescription opioid or unregulated substance use for at least three months. Participants were recruited through public health and treatment agencies. Semi-structured interviews were conducted in-person or by phone and analyzed using Braun and Clarke's six-phase thematic analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The sample (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;16) was primarily Indigenous (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;14), predominantly in their twenties, and single (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;14), with most participants having a high school education or less, low household income, and limited employment. Thematic analysis identified four themes: (1) the impact of limited accessibility on recovery, (2) parenthood as a motivator, (3) the role of peer, family, and professional support systems, and (4) the transformative power of resilience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Postpartum women with substance use disorders are highly motivated to recover, often driven by their roles as mothers. However, motivation alone is not enough without adequate recovery capital, including access to integrated, trauma-informed, and culturally safe treatment, social supports, and structural resources. Findings highlight the importance of expanding substance use programs that address structural barriers, promote resilience, and include peer, family, and professional supports. Comprehensive, strength-based treatment models are critical to sustaining and supporting long-term recovery for postpartum women.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bigalky</LastName><ForeName>Jodie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, University of Saskatchewan, 107 Wiggins Road, Saskatoon, SK, S7N 5E5, Canada. jodie.bigalky@usask.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mackey</LastName><ForeName>April</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, University of Saskatchewan, 107 Wiggins Road, Saskatoon, SK, S7N 5E5, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Essien</LastName><ForeName>Etieno</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, University of Saskatchewan, 107 Wiggins Road, Saskatoon, SK, S7N 5E5, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bahrey</LastName><ForeName>Ava</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, University of Saskatchewan, 107 Wiggins Road, Saskatoon, SK, S7N 5E5, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petrucka</LastName><ForeName>Pammla</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, University of Saskatchewan, 107 Wiggins Road, Saskatoon, SK, S7N 5E5, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Subst Abuse Treat Prev Policy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101258060</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1747-597X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motivation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perinatal health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postpartum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Substance use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women&#x2019;s health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the University of Saskatchewan Research Ethics Board (Beh-5070). All participants provided written informed consent prior to enrollment in the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable, this study does not contain data from an individual person. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13011-026-00718-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13011-026-00718-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ledlie S, Juurlink DN, Tadrous M, Mamdani M, Paterson JM, Gomes T. Opioid-related deaths between 2019 and 2021 across 9 Canadian provinces and territories. Can Med Assoc J (CMAJ). 2024;196(14):E469&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1503/cmaj.231339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Canada. Opioid-and stimulant-related harms in Canada. 2025. https://health-infobase.canada.ca/substance-related-harms/opioids-stimulants/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigalky J, Mackey A, Tooke N, Khoshnoodi R, Petrucka P. Navigating recovery: a scoping review of comprehensive approaches to postpartum substance use care and support. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):3231. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-025-23448-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin CE, Parlier-Ahmad AB. Addiction treatment in the postpartum period: an opportunity for evidence-based personalized medicine. Int Rev Psychiatr Psychiatry. 2021;33(6):579&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1080/09540261.2021.1898349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazel S, Alexander K, Cioffi C, Terplan M. Interventions to support engagement in addiction care postpartum: principles and pitfalls. Subst Abuse Rehabil. 2023;14:49&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.2147/SAR.S375652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nidey N, Kair LR, Wilder C, Froehlich TE, Weber S, Folger A, et al. Substance use and utilization of prenatal and postpartum care. J Addict Med. 2022;16(1):84&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1097/ADM.0000000000000843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams ZM, Ginapp CM, Price CR, Qin Y, Madden LM, Yonkers K, et al. &#x201c;A good mother&#x201d;: impact of motherhood identity on women&#x2019;s substance use and engagement in treatment across the lifespan. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2021;130:108474. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsat.2021.108474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S, Rosenbloom D, Stein MD, Raifman J, Clark J. Differential gateways, facilitators, and barriers to substance use disorder treatment for pregnant women and mothers: a scoping systematic review. Addict Med. 2022;16(3):e185&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1097/ADM.0000000000000909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frazer Z, McConnell K, Jansson LM. Treatment for substance use disorders in pregnant women: motivators and barriers. Drug Alcohol Depen. 2019;205(1):107652. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2019.107652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holcomb L, Treado B, Mayo R, Cartmell K, Dickes L, Barkin J, et al. &#x201c;If we didn&#x2019;t have our babies, we wouldn&#x2019;t be here right now&#x201d;: a qualitative exploration of new motherhood while navigating substance use disorder recovery. Subst Use Addict J. 2025;29767342251331398. https://doi.org/10.1177/29767342251331398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirani S, Sandhu M, Bandara NA, Bungay V, Twomey M. Understanding parenting and pregnant women&#x2019;s perceptions of accessing, utilizing, and barriers to seeking social support for mental well-being. Behavioral Sci. 2025;15(3):348. https://doi.org/10.3390/bs15030348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigalky J. Who cares for the mothers? A narrative inquiry exploring substance use disorders among pregnant women. Int Health Trends Perspectives. 2023;3(2):216&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.32920/ihtp.v3i2.1806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cloud W, Granfield R. Natural recovery from substance dependency: lessons for treatment providers. J Soc Work Pract The Addictions. 2001;1:83&#x2013;104. https://doi.org/10.1300/J160v01n01_07.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cloud W, Granfield R. Conceptualizing recovery capital: expansion of a theoretical construct. Subst Use Misuse. 2008;43, 1971-1986. doi: https://doi.org/10.1080/10826080802289762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granfield R, Cloud W. Coming clean: overcoming addiction without treatment. New York University Press; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day E, Pechey LC, Roscoe S, Kelly JF. Recovery support services as part of a continuum of care for alcohol or drug use disorders. Addiction. 2025;1&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1111/add.16751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersen G, Bjerke T, Hoxmark EM, Sterri NHE, Rosenvinge JH. From existing to living: exploring the meaning of recovery and a sober life after a long duration of a substance use disorder. Nord Stud Alcohol Drugs. 2023;40(6):577&#x2013;89. https://doi.org/10.1177/14550725231170454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennessy E. Recovery capital: a systematic review of the literature. Addict Res Theory. 2017;25(5):349&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1080/16066359.2017.1297990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health Agency of Canada. What mothers say: the Canadian maternity experiences survey. 2009. https://www.canada.ca/content/dam/phac-aspc/migration/phac-aspc/rhs-ssg/pdf/survey-eng.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber A, Miskle B, Lynch A, Arndt S, Acion L. Substance use in pregnancy: identifying stigma and improving care. Subst Abuse Rehabil. 2021;12:105&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.2147/SAR.S319180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigalky J, Mackey A, Serrano O, Petrucka P. Beyond the 1%: advocating for comprehensive data on perinatal substance use in Canada. Can J Nurs Leadersh. 2025;38(1):44&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.12927/cjnl.2025.27657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman DJ, Saunders EC, Wolff KB. In their own words: a qualitative study of factors promoting resilience and recovery among postpartum women with opioid use disorders. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(178):1&#x2013;10. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12884-020-02872-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright ME, Temples HS, Shores E, Chafe O, Lannamann R, Lautenschlager C. Pregnant and parenting women&#x2019;s experiences with substance use disorder. Am J Intellect Dev Disabil J Maternal Child Nurs. 2021;46(5):271&#x2013;76. https://doi.org/10.1097/NMC.0000000000000741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cainelli E, Vedovelli L, Bisiacchi P. The mother-child interface: a neurobiological metamorphosis. Neuroscience. 2024;561:92&#x2013;106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2024.10.027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forray A, Merry B, Lin H, Ruger JP, Yonkers KA. Perinatal substance use: a prospective evaluation of abstinence and relapse. Drug Alcohol Depen. 2015;150:147&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.02.027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malterud K, Siersma VD, Guassora AD. Sample size in qualitative interview studies: guided by information power. Innovative Methods. 2016;26(13):1753&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1177/1049732315617444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clark V. Thematic analysis: a practical guide. Sage; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumivero. Nvivo (version 14). [Software]. 2023. https://lumivero.com/products/nvivo/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln YS, Guba EG. Naturalistic inquiry. Sage Publications; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole N, Isaac B. Barriers to treatment for substance-using mothers. British Columbia Centre for Women&#x2019;s Health; 2001. https://cewh.ca/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/2001_Apprehensions-Barriers-to-Treatment-for-Substance- Using-Mothers.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proulx D, Fantasia HC. The lived experience of postpartum women attending outpatient substance treatment for opioid or heroin use. J Midwifery Womens Health. 2021;66:211&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.1111/jmwh.13165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schempf AH, Strobino DM. Drug use and limited prenatal care: an examination of responsible barriers. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2009;200(4, 412,):e1&#x2013;412.e10. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajog.2008.10.055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass R, Flinchum G, Ramage M, Galvin SL, Cabello-De la Garza A, Caron O, et al. Accessing perinatal substance use disorder care in your local community: a case study of an innovative hub and spoke network in western North Carolina. J Educ Chang Subst Use Addict Treat. 2024;158:209268. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.josat.2023.209268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanon BM, Tsetso K, Tanche K, Morton Ninomiya ME. Effective health and wellness systems for rural and remote Indigenous communities: a rapid review. Int J Circumpolar Health. 2023;82(1):2215553. https://doi.org/10.1080/22423982.2023.2215553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen A, Bueno Y, Mallahan S, MacPherson AH, Armin J. Opportunities to expand postpartum support for those in recovery from opioid use disorder: results from a qualitative study. Drug Alcohol Depend Rep. 2023;7:100170. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dadr.2023.100170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen L, Wodtke L, Hayward A, Read C, Cyr M, Cidro J. Pregnant and early parenting Indigenous women who use substances in Canada: a scoping review of health and social issues, supports, and strategies. J Ethnicity Subst Abuse. 2023;22(4):827&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1080/15332640.2022.2043799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman DJ, Saunders EC, Frew JR, Arsan C, Xie H, Bonasia KL, et al. Integrated vs nonintegrated treatment for perinatal opioid use disorder: retrospective cohort study. Am J Obstet Gynecology MFM. 2022;4(1):100489. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajogmf.2021.100489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutman D, Hubberstey C, Poole N, Schmidt RA, Van Bibber M. Multi-service prevention programs for pregnant and parenting women with substance use and multiple vulnerabilities: program structure and clients&#x2019; perspectives on wraparound programming. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20(1):441. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12884-020-03109-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarasoff LA, Milligan K, Le TL, Usher AM, Urbanoski K. Integrated treatment programs for pregnant and parenting women with problematic substance use: service descriptions and client perceptions of care. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2018;90:9&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsat.2018.04.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce S, Piske M, Norris C, W ES, Barker B, David R, et al. &#x201c;There was no services that I could access so I just stayed on the street &#x2026; using until I went into labour.&#x201d;: a qualitative study of accessibility and cultural safety of services for perinatal substance use in British Columbia, Canada. J Educ Chang Subst Use Addict Treat. 2025;169:209604. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.josat.2024.209604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathias H, Foster LA, Rushton A. Programs and practices that support pregnant people who use drugs&#x2019; access to sexual and reproductive health care in Canada: a scoping review. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2024;24(1):72. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12884-023-06225-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin KA, Marsh TN, Eshakakogan C, Eibl JK, Spence M, Gauthier G, et al. Community trial evaluating the integration of Indigenous healing practices and a harm reduction approach with principles of seeking safety in an Indigenous residential treatment program in northern Ontario. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):1045. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-022-08406-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renbarger KM. Factors influencing maternal substance use and recovery in the perinatal period. West J Nurs Res. 2024;46(9):725&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.1177/01939459241266736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darlington CK, Clark R, Jacoby SF, Terplan M, Alexander K, Compton P. Outcomes and experiences after child custody loss among mothers who use drugs: a mixed studies systematic review. Drug Alcohol Depen. 2023;251:110944. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2023.110944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jirikowic T, Graham JC, Grant T. A trauma-informed parenting intervention model for mothers parenting young children during residential treatment for substance use disorder. Occup Ther Ment Health. 2023;39(2):156&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1080/0164212X.2022.2089315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen P, Mackean T, Walker N, Coombes J, Bennett-Brook K, Clapham K, et al. Integrating trauma and violence informed care in primary health care settings for First Nations women experiencing violence: a systematic review. Trauma Violence Abuse Abuse. 2022;23(4):1204&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.1177/1524838020985571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanojlovi&#x107; M, Davidson L. Targeting the barriers in the substance use disorder continuum of care with peer recovery support. Subst Abuse Res Treat. 2021;15:1178221820976988. https://doi.org/10.1177/1178221820976988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collinson B, Hall L. The role of social mechanisms of change in women&#x2019;s addiction recovery. Drugs Educ Prev Policy. 2021;28(5):426&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1080/09687637.2021.1929077.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holcomb L, Koob C, Treado B, Mayo R, Cartmell KB, Barkin J, et al. Recovery together: the socioecological impact of social networks on postpartum substance use disorder recovery. Community Ment Health J. 2025;61:1471&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10597-025-01482-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternberger L, Sorensen-Alawad A, Prescott T, Sakai H, Brown K, Finkelstein N, et al. Lessons learned serving pregnant, postpartum, and parenting people with substance use disorders in Massachusetts: the Moms Do Care program. Matern Child Health J. 2023;27(1):67&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10995-023-03775-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingel S, Barberi D, Rudes DS, Taxman FS. Lessons learned from a peer support program for individuals seeking substance use recovery. J Offender Rehabil. 2022;61(8):411&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1080/10509674.2022.2128151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadowen C, Jallo N, Parlier-Ahmad AB, Brown L, Kinser P, Svikis D, et al. What recovery means to postpartum women in treatment for opioid use disorder. Women&#x2019;s Health Rep. 2022;3(1):93&#x2013;103. https://doi.org/10.1089/whr.2021.0064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusco RA, Kulkarni SJ, Pless J. &#x201c;He gets mad that I&#x2019;m sober&#x201d;: experiences of substance use coercion among postpartum women in recovery. J Educ Chang Subst Use Addict Treat. 2024;164:209407. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.josat.2024.209407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bann CM, Okoniewski KC, Clarke L, Wilson-Costello D, Merhar S, DeMauro S, et al. Psychological distress among postpartum women who took opioids during pregnancy: the role of perceived stigma in healthcare settings. Arch Women&#x2019;s Ment Health. 2024;27(2):275&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00737-023-01390-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merritt Z, Burduli E, Purath J, Smart D. Exploring perceptions of health care providers in caring for pregnant women with substance use disorder. J Obstet Gynecol Neonatal Nurs. 2022;51(4):S87. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jogn.2022.05.109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syvertsen JL, Howard H, Spadola CE, Madden DR, Clapp JD, Toneff H. Conceptualizing stigma in contexts of pregnancy and opioid misuse: a qualitative study with women and healthcare providers in Ohio. Drug Alcohol Depen. 2021;222:108677. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2021.108677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett ER, Knight E, Herman RJ, Amarakaran K, Jankowski MK. Difficult binds: a systematic review of facilitators and barriers to treatment among mothers with substance use disorders. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2021;126, Article 108341. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsat.2021.108341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorvine MM, Haynes TF, Marshall SA, Clark CJ, Lovelady NN, Zaller ND. A qualitative exploration of women&#x2019;s lives and resilience in substance use disorder recovery. Intgr Med. 2021;20(3):20&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Meyer F, Roets G, Vanderplasschen W, De Ruysscher C. From (in)dependence to interdependence: a qualitative study on multiplicity in assemblages of agency and addiction recovery. Health. 2025;13634593251342997. https://doi.org/10.1177/13634593251342997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurice R, Vaccaro M, Greene S, Griffith G. Strengths-based support for pregnant, birthing, and parenting individuals who use drugs. In: Strengths-based practice in adult social work and social care. Routledge; 2025. p. 155&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>