<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41824542</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The 5G COVID-19 Digital Wildfire: An evolving network of Twitter contacts to explore phase transition metaphors in viral misinformation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0343661</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0343661</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0343661</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0343661</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Shortly after the first COVID-19 cases became apparent in December 2019, rumors spread on social media suggesting a connection between the virus and the 5G radiation emanating from the recently deployed telecommunications network. In the course of the following weeks, this idea gained increasing popularity, and various alleged explanations for how such a connection manifests emerged. Ultimately, after being amplified by prominent conspiracy theorists, a series of arson attacks on telecommunication equipment followed, concluding with the kidnapping of telecommunication technicians in Peru. In this paper, we study the spread of content related to a conspiracy theory with harmful consequences, a so-called Digital Wildfire (DW). In particular, we investigate the 5G and COVID-19 DW on Twitter before, during, and after its peak in April and May 2020. For this purpose, we examine the community dynamics in complex temporal interaction networks underlying Twitter user activity. We assess the evolution of this particular DW by appropriately defining the temporal dynamics of communication in communities within social networks. We observe that, for this specific DW, the number of interactions of the users participating in the DW, as well as the size of the engaged communities, both exhibit visual patterns suggestive of power-law distributions, consistent with other social networks, though based on exploratory inspection rather than formal statistical tests. Moreover, our exploratory analysis elucidates the possibility of conceptualizing the phases of a DW, as per established literature. We identify one such phase as a potential critical shift, marked by a shift from sporadic tweets to a global spreading event, highlighting patterns suggestive of dramatic scaling in misinformation propagation, used heuristically without quantitative physical parameters. Additionally, we argue that patterns suggest the observed shift is associated with influential users, who appear to amplify the spread of misinformation, though causality is exploratory. Lastly, our data suggest that the characteristics of such events could contribute to prediction models, at least in some instances. From this data, we hypothesize that monitoring minor peaks in user interactions, which precede the critical phase culminating in real-world consequences, could serve as an early warning system, aiding in the anticipation and potentially the mitigation of DWs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 G&#xe5;sv&#xe6;r et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xe5;sv&#xe6;r</LastName><ForeName>Kaspara Skovli</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics and Center for Computing in Science Education, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lind</LastName><ForeName>Pedro G</ForeName><Initials>PG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Economics, Innovation and Technology, Kristiania University of Applied Sciences, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, OsloMet-Oslo Metropolitan University, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langguth</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4200-511X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for High Performance Computing, Simula Research Laboratory, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hjorth-Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Morten</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0174-1364</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics and Center for Computing in Science Education, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreil</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bayerischer Rundfunk, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schroeder</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Thilo</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0125-5243</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Sustainable Communication Technologies, SINTEF, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061108" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Media</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Communication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086402" MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000075923" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wildfires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010568" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Peru</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019365" MajorTopicYN="N">Metaphor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41824542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12987581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0343661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-12853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>A Brief History of the Internet by the Board of Regents of the University System of Georgia. Available from: https://www.usg.edu/galileo/skills/unit07/internet07_02.phtml</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peattie S. The Internet as a Medium for Communicating with Teenagers. Soc Market Quart. 2007;13(2):21&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1080/15245000701326343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15245000701326343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>boyd danah m., Ellison NB. Social Network Sites: Definition, History, and Scholarship. J Comput-Mediat Commun. 2007;13(1):210&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1111/j.1083-6101.2007.00393.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1083-6101.2007.00393.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Network IFC. IFCN&#x2018;s code of principles transparency report for 2020. Report.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton K, Blair S, Busam JA, Forstner S, Glance J, Green G, et al. Real Solutions for Fake News? Measuring the Effectiveness of General Warnings and Fact-Check Tags in Reducing Belief in False Stories on Social Media. Polit Behav. 2019;42(4):1073&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1007/s11109-019-09533-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11109-019-09533-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Data R. Put More of Your Business Data to Work&#x2014;From Edge to Cloud. A Seagate Technology Report-2020. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder DT, Cha M, Baronchelli A, Bostrom N, Christakis NA, Garcia D, et al. How Malicious AI Swarms Can Threaten Democracy. 2025. Available from: https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.06299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41570131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banaji S, Bhat R, Agarwal A, Passanha N, Sadhana PM. WhatsApp vigilantes: An exploration of citizen reception and circulation of WhatsApp misinformation linked to mob violence in India. London School of Economics and Political Science; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twickel Nv. Fake twitter account pumps up oil prices. 2012. Available from: https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2012/08/07/fake-twitter-account-pumps-up-oil-prices-a16852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas S. Social Media and the India Exodus. 2012. Available from: https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-19292572</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher M, Cox JW, Hermann P. Pizzagate: From rumor, to hashtag, to gunfire in DC. Washington Post. 2016;6:8410&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell L. Digital wildfires in a hyperconnected world. 2013. Available from: http://reports.weforum.org/global-risks-2013/risk-case-1/digital-wildfires-in-a-hyperconnected-world/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts DJ. A simple model of global cascades on random networks. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2002;99(9):5766&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1073/pnas.082090499</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.082090499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC122850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16578874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen K, Moloney NR. Complexity and criticality. Imperial College University Press; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langguth J, Filkukov&#xe1; P, Brenner S, Schroeder DT, Pogorelov K. COVID-19 and 5G conspiracy theories: long term observation of a digital wildfire. Int J Data Sci Anal. 2023;15(3):329&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1007/s41060-022-00322-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41060-022-00322-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9137448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35669096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Conroy NJ, Rubin VL. Misleading online content: recognizing clickbait as &#x201c;false news&#x201d;. In: Proceedings of the 2015 ACM on workshop on multimodal deception detection. 2015. p. 15&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Lamba H, Kumaraguru P, Joshi A. Faking sandy: characterizing and identifying fake images on twitter during hurricane sandy. In: Proceedings of the 22nd international conference on World Wide Web. 2013. p. 729&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo C, Mendoza M, Poblete B. Information credibility on twitter. In: Proceedings of the 20th international conference on World wide web. 2011. p. 675&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1145/1963405.1963500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/1963405.1963500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruchansky N, Seo S, Liu Y. Csi: A hybrid deep model for fake news detection. In: Proceedings of the 2017 ACM on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management. 2017. p. 797&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Z, Cao J, Zhang Y, Luo J. News Verification by Exploiting Conflicting Social Viewpoints in Microblogs. AAAI. 2016;30(1). doi: 10.1609/aaai.v30i1.10382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v30i1.10382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pogorelov K, Schroeder DT, Burchard L, Moe J, Brenner S, Filkukova P, et al. FakeNews: Corona Virus and 5G Conspiracy Task at MediaEval 2020. In: MediaEval; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pogorelov K, Schroeder DT, Brenner S, Maulana A, Langguth J. Combining tweets and connections graph for fakenews detection at mediaeval 2022. In: Multimedia Benchmark Workshop; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder DT, Schaal F, Filkukova P, Pogorelov K, Langguth J. WICO Graph: a Labeled Dataset of Twitter Subgraphs based on Conspiracy Theory and 5G-Corona Misinformation Tweets. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vosoughi S, Roy D, Aral S. The spread of true and false news online. Science. 2018;359(6380):1146&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1126/science.aap9559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aap9559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29590045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman MEJ, Girvan M. Finding and evaluating community structure in networks. Phys Rev E Stat Nonlin Soft Matter Phys. 2004;69(2 Pt 2):026113. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevE.69.026113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.69.026113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14995526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blondel VD, Guillaume J-L, Lambiotte R, Lefebvre E. Fast unfolding of communities in large networks. J Stat Mech. 2008;2008(10):P10008. doi: 10.1088/1742-5468/2008/10/p10008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-5468/2008/10/p10008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traag VA, Waltman L, van Eck NJ. From Louvain to Leiden: guaranteeing well-connected communities. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):5233. doi: 10.1038/s41598-019-41695-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-41695-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6435756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30914743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starbird K. Examining the Alternative Media Ecosystem Through the Production of Alternative Narratives of Mass Shooting Events on Twitter. ICWSM. 2017;11(1):230&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1609/icwsm.v11i1.14878</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/icwsm.v11i1.14878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Vicario M, Bessi A, Zollo F, Petroni F, Scala A, Caldarelli G, et al. The spreading of misinformation online. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(3):554&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1517441113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1517441113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4725489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26729863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friggeri A, Adamic L, Eckles D, Cheng J. Rumor Cascades. ICWSM. 2014;8(1):101&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1609/icwsm.v8i1.14559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/icwsm.v8i1.14559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelion L. Coronavirus: 20 suspected phone mast attacks over Easter. 2020. Available from: https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-52281315</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staff R. False claim: Video shows a 5g mast burning in Nigeria. 2020. Available from: https://www.reuters.com/article/uk-factcheck-5g-nigeria-burning-idUSKBN22225W</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamoureux M. It looks like the 5G conspiracy theory fires have arrived in Canada. 2020. Available from: https://www.vice.com/en/article/g5px8x/5g-conspiracy-theory-coronavirus-cell-tower-fires-canada</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pogorelov K, Schroeder DT, Filkukov&#xe1; P, Brenner S, Langguth J. Wico text: a labeled dataset of conspiracy theory and 5g-corona misinformation tweets. In: Proceedings of the 2021 Workshop on Open Challenges in Online Social Networks. 2021. p. 21&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins K. Violence, arson, abuse: The real-world consequences of those false 5G conspiracies. 2020. Available from: https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/fake-5g-coronavirus-theories-have-real-world-consequences/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert P. Vodacom, MTN towers burnt in SA by alleged 5G conspiracy theorists. 2021. Available from: http://www.connectingafrica.com/author.asp?section_id=761doc_id=766499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staff N. Police say cell phone tower fire in Scarborough considered arson; 2021. Available from: https://toronto.citynews.ca/2021/03/31/fire-crews-battle-burning-cell-phone-tower-in-scarborough/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley HE. Introduction to Phase Transitions and Critical Phenomena. Oxford University Press; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder DT, Langguth J, Burchard L, Pogorelov K, Lind PG. The connectivity network underlying the German&#x2019;s Twittersphere: a testbed for investigating information spreading phenomena. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):4085. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-07961-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-07961-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8902855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35260708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder DT, Pogorelov K, Langguth J. FACT: a Framework for Analysis and Capture of Twitter Graphs. In: 2019 Sixth International Conference on Social Networks Analysis, Management and Security (SNAMS). 2019. p. 134&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1109/snams.2019.8931870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/snams.2019.8931870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burchard L, Schroeder DT, Becker S, Langguth J. Resource Efficient Algorithms for Message Sampling in Online Social Networks. In: 2020 Seventh International Conference on Social Networks Analysis, Management and Security (SNAMS). 2020. p. 1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1109/snams52053.2020.9336530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/snams52053.2020.9336530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barabasi A, Albert R. Emergence of scaling in random networks. Science. 1999;286(5439):509&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1126/science.286.5439.509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.286.5439.509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10521342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortunato S. Community detection in graphs. Physics Reports. 2010;486(3&#x2013;5):75&#x2013;174. doi: 10.1016/j.physrep.2009.11.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physrep.2009.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faloutsos M, Faloutsos P, Faloutsos C. On power-law relationships of the Internet topology. SIGCOMM Comput Commun Rev. 1999;29(4):251&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1145/316194.316229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/316194.316229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamic LA, Huberman BA. Power-Law Distribution of the World Wide Web. Science. 2000;287(5461):2115&#x2013;2115. doi: 10.1126/science.287.5461.2115a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.287.5461.2115a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong H, Tombor B, Albert R, Oltvai ZN, Barab&#xe1;si AL. The large-scale organization of metabolic networks. Nature. 2000;407(6804):651&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1038/35036627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/35036627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11034217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Alderson D, Doyle JC, Willinger W. Towards a Theory of Scale-Free Graphs: Definition, Properties, and Implications. Internet Mathematics. 2005;2(4):431&#x2013;523. doi: 10.1080/15427951.2005.10129111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15427951.2005.10129111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauset A, Shalizi CR, Newman MEJ. Power-Law Distributions in Empirical Data. SIAM Rev. 2009;51(4):661&#x2013;703. doi: 10.1137/070710111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1137/070710111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mislove A, Marcon M, Gummadi KP, Druschel P, Bhattacharjee B. Measurement and analysis of online social networks. In: Proceedings of the 7th ACM SIGCOMM conference on Internet measurement. 2007. p. 29&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1145/1298306.1298311</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/1298306.1298311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert R, Barab&#xe1;si A-L. Statistical mechanics of complex networks. Rev Mod Phys. 2002;74(1):47&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1103/revmodphys.74.47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/revmodphys.74.47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama Y, Fukui M, Kikuchi M, Hasebe K, Nakayama A, Nishinari K, et al. Traffic jams without bottlenecks&#x2014;experimental evidence for the physical mechanism of the formation of a jam. New J Phys. 2008;10(3):033001. doi: 10.1088/1367-2630/10/3/033001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1367-2630/10/3/033001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moussa&#xef;d M, K&#xe4;mmer JE, Analytis PP, Neth H. Social influence and the collective dynamics of opinion formation. PLoS One. 2013;8(11):e78433. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0078433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0078433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3818331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24223805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen K, Moloney NR. Complexity and criticality. vol. 1. Imperial College Press; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts DJ, Dodds PS. Influentials, networks, and public opinion formation. J Consum Res. 2007;34(4):441&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>