<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41354941</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2044-8341</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychology and psychotherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychol Psychother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hearing voices and the quest for autonomy: An interpretative phenomenological analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/papt.70026</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Hearing voices is often experienced as being controlling, powerful, threatening or critical. This study aimed to examine the lived experiences of autonomy among people who hear voices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Employing a qualitative design, this study sought to examine the personal narratives and meaning-making processes of voice hearers and gain deeper insights into the nuanced ways autonomy is experienced, diminished, attempted, re-established and constructed by those who hear voices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">In-depth semi-structured phenomenological interviews with six voice hearers were analysed using interpretative phenomenological analysis to capture the ways participants interpret and respond to their experiences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Participants' accounts revealed that autonomy was continuously negotiated, requiring reflection, adaptation and self-regulation. Three superordinate themes were identified in the data. First, participants reflected on how hearing voices challenged their sense of self, individuality and the space available for self-authorship. As such, developing a personally meaningful narrative was crucial for re-establishing autonomy. Second, they portrayed a co-existing dynamic where autonomy and power were shared and negotiated with voices. Third, participants described how hearing voices interfered with their perceived competence, and decision-making, introducing limitations to their ability to navigate life on their own terms. Participants' capacity for integration, and perceptions of their ability to influence and cause change, affected the extent to which they felt self-determined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study highlights the importance of supporting voice hearers in constructing meaningful, self-oriented narratives to strengthen their sense of autonomy. Future research should explore strategies that empower voice hearers to integrate their experiences constructively, thereby promoting resilience and autonomy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The British Psychological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noroozi</LastName><ForeName>Sepinood</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-5763-4679</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Mental Health and Brain Sciences, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doroud</LastName><ForeName>Nastaran</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2552-9918</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing and Allied Health, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longden</LastName><ForeName>Eleanor</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3046-9697</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychosis Research Unit, Greater Manchester Mental Health NHS Foundation Trust, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Neil</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7006-6361</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Mental Health and Brain Sciences, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Alfred Hospital, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Australian Government Research Training Program Scholarship</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NIHR301598</GrantID><Agency>National Institute for Health and Care Research (NIHR) Development and Skills Enhancement Award</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Psychol Psychother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101135751</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1476-0835</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">auditory verbal hallucinations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personal autonomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self&#x2010;determination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sense of agency</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41354941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/papt.70026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Anderson, J. (2014). Regimes of autonomy. Ethical Theory and Moral Practice, 17(3), 355&#x2013;368. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10677&#x2010;013&#x2010;9448&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura, A. (1989). Human agency in social cognitive theory. American Psychologist, 44(9), 1175&#x2013;1184. https://doi.org/10.1037/0003&#x2010;066X.44.9.1175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura, A. (1997). Self&#x2010;efficacy: The exercise of control. Macmillan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura, A. (2018). Toward a psychology of human agency: Pathways and reflections. Perspectives on Psychological Science, 13(2), 130&#x2013;136. https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691617699280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beavan, V., Read, J., &amp; Cartwright, C. (2011). The prevalence of voice&#x2010;hearers in the general population: A literature review. Journal of Mental Health, 20(3), 281&#x2013;292. https://doi.org/10.3109/09638237.2011.562262</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekker, M. H., &amp; Belt, U. (2006). The role of autonomy&#x2010;connectedness in depression and anxiety. Depression and Anxiety, 23(5), 274&#x2013;280. https://doi.org/10.1002/da.20178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell, V. (2013). A community of one: Social cognition and auditory verbal hallucinations. PLoS Biology, 11(12), e1001723. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.1001723</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin, L. S. (1989). Is chronicity a function of the relationship between the person and the auditory hallucination? Schizophrenia Bulletin, 15(2), 291&#x2013;310. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/15.2.291</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergamin, J., Luigjes, J., Kiverstein, J., Bockting, C. L., &amp; Denys, D. (2022). Defining autonomy in psychiatry. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 13, 801415. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2022.801415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birchwood, M., &amp; Chadwick, P. (1997). The omnipotence of voices: Testing the validity of a cognitive model. Psychological Medicine, 27(6), 1345&#x2013;1353. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291797005552</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birchwood, M., Meaden, A., Trower, P., &amp; Gilbert, P. (2002). Shame, humiliation, and entrapment in psychosis: A social rank theory approach to cognitive intervention with voices and delusions. In A. P. Morrison (Ed.), A casebook of cognitive therapy for psychosis (pp. 108&#x2013;131). Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birchwood, M., Meaden, A., Trower, P., Gilbert, P., &amp; Plaistow, J. (2000). The power and omnipotence of voices: Subordination and entrapment by voices and significant others. Psychological Medicine, 30(2), 337&#x2013;344. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291799001828</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bratman, M. E. (2003). Autonomy and hierarchy. Social Philosophy and Policy, 20(2), 156&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadwick, P., &amp; Birchwood, M. (1994). The omnipotence of voices: A cognitive approach to auditory hallucinations. British Journal of Psychiatry, 164(2), 190&#x2013;201. https://doi.org/10.1192/bjp.164.2.190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chau, A. K. C., Minihan, S., Okayama, S., &amp; Schweizer, S. (2025). The relationship between cognitive and affective control and symptoms of depression and anxiety across the lifespan: A 3&#x2010;wave longitudinal study. Comprehensive Psychiatry, 137, 152564. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comppsych.2024.152564</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chirkov, V. I. (2011). Human psychological autonomy: Reflections on the debates about its understanding in modern psychology. Social and Personality Psychology Compass, 5(7), 609&#x2013;620. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1751&#x2010;9004.2011.00380.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christman, J. (2020). Autonomy in moral and political philosophy. In E. N. Zalta (Ed.), The Stanford encyclopedia of philosophy (Fall 2020 Edition). Metaphysics Research Lab, Stanford University. https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/autonomy&#x2010;moral/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, E., Olympia, D. E., Jensen, J., Heathfield, L. T., &amp; Jenson, W. R. (2003). Striving for autonomy in a contingency&#x2010;governed world: Another challenge for individuals with developmental disabilities. Psychology in the Schools, 41(1), 143&#x2013;153. https://doi.org/10.1002/pits.10146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connell, J., Brazier, J., O'Cathain, A., Lloyd&#x2010;Jones, M., &amp; Paisley, S. (2012). Quality of life of people with mental health problems: A synthesis of qualitative research. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes, 10, 138. https://doi.org/10.1186/1477&#x2010;7525&#x2010;10&#x2010;138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corstens, D., Longden, E., McCarthy&#x2010;Jones, S., Waddingham, R., &amp; Thomas, N. (2014). Emerging perspectives from the hearing voices movement: Implications for research and practice. Schizophrenia Bulletin, 40(Suppl 4), S285&#x2013;S294. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/sbu007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Haan, S., Rietveld, E., &amp; Denys, D. (2015). Being free by losing control: What obsessive compulsive disorder can tell us about free will. In Neuroscience and philosophy: Legal and personal perspectives (pp. 83&#x2013;102). Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781139565820.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci, E. L., &amp; Ryan, R. M. (2013). The importance of autonomy for development and well&#x2010;being. In B. W. Sokol, F. M. E. Gouze, &amp; U. M&#xfc;ller (Eds.), Self&#x2010;regulation and autonomy: Social and developmental dimensions of human conduct (pp. 19&#x2013;46). Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De&#x2010;Juanas, &#xc1;., Bernal Romero, T., &amp; Goig, R. (2020). The relationship between psychological well&#x2010;being and autonomy in young people according to age. Frontiers in Psychology, 11, 559976. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2020.559976</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dworkin, G. (1988). The theory and practice of autonomy. Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding&#x2010;Smith, S. F., Hayward, M., Strauss, C., Fowler, D., Paulik, G., &amp; Thomas, N. (2015). Bringing the &#x201c;self&#x201d; into focus: Conceptualising the role of self&#x2010;experience for understanding and working with distressing voices. Frontiers in Psychology, 6, 1129. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.01129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frith, C. D. (1992). The cognitive neuropsychology of schizophrenia (1st ed.). Psychology Press. https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315785011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frith, C. D., Blakemore, S., &amp; Wolpert, D. M. (2000). Explaining the symptoms of schizophrenia: Abnormalities in the awareness of action. Brain Research Reviews, 31(2&#x2013;3), 357&#x2013;363. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165&#x2010;0173(99)00052&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garety, P. A., Edwards, C. J., Jafari, H., Emsley, R., Huckvale, M., Rus&#x2010;Calafell, M., Fornells&#x2010;Ambrojo, M., Gumley, A., Haddock, G., Bucci, S., McLeod, H. J., McDonnell, J., Clancy, M., Fitzsimmons, M., Ball, H., Montague, A., Xanidis, N., Hardy, A., Craig, T. K. J., &amp; Ward, T. (2024). Digital AVATAR therapy for distressing voices in psychosis: The phase 2/3 AVATAR2 trial. Nature Medicine, 30(12), 3658&#x2013;3668. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591&#x2010;024&#x2010;03252&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenth&#xf8;j, L., Smith, L., Vernal, D. A., Mariegaard, L., Christensen, A., &amp; Jansen, J. (2024). Virtual reality&#x2010;assisted therapy targeting persistent auditory verbal hallucinations in patients diagnosed with schizophrenia spectrum disorders: The challenge single&#x2010;blind randomized controlled trial. Preprint.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haggard, P. (2017). Sense of agency in the human brain. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 18, 196&#x2013;207. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn.2017.14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, B., Terry, R., &amp; Hayward, M. (2023). A systematic review and thematic synthesis of qualitative literature on personal recovery and voice hearing. Clinical Psychology &amp; Psychotherapy, 30(3), 491&#x2013;509. https://doi.org/10.1002/cpp.2814</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson, L. (2006). Determinants of quality of life in people with severe mental illness. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica, 113(Suppl 429), 46&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0447.2005.00717.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrop, C., &amp; Trower, P. (2001). Why does schizophrenia develop at late adolescence? Clinical Psychology Review, 21(2), 241&#x2013;265. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0272&#x2010;7358(99)00047&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser, M., Knoblich, G., Repp, B. H., Lautenschlager, M., Gallinat, J., Heinz, A., &amp; Voss, M. (2011). Altered sense of agency in schizophrenia and the putative psychotic prodrome. Psychiatry Research, 186(2&#x2013;3), 170&#x2013;176. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2010.08.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward, M., Jones, A. M., Bogen&#x2010;Johnston, L., Thomas, N., &amp; Strauss, C. (2017). Relating therapy for distressing auditory hallucinations: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Schizophrenia Research, 183, 137&#x2013;142. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.schres.2016.11.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henden, E. (2023). Addiction and autonomy: Why emotional dysregulation in addiction impairs autonomy and why it matters. Frontiers in Psychology, 14, 1081810. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1081810</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovenkamp&#x2010;Hermelink, J. H., Jeronimus, B. F., Spinhoven, P., Penninx, B. W., Schoevers, R. A., &amp; Riese, H. (2019). Differential associations of locus of control with anxiety, depression and life&#x2010;events: A five&#x2010;wave, nine&#x2010;year study to test stability and change. Journal of Affective Disorders, 253, 26&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2019.04.057</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husserl, E. (1931). Ideas: General introduction to pure phenomenology (Carr, D., Trans.). Northwestern University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson, L. J., Hayward, M., &amp; Cooke, A. (2011). Developing positive relationships with voices: A preliminary grounded theory. The International Journal of Social Psychiatry, 57(5), 487&#x2013;495. https://doi.org/10.1177/0020764010368624</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, S. R., &amp; Fernyhough, C. (2007). Thought as action: Inner speech, self&#x2010;monitoring, and auditory verbal hallucinations. Consciousness and Cognition, 16(2), 391&#x2013;399. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.concog.2006.09.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law, H., &amp; Morrison, A. P. (2014). Recovery in psychosis: A Delphi study with experts by experience. Schizophrenia Bulletin, 40(6), 1347&#x2013;1355. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/sbu047</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leamy, M., Bird, V., Le Boutillier, C., Williams, J., &amp; Slade, M. (2011). Conceptual framework for personal recovery in mental health: Systematic review and narrative synthesis. The British Journal of Psychiatry, 199(6), 445&#x2013;452. https://doi.org/10.1192/bjp.bp.110.083733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln, T. M., Pillny, M., Schlier, B., &amp; Hayward, M. (2021). RELATE &#x2013; A randomised controlled feasibility trial of a relating therapy module for distressing auditory verbal hallucinations: A study protocol. BMJ Open, 11(6), e046390. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen&#x2010;2020&#x2010;046390</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longden, E., Corstens, D., Bowe, S., Stainsby, M., Steel, C., Hurtado, M., &amp; Morrison, A. P. (2022). A psychological intervention for engaging dialogically with auditory hallucinations (talking with voices): A single&#x2010;site, randomised controlled feasibility trial. Schizophrenia Research, 250, 172&#x2013;179. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.schres.2022.11.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longden, E., Corstens, D., Morrison, A. P., Larkin, A., Murphy, E., Holden, N., Steele, A., Branitsky, A., &amp; Bowe, S. (2021). A treatment protocol to guide the delivery of dialogical engagement with auditory hallucinations: Experience from the talking with voices pilot trial. Psychology and Psychotherapy: Theory, Research and Practice, 94(3), 558&#x2013;572. https://doi.org/10.1111/papt.12331</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luhrmann, T. (2012). Living with voices. The American Scholar, 81(3), 48&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysaker, P. H., &amp; Lysaker, J. T. (2002). Narrative structure in psychosis: Schizophrenia and disruptions in the dialogical self. Theory &amp; Psychology, 12(2), 207&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancini, A. D. (2008). Self&#x2010;determination theory: A framework for the recovery paradigm. Advances in Psychiatric Treatment, 14(5), 358&#x2013;365. https://doi.org/10.1192/apt.bp.107.004036</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCann, T. V., &amp; Clark, E. (2004). Advancing self&#x2010;determination with young adults who have schizophrenia. Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing, 11(1), 12&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2850.2004.00645.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mele, A. R. (1995). Autonomous agents: From self control to autonomy. Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milligan, D., McCarthy&#x2010;Jones, S., Winthrop, A., &amp; Dudley, R. (2013). Time changes everything? A qualitative investigation of the experience of auditory verbal hallucinations over time. Psychosis, 5(2), 107&#x2013;118. https://doi.org/10.1080/17522439.2012.667438</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison, A. P., Haddock, G., &amp; Tarrier, N. (1995). Intrusive thoughts and auditory hallucinations: A cognitive approach. Behavioural and Cognitive Psychotherapy, 23(3), 265&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayani, T. H., &amp; David, A. S. (1996). The auditory hallucination: A phenomenological survey. Psychological Medicine, 26(1), 177&#x2013;189. https://doi.org/10.1017/S003329170003381X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nizza, I. E., Farr, J., &amp; Smith, J. A. (2021). Achieving excellence in interpretative phenomenological analysis (IPA): Four markers of high quality. Qualitative Research in Psychology, 18(3), 369&#x2013;386. https://doi.org/10.1080/14780887.2020.1854404</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshana, M. (2016). Personal autonomy in society. Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne, T., Allen, J., &amp; Lavender, T. (2017). Hearing voices network groups: Experiences of eight voice hearers and the connection to group processes and recovery. Psychosis, 9(3), 205&#x2013;215. https://doi.org/10.1080/17522439.2017.1300183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peh, O., Rapisarda, A., &amp; Lee, J. (2019). Childhood adversities in people at ultra&#x2010;high risk (UHR) for psychosis: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Psychological Medicine, 49(7), 1089&#x2013;1101. https://doi.org/10.1017/S003329171800394X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peh, O. H., Rapisarda, A., &amp; Lee, J. (2020). Quality of parental bonding is associated with symptom severity and functioning among individuals at ultra&#x2010;high risk for psychosis. Schizophrenia Research, 215, 204&#x2013;210. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.schres.2019.10.029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piaget, J. (1971). Biology and knowledge. University of Chicago Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietkiewicz, I., &amp; Smith, J. A. (2014). A practical guide to using interpretative phenomenological analysis in qualitative research psychology. Psychological Journal, 20, 7&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.14691/CPPJ.20.1.7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitt, L., Kilbride, M., Nothard, S., Welford, M., &amp; Morrison, A. (2007). Researching recovery from psychosis: A user&#x2010;led project. Psychiatric Bulletin, 31(2), 55&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdon, C., &amp; Clark, D. A. (2002). The need to control thoughts. In R. O. Frost &amp; G. Steketee (Eds.), Cognitive approaches to obsessions and compulsions (pp. 29&#x2013;43). Pergamon.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricoeur, P. (1966). Freedom and nature: The voluntary and the involuntary (E. Koh&#xe1;k, Trans.). Northwestern University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe, D., &amp; Davidson, L. (2005). Self and narrative in schizophrenia: Time to author a new story. Medical Humanities, 31(2), 89&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1136/jmh.2005.000214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romme, M. A., &amp; Escher, A. D. (1989). Hearing voices. Schizophrenia Bulletin, 15(2), 209&#x2013;216. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/15.2.209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotter, J. B. (1954). Social learning and clinical psychology. Prentice&#x2010;Hall, Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, R. M., &amp; Deci, E. L. (2000). Self&#x2010;determination theory and the facilitation of intrinsic motivation, social development, and well&#x2010;being. American Psychologist, 55(1), 68&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1037/0003&#x2010;066X.55.1.68</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, R. M., &amp; Deci, E. L. (2006). Self&#x2010;regulation and the problem of human autonomy: Does psychology need choice, self&#x2010;determination, and will? Journal of Personality, 74(6), 1557&#x2013;1586. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467&#x2010;6494.2006.00420.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, R. M., Deci, E. L., &amp; Vansteenkiste, M. (2016). Autonomy and autonomy disturbances in self&#x2010;development and psychopathology: Research on motivation, attachment, and clinical process. Development and Psychopathology, 1, 1&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sass, L. A. (2011). Autonomy and schizophrenia: Reflections on an ideal. In C. Piers &amp; D. Shapiro (Eds.), Personality and psychopathology: Critical dialogues with David Shapiro (pp. 99&#x2013;126). Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978&#x2010;1&#x2010;4419&#x2010;6214&#x2010;0_5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlechter, P., Hellmann, J. H., &amp; Morina, N. (2024). The longitudinal relationship between well&#x2010;being comparisons and anxiety symptoms in the context of uncontrollability of worries and external locus of control: A two&#x2010;wave study. Anxiety, Stress, and Coping, 37(5), 602&#x2013;614. https://doi.org/10.1080/10615806.2024.2306530</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro, D. (1981). Autonomy and rigid character.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheaves, B., Johns, L., Griffith, L., Isham, L., Kabir, T., &amp; Freeman, D. (2020). Why do patients with psychosis listen to and believe derogatory and threatening voices? 21 reasons given by patients. Behavioural and Cognitive Psychotherapy, 48(6), 631&#x2013;645. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1352465820000429</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade, P. D., &amp; Bentall, R. P. (1988). Sensory deception: A scientific analysis of hallucination. Croom Helm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, J. A. (2004). Reflecting on the development of interpretative phenomenological analysis and its contribution to qualitative research in psychology. Qualitative Research in Psychology, 1(1), 39&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1191/1478088704qp004oa</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, J. A. (2010). Evaluating the contribution of interpretative phenomenological analysis. Health Psychology Review, 5(1), 9&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1080/17437199.2010.510659</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, J. A., &amp; Fieldsend, M. (2021). Interpretative phenomenological analysis. In P. M. Camic (Ed.), Qualitative research in psychology: Expanding perspectives in methodology and design (2nd ed., pp. 147&#x2013;166). American Psychological Association. https://doi.org/10.1037/0000252&#x2010;008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, J. A., Flowers, P., &amp; Larkin, M. (2009). Interpretative phenomenological analysis: Theory, method and research. Sage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, J. A., &amp; Osborn, M. (2008). Interpretative phenomenological analysis. In J. A. Smith (Ed.), Qualitative psychology: A practical guide to research methods (2nd ed., pp. 53&#x2013;80). Sage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steckermeier, L. C. (2021). The value of autonomy for the good life. In an empirical investigation of autonomy and life satisfaction in Europe (Vol. 154). Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steel, C., Garety, P. A., Freeman, D., Craig, E., Kuipers, E., Bebbington, P., Fowler, D., &amp; Dunn, G. (2007). The multidimensional measurement of the positive symptoms of psychosis. International Journal of Methods in Psychiatric Research, 16(2), 88&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1002/mpr.203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephane, M., Barton, S., &amp; Boutros, N. N. (2001). Auditory verbal hallucinations and dysfunction of the neural substrates of speech. Schizophrenia Research, 50(1&#x2013;2), 61&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0920&#x2010;9964(00)00150&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upthegrove, R., Ives, J., Broome, M. R., Caldwell, K., Wood, S. J., &amp; Oyebode, F. (2016). Auditory verbal hallucinations in first&#x2010;episode psychosis: A phenomenological investigation. BJPsych Open, 2(1), 88&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1192/bjpo.bp.115.002303</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Weeghel, J., van Zelst, C., Boertien, D., &amp; Hasson&#x2010;Ohayon, I. (2019). Conceptualizations, assessments, and implications of personal recovery in mental illness: A scoping review of systematic reviews and meta&#x2010;analyses. Psychiatric Rehabilitation Journal, 42(2), 169&#x2013;181. https://doi.org/10.1037/prj0000356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varese, F., Mansell, W., &amp; Tai, S. J. (2017). What is distressing about auditory verbal hallucinations? The contribution of goal interference and goal facilitation. Psychology and Psychotherapy, 90(4), 720&#x2013;734. https://doi.org/10.1111/papt.12135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vella, J. (2024). In pursuit of credibility: Evaluating the divergence between member&#x2010;checking and hermeneutic phenomenology. Research in Social &amp; Administrative Pharmacy: RSAP, 20(7), 665&#x2013;669. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sapharm.2024.04.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters, F., &amp; Fernyhough, C. (2017). Hallucinations: A systematic review of points of similarity and difference across diagnostic classes. Schizophrenia Bulletin, 43(1), 32&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/sbw132</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woods, A., Jones, N., Alderson&#x2010;Day, B., Callard, F., &amp; Fernyhough, C. (2015). Experiences of hearing voices: Analysis of a novel phenomenological survey. The Lancet Psychiatry, 2(4), 323&#x2013;331. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215&#x2010;0366(15)00006&#x2010;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, S., Levesque&#x2010;Bristol, C., &amp; Maeda, Y. (2018). General need for autonomy and subjective well&#x2010;being: A meta&#x2010;analysis of studies in the US and East Asia. Journal of Happiness Studies, 19, 1863&#x2013;1882. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10902&#x2010;017&#x2010;9898&#x2010;2</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>