<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41649229</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Machine learning model identifies tibial anatomical variables as potential risk factors for anterior cruciate ligament injury.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1513</StartPage><EndPage>1523</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1513-1523</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70322</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The tibial slope is a well-known risk factor for anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) injury. As machine learning continues to progress, it has become an increasingly explored tool for clinical screening and risk factor analysis. This study aims to develop and validate a prognostic machine learning model to predict the outcome of ACL injury from tibial anatomic parameters and identify the most predictive features.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A pre-published dataset of coronal, medial and lateral tibial slopes and medial tibial depth was constructed using magnetic resonance imaging scans taken from 104 subjects (44 males: 22 injured, 22 uninjured; 60 females: 27 injured, 33 uninjured). The dataset was split into train-validation and test sets to ensure robust model evaluation. AutoGluon-enabled machine learning models, including XGBoost, LightGBM, CatBoost, TabPFN, TabM, TabICL, MITRA and their weighted ensembles were trained and tuned with respect to the F2-score across ten different random seeds. Two instances of the best-performing model were developed: a default tested model (weighted ensemble from the default seed of 42) and a full-dataset model (weighted ensemble retrained on the entire dataset). Global SHapley Additive exPlanations analysis was used to elucidate the most predictive features, and local SHapley Additive exPlanations analysis to provide interpretability for individual predictions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The default tested model achieved a 73.60% validation F2-score. On the test set, it demonstrated a 95.44% test balanced accuracy, 95.24% F1-score, 98.04% F2-score, 100% ROC AUC, 90.91% precision and 100% recall. The full-dataset model achieved an 81.30% validation F2-score. The relative importance of tibial anatomical features were identified.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Overall, the study presented two prognostic models with moderately high predictive power to identify subjects with high likelihood of ACL injury. Decreased medial tibial depth along with increased medial and lateral tibial slopes were reported as top predictors for ACL injury. These models can potentially be integrated into clinical practice to assist clinicians in predicting the likelihood of ACL injury, but require external validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level III, case-control study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kao</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Hao</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Mechatronics Engineering, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hashemi</LastName><ForeName>Javad</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ocean and Mechanical Engineering &amp; Department of Biomedical Engineering, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slauterbeck</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNC Health, Lumberton, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandrashekar</LastName><ForeName>Naveen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9991-2258</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Mechatronics Engineering, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070598" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013977" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tibia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feature importance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tibial anatomical feature</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41649229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13037345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Airlangga G, Liu A. A hybrid gradient boosting and neural network model for predicting urban happiness: integrating ensemble learning with deep representation for enhanced accuracy. Mach Learn Knowl Extract. 2025;7(1):4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andriollo L, Picchi A, Sangaletti R, Perticarini L, Rossi SMP, Logroscino G, et al. The role of artificial intelligence in anterior cruciate ligament injuries: current concepts and future perspectives. Healthcare. 2024;12(3):300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10855330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38338185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayer S, Meredith SJ, Wilson KW, de SA D, Pauyo T, Byrne K, et al. Knee morphological risk factors for anterior cruciate ligament injury: a systematic review. J Bone Jt Surg. 2020;102(8):703&#x2013;718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31977822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackman B, Vivekanantha P, Mughal R, Pareek A, Bozzo A, Samuelsson K, et al. Machine learning models predicting risk of revision or secondary knee injury after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction demonstrate variable discriminatory and accuracy performance: a systematic review. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2025;26:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11699785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39755642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boden BP, Sheehan FT, Torg JS, Hewett TE. Noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injuries: mechanisms and risk factors. Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2010;18(9):520&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3625971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20810933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter JC, Sturnick DR, Vacek PM, DeSarno MJ, Argentieri EC, Slauterbeck JR, et al. Relationship between geometry of the extensor mechanism of the knee and risk of anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Orthop Res. 2017;35(5):965&#x2013;973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corban J, Lorange JP, Laverdiere C, Khoury J, Rachevsky G, Burman M, et al. Artificial intelligence in the management of anterior cruciate ligament injuries. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9(7):23259671211014206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8255602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34277880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai B, Herman D, Liu H, Garrett WE, Yu B. Prevention of ACL injury, part i: injury characteristics, risk factors, and loading mechanism. Res Sports Med. 2012;20(3&#x2013;4):180&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22742075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endo Y, Takemura M, Monma M, Mutsuzaki H, Mizukami M. Difference in sex and the effect of a dominant lower extremity in the posterior tibial slope angle in healthy Japanese subjects. Asia Pac J Sports Med Arthrosc Rehabil Technol. 2021;23:8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33299801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Erickson N, Mueller J, Shirkov A, Zhang H, Larroy P, Li M, et al. AutoGluon&#x2010;tabular: robust and accurate autoML for structured data. 2020. <i>ArXiv</i>. http://arxiv.org/abs/2003.06505
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Erickson N, Purucker L, Tschalzev A, Holzm&#xfc;ller D, Desai PM, Salinas D, et al. TabArena: a living benchmark for machine learning on tabular data. 2025. <i>ArXiv</i>. http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.16791
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xe4;ltstr&#xf6;m A, Kvist J, Bittencourt NFN, Mendon&#xe7;a LD, H&#xe4;gglund M. Clinical risk profile for a second anterior cruciate ligament injury in female soccer players after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(6):1421&#x2013;1430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetschius J, Smith HC, Vacek PM, Holterman LA, Shultz SJ, Tourville TW, et al. Application of a clinic&#x2010;based algorithm as a tool to identify female athletes at risk for anterior cruciate ligament injury: a prospective cohort study with a nested, matched case&#x2010;control analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(9):1978&#x2013;1984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6503969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grinsztajn L, Oyallon E, Varoquaux G. Why do tree&#x2010;based models still outperform deep learning on typical tabular data? Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2022;35:507&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi J, Chandrashekar N, Gill B, Beynnon BD, Slauterbeck JR, Schutt RC, et al. The geometry of the tibial plateau and its influence on the biomechanics of the tibiofemoral joint. J Bone Jt Surg Am Vol. 2008;90(12):2724&#x2013;2734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2663332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19047719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi J, Chandrashekar N, Mansouri H, Gill B, Slauterbeck JR, Schutt RC, et al. Shallow medial tibial plateau and steep medial and lateral tibial slopes: new risk factors for anterior cruciate ligament injuries. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38(1):54&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haussler D, Warmuth M. The probably approximately correct (PAC) and other learning models. In: Meyrowitz AL, Chipman S editors Foundations of knowledge acquisition: machine learning. Springer US; 1993. p. 291&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He M, Li J. Increased lateral femoral condyle ratio measured by MRI is associated with higher risk of noncontact anterior cruciate ligament injury. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23(1):190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8886831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35232401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinzadeh S, Kiapour AM. Sex differences in anatomic features linked to anterior cruciate ligament injuries during skeletal growth and maturation. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(9):2205&#x2013;2212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson QJ, Jabal MS, Arguello AM, Lu Y, Jurgensmeier K, Levy BA, et al. Machine learning can accurately predict risk factors for all&#x2010;cause reoperation after ACLR: creating a clinical tool to improve patient counseling and outcomes. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(10):4099&#x2013;4108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37414947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Key S, Baygin M, Demir S, Dogan S, Tuncer T. Meniscal tear and ACL injury detection model based on AlexNet and iterative reliefF. J Digit Imaging. 2022;35(2):200&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8921447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan I, Ali H, Siddiqui MF, Geetha GMN. Machine learning approaches to injury risk prediction in sport. Premier J Comp Sci. 2025;4:100012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiapour AM, Yang DS, Badger GJ, Karamchedu NP, Murray MM, Fadale PD, et al. Anatomic features of the tibial plateau predict outcomes of ACL reconstruction within 7 years after surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(2):303&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30640519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkotis C, Moustakidis S, Tsatalas T, Ntakolia C, Chalatsis G, Konstadakos S, et al. Leveraging explainable machine learning to identify gait biomechanical parameters associated with anterior cruciate ligament injury. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):6647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9026057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35459787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landis SE, Baker RT, Seegmiller JG. Non&#x2010;contact anterior cruciate ligament and lower extremity injury risk prediction using functional movement screen and knee abduction moment: an epidemiological observation of female intercollegiate athletes. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2018;13(6):973&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6253749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30534463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez CD, Gazgalis A, Peterson JR, Confino JE, Levine WN, Popkin CA, et al. Machine learning can accurately predict overnight stay, readmission, and 30&#x2010;day complications following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Rel Surg. 2023;39(3):777&#x2013;786.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35817375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Pareek A, Yang L, Rouzrokh P, Khosravi B, Okoroha KR, et al. Deep learning artificial intelligence tool for automated radiographic determination of posterior tibial slope in patients with ACL injury. Orthop J Sports Med. 2023;11(12):23259671231215820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10725654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38107846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Till SE, Labott JR, Reinholz AK, Hevesi M, Krych AJ, et al. Graft failure and contralateral ACL injuries after primary ACL reconstruction: an analysis of risk factors using interpretable machine learning. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(10):23259671241282316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11504090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39464204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Lundberg SM, Lee S&#x2010;I. A unified approach to interpreting model predictions. In: Advances in neural information processing systems 30 (NIPS 2017). Vol. 30 Curran Associates, Inc; 2017. https://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2017/hash/8a20a8621978632d76c43dfd28b67767-Abstract.html
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElfresh D, Khandagale S, Valverde J, Prasad CV, Ramakrishnan G, et al. When do neural nets outperform boosted trees on tabular data? In: NIPS '23: Proceedings of the 37th international conference on neural information processing system. Curran Associates Inc.; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padua DA, DiStefano LJ, Beutler AI, de la Motte SJ, DiStefano MJ, Marshall SW. The landing error scoring system as a screening tool for an anterior cruciate ligament injury&#x2013;prevention program in elite&#x2010;youth soccer athletes. J Athl Train. 2015;50(6):589&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4527442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25811846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmanto B, Munro PW, Doyle HR. Reducing variance of committee prediction with resampling techniques. Connect Sci. 1996;8(3&#x2013;4):405&#x2013;426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawan Kumar KM, Mundargi A, Puttamaregowda M, Kammagondanahalli RK, Perumalswamy S, Shantharam SM. LFCI and knee morphological parameters as a risk factor in anterior cruciate ligament tear on magnetic resonance imaging: a case control analysis. J Clin Orthop Trauma. 2024;55:102514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11377136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39247087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedoia V, Lansdown DA, Zaid M, McCulloch CE, Souza R, Ma CB, et al. Three&#x2010;dimensional MRI&#x2010;based statistical shape model and application to a cohort of knees with acute ACL injury. Osteoarthr Cartil. 2015;23(10):1695&#x2013;1703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5019115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26050865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeifer CE, Beattie PF, Sacko RS, Hand A. Risk factors associated with non&#x2010;contact anterior cruciate ligament injury: a systematic review. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2018;13(4):575&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6088120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30140551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabu M, Chandrashekar S, Duddukunta VR, Naresh G, Raja S. The influence of tibial plateau morphometric risk factors on ACL injury: a retrospective case control study: an Indian perspective. Int J Health Sci. 2022;2022:5895&#x2013;5902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu S, Wang Y, Xing G, Pu Q, Zhao Z, Zhao L. Precise and efficient measurement of tibial slope on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI): two novel autonomous pipelines by traditional and deep learning algorithms. Quant Imaging Med Surg. 2024;14(8):5304&#x2013;5320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11320518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39144010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schilaty ND, Bates NA, Kruisselbrink S, Krych AJ, Hewett TE. Linear discriminant analysis successfully predicts knee injury outcome from biomechanical variables. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(10):2447&#x2013;2455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7566284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32693617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulc A, Leite CBG, Cs&#xe1;kv&#xe1;ri M, Lattermann L, Zgoda MF, Farina EM, et al. Identifying anterior cruciate ligament injuries through automated video analysis of in&#x2010;game motion patterns. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(3):23259671231221579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10935765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38482336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith HC, Vacek P, Johnson RJ, Slauterbeck JR, Hashemi J, Shultz S, et al. Risk factors for anterior cruciate ligament injury: a review of the literature &#x2014; part 1: neuromuscular and anatomic risk. Sports Health A Multidiscipl Appr. 2012;4(1):69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3435896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23016072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturnick DR, Van Gorder R, Vacek PM, DeSarno MJ, Gardner&#x2010;Morse MG, Tourville TW, et al. Tibial articular cartilage and meniscus geometries combine to influence female risk of anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Orthop Res. 2014;32(11):1487&#x2013;1494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6886124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25099246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturnick DR, Vacek PM, DeSarno MJ, Gardner&#x2010;Morse MG, Tourville TW, Slauterbeck JR, et al. Combined anatomic factors predicting risk of anterior cruciate ligament injury for males and females. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(4):839&#x2013;847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6607022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25583759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taborri J, Molinaro L, Santospagnuolo A, Vetrano M, Vulpiani MC, Rossi S. A machine&#x2010;learning approach to measure the anterior cruciate ligament injury risk in female basketball players. Sensors. 2021;21(9):3141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8125336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33946515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamimi I, Ballesteros J, Lara AP, Tat J, Alaqueel M, Schupbach J, et al. A prediction model for primary anterior cruciate ligament injury using artificial intelligence. Orthop J Sports Med. 2021;9(9):23259671211027543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34568504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mars G, Vasavada K, Vasavada V, Moran J, Devana S, Lee C, et al. A novel machine learning model to predict revision acl reconstruction failure in the MARS cohort. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(11):23259671241291920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11565622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39555321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yang T, Zeng C, Wei J, Xie D, Yang Y, et al. Association between tibial plateau slopes and anterior cruciate ligament injury: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Arthrosc J Arthrosc Rel Surg. 2017;33(6):1248&#x2013;1259.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28302427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetters N, Weber AE, Wuerz TH, Schub DL, Mandelbaum BR. Mechanism of injury and risk factors for anterior cruciate ligament injury. Oper Tech Sports Med. 2016;24(1):2&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitney DC, Sturnick DR, Vacek PM, DeSarno MJ, Gardner&#x2010;Morse M, Tourville TW, et al. Relationship between the risk of suffering a first&#x2010;time noncontact ACL injury and geometry of the femoral notch and ACL. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42(8):1796&#x2013;1805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6604056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24866891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wordeman SC, Quatman CE, Kaeding CC, Hewett TE. In vivo evidence for tibial plateau slope as a risk factor for anterior cruciate ligament injury. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(7):1673&#x2013;1681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4168892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22539537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao S&#x2010;Y, Zhang XZ, Podder S, Wu CT, Chan YS, Berco D, et al. Enhanced reliability and time efficiency of deep learning&#x2010;based posterior tibial slope measurement over manual techniques. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:59&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38796728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Z, Zhang T, Wu C, Qiao Y, Su W, Chen J, et al. Predicting the objective and subjective clinical outcomes of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a machine learning analysis of 432 patients. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(14):3786&#x2013;3795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36285651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng C, Borim FM, Lording T. Increased posterior tibial slope is a risk factor for anterior cruciate ligament injury and graft failure after reconstruction: a systematic review. J ISAKOS. 2025;12:100854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40164409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Ye Z, Cai J, Chen J, Zheng T, Xu J, et al. Ensemble algorithm for risk prediction of clinical failure after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12(8):23259671241261695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11334255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39165332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>