<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41624318</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2673-5059</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in global women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Glob Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A novice to expert analysis of skill development in birth doulas.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1604410</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1604410</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1604410</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fgwh.2025.1604410</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study applies the Benner interpretation of the Dreyfus Model of Skill Acquisition to birth doulas.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sixty-five doulas participated in open-ended interviews in five waves between 2002 and 2022. Constructivist grounded theory methods were used to collect and analyze the data. Participants attended over 25 births, spoke English fluently, and did not utilize any medical skills. The doulas ranged in age from 22 to 65 and practiced in a variety of areas and settings in the United States, Canada, and the Netherlands.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The Benner model was relevant. Birth doulas grow similarly to nurses from novice to expert, including the development of intuition. However, the skill set is different. As they improved in skill acquisition, birth doulas showed advancement in information processing; confidence; decision-making; communication; self-awareness; client and staff relationships; professional detachment; definition of an ideal birth; management of witnessing medical maltreatment and feelings of overwhelm; the ability to read client cues; anticipation of labor events and staff responses; managing the challenges of a professional doula lifestyle; sense of identity, the maturation of expert intuition; and awareness of when they had power to influence a situation. Swiftness in development depended on the variety of birth experiences and locations; the doula's ability to reflect and find meaning; and life and career background.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Birth doula work is more complex and multifaceted than previously thought and requires growth in specific skill sets to be successful. Effective birth doula work requires sophisticated emotion management, analytical and communication skills, in addition to labor support skills. Public perception that anyone can be a doula is erroneous. It is a separate profession from obstetrical nursing, although some skills may overlap. Rather than continually training new people, programs could concentrate on removing the challenges to continuing birth doula work. Doula programs should address the challenges of each stage, thus encouraging greater expertise and retention and growth of an experienced workforce.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Gilliland.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilliland</LastName><ForeName>Amy Louise</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Ecology, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Glob Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101776281</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2673-5059</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">birth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">doula</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">grounded theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intuition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">labor support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">longitudinal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maltreatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">novice to expert</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declares that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41624318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12855558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgwh.2025.1604410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Perez P, Snedeker C. Special Women: The Role of the Professional Labor Assistant. 1st ed. Katy, Texas: Cutting Edge Press; (1990). p. 194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klaus P. Birth, Interaction, and Attachment. Colorado Springs, CO: Pediatric Round Table, Johnson and Johnson; (1982). p. 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sosa R, Kennell J, Klaus M, Robertson S, Urrutia J. The effect of a supportive companion on perinatal problems, length of labor, and mother-infant interaction. N Engl J Med. (1980) 303(11):597&#x2013;600. 10.1056/NEJM198009113031101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198009113031101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7402234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A. The Truth About Doulas: They Aren't Just for Rich People. Newsweek. (2017). Available online at:
https://www.newsweek.com/doula-diaries-childbirth-bustle-romper-663841
(Accessed October 6, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker KJ. Inside the Million Dollar Get-Rich Clique: This Controversial Company Wants to Disrupt the Birth World. Buzzfeed News (2017). Available online at:
https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/katiejmbaker/doula-drama (Accessed February 8, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falconi AM, Bromfield SG, Tang T, Malloy D, Blanco D, Disciglio RNS, et al. Doula care across the maternity care continuum and impact on maternal health: evaluation of doula programs across three states using propensity score matching. eClinicalMedicine. (2022) 50:101531. 10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9257331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35812994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobczak A, Taylor L, Solomon S, Ho J, Kemper S, Phillips B, et al. The effect of doulas on maternal and birth outcomes: a scoping review. Cureus. (2023) 15(5):e39451. 10.7759/cureus.39451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.39451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10292163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37378162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilliland. After praise and encouragement: emotional support strategies used by birth doulas in the USA and Canada. Midwifery. (2011) 27(4):525&#x2013;31. 10.1016/j.midw.2010.04.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.midw.2010.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20850916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simkin P, O'Hara M. Nonpharmacologic relief of pain during labor: systematic reviews of five methods. Am J Obstet Gynecol. (2002) 186(5):S131&#x2013;S59. 10.1016/S0002-9378(02)70188-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-9378(02)70188-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12011879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simkin P. The Birth Partner: Everything You Need to Know to Help a Woman Through Childbirth. 1st ed. Boston: Harvard Common Press. (1989) p. 1&#x2013;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilliland A. <i>Effective labor support by doulas</i>. (unpublished master&#x2019;s thesis). University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas MP, Ammann G, Brazier E, Noyes P, Maybank A. Doula services within a healthy start program: increasing access for an underserved population. Matern Child Health J. (2017) 21(Suppl 1):59&#x2013;64. 10.1007/s10995-017-2402-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10995-017-2402-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5736765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29198051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallick L, Thoma M, Shenassa E. The role of doulas in respectful care for communities of color and Medicaid recipients. Birth. (2022) 00:1&#x2013;10. 10.1111/birt.12655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/birt.12655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9796025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35652195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinas J, Salinas M, Kahn M. Doulas, racism, and whiteness: how birth support workers process advocacy towards women of color. Societies. (2022) 12(19). 10.3390/soc12010019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/soc12010019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonapace J, Gagne GP, Chaillet N, Gagnon R, Hebert E, Buckley S. No. 355-physiologic basis of pain in labour and delivery: an evidence-based approach to its management. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. (2018) 40(2):227&#x2013;45. 10.1016/j.jogc.2017.08.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jogc.2017.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29447711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benner P. From Novice to Expert: Excellence and Power in Clinical Nursing Practice. Menlo Park: Addison-Wesley; (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshvandi K, Moghadam A, Khatigan M, Cheraghi F, Borzu R, Moradi Y. On the application of novice to expert theory in nursing; a systematic review. J Chem Pharm Sci. (2016) 9(4):3014&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss A, Corbin J. Basics of Qualitative Research. 2nd ed. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications; (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehn P, Simonsen SM, Olesen ML. Multidimensional factors determine skill acquisition development in guided self-determination: a qualitative study. Scand J Caring Sci. (2023) 37(2):549&#x2013;60. 10.1111/scs.13140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/scs.13140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36533327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woeber K. Development and implementation of a competency-based clinical evaluation tool for midwifery education. Midwifery. (2018) 62:92&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.midw.2018.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.midw.2018.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29660575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubsch SM, TyczKowski B. Benner&#x2019;s novice to expert model: an application to COVID-19 nurses on the front line. Beginnings. (2020) 40(5):12&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller EM, Hill PD. Intuition in clinical decision making: differences among practicing nurses. J Holist Nurs. (2017) 36(4):330&#x2013;1. 10.1177/0898010117725428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0898010117725428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RJ, Donnelly GW. A model to describe the relationship between knowledge, skill, and judgment in nursing practice. Nurs Forum. (2006) 41(4):150&#x2013;7. 10.1111/j.1744-6198.2006.00053.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1744-6198.2006.00053.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17076797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton C, Hall S. Enhanced doula support to improve pregnancy outcomes among African American women with disabilities. J Perinatal Educ. (2020) 29(4):188&#x2013;96. 10.1891/J-PE-D-19-00021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/J-PE-D-19-00021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33223792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Font G, Testani E. Doula programs improve cesarean section rate, breastfeeding initiation, maternal and perinatal outcomes. Obstet Gynecol. (2020) 135:170S. 10.1097/01.AOG.0000663940.10309.10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.AOG.0000663940.10309.10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinas J, Salinas M. Commentary: systemic racism in maternal health care centering doula advocacy for women of color during COVID-19. Fam Community Health. (2021) 44(2):110&#x2013;1. 10.1097/FCH.0000000000000293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/FCH.0000000000000293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33351518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilliland. Doulas Are Paraprofessionals (2016). Available online at:
https://amygilliland.com/blog/doulas-are-paraprofessionals
(Accessed May 31, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilliland. What motivates people to attend birth doula trainings? J Perinatal Educ. (2016) 25(3):174&#x2013;83. 10.1891/1058-1243.25.3.174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/1058-1243.25.3.174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6265612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30538414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez AM, Arteaga S, Arcara J, Cuentos A, Armstead M, Mehra R, et al. My 9 to 5 job is birth work": a case study of two compensation approaches for community doula care. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2021) 18(20). 10.3390/ijerph182010817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182010817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boire C, Lucas L. Birth companions: teaching nursing students to become doulas. J Perinatal Educ. (2022) 31(1):14&#x2013;20. 10.1891/J-PE-D-20-00064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/J-PE-D-20-00064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8827347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mottl-Santiago J, Herr K, Rodrigues D, Walker C, Feinberg E. The birth sisters program: a model of hospital-based doula support to promote health equity. J Health Care Poor Underserved. (2020) 31(1):43&#x2013;55. 10.1353/hpu.2020.0007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/hpu.2020.0007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32037316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horstman HK, Anderson J, Kuehl RA. Communicatively making sense of doulas within the U.S. master birth narrative: doulas as liminal characters. Health Commun. (2016) 32(12):1510&#x2013;9. 10.1080/10410236.2016.1234537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10410236.2016.1234537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27813661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henley MM. Walking that fine line: doulas as overseers of evidence-based practice. Sociol Perspect. (2023) 66(2):375&#x2013;94. 10.1177/07311214221121161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/07311214221121161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. Qualitative Inquiry and Research Design: Choosing Among Five Traditions. Thousand Oaks: Sage Publications; (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charmaz. Constructing Grounded Theory: A Practical Guide Through Qualitative Analysis. London: Sage Publications; (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilliland AL. The Heart of the Doula: Essentials for Practice and Life. Pennsauken, New Jersey: Book Baby; (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;a A. The dreyfus model of clinical problem-solving skills acquisition: a critical perspective. Med Educ Online. (2010) 15. 10.3402/meo.v15i0.4846</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3402/meo.v15i0.4846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20563279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daley BJ. Novice to expert: an exploration of how professionals learn. Adult Educ Q. (1999) 49(4):133&#x2013;47. 10.1177/074171369904900401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/074171369904900401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charmaz K. Grounded theory: objectivist and constructivist methods. In: Denzin N, Lincoln Y, editors. Handbook of Qualitative Research. Thousand Oaks: Sage Publications; (2000). p. 509&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln Y, Guba E. Naturalistic Inquiry. Newbury Park, CA: Sage Publications; (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolfe G. Beyond expertise: theory, practice and the reflexive practitioner. J Clin Nurs. (1997) 6(2):93&#x2013;7. 10.1111/j.1365-2702.1997.tb00290.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2702.1997.tb00290.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9188346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger JL, Parker K, Cason L, Hauck S, Kaetzel D, O'Nan C, et al. Responses to work complexity: the novice to expert effect. West J Nurs Res. (2010) 32(4):497&#x2013;510. 10.1177/0193945909355149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0193945909355149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20685907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernawati, Bratajaya CNA. Senior nurses&#x2019; perceptions of essential soft skills for novice nurses in a private hospital in Jakarta, Indonesia: a phenomenological study. Belitung Nurs J. (2021) 7(4):320&#x2013;8. 10.33546/bnj.1549</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33546/bnj.1549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10361054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37484891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pazandeh F, Moridi M, Safari K. Labouring women perspectives on mistreatment during childbirth: a qualitative study. Nurs Ethics. (2023) 30(4):513&#x2013;25. 10.1177/09697330231158732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09697330231158732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36921625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff CE, Jarodzka H, Boshuizen HPA. See and tell: differences between expert and novice teachers&#x2019; interpretations of problematic classroom management events. Teach Teach Educ. (2017) 66:295&#x2013;308. 10.1016/j.tate.2017.04.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tate.2017.04.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healy C. Self-appropriation in nurse engagement: facilitating the development of expert nurses using Benner and Lonergan. Nurs Philos. (2024) 25(3):e12480. 10.1111/nup.12480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nup.12480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38843085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosander M, Forslund Frykedal K, Barimani M, Berlin A. Experiences from leading parental education groups: perceived difficulties and rewards as an indication of skill acquisition. J Child Health Care. (2021) 26(1):68&#x2013;81. 10.1177/13674935211000940</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13674935211000940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8943476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33706563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman KA, Aitken LM, Duffield C. A comparison of novice and expert nurses&#x2019; cue collection during clinical decision-making: verbal protocol analysis. Int J Nurs Stud. (2009) 46(10):1335&#x2013;44. 10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2009.04.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2009.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie M, Parker L, Kirchner J. From novice to expert: a qualitative study of implementation facilitation skills. Implement Sci Commun. (2020) 1(25):1. 10.1186/s43058-020-00006-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43058-020-00006-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson S, Rixon A, Brown C. Non-clinical intuitions and adaptive heuristics in emergency care: a scoping review. Int Emerg Nurs. (2023) 71. 10.1016/j.ienj.2023.101371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ienj.2023.101371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37866122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vedam S, Stoll K, Taiwo TK, Rubashkin N, Cheyney M, Strauss N, et al. The giving voice to mothers study: inequity and mistreatment during pregnancy and childbirth in the United States. Reprod Health. (2019) 16. 10.1186/s12978-019-0729-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-019-0729-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6558766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31182118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia LM. Obstetric violence in the United States and other high-income countries: an integrative review. Sex Reprod Health Matters. (2023) 31(1). 10.1080/26410397.2024.2322194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/26410397.2024.2322194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11005882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38590127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadwick R. The dangers of minimizing obstetric violence. Violence Against Women. (2023) 29(9):1899&#x2013;908. 10.1177/10778012211037379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10778012211037379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34751065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayo E, Christy K, Habte R. Health in colour: black women, racism, and maternal health. Lancet Regional Health-Americas. (2023) 17. 10.1016/j.lana.2022.100408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lana.2022.100408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9735204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36531129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JK. Structural racism and maternal health among black women. J Law Med Ethics. (2020) 48(3):506&#x2013;17. 10.1177/1073110520958875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1073110520958875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33021163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boakye PN, Prendergast N, Bandari B, Brown EA, Odutayo AA, Salami S. Obstetric racism and perceived quality of maternity care in Canada: voices of black women. Womens Health. (2023) 19. 10.1177/17455057231199651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17455057231199651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10542226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37772754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson CL, Filan J, Lindsey L, Mundell A, Rathbone AP, Nazar H. Intersectional identities: making sense of skill development on clinical placements. Am J Pharm Educ. (2023) 87(5). 10.1016/j.ajpe.2023.01.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpe.2023.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37288692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>