<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41381694</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Channel-spatial attention modules in convolutional neural networks for image classification.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2348</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2348</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2348</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-32055-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Many studies have established that the attention mechanism has great potential in improving the performance of Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) in image classification problems in recent years. Combining channel and spatial attention modules is one of the different kinds of attention mechanisms that are inspired by the visual perception of the human brain. So far, no paper has considered both parallel and sequential states of combining channel-spatial attention modules, so that while comparing them comprehensively and accurately, it can be definitively said which of them is more optimal in terms of a better balance between efficiency and computational complexity of the model. In this paper, we introduced two new types of channel-spatial attention modules, the Parallel Channel-spatial Attention Module (PCSAM) and the Sequential Channel-spatial Attention Module (SCSAM), to embed in the architecture of any CNN. Each of the proposed attention modules is composed of a channel and spatial attention sub-modules. The Channel Attention Module (CAM) and Spatial Attention Module (SAM) help the network in extracting the channels related to the architecture of the Region of Interest (RoI) and its location in the input feature maps, respectively. We increase the representation power of the attention-based networks by extracting the features using Global Average Pooling (GAP) and Global Maximum Pooling (GMP) in the CAM and SAM. Also, the Dilation Convolution (DC) layer is employed in the structure of the SAM instead of the standard convolution to better focus on the RoI in the feature maps. The PCSAM and SCSAM are implemented in the architecture of the ResNet18 and MobileNetv4 to produce the ResNet18PCSAM, ResNet18SCSAM, MobileNetv4PCSAM, and MobileNetv4SCSAM. All networks are trained and evaluated on three general image classification datasets, the CIFAR-10, CIFAR-100, and Tiny-ImageNet, with the same experimental conditions for 50 epochs. The classification results in the test step show that the MobileNetv4SCSAM has a better efficiency than other architectures on all datasets. It also achieved higher performance than the previous existing channel-spatial attention modules.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zolfaghari</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saniee Abadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran. saniee@modares.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sajedi</LastName><ForeName>Hedieh</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mathematics, Statistics and Computer Science, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>4039017</GrantID><Agency>Iran National Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Convolutional neural networks (CNNs)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Image classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parallel channel-spatial attention module (PCSAM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sequential channel-spatial attention module (SCSAM)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41381694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12815917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-32055-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-32055-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Choi, S.-H., Jeong, G., Kim, Y.-B. &amp; Cho, Z.-H. Proposal for human visual pathway in the extrastriate cortex by fiber tracking method using diffusion-weighted MRI. <i>J. NeuroImage</i><b>220</b>, 117145 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2020.117145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32650055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolls, E. T. Two what, two where, visual cortical streams in humans. <i>J. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev.</i><b>160</b>, 105650 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2024.105650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38574782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, B. Acting on what you are perceiving: The two-visual-systems hypothesis revisited: Two-visual-systems hypothesis revisited. <i>J. Nphi.</i><b>3</b>, 49&#x2013;58 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, M.-H. et al. Attention mechanisms in computer vision: A survey. <i>IEEE J. Comput. Vis. Media</i><b>8</b>, 331&#x2013;368 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41095-022-0271-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanin, M., Anwar, S., Radwan, I., Khan, F. S. &amp; Mian, A. Visual attention methods in deep learning: An in-depth survey. <i>J. Inf. fusion.</i><b>108</b>, 102417&#x2013;102417 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2024.102417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareh, M., Toulabinejad, E., Manshaei, M. H. &amp; Zahabi, S. J. A deep learning model of dorsal and ventral visual streams for DVSD. <i>J. Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 27464 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-78304-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11551208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39523365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauwers, G. &amp; Frasincar, F. A general survey on attention mechanisms in deep learning. <i>IEEE J. Trans. Knowl. Data Eng.</i><b>35</b>, 3279&#x2013;3298 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TKDE.2021.3126456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Santana Correia, A. &amp; Colombini, E. L. Attention, please! A survey of neural attention models in deep learning. <i>J. Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>55</b>, 6037&#x2013;6124 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-022-10148-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou, L. Biological image processing algorithm based on attention mechanism and convolutional neural network. <i>J. Adv. Multimed.</i><b>2023</b>, 1&#x2013;7 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/7464628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karmakar, P., Teng, S. W. &amp; Lu, G. Thank you for attention: A survey on attention-based artificial neural networks for automatic speech recognition. <i>J. Intell. Syst. Appl.</i><b>23</b>, 200406 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madanian, S. et al. A multi-dilated convolution network for speech emotion recognition. <i>J. Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 8254 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-92640-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11894186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40064942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krichen, M. Convolutional neural networks: A survey. <i>J. Comput.</i><b>12</b>, 151&#x2013;151 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X. et al. A review of convolutional neural networks in computer vision. <i>J. Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>57</b>, 99 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-024-10721-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakullukcu, E. Leveraging convolutional neural networks for image-based classification of feature matrix data. <i>J. Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>281</b>, 127625 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2025.127625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zolfaghari, M. &amp; Hedieh, S. Automated classification of pollen grains microscopic images using cognitive attention based on human two visual streams hypothesis. <i>PLoS ONE</i><b>19</b>, e0309674 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0309674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11581319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39570884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawahar, M., Anbarasi, L. J., Narayanan, S. &amp; Gandomi, A. H. An attention-based deep learning for acute lymphoblastic leukemia classification. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 17447 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-67826-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11286757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39075091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zolfaghari, M. &amp; Sajedi, H. Automated classification of Acute Lymphocytic Leukemia (ALL) images using light residual cognitive attention based on human two visual streams hypothesis. <i>J. Soft Comput.</i><b>1</b>, 1&#x2013;19 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11581319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39570884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, J., Shen, L. &amp; Sun, G. Squeeze-and-excitation networks. In <i>2018 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)</i> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Z., Xie, J., Wang, Q. &amp; Li, P. Global second-order pooling convolutional networks. In <i>2019 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)</i> (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, Z., Zhang, P., Wu, F. &amp; Li, X. FcaNet: Frequency channel attention networks. In <i>2021 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)</i> (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q. et al. ECA-Net: Efficient channel attention for deep convolutional neural networks. In <i>2020 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H., Kim, H.-E. &amp; Nam, H. SRM: A style-based recalibration module for convolutional neural networks. In <i>2019 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)</i> (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Z., Zhu, L., Wu, Y. &amp; Yang, Y. Gated channel transformation for visual recognition. In <i>2020 IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mnih, V., Heess, N., Graves, A. &amp; Kavukcuoglu, K. Recurrent models of visual attention. arXiv: 1406.6247 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, J., Shen, L., Albanie, S., Sun, G. &amp; Vedaldi, A. Gather-Excite: Exploiting feature context in convolutional neural networks. arXiv: 1810.12348 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran, P. et al. Stand-Alone Self-Attention in Vision Models. arXiv:1906.05909 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosovitskiy, A. et al. An Image is Worth 16x16 Words: Transformers for Image Recognition at Scale. arXiv:2010.11929 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo, S., Park, J., Lee, J.-Y. &amp; Kweon, I. S. CBAM: Convolutional Block Attention Module. In <i>Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)</i> 3&#x2013;19 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J., Woo, S., Lee, J.-Y. &amp; Kweon, I. S. A simple and light-weight attention module for convolutional neural networks. <i>Int. J. Comput. Vis.</i><b>128</b>, 783&#x2013;798 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11263-019-01283-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, G., Fang, Q., Zha, L., Gao, X. &amp; Zheng, N. HAM: Hybrid attention module in deep convolutional neural networks for image classification. <i>J. Pattern Recognit.</i><b>129</b>, 108785 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patcog.2022.108785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, T. et al. Spatial channel attention for deep convolutional neural networks. <i>J. Math.</i><b>10</b>, 1750 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10101750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H., Zhang, Y. &amp; Chen, Y. A symmetric efficient spatial and channel attention (ESCA) module based on convolutional neural networks. <i>J. Symmetry.</i><b>16</b>, 952 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym16080952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. An attention mechanism module with spatial perception and channel information interaction. <i>J. Complex Intell. Syst.</i><b>10</b>, 5427&#x2013;5444 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40747-024-01445-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizhevsky, A., Hinton, G. et al. Learning Multiple Layers of Features from Tiny Images. (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le, Y. &amp; Yang, X. Tiny imagenet visual recognition challenge. <i>CS</i><b>231N</b>(7), 3 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, K., Zhang, X., Ren, S. &amp; Sun, J. Deep residual learning for image recognition. In <i>2016 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)</i> (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, D. et al. MobileNetV4: Universal Models for the Mobile Ecosystem. In <i>Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS)</i> 78&#x2013;96 (Springer Nature Switzerland, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamaqa, A. &amp; Alahamade, W. O. A multi-phase framework for enhancing diagnostic accuracy and transparency in renal cell carcinoma grading using YOLOv8 and GradCAM. <i>J. Sci Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 35370 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-19342-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12511598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41068260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>