<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41452912</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A scoping review of interventions to prevent and treat adverse events during treatment of rifampin-susceptible tuberculosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0339354</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0339354</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0339354</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0339354</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Treatment-related adverse events are one of the leading barriers to tuberculosis treatment completion but have not been the focus of late-phase clinical trials. We performed a scoping review to identify interventions to improve the safety and tolerability of rifampin-susceptible tuberculosis. Our objective was to determine what interventions have been evaluated to prevent or manage adverse events, as well as what research is underway.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We searched Embase, PubMed, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, and Web of Science from 1970 to December 2024 using a broad set of terms regarding adverse events, as well as citation searches to identify additional studies in topic areas that were not well-represented in the initial title search. To identify research in progress we searched Clintrials.gov, Cochrane reviews, and International Clinical Trials Registry Platform for trials reported to be active between January 2015 to April 2025. Of 7314 titles reviewed, 119 papers were available and eligible for this scoping review: 37 (31%) evaluated changes in the tuberculosis treatment regimen, 55 (46%) evaluated other interventions to prevent adverse events, and 27 (23%) evaluated treatment of adverse events. Only 7 studies reported enrollment of children&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;12 years old. Of the 49 clinical trials, 20 (41%) had sample sizes&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;50 participants/arm. Notable gaps in research in this field: uncertainty about the safety of pyrazinamide, lack of research on prevention and management of nausea/vomiting, uncertainty about the impact of hepatoprotectants, and lack of inclusion of children. Of the 8 study proposals that appear to be in progress, five were for a single topic: isoniazid dosing based on N-actyltransferase-2 status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">There has been considerable research on improving the safety and tolerability of tuberculosis treatment, but its impact is limited by under-powered studies, the lack of inclusion of key subgroups, and important gaps in the research portfolio (uncertainties about the safety of pyrazinamide and the efficacy of hepatoprotectants, lack of research on ways to manage and prevent treatment-related nausea). It is concerning that the research pipeline for interventions to improve safety and tolerability appears to be quite limited Our review has identified promising interventions that may make treatment better tolerated, and hence, more effective.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Burman et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burman</LastName><ForeName>William J</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6982-1825</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Institute at Denver Health, Denver, Colorado, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Colorado Anschutz Medical Campus, Aurora, Colorado, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martins</LastName><ForeName>M Florencia</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5412-6173</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Infectious Diseases, Boston Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flynn</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7494-2098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Sciences and Education, Boston University Chobanian &amp; Avedisian School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8879-4989</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Provincial TB Services, British Columbia Centre for Disease Control, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinha</LastName><ForeName>Pranay</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Infectious Diseases, Boston Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horsburgh</LastName><ForeName>C Robert</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Global Health, Epidemiology, Biostatistics and Medicine, Schools of Public Health and Medicine, Boston University, Boston, Massachusetts, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>VJT6J7R4TR</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012293">Rifampin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000995">Antitubercular Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012293" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rifampin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014376" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tuberculosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000995" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antitubercular Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug-Related Side Effects and Adverse Reactions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41452912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12742745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0339354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-52218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tweed CD, Crook AM, Amukoye EI, Dawson R, Diacon AH, Hanekom M, et al. Toxicity associated with tuberculosis chemotherapy in the REMoxTB study. BMC Infect Dis. 2018;18(1):317. doi: 10.1186/s12879-018-3230-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-018-3230-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6042413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29996783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra F, Marra CA, Bruchet N, Richardson K, Moadebi S, Elwood RK, et al. Adverse drug reactions associated with first-line anti-tuberculosis drug regimens. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2007;11(8):868&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17705952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorent N, Sebatunzi O, Mukeshimana G, Van den Ende J, Clerinx J. Incidence and risk factors of serious adverse events during antituberculous treatment in Rwanda: a prospective cohort study. PLoS One. 2011;6(5):e19566. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0019566</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0019566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21611117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv X, Tang S, Xia Y, Wang X, Yuan Y, Hu D, et al. Adverse reactions due to directly observed treatment strategy therapy in Chinese tuberculosis patients: a prospective study. PLoS One. 2013;8(6):e65037. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0065037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0065037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3672195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23750225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon EG, Rasool S, Otaalo B, Motee A, Dear JW, Sloan D, et al. No action is without its side effects: Adverse drug reactions and missed doses of antituberculosis therapy, a scoping review. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2024;90(1):313&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1111/bcp.15908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.15908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10952801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37712491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh AL, Makmor-Bakry M, Islahudin F, Wong IC. Prevalence and predictive factors of tuberculosis treatment interruption in the Asia region: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Glob Health. 2023;8(1):e010592. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2022-010592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2022-010592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9853156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36650014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox WS, Strydom N, Imperial MZ, Jarlsberg L, Savic RM. Examining nonadherence in the treatment of tuberculosis: The patterns that lead to failure. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2023;89(7):1965&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1111/bcp.15515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.15515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louie JK, Keh C, Agraz-Lara R, Phillips A, Graves S. Adverse events associated with treatment for pan-susceptible tuberculosis in San Francisco. Clin Infect Dis. 2023;76(6):1121&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36322073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon BS, Kim Y, Lee SH, Lim SY, Lee YJ, Park JS, et al. The high incidence of severe adverse events due to pyrazinamide in elderly patients with tuberculosis. PLoS One. 2020;15(7):e0236109. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0236109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0236109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7373258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32692774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso MA, do Brasil PEAA, Schmaltz CAS, Sant&#x2019;Anna FM, Rolla VC. Tuberculosis Treatment Outcomes and Factors Associated with Each of Them in a Cohort Followed Up between 2010 and 2014. Biomed Res Int. 2017;2017:3974651. doi: 10.1155/2017/3974651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/3974651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5763121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29445736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang P, Xia Y, Liu F, Wang X, Yuan Y, Hu D, et al. Incidence, clinical features and impact on anti-tuberculosis treatment of anti-tuberculosis drug induced liver injury (ATLI) in China. PLoS One. 2011;6(7):e21836. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0021836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0021836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3130045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21750735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen RAM, Miller RF, Gorsuch T, Smith CJ, Schwenk A, Holmes W, et al. Adverse events and treatment interruption in tuberculosis patients with and without HIV co-infection. Thorax. 2006;61(9):791&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1136/thx.2006.058867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2006.058867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16844730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui AN, Khayyam KU, Sharma M. Effect of Diabetes Mellitus on Tuberculosis Treatment Outcome and Adverse Reactions in Patients Receiving Directly Observed Treatment Strategy in India: A Prospective Study. Biomed Res Int. 2016;2016:7273935. doi: 10.1155/2016/7273935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/7273935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5013229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27642601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Przybylski G, D&#x105;browska A, Trzci&#x144;ska H. Alcoholism and other socio-demographic risk factors for adverse TB-drug reactions and unsuccessful tuberculosis treatment - data from ten years&#x2019; observation at the Regional Centre of Pulmonology, Bydgoszcz, Poland. Med Sci Monit. 2014;20:444&#x2013;53. doi: 10.12659/MSM.890012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.890012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3965286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24643127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burman W, Luczynski P, Horsburgh CR, Phillips PPJ, Johnston J. Representativeness and adverse event reporting in late-phase clinical trials for rifampin-susceptible tuberculosis: a systematic review. Lancet Infect Dis. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39612926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burman W, Rucsineanu O, Horsburgh CR, Johnston J, Dorman SE, Menzies D. Research on the treatment of rifampin-susceptible tuberculosis-Time for a new approach. PLoS Med. 2024;21(7):e1004438. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1004438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1004438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11309436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39052666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, McInerney P, Munn Z, Tricco AC, Khalil H. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis - Scoping Reviews. JBI. 2024. https://synthesismanual.jbi.global</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR): Checklist and Explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467&#x2013;73. doi: 10.7326/M18-0850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirt J, Nordhausen T, Fuerst T, Ewald H, Appenzeller-Herzog C, TARCiS study group. Guidance on terminology, application, and reporting of citation searching: the TARCiS statement. BMJ. 2024;385:e078384. doi: 10.1136/bmj-2023-078384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2023-078384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38724089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasipanodya JG, Gumbo T. Clinical and toxicodynamic evidence that high-dose pyrazinamide is not more hepatotoxic than the low doses currently used. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2010;54(7):2847&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1128/AAC.01567-09</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01567-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2897291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20439617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millard J. A study of the optimisation of tuberculosis therapy. University of Liverpool. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara E, Suido Y, Asaoka M, Katano T, Okuda R, Sekine A, et al. Safety of pyrazinamide-including regimen in late elderly patients with pulmonary tuberculosis: A prospective randomized open-label study. J Infect Chemother. 2019;25(12):1026&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/j.jiac.2019.05.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiac.2019.05.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31229376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horita N, Miyazawa N, Yoshiyama T, Kojima R, Ishigatsubo Y, Kaneko T. Currently Used Low-Dose Pyrazinamide Does Not Increase Liver-Injury in the First Two Months of Tuberculosis Treatment. Intern Med. 2015;54(18):2315&#x2013;20. doi: 10.2169/internalmedicine.54.5533</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2169/internalmedicine.54.5533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26370854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi J, Jo T, Aso S, Matsui H, Fushimi K, Yasunaga H. Safety of pyrazinamide in elderly patients with tuberculosis in Japan: A nationwide cohort study. Respirology. 2024;29(10):905&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1111/resp.14753</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.14753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38772620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon JY, Kim T-O, Kim JS, Kim HW, Lee EG, Jung SS, et al. Impact of pyrazinamide usage on serious adverse events in elderly tuberculosis patients: A multicenter cohort study. PLoS One. 2024;19(9):e0309902. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0309902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0309902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11426458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39325726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ca&#xf1;ete C, Galarza I, Granados A, Farrero E, Estop&#xe0; R, Manresa F. Tuberculous pleural effusion: experience with six months of treatment with isoniazid and rifampicin. Thorax. 1994;49(11):1160&#x2013;1. doi: 10.1136/thx.49.11.1160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.49.11.1160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC475281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7831634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutt AK, Moers D, Stead WW. Tuberculous pleural effusion: 6-month therapy with isoniazid and rifampin. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1992;145(6):1429&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1164/ajrccm/145.6.1429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/ajrccm/145.6.1429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1596014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Rodr&#xed;guez JF, Valcarce-Pardeiro N, &#xc1;lvarez-D&#xed;az H, Mari&#xf1;o-Callejo A. Long-term efficacy of 6-month therapy with isoniazid and rifampin compared with isoniazid, rifampin, and pyrazinamide treatment for pleural tuberculosis. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2019;38(11):2121&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1007/s10096-019-03651-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-019-03651-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31377953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X-F, Yang Z-W, Li J. Adjunctive therapy with interferon-gamma for the treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis: a systematic review. Int J Infect Dis. 2011;15(9):e594-600. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2011.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2011.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaitzeva SI, Matveeva SL, Gerasimova TG, Pashkov YN, Butov DA, Pylypchuk VS, et al. Treatment of cavitary and infiltrating pulmonary tuberculosis with and without the immunomodulator Dzherelo. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2009;15(12):1154&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2009.02760.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2009.02760.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19456829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batbold U, Butov DO, Kutsyna GA, Damdinpurev N, Grinishina EA, Mijiddorj O, et al. Double-blind, placebo-controlled, 1:1 randomized Phase III clinical trial of Immunoxel honey lozenges as an adjunct immunotherapy in 269 patients with pulmonary tuberculosis. Immunotherapy. 2017;9(1):13&#x2013;24. doi: 10.2217/imt-2016-0079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/imt-2016-0079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27868466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu AY, Vel&#xe1;squez GE, Zhang N, Chang VK, Phillips PPJ, Nahid P, et al. Pyrazinamide Safety, Efficacy, and Dosing for Treating Drug-Susceptible Pulmonary Tuberculosis: A Phase 3, Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2024;210(11):1358&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1164/rccm.202401-0165OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202401-0165OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11622436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39012226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang KC, Leung CC, Yew WW, Lau TY, Tam CM. Hepatotoxicity of pyrazinamide: cohort and case-control analyses. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2008;177(12):1391&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1164/rccm.200802-355OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200802-355OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Ke Z, Cheng S. Efficacy and safety of short-term chemotherapy for patients with spinal tuberculosis undergoing surgery in Chinese population: a meta-analysis. J Orthop Surg Res. 2021;16(1):229. doi: 10.1186/s13018-021-02375-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-021-02375-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azuma J, Ohno M, Kubota R, Yokota S, Nagai T, Tsuyuguchi K, et al. NAT2 genotype guided regimen reduces isoniazid-induced liver injury and early treatment failure in the 6-month four-drug standard treatment of tuberculosis: a randomized controlled trial for pharmacogenetics-based therapy. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;69(5):1091&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1007/s00228-012-1429-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00228-012-1429-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3641305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23150149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HW, Lee JK, Kim E, Yim J-J, Lee C-H. The Effectiveness and Safety of Fluoroquinolone-Containing Regimen as a First-Line Treatment for Drug-Sensitive Pulmonary Tuberculosis: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. PLoS One. 2016;11(7):e0159827. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0159827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0159827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4959712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27455053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies G, Cerri S, Richeldi L. Rifabutin for treating pulmonary tuberculosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2007;2007(4):CD005159. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD005159.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD005159.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6532710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17943842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deanasa RS, Simanjuntak AM, Syafira F, Afladhanti PM, Hawari A, Riviati N. Efficacy and Safety Rifapentine-Containing Regimen for Drug Sensitive Tuberculosis: Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Pneumon. 2024;37(2). doi: 10.18332/pne/186260</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/pne/186260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien J-Y, Chien S-T, Huang S-Y, Yu C-J. Safety of rifabutin replacing rifampicin in the treatment of tuberculosis: a single-centre retrospective cohort study. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2014;69(3):790&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1093/jac/dkt446</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24243988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horne DJ, Spitters C, Narita M. Experience with rifabutin replacing rifampin in the treatment of tuberculosis. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2011;15(11):1485&#x2013;9, i. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.11.0068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.11.0068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3290133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehloenya RJ, Dlamini S, Muloiwa R, Kakande B, Ngwanya MR, Todd G, et al. Therapeutic Trial of Rifabutin After Rifampicin-Associated DRESS Syndrome in Tuberculosis-Human Immunodeficiency Virus Coinfected Patients. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2016;3(3):ofw130. doi: 10.1093/ofid/ofw130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofw130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4942758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27419190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Castro N, Mecha&#xef; F, Bachelet D, Canestri A, Joly V, Vandenhende M, et al. Treatment With a Three-Drug Regimen for Pulmonary Tuberculosis Based on Rapid Molecular Detection of Isoniazid Resistance: A Noninferiority Randomized Trial (FAST-TB). Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(8):ofac353. doi: 10.1093/ofid/ofac353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofac353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35949399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo K-W, Kim M, Kim Y-J, Lee H-K, Kim HK, Jeon D, et al. Early discontinuation of ethambutol in pulmonary tuberculosis treatment based on results of the GenoType MTBDRplus assay: A prospective, multicenter, non-inferiority randomized trial in South Korea. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2019;63(12):e00980-19. doi: 10.1128/AAC.00980-19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00980-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6879208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31527020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J-K, Lee JY, Kim DK, Yoon HI, Jeong I, Heo EY, et al. Substitution of ethambutol with linezolid during the intensive phase of treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis: a prospective, multicentre, randomised, open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2019;19(1):46&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(18)30480-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(18)30480-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30477961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shangguan Y, Guo W, Feng X, Shi Y, Li X, Pan Z, et al. Randomized control study of the use of faropenem for treating patients with pulmonary tuberculosis. Int J Infect Dis. 2023;132:99&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2023.04.388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2023.04.388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang KC, Leung CC, Yew WW, Tam CM. Standard anti-tuberculosis treatment and hepatotoxicity: do dosing schedules matter?. Eur Respir J. 2007;29(2):347&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1183/09031936.00090306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00090306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17005575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bose A, Kalita S, Rose W, Tharyan P. Intermittent versus daily therapy for treating tuberculosis in children. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;2014(1):CD007953. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD007953.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD007953.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6532685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24470141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Kumar A, Patel R, Prakash SS, Kumar S, Surya H, et al. Incidence and risk factors of antituberculosis drug-induced liver injury in India: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Indian J Gastroenterol. 2025;44(1):35&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1007/s12664-024-01643-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12664-024-01643-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39225936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuchottaworn C, Saipan B, Kittisup C, Cheewakul K. Adverse drug reactions and outcome of short course anti-tuberculosis drugs between single daily dose and split drug dose (BID) in pulmonary tuberculosis. J Med Assoc Thai. 2012;95(Suppl 8):S1-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23130467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santha T, Rehman F, Mitchison DA, Sarma GR, Reetha AM, Prabhaker R, et al. Split-drug regimens for the treatment of patients with sputum smear-positive pulmonary tuberculosis--a unique approach. Trop Med Int Health. 2004;9(5):551&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-3156.2004.01229.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3156.2004.01229.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15117298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra UK, Kumar M, Kalita J. Standard versus sequential anti-tubercular treatment in patients with tuberculous meningitis: a randomized controlled trial. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2021;115(1):94&#x2013;102. doi: 10.1093/trstmh/traa144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/trstmh/traa144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33241267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JL, Hadad DJ, Dietze R, Maciel ELN, Sewali B, Gitta P, et al. Shortening treatment in adults with noncavitary tuberculosis and 2-month culture conversion. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2009;180(6):558&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1164/rccm.200904-0536OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200904-0536OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2742745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19542476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makharia GK, Ghoshal UC, Ramakrishna BS, Agnihotri A, Ahuja V, Chowdhury SD, et al. Intermittent Directly Observed Therapy for Abdominal Tuberculosis: A Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial Comparing 6 Months Versus 9 Months of Therapy. Clin Infect Dis. 2015;61(5):750&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1093/cid/civ376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/civ376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma JB, Singh N, Dharmendra S, Singh UB, P V, Kumar S, et al. Six months versus nine months anti-tuberculous therapy for female genital tuberculosis: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2016;203:264&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1016/j.ejogrb.2016.05.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejogrb.2016.05.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27391900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkova A, Wills GH, Wobudeya E, Chabala C, Palmer M, Kinikar A, et al. Shorter Treatment for Nonsevere Tuberculosis in African and Indian Children. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(10):911&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2104535</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2104535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35263517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grace AG, Mittal A, Jain S, Tripathy JP, Satyanarayana S, Tharyan P, et al. Shortened treatment regimens versus the standard regimen for drug-sensitive pulmonary tuberculosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019;12(12):CD012918. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD012918.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD012918.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6953336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31828771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallardo CR, Rigau Comas D, Valderrama Rodr&#xed;guez A, Roqu&#xe9; i Figuls M, Parker LA, Cayl&#xe0; J, et al. Fixed-dose combinations of drugs versus single-drug formulations for treating pulmonary tuberculosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;2016(5):CD009913. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD009913.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD009913.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4916937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27186634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menzies D, Benedetti A, Paydar A, Martin I, Royce S, Pai M, et al. Effect of duration and intermittency of rifampin on tuberculosis treatment outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS Med. 2009;6(9):e1000146. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1000146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1000146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2736385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19753109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang KC, Leung CC, Yew WW, Chan SL, Tam CM. Dosing schedules of 6-month regimens and relapse for pulmonary tuberculosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2006;174(10):1153&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1164/rccm.200605-637OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200605-637OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16908866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahid P, Dorman SE, Alipanah N, Barry PM, Brozek JL, Cattamanchi A, et al. Official American Thoracic Society/Centers for Disease Control and Prevention/Infectious Diseases Society of America Clinical Practice Guidelines: Treatment of Drug-Susceptible Tuberculosis. Clin Infect Dis. 2016;63(7):e147&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciw376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciw376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6590850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27516382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agal S, Baijal R, Pramanik S, Patel N, Gupte P, Kamani P, et al. Monitoring and management of antituberculosis drug induced hepatotoxicity. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2005;20(11):1745&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1746.2005.04048.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1746.2005.04048.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16246196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singanayagam A, Sridhar S, Dhariwal J, Abdel-Aziz D, Munro K, Connell DW, et al. A comparison between two strategies for monitoring hepatic function during antituberculous therapy. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2012;185(6):653&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201105-0850OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201105-0850OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22198973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Xia Y, Lv X, Zhang Y, Tang S, Yang Z, et al. Effect of scheduled monitoring of liver function during anti-Tuberculosis treatment in a retrospective cohort in China. BMC Public Health. 2012;12:454. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-12-454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-12-454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3447730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22712786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burman W, Ellis J, Hale G, Hill K. Adequacy of recommendations for adverse event management in national and international treatment guidelines for rifampicin-susceptible tuberculosis: a systematic review. EClinicalMedicine. 2025;82:103148. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2025.103148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2025.103148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11957802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40166655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emrani Z, Shojaei E, Khalili H. Ginger for Prevention of Antituberculosis-induced Gastrointestinal Adverse Reactions Including Hepatotoxicity: A Randomized Pilot Clinical Trial. Phytother Res. 2016;30(6):1003&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1002/ptr.5607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.5607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26948519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahani FF, Michelle LE, Sulaeman AH, et al. Antiemetic activities of indonesian stingless bee propolis on emetic induced by anti-tuberculosis drugs. Int J Pharm Pharm Sci. 2021;:39&#x2013;44. doi: 10.22159/ijpps.2021v13i4.39618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22159/ijpps.2021v13i4.39618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S, Zhao S, Liu J, Zhang J, Zhang C, Hao H, et al. Efficacy of proprietary Lactobacillus casei for anti-tuberculosis associated gastrointestinal adverse reactions in adult patients: a randomized, open-label, dose-response trial. Food Funct. 2020;11(1):370&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1039/c9fo01583c</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c9fo01583c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31815260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian J, Hu P, Lu Y, Liu Y, Wang X, Zhang Y, et al. Prophylactic antiviral treatment reduces the incidence of liver failure among patients coinfected with Mycobacterium tuberculosis and hepatitis B virus. Virus Res. 2019;270:197664. doi: 10.1016/j.virusres.2019.197664</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virusres.2019.197664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31315023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C-H, Zhao M-Z, Chen G, Qi J-Y, Song J-X, Ning Q, et al. Baseline HBV load increases the risk of anti-tuberculous drug-induced hepatitis flares in patients with tuberculosis. J Huazhong Univ Sci Technolog Med Sci. 2017;37(1):105&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s11596-017-1702-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11596-017-1702-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28224437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui GCY, Wong N-S, Wong RYK, Tse Y-K, Wong VWS, Leung C-C, et al. Antiviral Therapy for Hepatitis B Prevents Liver Injury in Patients With Tuberculosis and Hepatitis B Coinfection. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;70(4):660&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciz241</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciz241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30919884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu N-H, Li L, Zhang X, Gu J, Du Y-D, Cai C, et al. Role of bicyclol in preventing drug-induced liver injury in tuberculosis patients with liver disease. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2015;19(4):475&#x2013;80. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.14.0579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.14.0579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25860005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanabria-Cabrera J, Tabbai S, Niu H, Alvarez-Alvarez I, Licata A, Bj&#xf6;rnsson E, et al. N-Acetylcysteine for the Management of Non-Acetaminophen Drug-Induced Liver Injury in Adults: A Systematic Review. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:876868. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.876868</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.876868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9152180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35656297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safe IP, Lacerda MVG, Printes VS, Praia Marins AF, Rebelo Rabelo AL, Costa AA, et al. Safety and efficacy of N-acetylcysteine in hospitalized patients with HIV-associated tuberculosis: An open-label, randomized, phase II trial (RIPENACTB Study). PLoS One. 2020;15(6):e0235381. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0235381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0235381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7319340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32589648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukumaran D, Usharani P, Paramjyothi GK, Subbalaxmi MVS, Sireesha K, Abid Ali M. A study to evaluate the hepatoprotective effect of N- acetylcysteine on anti tuberculosis drug induced hepatotoxicity and quality of life. Indian J Tuberc. 2023;70(3):303&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1016/j.ijtb.2022.05.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijtb.2022.05.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37562904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross GB, Sari IP, Kityo C, Lu Q, Pokharkar Y, Moorakonda RB, et al. Rosuvastatin adjunctive therapy for rifampicin-susceptible pulmonary tuberculosis: a phase 2b, randomised, open-label, multicentre trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2023;23(7):847&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(23)00067-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(23)00067-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36966799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adewole OO, Omotoso BA, Ogunsina M, Aminu A, Odeyemi AO, Awopeju OF, et al. Atorvastatin accelerates Mycobacterium tuberculosis clearance in pulmonary TB: a randomised phase IIA trial. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2023;27(3):226&#x2013;8. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.22.0548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.22.0548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36855033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C-K, Huang J-Y, Chang C-H, Tsai S-J, Shu C-C, Wang H-C, et al. The effect of statins on the risk of anti-tuberculosis drug-induced liver injury among patients with active tuberculosis: A cohort study. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2024;57(3):498&#x2013;508. doi: 10.1016/j.jmii.2024.04.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmii.2024.04.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38632021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao L, Qu X, Zhang Y, Song Y, Zhang S-X. Prophylactic Therapy of Silymarin (Milk Thistle) on Antituberculosis Drug-Induced Liver Injury: A Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Can J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;2019:3192351. doi: 10.1155/2019/3192351</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/3192351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6348824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30733935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magula D, Galisova Z, Iliev N, Markova I, Szalmova S, Letkovicova M. Effect of silymarine and Fumaria alkaloids in the prophylaxis of drug-induced liver injury during antituberculotic treatment. Studia Pneumologica et Phtiseologica. 1996;56(5):206&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talebi A, Soltani R, Khorvash F, Jouabadi SM. The Effectiveness of Silymarin in the Prevention of Anti-tuberculosis Drug-induced Hepatotoxicity: A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial. Int J Prev Med. 2023;14:48. doi: 10.4103/ijpvm.ijpvm_81_22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijpvm.ijpvm_81_22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37351038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong J-Y, Ren H, Peng S-Y, Xing K, Fan L, Liu M-Z, et al. Comparative effectiveness of glycyrrhizic acid preparations aimed at preventing and treating anti-tuberculosis drug-induced liver injury: A network meta-analysis of 97 randomized controlled trials. Phytomedicine. 2022;98:153942. doi: 10.1016/j.phymed.2022.153942</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2022.153942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35093672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong K, Cai J, Liu P, Wang J, Zhao S, Xu L, et al. Lactobacillus casei Alleviated the Abnormal Increase of Cholestasis-Related Liver Indices During Tuberculosis Treatment: A Post Hoc Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trial. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2021;65(16):e2100108. doi: 10.1002/mnfr.202100108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mnfr.202100108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33864432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakimizad R, Soltani R, Khorvash F, Marjani M, Dastan F. The Effect of acetyl-L-carnitine, Alpha-lipoic Acid, and Coenzyme Q10 Combination in Preventing Anti-tuberculosis Drug-induced Hepatotoxicity: A Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Clinical Trial. Iran J Pharm Res. 2021;20(3):431&#x2013;40. doi: 10.22037/ijpr.2021.114618.14953</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22037/ijpr.2021.114618.14953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8653653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34903999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amagon KI, Awodele O, Akindele AJ. Methionine and vitamin B-complex ameliorate antitubercular drugs-induced toxicity in exposed patients. Pharmacol Res Perspect. 2017;5(5):e00360. doi: 10.1002/prp2.360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/prp2.360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5625164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28971606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dange SV, Shah KU, Bulakh PM, Joshi DR. Efficacy of stimuliv, an indigenous compound formulation, against hepatotoxicity of antitubercular drugs--a double blind study. Indian J Chest Dis Allied Sci. 1992;34(4):175&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1302750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani M, Baninemati M, Khorvash F, Ataei B, Soltani R. The effects of livercare tablet [Combination of milk thistle, dandelion, barberry, tumeric (Curcumin), and artichoke] in prevention of anti-tuberculosis drugs-induced hepatotoxicity: A randomized controlled clinical trial. Journal of Isfahan Medical School. 2021;38(597):804&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddahi SZ, Jokar A, Kamalinejad M, Behnampur N. The efficacy of Jujube syrup on the prevention of drug-induced hepatotoxicity in pulmonary tuberculosis patients: A pilot randomized double-blind placebo-controlled clinical trial. Pharmacol Res Perspect. 2022;10(1):e00902. doi: 10.1002/prp2.902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/prp2.902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8929366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34939363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S, Xia Y, Lv X, Tang S, Yang Z, Zhang Y, et al. Preventive use of hepatoprotectors yields limited efficacy on the liver toxicity of anti-tuberculosis agents in a large cohort of Chinese patients. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2015;30(3):540&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1111/jgh.12717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgh.12717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25160904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Hu A, Ma A, Jiang F, Xiao Y, Chen Y, et al. Effectiveness of Prophylactic Use of Hepatoprotectants for Tuberculosis Drug-Induced Liver Injury: A Population-Based Cohort Analysis Involving 6,743 Chinese Patients. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:813682. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2022.813682</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.813682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9065346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35517815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Zhang F, Xu C, Liu K-G, Wu W, Tian Y-X. Is the Prophylactic Use of Hepatoprotectants Necessary in Anti-Tuberculosis Treatment?. Chemotherapy. 2017;62(5):269&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1159/000465515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000465515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Cai X-L, Lin X, Zheng J, Wu Y-L, Peng X-E. Hepatoprotective drugs for prevention of liver injury resulting from anti-tuberculosis treatment: A meta-analysis of cohort studies. Infect Med (Beijing). 2022;1(3):154&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.imj.2022.07.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imj.2022.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10699724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38077625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkahadsee P, Sawangjit R, Phumart P, Chaiyakunapruk N, Sakloetsakun D. Systematic review and network meta-analysis of efficacy and safety of interventions for preventing anti-tuberculosis drug induced liver injury. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):19880. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-46565-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-46565-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10645982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37963954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meintjes G, Stek C, Blumenthal L, Thienemann F, Schutz C, Buyze J, et al. Prednisone for the Prevention of Paradoxical Tuberculosis-Associated IRIS. N Engl J Med. 2018;379(20):1915&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1800762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1800762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30428290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Critchley JA, Orton LC, Pearson F. Adjunctive steroid therapy for managing pulmonary tuberculosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;2014(11):CD011370. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD011370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6532561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25387839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan H, Yoo J, Darsini P. Corticosteroids for tuberculous pleurisy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;3(3):CD001876. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD001876.pub3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001876.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5461868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28290161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunkar ML, Agnihotri SP, Gupta PR, Arya S. Add-on prednisolone in the management of cervical lymph node tuberculosis. Indian J Tuberc. 2016;63(2):96&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.ijtb.2015.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijtb.2015.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27451818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad K, Singh MB, Ryan H. Corticosteroids for managing tuberculous meningitis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;4(4):CD002244. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD002244.pub4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002244.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4916936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27121755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan J, Bang ND, Imran D, Nghia HDT, Burhan E, Huong DTT, et al. Adjunctive Dexamethasone for Tuberculous Meningitis in HIV-Positive Adults. N Engl J Med. 2023;389(15):1357&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2216218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2216218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7615197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37819954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mai NTH, Dobbs N, Phu NH, Colas RA, Thao LTP, Thuong NTT, et al. A randomised double blind placebo controlled phase 2 trial of adjunctive aspirin for tuberculous meningitis in HIV-uninfected adults. Elife. 2018;7:e33478. doi: 10.7554/eLife.33478</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.33478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5862527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29482717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra UK, Kalita J, Nair PP. Role of aspirin in tuberculous meningitis: a randomized open label placebo controlled trial. J Neurol Sci. 2010;293(1&#x2013;2):12&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2010.03.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2010.03.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20421121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayford FEA, Dolman RC, Blaauw R, Nienaber A, Smuts CM, Malan L, et al. The effects of anti-inflammatory agents as host-directed adjunct treatment of tuberculosis in humans: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Respir Res. 2020;21(1):223. doi: 10.1186/s12931-020-01488-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-020-01488-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7448999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32847532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng J, Li X, Xiong Y, Wu Y, Liu P, Gao S. The role of vitamin D in the prevention and treatment of tuberculosis: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Infection. 2025;53(3):1129&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1007/s15010-024-02446-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15010-024-02446-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39612153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butov D, Zaitseva S, Butova T, Stepanenko G, Pogorelova O, Zhelezniakova N. Efficacy and safety of quercetin and polyvinylpyrrolidone in treatment of patients with newly diagnosed destructive pulmonary tuberculosis in comparison with standard antimycobacterial therapy. Int J Mycobacteriol. 2016;5(4):446&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmyco.2016.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmyco.2016.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27931686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin S, Livchits V, Connery HS, Shields A, Yanov S, Yanova G, et al. Effectiveness of alcohol treatment interventions integrated into routine tuberculosis care in Tomsk, Russia. Addiction. 2013;108(8):1387&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1111/add.12148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.12148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23490304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter A, Beko B, Memani B, Furin J, Daniels J, Rodriguez E, et al. Implementing a Substance-Use Screening and Intervention Program for People Living with Rifampicin-Resistant Tuberculosis: Pragmatic Experience from Khayelitsha, South Africa. Trop Med Infect Dis. 2022;7(2):21. doi: 10.3390/tropicalmed7020021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/tropicalmed7020021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8879094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanqiu X, Yang Y, Xiaoqing W, Zhixuan L, Kuan Z, Xin G, et al. Impact of hyperglycemia on tuberculosis treatment outcomes: a cohort study. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):13586. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-64525-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-64525-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11169383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38866898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal R, Ambasta AK. Prospective, open labelled, randomised, parallel group study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of metformin add-on therapy to standard ATT in newly diagnosed pulmonary tuberculosis patients. International Journal of Toxicological and Pharmacological Research. 2022;12(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padmapriydarsini C, Mamulwar M, Mohan A, Shanmugam P, Gomathy NS, Mane A, et al. Randomized Trial of Metformin With Anti-Tuberculosis Drugs for Early Sputum Conversion in Adults With Pulmonary Tuberculosis. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75(3):425&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciab964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciab964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9427151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34849651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villamor E, Mugusi F, Urassa W, Bosch RJ, Saathoff E, Matsumoto K, et al. A trial of the effect of micronutrient supplementation on treatment outcome, T cell counts, morbidity, and mortality in adults with pulmonary tuberculosis. J Infect Dis. 2008;197(11):1499&#x2013;505. doi: 10.1086/587846</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/587846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2564793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18471061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B YPK, D P, M VA. A PROSPECTIVE SINGLE-BLINDED STUDY ON THE SAFETY AND EFFICACY OF ZINC SUPPLEMENTATION IN PULMONARY TUBERCULOSIS. Asian J Pharm Clin Res. 2018;11. doi: 10.22159/ajpcr.2018.v11s4.31685</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22159/ajpcr.2018.v11s4.31685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan S, Jenita X, Kalaiselvi P, Muthu V, Chandrasekar D, Varalakshmi P. Salubrious effect of vitamin E supplementation on renal stone forming risk factors in urogenital tuberculosis patients. Ren Fail. 2004;26(2):135&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1081/jdi-120038490</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1081/jdi-120038490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15287196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh C-J, Su W-J, Wu S-C, Chiu J-H, Lin L-C. Efficacy of acupressure to prevent adverse reactions to anti-tuberculosis drugs: Randomized controlled trials. J Adv Nurs. 2019;75(3):640&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1111/jan.13881</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jan.13881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30375013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adewole OO, Omotoso BA, Ogunsina M, Aminu A, Ayoola O, Adedeji T, et al. Atorvastatin improves sputum conversion and chest X-ray severity score. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2023;27(12):912&#x2013;7. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.23.0190</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.23.0190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38042968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noubiap JJ, Nansseu JR, Nyaga UF, Nkeck JR, Endomba FT, Kaze AD, et al. Global prevalence of diabetes in active tuberculosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of data from 2&#xb7;3 million patients with tuberculosis. Lancet Glob Health. 2019;7(4):e448&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30487-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30487-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30819531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Necho M, Tsehay M, Seid M, Zenebe Y, Belete A, Gelaye H, et al. Prevalence and associated factors for alcohol use disorder among tuberculosis patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis study. Subst Abuse Treat Prev Policy. 2021;16(1):2. doi: 10.1186/s13011-020-00335-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13011-020-00335-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33388060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soni H, Kumar-M P, Mishra S, Bellam BL, Singh H, Mandavdhare HS, et al. Risk of hepatitis with various reintroduction regimens of anti-tubercular therapy: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2020;18(2):171&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/14787210.2020.1714436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14787210.2020.1714436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31923369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaitra KR, Nagaraja BS, Rejeev D, Kiran S. Antituberculosis drug induced liver injury: clinical profile and outcome of various reintroduction regimens. Journal of Cardiovascular Disease Research. 2022;13(4):234&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbaspour F, Hasannezhad M, Khalili H, SeyedAlinaghi S, Jafari S. Managing Hepatotoxicity Caused by Anti-tuberculosis Drugs: A Comparative Study of Approaches. Arch Iran Med. 2024;27(3):122&#x2013;6. doi: 10.34172/aim.2024.19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/aim.2024.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11097316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38685836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moosa MS, Maartens G, Gunter H, Allie S, Chughlay MF, Setshedi M, et al. Rechallenge after anti-tuberculosis drug-induced liver injury in a high HIV prevalence cohort. South Afr J HIV Med. 2022;23(1):1376. doi: 10.4102/sajhivmed.v23i1.1376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4102/sajhivmed.v23i1.1376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9257779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35923608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Gu J, Yang Y, Chen Y, Wang Y, Mei Z, et al. Efficacy and safety of bicyclol for treating patients with antituberculosis drug-induced liver injury. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2024;28(1):6&#x2013;12. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.23.0038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.23.0038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38178298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungo JR, Jones D, Ashkin D, Hollender ES, Bernstein D, Albanese AP, et al. Antituberculosis drug-induced hepatotoxicity. The role of hepatitis C virus and the human immunodeficiency virus. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1998;157(6 Pt 1):1871&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1164/ajrccm.157.6.9711039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/ajrccm.157.6.9711039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjani M, Fahim F, Sadr M, Kazempour Dizaji M, Moniri A, Khabiri S, et al. Evaluation of Silymarin for management of anti-tuberculosis drug induced liver injury: a randomized clinical trial. Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench. 2019;12(2):138&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6536020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito Z, Kaneko Y, Kinoshita A, Kurita Y, Odashima K, Horikiri T, et al. Effectiveness of hepatoprotective drugs for anti-tuberculosis drug-induced hepatotoxicity: a retrospective analysis. BMC Infect Dis. 2016;16(1):668. doi: 10.1186/s12879-016-2000-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-016-2000-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5105306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27835982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katikova O, Asanov BM, Vize-Khripunova MA, Burba EN, Ruzov VI. Use of the plant hepatoprotector Galstena tuberculostatics-induced hepatic lesions: experimental and clinical study. Probl Tuberk. 2002;(4):32&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12125250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolomoiets MI, Shorikov II. The effect of the preparation Wobenzym on the antioxidant protection indices and on the functional-morphological properties of the erythrocytes in a toxic lesion of the liver. Lik Sprava. 1999;(5):124&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10822699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardhan H, Singh S, Singh V. A Study of the Oxidative Stress and the Role of Antioxidants in ATT Induced Hepatotoxicity in Tuberculosis Patients. Ind Jour of Publ Health Rese &amp; Develop. 2016;7(2):243. doi: 10.5958/0976-5506.2016.00101.7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5958/0976-5506.2016.00101.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Chen Z, Chen Q, Lin Q. Clinical study of deoxyribonucleotidum for adjuvant treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis with hepatic lesion. Nan Fang Yi Ke Da Xue Xue Bao. 2006;26(7):1044&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16864110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meintjes G, Wilkinson RJ, Morroni C, Pepper DJ, Rebe K, Rangaka MX, et al. Randomized placebo-controlled trial of prednisone for paradoxical tuberculosis-associated immune reconstitution inflammatory syndrome. AIDS. 2010;24(15):2381&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1097/QAD.0b013e32833dfc68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/QAD.0b013e32833dfc68</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2940061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20808204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miwa S, Suzuki Y, Shirai M, Ohba H, Kanai M, Eifuku T, et al. Drug lymphocyte stimulation test is not useful for side effects of anti-tuberculosis drugs despite its timing. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2012;16(9):1265&#x2013;9. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.11.0163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.11.0163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22747856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki Y, Miwa S, Shirai M, Ohba H, Murakami M, Fujita K, et al. Drug lymphocyte stimulation test in the diagnosis of adverse reactions to antituberculosis drugs. Chest. 2008;134(5):1027&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1378/chest.07-3088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.07-3088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18583516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehloenya RJ, Todd G, Wallace J, Ngwanya MR, Muloiwa R, Dheda K. Diagnostic patch testing following tuberculosis-associated cutaneous adverse drug reactions induces systemic reactions in HIV-infected persons. Br J Dermatol. 2016;175(1):150&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1111/bjd.14492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.14492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26918554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobashi Y, Okimoto N, Matsushima T, Abe T, Nishimura K, Shishido S, et al. Desensitization therapy for allergic reactions of antituberculous drugs--evaluation of desensitization therapy according to the guideline of the Japanese Society for Tuberculosis. Kekkaku. 2000;75(12):699&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11201137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehloenya RJ, Todd G, Badri M, Dheda K. Outcomes of reintroducing anti-tuberculosis drugs following cutaneous adverse drug reactions. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2011;15(12):1649&#x2013;57. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.10.0698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.10.0698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22118173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modi B, Modha J. Spectrum of anti tubercular therapy induced cutaneous adverse drug reactions and its management through rechallenge: A prospective study at a Tertiary Care Centre. Indian J Tuberc. 2022;69(4):470&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.ijtb.2021.07.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijtb.2021.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36460378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siripassorn K, Ruxrungtham K, Manosuthi W. Successful drug desensitization in patients with delayed-type allergic reactions to anti-tuberculosis drugs. Int J Infect Dis. 2018;68:61&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.ijid.2018.01.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2018.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29410254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smadhi H, Ben Saad S, Daghfous H, Ben Mansour A, Tritar F. Allergy to anti-tuberculosis treatment: Place of reintroduction drug test. Tunis Med. 2019;97(3):484&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31729724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermingham WH, Bhogal R, Arudi Nagarajan S, Mutlu L, El-Shabrawy RM, Madhan R, et al. Practical management of suspected hypersensitivity reactions to anti-tuberculosis drugs. Clin Exp Allergy. 2022;52(3):375&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1111/cea.14084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cea.14084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34939251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh JH, Yun J, Yang M-S, Kim J-H, Kim S-H, Kim S, et al. Reintroduction of Antituberculous Drugs in Patients with Antituberculous Drug-Related Drug Reaction with Eosinophilia and Systemic Symptoms. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2021;9(9):3442-3449.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.jaip.2021.03.054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaip.2021.03.054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33872812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor&#xe1;n-Mari&#xf1;os C, Llanos-Tejada F, Salas-Lopez J, Villanueva-Villegas R, Chavez-Huamani A, Vidal-Ruiz M, et al. DRESS syndrome and tuberculosis: Implementation of a desensitization and re-desensitization protocol to recover antituberculosis drugs in a case series at a specialized TB Unit in Lima, Peru. Medicine (Baltimore). 2024;103(39):e39365. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000039365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000039365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11441958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39331920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kura MM, Hira SK. Reintroducing antituberculosis therapy after Stevens-Johnson syndrome in human immunodeficiency virus-infected patients with tuberculosis: role of desensitization. Int J Dermatol. 2001;40(7):481&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-4362.2001.01173-7.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-4362.2001.01173-7.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11679013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borisova MI, Stakhanov VA, Sharkova TI, Ivashchenko NA. The use of fenazid in patients with pulmonary tuberculosis with poor isoniazid tolerance. Probl Tuberk Bolezn Legk. 2003;(7):34&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12939876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysov AV, Mordyk AV, Zatvornitski&#x12d; VA, Kondria AV. Adverse neurotoxic reactions of chemotherapy for tuberculosis and their treatment. Probl Tuberk Bolezn Legk. 2006;(9):45&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17128801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moosa MS, Maartens G, Gunter H, Allie S, Chughlay MF, Setshedi M, et al. A Randomized Controlled Trial of Intravenous N-Acetylcysteine in the Management of Anti-tuberculosis Drug-Induced Liver Injury. Clin Infect Dis. 2021;73(9):e3377&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciaa1255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa1255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Monitoring and management strategies for MDR/RR-TB treatment. 2025. https://tbksp.who.int/en/node/2980</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ijaz K, Jereb JA, Lambert LA, Bower WA, Spradling PR, McElroy PD, et al. Severe or fatal liver injury in 50 patients in the United States taking rifampin and pyrazinamide for latent tuberculosis infection. Clin Infect Dis. 2006;42(3):346&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1086/499244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/499244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16392079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim J, Kim JS, Kim HW, Kim YH, Jung SS, Kim JW, et al. Metabolic Disorders Are Associated With Drug-Induced Liver Injury During Antituberculosis Treatment: A Multicenter Prospective Observational Cohort Study in Korea. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2023;10(8):ofad422. doi: 10.1093/ofid/ofad422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ofid/ofad422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10468151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37654787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imperial MZ, Phillips PPJ, Nahid P, Savic RM. Precision-Enhancing Risk Stratification Tools for Selecting Optimal Treatment Durations in Tuberculosis Clinical Trials. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;204(9):1086&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1164/rccm.202101-0117OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202101-0117OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34346856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson M, Kirkham J, Dwan K, Sloan DJ, Davies G, Jorgensen AL. NAT2 variants and toxicity related to anti-tuberculosis agents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2019;23(3):293&#x2013;305. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.18.0324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.18.0324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6421944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utsunomiya M, Dobashi H, Odani T, Saito K, Yokogawa N, Nagasaka K, et al. Optimal regimens of sulfamethoxazole-trimethoprim for chemoprophylaxis of Pneumocystis pneumonia in patients with systemic rheumatic diseases: results from a non-blinded, randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Res Ther. 2017;19(1):7. doi: 10.1186/s13075-016-1206-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-016-1206-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5241919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28100282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Para MF, Finkelstein D, Becker S, Dohn M, Walawander A, Black JR. Reduced toxicity with gradual initiation of trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole as primary prophylaxis for Pneumocystis carinii pneumonia: AIDS Clinical Trials Group 268. J Acquir Immune Defic Syndr. 2000;24(4):337&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1097/00126334-200008010-00007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00126334-200008010-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11015150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith DE, Aksamit TR. Managing Mycobacterium avium Complex Lung Disease With a Little Help From My Friend. Chest. 2021;159(4):1372&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2020.10.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2020.10.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33080299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrstedt J, Clark-Snow R, Ruhlmann CH, Molassiotis A, Olver I, Rapoport BL, et al. 2023 MASCC and ESMO guideline update for the prevention of chemotherapy- and radiotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting. ESMO Open. 2024;9(2):102195. doi: 10.1016/j.esmoop.2023.102195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esmoop.2023.102195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10937211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38458657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan TJ, Belani KG, Bergese S, Chung F, Diemunsch P, Habib AS, et al. Fourth Consensus Guidelines for the Management of Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting. Anesth Analg. 2020;131(2):411&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000004833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/ANE.0000000000004833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32467512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcagnile S, Lanzarotti C, Rossi G, Henriksson A, Kammerer KP, Timmer W. Effect of netupitant, a highly selective NK&#x2081; receptor antagonist, on the pharmacokinetics of palonosetron and impact of the fixed dose combination of netupitant and palonosetron when coadministered with ketoconazole, rifampicin, and oral contraceptives. Support Care Cancer. 2013;21(10):2879&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1007/s00520-013-1857-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-013-1857-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23748441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villikka K, Kivist&#xf6; KT, Neuvonen PJ. The effect of rifampin on the pharmacokinetics of oral and intravenous ondansetron. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1999;65(4):377&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/S0009-9236(99)70130-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0009-9236(99)70130-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10223773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, McDonnell D, Yu M, Kumar V, von Moltke L. A Phase I Open-Label Study to Evaluate the Effects of Rifampin on the Pharmacokinetics of Olanzapine and Samidorphan Administered in Combination in Healthy Human Subjects. Clin Drug Investig. 2019;39(5):477&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1007/s40261-019-00775-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40261-019-00775-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30888624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prodanuk M, Silverberg SL, Piche-Renaud PP, Farrar DS, Cunningham J, Kritzinger F. Adverse events of first-line therapy for pediatric tuberculosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Infect Dis. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40127187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>