<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41836133</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1478-4726</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British paramedic journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br Paramed J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>360-degree projection simulation versus traditional simulation in undergraduate paramedicine education: a pilot randomised controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17</StartPage><EndPage>26</EndPage><MedlinePgn>17-26</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.29045/14784726.2025.3.9.4.17</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Simulation is considered a mainstay for teaching and assessment in various clinical fields, including paramedicine. Simulation fidelity in educational practice is constantly changing to accommodate the integration of extended realities (XRs), such as augmented, mixed and virtual realities. However, little research has been undertaken to directly compare these newer, technology-enhanced methods, such as 360-degree projection simulation, with the traditional methods used in undergraduate education. The purpose of this research was to provide a direct comparison, exploring their effect on ratings of self-perceived performance in second-year paramedicine students.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Using a single-site, parallel randomised controlled, non-blinded trial, participants were randomly allocated to a three-day intensive 360-degree projection (intervention) or traditional (control) simulation programme. Ratings of self-perceived performance were collected using the Seattle University Simulation Evaluation tool at three different time points: after participants' first simulation as 'lead paramedic' on Day 1 of the intensive programme (Rating 1), after their final simulation on Day 3 of the intensive programme (Rating 2) and after their final simulation in a follow-up programme after a nine-week washout period (Rating 3).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Out of the 37 participants randomly allocated, 20 fulfilled the study requirements, with 11 in the 360-degree projection group and nine in the traditional simulation group. Participants consistently reported higher ratings of self-perceived performance in the traditional simulation group, in comparison to the 360-degree projection simulation group (p = 0.04). While no difference was seen between groups after the intensive programme (Rating 2), a notable difference was observed between groups at Rating 3 in favour of the traditional simulation group (p = 0.02).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This pilot study suggested that measures of self-perceived performance were lower when using 360-degree projection simulation spaces. While there may be some benefit to this form of simulation as an adjunct to current traditional methods used, further research, including studies that are appropriately powered and include objective outcome measures, is needed to understand the measure of effectiveness in a practical setting and to inform future educational interventions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vella</LastName><ForeName>Rachael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western Sydney University ORCID iD: https://orcid.org/0000-0001-8268-2866.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simpson</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western Sydney University ORCID iD: https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3875-0061.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thyer</LastName><ForeName>Liz</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western Sydney University ORCID iD: https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8144-4441.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br Paramed J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101697267</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1478-4726</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extended reality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immersive</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paramedics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">simulation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41836133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12981534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29045/14784726.2025.3.9.4.17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aebersold M. (2018). Simulation based learning: No longer a novelty in undergraduate education. <i>Online Journal of Issues in Nursing</i>, 23(2), 1. https://doi.org/10.3912/OJIN.Vol23No02PPT39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alastalo M., Salminen L., Vahlberg T., et al.  (2022). Subjective and objective assessment in skills evaluation: A cross-sectional study among critical care nurses. <i>Nordic Journal of Nursing Research</i>. https://doi.org/10.1177/20571585221089145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alconero-Camarero A. R., Sarabia-Cobo C. M., Catalan-Piris M. J., et al.  (2021). Nursing students&#x2019; satisfaction: A comparison between medium- and high-fidelity simulation training. <i>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</i>, 18(2), 1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18020804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33477836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Gharibi K. A. &amp; Arulappan J. (2020). Repeated simulation experience on self-confidence, critical thinking, and competence of nurses and nursing students &#x2013; An integrative review. <i>SAGE Open Nursing</i>, 6, 1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1177/2377960820927377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7774432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33415282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barr N. &amp; Foster J.-A. (2017). Using consensus group methods to improve simulation using immersive media in paramedicine. <i>Journal of Paramedic Practice</i>, 9(3). https://doi.org/10.12968/jpar.2017.9.3.121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birtill M., King J., Jones D., et al.  (2021). The use of immersive simulation in paramedicine education: A scoping review. <i>Interactive Learning Environments</i>, 31(4), 2428&#x2013;2443. https://doi.org/10.1080/10494820.2021.1889607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackmore C., Austin J., Lopushinksy S. R., et al.  (2014). Effects of postgraduate medical education boot camps on clinical skills, knowledge, and confidence: A meta-analysis. <i>Journal of Graduate Medical Education</i>, 6(4), 643&#x2013;652. https://doi.org/10.4300/JGME-D-13-00373.1.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4477555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26140112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle M., Williams B. &amp; Burgess S. (2007). Contemporary simulation education for undergraduate paramedic students. <i>Emergency Medicine Journal</i>, 24, 854&#x2013;857. https://doi.org/10.1136/emj.2007.046318.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2658363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18029524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert J. &amp; Abadia R. (2020). Impact of immersing university and high school students in educational linear narratives using virtual reality technology. <i>Computers &amp; Education</i>, 159, 104005. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2020.104005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter O. B. J., Mills B. W., Ross N. P., et al.  (2016). Assessing simulation based clinical training: Comparing the concurrent validity of students&#x2019; self-reported satisfaction and confidence measures against objective clinical examinations. <i>BMJ Simulation and Technology Enhanced Learning</i>, 2(2), 30&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjstel-2015-000089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8936985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35518192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conradi E., Kavia S., Burden D., et al.  (2009). Virtual patients in a virtual world: Training paramedic students for practice. <i>Medical Teacher</i>, 31(8), 713&#x2013;720. https://doi.org/10.1080/01421590903134160.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19811207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CONSORT. (2010). <i>The CONSORT flow diagram</i>. https://www.equator-network.org/reporting-guidelines/consort/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dante A., La Cerra C., Caponnetto V., et al.  (2022). Dose&#x2013;response relationship between high-fidelity simulation and intensive care nursing students&#x2019; learning outcomes: An Italian multimethod study. <i>International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</i>, 19(2), Article 617. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph19020617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8775508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35055439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlam G. D., Smythe L. &amp; Wright V. (2017). Navigating the storm of deteriorating patients: Seven scaffolds for simulation design. <i>Open Journal of Nursing</i>, 7(6), 683&#x2013;697. https://doi.org/10.4236/ojn.2017.76051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser K. L., Ayres P. &amp; Sweller J. (2015). Cognitive load theory for the design of medical simulations. <i>Simulation in Healthcare</i>, 10(5), 295&#x2013;307. https://doi.org/10.1097/SIH.0000000000000097.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26154251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graves L., Lalla L. &amp; Young M. (2017). Evaluation of perceived and actual competency in a family medicine objective structured clinical examination. <i>Canadian Family Physician</i>, 63(4), e238&#x2013;e243. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28404722/.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5389778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28404722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara M. A., Kangstrom A., Jonsson A., et al.  (2014). Effect of simulation on the clinical competence of Swedish ambulance nurses. <i>Australasian Journal of Paramedicine</i>, 11(2). https://doi.org/10.33151/ajp.11.2.20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey R. D., Mileham K., Bhatnager V., et al.  (2021). Modernizing clinical trial eligibility criteria: Recommendations of the ASCO-friends of cancer research washout period and concomitant medication work group. <i>Clinical Cancer Research</i>, 9(27), 2400&#x2013;2407. https://doi.org/10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-20-3855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8102304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33563635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imperial College London. (2014). <i>The London handbook for debriefing: Enhancing performance debriefing in clinical and simulated settings</i>. https://www.imperial.ac.uk/media/imperial-college/medicine/surgery-cancer/pstrc/lw2222ic_debrief_book_a5.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katowa-Mukwato P. &amp; Banda S. (2016). Self-perceived versus objectively measured competence in performing clinical procedures by final year medical students. <i>International Journal of Medical Education</i>, 7, 122&#x2013;129. https://doi.org/10.5116/ijme.5709.2a7e.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4860286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27132255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy S., Kenny A. &amp; O&#x2019;Meara P. (2015). Student paramedic experience of transition into the workforce: A scoping review. <i>Nurse Education Today</i>, 35(10), 1037&#x2013;1043. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nedt.2015.04.015.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keys E., Luctkar-Flude M., Tyermand J., et al.  (2021). The integration of virtual simulation gaming into undergraduate nursing resuscitation education: A pilot randomised controlled trial. <i>Clinical Simulation in Nursing</i>, 54, 54&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecns.2021.01.013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan L. C. (2018). Evaluating competence and confidence using simulation technology. <i>Nursing</i>, 48(10), 45&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.NURSE.0000545022.36908.f3.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6155363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30211760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koornneef E., Loney T., Alsuwaidi A. R., et al.  (2018). Is there a difference between self-perceived performance and observed performance in an objective structured clinical examination (OSCE)? An exploratory study among medical students in the United Arab Emirates. <i>MedEdPublish</i>, 7, Article 180. https://doi.org/10.15694/mep.2018.0000180.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leblanc V. R., Regehr C., Tavares W., et al.  (2012). The impact of stress on paramedic performance during simulated critical events. <i>Prehospital Disaster Management</i>, 27(4), 369&#x2013;374. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1049023X12001021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22831965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Noury P., Polman R., Maloney M., et al.  (2022). A narrative review of the current state of extended reality technology and how it can be utilised in sport. <i>Sports Medicine</i>, 52, 1473&#x2013;1489. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40279-022-01669-0.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9213326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35286617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lioce L., Lopreiato J., Anderson M., et al.  (2024). <i>Healthcare Simulation Dictionary &#x2013; Third Edition</i>. Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality. https://www.ahrq.gov/sites/default/files/wysiwyg/patient-safety/resources/simulation/sim-dictionary-3rd.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little A., Zeniou P., Maxwell A., et al.  (2021). <i>Getting hands-on: A reflection of the value of immersive simulation with 360-degree projection</i>. Australian Paramedic. http://hdl.handle.net/10072/407441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lochmannova A., Simon M., Horejsi P., et al.  (2022). The use of virtual reality in training paramedics for a mass casualty incident. <i>Applied Sciences</i>, 12(22), 11740. https://doi.org/10.3390/app122211740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikasa A. W., Cicero T. F. &amp; Adamson K. A. (2013). Outcome-based evaluation tool to evaluate student performance in high-fidelity simulation. <i>Clinical Simulation in Nursing</i>, 9(9), e361&#x2013;e367. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecns.2012.06.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills B. W., Carter O. B.-J., Rudd C. J., et al.  (2016). Effects of low- versus high-fidelity simulations on the cognitive burden and performance of entry-level paramedicine students: A mixed-methods comparison trial using eye-tracking, continuous heart rate, difficulty rating scales, video observation and interviews. <i>Simulation in Healthcare</i>, 11(1), 10&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1097/SIH.0000000000000119.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26536339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mould J., White H. &amp; Gallagher R. (2011). Evaluation of a critical care simulation series for undergraduate nursing students. <i>Contemporary Nurse</i>, 38(1&#x2013;2), 180&#x2013;190. https://doi.org/10.5172/conu.2011.38.1-2.180.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21854249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pekrun R. (2020). Self-report is indispensable to assess students&#x2019; learning. <i>Frontline Learning Research</i>, 8(3), 185&#x2013;193. https://doi.org/10.14786/flr.v8i3.637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilcher J., Goodall H., Jensen C., et al.  (2012). Simulation-based learning: It&#x2019;s not just for NRP. <i>Neonatal Network</i>, 31(5), 281&#x2013;287. https://doi.org/10.1891/0730-0832.31.5.281.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22908048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rees N., Vaughan N., Day T. W., et al.  (2020). ParaVR: A virtual reality training simulator for paramedic skills maintenance. <i>Journal of Paramedic Practice</i>, 12(12), 478&#x2013;486. https://doi.org/10.12968/jpar.2020.12.12.478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem M. &amp; Khan Z. (2023). Healthcare simulation: An effective way of learning in health care. <i>Pakistan Journal of Medical Sciences</i>, 39(4), 1185&#x2013;1190. https://doi.org/10.12669/pjms.39.4.7145.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10364267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37492303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A., Framp A. &amp; Andersen P. (2020). Assessing competence of undergraduate paramedic student practice: A preliminary evaluation tool of the Australasian paramedic competency assessment tool. <i>Australasian Journal of Paramedicine</i>, 17, 1&#x2013;8. 10.33151/ajp.17.804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33151/ajp.17.804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan A., Elshenawy S., Ades A., et al.  (2019). Acquiring and maintaining technical skills using simulation: Initial, maintenance, booster and refresher training. <i>Cureus</i>, 11(9), Article e5729. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.5729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6825451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31723493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svellingen A. H., Sovik M. B., Roykenes K., et al.  (2021). The effect of multiple exposures in scenario-based simulation &#x2013; A mixed study systematic review. <i>Nursing Open</i>, 8(1), 380&#x2013;394. https://doi.org/10.1002/nop2.639.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7729777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33318846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremosa L. (2022). <i>Beyond AR vs. VR: What is the difference between AR vs. MR vs. VR vs. XR</i>? Interaction Design Foundation. https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/beyond-ar-vs-vr-what-is-the-difference-between-ar-vs-mr-vs-vr-vs-xr.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virk A., Joshi A., Mahajan R., et al.  (2020). The power of subjectivity in competency-based assessment. <i>Journal of Postgraduate Medicine</i>, 66(4), 200&#x2013;205. https://doi.org/10.4103/jpgm.JPGM_591_20.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7819378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33037168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams B., Beovich B., Olaussen A., et al.  (2022). Immersive simulation and paramedicine students&#x2019; situational awareness: A mixed-methods pilot study. <i>Medical Research Archives</i>, 10(9). https://doi.org/10.18103/mra.v10i9.3029.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zweifach S. M. &amp; Triola M. M. (2019). Extended reality in medical education: Driving adoption through provider-centered design. <i>Digital Biomarkers</i>, 3(1), 14&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1159/000498923.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7015382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32095765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>