<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41779852</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural vibration monitoring with diffractive optical processors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eaea1712</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eaea1712</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eaea1712</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.aea1712</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Structural health monitoring (SHM) is vital for maintaining the safety and longevity of civil infrastructure, yet current solutions remain constrained by cost, power consumption, scalability, and the complexity of data processing. Here, we present a diffractive vibration monitoring system, integrating a jointly optimized diffractive layer with a shallow neural network-based backend to remotely extract three-dimensional (3D) structural vibration spectra, offering a low-power, cost-effective, and scalable solution. Unlike prior diffractive processors designed primarily for static image classification or reconstruction tasks, this framework establishes a dynamic computational sensing modality where the optical front-end is co-optimized to encode time-varying mechanical vibrations into distinct spatiotemporal optical patterns. This architecture eliminates the need for dense sensor arrays or extensive data acquisition; instead, it uses a spatially optimized passive diffractive layer that encodes 3D structural displacements into modulated light, captured by a minimal number of detectors and decoded in real time by shallow and low-power neural networks to reconstruct the 3D displacement spectra of structures. The diffractive system's efficacy was demonstrated both numerically and experimentally using millimeter-wave illumination on a laboratory-scale building model with a programmable shake table. Our system achieves more than an order-of-magnitude improvement in accuracy over conventional optics or separately trained modules, establishing a foundation for high-throughput 3D monitoring of structures. Beyond SHM, the 3D vibration monitoring capabilities of this cost-effective and data-efficient framework establish a distinct computational sensing modality with potential applications in disaster resilience, aerospace diagnostics, and autonomous navigation-where energy efficiency, low latency, and high-throughput are critical.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yuntian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-1774-3636</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bioengineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>California NanoSystems Institute (CNSI), University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yilmaz</LastName><ForeName>Zafer</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil and Environmental Engineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuhang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9364-4125</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bioengineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>California NanoSystems Institute (CNSI), University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Edward</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-5235-5156</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahlberg</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil and Environmental Engineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghahari</LastName><ForeName>Farid</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3847-5277</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>California Geological Survey, California Department of Conservation, Sacramento, CA 95814, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taciroglu</LastName><ForeName>Ertugrul</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9618-1210</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil and Environmental Engineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozcan</LastName><ForeName>Aydogan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0717-683X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bioengineering Department, University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>California NanoSystems Institute (CNSI), University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>A.O., E.T., Y.W., and Y.L. are coinventors of a pending patent application on the presented method, filed by UCLA (application no. 63/755,950; filed on 7 February 2025; currently pending). The other authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41779852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12959400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.aea1712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Blagojevi&#x107; N., Hefti F., Henken J., Didier M., Stojadinovi&#x107; B., Quantifying disaster resilience of a community with interdependent civil infrastructure systems. Struct. Infrastruct. Eng. 19, 1696&#x2013;1710 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang S. E., Shinozuka M., Measuring improvements in the disaster resilience of communities. Earthq. Spectra 20, 739&#x2013;755 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achillopoulou D. V., Mitoulis S. A., Argyroudis S. A., Wang Y., Monitoring of transport infrastructure exposed to multiple hazards: A roadmap for building resilience. Sci. Total Environ. 746, 141001 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32795756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao H., Bi K., Chen W., Pham T. M., Li J., Towards next generation design of sustainable, durable, multi-hazard resistant, resilient, and smart civil engineering structures. Eng. Struct. 277, 115477 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z., German S., Brilakis I., Visual retrieval of concrete crack properties for automated post-earthquake structural safety evaluation. Autom. Constr. 20, 874&#x2013;883 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghunandan M., Liel A. B., Luco N., Aftershock collapse vulnerability assessment of reinforced concrete frame structures. Earthq. Eng. Struct. Dyn. 44, 419&#x2013;439 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graybeal B. A., Phares B. M., Rolander D. D., Moore M., Washer G., Visual inspection of highway bridges. J. Nondestruct. Eval. 21, 67&#x2013;83 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho&#x142;a J., Sadowski &#x141;., Non-destructive testing in civil engineering. Appl.Sci. 12, 7187 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schabowicz K., Non-destructive testing of materials in civil engineering. Materials 12, 3237 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6804297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31623301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasal B., Anthony R. W., Advances in in situ evaluation of timber structures. Prog. Struct. Eng. Mat. 6, 94&#x2013;103 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj B., Jayakumar T., Rao B. P. C., Non-destructive testing and evaluation for structural integrity. Sadhana 20, 5&#x2013;38 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou Y., Tong L., Steven G. P., Vibration-based model-dependent damage (delamination) identification and health monitoring for composite structures&#x2014;A review. J. Sound Vib. 230, 357&#x2013;378 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieven N. A. J., Ewins D. J., Farrar C. R., Doebling S. W., Nix D. A., Vibration&#x2013;based structural damage identification. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. London Ser. A Math. Phys. Eng. Sci. 359, 131&#x2013;149 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritzen C. P., Vibration-based structural health monitoring&#x2014;Concepts and applications. Key Eng. Mater. 293-294, 3&#x2013;20 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Arnaud, W. Keith, <i>New Trends in Vibration Based Structural Health Monitoring</i> CISM International Centre for Mechanical Sciences, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;str&#xf6;m K. J., Eykhoff P., System identification&#x2014;A survey. Automatica 7, 123&#x2013;162 (1971).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Ljung, <i>System Identification (2nd Ed.): Theory for the User</i> (Prentice Hall PTR, 1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Bendat, A. G. Piersol, <i>Engineering Applications of Correlation and Spectral Analysis</i> (John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Overschee P., De Moor B., Subspace algorithms for the stochastic identification problem. Automatica 29, 649&#x2013;660 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. H. James III, T. G. Carne, J. P. Lauffer, &#x201c;The natural excitation technique (NExT) for modal parameter extraction from operating wind turbines&#x201d; (Sandia National Laboratories, 1993), p. 28603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juang J.-N., Pappa R. S., An eigensystem realization algorithm for modal parameter identification and model reduction. J. Guid. Control Dyn. 8, 620&#x2013;627 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., Taciroglu E., Blind modal identification of non-classically damped structures under non-stationary excitations. Struct. Control Health Monit. 24, e1925 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahari S. F., Ghannad M. A., Taciroglu E., Blind identification of soil&#x2013;structure systems. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 45, 56&#x2013;69 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., Ghannad M. A., Taciroglu E., Response-only modal identification of structures using strong motion data. Earthq. Eng. Struct. Dyn. 42, 1221&#x2013;1242 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abazarsa F., Nateghi F., Ghahari S. F., Taciroglu E., Blind modal identification of non-classically damped systems from free or ambient vibration records. Earthq. Spectra 29, 1137&#x2013;1157 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abazarsa F., Nateghi F., Ghahari S. F., Taciroglu E., Extended blind modal identification technique for nonstationary excitations and its verification and validation. J. Eng. Mech. 142, 04015078 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abazarsa F., Ghahari S. F., Nateghi F., Taciroglu E., Response-only modal identification of structures using limited sensors. Struct. Control Health Monit. 20, 987&#x2013;1006 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., Ghannad M. A., &#xc7;elebi M., Taciroglu E., Blind modal identification of structures from spatially sparse seismic response signals. Struct. Control Health Monit. 21, 649&#x2013;674 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Taciroglu, S. F. Ghahari, &#x201c;Identification of soil-foundation dynamic stiffness from seismic response signals,&#x201d; in <i>ACI Symposium Paper</i> (American Concrete Institute, 2017), vol. 316, pp. 113&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taciroglu E., Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., Efficient model updating of a multi-story frame and its foundation stiffness from earthquake records using a timoshenko beam model. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 92, 25&#x2013;35 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taciroglu E., &#xc7;elebi M., Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., An investigation of soil-structure interaction effects observed at the MIT Green Building. Earthq. Spectra 32, 2425&#x2013;2448 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., Jeong C., Kurtulus A., Taciroglu E., Blind identification of site effects and bedrock motion from surface response signals. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 107, 322&#x2013;331 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;elebi M., Hisada Y., Omrani R., Ghahari S. F., Taciroglu E., Responses of two tall buildings in Tokyo, Japan, before, during, and after the M9.0 Tohoku Earthquake of 11 March 2011. Earthq. Spectra 32, 463&#x2013;495 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;elebi M., Kashima T., Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., Taciroglu E., Responses of a tall building with U.S. Code-Type Instrumentation in Tokyo, Japan, to Events before, during, and after the Tohoku Earthquake of 11 March 2011. Earthq. Spectra 32, 497&#x2013;522 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahari S. F., Abazarsa F., Avci O., &#xc7;elebi M., Taciroglu E., Blind identification of the Millikan Library from earthquake data considering soil&#x2013;structure interaction. Struct. Control Health Monit. 23, 684&#x2013;706 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;elebi M., Kashima T., Ghahari S. F., Koyama S., Tacirogle E., Okawa I., Before and after retrofit behavior and performance of a 55-story tall building inferred from distant earthquake and ambient vibration data. Earthq. Spectra 33, 1599&#x2013;1626 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahari F., Malekghaini N., Ebrahimian H., Taciroglu E., Bridge digital twinning using an output-only Bayesian model updating method and recorded seismic measurements. Sensors 22, 1278 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8838164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35162022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Zhang P., Xu X., Literature review of digital twin technologies for civil infrastructure. J. Infrastruct. Intell. Resil. 2, 100050 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoodian M., Shahrivar F., Setunge S., Mazaheri S., Development of digital twin for intelligent maintenance of civil infrastructure. Sustainability 14, 8664 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang F., Ma L., Broyd T., Chen K., Digital twin and its implementations in the civil engineering sector. Autom. Constr. 130, 103838 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng R., Hou L., Xu S., A review of digital twin applications in civil and infrastructure emergency management. Buildings 13, 1143 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Rainieri, I. Rosati, L. Cieri, G. Fabbrocino, &#x201c;Development of the digital twin of a historical structure for SHM purposes&#x201d; in <i>European Workshop on Structural Health Monitoring</i>, P. Rizzo, A. Milazzo, Eds. (Springer International Publishing, 2023), pp. 639&#x2013;646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwis L. S. M., Bremer K., Roth B., Fiber optic sensors embedded in textile-reinforced concrete for smart structural health monitoring: A review. Sensors 21, 4948 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8347898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siringoringo D. M., Fujino Y., Experimental study of laser Doppler vibrometer and ambient vibration for vibration-based damage detection. Eng. Struct. 28, 1803&#x2013;1815 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothberg S. J., Allen M. S., Castellini P., Di Maio D., Dirckx J. J. J., Ewins D. J., Halkon B. J., Muyshondt P., Paone N., Ryan T., Steger H., Tomasini E. P., Vanlanduit S., Vignola J. F., An international review of laser Doppler vibrometry: Making light work of vibration measurement. Opt. Lasers Eng. 99, 11&#x2013;22 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Brownjohn J. M. W., Review of machine-vision based methodologies for displacement measurement in civil structures. J. Civ. Struct. Health Monit. 8, 91&#x2013;110 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro D., Santos R., Cabral R., Saramago G., Montenegro P., Carvalho H., Correia J., Cal&#xe7;ada R., Non-contact structural displacement measurement using Unmanned Aerial Vehicles and video-based systems. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 160, 107869 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center, NGA-West2&#x2014;Shallow Crustal Earthquakes in Active Tectonic Regimes (2013); https://peer.berkeley.edu/research/nga-west-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai B., Wei H., Yang X., Gan T., Mengu D., Jarrahi M., Ozcan A., Data-class-specific all-optical transformations and encryption. Adv. Mater. 35, 2212091 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37186024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Hou Y., Lin J., A review on the processing accuracy of two-photon polymerization. AIP Adv. 5, 030701 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen C.-Y., Batoni P., Yang X., Li J., Liao K., Stack J., Gardner J., Welch K., Ozcan A., Broadband unidirectional visible imaging using wafer-scale nano-fabrication of multi-layer diffractive optical processors. Light Sci Appl. 14, 267 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12340160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40789836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushima K., Shifted angular spectrum method for off-axis numerical propagation. Opt. Express 18, 18453&#x2013;18463 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20721240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin X., Rivenson Y., Yardimci N. T., Veli M., Luo Y., Jarrahi M., Ozcan A., All-optical machine learning using diffractive deep neural networks. Science 361, 1004&#x2013;1008 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30049787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma G., Yang X., Bai B., Li J., Li Y., Gan T., Shen C.-Y., Zhang Y., Li Y., I&#x15f;&#x131;l &#xc7;., Jarrahi M., Ozcan A., Multiplexed all-optical permutation operations using a reconfigurable diffractive optical network. Laser Photonics Rev. 18, 2400238 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai B., Lee R., Li Y., Gan T., Wang Y., Jarrahi M., Ozcan A., Information-hiding cameras: Optical concealment of object information into ordinary images. Sci. Adv. 10, eadn9420 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11168462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38865455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Li Y., Gan T., Liao K., Jarrahi M., Ozcan A., Optimizing structured surfaces for diffractive waveguides. Nat. Commun. 16, 5256 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12144198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40481002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen C.-Y., Li J., Gan T., Li Y., Jarrahi M., Ozcan A., All-optical phase conjugation using diffractive wavefront processing. Nat. Commun. 15, 4989 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11166986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38862510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Ronneberger, P. Fischer, T. Brox, U-Net: Convolutional networks for biomedical image segmentation. arXiv:1505.04597 [cs.CV] (2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>