<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41479264</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1447-0349</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of mental health nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Ment Health Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recovery-Oriented Practice in Public Mental Health Services: A Systematic Scoping Review of Multidisciplinary Clinicians' Views on Its Implementation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70188</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70188</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/inm.70188</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This scoping review examined the views of multidisciplinary clinicians on the implementation of recovery-oriented practice (ROP) in public mental health services. ROP is mandated in Victoria, Australia, and is being increasingly utilised worldwide. Multidisciplinary clinicians' views are of utmost importance as they are at the forefront of service delivery. Arksey and O'Malley's (2005) framework guided the systematic scoping review using five electronic databases: CINHL, EMBASE OVID, MEDLINE OVID, PSYCHINFO and WEB OF SCIENCE. A total of 30 studies were included. Data were summarised and thematically analysed. Nine were mixed methods, 18 were qualitative, and three were quantitative studies. Similarities and differences arose, and themes were drawn out. There were 10 themes regarding implementation approaches, barriers, and enablers that emerged in examining multidisciplinary clinicians' perspectives. Major findings included the need for organisational commitment to ROP and the importance of targeted training for clinicians-particularly those with longer service-to update knowledge, challenge biomedical assumptions, and strengthen shared decision-making and positive risk-taking. Successful implementation of ROP empowered service users and promoted professional equality for lived experience workers while highlighting persistent power imbalances between multidisciplinary clinicians and service users. Definitions of ROP are varied and can be confusing. Service users are most positively affected by successful implementation of ROP through empowerment and equal treatment. Lived experience workers gain professional equality. Clinicians have long held professional power relative to service users. Mental health services could, prioritise translating research into practice through ongoing professional development and cultural competency training. This review differentiates from the authors' previous studies by demonstrating an evolution in clinicians' attitudes towards ROP since prior data were collected.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chisholm</LastName><ForeName>Janice</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7201-6090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Access Team, Mental Health and Wellbeing Program, Eastern Health, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hope</LastName><ForeName>Judy</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eastern Health Clinical School, Faculty of Medicine, Nursing and Health Sciences, Monash, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health and Wellbeing Program, Eastern Health, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Education and Research, Delmont Private Hospital, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fossey</LastName><ForeName>Ellie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Therapy, School of Primary and Allied Health Care, Faculty of Medicine, Nursing and Health Sciences, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petrakis</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Work, Faculty of Medicine, Nursing and Health Sciences, Monash University, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St Vincent's Hospital (Melbourne), Mental Health Service, Fitzroy, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Ment Health Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101140527</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1445-8330</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008605" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Health Services</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="N">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001291" MajorTopicYN="Y">Attitude of Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">literature review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multidisciplinary clinicians</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery&#x2010;oriented practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">service users</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41479264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/inm.70188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Adeponle, A., R. Whitley, and L. J. Kirmayer. 2012. &#x201c;Cultural Contexts and Constructions of Recovery.&#x201d; In Recovery of People With Mental Illness: Philosophical and Related Perspectives, edited by A. Rudnick, 109&#x2013;132. Oxford University Press. https://doi.org/10.1093/med/9780199691319.003.0008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony, W. A. 1993. &#x201c;Recovery From Mental Illness: The Guiding Vision of the Mental Health Service System in the 1990s.&#x201d; Psychosocial Rehabilitation Journal 16, no. 4: 11&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1037/h0095655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anttila, M., T. Lantta, K. Hipp, and M. V&#xe4;lim&#xe4;ki. 2023. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Mental Health Principles in Psychiatric Hospitals: How Service Users, Family Members and Staff Perceive the Realization of Practices.&#x201d; Journal of Advanced Nursing 79, no. 7: 2732&#x2013;2743. https://doi.org/10.1111/jan.15506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey, H., and L. O'Malley. 2005. &#x201c;Scoping Studies: Towards a Methodological Framework.&#x201d; International Journal of Social Research Methodology 8, no. 1: 19&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.1080/1364557032000119616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aston, V., and M. Coffey. 2012. &#x201c;Recovery: What Mental Health Nurses and Service Users Say About the Concept of Recovery.&#x201d; Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing 19, no. 3: 257&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Health Ministers' Advisory Council. 2013. A National Framework for Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Mental Health Services: Guide for Practitioners and Providers. Department of Health and Ageing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass, H., A. Tickle, and N. Lewis. 2014. &#x201c;The Recovery&#x2010;Orientation of Three Mental Health Units.&#x201d; Mental Health Review Journal 19, no. 3: 163&#x2013;175. https://doi.org/10.1108/MHRJ&#x2010;11&#x2010;2013&#x2010;0036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben&#x2010;Dor, I. A., E. Kraus, Y. Goldfarb, A. Grayzman, B. Puschner, and G. S. Moran. 2024. &#x201c;Perspectives and Experiences of Stakeholders on Self&#x2010;Disclosure of Peers in Mental Health Services.&#x201d; Community Mental Health Journal 60, no. 7: 1308&#x2013;1321. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10597&#x2010;024&#x2010;01287&#x2010;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biran&#x2010;Ovadia, A., R. D. Strous, O. Bart, and L. Lipskaya&#x2010;Velikovsky. 2023. &#x201c;Study of Recovery Model Implementation in Psychiatric Hospitals: Clients and Multidisciplinary Staff Perspective.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 32, no. 2: 603&#x2013;614. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.13106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland, R., and M. Wyder. 2017. &#x201c;Working with People Who Have Psychotic Illness: Balancing Risk and Recovery.&#x201d; Beyond the risk paradigm in mental health policy and practice 86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramer, W. M., D. Giustini, G. B. de Jonge, L. Holland, and T. Bekhuis. 2017. &#x201c;De&#x2010;Duplication of Database Search Results for Systematic Reviews in EndNote.&#x201d; Journal of the Medical Library Association 105, no. 1: 84&#x2013;87. https://doi.org/10.5195/jmla.2017.11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabot, W., and B. Cronin. 2013. &#x201c;&#x2018;Recovery&#x2019;&#x2014;the Journey Within Three Rural Communities in New South Wales.&#x201d; Paper Presented at the 12th National Rural Health Conference, NSW. http://www.ruralhealth.org.au/12nrhc/wp&#x2010;content/uploads/2013/06/Cabot&#x2010;Wendy_Cronin&#x2010;Beth_ppr.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm, J., J. Hope, E. Fossey, and M. Petrakis. 2023. &#x201c;Mental Health Clinician Attitudes al Service User and Family Agency and Involvement in Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice.&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 20, no. 18: 6787. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph20186787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm, J., and M. Petrakis. 2020. &#x201c;Peer Worker Perspectives on Their Potential Role in the Success of Implementing Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice in a Clinical Mental Health Setting.&#x201d; Journal of Evidence&#x2010;Based Social Work 17, no. 3: 300&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm, J., and M. Petrakis. 2021. &#x201c;Clinician Perspectives and Sense of Efficacy About the Implementation of Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice in Mental Health.&#x201d; British Journal of Social Work 52: 1380&#x2013;1397. https://doi.org/10.1093/bjsw/bcab125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm, J., and M. Petrakis. 2022. &#x201c;Peer Worker Perspectives on Barriers and Facilitators: Implementation of Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice in a Public Mental Health Service.&#x201d; Journal of Evidence&#x2010;Based Social Work 20, no. 1: 84&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1080/26408066.2022.2118006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary, A., and M. Dowling. 2009. &#x201c;Knowledge and Attitudes of Mental Health Professionals in Ireland to the Concept of Recovery in Mental Health: A Questionnaire Survey.&#x201d; Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing 16, no. 6: 539&#x2013;545. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2850.2009.01411.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleary, M., J. Horsfall, M. O'Hara&#x2010;Aarons, and G. E. Hunt. 2013. &#x201c;Mental Health Nurses' Views of Recovery Within an Acute Setting.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 22, no. 3: 205&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cusack, E., F. Killoury, and L. E. Nugent. 2017. &#x201c;The Professional Psychiatric/Mental Health Nurse: Skills, Competencies and Supports Required to Adopt Recovery&#x2010;Orientated Policy in Practice.&#x201d; Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing 24, no. 2&#x2013;3: 93&#x2013;104. https://doi.org/10.1111/jpm.12347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wet, A., and C. Pretorius. 2021. &#x201c;Perceptions and Understanding of Mental Health Recovery for Service Users, Carers, and Service Providers: A South African Perspective.&#x201d; Psychiatric Rehabilitation Journal 44, no. 2: 157&#x2013;165. https://doi.org/10.1037/prj0000460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deegan, P. 1996. &#x201c;Recovery as A Journey of the Heart.&#x201d; Psychiatric Rehabilitation Journal 19, no. 3: 91&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1037/h0101301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health. 2021. &#x201c;State of Victoria, Royal Commission Into Victoria's Mental Health System Victoria&#x201d;.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faccio, E., M. Rocelli, L. Bitetti, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;One or Many Recoveries? Recoveries in the Plural for a Better Understanding of One's Healing Journey.&#x201d; Health Expectations 28, no. 2: e70209. https://doi.org/10.1111/hex.70209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felton, A., J. Repper, and M. Avis. 2018. &#x201c;Therapeutic Relationships, Risk, and Mental Health Practice.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 27, no. 3: 1137&#x2013;1148. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.12430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaffey, K., D. S. Evans, and F. Walsh. 2016. &#x201c;Knowledge and Attitudes of Irish Mental Health Professionals to the Concept of Recovery from Mental Illness&#x2013;Five Years Later.&#x201d; Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing 23, no. 6&#x2013;7: 387&#x2013;398. https://doi.org/10.1111/jpm.12325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddaway, N. R., A. M. Collins, D. Coughlin, and S. Kirk. 2015. &#x201c;The Role of Google Scholar in Evidence Reviews and Its Applicability to Grey Literature Searching.&#x201d; PLoS One 10, no. 9: e0138237. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0138237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Happell, B., and B. Scholz. 2018. &#x201c;Doing What We Can, but Knowing Our Place: Being an Ally to Promote Consumer Leadership in Mental Health.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 27, no. 1: 440&#x2013;447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardy, J., S. Parker, I. Hughes, and M. Anand. 2022. &#x201c;Factors Affecting Knowledge of Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice Amongst Mental Health Nursing and Staff Working on Acute Mental Health Inpatient Units.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 31, no. 5: 1228&#x2013;1238. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.13032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson, C. D., J. M. Noblett, H. M. Parke, et&#xa0;al. 2014. &#x201c;Mental Health&#x2010;Related Stigma in Health Care and Mental Health&#x2010;Care Settings.&#x201d; Lancet Psychiatry 1, no. 6: 467&#x2013;482. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215&#x2010;0366(14)00023&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornik&#x2010;Lurie, T., A. Shalev, L. Haknazar, et&#xa0;al. 2018. &#x201c;Implementing Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Interventions with Staff in a Psychiatric Hospital: A Mixed&#x2010;Methods Study.&#x201d; Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing 25, no. 9&#x2013;10: 569&#x2013;581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsfall, J., M. Cleary, and G. E. Hunt. 2010. &#x201c;Stigma in Mental Health: Clients and Professionals.&#x201d; Issues in Mental Health Nursing 31, no. 7: 450&#x2013;455. https://doi.org/10.3109/01612840903537167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob, S., I. Munro, and B. J. Taylor. 2015. &#x201c;Mental Health Recovery: Lived Experience of Consumers, Carers and Nurses.&#x201d; Contemporary Nurse 50, no. 1: 1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1080/10376178.2015.1012040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen, K., M. S. Hansen, T. Groth, M. Hansen, and B. Karlsson. 2023. &#x201c;Perspectives on Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Care in Mental Health Practices: Health Professionals Experiences.&#x201d; Issues in Mental Health Nursing 44, no. 3: 200&#x2013;208. https://doi.org/10.1080/01612840.2023.2186716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen, K., T. Rasmussen, M. Hansen, K. Andreasson, and B. Karlsson. 2020. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Intersectoral Care in Mental Health: As Perceived by Healthcare Professionals and Users.&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 17, no. 23: 8777. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17238777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen, K., B. Lerb&#xe6;k, J. Frederiksen, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Healthcare Professionals&#x2019; Experience with the Implementation of a Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Approach across in&#x2010;Patient Units and Assertive Community Treatment.&#x201d; Issues in Mental Health Nursing 46, no. 2: 197&#x2013;205. https://doi.org/10.1080/01612840.2025.2456180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpetis, G. 2020. &#x201c;How Experienced Social Workers Apply Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Mental Health Policies in Everyday Practice.&#x201d; European Journal of Social Work 23, no. 1: 106&#x2013;117. https://doi.org/10.1080/13691457.2018.1474855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kronkvist, M. B., K.&#x2010;A. Forsberg, M. R&#xe4;mg&#xe5;rd, M. Sandlund, T. Janarv, and P. Dahlqvist J&#xf6;nsson. 2022. &#x201c;User Participation in Decision&#x2010;Making &#x2013; A Qualitative Intervention Study on Mental Health Professionals' Experiences.&#x201d; Journal of Public Mental Health 21, no. 3: 250&#x2013;261. https://doi.org/10.1108/JPMH&#x2010;11&#x2010;2021&#x2010;0140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Boutillier, C., A. Chevalier, V. Lawrence, et&#xa0;al. 2015. &#x201c;Staff Understanding of Recovery&#x2010;Orientated Mental Health Practice: A Systematic Review and Narrative Synthesis.&#x201d; Implementation Science 10: 87. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13012&#x2010;015&#x2010;0275&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorien, L. M., M. Arthur, K. Keiler, J. Lowry, and K. Ryan. 2024. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice in a Hospital Mental Health Service.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 33, no. 4: 1100&#x2013;1109. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.13316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matoba, K., M. Buyo, R. Odachi, T. Kajiwara, and Y. Endo. 2023. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Daily Care Practice for Community&#x2010;Based Mental Health Service Consumers in Japan: A Grounded Theory Approach.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 32, no. 3: 854&#x2013;865. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.13128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna, B., T. Furness, D. Dhital, et&#xa0;al. 2014. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Care in Acute Inpatient Mental Health Settings: An Exploratory Study.&#x201d; Issues in Mental Health Nursing 35, no. 7: 526&#x2013;532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna, B., T. Furness, D. Dhital, and S. Ireland. 2014. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Care in Older&#x2010;Adult Acute Inpatient Mental Health Settings in Australia: An Exploratory Study.&#x201d; Journal of the American Geriatrics Society 62, no. 10: 1938&#x2013;1942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna, B., J. Oakes, N. Fourniotis, N. Toomey, and T. Furness. 2016. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Mental Health Practice in a Community Care Unit: An Exploratory Study.&#x201d; Journal of Forensic Nursing 12, no. 4: 167&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher, D., A. Liberati, J. Tetzlaff, and D. G. Altman. 2009. &#x201c;Reprint&#x2014;Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta&#x2010;Analyses: The PRISMA Statement.&#x201d; Physical Therapy 89, no. 9: 873&#x2013;880. https://doi.org/10.1093/ptj/89.9.873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugent, A., N. Hancock, and A. Honey. 2017. &#x201c;Developing and Sustaining Recovery&#x2010;Orientation in Mental Health Practice: Experiences of Occupational Therapists.&#x201d; Occupational Therapy International 2017: 5190901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omundo, J., S. A. Stiehl, M. Schulz, and A. Zingsheim. 2025. &#x201c;CHIME In Practice: A Qualitative Exploration of CHIME Framework Training Experiences and Outcomes for Service Users and Mental Health Professionals.&#x201d; Journal of Mental Health Training 20, no. 3. https://doi.org/10.1108/JMHTEP&#x2010;05&#x2010;2024&#x2010;0052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, S., F. Dark, E. Newman, N. Korman, Z. Rasmussen, and C. Meurk. 2017. &#x201c;Reality of Working in a Community&#x2010;Based, Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Mental Health Rehabilitation Unit: A Pragmatic Grounded Theory Analysis.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 26, no. 4: 355&#x2013;365. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.12251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petros, R., and P. L. Solomon. 2020. &#x201c;Social Workers' Propensity to Endorse Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Service Provision: A Randomised Factorial Design.&#x201d; British Journal of Social Work 50, no. 1: 42&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polat, S., and S. Duran. 2025. &#x201c;&#x201c;Believing Facilitates Success&#x201d;: Psychiatric Nurses' Perspectives on Recovery.&#x201d; BMC Nursing 24: 153. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12912&#x2010;025&#x2010;02785&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennick&#x2010;Egglestone, S., A. Ramsay, R. McGranahan, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;The Impact of Mental Health Recovery Narratives on Recipients Experiencing Mental Health Problems: Qualitative Analysis and Change Model.&#x201d; PLoS One 14, no. 12: e0226201&#x2010;e0226201. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0226201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth, C., M. Wensing, M. R. Kuzman, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practices and Role Perceptions of Healthcare Staff Providing Community&#x2010;Based Mental Healthcare as Team in Central and Eastern Europe: An Observational Study.&#x201d; https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs&#x2010;215308/v1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salberg, J., L. Ekselius, T. Hursti, and C. &#xd6;ster. 2022. &#x201c;Staff Experiences Related to Implementation of a Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Nursing Programme in Psychiatric Inpatient Care.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 31, no. 3: 731&#x2013;742. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.12995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade, M., N. Adams, and M. O'Hagan. 2012. &#x201c;Recovery: Past Progress and Future Challenges.&#x201d; International Review of Psychiatry 24, no. 1: 1&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.3109/09540261.2011.644847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon, B., D. Sutton, and B. McKenna. 2021. &#x201c;The Experience and Meaning of Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice for Nurses Working Acute Mental Health Services.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 30, no. 4: 963&#x2013;974. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.12851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreeram, A., W. M. Cross, and L. Townsin. 2023. &#x201c;Mental Health Nurses' Attitudes Towards Mental Illness and Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Practice in Acute Inpatient Psychiatric Units: A Non&#x2010;Participant Observation Study.&#x201d; International Journal of Mental Health Nursing 32, no. 4: 1112&#x2013;1128. https://doi.org/10.1111/inm.13152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stacey, G., A. Felton, A. Morgan, et&#xa0;al. 2016. &#x201c;A Critical Narrative Analysis of Shared Decision&#x2010;Making in Acute Inpatient Mental Health Care.&#x201d; Journal of Interprofessional Care 30, no. 1: 35&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.3109/13561820.2015.1064878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>State of Victoria. 2021. &#x201c;Royal Commission into Victoria's Mental Health System, Final Report, Volume 1: A new approach to mental health and wellbeing in Victoria.&#x201d; Par l Paper No. 202, Session 2018&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuber, J., A. Rocha, A. Christian, and D. Johnson. 2014. &#x201c;Predictors of Recovery&#x2010;Oriented Competencies Among Mental Health Professionals in One Community Mental Health System.&#x201d; Community Mental Health Journal 50, no. 8: 909&#x2013;914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorkildsen, E., B. John, and G. Roderique&#x2010;Davies. 2023. &#x201c;Mental Health Support Workers Recovery Perceptions and Positive Risk&#x2010;Taking Approaches Related to Service&#x2010;Users With a Dual Diagnosis.&#x201d; Alcoholism Treatment Quarterly 41, no. 4: 408&#x2013;431. https://doi.org/10.1080/07347324.2023.2234307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornicroft, G., and M. Tansella. 2014. &#x201c;Community Mental Health Care in the Future: Nine Proposals.&#x201d; Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease 202, no. 6: 507&#x2013;512. https://doi.org/10.1097/NMD.0000000000000151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh, F. P., P. Meskell, E. Burke, and M. Dowling. 2017. &#x201c;Recovery&#x2010;Based Training in Mental Health: Effects on Staff Knowledge and Attitudes to Recovery.&#x201d; Issues in Mental Health Nursing 38, no. 11: 886&#x2013;895. https://doi.org/10.1080/01612840.2017.1346014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>