<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41815530</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2639-5274</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research (Washington, D.C.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Research (Wash D C)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Textile Radio-Frequency Active Devices and Systems: Wireless Communication and Energy Harvesting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1101</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1101</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1101</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.34133/research.1101</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The integration of wearable technology and smart textiles has substantially advanced the development of radio-frequency (RF) electronics embedded in textile substrates, opening new opportunities across health monitoring, environmental sensing, and wireless communication. Despite their established performance, conventional rigid RF systems face inherent limitations in conformability and seamless integration within wearable platforms. This review comprehensively summarizes recent progress in textile-based RF active devices, encompassing reconfigurable antennas, tunable metasurfaces, and multifunctional RF systems. We emphasize the transition from isolated components to fully integrated, intelligent platforms capable of energy harvesting, low-power communication, and distributed sensing while proposing solution strategies and future development directions for enriched and systematic performance. Critical technical challenges such as high-precision fabrication, tunable RF response, and architecture design for complex systems are thoroughly discussed. Ultimately, this review outlines promising pathways toward autonomous, adaptive, and intelligently networked textile RF systems, highlighting the convergence of wireless functionality and system-level co-design for the next generation of wearable electronics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wenzhe Song et&#xa0;al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Wenzhe</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-3411-7539</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Millimeter Waves, School of Information Science and Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Millimeter Waves, School of Information Science and Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kou</LastName><ForeName>Zhenghao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Millimeter Waves, School of Information Science and Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zehui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Millimeter Waves, School of Information Science and Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jianing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Millimeter Waves, School of Information Science and Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Tian</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Millimeter Waves, School of Information Science and Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Xingce</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2508-3063</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Quantum Materials and Devices of the Ministry of Education, School of Physics, Southeast University, Nanjing 211189, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Weibing</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6337-1739</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Millimeter Waves, School of Information Science and Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Flexible RF Technology, Frontiers Science Center for Mobile Information Communication and Security, Southeast University, Nanjing 210096, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Research (Wash D C)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101747148</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2639-5274</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41815530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12972507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/research.1101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cima MJ. Next-generation wearable electronics. Nat Biotechnol. 2014;32(7):642&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25004232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Suh JM, Shin J, Liu Y, Yeon H, Qiao K, Kum HS, Kim C, Lee HE, Choi C, et al. Chip-less wireless electronic skins by remote epitaxial freestanding compound semiconductors. Science. 2022;377(6608):859&#x2013;864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35981034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ates HC, Nguyen PQ, Gonzalez-Macia L, Morales-Narv&#xe1;ez E, G&#xfc;der F, Collins JJ, Dincer C. End-to-end design of wearable sensors. Nat Rev Mater. 2022;7(11):887&#x2013;907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9306444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35910814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu H, Huang H, Li M, Gao X, Yin L, Qi R, Wu RS, Chen X, Ma Y, Shi K, et al. A wearable cardiac ultrasound imager. Nature. 2023;613(7945):667&#x2013;675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9876798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36697864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H. Wearable electronics. Natl Sci Rev. 2023;10(1): Article nwac193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9843123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36684518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Fu X, He J, Shi X, Chen T, Chen P, Wang B, Peng H. Application challenges in fiber and textile electronics. Adv Mater. 2020;32(5):1901971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31273843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhry NA, Arnold L, Rasheed A, Khan IA, Wang L. Textronics&#x2014;A review of textile-based wearable electronics. Adv Eng Mater. 2021;23(12):2100469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Z, Ye K, Luo H, Tang J, Yang G, Xie H, Yang H, Xu K. Textile hybrid electronics for multifunctional wearable integrated systems. Research. 2025;8:0779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12287603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40709102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta N, Cheung H, Payra S, Loke G, Li J, Zhao Y, Balachander L, Son E, Li V, Kravitz S, et al. A single-fibre computer enables textile networks and distributed inference. Nature. 2025;639:79&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40011780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Lu WB, Geng MY, Yu BY, Zhang C, Bo XZ, Li MZ, Kou ZH, Zhan JL, Liu ZG. Fabric-based smart metasurface. Adv Mater Technol. 2023;8(23):2301111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong K, Deng J, Ding W, Wang AC, Wang P, Cheng C, Wang YC, Jin L, Gu B, Sun B, et al. Versatile core&#x2013;sheath yarn for sustainable biomechanical energy harvesting and real-time human-interactive sensing. Adv Energy Mater. 2018;8(23):1801114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Zhou D, Liu Z, Hong X, Li C, Ge S, Cao W. Skin-inspired textile electronics enable ultrasensitive pressure sensing. Small. 2024;20(33):2310032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38566533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libanori A, Chen G, Zhao X, Zhou Y, Chen J. Smart textiles for personalized healthcare. Nat Electron. 2022;5(3):142&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang Q, Yao K, Zhang C, Song X, Zhou J, Zhang Y, Huang Q, Zhou Y, Yu X, Zheng Z. Permeable, three-dimensional integrated electronic skins with stretchable hybrid liquid metal solders. Nat Electron. 2024;7(7):598&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin R, Kim HJ, Achavananthadith S, Kurt SA, Tan SC, Yao H, Tee BC, Lee JK, Ho JS. Wireless battery-free body sensor networks using near-field-enabled clothing. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6978350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31974376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin R, Kim HJ, Achavananthadith S, Xiong Z, Lee JK, Kong YL, Ho JS. Digitally-embroidered liquid metal electronic textiles for wearable wireless systems. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):2190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9023486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35449159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Ma X, Lin Z, Chen F, Chen Z, Hu H, Xu H, Zhang X, Shi Y, Huang Q, et al. Well-defined in-textile photolithography towards permeable textile electronics. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10828459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38291087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Zhan JL, Xia H, Li JN, Chen ZH, Geng MY, Qu HT, Lv XY, Zhang C, Ju L, et al. Fabric-based stretchable and breathable backscattered monitoring system. Adv Energy Mater. 2025;15(14):2404589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter MJ, Resneck L, Ra&#x2019;di Y, Yu N. Flexible, textile metasurfaces. Adv Mater. 2024;36(32):2312087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38419481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SJ, Ranasinghe DC, Fumeaux C. A robust snap-on button solution for reconfigurable wearable textile antennas. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2018;66(9):4541&#x2013;4551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang QH, Chen SJ, Ranasinghe DC, Fumeaux C. A frequency-reconfigurable wearable textile antenna with one-octave tuning range. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2021;69(12):8080&#x2013;8089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X, Zeng Q, Nikolayev D, Ho JS. Conformal propagation and near-omnidirectional radiation with surface plasmonic clothing. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2020;68(11):7309&#x2013;7319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simorangkir RBVB, Yang Y, Esselle KP, Zeb BA. A method to realize robust flexible electronically tunable antennas using polymer-embedded conductive fabric. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2018;66(1):50&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Peng XL, Bo XZ, Geng MY, Yang XL, Zhan JL, Liu ZG, Dai YQ, Lu WB. All-fabric flexible frequency-selective-rasorber based on cutting-transfer patterning method. Adv Mater Interfaces. 2022;9(23):2200651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng MY, Chen H, Zhan JL, Zhang C, Ju L, Chen ZH, Kou ZH, Sun TS, Liu T, Liu ZG, et al. Fabric electromagnetic energy harvesting platform based on absorbing metasurface. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2025;70(9):7021&#x2013;7026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedighi P, Norouzi MH, Delrobaei M. An RFID-based assistive glove to help the visually impaired. IEEE Trans Instrum Meas. 2021;70:4004109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Ma Z, Yang C, Kui X, Liu X, Wang W, Wang J, Guo S. Real-time and accurate gesture recognition with commercial RFID devices. IEEE Trans Mob Comput. 2023;22(12):7327&#x2013;7342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng S, Wang X, Li W, Liu Z, Li Q, Yan F. Pressure-stamped stretchable electronics using a nanofibre membrane containing semi-embedded liquid metal particles. Nat Electron. 2024;7(7):576&#x2013;585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng K, Zhao S, Zhou Y, Wu Y, Zhang S, He Q, Wang X, Zhou Z, Fan W, Tan X, et al. A wireless textile-based sensor system for self-powered personalized health care. Matter. 2020;2(4):896&#x2013;907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X, Lee PM, Tan YJ, Wu TL, Yao H, Zhang M, Li Z, Ng KA, Tee BC, Ho JS. Wireless body sensor networks based on metamaterial textiles. Nat Electron. 2019;2(6):243&#x2013;251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou Z, Zhang C, Yu B, Chen H, Liu Z, Lu W. Wearable all-fabric hybrid energy harvester to simultaneously harvest radiofrequency and triboelectric energy. Adv Sci. 2024;11(17):2309050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11077651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38380554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vital D, Bhardwaj S, Volakis JL. Textile-based large area RF-power harvesting system for wearable applications. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2020;68(3):2323&#x2013;2331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotzler S, Krshiwoblozki M, Kallmayer C, Schneider-Ramelow M. Washability of E-textiles: Washing behavior of textile integrated circuits depending on textile substrate, circuit material and integration method. Adv Funct Mater. 2025;35(11):2417344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W, Yu BY, Ju L, Li G, Tang X, Xu K, Li MZ, Kou Z, Feng H, Zhao X, et al. Interwoven MXene sediment architecture empowers high-performance flexible microwave devices. Small. 2025;21(36):2503857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40341782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C, Wu J, Yan J, Liu X. Advanced fiber materials for wearable electronics. Adv Fiber Mater. 2023;5(1):12&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian Y, Shi H, Yuan Q, Zhu Y, Lin Z, Zhuang L, Han X, Wang P, Chen M, Wang X. Patterning techniques based on metallized electrospun nanofibers for advanced stretchable electronics. Adv Sci. 2024;11(26):2309735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11234419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38687841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai L, Lin W, Ai L, Li Y, Qiang M, Wang X, Shi M, Yang Z, Yao X. &#x201c;Heat-press-N-go&#x201d; stretchable interconnects enabled by liquid metal conductor with supramolecular confinement. Adv Funct Mater. 2025;35(20):2425264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun MJ, Sim YH, Lee DY, Cha SI. Highly stretchable large area woven, knitted and robust braided textile based interconnection for stretchable electronics. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):4038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7890051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33597572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simegnaw AA, Malengier B, Rotich G, Tadesse MG, Van Langenhove L. Review on the integration of microelectronics for E-textile. Materials. 2021;14(17):5113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8434590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Zhang C, Wang F, Yu J, Yang G, Surmenev RA, Li Z, Ding B. Smart textiles for personalized sports and healthcare. Nano Micro Lett. 2025;17(1):232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12031719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40278986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, Wang HQ, Ju L, Hou KX, Xiao ZD, Zhan JL, Zhang C, Chen H, Wang B, Liu ZG, et al. A bio-inspired microwave wireless system for constituting passive and maintenance-free IoT networks. Natl Sci Rev. 2025;12(2): Article nwae435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11737395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39830403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan JL, Lu WB, Ding C, Sun Z, Yu BY, Ju L, Liang XH, Chen ZM, Chen H, Jia YH, et al. Flexible and wearable battery-free backscatter wireless communication system for colour imaging. NPJ Flexible Electron. 2024;8(1): Article 19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu BY, Wang ZH, Ju L, Zhang C, Liu ZG, Tao L, Lu WB. Flexible and wearable hybrid RF and solar energy harvesting system. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2021;70(3):2223&#x2013;2233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Chen K, Dong S, Jiang T, Zhao J, Feng Y. Tunable topological polaritons by dispersion tailoring of an active metasurface. Adv Photonics. 2024;6(4): Article 046005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong W, Deng Y, Zhao J, Jiang T, Xu HX, Chen K, Feng Y. Broadband reconfigurable amplifying metasurface for real-time wavefront control. IEEE Trans Microw Theor Tech. 2025;73(10):8032&#x2013;8042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu K, Chen K, Hu Q, Zhao J, Jiang T, Feng Y. Deep-learning-assisted inverse design of dual-spin/frequency metasurface for quad-channel off-axis vortices multiplexing. Adv Photonics Nexus. 2023;2(1): Article 016010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu K, Chen K, Feng Y. Inverse design of metasurface polarization convertor with controllable bandwidth. In: <i>2021 IEEE International Symposium on Antennas and Propagation and USNC-URSI Radio Science Meeting (APS/URSI)</i>. Piscataway (NJ): IEEE; 2021. p. 863&#x2013;864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MR, Afroj S, Yin J, Novoselov KS, Chen J, Karim N. Advances in printed electronic textiles. Adv Sci. 2024;11(6):2304140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10853734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38009793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Zhang Y, Ruan K, Guo H, He M, Qiu H, Gu J. MXene-based fibers: Preparation, applications, and prospects. Sci Bull. 2024;69(17):2776&#x2013;2792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39098564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Chang D, Gao C. A review of multifunctional nanocomposite fibers: Design, preparation and applications. Adv Fiber Mater. 2024;6(1):68&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Jiang J, Wu Y, Zhang Y, Zhou J, Zhang Y, Huang Q, Zheng Z. Porous conductive textiles for wearable electronics. Chem Rev. 2024;124(4):1535&#x2013;1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38373392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brasier N, Frobert O, De Leso F, Meyer D, Kowatsch T, Ghaffari R. The potential of wearable sweat sensors in heart failure management. Nat Electron. 2024;7:182&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tat T, Chen G, Zhao X, Zhou Y, Xu J, Chen J. Smart textiles for healthcare and sustainability. ACS Nano. 2022;16(9):13301&#x2013;13313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35969207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z, Xu J, Zhou X, Wang Z, Liu Y, Wang S, Yuan S, Zhang H, He B, Xin J, et al. Advances in fiber-based wearable sensors with machine learning. Adv Devices Instrum. 2024;5:0054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng W, Shu L, Li Q, Chen S, Wang F, Tao XM. Fiber-based wearable electronics: A review of materials, fabrication, devices, and applications. Adv Mater. 2014;26(31):5310&#x2013;5336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24943999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Wu J, Wang Y, Zhang L, Ran F. Perspective in textile energy storage integrated textile elements: Textile materials, structure, and manufactured methods. Adv Energy Mater. 2024;14(9):2303587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Shi X, Jiang H, Zeng K, Zhou Z, Zhai P, Zhang L, Peng H. Design and fabrication of wearable electronic textiles using twisted fiber-based threads. Nat Protoc. 2024;19(5):1557&#x2013;1589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38429518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Z, Zhang Q. Chipless textile electronics enable wireless digital interactions. Innovation. 2024;5(5): Article 100676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11338183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39170943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Tian X, Qiu C-W, Ho JS. Metasurfaces for bioelectronics and healthcare. Nat Electron. 2021;4:382&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Wang Z, Volakis JL. Textile antennas and sensors for body-worn applications. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag Lett. 2012;11:1690&#x2013;1693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J, Liu S, Zhang L, Yang B, Shu L, Yang Y, Ren M, Wang Y, Chen J, Chen W, et al. Smart textile-integrated microelectronic systems for wearable applications. Adv Mater. 2020;32(5):1901958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31273850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z-M, Zhan JL, Chen H, Li Y, He H, Yang W, Liu ZG, Lu WB. Robust textile-based spoof plasmonic frequency scanning antenna for on-body IoT applications. Sci China Inf Sci. 2024;67: Article 182304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z-H, Chen H, Qu HT, By Y, Sun TS, Sun LY. A strain-insensitive stretchable and flexible wideband Vivaldi endfire filtenna. IEEE Trans Microw Theory Tech. 2025;73(9):5941&#x2013;5952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TK, Bui CD, Narbudowicz A, Nguyen-Trong N. Frequency-reconfigurable antenna with wide- and narrowband modes for sub-6 GHz cognitive radio. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag Lett. 2023;22(1):64&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Omari M, Attia H, Qureshi KK, Sheikh SIM. Design of frequency-reconfigurable antenna on dielectric and magnetic metamaterial composite substrate. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag. Lett. 2023;22(4):943&#x2013;947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z-M, Liang X, Li JN, Chen ZH, Yang W, Lu WB. On-body antenna with ultrawide operation band and dynamically broad notch band for IoT applications. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12(12):21144&#x2013;21157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Wei K, Li Y, Zhang Z. A polarization reconfigurable antenna for satellite communication in foldable smartphone. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2023;71(12):9938&#x2013;9943.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Zhang Z, Tang M-C, Zhu L, Liu N-W. Bandwidth enhancement and size reduction of a low-profile polarization-reconfigurable antenna by utilizing multiple resonances. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2022;70(2):1517&#x2013;1522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W, Wong H. Wideband circular polarization reconfigurable antenna. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2015;63(12):5938&#x2013;5944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S, Zhang Y, Han Z, Chiu C-Y, Murch R. A pattern-reconfigurable antenna for single-RF 5G millimeter-wave communications. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag Lett. 2021;20(12):2344&#x2013;2348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao CX, Zhang L, Khalily M, Xiao P. Single-pole double-throw filtering switch and its application in pattern reconfigurable antenna. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2022;70(2):1581&#x2013;1586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokolia M, Lacik J, Raida Z. Combined energy harvester integrated into car. In: <i>Loughborough Antennas &amp; Propagation Conference (LAPC 2017)</i>. Stevenage (UK): IET; 2018. p. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider J, Mrnka M, Gamec J, Gamcova M, Raida Z. Vivaldi antenna for RF energy harvesting. Radioengineering. 2016;25(4):666&#x2013;671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrnka M, Vasina P, Kufa M, Hebelka V, Raida Z. The RF energy harvesting antennas operating in commercially deployed frequency bands: A comparative study. Int J Antennas Propag. 2016;2016(1):7379624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebelka V, Velim J, Raida Z. Dual band Koch antenna for RF energy harvesting. In: <i>2016 10th European Conference on Antennas and Propagation (EuCAP)</i>. Piscataway (NJ): IEEE; 2016. p. 1&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrnka M, Raida Z, Grosinger J. Wide-band dielectric resonator antennas for RF energy harvesting. In: <i>2015 Conference on Microwave Techniques (COMITE)</i>. Piscataway (NJ): IEEE; 2015. p. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musa U, Shah SM, Majid HA, Abidin ZZ, Yahya MS, Babani S. Recent advancement of wearable reconfigurable antenna technologies: A review. IEEE Access. 2022;10:121831&#x2013;121863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir FA, Javed A. A compact dual-band frequency-reconfigurable textile antenna for wearable applications. Microw Opt Technol Lett. 2015;57(10):2251&#x2013;2257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamadzade B, Simorangkir RBVB, Hashmi RM, Gharaei R, Lalbakhsh A, Shrestha S. A conformal, dynamic pattern-reconfigurable antenna using conductive textile-polymer composite. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2021;69(10):6175&#x2013;6184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang QH, Nguyen-Trong N, Chen SJ, Fumeaux C. Pattern-reconfigurable flexible textile antenna using RF-switch integrated circuits. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2023;71(8):6490&#x2013;6500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan S, Vandenbosch GAE. Radiation pattern-reconfigurable wearable antenna based on metamaterial structure. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag Lett. 2016;15:1715&#x2013;1718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha S-J, Jung CW. Reconfigurable beam steering using a microstrip patch antenna with a U-slot for wearable fabric applications. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag Lett. 2011;10:1228&#x2013;1231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang QH, Chen SJ, Nguyen-Trong N, Fumeaux C. Multifunctional reconfigurable wearable textile antennas using coplanar reconfiguration modules. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2023;71(5):3806&#x2013;3815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salleh SM, Jusoh M, Ismail AH, Kamarudin MR, Nobles P, Rahim MKA. Textile antenna with simultaneous frequency and polarization reconfiguration for WBAN. IEEE Access. 2018;6:7350&#x2013;7358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronckers LA, Roch A, Smolders AB. A new design method for frequency-reconfigurable antennas using multiple tuning components. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2019;67(12):7285&#x2013;7295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S, Jung CW. Wearable fabric reconfigurable beam-steering antenna for on/off-body communication system. Int J Antennas Propag. 2015;2015: Article 539843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahrami S, Lee D, Hong W, Song H-J. Analysis of on-antenna power combining for realization of pattern-reconfigurable multifeed microstrip antennas. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2023;71(4):3091&#x2013;3103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Zhao X, Zhou H, Geng J, Lu J, Zhao R, Tang X, Liu H, Yuan X, He C, et al. A novel reconfigurable leaky-wave antenna with beam scanning ability at fixed frequency. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada JA, Kwiatkowski E, Lpoez-Yela A, Borgonos-Garcia M, Segovia-Vargas D, Barton T, Popovic Z. RF-harvesting tightly coupled rectenna array tee-shirt with greater than octave bandwidth. IEEE Trans Microw Theory Tech. 2020;68(9):3908&#x2013;3919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monti G, Corchia L, Tarricone L. UHF wearable rectenna on textile materials. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2013;61(7):3869&#x2013;3873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagih M, Weddell AS, Beeby S. 
Omnidirectional dual-polarized low-profile textile rectenna with over 50% efficiency for sub-&#x3bc;W/cm<sup>2</sup> wearable power harvesting. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2021;69(5):2522&#x2013;2536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y-Y, Sun S, Wu H, Yang S, Hu J. Integrated coupler-antenna design for multibeam dual-polarized patch-array rectenna. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2022;70(3):1869&#x2013;1883.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Song C, Zhang J, Zheng X, Volskiy V, Chu P. Wearable rectenna with integrated miniaturized feeding slot and rectifier structure. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2023;71(6):3868&#x2013;3881.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Lu D, Li R, Yu Y. Flexible broadband rectifying array antenna based on printed liquid metal. IEEE Trans. Microw Theory Tech. 2025;73(9):6001&#x2013;6008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagih M, Hilton GS, Weddell AS, Beeby S. Dual-polarized wearable antenna/rectenna for full-duplex and MIMO simultaneous wireless information and power transfer (SWIPT). IEEE Open J Antennas Propag. 2021;2:844&#x2013;857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagih M, Komolafe A, Weddell AS, Beeby S. Broadband compact substrate-independent textile wearable antenna for simultaneous near- and far-field wireless power transmission. IEEE Open J Antennas Propag. 2022;3:398&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui KW, Murphy OH, Toumazou C. A wearable wideband circularly polarized textile antenna for effective power transmission on a wirelessly-powered sensor platform. IEEE Trans Antennas Propag. 2013;61(7):3873&#x2013;3876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adami S-E, Proynov P, Hilton GS, Yang G, Zhang C, Zhu D. A flexible 2.45-GHz power harvesting wristband with net system output from &#x2212;24.3 dBm of RF power. IEEE Trans Microw Theory Tech. 2018;66(1):380&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosht RME, Feshawy MAE,Shorbagy MAE, Farag MN, Said AEE<i>.</i> A foldable textile-based broadband archimedean spiral rectenna for RF energy harvesting. In: <i>2016 16th Mediterranean Microwave Symposium (MMS)</i>. Piscataway (NJ): IEEE; 2016. p. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai M, Tian W, Pei R, Xu C, Leach M, Lim EG. Design, simulation and measurement of metapocket: An all-textile reflective metasurface for on-body smartphone radiation improvement. IEEE Trans Consum Electron. 2025;71(2):5446&#x2013;5456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai M, Zhang T, Pei R, Leach M, Lim EG, Wang Z. A reflecting/absorbing dual-mode textile metasurface design. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag Lett. 2024;23(10):3043&#x2013;3047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgnies L, Cochrane C, Rault F, Sadaune V, Lheurette E, Koncar V, Lippens D. Experimental phase-advance in woven textile metasurface. Appl Phys Lett. 2015;107: Article 203505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao G-P, Yang C, Hu B, Zhang R-F, Wang S-F. A wearable PIFA with an all-textile metasurface for 5 GHz WBAN applications. IEEE Antennas Wirel Propag Lett. 2019;18(2):288&#x2013;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain K, Sabapathy T, Jusoh M, Soh PJ, Jamaluddin MH, Al-Bawri SS, Osman MN, Ahmad RB, Rahim HA, Yasin MNM, et al. Electrically tunable left-handed textile metamaterial for microwave applications. Materials. 2021;14(5):1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Geng MY, Chen ZM, Chen JY, Zhang L, Yu BY, Ju L, Ding C, Guan YS, Liu ZG, et al. Digitally controlled tunable fabric microwave filter based on organic electrochemical transistors. Adv Mater Technol. 2023;8(18):2300428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Wang Z, Li J, Liu Y, Wang Y, Qin Y, Zheng Y, Huan Y, Peng H, Chen P. High-resolution and stretchable textile circuit by photopatterning of surface-modified liquid metal nanoparticles. Sci China Chem. 2025;68:6648&#x2013;6660.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>