<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41855311</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Ischemic Preconditioning Interventions With Different Cycles on Exercise Performance in Team Sport Athletes.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005427</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>&#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk, F, Ceylan, B, and Balc&#x131;, &#x15e;S. Effect of ischemic preconditioning interventions with different cycles on exercise performance in team sport athletes. J Strength Cond Res XX(X): 000-000, 2025-This study examined the effects of ischemic preconditioning (IPC) interventions with different cycle durations on anaerobic and agility performance and recovery in team sport athletes. Twelve young female athletes completed 4 visits. During the first visit, anthropometric assessments and familiarization procedures were conducted. In the remaining visits, athletes completed 1 of 3 conditions-IPC 1 &#xd7; 5 minutes, IPC 3 &#xd7; 5 minutes, or control-in a randomized order. Each session comprised a Modified Agility Test and the Running-Based Anaerobic Sprint Test, followed by a 5-minute recovery period. A 7-day rest period was given between conditions. Both IPC interventions significantly improved peak power output compared with control condition (p = 0.01). Mean power was higher after IPC 1 &#xd7; 5 minutes than control (p = 0.01), with no significant differences between the other conditions. Agility performance improved after IPC 3 &#xd7; 5 minutes compared with after IPC 1 &#xd7; 5 minutes (p = 0.01) but showed no difference relative to control (p &gt; 0.05). Heart rate (HR) values were lower after IPC interventions than in the control condition (p = 0.01), indicating enhanced cardiovascular recovery. However, IPC had no significant effect on ratings of perceived exertion scores or the time course of HR recovery. In conclusion, IPC enhanced specific aspects of anaerobic performance and supported cardiovascular recovery. Given the comparable outcomes across conditions, the shorter IPC protocol (1 &#xd7; 5 minutes) may represent a practical alternative to its longer counterpart.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk</LastName><ForeName>Furkan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sport Sciences, D&#xfc;zce University, D&#xfc;zce, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ceylan</LastName><ForeName>Bayram</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Kastamonu University, Kastamonu, T&#xfc;rkiye; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balc&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>&#x15e;&#xfc;kr&#xfc; Serdar</ForeName><Initials>&#x15e;S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Sel&#xe7;uk University, Konya, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">agility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anaerobic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41855311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arriel RA, de Souza HLR, da Mota GR, Marocolo M. Declines in exercise performance are prevented 24 hours after post-exercise ischemic conditioning in amateur cyclists. PLoS One 13: e0207053, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arriel RA, Meireles A, Hohl R, Marocolo M. Ischemic preconditioning improves performance and accelerates the heart rate recovery. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 60: 1209&#x2013;1215, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Art&#xe9;s A, Ferrer-Ramos P, Javierre C, Viscor G, Garc&#xed;a I. Effects of intermittent pneumatic compression on the recovery of cardiovascular parameters after repeated sprint exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol 124: 1037&#x2013;1048, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaven CM, Cook CJ, Kilduff L, Drawer S, Gill N. Intermittent lower-limb occlusion enhances recovery after strenuous exercise. APNM 37: 1132&#x2013;1139, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellini D, Chapman C, Peden D, Hoekstra SP, Ferguson RA, Leicht CA. Ischaemic preconditioning improves upper-body endurance performance without altering V&#x307;O2 kinetics. Eur J Sport Sci 23: 1538&#x2013;1546, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromley SJ, Drew MK, McIntosh A, Talpey S. Rating of perceived exertion is a stable and appropriate measure of workload in judo. J Sci Med Sport 21: 1008&#x2013;1012, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caru M, Levesque A, Lalonde F, Curnier D. An overview of ischemic preconditioning in exercise performance: A systematic review. J Sport Health Sci 8: 355&#x2013;369, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho L, Barroso R. Ischemic preconditioning improves strength endurance performance. J Strength Cond Res 33: 3332&#x2013;3337, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Franchini E. Ischemic preconditioning does not improve judo-specific performance but leads to better recovery in elite judo athletes. Sci Sports 37: 322.e1&#x2013;322.e7, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Ta&#x15f;k&#x131;n HB, &#x160;imenko J. Effect of ischemic preconditioning on acute recovery in elite judo athletes: A randomized, single-blind, crossover trial. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 18: 180&#x2013;186, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MJ, Fan X, Moe ST. Criterion-related validity of the Borg ratings of perceived exertion scale in healthy individuals: A meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 20: 873&#x2013;899, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Wu W, Qiang L, Wang C, He Z, Wang Y. The effect of ischemic preconditioning on physical fitness and performance: A meta-analysis in healthy adults. Eur J Appl Physiol 125: 805&#x2013;821, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C-F, Kuo Y-H, Hsu W-C, Chen C, Pan C-H. Local and remote ischemic preconditioning improves sprint interval exercise performance in team sport athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health 18: 10653, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung CP, Slysz JT, Burr JF. Ischemic preconditioning: Improved cycling performance despite nocebo expectation. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 15: 354&#x2013;360, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clevidence MW, Mowery RE, Kushnick MR. The effects of ischemic preconditioning on aerobic and anaerobic variables associated with submaximal cycling performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 3649&#x2013;3654, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocking S, Wilson MG, Nichols D, et al. Is there an optimal ischemic-preconditioning dose to improve cycling performance? Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 274&#x2013;282, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, G&#xe1;spari AF, Ramkrapes AP, et al. Anaerobic metabolism induces greater total energy expenditure during exercise with blood flow restriction. PLoS One 13: e0194776, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz RSdO, de Aguiar RA, Turnes T, Pereira KL, Caputo F. Effects of ischemic preconditioning on maximal constant-load cycling performance. J Appl Physiol 119: 961&#x2013;967, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groot PCE, Thijssen DHJ, Sanchez M, Ellenkamp R, Hopman MTE. Ischemic preconditioning improves maximal performance in humans. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 141&#x2013;146, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durnin JV, Womersley J. Body fat assessed from total body density and its estimation from skinfold thickness: Measurements on 481 men and women aged from 16 to 72 years. Br J Nutr 32: 77&#x2013;97, 1974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>French C, Robbins D, Gernigon M, Gordon D. The effects of lower limb ischaemic preconditioning: A systematic review. Front Physiol 14: 1323310, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia CA, da Mota GR, Leicht AS, Marocolo M. Ischemic preconditioning and acute recovery of performance in rugby union players. Sports Med Int Open 1: E107&#x2013;E112, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausenloy DJ, Yellon DM. Remote ischaemic preconditioning: Underlying mechanisms and clinical application. Cardiovasc Res 79: 377&#x2013;386, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incognito AV, Burr JF, Millar PJ. The effects of ischemic preconditioning on human exercise performance. Sports Med 46: 531&#x2013;544, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastrz&#x119;bska AD. Comparison of usefulness of two tests measuring anaerobic performance of untrained and soccer-training girls U12. Sci Rep 13: 19498, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson EC, Pryor RR, Casa DJ, et al. Precision, accuracy, and performance outcomes of perceived exertion vs. heart rate guided run-training. J Strength Cond Res 31: 630&#x2013;637, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakehashi T, Ryota S, Komatsu M, Nakajima M. Immediate effect of ischemic loading on quadriceps muscle output by using a pneumatic cuff. J Bodyw Mov Ther 41: 159&#x2013;163, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataoka R, Song JS, Yamada Y, et al. The impact of different ischemic preconditioning pressures on pain sensitivity and resistance exercise performance. J Strength Cond Res 38: 864&#x2013;872, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner TD, Scholten SD, Halverson JM, Baumgarten KM, Birger CB, Nowotny BG. The acute effects of ischemic preconditioning on power and sprint performance. S D Med 74: 210&#x2013;219, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisb&#xf4;a FD, Turnes T, Cruz RSO, Raimundo JAG, Pereira GS, Caputo F. The time dependence of the effect of ischemic preconditioning on successive sprint swimming performance. J Sci Med Sport 20: 507&#x2013;511, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo IC, da Mota GR, Londe AM, Patterson SD, Barbosa Neto O, Marocolo M. Acute ischemic preconditioning does not influence high-intensity intermittent exercise performance. PeerJ 5: e4118, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Da Mota G, Pelegrini V, Appell Coriolano HJ. Are the beneficial effects of ischemic preconditioning on performance partly a placebo effect? Int J Sports Med 36: 822&#x2013;825, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Souza HLR, Surke P, Ferrauti A. Potential Short- and long-term physiological effects of ischemic preconditioning as an ergogenic aid: Revisiting foundational mechanisms and applications. Sports Med 55: 1547&#x2013;1557, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra P, Pandey CM, Singh U, Gupta A, Sahu C, Keshri A. Descriptive statistics and normality tests for statistical data. Ann Card Anaesth 22: 67&#x2013;72, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien L, Jacobs I. Methodological variations contributing to heterogenous ergogenic responses to ischemic preconditioning. Front Physiol 12: 656980, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paixao R, da Mota GR, Marocolo M. Acute effect of ischemic preconditioning is detrimental to anaerobic performance in cyclists. Int J Sports Med 35: e5&#x2013;e915, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis-Desch&#xea;nes P, Joanisse DR, Mauri&#xe8;ge P, Billaut F. Ischemic preconditioning enhances aerobic adaptations to sprint-interval training in athletes without altering systemic hypoxic signaling and immune function. Front Sports Act Living 2: 41, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Bezodis NE, Glaister M, Pattison JR. The effect of ischemic preconditioning on repeated sprint cycling performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 1652&#x2013;1658, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabino-Carvalho JL, Lopes TR, Obeid-Freitas T, et al. Effect of ischemic preconditioning on endurance performance does not surpass placebo. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49: 124&#x2013;132, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador AF, De Aguiar RA, Lisb&#xf4;a FD, Pereira KL, Cruz RS, Caputo F. Ischemic preconditioning and exercise performance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 4&#x2013;14, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassi RH, Dardouri W, Yahmed MH, Gmada N, Mahfoudhi ME, Gharbi Z. Relative and absolute reliability of a modified agility T-test and its relationship with vertical jump and straight sprint. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1644&#x2013;1651, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. The gross composition of the body. Advances in Biological and Medical Physics. Amsterdam, The Netherlands: Elsevier, 1956. pp. 239&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz JT, Burr JF. Impact of 8 weeks of repeated ischemic preconditioning on running performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 119: 1431&#x2013;1437, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka D, Suga T, Shimoho K, Isaka T. Effect of 2-Weeks ischemic preconditioning on exercise performance: A pilot study. Front Sports Act Living 3: 646369, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turnes T, de Aguiar RA, de Oliveira Cruz RS, et al. Impact of ischaemia&#x2013;reperfusion cycles during ischaemic preconditioning on 2000-m rowing ergometer performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 1599&#x2013;1607, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharogiannis E, Paradisis G, Tziortzis S. An evaluation of tests of anaerobic power and capacity. Med Sci Sports Exerc 36: S116, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagatto AM, Beck WR, Gobatto CA. Validity of the running anaerobic sprint test for assessing anaerobic power and predicting short-distance performances. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1820&#x2013;1827, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinner C, Born D-P, Sperlich B. Ischemic preconditioning does not alter performance in multidirectional high-intensity intermittent exercise. Front Physiol 8: 1029, 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>