<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888170</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Programmable multiscale energy release in synergistic energetic composites with three dimensional printed architectures.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-71222-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Energetic materials are central to propulsion and detonation technologies, yet their performance is often limited by poor control over energy release across multiple length and time scales. Integrating highly reactive composites with molecular explosives while maintaining structural precision remains challenging. Here we show a three dimensional printing strategy that enables programmable energetic composites by combining highly reactive metastable composite systems with a crystalline high explosive through acoustic-assisted assembly. Uniform coating and intimate interfacial contact produce dense architectures with enhanced thermal reactivity, accelerated pressurisation and increased energy output under confined conditions. Printed filamentary and core-shell structures further enable multistage and geometry-dependent energy release, including sustained combustion, secondary pressurisation and intense fireball formation. Laser-driven and combustion experiments reveal that the energy release characteristics can be systematically tuned by composition and architecture. This work establishes a general route to structure-performance control in energetic materials and highlights additive manufacturing as a powerful platform for designing next-generation reactive and explosive systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yongjin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3030-733X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7940-6630</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China. renhui@bit.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xin</LastName><ForeName>Haoyue</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-5615-9068</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xinzhou</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9149-9668</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiao</LastName><ForeName>Qingjie</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9186-4776</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>21975024</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202406030020</GrantID><Agency>China Scholarship Council (CSC)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-71222-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-71222-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sundaram, D., Yang, V. &amp; Yetter, R. A. Metal-based nanoenergetic materials: synthesis, properties, and applications. Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 61, 293&#x2013;365 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, W., Liu, P. J., He, G. Q., Gozin, M. &amp; Yan, Q. L. Highly reactive metastable intermixed composites (MICs): preparation and characterization. Adv. Mater. 30, 1706293 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, X., Li, Y., Hussain, I., Shen, R., Yang, G. &amp; Zhang, K. Core-shell structured nanoenergetic materials: preparation and fundamental properties. Adv. Mater. 32, e2001291 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe9;verac, F., Alphonse, P., Est&#xe8;ve, A., Bancaud, A. &amp; Rossi, C. High-energy Al/CuO nanocomposites obtained by DNA-directed assembly. Adv. Funct. Mater. 22, 323&#x2013;329 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan, K. T. et al. Controlling material reactivity using architecture. Adv. Mater. 28, 1934&#x2013;1939 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, X., Jiang, L., Zhu, C. &amp; Wang, X. Effects of Aluminum powder on ignition performance of RDX, HMX, and CL-20 explosives. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2018, 1&#x2013;8 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton, P. E., Gilardi, R. L. &amp; Zhang, M. X. Polynitrocubanes: advanced high-density, high-energy materials. Adv. Mater. 12, 1143&#x2013;1148 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baer, M. Modeling heterogeneous energetic materials at the mesoscale. Thermochim. Acta 384, 351&#x2013;367 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilyushin, M. A., Tselinsky, I. V. &amp; Shugalei, I. V. Environmentally friendly energetic materials for initiation devices. Cent. Eur. J. Energetic Mater. 9, 293&#x2013;327 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, S.H. &amp; Grubelich, M. Theoretical energy release of thermites, intermetallics, and combustible metals. https://doi.org/10.2172/658208 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. et al. Effects of oxidizer and architecture on the thermochemical reactivity, laser ignition and combustion properties of nanothermite. Fuel 314, 123141 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granier, J. J. &amp; Pantoya, M. L. Laser ignition of nanocomposite thermites. Combust. Flame 138, 373&#x2013;383 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichot, V., Comet, M., Miesch, J. &amp; Spitzer, D. Nanodiamond for tuning the properties of energetic composites. J. Hazard Mater. 300, 194&#x2013;201 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. et al. Tuning the ignition performance of a microchip initiator by integrating various Al/MoO3 reactive multilayer films on a semiconductor bridge. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 9, 5580&#x2013;5589 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ao, W. et al. Combustion and agglomeration characteristics of aluminized propellants containing Al/CuO/PVDF metastable intermolecular composites: A highly adjustable functional catalyst. Combust. Flame 241, 112110 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noor, F., Vorozhtsov, A., Lerner, M. &amp; Wen, D. Exothermic characteristics of aluminum based nanomaterials. Powder Technol. 282, 19&#x2013;24 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sippel, T. R., Son, S. F. &amp; Groven, L. J. Aluminum agglomeration reduction in a composite propellant using tailored Al/PTFE particles. Combust. Flame 161, 311&#x2013;321 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi, C., Zhang, K., Esteve, D., Alphonse, P., Tailhades, P. &amp; Vahlas, C. Nanoenergetic materials for MEMS: a review. J. Microelectromechanical Syst. 16, 919&#x2013;931 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders, V. E., Asay, B. W., Foley, T. J., Tappan, B. C., Pacheco, A. N. &amp; Son, S. F. Reaction propagation of four nanoscale energetic composites (Al/MoO3, Al/WO3, Al/CuO, and B12O3). J. Propul. Power 23, 707&#x2013;714 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weismiller, M. R., Malchi, J. Y., Yetter, R. A. &amp; Foley, T. J. Dependence of flame propagation on pressure and pressurizing gas for an Al/CuO nanoscale thermite. Proc. Combust. Inst. 32, 1895&#x2013;1903 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLuca, L. et al. Microstructure effects in aluminized solid rocket propellants. J. Propul. Power 26, 724&#x2013;732 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried, L. E., Manaa, M. R., Pagoria, P. F. &amp; Simpson, R. L. Design and synthesis of energetic materials. Annu. Rev. Mater. Res. 31, 291&#x2013;321 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elghafour, A. M., Radwan, M. A., Mostafa, H. E., Fahd, A. &amp; Elbasuney, S. Highly energetic nitramines: A novel platonizing agent for double-base propellants with superior combustion characteristics. Fuel 227, 478&#x2013;484 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbasuney, S., Zaky, M. G., Radwan, M. &amp; Mostafa, S. F. Stabilized super-thermite colloids: a new generation of advanced highly energetic materials. Appl. Surf. Sci. 419, 328&#x2013;336 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbasuney, S., Hamed, A., Ismael, S., Mokhtar, M. &amp; Gobara, M. Novel high energy density material based on metastable intermolecular nanocomposite. J. Inorg. Organomet. Polym. Mater. 30, 3980&#x2013;3988 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbasuney, S. et al. Synergistic catalytic effect of thermite nanoparticles on HMX thermal decomposition. J. Inorg. Organomet. Polym. Mater. 31, 2293&#x2013;2305 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbasuney, S. et al. The Impact of metastable intermolrecular nanocomposite particles on kinetic decomposition of heterocyclic nitramines Using Advanced Solid-Phase Decomposition Models. J. Inorg. Organomet. Polym. Mater. 31, 3665&#x2013;3676 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbasuney, S., Hamed, A., Yehia, M., Gobara, M. &amp; Mokhtar, M. The significant impact colloidal nanothermite particles (Fe2O3/Al) on HMX kinetic decomposition. J. Energet. Mater. 41, 27&#x2013;42 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y. et al. In situ preparation of explosive embedded CuO/Al/CL20 nanoenergetic composite with enhanced reactivity. Chem. Eng. J. 354, 885&#x2013;895 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCollum, J., Pantoya, M. L. &amp; Iacono, S. T. Activating aluminum reactivity with fluoropolymer coatings for improved energetic composite combustion. ACS Appl. Mater. interfaces 7, 18742&#x2013;18749 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Fabrication of high electrostatic safety metastable Al/CuO nanocomposites doped with nitro-functionalized graphene with fast initiation ability and tunable reaction performance. Combust. Flame 233, 111580 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, J. et al. Pressure loss and compensation in the combustion process of Al&#x2013;CuO nanoenergetics on a microheater chip. Combust. Flame 161, 2975&#x2013;2981 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. et al. An excellent synergy between CL-20 and nanothermites in flaming and propelling with high specific impulse and superior safety to electrostatic discharge. Combust. Flame 240, 112024 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, J. et al. Ammonium perchlorate as an effective additive for enhancing the combustion and propulsion performance of Al/CuO nanothermites. J. Phys. Chem. C 122, 10240&#x2013;10247 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Q-p, Long X-p, Liu G-x, Wu C. Deflagration to detonation transition in weakly confined conditions for a type of potentially novel green primary explosive: Al/Fe2O3/RDX hybrid nanocomposites. Def. Technol. 22, 28&#x2013;36 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiruvengadathan, R. et al. Combustion characteristics of novel hybrid nanoenergetic formulations. Combust. Flame 158, 964&#x2013;978 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ligon, S. C., Liska, R., Stampfl, J., Gurr, M. &amp; M&#xfc;lhaupt, R. Polymers for 3D printing and customized additive manufacturing. Chem. Rev. 117, 10212&#x2013;10290 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamba, L., Lajoie, J. A., Sippel, T. R. &amp; Secor, E. B. Multi-material aerosol Jet printing of Al/Cuo nanothermites for versatile fabrication of energetic antennas. Adv. Funct. Mater. 33, 2304060 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C-y, Kong S, Liao D-j, An C-w, Ye B-y, Wang J-y. Fabrication and characterization of mussel-inspired layer-by-layer assembled CL-20-based energetic films via micro-jet printing. Def. Technol. 18, 1748&#x2013;1759 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray, A. K. et al. Selectively-deposited energetic materials: A feasibility study of the piezoelectric inkjet printing of nanothermites. Addit. Manuf. 22, 69&#x2013;74 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, J. et al. Combustion of 3D printed 90 wt% loading reinforced nanothermite. Combust. Flame 215, 86&#x2013;92 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Deng, Y., Ren, H. &amp; Jiao, Q. Additive manufacturing and performance tuning of functionally graded Al/AP with continuous change of content. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 24, 6992&#x2013;7003 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, N., He, C. &amp; Pang, S. Additive manufacturing of energetic materials: Tailoring energetic performance via printing. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 127, 29&#x2013;47 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muravyev, N. V., Monogarov, K. A., Schaller, U., Fomenkov, I. V. &amp; Pivkina, A. N. Progress in additive manufacturing of energetic materials: creating the reactive microstructures with high potential of applications. Propellants, Explos. Pyrotech. 44, 941&#x2013;969 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Direct Writing of a 90 wt% Particle Loading Nanothermite. Adv. Mater. 31, 1806575.1806571&#x2013;1806575.1806577 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Ren, H., Wu, X., Xin, H. &amp; Jiao, Q. Litchi-like&#x201d; metastable Al/Ti/CuO micro-nano composites with enhanced combustion reaction and their energy characteristics. Combust. Flame 256, 112947 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Z., Ding, L., Wu, P., Liu, Y., Nie, F. &amp; Huang, F. Fabrication of RDX, HMX and CL-20 based microcapsules via in situ polymerization of melamine&#x2013;formaldehyde resins with reduced sensitivity. Chem. Eng. J. 268, 60&#x2013;66 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer, R., K&#xf6;hler, J. &amp; Homburg, A. Explosives. (John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan, K.T. et al. Controlling material reactivity using architecture. Adv. Mater. 28, 1934&#x2013;1939 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. et al. Adsorption and catalysis of Bi-doped Fe2O3 on gas products of HMX decomposition: A DFT study. Appl. Surf. Sci. 573, 151545 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Self-assembly preparation of advanced metastable MCo2O4/GO/Al (M= Cu, Mg, Zn, Ni) nanothermites to realize large heat release, stable combustion and high safety. Ceram. Int. 48, 20825&#x2013;20837 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbasuney, S. &amp; El-Sayyad, G. S. The potentials of TiO2 nanocatalyst on HMX thermolysis. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Electron. 31, 14930&#x2013;14940 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey, R., Srivastava, P., Kapoor, I. &amp; Singh, G. Synthesis, characterization and catalytic behavior of Cu nanoparticles on the thermal decomposition of AP, HMX, NTO and composite solid propellants, Part 83. Thermochim. Acta 549, 102&#x2013;109 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao, Z. et al. Fast deflagration to detonation transition of energetic material based on a quasi-core/shell structured nanothermite composite. Compos. Sci. Technol. 107, 113&#x2013;119 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palopoli, S. &amp; Brill, T. Thermal decomposition of energetic materials 52. On the foam zone and surface chemistry of rapidly decomposing HMX. Combust. Flame 87, 45&#x2013;60 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azambre, B., Zenboury, L., Koch, A. &amp; Weber, J. Adsorption and desorption of NO x on commercial ceria-zirconia (Ce x Zr1&#x2212; x O2) mixed oxides: a combined TGA, TPD-MS, and DRIFTS study. J. Phys. Chem. C. 113, 13287&#x2013;13299 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohlin, L., Bazin, P., Thibault-Starzyk, F., Hedlund, J. &amp; Grahn, M. Adsorption of CO2, CH4, and H2O in zeolite ZSM-5 studied using in situ ATR-FTIR spectroscopy. J. Phys. Chem. C. 117, 16972&#x2013;16982 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>REN X-N. et al. An investigation on the flash pyrolysis process of octahydro-1, 3, 5, 7-tetranitro-1, 3, 5, 7-tetrazocine (HMX) by T-Jump/FTIR spectroscopy. Acta Chim. Sin. 68, 1193 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpowicz, R. &amp; Brill, T. In situ characterization of the &#x201c;melt&#x201d; phase of RDX and HMX by rapid-scan FTIR spectroscopy. Combust. Flame 56, 317&#x2013;325 (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brill, T. &amp; Brush, P. Condensed phase chemistry of explosives and propellants at high temperature: HMX, RDX and BAMO. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. Ser. A Phys. Eng. Sci. 339, 377&#x2013;385 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comet, M., Martin, C., Klaum&#xfc;nzer, M., Schnell, F. &amp; Spitzer, D. Energetic nanocomposites for detonation initiation in high explosives without primary explosives. Appl. Phys. Lett. 107, 243108 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarko, V. E. &amp; Gromov, A. A. Energetic nanomaterials: Synthesis, characterization, and application. (Elsevier, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, Q.-L., Zhao, F.-Q., Kuo, K. K., Zhang, X.-H., Zeman, S. &amp; DeLuca, L. T. Catalytic effects of nano additives on decomposition and combustion of RDX-, HMX-, and AP-based energetic compositions. Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 57, 75&#x2013;136 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mckay, J. A. et al. Pulsed-CO2-laser interaction with aluminum in air: Thermal response and plasma characteristics. J. Appl. Phys. 50, 3231&#x2013;3240 (1979).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe1;nai, L. &amp; Hevesi, I. Time-resolved spectral investigations of laser light induced microplasma. Spectrochim. Acta Part A Mol. Spectrosc. 48, 19&#x2013;24 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller, K. K., Gottfried, J. L., Walck, S. D., Pantoya, M. L. &amp; Wu, C. C. Combustion and Flame Plasma surface treatment of aluminum nanoparticles for energetic material applications. Combust. Flame 206, 211&#x2013;213 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harilal, S., Bindhu, C., Tillack, M., Najmabadi, F. &amp; Gaeris, A. Internal structure and expansion dynamics of laser ablation plumes into ambient gases. J. Appl. Phys. 93, 2380&#x2013;2388 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, T., Wang, X., Zavalij, P. Y., DeLisio, J. B., Wang, H. &amp; Zachariah, M. R. Performance of iodine oxides/iodic acids as oxidizers in thermite systems. Combust. Flame 191, 335&#x2013;342 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, Z. et al. Sulfate-based nanothermite: a green substitute of primary explosive containing lead. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 6, 8584&#x2013;8590 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, J. et al. Facile formation of nitrocellulose-coated Al/Bi2O3 nanothermites with excellent energy output and improved electrostatic discharge safety. Mater. Des. 143, 93&#x2013;103 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottfried, J. L. Influence of exothermic chemical reactions on laser-induced shock waves. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 16, 21452&#x2013;21466 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Fast explosive performance prediction via small-dose energetic materials based on time-resolved imaging combined with machine learning. J. Mater. Chem. A10, 13114&#x2013;13123 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargather, M. J. &amp; Settles, G. S. A comparison of three quantitative schlieren techniques. Opt. Lasers Eng. 50, 8&#x2013;17 (2012).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>