<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41480610</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1948-9358</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of diabetes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Diabetes</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Electroacupuncture in glycemic control: Transitioning from clinical controversies to potential basic research.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>112580</StartPage><MedlinePgn>112580</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">112580</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4239/wjd.v16.i12.112580</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetes is a major global metabolic disorder, with the type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) population in China expected to reach 168 million by 2050. Electroacupuncture (EA) and auricular acupuncture represent safe, accessible, and multi-targeted strategies for glycemic control with strong translational potential. Clinical studies indicate that EA, targeting trunk and limb acupoints, can significantly reduce fasting plasma glucose and glycated hemoglobin. Mechanistically, EA modulates the neuro-endocrine-immune axis, regulates gut microbiota, and activates insulin signaling pathways. Auricular acupuncture, through vagal innervation, may also exert rapid effects on glucose homeostasis via autonomic modulation. The review's objective is to synthesize and critically evaluate current clinical trials and animal studies on EA and auricular acupuncture for glycemic control in diabetes, particularly T2DM, and to highlight translational implications, mechanistic insights, and evidence gaps. This review also emphasizes translational considerations by highlighting species differences between rodents and humans - an underappreciated yet critical factor influencing the clinical applicability of preclinical findings. Through the integration of recent research advances, the present review not only consolidates clinical and preclinical evidence but also advances a deeper mechanistic framework and underscores the importance of species-specific factors in bridging experimental research and patient care. Future progress requires rigorously designed, adequately powered, multicenter randomized controlled trials with standardized protocols to validate efficacy and define their role in precision diabetes management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shuai-Yan</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Xi</ForeName><Initials>CX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Ning</ForeName><Initials>YN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Mei-Xin</ForeName><Initials>MX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Si-Yu</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Fan</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China. xubin@njucm.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Tian-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Acupuncture and Medicine Research of Ministry of Education, Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Nanjing 210023, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Diabetes</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101547524</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1948-9358</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Auricular acupuncture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Basic research in acupuncture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood glucose management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body acupuncture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical controversies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electroacupuncture</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41480610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12754118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v16.i12.112580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>International Diabetes Federation. Diabetes Atlas. 11th ed. Brussels, Belgium: International Diabetes Federation, 2025: 47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An J, Wang L, Song S, Tian L, Liu Q, Mei M, Li W, Liu S. Electroacupuncture reduces blood glucose by regulating intestinal flora in type 2 diabetic mice. J Diabetes. 2022;14:695&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9574722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36195536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XX, Zhang LZ, Zhang HH, Lai LF, Wang YQ, Sun J, Xu NG, Li ZX. Low-frequency electroacupuncture improves disordered hepatic energy metabolism in insulin-resistant Zucker diabetic fatty rats via the AMPK/mTORC1/p70S6K signaling pathway. Acupunct Med. 2022;40:360&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35034504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boccino J. Auricular Acupuncture for Lowering Blood Glucose in Type 2 Diabetes: A Pilot Study. Med Acupunct. 2023;35:186&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10440671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37609549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kann JR. Acupuncture Not Supported By Strong Scientific Evidence. Am Fam Physician. 2020;101:326&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32163259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Zhang Y, Tang X, Ge S, Wen H, Zeng J, Wang L, Zeng Z, Rada G, &#xc1;vila C, Vergara C, Tang Y, Zhang P, Chen R, Dong Y, Wei X, Luo W, Wang L, Guyatt G, Tang C, Xu N. Evidence on acupuncture therapies is underused in clinical practice and health policy. BMJ. 2022;376:e067475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8868048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35217525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu T, Yu Z, Liu Y, Lu M, Gong M, Li Q, Xia Y, Xu B. Hypoglycemic Effect of Electroacupuncture at ST25 Through Neural Regulation of the Pancreatic Intrinsic Nervous System. Mol Neurobiol. 2022;59:703&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34757591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong S, Zhao L, Liu J, Sha X, Wu Y, Liu W, Sun J, Su Y, Zhuang Z, Chen J, Dong Y, Xie B, Zhou A, Ji H, Wang Y, Deng X, Jing X, Ma Q, Wang N, Liu S. Neuroanatomical organization of electroacupuncture in modulating gastric function in mice and humans. Neuron. 2025;113:3243&#x2013;3259.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40713955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Liu W, Ge J, Liu S. The immunomodulatory mechanisms for acupuncture practice. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1147718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10117649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37090714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Chen Y, Pang Y, Kou L, Lu D, Ke W. An AAM-Based Identification Method for Ear Acupoint Area. Biomimetics (Basel) 2023;8:307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10807013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37504195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LQ, Chen Z, Zhang K, Liang N, Yang GY, Lai L, Liu JP. Zusanli (ST36) Acupoint Injection for Diabetic Peripheral Neuropathy: A Systematic Review of Randomized Controlled Trials. J Altern Complement Med. 2018;24:1138&#x2013;1149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30431314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YC, Li TM, Tzeng CY, Chen YI, Ho WJ, Lin JG, Chang SL. Electroacupuncture at the Zusanli (ST-36) Acupoint Induces a Hypoglycemic Effect by Stimulating the Cholinergic Nerve in a Rat Model of Streptozotocine-Induced Insulin-Dependent Diabetes Mellitus. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2011;2011:650263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3136799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo K, Lu Y, Wang X, Duan Y, Li H, Gao F, Wang J. Multi-level exploration of auricular acupuncture: from traditional Chinese medicine theory to modern medical application. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:1426618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11456840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39376538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Xiang Q, Liu X, Yin Y, Bai S, Yu R. Auricular pressure as an adjuvant treatment for type 2 diabetes: data mining and meta-analysis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2024;15:1424304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11410687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39301316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua K, Usichenko T, Cummings M, Bernatik M, Willich SN, Brinkhaus B, Dietzel J. Effects of auricular stimulation on weight- and obesity-related parameters: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled clinical trials. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:1393826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11333859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39165337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R, Mooventhan A, Manjunath NK. Immediate Effect of Needling at CV-12 (Zhongwan) Acupuncture Point on Blood Glucose Level in Patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Pilot Randomized Placebo-Controlled Trial. J Acupunct Meridian Stud. 2017;10:240&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28889840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooventhan A, Ningombam R, Nivethitha L. Effect of bilateral needling at an acupuncture point, ST-36 (Zusanli) on blood glucose levels in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients: A pilot randomized placebo controlled trial. J Complement Integr Med. 2020;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Ao Y, Liu B, Huang J, Wang Q, Ao X, Wang X, Ban X. The safety and efficacy of acupuncture in treating nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis based on randomized controlled trials. Medicine (Baltimore) 2025;104:e42272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12055161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40324281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SQ, Chen JR, Liu ML, Wang YP, Zhou X, Sun X. Effect and Safety of Acupuncture for Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of 21 Randomised Controlled Trials. Chin J Integr Med. 2022;28:463&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34432205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald JL, Bauer M. Is Electroacupuncture Contraindicated for Preventing and Treating Chemotherapy-Induced Peripheral Neuropathy? Med Acupunct. 2023;35:290&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10753944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38162553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Yan J, Hu J, Liu X, Wang F. Efficacy and safety of electroacupuncture for carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS): A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Surg. 2022;9:952361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9539120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Lu Z, Chen S, Gao T, Gang X, Pan T, Meng M, Liu M. Effect of electroacupuncture on glucose and lipid metabolism in type 2 diabetes: A protocol for systematic review and meta-analysis. Medicine (Baltimore) 2021;100:e27762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34889226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang P, Zhao J, Yang H. The efficacy of electroacupuncture in among early diabetic patients with lower limb arteriosclerotic wounds. Int Wound J. 2024;21:e14526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10961040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38093499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manlai U, Chang SW, Lee SC, Ho WJ, Hsu TH, Lin JG, Lin CM, Chen YI, Chang SL. Hypoglycemic Effect of Electroacupuncture Combined with Antrodia cinnamomea in Dexamethasone-Induced Insulin-Resistant Rats. Med Acupunct. 2021;33:58&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7894032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33613812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YJ, Zhou XC, Tian HR, Liang FX. Electroacupuncture relieves type 2 diabetes by regulating gut microbiome. World J Diabetes. 2025;16:103032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11885963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40093270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Q, Chen R, Peng M, Li L, Li T, Liang FX, Xu F. [Effect of electroacupuncture on SIRT1/NF-&#x3ba;B signaling pathway in adipose tissue of obese rats] Zhongguo Zhen Jiu. 2020;40:185&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32100506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera O, Berman DM, Kenyon NS, Ricordi C, Berggren PO, Caicedo A. The unique cytoarchitecture of human pancreatic islets has implications for islet cell function. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:2334&#x2013;2339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1413730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finnerup NB, Kuner R, Jensen TS. Neuropathic Pain: From Mechanisms to Treatment. Physiol Rev. 2021;101:259&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Cuadros M, Miettinen TP, Skinner OS, Sheedy D, D&#xed;az-Garc&#xed;a CM, Gapon S, Hubaud A, Yellen G, Manalis SR, Oldham WM, Pourqui&#xe9; O. Metabolic regulation of species-specific developmental rates. Nature. 2023;613:550&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9944513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36599986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang S, Liu S, Li R, Duan H. Electroacupuncture alleviates insulin resistance and impacts the hypothalamic IRS-1/PI3K/AKT pathway and miRNA-29a-3p in a rat model of type 2 diabetes. Acupunct Med. 2025;43:104&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40116412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peplow PV, Baxter GD. Electroacupuncture for control of blood glucose in diabetes: literature review. J Acupunct Meridian Stud. 2012;5:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22309901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man KM, Lee YC, Chen YI, Chen YH, Chang SL, Huang CC. Electroacupuncture at Bilateral ST36 Acupoints: Inducing the Hypoglycemic Effect through Enhancing Insulin Signal Proteins in a Streptozotocin-Induced Rat Model during Isoflurane Anesthesia. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2021;2021:5852599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8514912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34659435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Cui Y, Sun ZR, Zhou XY, Cao Y, Li XL, Yin HN. Research progress on the mechanism of acupuncture on type &#x2161; diabetes mellitus. Zhen Ci Yan Jiu. 2024;49:641&#x2013;649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38897809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J, Kuang J, Chandalia M, Tuvdendorj D, Tumurbaatar B, Abate N, Chen JD. Hypoglycemic effects and mechanisms of electroacupuncture on insulin resistance. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2014;307:R332&#x2013;R339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4121630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24848362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Fang Y, Wang Y, Hao Y. Acupoint Therapy on Diabetes Mellitus and Its Common Chronic Complications: A Review of Its Mechanisms. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:3128378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6217896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30426006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N, Guo Y, Gong Y, Zhang Y, Fan W, Yao K, Chen Z, Dou B, Lin X, Chen B, Chen Z, Xu Z, Lyu Z. The Anti-Inflammatory Actions and Mechanisms of Acupuncture from Acupoint to Target Organs via Neuro-Immune Regulation. J Inflamm Res. 2021;14:7191&#x2013;7224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8710088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34992414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Chen X, Wang H, Huang H, Li M, Yao L, Ma S, Zhong Z, Yang H, Wang H. "Adjusting Internal Organs and Dredging Channel" Electroacupuncture Ameliorates Insulin Resistance in Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus by Regulating the Intestinal Flora and Inhibiting Inflammation. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. 2021;14:2595&#x2013;2607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8200173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34135611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding SS, Hong SH, Wang C, Guo Y, Wang ZK, Xu Y. Acupuncture modulates the neuro-endocrine-immune network. QJM. 2014;107:341&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24106314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butt MF, Albusoda A, Farmer AD, Aziz Q. The anatomical basis for transcutaneous auricular vagus nerve stimulation. J Anat. 2020;236:588&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7083568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31742681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Jing XH, Zhu B, Zhu XL, Li L, Bai WZ, Ben H. The auriculo-vagal afferent pathway and its role in seizure suppression in rats. BMC Neurosci. 2013;14:85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3751281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23927528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toschi N, Duggento A, Barbieri R, Garcia RG, Fisher HP, Kettner NW, Napadow V, Sclocco R. Causal influence of brainstem response to transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation on cardiovagal outflow. Brain Stimul. 2023;16:1557&#x2013;1565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10809655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37827358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Wang X, Shi H, Shang H, Li L, Jing X, Zhu B. Auricular acupuncture and vagal regulation. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2012;2012:786839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3523683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23304215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller SJ, Teckentrup V, Rebollo I, Hallschmid M, Kroemer NB. Vagus nerve stimulation increases stomach-brain coupling via a vagal afferent pathway. Brain Stimul. 2022;15:1279&#x2013;1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36067977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh CH, Chien LC, Chiang YC, Huang LC. Auricular point acupressure for chronic low back pain: a feasibility study for 1-week treatment. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2012;2012:383257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3395299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22811745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgmann D, Fenselau H. Vagal pathways for systemic regulation of glucose metabolism. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2024;156:244&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37500301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong PJ, Zhao JJ, Li YQ, Litscher D, Li SY, Gaischek I, Zhai X, Wang L, Luo M, Litscher G. Auricular acupuncture and biomedical research--A promising Sino-Austrian research cooperation. Chin J Integr Med. 2015;21:887&#x2013;894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26631173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaniusas E, Kampusch S, Tittgemeyer M, Panetsos F, Gines RF, Papa M, Kiss A, Podesser B, Cassara AM, Tanghe E, Samoudi AM, Tarnaud T, Joseph W, Marozas V, Lukosevicius A, I&#x161;tuk N, &#x160;aroli&#x107; A, Lechner S, Klonowski W, Varoneckas G, Sz&#xe9;les JC. Current Directions in the Auricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation I - A Physiological Perspective. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6697069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31447643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan JA, Mitchell R. Some observations on the innervation of the pinna of the ear of the rat. J Anat. 1974;117:397&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1231412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4461730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirz-Ridolfi A. The History of Ear Acupuncture and Ear Cartography: Why Precise Mapping of Auricular Points Is Important. Med Acupunct. 2019;31:145&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6604909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31297168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Jia S, Li Q, Lu D, Zhang S, Xiao W. [Deep learning approach for automatic segmentation of auricular acupoint divisions] Sheng Wu Yi Xue Gong Cheng Xue Za Zhi. 2024;41:114&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10894748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38403611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashmi SS, van Staalduinen EK, Massoud TF. Anatomy of the Spinal Cord, Coverings, and Nerves. Neuroimaging Clin N Am. 2022;32:903&#x2013;914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36244730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang J, Sun W, Zhou Y, Zhang P, Chen Y, Li X, He H, Liu X, Zhou S, Shen J, Jiang H, Chen Y, Tang R, Yan L. Study on the Central Neural Pathways Connecting the Brain and Peripheral Acupoints Using Neural Tracers. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2025;31:e70554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12322693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40762123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo YT, Lam JL, Jiang L, Lam WL, Edgerton VR, Liu CY. Cervical spinal cord stimulation for treatment of upper limb paralysis: a narrative review. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2025;50:781&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39932700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davids M, Guerin B, Klein V, Wald LL. Optimization of MRI Gradient Coils With Explicit Peripheral Nerve Stimulation Constraints. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2021;40:129&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7772273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian H, Wang Y, Ji Y, Rahman MM. [Fully Automatic Glioma Segmentation Algorithm of Magnetic Resonance Imaging Based on 3D-UNet With More Global Contextual Feature Extraction: An Improvement on Insufficient Extraction of Global Features] Sichuan Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. 2024;55:447&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11026905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38645864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugimoto YA, Yadohisa H, Abe MS. Network structure influences self-organized criticality in neural networks with dynamical synapses. Front Syst Neurosci. 2025;19:1590743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12213684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40606012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Fei Z, Xie Y, Deng D, Ming X, Niu F. A review of acupoint localization based on deep learning. Chin Med. 2025;20:116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12281682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40696423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vachha B, Huang SY. MRI with ultrahigh field strength and high-performance gradients: challenges and opportunities for clinical neuroimaging at 7 T and beyond. Eur Radiol Exp. 2021;5:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34435246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang G, Chen X, Liao C. AI-Driven Wearable Bioelectronics in Digital Healthcare. Biosensors (Basel) 2025;15:410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12294109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40710060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitri P, Savage MO. Artificial intelligence in paediatric endocrinology: conflict or cooperation. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2024;37:209&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38183676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano M, Fratini A, Gargiulo GD, Cesarelli M, Iuppariello L, Bifulco P. On the Power Spectrum of Motor Unit Action Potential Trains Synchronized With Mechanical Vibration. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2018;26:646&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29522409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du J, Luo S, Shi P. A Wearable EMG-Driven Closed-Loop TENS Platform for Real-Time, Personalized Pain Modulation. Sensors (Basel) 2025;25:5113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12390560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40871975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tryggestad JB, Willi SM. Complications and comorbidities of T2DM in adolescents: findings from the TODAY clinical trial. J Diabetes Complications. 2015;29:307&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4333013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25468310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarr AW, Backx M, Hamed MR, Urbanowicz RA, McClure CP, Brown RJP, Ball JK. Immunization with a synthetic consensus hepatitis C virus E2 glycoprotein ectodomain elicits virus-neutralizing antibodies. Antiviral Res. 2018;160:25&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30217650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu FJ, Wu J, Gong LJ, Yang HS, Chen H. Non-invasive vagus nerve stimulation in anti-inflammatory therapy: mechanistic insights and future perspectives. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:1490300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11599236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39605787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staats PS, Staats A, Mikhaiel B, Chen J, Azabou E, Rangon CM. Combined minimally invasive vagal cranial nerve and trigeminocervical complex peripheral nerve stimulation produces prolonged improvement of severe painful peripheral neuropathy and hyperglycemia in type 2 diabetes. Front Neurosci. 2025;19:1644961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12418259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40933195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y. Applying auricular magnetic therapy to decrease blood glucose levels and promote the healing of gangrene in diabetes patients: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2024;18:636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11668058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39716230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Li R, Chen Y, Yang H, Fitzgerald M, Wang Q, Xu Z, Huang N, Lu D, Luo L. Integration of traditional, complementary, and alternative medicine with modern biomedicine: the scientization, evidence, and challenges for integration of traditional Chinese medicine. Acupunct Herb Med. 2024;4:68&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>