<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41826658</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute physiological and pupillary responses during power snatch and clean &amp; jerk training sessions in elite female weightlifters.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-44315-9</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>I&#x15f;&#x131;k</LastName><ForeName>B&#xfc;lent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8753-8302</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Physiology, Medical School, University of Karamano&#x11f;lu Mehmetbey, Karaman, 70200, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Da&#x15f;delen</LastName><ForeName>Dervi&#x15f;</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2378-8780</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Physiology, Medical School, University of Karamano&#x11f;lu Mehmetbey, Karaman, 70200, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zbay</LastName><ForeName>Erkan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8781-3877</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Karamano&#x11f;lu Mehmetbey University Vocational School of Health, Karaman, 70200, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osmano&#x11f;lu</LastName><ForeName>Usame &#xd6;mer</ForeName><Initials>U&#xd6;</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1198-2447</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Biostatistics, Medical School, University of Karamano&#x11f;lu Mehmetbey, Karaman, 70200, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Erda&#x11f;&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>Kenan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2338-6546</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Physical Education and Sports, Ahmet Kele&#x15f;o&#x11f;lu Faculty of Education, Necmettin Erbakan University, Konya, 42090, Turkey. k.erdagi@erbakan.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamic response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Olympic weightlifting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performing athlete health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physiological monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pupil diameter</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval: The research was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki38. The Institutional Review Board approved the study (Karamano&#x11f;lu Mehmetbey University Medicine Faculty Scientific Ethics Committee; approval number 05-2023/19; June1, 2023), and written informed consent was obtained from the weightlifters. Informed consent for the publication of identifiable images in an online open-access publication was obtained from all participants whose photographs appear in the manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41826658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-44315-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-44315-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Erda&#x11f;&#x131;, K. Olimpik Halter E&#x11f;itimi ve A&#x11f;&#x131;rl&#x131;k Antrenmanlar&#x131;nda &#xc7;al&#x131;&#x15f;an Kas Gruplar&#x131; (Muscle Groups Working in Olympic Weightlifting Training and Weight Training). Ed.; Erda&#x11f;&#x131; K. T&#xfc;rk E&#x11f;itim Yay&#x131;nlar&#x131;, 2nd ed., Ni&#x11f;de, Turkey; ; p:10&#x2013;51, (In Turkish). (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry, A. C. et al. Anthropometric and performance variables discriminating elite American junior men weightlifters. J. Strength. Cond Res. 20 (4), 861&#x2013;866 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano, M. A., Suchomel, T. J. &amp; Comfort, P. Weightlifting overhead pressing derivatives: a review of the literature. Sports Med. 49 (6), 867&#x2013;885 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel, T. J., Comfort, P. &amp; Lake, J. P. Enhancing the force-velocity profile of athletes using weightlifting derivatives. Strength. Conditioning J. 39 (1), 10&#x2013;20 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storey, A. &amp; Smith, H. K. Unique aspects of competitive weightlifting: performance, training and physiology. Sports Med. 42 (9), 769&#x2013;790 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, J. H., Haskell, W., Snell, P. &amp; Van Camp, S. P. Task Force 8: classification of sports. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 45 (8), 1364&#x2013;1367 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiler, S. What is best practice for training intensity and duration distribution in endurance athletes? Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 5 (3), 276&#x2013;291 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shookster, D., Lindsey, B., Cortes, N. &amp; Martin, J. R. Accuracy of commonly used age-predicted maximal heart rate equations. Int. Exerc. Sci. 13 (7), 1242&#x2013;1250 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verschuren, O., Maltais, D. B. &amp; Takken, T. The 220-age equation does not predict maximum heart rate in children and adolescents. Dev. Med. Child. Neurol. 53 (9), 861&#x2013;864 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolaidis, P. T., Rosemann, T. &amp; Knechtle, B. Age-predicted maximal heart rate in recreational marathon runners: a cross-sectional study on Fox&#x2019;s and Tanaka&#x2019;s equations. Front. Physiol. 9, 226 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicone, Z. S., Holmes, C. J., Fedewa, M. V., MacDonald, H. V. &amp; Esco, M. R. Age-based prediction of maximal heart rate in children and adolescents: A systematic review and meta-analysis. RQES 2019;90(3):417&#x2013;428. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branco, B. H. M. et al. Maximum heart rate predicted by formulas versus values obtained in graded exercise tests in Brazilian jiu-jitsu athletes. Sport Sci. Health. 16, 39&#x2013;45 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 41 (3), 687&#x2013;708 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chodzko-Zajko, W. J. et al. American college of sports medicine position stand. exercise and physical activity for older adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 41 (7), 1510&#x2013;1530 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone, M. H., Pierce, K. C., Sands, W. A. &amp; Stone, M. E. Weightlifting: program design. Strength. Conditioning J. 28 (2), 10&#x2013;17 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce, K. C., Hornsby, W. G. &amp; Stone, M. H. Weightlifting for children and adolescents: a narrative review. Sports Health. 14 (1), 45&#x2013;56 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan, B., Hawley, J. A., Zierath, J. R. &amp; SnapShot Exerc. Metabolism Cell. Metab. ;24(2):342&#x2013;342e341. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillon, N. J., Bilan, P. J., Fink, L. N. &amp; Klip, A. Cross-talk between skeletal muscle and immune cells: muscle-derived mediators and metabolic implications. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 304 (5), E453&#x2013;465 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo, J. J., Izquierdo, M. &amp; Gorostiaga, E. M. Moderate volume of high relative training intensity produces greater strength gains compared with low and high volumes in competitive weightlifters. J. Strength. Cond Res. 20 (1), 73&#x2013;81 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman, J. R., Cooper, J., Wendell, M. &amp; Kang, J. Comparison of Olympic vs. traditional power lifting training programs in football players. J. Strength. Cond Res. 18 (1), 129&#x2013;135 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poletaev, P. &amp; Cervera, V. O. The Russian approach to planning a weightlifting program. Strength. Conditioning J. 17 (1), 20&#x2013;26 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes, J. P. et al. What influence does resistance exercise order have on muscular strength gains and muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 21 (2), 149&#x2013;157 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang, D. J., Koo, J. H., Kim, T. K., Jang, Y. C. &amp; Cho, J. Y. Heart rate recovery as a critical determinant in weightlifting. J. Korean Appl. Sci. Technol. 40 (6), 1340&#x2013;1349 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furrer, R., Hawley, J. A. &amp; Handschin, C. The molecular athlete: exercise physiology from mechanisms to medals. Physiol. Rev. 103 (3), 1693&#x2013;1787 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I&#x15f;&#x131;k, B. &amp; Erda&#x11f;&#x131;, K. Investigation of Trapezius Muscle Strength in Elite and Sub-Elite Female Weightlifters. J. Gen. Med. 33 (1), 87&#x2013;94 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi, N. &amp; Someya, N. Muscle metaboreflex activation by static exercise dilates pupil in humans. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 111 (6), 1217&#x2013;1221 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwamizu, R. et al. Pupil-linked arousal with very light exercise: pattern of pupil dilation during graded exercise. J. Physiol. Sci. 72 (1), 23 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zen, G., Atar, &#xd6;., Yurdakul, H. &#xd6;., Pehlivan, B. &amp; Ko&#xe7;, H. The effect of pre-season football training on hematological parameters of well-trained young male football players. Pedagogy Phys. Cult. Sports. 24 (6), 303&#x2013;309 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzun, M. Cardiovascular System and Exercise. Turk. J. Card Nur. 7 (60), 48&#x2013;53 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xe9;non, A., Sidib&#xe9;, M. &amp; Olivier, E. Pupil size variations correlate with physical effort perception. Front. Behav. Neurosci. 8, 286 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, S. &amp; Gold, J. I. Pupil size as a window on neural substrates of cognition. Trends Cogn. Sci. 24 (6), 466&#x2013;480 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwamizu, R. et al. Pupil dynamics during very light exercise predict benefits to prefrontal cognition. NeuroImage 277, 120244 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clau&#xdf;en, L. &amp; Heidelbach, T. Resistance exercising on unstable surface leads to Pupil Dilation. BMC Sports Sc&#x131; Med. R. 16 (1), 62 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A&#x11f;ar, E. &#x130;nsan Fizyolojisi (Human Physiology). Ed.; A&#x11f;ar E. &#x130;stanbul T&#x131;p Kitabevleri 1st edn, Vol., 593&#x2013;604 (&#x130;stanbul, 2021). (In Turkish).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megemont, M., McBurney-Lin, J. &amp; Yang, H. Pupil diameter is not an accurate real-time readout of locus coeruleus activity. Elife 11, e70510 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi, N., Someya, N. &amp; Fukuba, Y. Effect of intensity of dynamic exercise on pupil diameter in humans. J. Physiol. Anthropol. 29, 119&#x2013;122 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, P., Wittekind, A. &amp; Beneke, R. Amateur boxing: activity profile of winners and losers. Int. J. Sports Physiol. Perform. 8 (1), 84&#x2013;91 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. Declaration of Helsinki. ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA 310, 2191&#x2013;2194 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul, F., Erdfelder, E., Lang, A. G. &amp; Buchner, A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav. Res. Methods. 39 (2), 175&#x2013;191 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliva, F., Marsilio, E., Cuozzo, F. &amp; Maffulli, N. Quadriceps tendon tears rehabilitation: a narrative review of the literature. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 13 (4), 667&#x2013;676. https://doi.org/10.32098/mltj.04.2023.20 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, J. A power primer. Ed. Kazdin AE. Methodological issues &amp; strategies in clinical research 3rd edn, p: 427&#x2013;436 (American Psychological Association, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar, A. et al. Temporal specificity of training: intra-day effects on biochemical responses and Olympic-Weightlifting performances. J. Sports Sci. 33 (4), 358&#x2013;368 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird, S. P., Tarpenning, K. M. &amp; Marino, F. E. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness: a review of the acute programme variables. Sports Med. 35 (10), 841&#x2013;851 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdez-Lowe, C., Ghareeb, S. A. &amp; Artinian, N. T. Pulse oximetry in adults. Am. J. Nurs. 109 (6), 52&#x2013;59 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sund-Levander, M. &amp; Grodzinsky, E. Assessment of body temperature measurement options. Br. J. Nurs. 2 (16), 944&#x2013;950 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ak&#xe7;a, H. &#x15e;. et al. Effect of ipratropium inhalation on pupil dilatation in rats. Eurasian J. Emerg. Med. 20, 39&#x2013;42 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napoli, R. et al. Cross cultural adaptation and multi centric validation of the Italian version of the tegner activity scale. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 13 (1), 156&#x2013;162. https://doi.org/10.32098/mltj.01.2023.18 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo, T. K. &amp; Li, M. Y. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J. Chiropr. Med. 15 (2), 155&#x2013;163. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcm.2016.02.012 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober, P., Boer, C. &amp; Schwarte, L. Correlation coefficients: Appropriate use and interpretation. Anesth. Analgesia. 126 (5), 1763&#x2013;1768. https://doi.org/10.1213/ANE.0000000000002864 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa, G. F. et al. More training, less trainability: true? a muscle swelling analysis. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 14 (3), 402&#x2013;409. https://doi.org/10.32098/mltj.03.2024.03 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuli&#x15b;, S., Pietraszewski, P. &amp; Callegari, B. Characteristics of post-exercise lower limb muscle tremor among speed skaters. Sensors 25 (14), 4301. https://doi.org/10.3390/s25144301 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr, E. et al. In Sensor-based vital sign monitoring, analysis and visualisation for ageing in place. In: 2018 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), (IEEE, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner, M. J. &amp; Casey, D. P. Regulation of increased blood flow (hyperemia) to muscles during exercise: a hierarchy of competing physiological needs. Physiol. Rev. 95 (2), 549&#x2013;601 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyton, A. C. &amp; Hall, J. E. Textbook of Medical Physiology, 11. Ed.; Saunders: Philadelphia, PA, 19103&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;2899, USA, ; p:74&#x2013;88, 106&#x2013;122, 244&#x2013;258, 259&#x2013;270, 773&#x2013;785, 1082&#x2013;1096. ISBN: 978-1-4557-7005-2 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suna, G. &amp; Alp, M. Comparison of strength, heart rate, oxygen saturation and technical test values of 12&#x2013;14 Year male tennis players in competition period. J. Educ. Learn. 8 (6), 187&#x2013;194 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez, J., Mendez-Villanueva, A. &amp; Pluim, B. M. Intensity of tennis match play. Br. J. Sports Med. 40 (5), 387&#x2013;391 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic, G., Vucetic, V. &amp; Cardinale, M. Heart rate and lactate responses to taekwondo fight in elite women performers. Biology sport. 25 (2), 135 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchheit, M. &amp; Gindre, C. Cardiac parasympathetic regulation: respective associations with cardiorespiratory fitness and training load. Am. J. Physiol. Heart Circ. Physiol. 291 (1), H451&#x2013;458 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen, S. E., Barber, S. J., Chai, A., Clewett, D. V. &amp; Mather, M. Sympathetic arousal increases a negative memory bias in young women with low sex hormone levels. Psyneuen 62, 96&#x2013;106 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mather, M. et al. Isometric exercise facilitates attention to salient events in women via the noradrenergic system. Neuroimage 210, 116560 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adler, Y. et al. Left ventricular diastolic function in trained male weightlifters at rest and during isometric exercise. Am. J. Cardiol. 102 (1), 97&#x2013;101 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalande, S. &amp; Baldi, J. C. Left ventricular mass in elite olympic weightlifters. Am. J. Cardiol. 100 (7), 1177&#x2013;1180 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padulo, J. et al. Acute effects of whole-body vibration on running gait in marathon runners. J. Sports Sci. 32 (12), 1120&#x2013;1126 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdo&#x11f;du, M. et al. The effects of acute moderate intensity training on hematological parameters in elite para-badminton athletes. J. Men&#x2019;s Health. 18 (2), 1&#x2013;8 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barclay, C. J. Energy demand and supply in human skeletal muscle. J. Muscle Res. Cell. Motil. 38 (2), 143&#x2013;155 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermawan, R. &amp; Priyono, D. Anthropometry and anaerobic exercise to aerobic athletes in weightlifting athletes. Adv. Health Exerc. 2, 38&#x2013;44 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastin, P. B. Energy system interaction and relative contribution during maximal exercise. Sports Med. 31, 725&#x2013;741. https://doi.org/10.2165/00007256-200131100-00003 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengtsson, V., Berglund, L. &amp; Aasa, U. Narrative review of injuries in powerlifting with special reference to their association to the squat, bench press and deadlift. BMJ Open. Sport Exerc. Med. 4, e000382 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler, P. C., Dudson, C. &amp; Calver, R. Radial extracorporeal shockwave therapy (rESWT) is non-superior to minimal-dose rESWT for patients with chronic patella tendinopathy: a double-blinded randomized controlled trial. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 13 (4), 531&#x2013;540. https://doi.org/10.32098/mltj.04.2023.03 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pipino, G. et al. Rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: dry land vs aquatic rehabilitation. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 13 (3), 421&#x2013;429. https://doi.org/10.32098/mltj.03.2023.10 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Onofrio, R., Alashram, A. R., Annino, G., Sannicandro, I. &amp; Manzi, V. The Interval Kicking Program (IKP) as a Reprogramming Technique for the Soccer Player in an Anterior Cruciate Ligament (ACL) Rehabilitation: A Technical Report. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J, ;13(4), 541&#x2013;549. (2023). https://doi.org/10.32098/mltj.04.2023.04</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frizziero, A. et al. Changes in proprioceptive control in the menstrual cycle: a risk factor for injuries? a proof-of-concept study. Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 13 (3), 360&#x2013;367. https://doi.org/10.32098/mltj.03.2023.02 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x131;l&#x131;ncarslan, &#xd6;. &amp; Erda&#x11f;&#x131;, S. A review study on Olympic weightlifting. J. Sport Sci. Innov. (JOSSI). 1 (1), 54&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.65668/r52yeh19 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x131;r, R., Civan, A. H., Co&#x15f;kun, F., K&#x131;l&#x131;ncarslan, Z. &amp; Garc&#xed;a-V&#xe1;zquez, J. F. Handgrip strength in female olympic-style weightlifters: an investigation of its associations with competitive level, performance, and anthropometric characteristics. J. Sport Sci. Innov. (JOSSI). 1 (1), 1&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.65668/3vpa1654 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x131;r, R., Uzun, M. E., Garc&#xed;a-V&#xe1;zquez, J. F. &amp; &#xdc;nl&#xfc;, S. Comparison of pinch strength andits relationship with performance and demographic variables in elite female weightlifters. J. Sport Sci. Innov. (JOSSI). 1 (1), 16&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.65668/4rxn6e49 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raiola, G., Esposito, G., Aliberti, S., D&#x2019;Isanto, T. &amp; D&#x2019;Elia, F. University education for physical education teachers, sports and preventive and adapted physical activities kinesiologists and sports manager. Acta Kinesiologica. 17 (1), 55&#x2013;59 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>