<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41509878</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2574-0954</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cardiovascular endocrinology &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Autonomic dysfunction and insulin resistance in type 2 diabetes mellitus with hypoglycemia unawareness: an observational study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e00354</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e00354</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e00354</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/XCE.0000000000000354</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To evaluate the association between hypoglycemia unawareness, cardiac autonomic function, and insulin resistance in individuals with type2 diabetes, and explore potential correlations between autonomic dysfunction and metabolic parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">50 individuals with type2 diabetes (age 50-65 years, duration &gt;5 years) were recruited and classified into two groups using Clarke's Hypoglycemia Awareness Questionnaire: hypoglycemia unawareness group (<i>n</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;25) and controls (<i>n</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;25). Standardized cardiovascular autonomic function tests (AFTs) and short-term heart rate variability (HRV) analyses were performed. Autonomic dysfunction was graded using Ewing's, Bellavere's, and All India Institute of Medical Sciences AFT Lab criteria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The hypoglycemia unawareness group exhibited significantly lower Valsalva ratio (1.49&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;0.31) vs. the control group (1.80 &#xb1;&#x2005;0.42) (<i>P</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.004), and reduced diastolic blood pressure (BP) response during the cold pressor test (10.92&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;9.81&#x2005;mmHg) vs. the control group (18.36&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;8.50&#x2005;mmHg) (<i>P</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.001). A greater fall in systolic BP during postural change was also noted (11.08&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;6.38&#x2005;mmHg) vs. the control group (7.64&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;3.53&#x2005;mmHg) (<i>P</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.037). HRV indices like SD of all <i>N</i>-<i>N</i> intervals and total power were reduced in hypoglycemia-unawareness individuals, indicating impaired sympatho-vagal modulation. Fasting glucose was significantly higher in hypoglycemia-unawareness individuals (114.36&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;11.81) vs. the control group (106.44&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;13.11) (<i>P</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.021), but no significant difference in homeostatic model assessment for insulin resistance was observed. Serum insulin levels showed negative correlations with sympathetic function measures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Hypoglycemia unawareness in T2DM is associated with combined sympathetic and parasympathetic dysfunction and reduced HRV, consistent with a hypoglycemia-associated autonomic failure cycle. Routine autonomic assessment may aid in early detection, risk stratification, and prevention of adverse cardiovascular outcomes in this high-risk subgroup.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nandi</LastName><ForeName>Debarshi</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Himalayan Institute of Medical Sciences, Swami Rama Himalayan University, Dehradun, Uttarakhand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Supriya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, School of Medical Sciences and Research, Sharda University, Greater Noida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ajmera</LastName><ForeName>Nasar</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Teerthankar Mahaveer Medical College and Research Centre, Moradabad, Uttar Pradesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Selvaraj</LastName><ForeName>Ramkumar</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Himalayan Institute of Medical Sciences, Swami Rama Himalayan University, Dehradun, Uttarakhand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gulati</LastName><ForeName>Sameer</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Lady Hardinge Medical College.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaheer</LastName><ForeName>Sufian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Vardhaman Mahavir Medical College and Hospital, New Delhi, Delhi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomar</LastName><ForeName>Akash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Kasturba Medical College Manipal, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101730894</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2574-0954</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic function testing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac autonomic neuropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular risk stratification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoglycemia unawareness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41509878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12778135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/XCE.0000000000000354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">CAEN-D-25-00043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Magliano DJ, Boyko EJ, Committee IDA 10<sup>th</sup> Edition Scientific. Global picture. In: &gt;Magliano DJ, Boyko EJ, editors. IDF DIABETES ATLAS. 10th ed. International Diabetes Federation. 2021. 
https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK581940/. [Accessed 29 July 2025]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradeepa R, Mohan V. Epidemiology of type 2 diabetes in India. Indian J Ophthalmol 2021; 69:2932&#x2013;2938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8725109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34708726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinik AI, Erbas T, Casellini CM. Diabetic cardiac autonomic neuropathy, inflammation and cardiovascular disease. J Diabetes Investig 2013; 4:4&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3580884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23550085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBouef T, Yaker Z, Whited L. Physiology, autonomic nervous system. StatPearls Publishing. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30860751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis MJ, Short AL, Lewis KE. Autonomic nervous system control of the cardiovascular and respiratory systems in asthma. Respir Med 2006; 100:1688&#x2013;1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16524708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomar A, Ahluwalia H, Ramkumar S, Pattnaik S, Nandi D, Raturi P. The interplay of heart rate variability and ventricular repolarization parameters in the obese state: a review. Cardiovasc Endocrinol Metab. 2025; 14:e00323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11723674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39802372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Tim&#xf3;n I, del Ca&#xf1;izo-G&#xf3;mez FJ. Mechanisms of hypoglycemia unawareness and implications in diabetic patients. World J Diabetes 2015; 6:912&#x2013;926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4499525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26185599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartill E, Gillis RB, Imran Jiwani S, Recchia N, Meal A, Adams GG. Hypoglycaemic unawareness: a systematic review of qualitative studies of significant others&#x2019; (SO) supportive interventions for patients with diabetes mellitus. Heliyon 2018; 4:e00887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30417151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cryer PE. Mechanisms of hypoglycemia-associated autonomic failure and its component syndromes in diabetes. Diabetes 2005; 54:3592&#x2013;3601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16306382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heald AH, Narayanan RP, Lowes D, Jarman E, Onyekwelu E, Qureshi Z, et al. HOMA-S is associated with greater HbA1c reduction with a GLP-1 analogue in patients with type 2 diabetes. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes 2012; 120:420&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22639398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohm TV, Meier DT, Olefsky JM, Donath MY. Inflammation in obesity, diabetes and related disorders. Immunity 2022; 55:31&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8773457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35021057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papaioannou VE, Pneumatikos I, Maglaveras N. Association of heart rate variability and inflammatory response in patients with cardiovascular diseases: current strengths and limitations. Front Physiol 2013; 4:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3706751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23847549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivieri F, Biscetti L, Pimpini L, Pelliccioni G, Sabbatinelli J, Giunta S. Heart rate variability and autonomic nervous system imbalance: potential biomarkers and detectable hallmarks of aging and inflammaging. Ageing Res Rev 2024; 101:102521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39341508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yugar LBT, Yugar-Toledo JC, Dinamarco N, Sedenho-Prado LG, Moreno BVD, Rubio T de A, et al. The role of heart rate variability (HRV) in different hypertensive syndromes. Diagnostics 2023; 13:785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9955360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36832273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke WL, Cox DJ, Gonder-Frederick LA, Julian D, Schlundt D, Polonsky W. Reduced awareness of hypoglycemia in adults with IDDM: a prospective study of hypoglycemic frequency and associated symptoms. Diabetes Care 1995; 18:517&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7497862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryder RE, Owens DR, Hayes TM, Ghatei MA, Bloom SR. Unawareness of hypoglycaemia and inadequate hypoglycaemic counterregulation: no causal relation with diabetic autonomic neuropathy. BMJ 1990; 301:783&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1663909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2224265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomar A, Ahluwalia H, Isser HS, Gulati S, Kumar P, Yadav I. Analysis of ventricular repolarization parameters and heart rate variability in obesity: a comparative study. Sci Rep 2024; 14:25855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11519358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39468214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews DR, Hosker JP, Rudenski AS, Naylor BA, Treacher DF, Turner RC. Homeostasis model assessment: insulin resistance and beta-cell function from fasting plasma glucose and insulin concentrations in man. Diabetologia 1985; 28:412&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3899825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heller SR, Macdonald IA, Herbert M, Tattersall RB. Influence of sympathetic nervous system on hypoglycaemic warning symptoms. Lancet (London, England) 1987; 2:359&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2886822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman R, Chapleau MW. Chapter 7 &#x2013; testing the autonomic nervous system. In: Said G, Krarup C, editors. Handbook of clinical neurology. Vol. 115. Elsevier; 2013. pp. 115&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23931777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cichosz SL, Frystyk J, Tarnow L, Fleischer J. Are changes in heart rate variability during hypoglycemia confounded by the presence of cardiovascular autonomic neuropathy in patients with diabetes? Diabetes Technol Ther 2017; 19:91&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28118049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeva-Andany MM, Mart&#xed;nez-Rodr&#xed;guez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Luc&#xe1;n M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Fern&#xe1;ndez C, Castro-Quintela E. Insulin resistance is a cardiovascular risk factor in humans. Diabetes Metab Syndr 2019; 13:1449&#x2013;1455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31336505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schloot NC, Haupt A, Sch&#xfc;tt M, Badenhoop K, Laimer M, Nicolay C, et al. Risk of severe hypoglycemia in sulfonylurea-treated patients from diabetes centers in Germany/Austria: how big is the problem? Which patients are at risk? Diabetes Metab Res Rev 2016; 32:316&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26409039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob G, Diedrich L, Sato K, Brychta RJ, Raj SR, Robertson D, et al. Vagal and sympathetic function in neuropathic postural tachycardia syndrome. Hypertension 2019; 73:1087&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6592426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JW, Okamoto LE, Kim SH, Baek SH, Sung JH, Jeon N, et al. Use of Valsalva maneuver to detect late-onset delayed orthostatic hypotension. Hypertension 2023; 80:792&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10023507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36695176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonete G, Dias BAL, Leandro DAM, Fernandes ATNSF, Pereira CH, Ribeiro CTD, et al. Impaired heart rate variability, Valsalva and 30:15 ratio indexes are associated with reduced submaximal exercise capacity in subjects with diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2019; 155:107813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31408665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruter RH, Eizirik DL, Gross JL. Relationship of the Valsalva ratio to autonomic neuropathy and other complications of diabetes mellitus. Braz J Med Biol Res 1982; 15:35&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7150819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond V, Curry BH, Adams RG, Obisesan T, Pemminati S, Gorantla VR, et al. Cardiovascular responses to an isometric handgrip exercise in females with prehypertension. N Am J Med Sci 2016; 8:243&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4960933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27500128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown CM, Marthol H, Zikeli U, Ziegler D, Hilz MJ. A simple deep breathing test reveals altered cerebral autoregulation in type 2 diabetic patients. Diabetologia 2008; 51:756&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18309474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridhar B, Haleagrahara N, Bhat R, Kulur AB, Avabratha S, Adhikary P. Increase in the heart rate variability with deep breathing in diabetic patients after 12-month exercise training. Tohoku J Exp Med 2010; 220:107&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunutsor SK, Voutilainen A, Laukkanen JA. Handgrip strength improves prediction of type 2 diabetes: a prospective cohort study. Ann Med 2020; 52:471&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32840381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;rei AE, Kempler M, Istenes I, V&#xe1;gi OE, Putz Z, Horv&#xe1;th VJ, et al. Why not to use the handgrip test in the assessment of cardiovascular autonomic neuropathy among patients with diabetes mellitus? Curr Vasc Pharmacol 2017; 15:66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27550055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedorowski A, Gibbons C. Orthostatic hypotension and diabetes are dangerous companions. J Diabetes Complications 2016; 30:5&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26601788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontoni S, Bracaglia D, Gigli F. Relationship between autonomic dysfunction, insulin resistance and hypertension, in diabetes. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis 2005; 15:441&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16314230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh R, Pandurangan V, Madhavan S, Srinivasan D, Bhaskar E, Marappa L, et al. Comparison of fasting insulin level, homeostatic model of insulin resistance, and lipid levels between patients with primary hypertension and normotensive subjects. Rambam Maimonides Med J 2022; 13:e0009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9049152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35482462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton WB, Love KM, Gregory JM, Liu Z, Barrett EJ. Metabolic and vascular insulin resistance: partners in the pathogenesis of cardiovascular disease in diabetes. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 2025; 328:H1218&#x2013;H1236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12172477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40257392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobato NS, Filgueira FP, Akamine EH, Tostes RC, Carvalho MHC, Fortes ZB. Mechanisms of endothelial dysfunction in obesity-associated hypertension. Braz J Med Biol Res 2012; 45:392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3854291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22488221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman AM, Acevedo LA, Pennings N. Insulin resistance. StatPearls Publishing. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29939616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>