<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41930519</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3336</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>508</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hazardous materials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hazard Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Text mining and machine learning based health risk prediction for soil polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons at typical coal-fired industrial sites in china.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>141934</StartPage><MedlinePgn>141934</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2026.141934</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0304-3894(26)00912-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) are persistent organic pollutants posing significant threats to the environment and human health, particularly at active coal-fired industrial sites (coking, steel smelting, and thermal electric power generation) in China. However, for active industrial enterprises, effectively predicting PAHs exposure risks at the national scale remains challenging due to spatial uncertainty of contamination distribution and difficulties in the acquisition of large-scale monitoring data. This study introduces a multidisciplinary framework integrating text mining, probabilistic risk assessment, and machine learning to predict and assess health risks of PAHs in soils at these active industrial sites. Text mining extracted comprehensive PAHs-related data from literature, forming a national database with over 1600 entries. Probabilistic risk assessment with Monte Carlo simulation (1000 iterations per sample) revealed that 32% of historically reported sites in the text-mined database exceeded the acceptable target risk (ATR = 1&#x202f;&#xd7;10<sup>-6</sup>), with benzo[a]pyrene (BaP) and dibenzo[a,h]anthracene (DahA) emerging as primary risk drivers, while non-carcinogenic risks were mostly below safety thresholds (hazard quotient &lt; 1). Four machine learning algorithms including Support Vector Machine (SVM), Random Forest (RF), Extreme Gradient Boosting (XGBoost), and Light Gradient Boosting Machine (LightGBM) were evaluated for risk classification, with LightGBM achieving optimal performance (accuracy: 98.88%, ROC-AUC: 1.0000). Feature importance analysis identified enterprise insured population, regional atmospheric CO concentration, and particulate emission limits as key predictors. National-scale prediction for 1263 sites identified 15.30% exceeding the ATR, predominantly concentrated in eastern and central China. Industry-specific analysis showed coking plants (39.40%) and steel smelting facilities (38.00%) exhibited higher proportions of sites exceeding the ATR than thermal power plants (22.60%), reflecting process-specific PAHs generation patterns. This framework provides an efficient, scalable approach for PAHs risk assessment and management at coal-fired sites in China, offering a replicable model for similar environmental challenges globally.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Soil and Sustainable Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 211135, China; Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory for Soil and Groundwater Remediation of Contaminated Sites, Institute of Soil Science, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Hanyuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Environment, Zhejiang University of Technology, Hangzhou 310014, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Mengfang</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Soil and Sustainable Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 211135, China; University of Chinese Academy of Science, Beijing 100049, China; Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory for Soil and Groundwater Remediation of Contaminated Sites, Institute of Soil Science, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 210008, China. Electronic address: mfchen@issas.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Zhanfei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Environment, Zhejiang University of Technology, Hangzhou 310014, China. Electronic address: zhanfeihe@zjut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Yufei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Soil and Sustainable Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 211135, China; University of Chinese Academy of Science, Beijing 100049, China; Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory for Soil and Groundwater Remediation of Contaminated Sites, Institute of Soil Science, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Yudong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Soil and Sustainable Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 211135, China; Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory for Soil and Groundwater Remediation of Contaminated Sites, Institute of Soil Science, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 210008, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Soil and Sustainable Agriculture, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Nanjing 211135, China; Nanjing Kaiye Environmental Technology Co Ltd, Nanjing 210034, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Ya</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory of Regional Polluted Environment Ecological Restoration, Shenyang University, Shenyang 110000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zou</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environmental Studies, China University of Geosciences, Wuhan 430078, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Hazard Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9422688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-3894</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coal-fired industrial sites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health risk assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PAHs pollution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Text mining</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41930519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2026.141934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0304-3894(26)00912-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>