<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41557693</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improved one-dimensional residual network high-voltage DC diagnosis for high-precision fault identification.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0341115</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0341115</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0341115</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0341115</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>High-Voltage Direct Current (HVDC) transmission systems require fast and reliable fault diagnosis to ensure secure and stable operation. However, existing methods, including conventional Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), often suffer from limited accuracy and degraded training performance as network depth increases. To address these limitations, this study proposes an improved one-dimensional Residual Neural Network (1D-ResNet) that integrates an attention mechanism within the residual blocks to enhance feature extraction, stabilize gradient propagation, and accelerate model convergence. A comprehensive simulated HVDC platform is established to generate multiple fault scenarios, and the proposed network is trained to identify one normal condition and six typical fault types. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed method achieves an average diagnostic accuracy of 99.15%, outperforming traditional CNN-based approaches by 12.89%. Moreover, the loss value is significantly lower than that of the conventional CNN model, indicating substantial improvements in both robustness and learning efficiency. These findings confirm the effectiveness of the proposed attention-enhanced residual framework for high-precision HVDC fault diagnosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Li et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-8756-6491</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Shanxi Electric Power Research Institute, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaopeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Shanxi Electric Power Research Institute, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hao</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Shanxi Electric Power Research Institute, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Shanxi Electric Power Research Institute, Taiyuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41557693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12818625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0341115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-33193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xiang W, Yang S, Adam GP, Zhang H, Zuo W, Wen J. DC fault protection algorithms of MMC-HVDC grids: fault analysis, methodologies, experimental validations, and future trends. IEEE Trans Power Electron. 2021;36(10):11245&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1109/tpel.2021.3071184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tpel.2021.3071184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahrman M, Johnson B. The ABCs of HVDC transmission technologies. IEEE Power and Energy Mag. 2007;5(2):32&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1109/mpae.2007.329194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/mpae.2007.329194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Song G, Wu L, Wei H, Guang S, Chao L. Novel reclosure scheme of MMC-HVDC system based on characteristic signal injection. J Eng. 2019;2019(16):1153&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1049/joe.2018.8869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/joe.2018.8869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Zhang Y, Wang S, Li X, Gooi HB, Ghias AMYM. Fault identification and fault location methods for VSC-HVDC transmission lines based on the traveling waveform difference. Inter J Elect Power Energy Syst. 2023;147:108867. doi: 10.1016/j.ijepes.2022.108867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2022.108867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Xiang W, Zhou M, Zuo W, Wen J. A single-end protection scheme for hybrid MMC HVDC grids considering the impacts of the active fault current-limiting control. IEEE Trans Power Delivery. 2021;36(4):2001&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1109/tpwrd.2020.3017895</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tpwrd.2020.3017895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao H, Li Y, Liu R, Duan X. Single-end time-domain transient electrical signals based protection principle and its efficient setting calculation method for LCC-HVDC lines. IET Generation Trans Dist. 2017;11(5):1233&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1049/iet-gtd.2016.1159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-gtd.2016.1159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzelepis D, Dysko A, Fusiek G, Nelson J, Niewczas P, Vozikis D, et al. Single-ended differential protection in MTDC networks using optical sensors. IEEE Trans Power Delivery. 2017;32(3):1605&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1109/tpwrd.2016.2645231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tpwrd.2016.2645231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu JJQ, Hou Y, Lam AYS, Li VOK. Intelligent fault detection scheme for microgrids with wavelet-based deep neural networks. IEEE Trans Smart Grid. 2019;10(2):1694&#x2013;703. doi: 10.1109/tsg.2017.2776310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tsg.2017.2776310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary B. An advanced genetic algorithm with improved support vector machine for multi-class classification of real power quality events. Elect Power Syst Res. 2021;191:106879. doi: 10.1016/j.epsr.2020.106879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2020.106879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayed Tassawar Hussain K, Song G, Wang T, Hou J, Masood B. Adaptive fault recovery strategy of LCC-MMC based hybrid HVDC. IET Generat Trans Dist. 2021;15(16):2396&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1049/gtd2.12186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/gtd2.12186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Yu Z, Xie F, Hao Z, Monti A, Ponci F. Protection of line faults in HVDC grids through convexity detection in backward traveling wave voltages. IEEE Trans Power Delivery. 2023;38(5):3660&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1109/tpwrd.2023.3286863</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tpwrd.2023.3286863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JM, Yadav A. Complete protection scheme for fault detection, classification and location estimation in HVDC transmission lines using support vector machines. IET Sci Measure Tech. 2017;11(3):279&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1049/iet-smt.2016.0244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-smt.2016.0244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou R, Wang Y. Transmission line fault identification based on BP neural network. In: 2019 IEEE innovative smart grid technologies-Asia (ISGT Asia). IEEE; 2019. 991&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moloi K, Yusuff AA. A Wavelet-neural network-based technique for fault diagnostics in power system. In: 2020 7th International conference on soft computing and machine intelligence (ISCMI), 2020. 131&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1109/iscmi51676.2020.9311601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iscmi51676.2020.9311601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Wang Q, Yu K, Hu X, Ran M. A novel intelligent fault identification method based on random forests for HVDC transmission lines. PLoS One. 2020;15(3):e0230717. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0230717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0230717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7098650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32214364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawad RS, Abid H. HVDC fault detection and classification with artificial neural network based on ACO-DWT method. Energies. 2023;16(3):1064. doi: 10.3390/en16031064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en16031064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verrax P, Bertinato A, Kieffer M, Raison B. Fast fault identification in bipolar HVDC grids: a fault parameter estimation approach. IEEE Trans Power Delivery. 2022;37(1):258&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1109/tpwrd.2021.3056876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tpwrd.2021.3056876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo MF, Yang NC, Chen WF. Deep-learning-based fault classification using hilbert&#x2013;huang transform and convolutional neural network in power distribution systems. IEEE Sensors J. 2019;19(16):6905&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1109/jsen.2019.2913006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jsen.2019.2913006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh MS, Lin H, Xie S, Dong X, Lin Y, Shiva CK, et al. An intelligent hybrid grey wolf-particle swarm optimizer for optimization in complex engineering design problem. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):18313. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-02154-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-02154-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12106706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40419534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh MS, Raj S, Babu R, Kumar S, Sagrolikar K. A hybrid moth&#x2013;flame algorithm with particle swarm optimization with application in power transmission and distribution. Decision Anal J. 2023;6:100182. doi: 10.1016/j.dajour.2023.100182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dajour.2023.100182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latif SA, Drieberg M, Sarang S, Abd A, Ahmad R, Stojanovic&#xb4; GM. A reinforcement learning based intelligent duty cycle MAC protocol for internet of things. IEEE Access. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Ding Q, Sun J-Q. Remaining useful life estimation in prognostics using deep convolution neural networks. Reliabil Eng Syst Saf. 2018;172:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.ress.2017.11.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ress.2017.11.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taye MM. Theoretical understanding of convolutional neural network: concepts, architectures, applications, future directions. Computation. 2023;11(3):52. doi: 10.3390/computation11030052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/computation11030052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Zhang X, Ren S, Sun J. Deep residual learning for image recognition. In: Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition, 2016. 770&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Y, Zhang Y, Chen F, Wang Z. Analog circuit incipient fault detection based on attention mechanism and fully convolutional network. IEEE Access. 2024;12:137247&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1109/access.2024.3403908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2024.3403908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>