<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41602206</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2673-253X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From abandonment to adoption: advancing assistive technologies for blindness and low vision in the AI era.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1719746</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1719746</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1719746</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fdgth.2025.1719746</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Assistive technologies can enhance safety, independence, and quality of life for people with blindness and low vision. Despite their benefits, abandonment of these technologies remains widespread, and recent research on this issue is limited. In this Perspective article, we draw on both professional experiences and relevant scientific literature to examine adoption and abandonment in the context of new artificial intelligence-powered applications. We highlight risks arising from misaligned design, inconsistent industry support, and inadequate user training. We synthesize existing knowledge on factors that influence abandonment and propose three priorities to realign assistive technology development: participatory and transdisciplinary research, integrated technology ecosystems, and socially supported engagement. Taken collectively, these priorities ensure that emerging assistive technologies better align with the needs of people with blindness and low vision, promoting lasting adoption rather than abandonment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Barak Ventura, Hamilton-Fletcher and Rizzo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barak Ventura</LastName><ForeName>Roni</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Applied Engineering and Technology, New Jersey Institute of Technology, Newark, NJ, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamilton-Fletcher</LastName><ForeName>Giles</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rizzo</LastName><ForeName>John-Ross</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, NYU Tandon School of Engineering, Brooklyn, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Urban Science and Progress, NYU Tandon School of Engineering, Brooklyn, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, NYU Tandon School of Engineering, Brooklyn, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101771889</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2673-253X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">assistive technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blindness and low vision</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">technology abandonment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">technology adoption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">user-centerd design</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41602206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12832816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2025.1719746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scherer MJ. Outcomes of assistive technology use on quality of life. Disabil Rehabil. (1996) 18(9):439&#x2013;48. 10.3109/09638289609165907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09638289609165907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8877302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosner Y, Perlman A. The effect of the usage of computer-based assistive devices on the functioning and quality of life of individuals who are blind or have low vision. J Vis Impair Blind. (2018) 112(1):87&#x2013;99. 10.1177/0145482X1811200108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0145482X1811200108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leporini B, Rosellini M, Forgione N. Designing assistive technology for getting more independence for blind people when performing everyday tasks: an auditory-based tool as a case study. J Ambient Intell Humaniz Comput. (2020) 11(12):6107&#x2013;23. 10.1007/s12652-020-01944-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12652-020-01944-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkstra LM, Bhatia T, Van Os A, Beyeler M. Assistive technology use in domestic activities by people who are blind. Sci Rep. (2025) 15(1):7486. 10.1038/s41598-025-91755-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-91755-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11876317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40032957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips B, Zhao H. Predictors of assistive technology abandonment. Assist Technol. (1993) 5(1):36&#x2013;45. 10.1080/10400435.1993.10132205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10400435.1993.10132205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10171664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos ADP, Ferrari ALM, Medola FO, Sandnes FE. Aesthetics and the perceived stigma of assistive technology for visual impairment. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2022) 17(2):152&#x2013;8. 10.1080/17483107.2020.1768308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2020.1768308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32501732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batavia AI, Hammer GS. Toward the development of consumer-based criteria for the evaluation of assistive devices. J Rehabil Res Dev. (1990) 27(4):425. 10.1682/JRRD.1990.10.0425</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1682/JRRD.1990.10.0425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2089152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler SLH, Vogel B, Hoenig H, Ripley DCC, Wu S, Fitzgerald SG, et al. Cost, utilization, and policy of provision of assistive technology devices to veterans poststroke by medicare and VA. Med Care. (2010) 48(6):558&#x2013;62. 10.1097/MLR.0b013e3181bd4a11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MLR.0b013e3181bd4a11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20125048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson D, Ehrlich N. Sources of payment for assistive technology: findings from a national survey of persons with disabilities. Assist Technol. (2006) 18(1):77&#x2013;86. 10.1080/10400435.2006.10131908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10400435.2006.10131908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16796243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Y, Magay A, Huang H, Yuan S, Wen C, Fang Y. Chatmap: a wearable platform based on the multi-modal foundation model to augment spatial cognition for people with blindness and low vision. In: 2024 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates: IEEE; (2024). p. 129&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waisberg E, Ong J, Masalkhi M, Zaman N, Sarker P, Lee AG, et al. Meta smart glasses&#x2014;large language models and the future for assistive glasses for individuals with vision impairments. Eye. (2024) 38(6):1036&#x2013;8. 10.1038/s41433-023-02842-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41433-023-02842-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11009354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38049627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui W, Li B, Yuan S, Rizzo JR, Sharma L, Feng C, et al. An assistive low-vision platform that augments spatial cognition through proprioceptive guidance: point-to-tell-and-touch. In: 2019 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS). Macau, China: IEEE; (2019). p. 3817&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang A, Beheshti M, Hudson TE, Vedanthan R, Riewpaiboon W, Mongkolwat P, et al. UNav: an infrastructure-independent vision-based navigation system for people with blindness and low vision. Sensors. (2022) 22(22):8894. 10.3390/s22228894</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22228894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9696753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36433501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang A, Tamkittikhun N, Hamilton-Fletcher G, Ramdhanie V, Vu T, Beheshti M, et al. Evaluating the efficacy of UNav: a computer vision-based navigation aid for persons with blindness or low vision. Assist Technol. (2024) 37(6):1&#x2013;15. 10.1080/10400435.2024.2382113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10400435.2024.2382113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11822047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39137956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrie H, Carmien S, Lewis A. Assistive technology abandonment: research realities and potentials. In: Bertino E, Gao W, Steffen B, Yung M, editors. Lecture Notes in Computer Science. Cham: Springer International Publishing; (2018). p. 532&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobeille MR, Malkin AG, Jamara R, Ross NC. Utilization and abandonment of low vision devices prescribed on a mobile clinic. Optom Vis Sci. (2018) 95(9):859&#x2013;64. 10.1097/OPX.0000000000001267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/OPX.0000000000001267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6448560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30169360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherer MJ. Living in the State of Stuck: How Assistive Technology Impacts the Lives of People with Disabilities. 4th ed. Brookline, Massachusetts: Brookline Books; (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigg S, Lagerspetz E, Peltonen E, Nurmi P, Tarkoma S. Exploiting usage to predict instantaneous app popularity: trend filters and retention rates. ACM Trans Web. (2019) 13(2):1&#x2013;25. 10.1145/3199677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3199677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidman PG, Curtis RG, Watson A, Maher CA. When and why adults abandon lifestyle behavior and mental health mobile apps: scoping review. J Med Internet Res. (2024) 26:e56897. 10.2196/56897</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/56897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11694054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39693620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karamolegkou A, Nikandrou M, Pantazopoulos G, Villegas DS, Rust P, Dhar R, et al. https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.22610 Evaluating multimodal language models as visual assistants for visually impaired users [Internet]. arXiv. (2025). Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez Penuela RE, Collins J, Bennett C, Azenkot S. Investigating use cases of AI-powered scene description applications for blind and low vision people. In: Proceedings of the CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. Honolulu HI USA: ACM; (2024). p. 1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangmo T, Lipps M, Kressig RW, Ienca M. Ethical concerns with the use of intelligent assistive technology: findings from a qualitative study with professional stakeholders. BMC Med Ethics. (2019) 20(1):98. 10.1186/s12910-019-0437-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12910-019-0437-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6924051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31856798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akter T, Ahmed T, Kapadia A, Swaminathan M. Shared privacy concerns of the visually impaired and sighted bystanders with camera-based assistive technologies. ACM Trans Access Comput. (2022) 15(2):1&#x2013;33. 10.1145/3506857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3506857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard J, Fisher Z, Kemp AH, Lindsay S, Tasker LH, Tree JJ. Exploring the barriers to using assistive technology for individuals with chronic conditions: a meta-synthesis review. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2022) 17(4):390&#x2013;408. 10.1080/17483107.2020.1788181</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2020.1788181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verza R, Carvalho MLL, Battaglia MA, Uccelli MM. An interdisciplinary approach to evaluating the need for assistive technology reduces equipment abandonment. Mult Scler J. (2006) 12(1):88&#x2013;93. 10.1191/1352458506ms1233oa</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1352458506ms1233oa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16459724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin JC, Donnell CM. Educating the consumer and caretaker on assistive technology. In: Scherer MJ, editor. Assistive Technology: Matching Device and Consumer for Successful Rehabilitation. Washington: American Psychological Association; (2002). p. 153&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley AR, Masingila JO. The use of mobile devices as assistive technology in resource-limited environments: access for learners with visual impairments in Kenya. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2015) 10(4):332&#x2013;9. 10.3109/17483107.2014.974220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17483107.2014.974220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25342493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martiniello N, Eisenbarth W, Lehane C, Johnson A, Wittich W. Exploring the use of smartphones and tablets among people with visual impairments: are mainstream devices replacing the use of traditional visual aids? Assist Technol. (2022) 34(1):34&#x2013;45. 10.1080/10400435.2019.1682084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10400435.2019.1682084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31697612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips M, Proulx MJ. Social interaction without vision: an assessment of assistive technology for the visually impaired. Technol Innov. (2018) 20(1):85&#x2013;93. 10.21300/20.1-2.2018.85</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21300/20.1-2.2018.85</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittich W, Granberg S, Wahlqvist M, Pichora-Fuller MK, M&#xe4;ki-Torkko E. Device abandonment in deafblindness: a scoping review of the intersection of functionality and usability through the international classification of functioning, disability and health lens. BMJ Open. (2021) 11(1):e044873. 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-044873</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-044873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7839866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33495263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hocking C. Function or feelings: factors in abandonment of assistive devices1. Technol Disabil. (1999) 11(1&#x2013;2):3&#x2013;11. 10.3233/TAD-1999-111-202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/TAD-1999-111-202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federici S, Borsci S. Providing assistive technology in Italy: the perceived delivery process quality as affecting abandonment. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2016) 11(1):22&#x2013;31. 10.3109/17483107.2014.930191</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17483107.2014.930191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24936571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminparvin H, Henrichs L, Auger C, Dumassais S, Renaud J, Wittich W. Follow-up in low vision rehabilitation for users of assistive technology: a scoping review. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2025) 20(4):721&#x2013;32. 10.1080/17483107.2024.2433035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2024.2433035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39607837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Shehri W, Almalki J, Alshahrani SM, Alammari A, Khan F, Alangari S. Assistive technology acceptance for visually impaired individuals: a case study of students in Saudi Arabia. PeerJ Comput Sci. (2022) 8:e886. 10.7717/peerj-cs.886</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj-cs.886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35494809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugawara AT, Ramos VD, Alfieri FM, Battistella LR. Abandonment of assistive products: assessing abandonment levels and factors that impact on it. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2018) 13(7):716&#x2013;23. 10.1080/17483107.2018.1425748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2018.1425748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29334475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Freitas MP, Piai VA, Farias RH, Fernandes AMR, De Moraes Rossetto AG, Leithardt VRQ. Artificial intelligence of things applied to assistive technology: a systematic literature review. Sensors. (2022) 22(21):8531. 10.3390/s22218531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22218531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9658699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36366227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ran M, Banes D, Scherer MJ. Basic principles for the development of an AI-based tool for assistive technology decision making. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2022) 17(7):778&#x2013;81. 10.1080/17483107.2020.1817163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2020.1817163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33275457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adnin R, Das M. &#x201c;I look at it as the king of knowledge&#x201d;: how blind people use and understand generative AI tools. In: The 26th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility. St. John&#x2019;s NL Canada: ACM; (2024). p. 1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonnall MC, Steverson A, Sessler Trinkowsky R, Sergi K. Assistive technology use in the workplace by people with blindness and low vision: perceived skill level, satisfaction, and challenges. Assist Technol. (2024) 36(6):429&#x2013;36. 10.1080/10400435.2023.2213762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10400435.2023.2213762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10703993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37171786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonnall MC, Boydstun J, Steverson A. Is one enough? Screen reader use among employed people who are blind or have low vision in the U.S. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. (2025) 20(8):1&#x2013;11. 10.1080/17483107.2025.2528858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2025.2528858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40614067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Otaka Y, Osu R, Kumagai M, Kitamura S, Yaeda J. Motivation for rehabilitation in patients with subacute stroke: a qualitative study. Front Rehabil Sci. (2021) 2:664758. 10.3389/fresc.2021.664758</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fresc.2021.664758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones ML, Gassaway J, Sweatman WM. Peer mentoring reduces unplanned readmissions and improves self-efficacy following inpatient rehabilitation for individuals with spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med. (2021) 44(3):383&#x2013;91. 10.1080/10790268.2019.1645407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10790268.2019.1645407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8081317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31403374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosdahl J, Vin A, Schneider S, Muir K. Health coaching for glaucoma care: a pilot study using mixed methods. Clin Ophthalmol. (2015) 9:1931. 10.2147/OPTH.S92935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OPTH.S92935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4629983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26604666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jong LD, Coe D, Bailey C, Adams N, Skelton DA. Views and experiences of visually impaired older people and exercise instructors about the falls management exercise programme: a qualitative study. Disabil Rehabil. (2021) 43(18):2561&#x2013;7. 10.1080/09638288.2019.1704894</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638288.2019.1704894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31875460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting J, Merom D, Astuti PAS, Antoun M, Edwards K, Ding D. Physical activity interventions for adults who are visually impaired: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open. (2020) 10(2):e034036. 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-034036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-034036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7045169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32051316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rokach A, Berman D, Rose A. Loneliness of the blind and the visually impaired. Front Psychol. (2021) 12:641711. 10.3389/fpsyg.2021.641711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.641711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8267375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>