<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41757304</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Durable and breathable EMI shielding spacer fabrics enabled by synergistic thiol and TPU coatings.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11077</StartPage><EndPage>11089</EndPage><MedlinePgn>11077-11089</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5ra09013j</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The proliferation of high-power electronics and 5G technology has created an increasing demand for high-performance electromagnetic interference (EMI) shielding materials that are durable, breathable, and comfortable for wearable applications. Although silver-coated textiles offer excellent shielding, their limited durability and susceptibility to corrosion hinder their practical use. This study develops a flexible, breathable, and corrosion-resistant electromagnetic interference (EMI) shielding spacer fabric using a multi-step coating strategy. The fabric features a conductive network formed by PDA-assisted electroless silver plating, followed by a thiol self-assembled layer (HDT) and finally encapsulated with a thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU) coating. The optimized composite fabric demonstrates an EMI shielding effectiveness (EMI SE) of up to 57.74 dB in the X-band, with excellent air permeability (2436.1 mm s<sup>-1</sup>), superior corrosion resistance (only 7.8% resistance change after immersion in Na<sub>2</sub>S solution), and mechanical durability (negligible resistance changes after 3000 compression cycles). Combined with its superhydrophobicity (contact angle &gt;140&#xb0;), this fabric offers a promising solution for wearable electronics and personal protective applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiujuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0672-4248</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Arts, Hubei University of Arts and Science Xiangyang 441053 China xjwang2023@outlook.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Textile Science and Engineering, Tiangong University Tianjin 300387 China liuyuanjunsd@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lingzhu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Textile Science and Engineering, Tiangong University Tianjin 300387 China liuyuanjunsd@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yuanjun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Textile Science and Engineering, Tiangong University Tianjin 300387 China liuyuanjunsd@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yaming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Textile Science and Engineering, Tiangong University Tianjin 300387 China liuyuanjunsd@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0089-4254</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Textile Science and Engineering, Tiangong University Tianjin 300387 China liuyuanjunsd@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Smart Wearable Electronic Textiles, Tiangong University Tianjin 300387 China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Advanced Textile Composite Materials of Ministry of Education, Tiangong University China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bio-based Fiber Materials Beijing 100025 China liuhao_0760@163.com jiangyaming@tiangong.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41757304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12933731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ra09013j</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5ra09013j</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yan X. Guo F. Lin Y. et al., Recent advances in multifunctional electromagnetic interference shielding materials. Chem. Commun. 2025;61:1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41147130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahandashti Y. M. Larijani S. Eskandari M. et al., Biomedical potentials of MXene-based self-powered wearable devices: the future of next-generation wearables. RSC Adv. 2025;15:33773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12439251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40963781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sait S. M. Ahmed S. F. Rafiq M. R. Experimental study on broadband radiofrequency electromagnetic radiations near cellular base stations: a novel perspective of public health. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2021;143:1935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari S. Dalal J. Kumar A. et al., Enhanced microwave absorption properties of conducting polymer @ graphene composite to counteract electromagnetic radiation pollution: green EMI shielding. RSC Adv. 2024;14:662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10760626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38173587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao H. Wang Y. Xu W. Research Progress of Fiber-Based Electromagnetic Shielding Materials. Fibers Polym. 2025 doi: 10.1007/s12221-025-00545-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12221-025-00545-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L. X. Yang C. Research Progress on Electromagnetic Shielding Mechanisms and Textile-Based Protective Materials. Text. Leather Rev. 2024;7:1417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sankaran S. Deshmukh K. Ahamed M. B. et al., Recent advances in electromagnetic interference shielding properties of metal and carbon filler reinforced flexible polymer composites: a review. Composites, Part A. 2018;114:49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M. Tang X. H. Cai J. H. et al., Fabrication, mechanisms and perspectives of conductive polymer composites with multiple interfaces for electromagnetic interference shielding: a review. Carbon. 2021;177:377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akram S. Ashraf M. Javid A. et al., Recent advances in electromagnetic interference (EMI) shielding textiles: A comprehensive review. Synth. Met. 2023;294:117305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D. Hu S. Kremenakova D. et al., Evaluation of the wearing comfort properties for winter used electromagnetic interference shielding sandwich materials. J. Ind. Text. 2023;53:15280837231159869.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu N. N. Hu Q. Wei R. B. et al., Review on the electromagnetic interference shielding properties of carbon-based materials and their novel composites: recent progress, challenges and prospects. Carbon. 2021;176:88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J. F. Luo J. C. Wang L. et al., Flexible, superhydrophobic and highly conductive composite based on non-woven polypropylene fabric for electromagnetic interference shielding. Chem. Eng. J. 2019;364:493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren W. Yang Y. Q. Yang J. et al., Multifunctional and corrosion resistant poly(phenylene sulfide)/Ag composites for electromagnetic interference shielding. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;415:128574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan T. Liu Y. Zhou C. X. et al., Fabrication, properties, and applications of open-cell aluminum foams: a review. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2021;62:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J. C. Wang L. Huang X. W. et al., Mechanically Durable, Highly Conductive, and Anticorrosive Composite Fabrics with Excellent Self-Cleaning Performance for High-Efficiency Electromagnetic Interference Shielding. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2019;11:10883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30844225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. Y. Zhou Z. H. Zhou C. G. et al., Lightweight and Robust Carbon Nanotube/Polyimide Foam for Efficient and Heat-Resistant Electromagnetic Interference Shielding and Microwave Absorption. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12:8704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31971778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang L. Y. Xu P. H. Wang Y. F. et al., Flexible polyvinylidene fluoride film with alternating oriented graphene/Ni nanochains for electromagnetic interference shielding and thermal management. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;395:125138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H. Zhu L. L. He Y. et al., A novel method for fabricating elastic conductive polyurethane filaments by in situ reduction of polydopamine and electroless silver plating. Mater. Des. 2017;113:254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L. X. Chen W. Zhang H. B. et al., Flexible and Multifunctional Silk Textiles with Biomimetic Leaf-Like MXene/Silver Nanowire Nanostructures for Electromagnetic Interference Shielding, Humidity Monitoring, and Self-Derived Hydrophobicity. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2019;29:1905197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou B. Su M. J. Yang D. Z. et al., Flexible MXene/Silver Nanowire-Based Transparent Conductive Film with Electromagnetic Interference Shielding and Electro-Photo-Thermal Performance. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12:40859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32803950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W. Li W. Y. Gao C. C. et al., A novel preparation of silver-plated polyacrylonitrile fibers functionalized with antibacterial and electromagnetic shielding properties. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2015;342:120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T. T. Wang Y. T. Peng H. K. et al., Lightweight, flexible and superhydrophobic composite nanofiber films inspired by nacre for highly electromagnetic interference shielding. Composites, Part A. 2020;128:105685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan Y. J. Zhu P. L. Yu S. H. et al., Anticorrosive, Ultralight, and Flexible Carbon-Wrapped Metallic Nanowire Hybrid Sponges for Highly Efficient Electromagnetic Interference Shielding. Small. 2018;14:1800530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29847702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y. L. Guo X. Wang W. et al., Highly Sensitive, Low Hysteretic and Flexible Strain Sensor Based on Ecoflex-AgNWs-MWCNTs Flexible Composite Materials. IEEE Sens. J. 2020;20:14118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh J. Rupanty N. S. Noor T. et al., Functional coatings for textiles: advancements in flame resistance, antimicrobial defense, and self-cleaning performance. RSC Adv. 2025;15:10984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11976222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40201212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan D. L. Li N. X. Li M. G. et al., Polyurethane/polydopamine/graphene auxetic composite foam with high-efficient and tunable electromagnetic interference shielding performance. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;427:131590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X. S. Wang X. F. Lei Z. W. et al., Flexible MXene-Decorated Fabric with Interwoven Conductive Networks for Integrated Joule Heating, Electromagnetic Interference Shielding, and Strain Sensing Performances. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12:14459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S. Wang M. Y. Qiang Z. et al., Multi-functional and highly conductive textiles with ultra-high durability through 'green' fabrication process. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;406:126793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H. Y. Jia L. C. Yan D. X. et al., Simultaneously improved electromagnetic interference shielding and mechanical performance of segregated carbon nanotube/polypropylene composite via solid phase molding. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2018;156:87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam R. Sood Y. Mudila H. et al., Microwave absorbing properties of polypyrrole-based 2D nanocomposites. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2024;12:31004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K. Jung M. Jeon S. et al., Robust and scalable three-dimensional spacer textile pressure sensor for human motion detection. Smart Mater. Struct. 2019;28:065002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q. W. Zhang H. B. Liu J. et al., Multifunctional and Water-Resistant MXene-Decorated Polyester Textiles with Outstanding Electromagnetic Interference Shielding and Joule Heating Performances. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2019;29:1806812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng L. Ma Y. Zou Y. et al., Lightweight, breathable and self-cleaning polypyrrole-modified multifunctional cotton fabric for flexible electromagnetic interference shielding. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2024;274:133347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38917920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X. Zhang P. Zhang S. et al., Breathable, robust, and flexible hierarchical design of multifunctional integrated smart textiles for human health management. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;507:160736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moaref R. Mehdipour N. M. Sundararaj U. Achieving Outstanding Absorption Performance in Electromagnetic Interference Shielding via Improving Impedance Mismatch: Sandwiched PP/CaCO3/Ground Tire Rubber/MWCNT Composites. ACS Appl. Eng. Mater. 2025;3:2811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F. Long H. Yang W. et al., Gradient structural foam-coated fabric for ultra-low reflection electromagnetic interference shielding. Composites, Part A. 2026;201:109414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W. Pan D. Liu S. et al., Multifunctional Wearable Conductive Nanofiber Membrane with Antibacterial and Breathable Ability for Superior Sensing, Electromagnetic Interference Shielding, and Thermal Management. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025;35:2414811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z. Xing D. Yin R. et al., Breathable and waterproof conductive cotton fabric pressure sensor with distinguished electrothermal and electromagnetic interference shielding performances. Appl. Mater. Today. 2024;38:102256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W. Dong J. Long H. et al., Flexible polyimide-based conductive composite film with confined carbon nanotubes networks for EMI shielding and joule heating. Adv. Nanocompos. 2025;2:322&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu R. H. Ma L. Y. Patil A. et al., All-Textile Electronic Skin Enabled by Highly Elastic Spacer Fabric and Conductive Fibers. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2019;11:33336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31424911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao L. F. Li C. Huang W. C. et al., MXene/Polymer Membranes: Synthesis, Properties, and Emerging Applications. Chem. Mater. 2020;32:1703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J. Zhang H. B. Sun R. H. et al., Hydrophobic, Flexible, and Lightweight MXene Foams for High-Performance Electromagnetic-Interference Shielding. Adv. Mater. 2017;29:1702367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28799671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J. Chen B. L. Wang Z. C. et al., Surface coordination layer passivates oxidation of copper. Nature. 2020;586:390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33057223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M. F. Chen J. X. Zhong W. B. et al., Large-Area, Wearable, Self-Powered Pressure-Temperature Sensor Based on 3D Thermoelectric Spacer Fabric. ACS Sens. 2020;5:2545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32672940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. T. Peng H. K. Li T. T. et al., MXene-coated conductive composite film with ultrathin, flexible, self-cleaning for high-performance electromagnetic interference shielding. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;412:128676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X. H. Nie W. Q. Hu Q. L. et al., Multifunctional RGO/Ti3C2Tx MXene fabrics for electrochemical energy storage, electromagnetic interference shielding, electrothermal and human motion detection. Mater. Des. 2021;200:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao R. Pu X. J. Du X. Y. et al., Screen-Printed Washable Electronic Textiles as Self-Powered Touch/Gesture Tribo-Sensors for Intelligent Human-Machine Interaction. ACS Nano. 2018;12(6):5190&#x2013;5196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29771494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>