<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41787540</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How to improve statistical power in a trial with SCA2 patients using natural history data.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-026-09591-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trials are the gold standard for evaluating treatment effects, as they minimize biases. However, they raise ethical concerns regarding participant exposure to potentially ineffective interventions. For rare neurodegenerative diseases, these trials are further challenged by the limited number of patients. Our goal is to leverage recent advancements in statistical methodologies to enhance the statistical power of these trials. We aim to test these methods to the ATRIL study, which evaluated the efficacy of riluzole in patients with dominant cerebellar ataxia SCA2. We trained a progression model on natural history data to capture the progression of the disease, using Disease Course Mapping. We explored the prediction-powered inference for clinical trials method (PPCT), which leverages the prognostic scores predicted by this model, to offer an unbiased comparison between the observed progression in treated patients and the predicted progression if they had not been treated. Then, we compared PPCT to the prognostic covariate adjustment and the Hybrid Augmented Inverse Probability Weighting (H-AIPW) methods, which respectively incorporate the prognostic score to the analysis of covariance or to the Augmented Inverse Probability Weighting (AIPW) method. These methods were applied to the ATRIL trial, which included treated and placebo SCA2 patients, using a model trained on patients from US and European cohorts (EUROSCA, SPATAX, CRC-SCA). Disease Course Mapping models accurately forecasted the prognostic scores, namely the predicted one-year SARA score progression, with correlations around 0.15. The treatment effect estimator had a lower variance using the PPCT (0.342), prognostic covariate adjustment (0.344), and H-AIPW (0.348) methods compared to the classical variance (0.407). Notably, PPCT would reduce the sample size by 14.5% (6 patients). Using the PPCT estimator of the average treatment effect, the same variance reported in the ATRIL paper could have been achieved with 39 patients instead of 45. Our study addresses the challenge of statistical power in clinical trials and explores new methodological advancements. Applying the PPCT, prognostic covariate adjustment, or H-AIPW methods helps reduce confidence intervals, enhance statistical power, or decrease the required sample size for the trial by leveraging information from external data. Although the ATRIL's trial conclusion on riluzole remains unchanged, these methods could have enabled the selection of fewer patients, which is crucial for rare neurodegenerative diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Maylis</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-8150-9512</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne University, Paris Brain Institute (ICM), INSERM, INRIA, CNRS, APHP, Paris, France. maylis.tran@icm-institute.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poulet</LastName><ForeName>Pierre-Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne University, Paris Brain Institute (ICM), INSERM, INRIA, CNRS, APHP, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petit</LastName><ForeName>Emilien</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne University, Paris Brain Institute (ICM), INSERM, INRIA, CNRS, APHP, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durr</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne University, Paris Brain Institute (ICM), INSERM, INRIA, CNRS, APHP, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klockgether</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE), Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashizawa</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weill Cornell Medicine at the Houston Methodist Research Institute, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coarelli</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne University, Paris Brain Institute (ICM), INSERM, INRIA, CNRS, APHP, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>du Montcel</LastName><ForeName>Sophie Tezenas</ForeName><Initials>ST</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne University, Paris Brain Institute (ICM), INSERM, INRIA, CNRS, APHP, Paris, France. sophie.tezenas@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>U01 NS104326</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NIH RC1 NS068897</GrantID><Agency>National Institute of Health</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ANR-10-IAIHU-06</GrantID><Agency>Agence Nationale de la Recherche (ANR) - Investissements d'avenir</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trial design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital twins</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">External data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Natural history data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction-powered inference for clinical trials (PPCT)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic covariate adjustment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic score methodology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Statistical power increase</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: Dr. Tezenas du Montcel receives research support from Biogen and Vico Therapeutics. Dr. Ashizawa received grants from NAF and Biogen and participates in Biohaven clinical trials NCT03952806 and NCT03701399. Dr. Durr declares that her institution (Paris Brain Institute) receives consulting or compensation fees on her behalf from Biogen, Huntix, UCB, Wavelife Therapeutics, PTC Therapeutics, Vico, as well as research grants from the NIH, ANR, Brain-team and the National Hospital Clinical Research Program, and she holds partly a patent B 06291873.5 on &#x201c;Anaplerotic therapy of Huntington&#x2019;s disease and other polyglutamine diseases.&#x201d;</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41787540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-026-09591-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-026-09591-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Bothwell LE, Greene JA, Podolsky SH, Jones DS. Assessing the gold standard &#x2014; lessons from the history of RCTs. Malina D, editor. N Engl J Med. 2016;374(22):2175&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temple R, Ellenberg SS. Placebo-controlled trials and active-control trials in the evaluation of new treatments. Part 1: ethical and scientific issues. Ann Intern Med. 2000;133(6):455&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhardwaj SS, Camacho F, Derrow A, Fleischer AB Jr, Feldman SR. Statistical significance and clinical relevance: the importance of power in clinical trials in dermatology. Arch Dermatol. 2004;140(12):1520&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beiner M, Powell L, Rogula B, Potashman M, Wirtz V, Schmahmann J, et al. Matching-adjusted indirect comparison of troriluzole versus untreated natural history cohort in spinocerebellar ataxia (S35.009). Neurology. 2024;102(17_supplement_1):3472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheux E, Ortholand J, Birkenbihl C, Thibeau-Sutre E, Sood M, Archetti D, et al. Forecast Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease progression to better select patients for clinical trials. In: ISCB 2021: 42nd Conference of the International Society for Clinical Biostatistics. Online, France; 2021. Available from: https://hal.science/hal-03483237. Cited 2024 Sept 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weissler EH, Naumann T, Andersson T, Ranganath R, Elemento O, Luo Y, et al. The role of machine learning in clinical research: transforming the future of evidence generation. Trials. 2021;22(1):537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordukova M, Makarov N, Rodriguez-Esteban R, Schmich F, Menden MP. Generative artificial intelligence empowers digital twins in drug discovery and clinical trials. Expert Opin Drug Discov. 2024;19(1):33&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulet PE, Tran M, Tezenas du Montcel S, Dubois B, Durrleman S, Jedynak B, et al. Prediction-powered inference for clinical trials: application to linear covariate adjustment. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2025;25(1):204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler A, Walsh D, Hall D, Walsh J, Fisher C. Increasing the efficiency of randomized trial estimates via linear adjustment for a prognostic score. Int J Biostat. 2022;18(2):329&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomeis PD, Abad J, Wang G, Donhauser K, Duch RM, Yang F, et al. Efficient randomized experiments using foundation models. arXiv. 2025. Available from: http://arxiv.org/abs/2502.04262. Cited 2025 Feb 21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruano L, Melo C, Silva MC, Coutinho P. The Global Epidemiology of hereditary ataxia and spastic paraplegia: a systematic review of prevalence studies. Neuroepidemiology. 2014;42(3):174&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coarelli G, Coutelier M, Durr A. Autosomal dominant cerebellar ataxias: new genes and progress towards treatments. Lancet Neurol. 2023;22(8):735&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durr A. Autosomal dominant cerebellar ataxias: polyglutamine expansions and beyond. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9(9):885&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi&#xf2; A, Calvo A, Moglia C, Canosa A, Brunetti M, Barberis M, et al. ATXN2 polyQ intermediate repeats are a modifier of ALS survival. Neurology. 2015;84(3):251&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi H, du Montcel ST, Bauer P, Giunti P, Cook A, Labrum R, et al. Long-term disease progression in spinocerebellar ataxia types 1, 2, 3, and 6: a longitudinal cohort study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14(11):1101&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz-H&#xfc;bsch T, du Montcel ST, Baliko L, Berciano J, Boesch S, Depondt C, et al. Scale for the assessment and rating of ataxia. Neurology. 2006;66(11):1717&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coarelli G, Heinzmann A, Ewenczyk C, Fischer C, Chupin M, Monin ML, et al. Safety and efficacy of riluzole in spinocerebellar ataxia type 2 in France (ATRIL): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21(3):225&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elden AC, Kim HJ, Hart MP, Chen-Plotkin AS, Johnson BS, Fang X, et al. Ataxin-2 intermediate-length polyglutamine expansions are associated with increased risk for ALS. Nature. 2010;466(7310):1069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Khleifat AA, Meurgey JH, Jones A, Leigh PN, Bensimon G, et al. Stage at which riluzole treatment prolongs survival in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a retrospective analysis of data from a dose-ranging study. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(5):416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulst SM. Degenerative ataxias, from genes to therapies: the 2015 Cotzias Lecture. Neurology. 2016;86(24):2284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robins JM, Rotnitzky A, Zhao LP. Estimation of regression coefficients when some regressors are not always observed. J Am Stat Assoc. 1994;89(427):846&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelopoulos AN, Bates S, Fannjiang C, Jordan MI, Zrnic T. Prediction-powered inference. Science. 2023;382(6671):669&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelopoulos AN, Duchi JC, Zrnic T. PPI++: efficient prediction-powered inference. arXiv. 2024. Available from: http://arxiv.org/abs/2311.01453. Cited 2024 Aug 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mani P, Xu P, Lipton ZC, Oberst M. No free lunch: non-asymptotic analysis of prediction-powered inference. arXiv. 2025. Available from: http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20178. Cited 2025 Nov 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>others. Guideline on adjustment for baseline covariates in clinical trials. Comm Med Prod Hum Use. European Medicines Agency, London.&#xa0;2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulet PE, Tran M, Montcel ST du, Dubois B, Durrleman S, Jedynak B. Prediction-powered inference for clinical trials. medRxiv; 2025. p. 2025.01.15.25320578. Available from:&#xa0;https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2025.01.15.25320578v1. Cited 2025 Jan 20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit E, Schmitz-H&#xfc;bsch T, Coarelli G, Jacobi H, Heinzmann A, Figueroa KP, et al. SARA captures disparate progression and responsiveness in spinocerebellar ataxias. J Neurol. 2024;271(7):3743&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monin ML, Tezenas du Montcel S, Marelli C, Cazeneuve C, Charles P, Tallaksen C, et al. Survival and severity in dominant cerebellar ataxias. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2015;2(2):202&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashizawa T, Figueroa KP, Perlman SL, Gomez CM, Wilmot GR, Schmahmann JD, et al. Clinical characteristics of patients with spinocerebellar ataxias 1, 2, 3 and 6 in the US; a prospective observational study. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2013;8(1):177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi H, Rakowicz M, Rola R, Fancellu R, Mariotti C, Charles P, et al. Inventory of non-ataxia signs (INAS): validation of a new clinical assessment instrument. Cerebellum. 2013;12(3):418&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiratti JB, Allassonni&#xe8;re S, Colliot O, Durrleman S. A Bayesian mixed-effects model to learn trajectories of changes from repeated manifold-valued observations. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiratti JB, Allassonniere S, Colliot O, Durrleman S. Learning spatiotemporal trajectories from manifold-valued longitudinal data. In: Advances in neural information processing systems. Curran Associates, Inc.; 2015. Available from: https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper_files/paper/2015/hash/186a157b2992e7daed3677ce8e9fe40f-Abstract.html. Cited 2024 Aug 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulet PE, Durrleman S. Multivariate disease progression modeling with longitudinal ordinal data. Stat Med. 2023;42(18):3164&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burman CF, Hermansson E, Bock D, Franz&#xe9;n S, Svensson D. Digital twins and Bayesian dynamic borrowing: two recent approaches for incorporating historical control data. Pharm Stat. 2024;23(5):611&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Ma S. Machine learning methods for leveraging baseline covariate information to improve the efficiency of clinical trials. Stat Med. 2019;38(10):1703&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirracchio R, Petersen ML, van der Laan M. Improving propensity score estimators&#x2019; robustness to model misspecification using super learner. Am J Epidemiol. 2015;181(2):108&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng A, Xu Y, Kohavi R, Walker T. Improving the sensitivity of online controlled experiments by utilizing pre-experiment data. In: Proceedings of the sixth ACM international conference on Web search and data mining. New York, NY, USA: Association for Computing Machinery; 2013. p. 123&#x2013;32. (WSDM &#x2019;13). Available from: https://doi.org/10.1145/2433396.2433413.&#xa0;Cited 2024 Aug 14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzati A, Lipton RB, Initiative for the ADN. Machine learning predictive models can improve efficacy of clinical trials for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. J Alzheimers Dis. 2020;74(1):55&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colnet B, Josse J, Varoquaux G, Scornet E. Reweighting the RCT for generalization: finite sample error and variable selection. arXiv; 2022. Available from: https://arxiv.org/abs/2208.07614. Cited 2024 Oct 4.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>