<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41399958</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dual-Phase Regulation via a Volatile Morphology Director Enables Trap-Suppressed Organic Solar Cells with 20.6% Efficiency.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e20162</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e20162</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202520162</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Immense trap densities arising from faint donor self-assembly and excessive acceptor aggregation severely restrain power conversion efficiencies (PCEs) in organic solar cells. Yet, most studies focus solely on acceptor regulation, and synergistic co-modulation of donor and acceptor phases for trap suppression has rarely been achieved. Here, 1,3-dibromo-5-iodobenzene (DBI) as a volatile solid additive with multiple noncovalent interactions to concurrently optimize both phases is introduced. Using PM6:Y6 as representative, from systemic coarse-grained molecular dynamic simulation, in-situ synchronic and spectroscopy and transient optoelectronic characterizations, it is demonstrated that DBI can selectively bind with the fluorinated benzo[1,2-b:4,5-b']dithiophene segments in PM6 backbone, which strengthens interchain interactions, enhances interchain packing density, and triggers the pre-aggregation of PM6 in solution state. Moreover, this preferentially precipitation of PM6 matrix sterically mitigates the oversized Y6 aggregation, which yields well-defined phase separation with appropriate domain sizes, which markedly substitute energetic disorder and trap density. As a result, the DBI treated devices yielded an elevated performance of 18.4% compared to 17.0% for reference devices. The generality of such strategy is also validated by PM6:L8-BO:L8-BO-F ternary system, where adding an optimal amount of DBI achieves a champion PCE of 20.6% with a boosted operational stability (T<sub>80</sub>:769&#xa0;h) under continuous light-soaking condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4201-8749</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory of Light-Electricity-Heat Energy-Converting Materials and Applications, Changzhou University, Changzhou, 213164, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Luminescent Materials and Devices, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510640, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Tongrui</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Automobile Materials, Ministry of Education, and School of Materials Science and Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun, 130022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hongxiang</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials and Energy, Guang'an Institute of Technology, Guang'an, 638000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xingting</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory of Light-Electricity-Heat Energy-Converting Materials and Applications, Changzhou University, Changzhou, 213164, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xunchang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Flexible Optoelectronic Materials and Technology, Ministry of Education, School of Optoelectronic Materials &amp; Technology, Jianghan University, Wuhan, 430056, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Tonghui</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Automobile Materials, Ministry of Education, and School of Materials Science and Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun, 130022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;ller-Buschbaum</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chair for Functional Materials, Department of Physics, TUM School of Natural Sciences, Technical University of Munich, James-Franck-Stra&#xdf;e 1, 85748, Garching, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Weiguo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory of Light-Electricity-Heat Energy-Converting Materials and Applications, Changzhou University, Changzhou, 213164, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22575029</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62105129</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52130101</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023YFB3003000</GrantID><Agency>National Key R&amp;D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Opening Fund of the State Key Laboratory of Luminescent Materials and Devices and South China University of Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blend morphology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organic solar cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trap density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">volatile solid additive</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41399958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202520162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>J. Yuan, Y. Zhang, L. Zhou, G. Zhang, H.&#x2010;L. Yip, T.&#x2010;K. Lau, X. Lu, C. Zhu, H. Peng, P. A. Johnson, M. Leclerc, Y. Cao, J. Ulanski, Y. Li, Y. Zou, Joule 2019, 3, 1140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Liang, D. Zhang, Z. Wu, T. Jia, L. L&#xfc;er, H. Tang, L. Hong, J. Zhang, K. Zhang, C. J. Brabec, N. Li, F. Huang, Nat. Energy 2022, 7, 1180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Zeng, W. Chen, X. Chen, Y. Hu, Y. Chen, B. Zhang, H. Chen, W. Sun, Y. Shen, Y. Li, F. Yan, Y. Li, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2022, 144, 8658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wu, G. Li, J. Fang, X. Guo, L. Zhu, B. Guo, Y. Wang, G. Zhang, L. Arunagiri, F. Liu, H. Yan, M. Zhang, Y. Li, Nat. Commun. 2020, 11, 4612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Lin, J. Wang, Z.&#x2010;G. Zhang, H. Bai, Y. Li, D. Zhu, X. Zhan, Adv. Mater. 2015, 27, 1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Venkateshvaran, M. Nikolka, A. Sadhanala, V. Lemaur, M. Zelazny, M. Kepa, M. Hurhangee, A. J. Kronemeijer, V. Pecunia, I. Nasrallah, I. Romanov, K. Broch, I. McCulloch, D. Emin, Y. Olivier, J. Cornil, D. Beljonne, H. Sirringhaus, Nature 2014, 515, 384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Dou, S. Luo, P. Zhu, L. Zhu, G. Zhang, C. Bao, H. Yan, J. Zhu, S. Chen, Joule 2025, 9, 101774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, G. Cai, Y. Li, Z. Zhang, T. Li, X. Zuo, X. Lu, Y. Lin, Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2008134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Ni, C. Bao, Y. Liu, Q. Jiang, W.&#x2010;Q. Wu, S. Chen, X. Dai, B. Chen, B. Hartweg, Z. Yu, Z. Holman, J. Huang, Science 2020, 367, 1352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Chen, A. A. Sergeev, N. Zhang, L. Ke, Y. Wu, B. Tang, C. K. Tao, H. Liu, G. Zou, Z. Zhu, Y. An, Y. Li, A. Portniagin, K. A. Sergeeva, K. S. Wong, H.&#x2010;L. Yip, A. L. Rogach, Nat. Commun. 2025, 16, 2367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. A. Carr, S. Chaudhary, Energy Environ. Sci. 2013, 6, 3414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Fratini, D. Mayou, S. Ciuchi, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2016, 26, 2292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. K. Jena, A. Kulkarni, T. Miyasaka, Chem. Rev. 2019, 119, 3036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Jiang, K. Liu, F. Liu, G. Ran, M. Wang, T. Zhang, R. Xu, H. Liu, W. Zhang, Z. Wei, Y. Cui, X. Lu, J. Hou, X. Zhu, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2500282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Jiang, S. Sun, R. Xu, F. Liu, X. Miao, G. Ran, K. Liu, Y. Yi, W. Zhang, X. Zhu, Nat. Energy 2024, 9, 975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Rivnay, L. H. Jimison, J. E. Northrup, M. F. Toney, R. Noriega, S. Lu, T. J. Marks, A. Facchetti, A. Salleo, Nat. Mater. 2009, 8, 952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhou, D. He, Y. Li, F. Huang, J. Zhang, C. Zhang, Y. Yuan, Y. Lin, C. Wang, F. Zhao, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2207336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zheng, X. Wang, F. Sun, M. Wan, Z. Li, C. Xiao, T. Cong, T. Hu, Y. Liao, R. Yang, Chem. Eng. J. 2023, 475, 145520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Gao, Y. Zhang, S. Jeong, X. Zhou, H. Xu, S. Xu, D. Chen, W. Liu, C. Yang, S. Meng, W. Zhu, X. Song, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 5542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Sun, X. Zheng, T. Hu, J. Wu, M. Wan, Y. Xiao, T. Cong, Y. Li, B. Xiao, J. Shan, E. Wang, X. Wang, R. Yang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 1916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Luo, Y. Dou, X. Shi, Y. Liu, T. Liu, X. Hu, T. Li, X. Peng, H. Hu, H. Yan, S. Chen, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2407609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. G. Jeon, J. Kim, H. J. Eun, J.&#x2010;W. Ha, S. Chung, S. J. Shin, K. Cho, S. C. Yoon, B. J. Kim, S.&#x2010;J. Ko, J. H. Kim, Chem. Eng. J. 2024, 495, 153419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. McDowell, M. Abdelsamie, M. F. Toney, G. C. Bazan, Adv. Mater. 2018, 30, 1707114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Wang, T. Chen, Y. Li, G. Ding, Z. Chen, J. Li, C. Xu, A. Wupur, C. Xu, Y. Fu, J. Xue, W. Fu, W. Qiu, X. Yang, D. Wang, W. Ma, X. Lu, H. Zhu, X. Chen, X. Wang, H. Chen, L. Zuo, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 2598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Shan, D. Luo, J. Zeng, T. Dai, X. Gu, X. Xu, Z. Li, E. Zhou, B. Xu, A. K. K. Kyaw, Chem. Eng. J. 2025, 505, 159658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Chen, S. Zhang, T. Zhang, J. Ren, J. Dai, H. Li, J. Qiao, X. Hao, J. Hou, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202317892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Song, H. Xu, X. Jiang, S. Gao, X. Zhou, S. Xu, J. Li, J. Yu, W. Liu, W. Zhu, P. M&#xfc;ller&#x2010;Buschbaum, Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 3441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Song, K. Zhang, R. Guo, K. Sun, Z. Zhou, S. Huang, L. Huber, M. Reus, J. Zhou, M. Schwartzkopf, S. V. Roth, W. Liu, Y. Liu, W. Zhu, P. M&#xfc;ller&#x2010;Buschbaum, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2200907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Cheng, H. Li, X. Zhang, Y. Chen, G. Ran, Y. Yue, N. Wei, X. Zhu, X. Yan, Y. Liu, H. Lu, Y. Liu, Z. Bo, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2415468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Li, X. Gu, Z. Chen, X. Han, N. Yu, Y. Wei, J. Gao, H. Chen, M. Zhang, A. Wang, J. Zhang, Z. Wei, Q. Peng, Z. Tang, X. Hao, X. Zhang, H. Huang, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2022, 144, 14731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Song, L. Mei, X. Zhou, H. Li, H. Xu, X. Liu, S. Gao, S. Xu, Y. Yang, W. Zhu, J. Wang, X.&#x2010;H. Zhang, X.&#x2010;K. Chen, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202411512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Fu, L. Xu, Y. Li, E. J. Yang, Y. Guo, G. Cai, P. F. Chan, Y. Ke, C.&#x2010;J. Su, U. S. Jeng, P. C. Y. Chow, J.&#x2010;S. Kim, M.&#x2010;C. Tang, X. Lu, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 8893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Fan, H. Yang, Y. Wu, O. Yildiz, X. Zhu, T. Marszalek, P. W. M. Blom, C. Cui, Y. Li, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2021, 31, 2103944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Chen, H. Yao, J. Wang, J. Zhang, T. Zhang, Z. Li, J. Qiao, S. Xiu, X. Hao, J. Hou, Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 2637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, Y. Wang, P. Bi, Z. Chen, J. Qiao, J. Li, W. Wang, Z. Zheng, S. Zhang, X. Hao, J. Hou, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2301583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Song, B. Zhang, X. Liu, L. Mei, H. Li, S. Yin, X. Zhou, H. Chen, Y. Lin, W. Zhu, X.&#x2010;K. Chen, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2418393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhang, Z. Li, X. Jiang, L. Xie, G. Pan, A. Buyan&#x2010;Arivjikh, T. Baier, S. Tu, P. M&#xfc;ller&#x2010;Buschbaum, Adv. Energy Mater. 2025, 15, 2404724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Yang, F. C. L&#xf6;hrer, F. C. L&#xf6;hrer, V. K&#xf6;rstgens, A. Schreiber, S. Bernstorff, J. M. Buriak, P. M&#xfc;ller&#x2010;Buschbaum, ACS Energy Lett. 2019, 4, 464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Zhang, H. Chen, T. Wang&#x2009;, L. Kobera, L. He, Y. Huang, J. Ding, B. Zhang, A. Khasbaatar, C. Zhu, H. Liu, X. Lu, Q. Jiang, V. Coropceanu, J. Br&#xe9;das, Y. Li, Y. Li, F. Gao, Nat. Energy 2025, 10, 124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Song, C. Zhang, C. Li, J. Qiao, J. Yu, J. Gao, X. Wang, X. Hao, Z. Tang, G. Lu, R. Yang, H. Yan, Y. Sun, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202404297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Luo, C. Li, J. Zhang, X. Zou, H. Zhao, K. Ding, H. Huang, J. Song, J. Yi, H. Yu, K. S. Wong, G. Zhang, H. Ade, W. Ma, H. Hu, Y. Sun, H. Yan, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 6964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Liao, X. Xu, T. Yang, W. Qiu, Y. Duan, R. Li, L. Yu, Q. Peng, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2411071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Gao, S. Xu, C. Sun, L. Yu, J. Li, R. Li, X. Liu, X. Zhou, H. Chen, Y. Lin, X. Bao, W. Zhu, X. Song, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2420631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhao, S. Chung, H. Li, Z. Zhao, C. Zhu, J. Yin, K. Cho, Z. Kan, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2307355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Saladina, C. W&#xf6;pke, C. G&#xf6;hler, I. Ramirez, O. Gerdes, C. Liu, N. Li, T. Heum&#xfc;ller, C. J. Brabec, K. Walzer, M. Pfeiffer, C. Deibel, Phys. Rev. Lett. 2023, 130, 236403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yuan, C. Zhang, B. Qiu, W. Liu, S. K. So, M. Mainville, M. Leclerc, S. Shoaee, D. Neher, Y. Zou, Energy Environ. Sci. 2022, 15, 2806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Wang, X. Ma, Y.&#x2010;f. Shen, D. Deng, H. Zhang, T. Wang, J. Zhang, J. Li, R. Wang, L. Zhang, Q. Cheng, Z. Zhang, H. Zhou, C. Tian, Z. Wei, Joule 2023, 7, 2386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wu, X. Jiang, X. Li, J. Zhang, K. Ding, H. Zhuo, J. Guo, J. Li, L. Meng, H. Ade, Y. Li, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2302946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wu, J. Lee, Y.&#x2010;C. Chin, H. Yao, H. Cha, J. Luke, J. Hou, J.&#x2010;S. Kim, J. R. Durrant, Energy Environ. Sci. 2020, 13, 2422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Yu, T. Zhang, Y. Li, G.&#x2010;F. Han, X.&#x2010;Y. Lang, J.&#x2010;L. Br&#xe9;das, T. Wang, Q. Jiang, EES Sol. 2025, https://doi.org/10.1039/d5el00117j.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Cai, Y. Li, R. Wang, H. Wu, Z. Chen, J. Zhang, Z. Ma, X. Hao, Y. Zhao, C. Zhang, F. Huang, Y. Sun, Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2101733.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>