<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41657732</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2673-3129</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in medical technology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Med Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>IoMT-Fog-Cloud-based AI frameworks for chronic disease diagnosis: updated comparative analysis with recent AI-IoMT models (2020-2025).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1748964</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1748964</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1748964</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmedt.2026.1748964</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic diseases such as diabetes and cardiovascular disease require frequent monitoring and timely clinical feedback to prevent complications. Internet of Medical Things (IoMT) systems increasingly combine near-patient sensing with Fog and Cloud computing so that time-critical preprocessing and inference can run close to the patient while compute-intensive training and population-level analytics remain in the Cloud. This review synthesizes primary studies published between 2020 and 2025 that implement AI-enabled IoMT, with an emphasis on systems that report both diagnostic performance and network quality-of-service (QoS). Following PRISMA 2020, we screened database records and included 14 primary studies; we focus the joint performance-QoS synthesis on six IoMT-Fog-Cloud frameworks for diabetes and cardiovascular disease and compare them with two recent multi-disease AI-IoMT models (DACL and TasLA). Diabetes-oriented implementations commonly report accuracy around 95%-96% using explainable or ensemble deep learning, whereas some cardiovascular frameworks report &gt;99% accuracy in controlled settings; we therefore discuss plausible sources of optimistic performance, including small datasets, class imbalance, curated benchmarks, and potential leakage/overfitting in simulation-based evaluations. Across IoMT-Fog-Cloud studies, placing preprocessing and/or inference at the Fog layer repeatedly reduces end-to-end latency for streaming biosignals, but multi-Fog provisioning can increase energy and power demands. To support more reproducible comparisons, we organize 14 extracted metrics into (i) diagnostic performance (accuracy, precision, recall, F1-score, sensitivity, specificity) and (ii) system/network QoS (latency, jitter, throughput, bandwidth utilization, processing/execution time, network usage, energy consumption, power consumption), and we translate the evidence into study-linked design recommendations for future deployments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Locharoenrat.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Locharoenrat</LastName><ForeName>Kitsakorn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, School of Science, King Mongkut's Institute of Technology Ladkrabang, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Med Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101772626</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2673-3129</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic disease diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cloud computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fog computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">internet of Medical Things (IoMT)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41657732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12872747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmedt.2026.1748964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pati A, Parhi M, Pattanayak BK, Singh D, Samanta D, Banerjee A, et al. Diagnose diabetic mellitus illness based on IoT smart architecture. Wirel Commun Mob Comput. (2022) 2022:7268571. 10.1155/2022/7268571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/7268571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Rashidy N, ElSayed NE, El-Ghamry A, Talaat FM. RETRACTED ARTICLE: utilizing fog computing and explainable deep learning techniques for gestational diabetes prediction. Neural Comput Appl. (2023) 35:7423&#x2013;42. 10.1007/s00521-022-08007-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-022-08007-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m E, Cicio&#x11f;lu M, &#xc7;alhan A. Fog-cloud architecture-driven internet of medical things framework for healthcare monitoring. Med Biol Eng Comput. (2023) 61(5):1133&#x2013;47. 10.1007/s11517-023-02776-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11517-023-02776-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9859747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36670240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, Yu Q, Peng D, Subramani S, Wang X. Fogmed: a fog-based framework for disease prognosis based on medical sensor data streams. Comput Mat Contin. (2021) 66(1):603&#x2013;19. 10.32604/cmc.2020.012515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/cmc.2020.012515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pati A, Parhi M, Alnabhan M, Pattanayak BK, Habboush AK, Nawayseh A, et al. An IoT&#x2013;fog&#x2013;cloud integrated framework for real-time remote cardiovascular disease diagnosis. Informatics. (2023) 10(1):21. 10.3390/informatics10010021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/informatics10010021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angel Nancy A, Ravindran D, Vincent DR, Srinivasan K, Chang C-Y. Fog-based smart cardiovascular disease prediction system powered by modified gated recurrent unit. Diagnostics. (2023) 13(12):2071. 10.3390/diagnostics13122071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13122071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10297507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37370966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nandagopal M, Seerangan K, Govindaraju T, Abi NE, Balusamy B, Selvarajan S. A deep auto-optimized collaborative learning (DACL) model for disease prognosis using AI-IoMT systems. Sci Rep. (2024) 14:10280. 10.1038/s41598-024-59846-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-59846-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11069552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38704423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadidos AO, Khadidos AO, Selvarajan S, Mirza OM. TasLA: an innovative tasmanian and lichtenberg optimized attention deep convolution-based data fusion model for IoMT smart healthcare. Alexandria Eng J. (2023) 79:337&#x2013;53. 10.1016/j.aej.2023.08.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2023.08.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvarajan S, Manoharan H, Iwendi C, Alsowail RA, Pandiaraj S. A comparative recognition research on excretory organism in medical applications using artificial neural networks. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. (2023) 11:1211143. 10.3389/fbioe.2023.1211143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2023.1211143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10312079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37397968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Kumar SA, Dutt V, Selvarajan S, Tripathi E. IoT-based arrhythmia classification using the enhanced hunt optimization-based deep learning. Expert Systems. (2023) 40(7):e13298. 10.1111/exsy.13298</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exsy.13298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvarajan S. A comprehensive study on modern optimization techniques for engineering applications. Artif Intell Rev. (2024) 57:194. 10.1007/s10462-024-10829-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-024-10829-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigar N, Jaleel A, Islam S, Shahzad MK, Affum EA. IoMT meets machine learning: from edge to cloud chronic diseases diagnosis system. J Healthc Eng. (2023) 2023:9995292. 10.1155/2023/9995292</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/9995292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10250092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37304462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xhaferra E, Ismaili F, Cina E. Comparative study of ML-based diabetes detection using IoT and lab data in fog. Ann Emerg Technol Comput. (2025) 9(3):1&#x2013;21. 10.33166/aetic.2025.03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33166/aetic.2025.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suleiman HJ, Hamid IRA, Olaniran OR. Smart health monitoring for predicting heart disease using IoT&#x2013;fog&#x2013;cloud computing model. Eng Technol Appl Sci Res. (2025) 15(3):22565&#x2013;72. 10.48084/etasr.10048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48084/etasr.10048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Rubio Rodr&#xed;guez-Kirby LA, Lin Y, Wang W, Song M, Wang L, et al. Spatial dynamics of brain development and neuroinflammation. Nature. (2025) 647:213&#x2013;27. 10.1038/s41586-025-09663-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-025-09663-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12589135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41193846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan R, Baysoy A, Tian X, Zhang F, Renauer P, Bai Z, et al. 
Spatially resolved panoramic <i>in vivo</i> CRISPR screen via perturb-DBiT. Res Sq. (preprint) (2025). 10.21203/rs.3.rs-6481967/v1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-6481967/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashyap V, Kumar A, Kumar A, Hu Y-C. A systematic survey on fog and IoT driven healthcare: open challenges and research issues. Electronics (Basel). (2022) 11(17):2668. 10.3390/electronics11172668</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics11172668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navakauskas D, Kazlauskas M. Fog computing in healthcare: systematic review. Informatica. (2023) 34(3):577&#x2013;602. 10.15388/23-INFOR525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15388/23-INFOR525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad AI, Fouda MM, Khashaba MM, Mohamed ER, Hosny KM. Utilization of mobile edge computing on the internet of medical things: a survey. ICT Express. (2023) 9(3):473&#x2013;85. 10.1016/j.icte.2022.05.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.icte.2022.05.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younas MI, Iqbal MJ, Aziz A, Sodhro AH. Toward QoS monitoring in IoT edge devices driven healthcare&#x2014;a systematic literature review. Sensors. (2023) 23(21):8885. 10.3390/s23218885</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23218885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10650388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37960584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alturki B, Abu Al-Haija Q, Alsemmeari RA, Alsulami AA, Alqahtani A, Alghamdi BM, et al. IoMT landscape: navigating current challenges and pioneering future research trends. Discover Applied Sciences. (2024) 7:26. 10.1007/s42452-024-06351-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-024-06351-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>