<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41445641</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>medRxiv : the preprint server for health sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>medRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Toward Trustworthy Chatbots: A Protocol for Red Teaming for Health Related Conversations.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2025.12.15.25342297</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.64898/2025.12.15.25342297</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Health-related chatbots are increasingly used to mediate conversations that carry clinical significance and emotional weight. Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) can reduce factual errors ("hallucinations"), but the risks remain, with additional challenges coming from chatbots acting against behavioral safety and scope rules. Red teaming, an adversarial testing process that deliberately probes systems for failures before deployment, offers a way to surface potential risks. We describe a task-informed red-teaming protocol for health-related and patient-facing chatbots..</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our protocol is composed of an error stratification, single and multi-turn attack evaluation, and a framework for mitigation techniques. We define an error framework that distinguishes Knowledge Adherence (KA: staying faithful to retrieved documents) from Behavioral Adherence (BA: following safety, tone, and scope instructions). Our single-turn attacks consist of seven attack vectors reflecting real-world pressures, including advice-seeking, user distress, and prompt injection. A subset of these vectors are evaluated in multi-turn attacks. We evaluate two mitigation strategies: (1) prompt augmentation, which adds explicit guardrails to the chatbot prompt, and (2) document augmentation, which adds a localized FAQ document to the retrieval corpus. Finally, we apply this protocol to a social care chatbot (specifically supporting Health-Related Social Needs (HRSN)), developed as an agentic workflow that queries a vetted HRSN resource index. The evaluation corpus comprises 140 single-turn probes and 20 multi-turn stress tests. We assess correctness and risk severity via human annotation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our error framework identified that the primary safety risk was a failure to follow behavioral rules, rather than a lack of factual knowledge. Furthermore, multi-turn stress tests revealed critical vulnerabilities that single-turn testing missed, directly informing our choice of targeted mitigations. In single-turn tests, the chatbot was factually robust, yielding 0/60 KA errors; however, it struggled with behavioral instructions, producing a 15% (12/80) BA error rate, with 21% (4/19) of those being high-severity. Notable vulnerabilities included advice_query (BA 30%, 6/20) and prompt_injection (BA 20%, 4/20). User_distress triggered the hallucination of unverified contact details in 20% (4/20) of cases. In multi-turn stress tests, error rates rose sharply under conversational persistence: advice_query BA errors reached 50% (5/10) and user_distress reached 40% (4/10), accounting for all high-severity errors (4/4). Prompt augmentation reduced total errors across these vectors by 60% (15/60&#x2192;6/60). Document augmentation eliminated all single-turn user_distress errors (to 0/20) and reduced advice_query errors (7/20&#x2192;4/20). When combined in multi-turn tests, these mitigations eliminated high-severity errors entirely, reducing BA errors to 20% (advice_query) and 30% (user_distress) by forcing the chatbot into "safe failure" loops.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We demonstrate that a protocol combining single-turn breadth, multi-turn depth, and layered mitigations materially improves chatbot safety and offers a practical template for patient-facing chatbots. Future work should expand on this protocol with chatbots in more diverse clinical domains, and with a larger panel of evaluators.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussain</LastName><ForeName>Syed-Amad</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7529-8644</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Ohio State University, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jackson</LastName><ForeName>Daniel I</ForeName><Initials>DI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Ohio State University, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewis</LastName><ForeName>Ashley</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Linguistics, The Ohio State University, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fosler-Lussier</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Ohio State University, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sezgin</LastName><ForeName>Emre</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8798-9605</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University College of Medicine, Columbus OH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UM1 TR004548</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>medRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101767986</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interests None declared</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41445641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12723766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.64898/2025.12.15.25342297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2025.12.15.25342297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kurniawan MH, Handiyani H, Nuraini T, Hariyati RTS, Sutrisno S. A systematic review of artificial intelligence-powered (AI-powered) chatbot intervention for managing chronic illness. Ann Med. 2024;56: 2302980. doi: 10.1080/07853890.2024.2302980</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2024.2302980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10930147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38466897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreda M, Cantarero-Prieto D, Coca D, Delgado A, Lanza-Le&#xf3;n P, Lera J, et al. Transforming healthcare with chatbots: Uses and applications-A scoping review. Digit Health. 2025;11: 20552076251319174. doi: 10.1177/20552076251319174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076251319174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laymouna M, Ma Y, Lessard D, Schuster T, Engler K, Lebouch&#xe9; B. Roles, users, benefits, and limitations of chatbots in health care: Rapid review. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26: e56930. doi: 10.2196/56930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/56930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11303905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39042446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Authors, Clark M, Bailey S. Chatbots in health care: Connecting patients to information: Emerging health technologies. Ottawa (ON): Canadian Agency for Drugs and Technologies in Health; 2024. Available: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK602381/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinz MV, Mackin DM, Trudeau BM, Bhattacharya S, Wang Y, Banta HA, et al. Randomized trial of a generative AI chatbot for mental health treatment. NEJM AI. 2025;2. doi: 10.1056/aioa2400802</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/aioa2400802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore J, Grabb D, Agnew W, Klyman K, Chancellor S, Ong DC, et al. Expressing stigma and inappropriate responses prevents LLMs from safely replacing mental health providers. Proceedings of the 2025 ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency. New York, NY, USA: ACM; 2025. pp. 599&#x2013;627. doi: 10.1145/3715275.3732039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3715275.3732039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabral S, Restrepo D, Kanjee Z, Wilson P, Crowe B, Abdulnour R-E, et al. Clinical reasoning of a generative artificial intelligence model compared with physicians. JAMA Intern Med. 2024;184: 581&#x2013;583. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2024.0295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2024.0295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10985627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38557971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezgin E, Kocaballi AB, Dolce M, Skeens M, Militello L, Huang Y, et al. Chatbot for social need screening and resource sharing with vulnerable families: Iterative design and evaluation study. JMIR Hum Factors. 2024;11: e57114. doi: 10.2196/57114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/57114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11297373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39028995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocielnik R, Agapie E, Argyle A, Hsieh DT, Yadav K, Taira B, et al. 
HarborBot: A chatbot for social needs screening. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2019;2019: 552&#x2013;561. Available: https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7153089/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7153089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32308849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis P, Perez E, Piktus A, Petroni F, Karpukhin V, Goyal N, et al. 
Retrieval-augmented generation for knowledge-intensive NLP tasks. arXiv [cs.CL]. 2020. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.11401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawte V, Sheth A, Das A. A Survey of Hallucination in &#x201c;Large&#x201d; Foundation Models. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M, Yaramic I, Roy TD. Creating trustworthy LLMs: Dealing with hallucinations in healthcare AI. arXiv [cs.CL]. 2023. doi: 10.20944/preprints202310.1662.v1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20944/preprints202310.1662.v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial Intelligence Risk Management Framework (AI RMF 1.0). NIST AI. 2023. pp. 100&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assuring AI Security and Safety Through AI Regulation. MITRE Presidential Transition Priority Topic Memo. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AI Red Teaming: Applying Software TEVV for AI Evaluations. In: Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency CISA [Internet]. [cited 10 Oct 2025]. Available: https://www.cisa.gov/news-events/news/ai-red-teaming-applying-software-tevv-ai-evaluations</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullwinkel B, Minnich A, Chawla S, Lopez G, Pouliot M, Maxwell W, et al. 
Lessons from red teaming 100 generative AI products. arXiv [cs.AI]. 2025. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2501.07238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonmoy SMTI, Zaman SMM, Jain V, Rani A, Rawte V, Chadha A, et al. 
A comprehensive survey of hallucination mitigation techniques in Large Language Models. arXiv [cs.CL]. 2024. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2401.01313</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A, Krishna S, Gehrmann S, Seshadri M, Pradhan A, Ault T, et al. 
Operationalizing a threat model for red-teaming large language models (LLMs). arXiv [cs.CL]. 2025. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2407.14937</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao P, Debenedetti E, Robey A, Andriushchenko M, Croce F, Sehwag V, et al. 
JailbreakBench: An open robustness benchmark for jailbreaking large language models. arXiv [cs.CR]. 2024. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2404.01318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LLM01:2025 Prompt Injection. In: OWASP Gen AI Security Project [Internet]. OWASP Top 10 for LLM &amp; Generative AI Security; 10
Apr
2024.  [cited 10 Oct 2025]. Available: https://genai.owasp.org/llmrisk/llm01-prompt-injection/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo TY, Huang Y, Chen C, Xing Z. Red teaming ChatGPT via jailbreaking: Bias, Robustness, Reliability and toxicity. arXiv [cs.CL]. 2023. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2301.12867</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gehman S. RealToxicityPrompts: Evaluating Neural Toxic Degeneration in Language Models. Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2020. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N, Han Z, Steneker I, Primack W, Goodside R, Zhang H, et al. 
LLM defenses are not robust to multi-Turn Human Jailbreaks yet. arXiv [cs.LG]. 2024. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2408.15221</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X, Mo F, Wen M, Gu T, Zheng H, Jin H, et al. Multi-turn jailbreaking large Language Models via attention shifting. Proc Conf AAAI Artif Intell. 2025;39: 23814&#x2013;23822. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v39i22.34553</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v39i22.34553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CT, Farah H, Gui H, Rezaei SJ, Bou-Khalil C, Park Y-J, et al. Red teaming ChatGPT in medicine to yield real-world insights on model behavior. NPJ Digit Med. 2025;8: 149. doi: 10.1038/s41746-025-01542-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-025-01542-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11889229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40055532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Jeong H, Chen S, Li SS, Lu M, Alhamoud K, et al. Medical hallucination in foundation models and their impact on healthcare. medRxiv. 2025. doi: 10.1101/2025.02.28.25323115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2025.02.28.25323115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Li X, Zhang M, Jiang EH, Zeng Q, Yu C-H. CARES: Comprehensive evaluation of safety and adversarial robustness in medical LLMs. arXiv [cs.CL]. 2025. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu C, Wu Y, Zhu J, Xu S, Shum K, Zhong R, et al. RAGTruth: A hallucination corpus for developing trustworthy retrieval-augmented language models. Proceedings of the 62nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers). Stroudsburg, PA, USA: Association for Computational Linguistics; 2024. pp. 10862&#x2013;10878. doi: 10.18653/v1/2024.acl-long.585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18653/v1/2024.acl-long.585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Es S, James J, Espinosa Anke L, Schockaert S. RAGAs: Automated evaluation of retrieval augmented generation. Proceedings of the 18th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: System Demonstrations. Stroudsburg, PA, USA: Association for Computational Linguistics; 2024. pp. 150&#x2013;158. doi: 10.18653/v1/2024.eacl-demo.16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18653/v1/2024.eacl-demo.16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezgin E, Jackson DI, Boch S, Davenport M, Skeens M, Dolce M, et al. Digital health technologies for screening and identifying unmet social needs: Scoping review. J Med Internet Res. 2025;27: e78793. doi: 10.2196/78793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/78793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12604432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41217261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fichtenberg CM, Alley DE, Mistry KB. Improving Social Needs intervention research: Key questions for advancing the field. Am J Prev Med. 2019;57: S47&#x2013;S54. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2019.07.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2019.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>[cited 10 Oct 2025]. Available: https://assets.anthropic.com/m/61e7d27f8c8f5919/original/Claude-3-Model-Card.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S, Hilton J, Evans O. TruthfulQA: Measuring how models mimic human falsehoods. Proceedings of the 60th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers). Stroudsburg, PA, USA: Association for Computational Linguistics; 2022. doi: 10.18653/v1/2022.acl-long.229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18653/v1/2022.acl-long.229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartvigsen T, Gabriel S, Palangi H, Sap M, Ray D, Kamar E. ToxiGen: A large-scale machine-generated dataset for adversarial and implicit hate speech detection. arXiv [cs.CL]. 2022. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2203.09509</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu K, Wang J, Zhou J, Wang Z, Chen H, Wang Y, et al. 
PromptRobust: Towards evaluating the robustness of Large Language Models on adversarial prompts. arXiv [cs.CL]. 2023. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2306.04528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeune PL, Mal&#xe9;zieux B, Xiao W, Dora M. Phare: A Safety Probe for Large Language Models. arXiv [cs.CY]. 2025. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.11365</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Z, Liu Y, Chen Y, Chen J, Fang J, Hou L, et al. 
Are reasoning models more prone to hallucination?
arXiv [cs.CL]. 2025. Available: http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.23646</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu NF, Lin K, Hewitt J, Paranjape A, Bevilacqua M, Petroni F, et al. Lost in the middle: How language models use long contexts. Trans Assoc Comput Linguist. 2024;12: 157&#x2013;173. doi: 10.1162/tacl_a_00638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/tacl_a_00638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence HR, Schneider RA, Rubin SB, Matari&#x107; MJ, McDuff DJ, Jones Bell M. The opportunities and risks of large language models in mental health. JMIR Ment Health. 2024;11: e59479. doi: 10.2196/59479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/59479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11301767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39105570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>