<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41374849</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2073-4360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>23</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Polymers</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Polymers (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Dual-Modified Chitosan-Derived Silica Composite Aerogel with Simultaneous Improvement of Mechanical, Flame Retardancy, and Thermal Insulation Properties.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3162</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/polym17233162</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Energy-efficient buildings require materials with low thermal conductivity, and high fire resistance and mechanical properties. Traditional chitosan aerogel is limited by its poor fire resistance and silica aerogel is either brittle or displays a high thermal conductivity. Herein, we report a dual-modified aerogel with high mechanical properties, low thermal conductivity, and excellent fire resistance. Briefly, the chitosan-derived silica aerogel (CA) was first fabricated, followed by loading varying contents of phytate-piperazine (PPA) intumescent flame-retardant. This well-designed aerogel (CA/PPA) combines with the high mechanical strength of chitosan aerogel, the excellent fire resistance function of silica aerogel, and the intumescent flame-retardant performance of PPA. The as-created CA/PPA-2.0 exhibited enhanced mechanical properties, as evidenced by the fact that its compressive strength rose from 1.3 &#xb1; 0.10 to 2.9 &#xb1; 0.23 MPa at 90.0% strain compared to that of neat chitosan aerogel. Additionally, compared to CA, the CA/PPA aerogel with 2.0 wt% PPA exhibits significant fire safety performance. For instance, the peak heat release rate, total heat release, maximum average rate of heat emission, and thermal conductivity were reduced by 62.1%, 55.6%, 48.4%, and 12.5%, respectively. In addition, the CA/PPA-2.0 composite aerogel also exhibits a fire-alarm performance under flame attack. This work introduces a feasible strategy to produce high-performance aerogels with promising applications in construction, aerospace, and thermal insulation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Sicong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering and Technology, Hebei University of Technology, Tianjin 300130, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Innovation Center, Beijing Institute of Technology, Chongqing 401120, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Guifeng</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Aerospace Jianghe Chemical Co., Ltd., Yichang 444200, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Chuang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Innovation Center, Beijing Institute of Technology, Chongqing 401120, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Baisong</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering and Technology, Hebei University of Technology, Tianjin 300130, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Yingxi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering and Technology, Hebei University of Technology, Tianjin 300130, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering and Technology, Hebei University of Technology, Tianjin 300130, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Shaofeng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering and Technology, Hebei University of Technology, Tianjin 300130, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>KFJJ24-06M</GrantID><Agency>Opening project of State Key Laboratory of Explosion Science and Safety Protection (Beijing Institute of Technology)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Polymers (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2073-4360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual-modified aerogel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fire warning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intumescent flame retardant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermal insulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Guifeng Xiang was employed by the company Hubei Aerospace Jianghe Chemical Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. There is no known conflict of financial or personal relationships with other people or organizations that could inappropriately influence the work submitted.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41374849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12693858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym17233162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">polym17233162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mia M.H., Wan Y., Jiang Q., Huang L., Zhou M., Xu J., Gong X., Hu X., Yu Z., He H. A sustainable alginate-based multifunctional porous material with integrated thermal barrier and reversible fire warning for enhanced building protection. Carbohydr. Polym. 2025;358:123563. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2025.123563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2025.123563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40383601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Yao S., Zhou F., Hu M., Shen K., Liu M., Fan C., Wu X. Preparing hydrophobic silica aerogels with superior thermal insulation and fire safety by introducing sepiolite. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;461:139905. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.139905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.139905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Cheng F., Li K., Yao J., Li X., Xia Y. Lightweight, flame retardant Janus carboxymethyl cellulose aerogel with fire-warning properties for smart sensor. Carbohydr. Polym. 2024;328:121730. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2023.121730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2023.121730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38220348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Han Y., Zhang L., Li Z., Yang H., Zhang X., Zhang J. Silica aerogel-PVA dough: A high internal phase composite with superior thermal insulation and gas barrier. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2024;251:110553. doi: 10.1016/j.compscitech.2024.110553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2024.110553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M., Wei Y., Qin A., Xu Y., Xu M., Li B., Liu L. Novel silica hydrogel-based forest fire extinguishing agent: Construction, fire extinguishing performance and mechanism study. J. Clean. Prod. 2025;486:144490. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z.-L., Yang N., Apostolopoulou-Kalkavoura V., Qin B., Ma Z.-Y., Xing W.-Y., Qiao C., Bergstr&#xf6;m L., Antonietti M., Yu S.-H. Fire-Retardant and Thermally Insulating Phenolic-Silica Aerogels. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2018;57:4538&#x2013;4542. doi: 10.1002/anie.201711717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.201711717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29469238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei T.-Y., Lu S.-Y., Chang Y.-C. Transparent, Hydrophobic Composite Aerogels with High Mechanical Strength and Low High-Temperature Thermal Conductivities. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2008;112:11881&#x2013;11886. doi: 10.1021/jp804855v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp804855v</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18729501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantor Z., Wu T., Zeng Z., Gaan S., Lehner S., Jovic M., Bonnin A., Pan Z., Mazrouei-Sebdani Z., Opris D.M., et al. Heterogeneous silica-polyimide aerogel-in-aerogel nanocomposites. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;443:136401. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.136401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.136401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.X., Sepahvand S., Gauvin F., Schollbach K., Brouwers H.J.H., Yu Q. One-pot synthesis of monolithic silica-cellulose aerogel applying a sustainable sodium silicate precursor. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;293:123289. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Liao Y., Lu K., Wang Z., Wang J., Lai L., Xin W., Xiao Y., Xiong S., Ding F. Chitosan/silica hybrid aerogels with synergistic capability for superior hydrophobicity and mechanical robustness. Carbohydr. Polym. 2023;320:121245. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2023.121245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2023.121245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37659825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Zou Y., Liu Y., Cheng B., Hou Y., Huang F. A self-cross-linked core-shell Fe3O4/polyimide composite aerogel: High-mechanical, intelligent fire protection and electromagnetic wave absorption performance. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2025;270:111256. doi: 10.1016/j.compscitech.2025.111256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2025.111256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Chen G., Yang F., Luo Z., Yuan B., Chen X., Wang L. Serendipity discovery of fire early warning function of chitosan film. Carbohydr. Polym. 2022;277:118884. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2021.118884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2021.118884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34893287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Tao J., Yang M., Liu C., Yan C., Zhao Y., Yu C., Zhao H.-B., Rao W. A novel phosphorus-modified silica aerogel for simultaneously improvement of flame retardancy, mechanical and thermal insulation properties in rigid polyurethane foam. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;485:149909. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.149909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.149909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Wu D., Wang T., Liu Q., Jia D. Porous carbon generation by burning starch-based intumescent flame retardants for supercapacitors. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;486:150353. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.150353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.150353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Hu H., Tao B., Yin R., Liu L., Li B. Safe and economical preparation of amino acid-derived bio-based triazine char-forming agent for efficient intumescent flame retardant polypropylene. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;484:141876. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H., Wang J., Ni A., Ding A., Sun Z., Han X. Effect of novel intumescent flame retardant on mechanical and flame retardant properties of continuous glass fibre reinforced polypropylene composites. Compos. Struct. 2018;203:894&#x2013;902. doi: 10.1016/j.compstruct.2018.07.071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compstruct.2018.07.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao F., Peng W., Li K., Yuan B., Fontaine G., Bourbigot S. A highly fire-safe wood hybrid based on delignification and multi-component co-impregnation strategies. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;489:142360. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., Cui X., Mu C., Sun J., Gu X., Li H., Zhang S. Toward a new approach to synchronously improve the fire performance and toughness of polylactic acid by the incorporation of facilely synthesized ammonium polyphosphate derivatives. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2021;150:106595. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2021.106595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2021.106595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Yu B., Liu Y., Cheng B., Wang J., Yan J., Huang F. Novel bio-based nanosheets: Improving the fire safety, electromagnetic shielding and mechanical properties of polylactic acid. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2024;179:108044. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2024.108044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2024.108044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan B., Sun Y., Chen X., Shi Y., Dai H., He S. Poorly-/well-dispersed graphene: Abnormal influence on flammability and fire behavior of intumescent flame retardant. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2018;109:345&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2018.03.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2018.03.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul J., Qamar A., Ahankari S.S., Thomas S., Dufresne A. Chitosan-based aerogels: A new paradigm of advanced green materials for remediation of contaminated water. Carbohydr. Polym. 2024;338:122198. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2024.122198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2024.122198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38763724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Compressive Properties of Polymer Matrix Composite Materials Using a Combined Loading Compression (CLC) Test Fixture. ASTM; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Measuring the Minimum Oxygen Concentration to Support Candle-like Combustion of Plastics (Oxygen Index) ASTM; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Measuring the Comparative Burning Characteristics of Solid Plastics in a Vertical Position. ASTM; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Determining Flammability Characteristics of Plastics and Other Solid Materials Using Microscale Combustion Calorimetry. ASTM; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reaction-to-Fire Tests&#x2014;Heat Release, Smoke Production and Mass Loss Rate&#x2014;Part 3: Guidance on Measurement. International Organization for Standardization; Geneva, Switzerland: 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M.-J., Xia S.-Y., Liu C., Li B. Preparation of Poly(phosphoric acid piperazine) and Its Application as an Effective Flame Retardant for Epoxy Resin. Chin. J. Polym. Sci. 2018;36:655&#x2013;664. doi: 10.1007/s10118-018-2036-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10118-018-2036-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Liu Y., Zou Y., Wang J., Bai F., Yan J., Huang F. Poorly-/well-dispersed Fe3O4: Abnormal influence on electromagnetic wave absorption behavior of high-mechanical performance polyurea. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;493:152833. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.152833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.152833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao X., Hu S., Zhai J., Chen T., Mai Y. Thermal properties and combustion behaviors of flame-retarded glass fiber-reinforced polyamide 6 with piperazine pyrophosphate and aluminum hypophosphite. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2016;125:175&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1007/s10973-016-5391-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-016-5391-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang N.-J., Cao C.-F., Li Y., Zhao L., Zhang G.-D., Gao J.-F., Guan L.-Z., Jiang J.-X., Tang L.-C. Silane grafted graphene oxide papers for improved flame resistance and fast fire alarm response. Compos. Part B Eng. 2019;168:413&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.03.053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.03.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X., Wang X., Cai W., Qiu S., Hu Y., Liew K.M. Studies on Synthesis of Electrochemically Exfoliated Functionalized Graphene and Polylactic Acid/Ferric Phytate Functionalized Graphene Nanocomposites as New Fire Hazard Suppression Materials. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2016;8:25552&#x2013;25562. doi: 10.1021/acsami.6b08373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.6b08373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27588582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z., Wang Z. Synthesis of a bio-based piperazine phytate flame retardant for epoxy resin with improved flame retardancy and smoke suppression. Polym. Adv. Technol. 2021;32:4282&#x2013;4295. doi: 10.1002/pat.5429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pat.5429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y.-Y., Deng C., Du Y.-Y., Huang S.-C., Wang Y.-Z. A novel bio-based flame retardant for polypropylene from phytic acid. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2019;161:298&#x2013;308. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2019.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2019.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao C., Xing W., Ma C., Song L., Hu Y., Zhuang Z. Synthesis of phytic acid-based monomer for UV-Cured coating to improve fire safety of PMMA. Prog. Org. Coat. 2020;140:105497. doi: 10.1016/j.porgcoat.2019.105497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.porgcoat.2019.105497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Wang S., Wang W., Li H., Liu X., Gu X., Bourbigot S., Wang Z., Sun J., Zhang S. The flammability and mechanical properties of poly (lactic acid) composites containing Ni-MOF nanosheets with polyhydroxy groups. Compos. Part B Eng. 2020;183:107568. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecouvet B., Sclavons M., Bailly C., Bourbigot S. A comprehensive study of the synergistic flame retardant mechanisms of halloysite in intumescent polypropylene. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2013;98:2268&#x2013;2281. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2013.08.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2013.08.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Z.-B., Deng C., Tan Y., Chen M.-J., Chen L., Wang Y.-Z. An Efficient Mono-Component Polymeric Intumescent Flame Retardant for Polypropylene: Preparation and Application. Acs Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2014;6:7363&#x2013;7370. doi: 10.1021/am500789q.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/am500789q</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24742305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng C.-L., Du S.-L., Zhao J., Shen Z.-Q., Deng C., Wang Y.-Z. An intumescent flame retardant polypropylene system with simultaneously improved flame retardancy and water resistance. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2014;108:97&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2014.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2014.06.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sai T., Su Y., Shen H., Ran S., Huo S., Guo Z., Fang Z. Fabrication and Mechanism Study of Cerium-Based P, N-Containing Complexes for Reducing Fire Hazards of Polycarbonate with Superior Thermostability and Toughness. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2021;13:30061&#x2013;30075. doi: 10.1021/acsami.1c07153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.1c07153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34132088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu S., Sun J., Li Y., Zhu T., Li H., Gu X., Fei B., Zhang S. Life cycle design of fully bio-based poly(lactic acid) composites with high flame retardancy, UV resistance, and degradation capacity. J. Clean. Prod. 2022;360:132165. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.132165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.132165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo S., Ren Y., Chang R., He Y., Zhang D., Guan F., Yao M. Injectable Self-Healing Adhesive Chitosan Hydrogel with Antioxidative, Antibacterial, and Hemostatic Activities for Rapid Hemostasis and Skin Wound Healing. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2022;14:34455&#x2013;34469. doi: 10.1021/acsami.2c08870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c08870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35857973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian J., Yang Y., Xue T., Chao G., Fan W., Liu T. Highly flexible and compressible polyimide/silica aerogels with integrated double network for thermal insulation and fire-retardancy. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2022;105:194&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1016/j.jmst.2021.07.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2021.07.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N., Yuan R., You D., Zhang Q., Yang R., Wang J., Cheng Q., Ge L. Dual fire-alarm LBL safeguarding coatings with flame-retardant, EMI shielding and antibacterial properties. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2022;643:128763. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.128763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.128763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Li F., Ma L.-P., Cheng H.-M. Advanced Materials for Energy Storage. Adv. Mater. 2010;22:E28&#x2013;E62. doi: 10.1002/adma.200903328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.200903328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20217798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilman J.W. Flammability and thermal stability studies of polymer layered-silicate (clay) nanocomposites. Appl. Clay Sci. 1999;15:31&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1016/S0169-1317(99)00019-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-1317(99)00019-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Q.-R., Gu S., Wang Y.-Z., Chen L. A phosphonate-derived epoxy vitrimer with intrinsic flame retardancy and catalyst-free reprocessability. J. Polym. Sci. 2024;62:3195&#x2013;3205. doi: 10.1002/pol.20230211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pol.20230211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu H., Xiao Z., Zhang P., Guo W., Hu Y., Wang X. Flame retardant, heat insulating and hydrophobic chitosan-derived aerogels for the clean-up of hazardous chemicals. Sci. Total Environ. 2024;908:168261. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.168261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.168261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37918752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Xie H., Lai X., Li H., Gao J., Zeng X. An ultrasensitive fire-warning chitosan/montmorillonite/carbon nanotube composite aerogel with high fire-resistance. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;399:125729. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2020.125729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2020.125729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Li H., Niu G., Wang J., Zhu D. Poly(vinylalcohol)/chitosan-based high-strength, fire-retardant and smoke-suppressant composite aerogels incorporating aluminum species via freeze drying. Compos. Part B Eng. 2021;219:108919. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2021.108919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2021.108919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H., Wu N., Ma X., Niu F. Superior intrinsic flame-retardant phosphorylated chitosan aerogel as fully sustainable thermal insulation bio-based material. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2023;207:110213. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2022.110213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2022.110213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z., Niu Y., Wang S., Su M., Long Y., Sun H., Liang W., Li A. Magnesium hydroxide coated hollow glass microspheres/chitosan composite aerogels with excellent thermal insulation and flame retardancy. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2022;612:35&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2021.12.138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2021.12.138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34974256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varamesh A., Zhu Y., Hu G., Wang H., Rezania H., Li Y., Lu Q., Ren X., Jiang F., Bryant S.L., et al. Fully biobased thermal insulating aerogels with superior fire-retardant and mechanical properties. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;495:153587. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.153587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.153587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J., Yang F., Wu T., Shi J., Zhao H.-B., Rao W. Thermal insulation, flame retardancy, smoke suppression, and reinforcement of rigid polyurethane foam enabled by incorporating a P/Cu-hybrid silica aerogel. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;461:142061. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.142061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.142061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Code for Design of Industrial Equipment and Piping Insulation Engineering. National Standards of China; Beijing, China: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Z.-Q., Xiao Z.-T., Lan X.-Y., Wang X., Hu Y., Song L. Cardanol-derived polybenzoxazine networks integrated with high glass transition temperatures, flame retardancy and toughness. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2025;234:111232. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2025.111232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2025.111232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Feng X., Zhang L., Li M., Liu M., Tian A., Fu S. Cyclotriphosphazene-bridged periodic mesoporous organosilica-integrated cellulose nanofiber anisotropic foam with highly flame-retardant and thermally insulating properties. Chem. Eng. J. 2019;375:121933. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2019.121933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2019.121933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng B., Sun Y., Zhang W., Zhang W., Li D., Yang R. A bio-based flame retardant functionalized boron nitride nanosheet to improve flame retardancy and thermal conductivity of EVA composites. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2026;252:135&#x2013;146. doi: 10.1016/j.jmst.2025.07.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2025.07.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding H., Wang J., Yu P., He H., Wang H., Zhang W., Wang L., Lei Y., Yu B. Rapidly recyclable, monomer recovery and flame-retardant bio-based polyimine networks. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;481:148024. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.148024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.148024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang S., Ma X., Yuan B., Chen G., Sun Y., Huang C., He S., Dai H., Chen X. Modification of halloysite nanotubes with supramolecular self-assembly aggregates for reducing smoke release and fire hazard of polypropylene. Compos. Part B Eng. 2019;177:107371. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi P., Chen F., Li Y., Li H., Gu X., Sun J., Zhang S. A Review of Durable Flame-Retardant Fabrics by Finishing: Fabrication Strategies and Challenges. Adv. Fiber Mater. 2023;5:731&#x2013;763. doi: 10.1007/s42765-023-00255-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42765-023-00255-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J., Xu M., Hu X., Liu L., Xiao X., Li B. A multifunctional epoxy composites based on cellulose nanofiber/carbon nanotube aerogels: Simultaneously enhancing fire-safety, thermal conductive and photothermal performance. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2024;187:108514. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2024.108514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2024.108514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinilla-Pe&#xf1;alver E., Del Fresno &#xd3;., Cantero D., Moreira A., Gomes F., Miranda F., Oliveira M., Ornelas M., S&#xe1;nchez-Silva L., Romero A. Enhancing Flame-Retardant Properties of Polyurethane Aerogels Doped with Silica-Based Particles. Gels. 2024;10:465. doi: 10.3390/gels10070465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels10070465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11276070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39057489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Fu T., Guo D.-M., Lu J.-H., He J.-H., Chen L., Li W.-D., Wang Y.-Z. Trinity flame retardant with benzimidazole structure towards unsaturated polyester possessing high thermal stability, fire-safety and smoke suppression with in-depth insight into the smoke suppression mechanism. Polymer. 2023;275:125928. doi: 10.1016/j.polymer.2023.125928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymer.2023.125928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Huo S., Ye G., Song P., Wang H., Liu Z. A P/Si-containing polyethylenimine curing agent towards transparent, durable fire-safe, mechanically-robust and tough epoxy resins. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;451:138768. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.138768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.138768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Yuan B., Shang S., Zhang H., Shi Y., Yu B., Qi C., Dong H., Chen X., Yang X. Surface modification of ammonium polyphosphate by supramolecular assembly for enhancing fire safety properties of polypropylene. Compos. Part B Eng. 2020;181:107588. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao S., Wang R., Xu Y., Zhang H., Zhang S., Xu M., Liu L., Tao B., Xue H., Li S., et al. Facile construction of a micro-nano structure of green polyvinyl alcohol-based composite aerogel with superior mechanical properties, thermal insulation, and fire safety. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2025;241:111522. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2025.111522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2025.111522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Xu Y., Xu K., Yan C., Qin A., Du C., Xu M., Wang C., Li B., Liu L. Fire-resistant and thermal-insulating alginate aerogel with intelligent bionic armor for exceptional mechanical and fire early-warning performance. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;498:155181. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.155181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.155181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maleki H., Dur&#xe3;es L., Portugal A. Synthesis of mechanically reinforced silica aerogels via surface-initiated reversible addition-fragmentation chain transfer (RAFT) polymerization. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2015;3:1594&#x2013;1600. doi: 10.1039/C4TA05618C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C4TA05618C</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekaran S., Liebig W.V., Mecklenburg M., Fiedler B., Smazna D., Adelung R., Schulte K. Fracture, failure and compression behaviour of a 3D interconnected carbon aerogel (Aerographite) epoxy composite. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2016;122:50&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1016/j.compscitech.2015.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2015.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woignier T., Primera J., Alaoui A., Despetis F., Calas-Etienne S., Faivre A., Duffours L., Levelut C., Etienne P. Techniques for characterizing the mechanical properties of aerogels. J. Sol-Gel Sci. Technol. 2020;93:6&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1007/s10971-019-05173-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10971-019-05173-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Zhang T., Xu H., Li B., Wei G., Zhang X., Zhang J. Ionic liquid-mediated facile synthesis of porous cellulose/silica aerogel composites with improved thermal insulation. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;307:142418. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.142418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.142418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40122427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su L., Jia S., Ren J., Lu X., Guo S.-W., Guo P., Cai Z., Lu D., Niu M., Zhuang L., et al. Strong yet flexible ceramic aerogel. Nat. Commun. 2023;14:7057. doi: 10.1038/s41467-023-42703-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-42703-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10624812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37923727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y., Gu S., Li R., Xue B., Zhou Q., Yuan R., Cong L. Silicon-modified boron nitride aerogels with enhanced thermal stability for thermal insulation applications in high-temperature. J. Alloys Compd. 2025;1036:181759. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.181759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.181759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>