<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851249</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Implanted brain-computer interface functionality during nighttime in late-stage amyotrophic lateral sclerosis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-44228-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brain-computer interfaces (BCIs) hold promise as assistive communication technology for people with severe paralysis. Although such BCIs should be available 24/7, feasibility of nocturnal BCI use has not been investigated. Here, we addressed this question using data from an electrocorticography-BCI user with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. We investigated nocturnal dynamics of neural signal features used for BCI control. Additionally, we assessed nocturnal performance of a decoder trained on daytime data, by quantifying the number of unintentional BCI activations at night. Finally, we developed a nightmode functionality and assessed its performance. Mean and variance of low and high frequency band power were significantly higher at night than during the day. When applied to night data, daytime decoders caused unintentional BCI activations in 100% of nights (245 unintended click-commands and 13 unintended caregiver-calls per hour). The specifically developed nightmode functionality, however, functioned error-free in 79% of nights over a period of &#xb1;&#x2009;1.5 years, allowing the user to reliably call the caregiver. Reliable nighttime use of a BCI requires strategies to adjust to circadian and sleep-related signal changes. This demonstration of a reliable nightmode and its long-term use by an individual with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis underscores the importance of 24/7 BCI reliability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leinders</LastName><ForeName>Sacha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aarnoutse</LastName><ForeName>Erik J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Branco</LastName><ForeName>Mariana P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freudenburg</LastName><ForeName>Zac V</ForeName><Initials>ZV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geukes</LastName><ForeName>Simon H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schippers</LastName><ForeName>Anouck</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verberne</LastName><ForeName>Malinda S W</ForeName><Initials>MSW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Boom</LastName><ForeName>Max A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Vijgh</LastName><ForeName>Benny H</ForeName><Initials>BH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crone</LastName><ForeName>Nathan E</ForeName><Initials>NE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Denison</LastName><ForeName>Timothy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Research Council Brain Network Dynamics Unit, Department of Clinical Neurosciences, University of Oxford, Nuffield, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramsey</LastName><ForeName>Nick F</ForeName><Initials>NF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behavior, Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vansteensel</LastName><ForeName>Mariska J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery, UMC Utrecht Brain Center, University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands. m.j.vansteensel@umcutrecht.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UH3NS114439</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ADV 320708</GrantID><Acronym>ERC_</Acronym><Agency>European Research Council</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UGT7685</GrantID><Agency>Nederlandse Organisatie voor Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01DC016686</GrantID><Acronym>DC</Acronym><Agency>NIDCD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>medRxiv. 2024 Oct 15:2024.10.11.24315027. doi: 10.1101/2024.10.11.24315027.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">39484239</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain-Computer Interface</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Circadian</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrocorticography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Home-use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Night</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: Timothy Denison is a shareholder in Amber Therapeutics, board member at ONWARD, advisory board member and consultant with Cortec Neuro, and consultant with Synchron. Nick F. Ramsey was consultant for the Wyss Center (Geneva). Mariska J. Vansteensel was consultant for GA Capital and former board member ofthe International BCI Society.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-44228-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-44228-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Smith, E. &amp; Delargy, M. Locked-in syndrome. Bmj 330, 406&#x2013;409 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine. Recommendations for use of uniform nomenclature pertinent to patients with severe alterations in consciousness. Arch. Phys. Med. Rehabil. 76, 205&#x2013;209 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corallo, F. et al. Augmentative and alternative communication effects on quality of life in patients with locked-in syndrome and their caregivers. J. stroke Cerebrovasc. Dis. 26, 1929&#x2013;1933 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseau, M. C. et al. Quality of life in patients with locked-in syndrome: Evolution over a 6-year period. Orphanet J. Rare Dis. 10, 1&#x2013;8 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higginbotham, D. J., Shane, H., Russell, S. &amp; Caves, K. Access to AAC: Present, past, and future. Augmentative Altern. communication. 23, 243&#x2013;257 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolas-Alonso, L. F. &amp; Gomez-Gil, J. Brain computer interfaces, a review. sensors 12, 1211&#x2013;1279 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw, J. R., Birbaumer, N., McFarland, D. J., Pfurtscheller, G. &amp; Vaughan, T. M. Brain&#x2013;computer interfaces for communication and control. Clin. Neurophysiol. 113, 767&#x2013;791 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpaw, J. R. &amp; Wolpaw, E. W. Brain-computer interfaces: something new under the sun. Brain-computer interfaces: principles practice, Vol. 14 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg, L. R. et al. Neuronal ensemble control of prosthetic devices by a human with tetraplegia. Nature 442, 164&#x2013;171 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metzger, S. L. et al. A high-performance neuroprosthesis for speech decoding and avatar control. Nature 1&#x2013;10 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-023-06443-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metzger, S. L. et al. Generalizable spelling using a speech neuroprosthesis in an individual with severe limb and vocal paralysis. Nat. Commun. 13, 1&#x2013;15 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, P. et al. Assessment of safety of a fully implanted endovascular brain-computer interface for severe paralysis in 4 patients: The stentrode with thought-controlled digital switch (SWITCH) study. JAMA Neurol. 80, 270&#x2013;278 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moses, D. A. et al. Neuroprosthesis for Decoding Speech in a Paralyzed Person with Anarthria. N Engl. J. Med. 385, 217&#x2013;227 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxley, T. J. et al. Motor neuroprosthesis implanted with neurointerventional surgery improves capacity for activities of daily living tasks in severe paralysis: first in-human experience. J. NeuroIntervent Surg. 13, 102 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandarinath, C. et al. High performance communication by people with paralysis using an intracortical brain-computer interface. Elife 6, e18554 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavisky, S. D. et al. IEEE,. Decoding speech from intracortical multielectrode arrays in dorsal arm/hand areas of human motor cortex. in 93&#x2013;97 (2018). https://doi.org/10.1109/EMBC.2018.8512199</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vansteensel, M. J. et al. Fully implanted brain&#x2013;computer interface in a locked-in patient with ALS. N. Engl. J. Med. 375, 2060&#x2013;2066 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willett, F. R. et al. A high-performance speech neuroprosthesis. Nature 1&#x2013;6 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-023-06377-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willett, F. R., Avansino, D. T., Hochberg, L. R., Henderson, J. M. &amp; Shenoy, K. V. High-performance brain-to-text communication via handwriting. Nature 593, 249&#x2013;254 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vansteensel, M. J. et al. Longevity of a Brain&#x2013;Computer Interface for Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis. N. Engl. J. Med. 391, 619&#x2013;626 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achermann, P. EEG analysis applied to sleep. Epileptologie 26, 28&#x2013;33 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;u&#x161;m&#xe1;kov&#xe1;, K. Human sleep and sleep EEG. Meas. Sci. Rev. 4, 59&#x2013;74 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carli, F. et al. Activation of the motor cortex during phasic rapid eye movement sleep. Ann. Neurol. 79, 326&#x2013;330 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramot, M. et al. Emergence of sensory patterns during sleep highlights differential dynamics of REM and non-REM sleep stages. J. Neurosci. 33, 14715&#x2013;14728 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leinders, S. et al. Using a One-dimensional control signal for two Different output Commands in an implanted BCI. in Proceedings of the 7th Graz Brain-Computer Interface Conference 2017 (2017). https://doi.org/10.3217/978-3-85125-533-1-50</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leinders, S. et al. Dorsolateral prefrontal cortex-based control with an implanted brain&#x2013;computer interface. Sci. Rep. 10, 1&#x2013;10 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantero, J. L., Atienza, M., Madsen, J. R. &amp; Stickgold, R. Gamma EEG dynamics in neocortex and hippocampus during human wakefulness and sleep. Neuroimage 22, 1271&#x2013;1280 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon, I., Kripke, D. F., Youngstedt, S. D. &amp; Elliott, J. A. Actigraphy suggests age-related differences in napping and nocturnal sleep. J. Sleep Res. 12, 87&#x2013;93 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe, T., Matsuoka, T., Ogawa, K., Nittono, H. &amp; Hori, T. Gamma band EEG activity is enhanced after the occurrence of rapid eye movement during human REM sleep. Sleep. Biol. Rhythms. 6, 26&#x2013;33 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matarazzo, L. et al. A systems-level approach to human REM sleep. Rapid Eye Mov. Sleep: Regul. Function. 8, 71 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucia, D., McCombe, P. A., Henderson, R. D. &amp; Ngo, S. T. Disorders of sleep and wakefulness in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a systematic review. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. Frontotemporal Degeneration. 22, 161&#x2013;169 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Sleep in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis of polysomnographic findings. Sleep Med. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sleep.2023.04.014 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrahams, S. Neuropsychological impairment in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis-frontotemporal spectrum disorder. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 19, 655&#x2013;667 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anumanchipalli, G. K., Chartier, J. &amp; Chang, E. F. Speech synthesis from neural decoding of spoken sentences. Nature 568, 493&#x2013;498 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin, D. B. et al. Learned motor patterns are replayed in human motor cortex during sleep. J. Neurosci. 42, 5007&#x2013;5020 (2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>