<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41845935</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Performance, cardioventilatory and perceptual responses to perceived opponent ability during head-to-head cycling competition.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093246</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We aimed to investigate whether cycling competition influences performance and pacing compared to an individual time trial. The second aim was to determine whether performance is further influenced by deceptive or accurate augmented feedback, delivered as an opponent riding at 2% higher power outputs than a previous competitive time trial. Ventilatory, metabolic and perceptual responses were examined. Twelve male cyclists completed six laboratory sessions: (1) incremental test and familiarisation; (2) baseline 20-min individual time trial; (3-4) time trial against a virtual opponent replicating the baseline performance (Competition<sub>BSL</sub>); and (5-6) augmented feedback trials against an opponent riding at 2% higher power outputs than Competition<sub>BSL</sub>, presented as either Accurate (participants informed of the 2% increase) or Deception (told the opponent may have received an ergogenic aid). Power output, pacing, gas exchange, blood lactate, heart rate, ratings of perceived exertion (RPE), and motivation were recorded. Power output was higher only during Accurate (P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.032) compared to Baseline, accompanied by higher perceived exertion and <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"> <mml:semantics> <mml:msub><mml:mover><mml:mi>V</mml:mi> <mml:mo>&#x307;</mml:mo></mml:mover> <mml:mrow><mml:mi>C</mml:mi> <mml:msub><mml:mi>O</mml:mi> <mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:msub> </mml:mrow> </mml:msub> <mml:annotation>${{\dot{V}}_{{\mathrm{C}}{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$</mml:annotation></mml:semantics> </mml:math> . Relative to Baseline, no differences were observed in <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"> <mml:semantics> <mml:msub><mml:mover><mml:mi>V</mml:mi> <mml:mo>&#x307;</mml:mo></mml:mover> <mml:msub><mml:mi>O</mml:mi> <mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:msub> </mml:msub> <mml:annotation>${{\dot{V}}_{{{{\mathrm{O}}}_2}}}$</mml:annotation></mml:semantics> </mml:math> , <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"> <mml:semantics> <mml:msub><mml:mover><mml:mi>V</mml:mi> <mml:mo>&#x307;</mml:mo></mml:mover> <mml:mi>E</mml:mi></mml:msub> <mml:annotation>${{\dot{V}}_{\mathrm{E}}}$</mml:annotation></mml:semantics> </mml:math> , heart rate, RER, post-exercise blood lactate concentration, or motivation in any condition. Linear mixed-effects modelling indicated a curvilinear pacing across time, with no differences in pacing curve between conditions. Our findings may indicate that competitive framing, rather than the mere presence of an opponent, influenced performance during fixed-duration cycling time trial.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Experimental Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matta</LastName><ForeName>Guilherme</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5622-5442</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology &amp; Life Sciences, Canterbury Christ Church University, Canterbury, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edwards</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7314-8186</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Physical Education, Faculty of Liberal Arts and Social Sciences, The Education University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roelands</LastName><ForeName>Bart</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2808-044X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Physiology and Sports Physiotherapy research group (MFYS), Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Sports and Nutrition Research, Riga Stradi&#x146;&#x161; University, Riga, Latvia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hettinga</LastName><ForeName>Florentina</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7027-8126</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Sciences, Faculty of Behavioural and Human Movement Sciences, Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurst</LastName><ForeName>Philip</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9265-2975</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology &amp; Life Sciences, Canterbury Christ Church University, Canterbury, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Canterbury Christ Church University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">competitive behaviour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">expectation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41845935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abbiss, C., Quod, M., Levin, G., Martin, D., &amp; Laursen, P. (2009). Accuracy of the velotron ergometer and SRM power meter. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 30(02), 107&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbiss, C. R., Thompson, K. G., Lipski, M., Meyer, T., &amp; Skorski, S. (2016). Difference in pacing between time&#x2010; and distance&#x2010;based time trials in trained cyclists. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 11(8), 1018&#x2013;1023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansdell, P., Thomas, K., Howatson, G., Amann, M., &amp; Goodall, S. (2018). Deception improves TT performance in well&#x2010;trained cyclists without augmented fatigue. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 50(4), 809.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg, G. A. (1982). Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 14(5), 377&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossi, A. H., Matta, G., &amp; Florida&#x2010;James, G. (2025). Pacing during 24&#x2010;hour mountain bike races&#x2014;a modelling approach. Journal of Sports Sciences. Advance online publication. https://napier-repository.worktribe.com/output/4741165</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossi, A. H., Mesquida, C., Passfield, L., R&#xf8;nnestad, B. R., &amp; Hopker, J. G. (2020). Optimizing interval training through power&#x2010;output variation within the work intervals. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 15(7), 982&#x2013;989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucheit, M., &amp; Laursen, P. (2013). High intensity interval training, solutions to the programming puzzle. Part II: Anaerobic energy, neuromuscular load and practical applications. Sports Medicine, 43(10), 927&#x2013;954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, L. M. (2021). Nutritional approaches to counter performance constraints in high&#x2010;level sports competition. Experimental Physiology, 106(12), 2304&#x2013;2323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbett, J., Barwood, M. J., Ouzounoglou, A., Thelwell, R., &amp; Dicks, M. (2012). Influence of competition on performance and pacing during cycling exercise. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 44(3), 509&#x2013;515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crivoi, E., Renfree, A., Nishimura Vieira, C. Y., Ferreira, D. d. S., Truffi, G. A., &amp; Barroso, R. (2022). Effects of different goal orientations and virtual opponents performance level on pacing strategy and performance in cycling time trials. European Journal of Sport Science, 22(4), 491&#x2013;498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currell, K., &amp; Jeukendrup, A. E. (2008). Validity, reliability and sensitivity of measures of sporting performance. Sports Medicine, 38(4), 297&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies, M. J., Clark, B., Welvaert, M., Skorski, S., Garvican&#x2010;Lewis, L. A., Saunders, P., &amp; Thompson, K. G. (2016). Effect of environmental and feedback interventions on pacing profiles in cycling: A meta&#x2010;analysis. Frontiers in Physiology, 7, 591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducrocq, G., Hureau, T., Meste, O., &amp; Blain, G. (2017). Increased fatigue response to augmented deceptive feedback during cycling time trial. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 49(8), 1541&#x2013;1551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, A. M., Dutton&#x2010;Challis, L., Cottrell, D., Guy, J. H., &amp; Hettinga, F. J. (2018). Impact of active and passive social facilitation on self&#x2010;paced endurance and sprint exercise: Encouragement augments performance and motivation to exercise. British Medical Journal Open Sport &amp; Exercise Medicine, 4(1), e000368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans, M., McClure, T. S., Koutnik, A. P., &amp; Egan, B. (2022). Exogenous ketone supplements in athletic contexts: Past, present, and future. Sports Medicine, 52(Suppl 1), 25&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster, C., Florhaug, J. A., Franklin, J., Gottschall, L., Hrovatin, L. A., Parker, S., Doleshal, P., &amp; Dodge, C. (2001). A new approach to monitoring exercise training. The Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research, 15(1), 109&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hecksteden, A., Pitsch, W., Rosenberger, F., &amp; Meyer, T. (2018). Repeated testing for the assessment of individual response to exercise training. Journal of Applied Physiology, 124(6), 1567&#x2013;1579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hettinga, F. J., Konings, M. J., &amp; Pepping, G.&#x2010;J. (2017). The science of racing against opponents: Affordance competition and the regulation of exercise intensity in head&#x2010;to&#x2010;head competition. Frontiers in Physiology, 8, 118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbert, A. W., Billaut, F., Varley, M. C., &amp; Polman, R. C. (2018). Goal orientation and the presence of competitors influence cycling performance. Frontiers in Psychology, 9, 1212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins, W. G., Hawley, J. A., &amp; Burke, L. M. (1999). Design and analysis of research on sport performance enhancement. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 31(3), 472&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, H. S., Williams, E. L., Bridge, C. A., Marchant, D., Midgley, A. W., Micklewright, D., &amp; Mc Naughton, L. R. (2013). Physiological and psychological effects of deception on pacing strategy and performance: A review. Sports Medicine, 43(12), 1243&#x2013;1257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, H. S., Williams, E. L., Marchant, D., Sparks, S. A., Bridge, C. A., Midgley, A. W., &amp; Mc Naughton, L. R. (2016a). Improvements in cycling time trial performance are not sustained following the acute provision of challenging and deceptive feedback. Frontiers in Physiology, 7, 399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, H. S., Williams, E. L., Marchant, D. C., Sparks, S. A., Bridge, C. A., Midgley, A. W., &amp; Mc Naughton, L. R. (2016b). Deception has no acute or residual effect on cycling time trial performance but negatively effects perceptual responses. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 19(9), 771&#x2013;776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konings, M. J., Foulsham, T., Micklewright, D., &amp; Hettinga, F. (2020). Athlete&#x2010;opponent interdependency alters pacing and information&#x2010;seeking behavior. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 52(1), 153&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konings, M. J., Parkinson, J., Zijdewind, I., &amp; Hettinga, F. J. (2018). Racing an opponent: Alteration of pacing, performance, and muscle&#x2010;force decline but not rating of perceived exertion. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 13(3), 283&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konings, M. J., Schoenmakers, P. P., Walker, A. J., &amp; Hettinga, F. J. (2016). The behavior of an opponent alters pacing decisions in 4&#x2010;km cycling time trials. Physiology &amp; Behavior, 158, 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leo, P., Spragg, J., Podlogar, T., Lawley, J. S., &amp; Mujika, I. (2022). Power profiling and the power&#x2010;duration relationship in cycling: A narrative review. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 122(2), 301&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacInnis, M. J., Thomas, A. C., &amp; Phillips, S. M. (2019). The reliability of 4&#x2010;min and 20&#x2010;min time trials and their relationships to functional threshold power in trained cyclists. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 14(1), 38&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matta, G., Edwards, A., Roelands, B., Hettinga, F., &amp; Hurst, P. (2022). Reproducibility of 20&#x2010;min time&#x2010;trial performance on a virtual cycling platform. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 43(14), 1190&#x2013;1195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews, G., Campbell, S. E., &amp; Falconer, S. (2001). Assessment of motivational states in performance environments. Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting, 45(13), 906&#x2013;910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimmerichter, A., Williams, C., Bachl, N., &amp; Eston, R. (2010). Evaluation of a field test to assess performance in elite cyclists. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 31(03), 160&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parton, B. J., &amp; Neumann, D. L. (2019). The effects of competitiveness and challenge level on virtual reality rowing performance. Psychology of Sport and Exercise, 41, 191&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renfree, A., Martin, L., Micklewright, D., &amp; St Clair Gibson, A. (2014). Application of decision&#x2010;making theory to the regulation of muscular work rate during self&#x2010;paced competitive endurance activity. Sports Medicine, 44(2), 147&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhoden, C. L., West, J., Renfree, A., Corbett, M., &amp; Gibson, A. S. C. (2015). Adaptive self&#x2010;regulation in cycle time trials: Goal pursuit, goal disengagement and the affective experience. Journal of Science and Cycling, 4(3), 44&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei, R., Thompson, K., Chapman, R., Raglin, J., &amp; Mickleborough, T. (2016). Using deception to establish a reproducible improvement in 4&#x2010;km cycling time trial performance. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 37(05), 34&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone, M., Thomas, K., Wilkinson, M., Jones, A., St Clair Gibson, A., &amp; Thompson, K. (2012). Effects of deception on exercise performance: Implications for determinants of fatigue in humans. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 44(3), 534&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone, M. R., Thomas, K., Wilkinson, M., Stevenson, E., St Clair Gibson, A., Jones, A. M., &amp; Thompson, K. G. (2017). Exploring the performance reserve: Effect of different magnitudes of power output deception on 4,000 m cycling time&#x2010;trial performance. PLoS ONE, 12(3), e0173120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss, B. (2002). Social facilitation in motor tasks: A review of research and theory. Psychology of Sport and Exercise, 3(3), 237&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, K., Stone, M. R., Thompson, K. G., Gibson, A. S. C., &amp; Ansley, L. (2012). Reproducibility of pacing strategy during simulated 20&#x2010;km cycling time trials in well&#x2010;trained cyclists. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 112(1), 223&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triplett, N. (1898). The dynamogenic factors in pacemaking and competition. The American Journal of Psychology, 9(4), 507&#x2013;533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana, B., Oliveira, B. R., Inoue, A., Santos, L. E., Santos, T. M., &amp; Pires, F. O. (2025). Exercise expectation changes psychophysiological responses to sprint exercise regardless of changes in pacing and performance. International Journal of Sport and Exercise Psychology, 1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1080/1612197X.2024.2446329</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, E. L., Jones, H. S., Sparks, S., Marchant, D. C., Micklewright, D., &amp; McNaughton, L. R. (2014). Deception studies manipulating centrally acting performance modifiers: A review. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 46(7), 1441&#x2013;1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, E. L., Jones, H. S., Sparks, S. A., Marchant, D. C., Midgley, A. W., Bridge, C. A., &amp; McNaughton, L. R. (2016). Deceptive manipulation of competitive starting strategies influences subsequent pacing, physiological status, and perceptual responses during cycling time trials. Frontiers in Physiology, 7, 536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, E. L., Jones, H. S., Sparks, S. A., Marchant, D. C., Midgley, A. W., &amp; Mc Naughton, L. R. (2015). Competitor presence reduces internal attentional focus and improves 16.1&#xa0;km cycling time trial performance. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 18(4), 486&#x2013;491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, E. L., Massey, H., Sparks, S., Midgley, A. W., Marchant, D. C., Bridge, C. A., &amp; Mcnaughton, L. R. (2015). Altered psychological responses to different magnitudes of deception during cycling. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 47(11), 2423&#x2013;2430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilmore, J. H. (1968). Influence of motivation on physical work capacity and performance. Journal of Applied Physiology, 24(4), 459&#x2013;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood, T., Bui, C. T. L., Lubbock, C., Wilson, J., Jeffrey, S., Lawrence, M., Leung, C., Mashar, D., Sims, N., &amp; Konings, M. J. (2020). Head&#x2010;to&#x2010;head competition does not affect pacing or performance in 1&#xa0;km cycling time trials. Journal of Sports Sciences, 38(1), 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>