<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41522207</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2251-6581</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes and metabolic disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Metab Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genetic susceptibility to type 2 diabetes: Insights from a comprehensive meta-analysis of <i>FABP2</i> polymorphisms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>28</StartPage><MedlinePgn>28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">28</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40200-025-01847-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To investigate the association between the FABP2 (rs1799883) polymorphism and the risk of developing type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) across different populations and genetic models. Type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) is a multicausal condition influenced by both hereditary and environmental determinants. The <i>FABP2</i> (rs1799883) polymorphism has been proposed as a potential hereditary risk factor due to its role in lipid metabolism, though previous findings across populations and genetic models remain inconsistent.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Studies sourced from PubMed, ScienceDirect, EMBASE, and other relevant databases up to June 1, 2025, were used to conduct the meta-analysis. Appropriate case-control studies examining the <i>FABP2</i> polymorphism and T2DM were analyzed under four genetic models. Subgroup analysis by ethnicity, in silico functional predictions (SIFT, PolyPhen-2), and power analysis were also performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 26 studies, including 6032 T2DM patients and 8907 controls, were analyzed. The Ala54Thr variant showed no significant association with T2DM under the allele, dominant, or overdominant models. However, a strong association was identified within the recessive model (AA vs. AT&#x2009;+&#x2009;TT; OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.11, 95% CI: 2.96-5.71, <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.00001). Subgroup analysis revealed significant associations in Asian and Caucasian populations, while a protective effect was noted in other ethnic groups. In silico predictions indicated the variant is functionally tolerated and benign. The analysis had a high statistical power (99%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The Ala54Thr polymorphism of the <i>FABP2</i> gene is significantly associated with higher T2DM risk under a recessive model, notably in Asian and Caucasian populations. These findings support its potential utility as a genetic marker in risk assessment and highlight the importance of ethnicity-specific analysis in understanding T2DM susceptibility.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Tehran University of Medical Sciences 2026. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anilkumar</LastName><ForeName>Anu Shibi</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-9712-1719</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Cytogenetics and Genomics Laboratory, Faculty of Allied Health Sciences, Chettinad Hospital and Research Institute, Chettinad Academy of Research and Education, Kelambakkam, 603103 Tamil Nadu India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0394w2w14</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.448840.4</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Sheena Mariam</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-2904-5421</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Cytogenetics and Genomics Laboratory, Faculty of Allied Health Sciences, Chettinad Hospital and Research Institute, Chettinad Academy of Research and Education, Kelambakkam, 603103 Tamil Nadu India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0394w2w14</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.448840.4</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Veerabathiran</LastName><ForeName>Ramakrishnan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9307-5428</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Cytogenetics and Genomics Laboratory, Faculty of Allied Health Sciences, Chettinad Hospital and Research Institute, Chettinad Academy of Research and Education, Kelambakkam, 603103 Tamil Nadu India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0394w2w14</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.448840.4</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Metab Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2251-6581</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethnicity stratification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FABP2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gene polymorphism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic association</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41522207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12783404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-025-01847-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sugandh F, Chandio M, Raveena F, Kumar L, Karishma F, Khuwaja S, et al. Advances in the management of diabetes mellitus: a focus on personalized medicine. Cureus. 2023;15(8):e43697. 10.7759/cureus.43697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.43697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10505357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37724233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MJ, Al-Mamun M, Islam MR. Diabetes mellitus, the fastest growing global public health concern: Early detection should be focused. Health Sci Rep. 2024;7(3):e2004. 10.1002/hsr2.2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10958528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavithra M, Kavitha S, Chindiya J, Yogalakshmi R, Steffeprissill AA, Haripriya R, et al. Assess the prevalence of type 2 diabetes mellitus among adults at selected areas in Kanchipuram District, Tamilnadu, India. Indian Journal of Public Health Research &amp; Development. 2020;11(3):358&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal S, Rani J, Bhat MA, Vanita V. Genetics of diabetes. World J Diabetes. 2023;14(6):656&#x2013;79. 10.4239/wjd.v14.i6.656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v14.i6.656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10294065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37383588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meigs JB, Cupples LA, Wilson PW. Parental transmission of type 2 diabetes: the Framingham offspring study. Diabetes. 2000;49(12):2201&#x2013;7. 10.2337/diabetes.49.12.2201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diabetes.49.12.2201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11118026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekar G, G M, Krishnan M, Babu S, K P, Konduru P, et al. Effect of &#x3b2;-sitosterol on insulin resistance &amp; protein expression of insulin signalling molecules in quadriceps muscle of high fat diet-induced type-2 diabetic rats. Bioinformation. 2022;18(11):1098&#x2013;104. 10.6026/973206300181098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6026/973206300181098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10484696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37693081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathod L, Khan S, Mishra S, Das D, Bora K, Shubham S, et al. Genetic variants and type 2 diabetes in India: a systematic review and meta-analysis of associated polymorphisms in case-control studies. The Lancet regional health Southeast Asia. 2024;32:100518. 10.1016/j.lansea.2024.100518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lansea.2024.100518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11683328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39737336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albala C, Villarroel A, Santos JL, Angel B, Lera L, Liberman C, et al. FABP2 Ala54Thr polymorphism and diabetes in Chilean elders. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2007;77(2):245&#x2013;50. 10.1016/j.diabres.2006.12.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2006.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17292994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baier LJ, Sacchettini JC, Knowler WC, Eads J, Paolisso G, Tataranni PA, et al. An amino acid substitution in the human intestinal fatty acid binding protein is associated with increased fatty acid binding, increased fat oxidation, and insulin resistance. J Clin Invest. 1995;95(3):1281&#x2013;7. 10.1172/JCI117778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI117778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC441467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7883976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han TK, So WY. Effects of FABP2 Ala54Thr gene polymorphism on obesity and metabolic syndrome in middle-aged Korean women with abdominal obesity. Cent Eur J Public Health. 2019;27(1):37&#x2013;43. 10.21101/cejph.a5077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21101/cejph.a5077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30927395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanby P, Palmquist P, Ryd&#xe9;n I, Brattstr&#xf6;m L, Carlsson M. The FABP2 gene polymorphism in cerebrovascular disease. Acta Neurol Scand. 2004;110(6):355&#x2013;60. 10.1111/j.1600-0404.2004.00335.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.2004.00335.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15527447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida Y, Sugiura S, Nakashima T, Ando F, Shimokata H. The Ala54Thr polymorphism in the fatty acid-binding protein 2 (FABP2) gene is associated with hearing impairment: a preliminary report. Auris Nasus Larynx. 2010;37(4):496&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.anl.2010.01.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anl.2010.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20202768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamberlain AM, Schreiner PJ, Fornage M, Loria CM, Siscovick D, Boerwinkle E. Ala54Thr polymorphism of the fatty acid binding protein 2 gene and saturated fat intake in relation to lipid levels and insulin resistance: the coronary artery risk development in young adults (CARDIA) study. Metab Clin Exp. 2009;58(9):1222&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.metabol.2009.04.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2009.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Yu D, Jin X, Li C, Zhu F, Zheng Z, et al. The association between the <i>FABP2</i> Ala54Thr variant and the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: a meta-analysis based on 11 case-control studies. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2015;8(4):5422&#x2013;9.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4483856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu CJ, Ye XZ, Yu XJ, Peng XR, Li TH. Association between FABP2 Ala54Thr polymorphisms and type 2 diabetes mellitus risk: a huge review and meta-analysis. J Cell Mol Med. 2014;18(12):2530&#x2013;5. 10.1111/jcmm.12385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcmm.12385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4302657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;134:178&#x2013;89. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2021.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2021.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harun-Or-Roshid M, Ali MB, Jesmin, Mollah MNH. Statistical meta-analysis to investigate the association between the Interleukin-6 (IL-6) gene polymorphisms and cancer risk. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(3):e0247055. 10.1371/journal.pone.0247055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0247055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7939379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33684135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harun-Or-Roshid M, Mollah MNH, Jesmin. A comprehensive meta-analysis comprising 149 case-control studies to investigate the association between IL-6 gene rs1800795 polymorphism and multiple disease risk. Gene 861, (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36736866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harun-Or-Roshid M, Ali MB, Jesmin, Mollah MNH. Association of hypoxia inducible factor 1-Alpha gene polymorphisms with multiple disease risks: A comprehensive meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(8):e0273042. 10.1371/journal.pone.0273042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0273042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9380912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35972942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harun-Or-Roshid M, Nurul Haque Mollah M, Jesmin. Association of IL6 gene polymorphisms and neurological disorders: insights from integrated bioinformatics and Meta-Analysis. Neuromol Med. 2025;27(1):9. 10.1007/s12017-025-08831-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12017-025-08831-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39812719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rissanen J, Pihlajam&#xe4;ki J, Heikkinen S, Kek&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen P, Kuusisto J, Laakso M. The Ala54Thr polymorphism of the fatty acid binding protein 2 gene does not influence insulin sensitivity in Finnish nondiabetic and NIDDM subjects. Diabetes. 1997;46(4):711&#x2013;2. 10.2337/diab.46.4.711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diab.46.4.711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9075815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada K, Yuan X, Ishiyama S, Koyama K, Ichikawa F, Koyanagi A, et al. Association between Ala54Thr substitution of the fatty acid-binding protein 2 gene with insulin resistance and intra-abdominal fat thickness in Japanese men. Diabetologia. 1997;40(6):706&#x2013;10. 10.1007/s001250050737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s001250050737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9222651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito K, Nakatani K, Fujii M, Katsuki A, Tsuchihashi K, Murata K, Goto H, Yano Y, Gabazza EC, Sumida Y, Adachi Y. Codon 54 polymorphism of the fatty acid binding protein gene and insulin resistance in the Japanese population. Diabet Medicine: J Br Diabet Association. 1999;16(2):119&#x2013;24. 10.1046/j.1464-5491.1999.00034.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1464-5491.1999.00034.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10229304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei HH, Coresh J, Shuldiner AR, Boerwinkle E, Brancati FL. Variants of the insulin receptor substrate-1 and fatty acid binding protein 2 genes and the risk of type 2 diabetes, obesity, and hyperinsulinemia in African-Americans: the atherosclerosis risk in communities study. Diabetes. 1999;48(9):1868&#x2013;72. 10.2337/diabetes.48.9.1868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diabetes.48.9.1868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10480621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang K, Zheng T, Jia W, Sun D, Ding W, Lu J, Tang J. The impact of codon 54 variation in intestinal fatty acid binding protein gene on the pathogenesis of diabetes mellitus in Chinese. Chin Med J. 1999;112(2):99&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11593593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boullu-Sanchis S, Lepr&#xea;tre F, Hedelin G, Donnet JP, Schaffer P, Froguel P, Pinget M. Type 2 diabetes mellitus: association study of five candidate genes in an Indian population of Guadeloupe, genetic contribution of FABP2 polymorphism. Diabetes Metab. 1999;25(2):150&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10443326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayakawa T, Nagai Y, Nohara E, Yamashita H, Takamura T, Abe T, Nomura G, Kobayashi K. Variation of the fatty acid binding protein 2 gene is not associated with obesity and insulin resistance in Japanese subjects. Metab Clin Exp. 1999;48(5):655&#x2013;7. 10.1016/s0026-0495(99)90067-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0026-0495(99)90067-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10337870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahvanainen E, Molin M, Vainio S, Tiret L, Nicaud V, Farinaro E, et al. Intestinal fatty acid binding protein polymorphism at codon 54 is not associated with postprandial responses to fat and glucose tolerance tests in healthy young Europeans. Results from EARS II participants. Atherosclerosis. 2000;152(2):317&#x2013;25. 10.1016/s0021-9150(99)00488-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0021-9150(99)00488-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10998459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G, Li Q, Hong T, et al. Association between fatty acid-binding protein 2 gene and type 2 diabetes. Clin Genet Res. 2001;14:447&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte NL, Colagiuri S, Palu T, Wang XL, Wilcken DE. Obesity, type II diabetes and the Ala54Thr polymorphism of fatty acid binding protein 2 in the Tongan population. Mol Genet Metab. 2003;79(3):183&#x2013;8. 10.1016/s1096-7192(03)00088-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1096-7192(03)00088-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12855223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guettier JM, Georgopoulos A, Tsai MY, Radha V, Shanthirani S, Deepa R, Gross M, Rao G, Mohan V. Polymorphisms in the fatty acid-binding protein 2 and Apolipoprotein C-III genes are associated with the metabolic syndrome and dyslipidemia in a South Indian population. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90(3):1705&#x2013;11. 10.1210/jc.2004-1338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2004-1338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15598690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher E, Li Y, Burwinkel B, K&#xfc;hr V, Hoffmann K, M&#xf6;hlig M, et al. Preliminary evidence of FABP2 A54T polymorphism associated with reduced risk of type 2 diabetes and obesity in women from a German cohort. Horm Metab Res. 2006;38(5):341&#x2013;5. 10.1055/s-2006-925400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2006-925400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16718632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Fisher E, Klapper M, Boeing H, Pfeiffer A, Hampe J, Schreiber S, Burwinkel B, Schrezenmeir J, D&#xf6;ring F. Association between functional FABP2 promoter haplotype and type 2 diabetes. Hormone Metabolic Res = Hormon- Und Stoffwechselforschung = Horm Et Metab. 2006;38(5):300&#x2013;7. 10.1055/s-2006-925405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2006-925405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16718625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vimaleswaran KS, Radha V, Mohan V. Thr54 allele carriers of the Ala54Thr variant of FABP2 gene have associations with metabolic syndrome and hypertriglyceridemia in urban South Indians. Metab Clin Exp. 2006;55(9):1222&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.metabol.2006.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2006.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16919542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albala B C, Jim&#xe9;nez R B, P&#xe9;rez B F, Liberman G C. Polimorfismo de la prote&#xed;na ligante de &#xe1;cidos grasos intestinal (FABP2), obesidad e insulina resistencia [Fatty acid binding protein 2 (FABP-2) polymorphism, obesity and insulin resistance]. Rev Med Chil. 2006;134(3):372&#x2013;9. 10.4067/s0034-98872006000300017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/s0034-98872006000300017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16676113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavridou A, Arvanitidis KI, Tiptiri-Kourpeti A, Petridis I, Ragia G, Kyroglou S, Christakidis D, Manolopoulos VG. Thr54 allele of fatty-acid binding protein 2 gene is associated with obesity but not type 2 diabetes mellitus in a Caucasian population. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2009;84(2):132&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.diabres.2009.02.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2009.02.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19324445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu L, Salto LM, De Leon KJ, De Leon M. Polymorphisms in fatty acid binding protein 5 show association with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2011;92(1):82&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.diabres.2011.01.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2011.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3078975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21288588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Q, Yan F, Wang X, et al. Association between polymorphism of the fatty acidbinding protein 2 gene and type 2 diabetes. Chin J Med Guide. 2012;14:930&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza ST, Fatima J, Ahmed F, Abbas S, Zaidi ZH, Singh S, et al. Association of angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) and fatty acid binding protein 2 (FABP2) genes polymorphism with type 2 diabetes mellitus in Northern India. J Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone Syst. 2014;15(4):572&#x2013;9. 10.1177/1470320313481082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1470320313481082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharbi KK, Khan IA, Bazzi MD, Al-Daghri NM, Hasan TN, Alnbaheen MS, et al. A54T polymorphism in the fatty acid binding protein 2 studies in a Saudi population with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Lipids Health Dis. 2014;13:61. 10.1186/1476-511X-13-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-511X-13-61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4032166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24690233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikhayeva N, Iskakova A, Saigi-Morgui N, Zholdybaeva E, Eap CB, Ramanculov E. Association between 28 single nucleotide polymorphisms and type 2 diabetes mellitus in the Kazakh population: a case-control study. BMC Med Genet. 2017;18(1):76. 10.1186/s12881-017-0443-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12881-017-0443-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5525290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28738793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza ST, Abbas S, Siddiqi Z, Mahdi F. Association between <i>ACE</i> (rs4646994), <i>FABP2</i> (rs1799883), <i>MTHFR</i> (rs1801133), <i>FTO</i> (rs9939609) genes polymorphism and type 2 diabetes with dyslipidemia. International journal of molecular and cellular medicine. 2017;6(2):121&#x2013;30. 10.22088/acadpub.BUMS.6.2.6.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22088/acadpub.BUMS.6.2.6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5581553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28890888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valeeva FV, Hasanova KB, Valeeva EV. Associacija polimorfizma rs1799883 gena <i>FABP2</i> s razlichnymi narushenijami uglevodnogo obmena u zhitelej Respubliki Tatarstan. Med Al&#x2019;manakh. 2018;6(57):116&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultana T, Raza A, Sultana S, Al-Ghanim KA, Al-Misned F, Shahid T, et al. A54T polymorphism in fatty acid binding protein 2 gene is associated in type 2 diabetes mellitus in adult subjects. J King Saud Univ. 2020;32(1):996&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2019.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mel&#x2019;nikova ES, Rymar OD, Ivanova AA, Mustafina SV, Shapkina MJ, Bobak M, Maljutina SK, Voevoda MI, Maksimov VN. Ter Arkh. 2020;92(10):40&#x2013;7. 10.26442/00403660.2020.10.000393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26442/00403660.2020.10.000393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33346478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durgawale Pratik P, Datkhile Kailas D, Patil Virendra C, Vasant D, V., Satish K, V. Association of genetic polymorphism in leptin, leptin Recptor, resistin and <i>FABP2</i> genes with type II diabetes mellitus in patients of rural South Western Maharashtra. Res J Biotechnol Vol. 2021;16:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal R, Singhal M, Jialal I. (2023). Type 2 Diabetes. In <i>StatPearls</i>. StatPearls Publishing.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30020625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali O. Genetics of type 2 diabetes. World J Diabetes. 2013;4(4):114&#x2013;23. 10.4239/wjd.v4.i4.114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v4.i4.114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23961321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreienkamp RJ, Voight BF, Gloyn AL, Udler MS. Genetics of type 2 diabetes. In: Lawrence JM, editor. al., Diabetes in America. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK); 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38117926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii T, Hirose H, Kawai T, Hayashi K, Maruyama H, Saito I, et al. Effects of intestinal fatty acid-binding protein gene Ala54Thr polymorphism and [beta] 3-adrenergic receptor gene Trp64Arg polymorphism on insulin resistance and fasting plasma glucose in young to older Japanese men. Metab Clin Exp. 2001;50(11):1301&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2001.27228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11699048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss EP, Brown MD, Shuldiner AR, Hagberg JM. Fatty acid binding protein-2 gene variants and insulin resistance: gene and gene-environment interaction effects. Physiol Genomics. 2002;10(3):145&#x2013;57. 10.1152/physiolgenomics.00070.2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physiolgenomics.00070.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12209017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee EJ. Diabetes in Asians. Endocrinol Metab (Seoul). 2015;30(3):263&#x2013;9. 10.3803/EnM.2015.30.3.263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3803/EnM.2015.30.3.263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4595349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26435131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiarella P, Capone P, Sisto R. Contribution of genetic polymorphisms in human health. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(2):912. 10.3390/ijerph20020912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20020912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9858723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36673670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>