<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41516534</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From Light to Energy: Machine Learning Algorithms for Position and Energy Deposition Estimation in Scintillator-SiPM Detectors.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26010101</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Scintillator-SiPM Particle Detectors (SSPDs) are compact, low-power devices with applications including particle physics, underground tomography, cosmic-ray studies, and space instrumentation. They are based on a prism-shaped scintillator with corner-mounted SiPMs. Previous work has demonstrated that analytic algorithms based on a physical model of light propagation can reconstruct particle impinging positions and tracks and estimate deposited energy and Linear Energy Transfer (LET) with moderate accuracy. In this study, we enhance this approach by applying machine learning (ML) methods, specifically gradient boosting techniques, to improve the accuracy of spatial location and energy deposition estimation. Using the GEANT4 simulation toolkit, we simulated cosmic muons and energetic oxygen ions traversing an SSPD, and we trained XGBoost and LightGBM models to predict particle impinging positions and deposited energy. Both algorithms outperformed the analytic baseline. We further investigated hybrid strategies, including hybrid boosting and probing. While hybrid boosting provided no significant improvement, probing yielded measurable gains in both position and LET estimation. These results suggest that ML-driven reconstruction provides a powerful enhancement to SSPD performance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simhony</LastName><ForeName>Yoav</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Raymond and Beverly Sackler School of Physics and Astronomy, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv-Yafo 6997801, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv-Yafo 6997801, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Segal</LastName><ForeName>Alex</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Mathematics, Afeka College of Engineering, Tel Aviv-Yafo 6998812, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amrani</LastName><ForeName>Ofer</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv-Yafo 6997801, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Etzion</LastName><ForeName>Erez</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Raymond and Beverly Sackler School of Physics and Astronomy, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv-Yafo 6997801, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SSPD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gradient boosting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41516534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12788095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26010101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26010101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Simhony Y., Segal A., Orlov Y., Amrani O., Etzion E. Scintillator-SiPM detector for tracking and energy deposition measurements. Nucl. Instruments Methods Phys. Res. Sect. A Accel. Spectrometers Detect. Assoc. Equip. 2024;1069:169955. doi: 10.1016/j.nima.2024.169955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nima.2024.169955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simhony Y., Amrani O., Etzion E. TauSat-3-A 3U CubeSat for investigating variations in solar and galactic cosmic rays; Proceedings of the 43rd COSPAR Scientific Assembly; Virtual. 28 January&#x2013;4 February 2021;  [(accessed on 30 October 2025)]. p. 1520. Available online:  https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2021cosp...43E1520S/abstract.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simhony Y., Segal A., Orlov Y., Bashi D., Amrani O., Etzion E. Spaceborne COTS-Capsule hodoscope: Detecting and characterizing particle radiation. Nucl. Instruments Methods Phys. Res. Sect. A Accel. Spectrometers Detect. Assoc. Equip. 2025;1070:169996. doi: 10.1016/j.nima.2024.169996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nima.2024.169996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heredge J., Archer J., Duffy A., Brown J., Guatelli S., Scutti F., Krishnan S., Webster C. Muon event localisation with AI. Nucl. Instruments Methods Phys. Res. Sect. A Accel. Spectrometers Detect. Assoc. Equip. 2021;1001:165237. doi: 10.1016/j.nima.2021.165237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nima.2021.165237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaari M., Barron U., Dom&#xed;nguez L.P., Chen B., Barak L., Etzion E., Giryes R. Trees vs neural networks for enhancing tau lepton real-time selection in proton-proton collisions. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:21832. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-04767-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-04767-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12217760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40594382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomadakis P., Angelopoulos A., Gavalian G., Chrisochoides N. Using machine learning for particle track identification in the CLAS12 detector. Comput. Phys. Commun. 2022;276:108360. doi: 10.1016/j.cpc.2022.108360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpc.2022.108360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siviero F., Arcidiacono R., Cartiglia N., Costa M., Ferrero M., Legger F., Mandurrino M., Sola V., Staiano A., Tornago M. First application of machine learning algorithms to the position reconstruction in Resistive Silicon Detectors. J. Instrum. 2021;16:P03019. doi: 10.1088/1748-0221/16/03/P03019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-0221/16/03/P03019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel G., Yahiaoui M.B., Comtat C., Jan S., Kochebina O., Martinez J.M., Sergeyeva V., Sharyy V., Sung C.H., Yvon D. Deep Learning reconstruction with uncertainty estimation for &#x3b3; photon interaction in fast scintillator detectors. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 2024;131:107876. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2024.107876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2024.107876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikari P., Ajaj R., Alp&#xed;zar-Venegas M., Amaudruz P.A., Anstey J., Araujo G., Auty D., Baldwin M., Batygov M., Beltran B., et al. Position reconstruction in the DEAP-3600 dark matter search experiment. J. Instrum. 2025;20:P07012. doi: 10.1088/1748-0221/20/07/P07012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-0221/20/07/P07012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ticchi G., Buonanno L., Di Vita D., Canclini F., Carminati M., Camera F., Fiorini C. Embedded artificial intelligence for position sensitivity in thick scintillators. Nucl. Instruments Methods Phys. Res. Sect. A Accel. Spectrometers Detect. Assoc. Equip. 2022;1041:167309. doi: 10.1016/j.nima.2022.167309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nima.2022.167309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buonanno L. Special Topics in Information Technology. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2022. Gamma-Ray Spectroscopy and Imaging with SiPMs Readout of Scintillators: Front-End Electronics and Position Sensitivity Algorithms; pp. 41&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller F., Schug D., Hallen P., Grahe J., Schulz V. A novel DOI positioning algorithm for monolithic scintillator crystals in PET based on gradient tree boosting. IEEE Trans. Radiat. Plasma Med. Sci. 2018;3:465&#x2013;474. doi: 10.1109/TRPMS.2018.2884320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRPMS.2018.2884320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller F., Schug D., Hallen P., Grahe J., Schulz V. Gradient tree boosting-based positioning method for monolithic scintillator crystals in positron emission tomography. IEEE Trans. Radiat. Plasma Med. Sci. 2018;2:411&#x2013;421. doi: 10.1109/TRPMS.2018.2837738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRPMS.2018.2837738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez Gonz&#xe1;lez B., Abascal Ruiz U., Villa Alfageme M., Hurtado Berm&#xfa;dez S.J. Accuracy of Machine Learning Algorithms for Hpge Detector Efficiency Determination. Radiat. Phys. Chem. 2026;239:113328. doi: 10.1016/j.radphyschem.2025.113328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radphyschem.2025.113328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yesilkanat C.M., Celik N., Celik A., Cevik U. Interpretable machine learning for rapid prediction and calibration of HPGe detector efficiency: A physics-informed approach and online platform. J. Radioanal. Nucl. Chem. 2025;334:7231&#x2013;7253. doi: 10.1007/s10967-025-10422-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10967-025-10422-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didona D., Quaglia F., Romano P., Torre E. Enhancing performance prediction robustness by combining analytical modeling and machine learning; Proceedings of the 6th ACM/SPEC International Conference on Performance Engineering; Austin, TX, USA. 31 January&#x2013;4 February 2015; pp. 145&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agostinelli S., Allison J., Amako K., Apostolakis J., Araujo H., Arce P., Asai M., Axen D., Banerjee S., Barrand G., et al. GEANT4&#x2014;A simulation toolkit. Nucl. Instrum. Meth. A. 2003;506:250&#x2013;303. doi: 10.1016/S0168-9002(03)01368-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0168-9002(03)01368-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T., Guestrin C. Xgboost: A scalable tree boosting system; Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining; San Francisco, CA, USA. 13&#x2013;17 August 2016; pp. 785&#x2013;794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke G., Meng Q., Finley T., Wang T., Chen W., Ma W., Ye Q., Liu T.Y. Lightgbm: A highly efficient gradient boosting decision tree. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2017;30:52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiba T., Sano S., Yanase T., Ohta T., Koyama M. Optuna: A next-generation hyperparameter optimization framework; Proceedings of the 25th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery &amp; Data Mining; Anchorage, AK, USA. 4&#x2013;8 August 2019; pp. 2623&#x2013;2631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargiulo R., Ciccarella V., Di Meco E., Diociaiuti E., Sarra I. Development of a sub-mm particle tracking detector based on a plastic scintillator with SiPM charge sharing. J. Instrum. 2024;19:T12006. doi: 10.1088/1748-0221/19/12/T12006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-0221/19/12/T12006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>