<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41405668</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1591-9528</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and experimental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrate bulk RNA and single-cell sequencing to identify prognostic genes associated with dietary restriction and circadian rhythm in colorectal cancer and conduct experimental verification.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>58</StartPage><MedlinePgn>58</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">58</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10238-025-01993-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Colorectal cancer (CRC) is an aggressive malignancy with a poor prognosis. Recent research has focused on the impact of dietary restriction (DR) and circadian rhythm (CR) on cancer; however, the roles of DR-related genes (DRRGs) and CR-related genes (CRRGs) in CRC remain poorly understood. Bulk RNA and single-cell sequencing data for CRC were retrieved from public databases, while DRRGs and CRRGs were compiled from existing literature. Prognostic genes were identified through univariate Cox regression and machine learning approaches. A prognostic risk model and a clinically applicable nomogram were developed. Differences in functional pathways, tumor microenvironment characteristics, and drug sensitivities were analyzed between the high-risk cohort (HRC) and the low-risk cohort (LRC). The expression of prognostic genes was assessed at the single-cell level and validated in clinical samples. Five prognostic genes, namely SOCS3, MMP3, SLC3A1, FABP4, and SERPINE1, were identified. Both the model and nomogram demonstrated strong predictive power. LRC was primarily associated with DNA replication pathways, whereas HRC exhibited higher ESTIMATE, immune, stromal, and TIDE scores, with significant differences across 24 immune cell types. Sensitivity to 61 drugs was observed in HRC, while 56 drugs were sensitive to LRC. Single-cell analysis highlighted fibroblasts as key cells, with dynamic expression of FABP4 and SOCS3 during differentiation. With the exception of SERPINE1, prognostic genes showed differential expression in clinical samples. The risk model effectively predicts CRC prognosis and emphasizes the prognostic relevance of DRRGs and CRRGs, offering novel insights for personalized CRC therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s10238-025-01993-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Dongqiang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, No. 82 Cu&#xec;y&#x12b;ng Gate, Chengguan District, Gansu, Lanzhou, 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, Gansu, Lanzhou, 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yalan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second School of Clinical Medicine, Lanzhou University, Gansu, Lanzhou, 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jiaxing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second School of Clinical Medicine, Lanzhou University, Gansu, Lanzhou, 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Wenzhang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second School of Clinical Medicine, Lanzhou University, Gansu, Lanzhou, 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Fan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Second School of Clinical Medicine, Lanzhou University, Gansu, Lanzhou, 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yumin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9267-1412</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, No. 82 Cu&#xec;y&#x12b;ng Gate, Chengguan District, Gansu, Lanzhou, 730030, China. liym@lzu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>(Grant number lzujbky-2022-sp08</GrantID><Agency>the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of Lanzhou University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant numbers&#xa0;22ZD6FA050 and 22JR9KA002</GrantID><Agency>Major Science and Technology Project of Gansu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Grant number 2021jyjbgs-02</GrantID><Agency>Project of Gansu Provincial Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022-2024</GrantID><Agency>Project of Gansu Provincial Development and Reform Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Exp Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100973405</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1591-8890</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Circadian rhythm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Colorectal cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic genes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval: This study was performed in line with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Approval was granted by the ethics committees of Lanzhou University Second Hospital, Lanzhou, China (ethical code: 2025&#xa0;A-425; date of approval: 27 March 2025). Consent to participate: Informed consent was obtained from all individual participants included in the study. Consent to publish: NA. Permission to reproduce material from other sources: Additional materials from this study are available by contacting the corresponding author at email: liym@lzu.edu.cn.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41405668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12712030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10238-025-01993-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10238-025-01993-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Liu Y, Wang X, Zhang C, Hou M, Liu Y. Integration of single-cell RNA sequencing and bulk RNA transcriptome sequencing reveals a heterogeneous immune landscape and pivotal cell subpopulations associated with colorectal cancer prognosis. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1184167. 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1184167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1184167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10477986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37675100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Ma X, Chakravarti D, Shalapour S, DePinho RA. Genetic and biological hallmarks of colorectal cancer. Genes Dev. 2021;35:787&#x2013;820. 10.1101/gad.348226.120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gad.348226.120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8168558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34074695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baidoun F, Elshiwy K, Elkeraie Y, Merjaneh Z, Khoudari G, Sarmini MT, et al. Colorectal cancer epidemiology: recent trends and impact on outcomes. Curr Drug Targets. 2021;22:998&#x2013;1009. 10.2174/1389450121999201117115717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1389450121999201117115717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33208072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H, Liu H, Li H, Dou W, Wang J, Zhang J, et al. Characterization of stem cell landscape and identification of stemness-relevant prognostic gene signature to aid immunotherapy in colorectal cancer. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2022;13:244. 10.1186/s13287-022-02913-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13287-022-02913-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9185878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35681225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Ho JWC, Fong DYT, Lee CF, Macfarlane DJ, Cerin E, et al. Effects of dietary and physical activity interventions on generic and cancer-specific health-related quality of life, anxiety, and depression in colorectal cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. J Cancer Surviv. 2020;14:424&#x2013;33. 10.1007/s11764-020-00864-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-020-00864-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32072434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun SK, Fortin BM, Fellows RC, Habowski AN, Verlande A, Song WA, et al. Disruption of the circadian clock drives apc loss of heterozygosity to accelerate colorectal cancer. Sci Adv. 2022;8:eabo2389. 10.1126/sciadv.abo2389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abo2389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9365282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35947664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou E, Rifkin S. Colorectal cancer and diet: risk versus Prevention, is diet an intervention? Gastroenterol. Clin North Am. 2021;50:101&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.gtc.2020.10.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gtc.2020.10.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33518157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JL, Xu X, Rixiati Y, Wang CY, Ni HL, Chen WS, et al. Dysfunctional circadian clock accelerates cancer metastasis by intestinal microbiota triggering accumulation of myeloid-derived suppressor cells. Cell Metab. 2024;36:1320&#x2013;e349. 10.1016/j.cmet.2024.04.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2024.04.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38838643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adafer R, Messaadi W, Meddahi M, Patey A, Haderbache A, Bayen S, et al. Food Timing, Circadian Rhythm and Chrononutrition: A Systematic Review of Time-Restricted Eating's Effects on Human Health. Nutrients. 2020;12. 10.3390/nu12123770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tognini P, Murakami M, Liu Y, Eckel-Mahan KL, Newman JC, Verdin E, et al. Distinct Circadian Signatures in Liver and Gut Clocks Revealed by Ketogenic Diet. Cell Metab. 2017;26:523-38.e5. 10.1016/j.cmet.2017.08.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28877456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Young KP, Bottera AR. A biobehavioral circadian model of restrictive eating and binge eating. Int J Eat Disord. 2022;55:1291-5. 10.1002/eat.23758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35704385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo M, Wang Q, Sun Y, Jiang Y, Wang Q, Gu Y, et al. Fasting-mimicking diet remodels gut microbiota and suppresses colorectal cancer progression. NPJ Biofilms Microbiomes. 2024;10:53. 10.1038/s41522-024-00520-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41522-024-00520-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11199600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38918380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Almeida CV, de Camargo MR, Russo E, Amedei A. Role of diet and gut microbiota on colorectal cancer Immunomodulation. World J Gastroenterol. 2019;25:151&#x2013;62. 10.3748/wjg.v25.i2.151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v25.i2.151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6337022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolinjivadi AM, Chong ST, Ngeow J. Molecular connections between circadian rhythm and genome maintenance pathways. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2021;28:R55-r66. 10.1530/erc-20-0372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33300498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia K, Levine B. Autophagy is required for dietary restriction-mediated life span extension in C. elegans. Autophagy. 2007;3:597-9. 10.4161/auto.4989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17912023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pe&#xf1;alver Bernab&#xe9; B, Oliveira ML, Wolf PG, McLeod A, Gabel K, Cares K, et al. Intermittent fasting: implications for Obesity-Related colorectal tumorigenesis. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am. 2025;54:61&#x2013;83. 10.1016/j.ecl.2024.10.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecl.2024.10.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12240480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39919878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding L, Liu J, Zhou L, Jia X, Li S, Zhang Q, et al. A high-fat diet disrupts the hepatic and adipose circadian rhythms and modulates the diurnal rhythm of gut microbiota-derived short-chain fatty acids in gestational mice. Front Nutr. 2022;9:925390. 10.3389/fnut.2022.925390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9554467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36245521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaziri-Moghadam A, Foroughmand-Araabi MH. Integrating machine learning and bioinformatics approaches for identifying novel diagnostic gene biomarkers in colorectal cancer. Sci Rep. 2024;14:24786. 10.1038/s41598-024-75438-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11494190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39433800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie S, Cai Y, Chen D, Xiang Y, Cai W, Mao J, et al. Single-cell transcriptome analysis reveals heterogeneity and convergence of the tumor microenvironment in colorectal cancer. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1003419. 10.3389/fimmu.2022.1003419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36685571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R, Chen X, Liang J, Chen Q, Tian H, Yang C, et al. A circadian rhythm-related gene signature associated with tumor immunity, cisplatin efficacy, and prognosis in bladder cancer. Aging. 2021;13:25153&#x2013;79. 10.18632/aging.203733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.203733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8714136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34862329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X, Wei J, Li Y, Zhu W, Cai Z, Li K, et al. An integrative pan-cancer analysis of the molecular characteristics of dietary restriction in tumour microenvironment. EBioMedicine. 2024;102:105078. 10.1016/j.ebiom.2024.105078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebiom.2024.105078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10965464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38507875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsch&#xf6;pe C, Spillmann F, Potapov E, Faragli A, Rapis K, Nelki V, et al. The TIDE-Algorithm for the weaning of patients with cardiogenic shock and temporarily mechanical left ventricular support with impella Devices. A cardiovascular Physiology-Based approach. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:563484. 10.3389/fcvm.2021.563484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2021.563484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7933542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33681302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livak KJ, Schmittgen TD. Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2(-Delta delta C(T)) method. Methods. 2001;25:402&#x2013;8. 10.1006/meth.2001.1262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/meth.2001.1262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Rawi NH, Rizvi Z, Mkadmi S, Abu Kou R, Elmabrouk N, Alrashdan MS, et al. Differential expression profile of salivary OncomiRNAs among smokeless tobacco users. Eur J Dent. 2023;17:1215&#x2013;20. 10.1055/s-0043-1761191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-1761191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10756836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36812928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahai E, Astsaturov I, Cukierman E, DeNardo DG, Egeblad M, Evans RM, et al. A framework for advancing our Understanding of cancer-associated fibroblasts. Nat Rev Cancer. 2020;20:174&#x2013;86. 10.1038/s41568-019-0238-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41568-019-0238-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7046529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31980749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimeck L, Heisser T, Hoffmeister M, Brenner H. Colorectal cancer: A health and economic problem. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2023;66:101839. 10.1016/j.bpg.2023.101839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpg.2023.101839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37852707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nfonsam V, Wusterbarth E, Gong A, Vij P. Early-Onset colorectal cancer. Surg Oncol Clin N Am. 2022. 10.1016/j.soc.2021.11.001. 31:143&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soc.2021.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35351270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Ling Z, Li L. The intestinal microbiota and colorectal cancer. Front Immunol. 2020;11:615056. 10.3389/fimmu.2020.615056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2020.615056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33329610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orlich MJ, Singh PN, Sabat&#xe9; J, Fan J, Sveen L, Bennett H, et al. Vegetarian dietary patterns and the risk of colorectal cancers. JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175:767&#x2013;76. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2015.59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2015.59</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4420687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25751512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai XC, Zhang YH, Huang YL, Wu XT, Fang YJ, Gao YJ, et al. Calorie restriction remodels gut microbiota and suppresses tumorigenesis of colorectal cancer in mice. Exp Ther Med. 2023;25:59. 10.3892/etm.2022.11758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2022.11758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9780522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36588818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Yang Z, Chen B, Gu L, Tian G, Sui X. SOCS3 as a potential driver of lung metastasis in colon cancer patients. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1088542. 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1088542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1088542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10070831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37025997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Wang X. Research advances on suppressor of cytokine signaling 3 (SOCS3) in animal carbohydrate and lipid metabolism processes. Pak J Biol Sci. 2022;25:1100&#x2013;8. 10.3923/pjbs.2022.1100.1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/pjbs.2022.1100.1108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36978278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morelli M, Madonna S, Albanesi C. SOCS1 and SOCS3 as key checkpoint molecules in the immune responses associated to skin inflammation and malignant transformation. Front Immunol. 2024;15:1393799. 10.3389/fimmu.2024.1393799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2024.1393799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11224294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38975347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, de Haar C, Peppelenbosch MP, van der Woude CJ. SOCS3 in immune regulation of inflammatory bowel disease and inflammatory bowel disease-related cancer. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2012;23:127&#x2013;38. 10.1016/j.cytogfr.2012.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cytogfr.2012.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22591635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Yan Z, Yang W, Buckley JA, Al Diffalha S, Benveniste EN, et al. Socs3 expression in myeloid cells modulates the pathogenesis of dextran sulfate sodium (DSS)-induced colitis. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1163987. 10.3389/fimmu.2023.1163987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2023.1163987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10239850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37283760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Hong S, Song Y, Bi M. microR-4449 promotes colorectal cancer cell proliferation via regulation of SOCS3 and activation of STAT3 signaling. Cancer Manag Res. 2021;13:3029&#x2013;39. 10.2147/cmar.S266153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/cmar.S266153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8039016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33854373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan DE, Rai R, Khan SS, Eren M, Ghosh AK. Plasminogen activator Inhibitor-1 is a marker and a mediator of senescence. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2017;37:1446&#x2013;52. 10.1161/atvbaha.117.309451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/atvbaha.117.309451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5846199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28572158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Li F, Xu Z, Li L, Hu H, Li Y, et al. Identification and validation of SERPINE1 as a prognostic and immunological biomarker in pan-cancer and in CcRCC. Front Pharmacol. 2023;14:1213891. 10.3389/fphar.2023.1213891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2023.1213891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10482042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37680718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Wang X, Lai J, Mao S, Li H. Unraveling a novel hippo-associated immunological prognostic signature: the contribution of SERPINE1 in facilitating colorectal cancer progression via the Notch signaling pathway. Genomics. 2024;116:110794. 10.1016/j.ygeno.2024.110794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygeno.2024.110794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38224823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Zhang JW, Xu H, Chen X, Gao Y, Jiang HG, et al. Therapy-induced senescent tumor cell-derived extracellular vesicles promote colorectal cancer progression through SERPINE1-mediated NF-&#x3ba;B p65 nuclear translocation. Mol Cancer. 2024;23:70. 10.1186/s12943-024-01985-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12943-024-01985-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38576002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x15f;ar&#x131;r Sivri FN, &#xc7;ift&#xe7;i S. A new insight into fatty acid binding protein 4 mechanisms and therapeutic implications in Obesity-Associated diseases: A mini review. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2024;68:e2300840. 10.1002/mnfr.202300840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mnfr.202300840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38593305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luis G, Godfroid A, Nishiumi S, Cimino J, Blacher S, Maquoi E, et al. Tumor resistance to ferroptosis driven by Stearoyl-CoA Desaturase-1 (SCD1) in cancer cells and fatty acid biding Protein-4 (FABP4) in tumor microenvironment promote tumor recurrence. Redox Biol. 2021;43:102006. 10.1016/j.redox.2021.102006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.redox.2021.102006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8163990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34030117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Liu S, Li Y, Fan Z, Meng Y, Zhou B, et al. FABP4 in macrophages facilitates obesity-associated pancreatic cancer progression via the NLRP3/IL-1&#x3b2; axis. Cancer Lett. 2023;575:216403. 10.1016/j.canlet.2023.216403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canlet.2023.216403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37741433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Wang Y, Wang X, Ma J, Wei M, Li N, et al. FABP4 Regulates Cell Proliferation, Stemness, Apoptosis, and Glycolysis in Colorectal Cancer via Modulating ROS/ERK/mTOR Pathway. Discov Med. 2023;35:361&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37272103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng YC, Chen MY, Yadav VK, Pikatan NW, Fong IH, Kuo KT, et al. Targeting FABP4/UCP2 axis to overcome cetuximab resistance in obesity-driven CRC with drug-tolerant persister cells. Transl Oncol. 2025;53:102274. 10.1016/j.tranon.2025.102274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11787020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39823981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang W, Xia M, Xie Z, An F, Zhan Q, et al. High expression of FABP4 in colorectal cancer and its clinical significance. J Zhejiang Univ Sci B. 2021;22:136&#x2013;45. 10.1631/jzus.B2000366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1631/jzus.B2000366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7897597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33615754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polz A, Morshed K, Drop B, Polz-Dacewicz M. Could MMP3 and MMP9 serve as biomarkers in EBV-Related oropharyngeal cancer. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25. 10.3390/ijms25052561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10931672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38473807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintero-Fabi&#xe1;n S, Arreola R, Becerril-Villanueva E, Torres-Romero JC, Arana-Arg&#xe1;ez V, Lara-Riegos J, et al. Role of matrix metalloproteinases in angiogenesis and cancer. Front Oncol. 2019;9:1370. 10.3389/fonc.2019.01370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2019.01370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6915110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31921634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, Kang Q, Chan KI, Zhang Y, Zhong Z, Tan W. The Immunomodulatory role of matrix metalloproteinases in colitis-associated cancer. Front Immunol. 2022;13:1093990. 10.3389/fimmu.2022.1093990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.1093990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9910179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36776395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Chi H, Liao X, Cen S, Zou Y. The glabridin from Huangqin Decoction prevents the development of ulcerative colitis into colitis-Associated colorectal cancer by modulating MMP1/MMP3 activity. Int Immunopharmacol. 2024;135:112262. 10.1016/j.intimp.2024.112262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2024.112262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38805906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bufu T, Di X, Yilin Z, Gege L, Xi C, Ling W. Celastrol inhibits colorectal cancer cell proliferation and migration through suppression of MMP3 and MMP7 by the PI3K/AKT signaling pathway. Anticancer Drugs. 2018;29:530&#x2013;8. 10.1097/cad.0000000000000621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/cad.0000000000000621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29553945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Zhao Y, Xue X, Hou X, Xu H, Zhao X, et al. Novel compound heterozygous pathogenic variants in the SLC3A1 gene in a Chinese family with cystinuria. BMC Med Genomics. 2023;16:333. 10.1186/s12920-023-01767-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12920-023-01767-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10731833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38114997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, Cao Y, Wang Y, Li W, Liu X, Lv Y, et al. Cysteine transporter SLC3A1 promotes breast cancer tumorigenesis. Theranostics. 2017;7:1036&#x2013;46. 10.7150/thno.18005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/thno.18005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5381264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28382174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomohiro M, Matsumoto T, Miura R, Oguri Y, Yokoi A, Tochimoto M, et al. Alterations in &#x3b2;-catenin, microsatellite instability, and HNF-1&#x3b2; levels are independently associated with ovarian endometriosis-associated tumorigenesis. Hum Pathol. 2019;89:10&#x2013;23. 10.1016/j.humpath.2019.04.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humpath.2019.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31022415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia J, Ma N, Shi Q, Liu QC, Zhang W, Cao HJ, et al. XAF1 promotes colorectal cancer metastasis via VCP-RNF114-JUP axis. J Cell Biol. 2024;223. 10.1083/jcb.202303015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10720657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38095639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Wagle NS, Cercek A, Smith RA, Jemal A. Colorectal cancer statistics, 2023. CA Cancer J Clin. 2023;73:233&#x2013;54. 10.3322/caac.21772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36856579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv J, Liu YY, Jia YT, He JL, Dai GY, Guo P, et al. A nomogram model for predicting prognosis of obstructive colorectal cancer. World J Surg Oncol. 2021;19:337. 10.1186/s12957-021-02445-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12957-021-02445-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8638364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34857001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastrinos F, Kupfer SS, Gupta S. Colorectal cancer risk assessment and precision approaches to screening: brave new world or worlds apart? Gastroenterology. 2023;164:812&#x2013;27. 10.1053/j.gastro.2023.02.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2023.02.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10370261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36841490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li BW, Ma XY, Lai S, Sun X, Sun MJ, Chang B. Development and validation of a prognostic nomogram for colorectal cancer after surgery. World J Clin Cases. 2021;9:5860&#x2013;72. 10.12998/wjcc.v9.i21.5860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v9.i21.5860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8316929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34368305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Chen X, Jin C, Mo J, Jiang H, Yi B, et al. A novel immune-related genes prognosis biomarker for hepatocellular carcinoma. Aging. 2020;13:675&#x2013;93. 10.18632/aging.202173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.202173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33260154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X, Li Y, Chen D, Xu X, Liu F, Zhao F. Nomogram predicting the survival of Young-Onset patients with colorectal cancer liver metastases. Diagnostics (Basel). 2022;12. 10.3390/diagnostics12061395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9221975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35741205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Li F, Jia B, Wu Z, Huang Z, He M, et al. Intranasal delivery of small extracellular vesicles reduces the progress of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and the overactivation of complement-coagulation cascade and NF-&#x138;B signaling in SOD1(G93A) mice. J Nanobiotechnol. 2024;22:503. 10.1186/s12951-024-02764-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12951-024-02764-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11340036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39174972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydbirk R, &#xd8;stergaard O, Folke J, Hempel C, DellaValle B, Andresen TL, et al. Brain proteome profiling implicates the complement and coagulation cascade in multiple system atrophy brain pathology. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2022;79:336. 10.1007/s00018-022-04378-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-022-04378-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9164190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35657417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Yuan K, Wang Y, Xu M, Cai S, Chen C, et al. Identification of candidate biomarkers and prognostic analysis in colorectal cancer liver metastases. Front Oncol. 2021;11:652354. 10.3389/fonc.2021.652354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2021.652354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8371911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34422629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L, Zeng X, Liang S, Wang Y, Dai X, Sun Y, et al. Construction of a co-expression network and prediction of metastasis markers in colorectal cancer patients with liver metastasis. J Gastrointest Oncol. 2022;13:2426&#x2013;38. 10.21037/jgo-22-965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jgo-22-965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9660078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36388701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Li Y, Liu C, Kang Y, Qin D, Chen S, et al. In situ engineering of Tumor-Associated macrophages via a Nanodrug-Delivering-Drug (&#x3b2;-Elemene@Stanene) strategy for enhanced cancer Chemo-Immunotherapy. Angew Chem Int Ed Engl. 2023;62:e202308413. 10.1002/anie.202308413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202308413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37380606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhang Z, Shi Y, Zhang W, Su C, Wang D. Construction of a novel Mitochondria-Associated gene model for assessing ESCC immune microenvironment and predicting survival. J Microbiol Biotechnol. 2024;34:1164&#x2013;77. 10.4014/jmb.2310.10052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4014/jmb.2310.10052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11180922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38719775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao T, Siu IM, Williamson T, Zhang H, Ji C, Burger PC, et al. AZD8055 enhances in vivo efficacy of Afatinib in Chordomas. J Pathol. 2021;255:72&#x2013;83. 10.1002/path.5739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/path.5739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34124783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Lee CH, Tseng BY, Tsai YH, Tsai HW, Yao CL, et al. AZD8055 exerts antitumor effects on colon cancer cells by inhibiting mTOR and Cell-cycle progression. Anticancer Res. 2018;38:1445&#x2013;54. 10.21873/anticanres.12369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/anticanres.12369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29491070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu W, Zhang Y, Ning J, Li M, Tang Y, Li L, et al. Anti-tumor effect of AZD8055 against bladder cancer and bladder cancer-associated macrophages. Heliyon. 2023;9:e14272. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e14272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e14272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10020012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36938467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng Z, Wang X, Ding X, Zheng Y, Guo A, Cui J, et al. Exosomal miRNA-92a derived from cancer-associated fibroblasts promote invasion and metastasis in breast cancer by regulating G3BP2. Cell Signal. 2024;119:111182. 10.1016/j.cellsig.2024.111182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cellsig.2024.111182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38640983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agorku DJ, Bosio A, Alves F, Str&#xf6;bel P, Hardt O. Colorectal cancer-associated fibroblasts inhibit effector T cells via NECTIN2 signaling. Cancer Lett. 2024;595:216985. 10.1016/j.canlet.2024.216985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canlet.2024.216985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38821255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Z, Ren Z, Tong Z, Zhu Y, Zhu Y, Hu K. Interactions between MFAP5&#x2009;+&#x2009;fibroblasts and tumor-infiltrating myeloid cells shape the malignant microenvironment of colorectal cancer. J Transl Med. 2023;21:405. 10.1186/s12967-023-04281-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-023-04281-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10286363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37344903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Z, Ye M, Ding H, Feng Z, Hu K. Spatial transcriptomics atlas reveals the crosstalk between cancer-associated fibroblasts and tumor microenvironment components in colorectal cancer. J Transl Med. 2022;20:302. 10.1186/s12967-022-03510-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-022-03510-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9258101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35794563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi J, Sun H, Zhang Y, Wang Z, Xun Z, Li Z, et al. Single-cell and Spatial analysis reveal interaction of FAP(+) fibroblasts and SPP1(+) macrophages in colorectal cancer. Nat Commun. 2022;13:1742. 10.1038/s41467-022-29366-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-29366-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atanasova VS, de Jesus Cardona C, Hejret V, Tiefenbacher A, Mair T, Tran L, et al. Mimicking tumor cell heterogeneity of colorectal cancer in a Patient-derived Organoid-Fibroblast model. Cell Mol Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2023;15:1391&#x2013;419. 10.1016/j.jcmgh.2023.02.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcmgh.2023.02.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10141529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36868311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusza&#x142;a M, Pilszyk A, Niebrzydowska M, Kimber-Trojnar &#x17b;, Trojnar M, Leszczy&#x144;ska-Gorzelak B. Novel biomolecules in the pathogenesis of gestational diabetes mellitus 2.0. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23. 10.3390/ijms23084364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9031541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35457182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Mo M, Chen X, Chao D, Zhang Y, Chen X, et al. Targeting Inhibition of prognosis-related lipid metabolism genes including CYP19A1 enhances immunotherapeutic response in colon cancer. J Exp Clin Cancer Res. 2023;42:85. 10.1186/s13046-023-02647-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13046-023-02647-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10100168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couselo-Seijas M, V&#xe1;zquez-Abu&#xed;n X, G&#xf3;mez-L&#xe1;zaro M, Pereira L, G&#xf3;mez AM, Caballero R, et al. FABP4 enhances lipidic and fibrotic cardiac structural and Ca(2+) dynamic changes. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2024;17:e012683. 10.1161/circep.123.012683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circep.123.012683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39212041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoneau J, Dumontier S, Gosselin R, Scott MS. Current RNA-seq methodology reporting limits reproducibility. Brief Bioinform. 2021;22:140&#x2013;5. 10.1093/bib/bbz124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbz124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31813948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovic D, Liang X, Zeng H, Lin L, Xu F, Luo Y. Single-cell RNA sequencing technologies and applications: A brief overview. Clin Transl Med. 2022;12:e694. 10.1002/ctm2.694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ctm2.694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35352511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armand EJ, Li J, Xie F, Luo C, Mukamel EA. Single-Cell sequencing of brain cell transcriptomes and epigenomes. Neuron. 2021;109:11&#x2013;26. 10.1016/j.neuron.2020.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2020.12.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33412093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimptsch K, Aleksandrova K, Pham TT, Papadimitriou N, Janke J, Christakoudi S, et al. Prospective and Mendelian randomization analyses on the association of Circulating fatty acid binding protein 4 (FABP-4) and risk of colorectal cancer. BMC Med. 2023;21:391. 10.1186/s12916-023-03104-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-023-03104-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10576353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37833736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>