<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41414884</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-2359</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cancer control : journal of the Moffitt Cancer Center</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cancer Control</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Extreme Weather Events on Radiation Oncology Practices in Puerto Rico.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10732748251394061</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10732748251394061</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10732748251394061</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/10732748251394061</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>ObjectivesThis study aims to evaluate the perceived impact of extreme weather events from 2017 - 2024 on delivery of radiotherapy in Puerto Rico (PR), including effects on radiation oncologists, medical physicists, clinical staff, and patients. A secondary objective is to identify resources and strategies that may strengthen resiliency and support continuity of care in radiation oncology clinics located in weather-vulnerable regions.MethodsWe developed a comprehensive online cross-sectional survey to evaluate clinic emergency preparedness and the impact of extreme weather events on radiation oncology clinic stakeholders in PR. Potential participants were identified through the American Society for Radiation Oncology (ASTRO) membership directory and were invited to participate via email and direct outreach.ResultsFourteen radiation oncologists and four medical physicists were invited to participate, with a response rate of 56% (n = 10), representing 71.4% of radiation oncology clinics in PR. Among respondents, 90% reported clinical disruptions due to extreme weather events from 2017 to 2024. The most commonly reported impacts were property damage (90%), communication failures between providers, patients and staff (90%), power outages (80%), and school and/or childcare closures (80%). A majority (90%) supported developing comprehensive supportive resources, including professional society resources, to enhance disaster preparedness and operational resiliency.ConclusionRadiation oncology providers in PR reported significant disruptions in care delivery from extreme weather events and identified a need for strong resiliency measures. Institutional policy, coupled with targeted support from professional societies, may reduce lapses in treatment, safeguard vulnerable patients - particularly those with complex treatment plans - and improve continuity of care and outcomes in weather-prone regions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drew</LastName><ForeName>Taylor</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-7068-1322</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Grant Medical Center, Columbus, OH, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">24594</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conway</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Elgin Air Force Base Hospital, Fort Walton Beach, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Do</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham Marnix E. Heersink School of Medicine, Birmingham, AL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marrero Morales</LastName><ForeName>Leyda</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6220-1391</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California San Francisco School of Medicine, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">8785</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Medhat</LastName><ForeName>Yasmeen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California San Francisco School of Medicine, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">8785</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Genevieve S</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Transitional Year Residency Program, Penn Medicine Doylestown Health, Doylestown, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Occupational Environmental and Climate Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of California, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gay</LastName><ForeName>Hiram A</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Washington University Medical Center, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">189396</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santiago-Mendez</LastName><ForeName>Robert J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Hospital Auxilio Mutuo, San Juan, Puerto Rico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McComas</LastName><ForeName>Kyra N</ForeName><Initials>KN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Cancer Care Northwest, Spokane, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, TN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lichter</LastName><ForeName>Katie E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Occupational Environmental and Climate Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of California, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology and Applied Sciences, Darthmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center, Lebanon, NH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dartmouth Institute for Health Policy and Clinical Practice, Dartmouth Geisel School of Medicine, Lebanon, NH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cancer Control</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9438457</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1073-2748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011647" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Puerto Rico</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018787" MajorTopicYN="Y">Radiation Oncology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="N">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014887" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weather</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004189" MajorTopicYN="N">Disaster Planning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000532" MajorTopicYN="N">radiotherapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText><b>Lessons from Puerto Rico: Protecting Cancer Patients During Extreme Weather Events</b>Extreme weather events such as powerful hurricanes are becoming more common, especially in vulnerable places such as Puerto Rico. When Hurricane Maria struck in 2017, it exposed how fragile health systems can be during these crises. Cancer care is especially at risk because patients often depend on strict treatment schedules. Most past research has focused on the experiences of cancer patients, with limited attention given to the oncology providers that care for them. These providers have valuable insights on how to better prepare clinics and care for patients after extreme weather events. In our study, we surveyed oncology providers in Puerto Rico to understand how extreme weather events affect providers, patients, and staff, as well as how health systems prepare for and respond to these events. We found that nearly all providers were negatively impacted by extreme weather events. Providers, patients, and staff frequently experienced shortages in food, clean water, transportation, electricity, and healthcare access. Providers reported that strong community partnerships and institutional emergency plans were the most effective tools for getting cancer care quickly back on track. They also recommended and requested that professional medical societies create official platforms to share patient education, resources, and even financial support during such emergencies. By learning from the resilience of oncology providers in Puerto Rico, health systems everywhere can strengthen disaster preparedness, reduce harm to patients, staff, and providers, and improve the continuity of life-saving cancer care when extreme weather events occur.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Puerto Rico (PR)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">climate change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">climate resilience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disaster preparedness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emergency preparedness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extreme weather events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare sustainability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hurricanes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical physics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiation oncology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41414884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12717360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10732748251394061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Smith AB. U.S. billion-dollar Weather and Climate Disasters in Historical Context. NOAA; 2022. Published January 10, 2023. https://www.climate.gov/news-features/blogs/beyond-data/2022-us-billion-dollar-weather-and-climate-disasters-historical. Accessed 13 March 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogueira LM, Sahar L, Efstathiou JA, Jemal A, Yabroff KR. Association between declared hurricane disasters and survival of patients with lung cancer undergoing radiation treatment. JAMA. 2019;322(3):269-271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6635902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31310288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence JM, Ibne Hossian NU, Jaradat R, Hamilton M. Leveraging a Bayesian network approach to model and analyze supplier vulnerability to severe weather risk: a case study of the U.S. pharmaceutical supply chain following Hurricane Maria. IJDRR. 2020;49:101607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinel Z, Nogueira LM, Gay HA, et al. Climate-driven Atlantic hurricanes create complex challenges for cancer care. Lancet Oncol. 2022;23(12):1497-1498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36272419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gay HA, Santiago R, Gil B, et al. Lessons learned from hurricane Maria in Puerto Rico: practical measures to mitigate the impact of a catastrophic natural disaster on radiation oncology patients. Pract Rad Oncol. 2019;9(5):305-321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30999000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichter KE, Baniel CC, Do I, et al. Effects of wildlife events on California radiation oncology clinics and patients. Adv Radiat Oncol. 2023;9(3):101395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10831805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38304108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz-Torres F, Soto-Salgado M, Ortiz-Ortiz KJ, L&#xf3;pez-Le&#xf3;n XS, S&#xe1;nchez-Cabrera Y, Col&#xf3;n-L&#xf3;pez V. Cancer treatment disruption by residence region in the aftermath of hurricanes Irma and Mar&#xed;a in Puerto Rico. Int J Environ Res Publ Health. 2024;21(10):1334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11508132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39457307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von EE, Altman DG, Egger M, et al. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147:573-577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dieppa IS, Bayne M, Lydersen K. Mapping vulnerability in Puerto Rico. Pulitzer Center. Published January 10, 2020. https://pulitzercenter.org/stories/mapping-vulnerability-puerto-rico. Accessed September 23, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz AP, Calo WA, Mendez-Lazaro P, et al. Strengthening resilience and adaptive capacity to disasters in cancer control plans: lessons learned from Puerto Rico. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2020;29(7):1290-1293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder A, Dresser C, Yadav A, et al. CrisisReady&#x2019;s novel framework for transdisciplinary translation: Case-studies in wildfire and hurricane response. J Clim Chang Health. 2023;9:100193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrah S. Frequently asked questions from Puerto Rican students About UMHS. UMHS. Published July 27, 2017. https://www.umhs-sk.org/blog/frequently-asked-questions-from-puerto-rican-students-about. Accessed July 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>