<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41495282</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Developing a multidimensional scale of healing tourism experiences based on a mixed methods approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4193</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4193</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4193</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34286-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">This paper develops a scale to measure the healing tourism experiences, drawing on grounded theory and extant relevant literature. In Study 1, 30 in-depth interviews with purposive sampling were conducted to establish a conceptual model comprising four dimensions: anticipated healing, embodied healing, interactive healing, and reminiscence healing. Study 2 applied multivariate statistical analyses to refine the scale, and based on 280 valid questionnaires, developed a 13-item instrument representing the four dimensions. Study 3 further tested the validity and applicability of the scale using data from Study 2, confirming its reliability and predictive power. Study 4 was subsequently conducted to validate the model&#x2019;s predictive utility by testing the relationship between healing tourism experiences and tourists&#x2019; willingness to revisit, thereby confirming the criterion-related validity of the scale. The findings contribute both theoretically and practically: the scale offers a robust measurement standard for scholars to investigate the healing tourism experiences in greater depth, and it provides a theoretical reference for practitioners seeking to evaluate and enhance the restorative value of tourism products and services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-025-34286-8.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Jize</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Technology, No.1 East 3 road ErXian brige, Chengdu, 610059, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Han</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Technology, No.1 East 3 road ErXian brige, Chengdu, 610059, PR China. sc_lh@cdut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ziyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Technology, No.1 East 3 road ErXian brige, Chengdu, 610059, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Technology, No.1 East 3 road ErXian brige, Chengdu, 610059, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hua</LastName><ForeName>Haiyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Technology, No.1 East 3 road ErXian brige, Chengdu, 610059, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>24YJC890053</GrantID><Agency>the Ministry of Education's Humanities and Social Sciences Research Youth Fund Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024NSFSC0270</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Sichuan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Grounded theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healing tourism experiences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scale development</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Methods and human experiments statement: The ethics committee of the Business School Chengdu University of Technology has approved the experiment on " Developing a Multidimensional Scale of Healing Tourism Experiences Based on a Mixed Methods Approach&#x201d; conducted by Jize Xie et al. The research group promised that the experiment would be conducted with full information given, and informed consent from all subjects received. The experiment would not cause any psychological or physical harm to the subjects. Subjects have the right to withdraw from the experiment at any stage. For data collected in the experiment, they can be used in the study after anonymization. The subject has the right to ask the research group to delete the experiment result about himself at any stage. Furthermore, we confirm that this study has been conducted in accordance with the relevant guidelines and regulations and that all methods have been approved by the appropriate authorities.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41495282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12858923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34286-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34286-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen, H., Jiao, Y., Li, X. &amp; Zhang, K. Family tourism: interpersonal interaction, existential authenticity and quality of tourist experience. <i>J. VACAT MARK.</i><b>28</b>, 82 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13567667211022407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christou, P. &amp; Simillidou, A. Tourist experience: the catalyst role of tourism in comforting melancholy, or not. <i>J. HOSP. TOUR MANAG</i>. <b>42</b>, 210 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhtm.2020.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, M., Liu, B. &amp; Li, Y. Tourist inspiration: how the wellness tourism experience inspires tourist engagement. <i>J. HOSP. TOUR RES.</i><b>47</b>, 1115 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10963480211026376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, S. et al. Health tourism evolution: a review based on bibliometric analysis and the China National knowledge infrastructure database. <i>SUSTAINABILITY-BASEL</i><b>14</b>, 10435 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su141610435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B., Kralj, A., Moyle, B., He, M. &amp; Li, Y. Perceived destination restorative qualities in wellness tourism: the role of ontological security and psychological resilience. <i>J. TRAVEL RES.</i><b>64</b>, 658059581 (2024). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, I. A., Lin, Z. &amp; Kou, I. E. Restoring hope and optimism through staycation programs: an application of psychological capital theory. <i>J. SUSTAIN. TOUR</i>. <b>31</b>, 91 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09669582.2021.1970172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley, R. C. Therapeutic mental health effects perceived by outdoor tourists: A large-scale, multi-decade, qualitative analysis. <i>ANN. TOURISM RES.</i><b>77</b>, 164 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annals.2018.12.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. E., Um, S. H. &amp; Lee, T. J. Healing effects from the on-site experiences of tourists. <i>INT. J. TOUR RES.</i><b>22</b>, 192 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jtr.2328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. &amp; So, K. K. F. Two decades of customer experience research in hospitality and tourism: A bibliometric analysis and thematic content analysis. <i>INT. J. HOSP. MANAG</i>. <b>100</b>, 103082 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhm.2021.103082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, E. A phenomenology of tourist experiences. <i>SOCIOLOGY</i><b>13</b>, 179 (1979).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/003803857901300203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C. &amp; Kuo, B. Z. The behavioral consequences of tourist experience. <i>TOUR MANAG PERSPECT.</i><b>18</b>, 84 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, H., Fiore, A. M. &amp; Jeoung, M. Measuring experience economy concepts: tourism applications. <i>J. TRAVEL RES.</i><b>46</b>, 119 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0047287507304039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto, J. E. &amp; Ritchie, J. B. The service experience in tourism. <i>TOURISM MANAGE.</i><b>17</b>, 165 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0261-5177(96)00003-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teoh, M. W., Wang, Y. &amp; Kwek, A. Conceptualising co-created transformative tourism experiences: A systematic narrative review. <i>J. HOSP. TOUR MANAG</i>. <b>47</b>, 176 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhtm.2021.03.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzova, D., Cervera Taulet, A. &amp; Sanz Blas, S. Exploring multisensory place experiences through cruise blog analysis. <i>PSYCHOL. MARKET</i>. <b>37</b>, 131 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mar.21286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chirakranont, R. &amp; Sakdiyakorn, M. Conceptualizing meaningful tourism experiences: case study of a small craft beer brewery in Thailand. <i>J. DESTIN MARK. MANAGE.</i><b>23</b>, 100691 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agapito, D., Valle, P. &amp; Mendes, J. The sensory dimension of tourist experiences: capturing meaningful sensory-informed themes in Southwest Portugal. <i>TOURISM MANAGE.</i><b>42</b>, 224 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tourman.2013.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri, F., Guerreiro, M., Pinto, P. &amp; Ghaderi, Z. From tourist experience to satisfaction and loyalty: Exploring the role of a sense of well-being. <i>J TRAVEL RES</i> 63 (2024). (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer, J. &amp; Ballantyne, R. Conceptualizing the visitor experience: A review of literature and development of a multifaceted model. <i>VISIT STUD.</i><b>19</b>, 128 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10645578.2016.1144023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung, V. W. S. &amp; Ritchie, J. B. Exploring the essence of memorable tourism experiences. <i>ANN. TOURISM RES.</i><b>38</b>, 1367 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annals.2011.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. &amp; Rahman, I. Cultural tourism: an analysis of engagement, cultural contact, memorable tourism experience and destination loyalty. <i>TOUR MANAG PERSPECT.</i><b>26</b>, 153 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, D. X., Tsaur, S., Lin, J., Chang, T. &amp; Tsa, Y. T. Tourist intercultural competence: A multidimensional measurement and its impact on tourist active participation and memorable cultural experiences. <i>J. TRAVEL RES.</i><b>61</b>, 414 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0047287520982372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triantafillidou, A. &amp; Petala, Z. The role of sea-based adventure experiences in tourists&#x2019; satisfaction and behavioral intentions. <i>J. TRAVEL TOUR MARK.</i><b>33</b>, 67 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10548408.2015.1008667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y. et al. Flow in soundscape: The conceptualization of soundscape flow experience and its relationship with soundscape perception and behaviour intention in tourism destinations. <i>CURR ISSUES TOUR</i><b>25</b> (2022). (2090).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig, C., Hiskey, S. &amp; Spector, A. Compassion focused therapy: A systematic review of its effectiveness and acceptability in clinical populations. <i>EXPERT REV. NEUROTHER.</i><b>20</b>, 385 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2020.1746184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32196399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazdin, A. E. Interventions in everyday life to improve mental health and reduce symptoms of psychiatric disorders. <i>AM. PSYCHOL.</i><b>79</b>, 185 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/amp0001158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37079813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucea-Manea-&#x21a;oni&#x219;, R. &amp; P&#x103;un, D. G. Yoga, a mindfulness therapy to prevent PTSD as to encompass athletes&#x2019; performance. <i>FRONT. PSYCHOL.</i><b>15</b>, 1334278 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1334278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11074427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38716278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers, L., Phillips, K. &amp; Cooper, N. Energy healing therapies: A systematic review and critical appraisal. <i>HEALTH PSYCHOL. REV.</i><b>2</b>, 162 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley, R. Nature tourism and mental health: parks, happiness, and causation. <i>J. SUSTAIN. TOUR</i>. <b>28</b>, 1409 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09669582.2020.1742725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan, R. &amp; Kaplan, S. <i>The Experience of Nature: A Psychological Perspective</i> (Cambridge University Press, 1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok, I. et al. Poetry as a healing modality in medicine: Current state and common structures for implementation and research. <i>J PAIN SYMPTOM MANAG</i><b>64</b> e91 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuckey, H. L. &amp; Nobel, J. The connection between art, healing, and public health: A review of current literature. <i>AM. J. PUBLIC. HEALTH</i>. <b>100</b>, 254 (2010).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2008.156497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2804629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. Y., Paek, S., Kim, T. &amp; Lee, T. H. Health tourism: needs for healing experience and intentions for transformation in wellness resorts in Korea. <i>INT. J. CONTEMP. HOSP. M</i>. <b>27</b>, 1881 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJCHM-11-2013-0505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terzidou, M., Scarles, C. &amp; Saunders, M. N. The complexities of religious tourism motivations: sacred places, vows and visions. <i>ANN. TOURISM RES.</i><b>70</b>, 54 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annals.2018.02.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhalla, R., Chowdhary, N. &amp; Ranjan, A. Spiritual tourism for psychotherapeutic healing post COVID-19. <i>J. TRAVEL TOUR MARK.</i><b>38</b>, 769 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10548408.2021.1930630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knobloch, U., Robertson, K. &amp; Aitken, R. Experience, emotion, and eudaimonia: A consideration of tourist experiences and well-being. <i>J. TRAVEL RES.</i><b>56</b>, 651 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0047287516650937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchill, G. A. Jr A paradigm for developing better measures of marketing constructs. <i>J. Mark. RES.</i><b>16</b>, 64 (1979).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/002224377901600110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinkin, T. R. A brief tutorial on the development of measures for use in survey questionnaires. <i>ORGAN. RES. METHODS</i>. <b>1</b>, 104 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/109442819800100106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makri, C. &amp; Neely, A. Grounded theory: A guide for exploratory studies in management research. <i>INT. J. QUAL. METH</i>. <b>20</b>, 2119180822 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/16094069211013654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertler, C. A., Vannatta, R. A. &amp; LaVenia, K. N. <i>Advanced and Multivariate Statistical Methods: Practical Application and Interpretation</i> (Routledge, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVellis, R. F. &amp; Thorpe, C. T. <i>Scale Development: Theory and Applications</i> (Sage, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manthiou, A., Ulrich, I. &amp; Kuppelwieser, V. The travel influencer construct: an empirical exploration and validation. <i>TOURISM MANAGE.</i><b>101</b>, 104858 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tourman.2023.104858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Likert, R. A technique for the measurement of attitudes. <i>Archives Psychol.</i><b>140</b>, 155 (1932). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Cui, W. &amp; Chee, W. M. Investigating tourism experiences and attention allocation of outbound tourists through the lens of the two-factor theory: a grounded theory analysis of Chinese tourists&#x2019; travelogues in Malaysia. <i>HELIYON</i> 9 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10359871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37483812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, K., Wang, M., Yuan, H. &amp; Zhang, B. The countryside in the eyes of the beholder: developing and testing a tourists&#x2019; rurality perception scale. <i>CURR. ISSUES TOUR</i>. <b>27</b>, 2815 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13683500.2023.2240476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J. Basics of qualitative research techniques. (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen, G. A. Naturalistic inquiry and the saturation concept: a research note. <i>QUAL. RES.</i><b>8</b>, 137 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1468794107085301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csikszentmihalyi, M. <i>Flow: The psychology of optimal experience</i> (Harper &amp; Row New York, 1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tajfel, H. &amp; Turner, J. C. <i>In Political Psychology</i> pp. 276 (Psychology, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillemer, D. Directive functions of autobiographical memory: the guiding power of the specific episode. <i>MEMORY</i><b>11</b>, 193 (2003).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/741938208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12820831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, Y. &amp; Yu, Q. Sense of safety toward tourism destinations: A social constructivist perspective. <i>J. DESTIN MARK. MANAGE.</i><b>24</b>, 100708 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, L., Deng, B., Morrison, A. M., Coca-Stefaniak, J. A. &amp; Yang, L. Medical, health and wellness tourism research&#x2014;A review of the literature (1970&#x2013;2020) and research agenda. <i>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health</i>. <b>18</b>, 10875 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182010875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y., Hou, Y. &amp; Dong, Z. From good expectancy to good feelings: how optimism is related to subjective well-being in Chinese adults through the pathway of coping. <i>BEHAV. SCI-BASEL</i>. <b>14</b>, 165 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs14030165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10967884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38540468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lench, H. C. et al. Optimistic expectations have benefits for effort and emotion with little cost. <i>EMOTION</i><b>21 </b>1213 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33646801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed, B., Tasmin, R., Mahmood, A. &amp; Hafeez, A. Development of a multi-item operational excellence scale: exploratory and confirmatory factor analysis. <i>TQM J.</i><b>34</b>, 576 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karl, M., Kock, F., Ritchie, B. W. &amp; Gauss, J. Affective forecasting and travel decision-making: an investigation in times of a pandemic. <i>ANN. TOURISM RES.</i><b>87</b>, 103139 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annals.2021.103139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang, X. &amp; Wang, Y. Social support and travel: enhancing relationships, communication, and Understanding for travel companions. <i>INT. J. TOUR RES.</i><b>26</b>, e2712 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jtr.2712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puusepp, V. Becoming closer to one another: shared emotions and social relationships. <i>PHILOS. PSYCHOL.</i><b>37</b>, 2533 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09515089.2023.2171858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karag&#xf6;z, D. &amp; Ramkissoon, H. Loneliness, travel nostalgia, subjective well-being and prevention regulatory focus: A moderated mediation model analysis. <i>CURR. ISSUES TOUR</i>. <b>27</b>, 217 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13683500.2023.2175201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornell, C. Structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error: Algebra and statistics. (1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair, J. Multivariate data analysis. <i>Exploratory factor analysis</i> (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne, B. M. Basic concepts, applications, and programming. <i>Struct. Equation Model. AMOS</i>. <b>396</b>, 227 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, L. T. &amp; Bentler, P. M. Cutoff criteria for fit indexes in covariance structure analysis: conventional criteria versus new alternatives. <i>Struct. Equation Modeling: Multidisciplinary J.</i><b>6</b>, 1 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10705519909540118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stylos, N., Vassiliadis, C. A., Bellou, V. &amp; Andronikidis, A. Destination images, holistic images and personal normative beliefs: predictors of intention to revisit a destination. <i>TOURISM MANAGE.</i><b>53</b>, 40 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tourman.2015.09.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, L. &amp; Bentler, P. M. Fit indices in covariance structure modeling: sensitivity to underparameterized model misspecification. <i>PSYCHOL. METHODS</i>. <b>3</b>, 424 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1082-989X.3.4.424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X. presented at the International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction, 2024 (unpublished).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, G., Li, M., Li, B. &amp; Meng, Y. A healing journey with animals. <i>J. HOSP. TOUR MANAG</i>. <b>60</b>, 252 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhtm.2024.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood, E. H., Kinnunen, M., Moss, J. &amp; Li, Y. Shared festival tourism experiences: the power and purpose of remembering together. <i>J. TRAVEL RES.</i><b>63</b>, 409 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00472875231158591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, Y., Ribeiro, M. A. &amp; Li, G. Tourism memory, mood repair and behavioral intention. <i>ANN. TOURISM RES.</i><b>93</b>, 103369 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annals.2022.103369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, I., Martin, D. S. &amp; Liu, S. Outbound medical tourists: the interplay of perceived quality, length of stay, group-size, post-visit destination image and revisit intention. <i>PLOS ONE</i>. <b>17</b>, e0267755 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0267755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9089917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35536776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z., Shi, D., Huang, Z. &amp; Liu, X. How does tourism memory affect revisit decisions? The mediating role of episodic future thinking. <i>TOUR MANAG PERSPECT.</i><b>49</b>, 101199 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, C. &amp; Wang, W. Impacts of climate change knowledge on coastal tourists&#x2019; destination decision-making and revisit intentions. <i>J. HOSP. TOUR MANAG</i>. <b>56</b>, 322 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhtm.2023.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stylidis, D. Exploring resident&#x2013;tourist interaction and its impact on tourists&#x2019; destination image. <i>J. TRAVEL RES.</i><b>61</b>, 186 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0047287520969861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuxin, F., Jianpeng, Q., Xiaoyu, L., Yunxia, T. &amp; Weilong, M. Exploring the influence of historical storytelling on cultural heritage tourists&#x2019; revisit intention: A case study of the Mogao Grottoes in Dunhuang. <i>PLOS ONE</i> 19 e0307869 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11412526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39298447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vroom, V. H. Work and motivation. (1964).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, T. D. &amp; Gilbert, D. T. Affective forecasting: knowing what to want. <i>CURR. DIR. PSYCHOL. SCI.</i><b>14</b>, 131 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0963-7214.2005.00355.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, T. D., Lindsey, S. &amp; Schooler, T. Y. A model of dual attitudes. <i>PSYCHOL. REV.</i><b>107</b>, 101 (2000).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-295X.107.1.101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10687404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, Y. &amp; La, S. What influences the relationship between customer satisfaction and repurchase intention? Investigating the effects of adjusted expectations and customer loyalty. <i>PSYCHOL. MARKET</i>. <b>21</b>, 351 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mar.20009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, D. T. &amp; Wilson, T. D. Prospection: Experiencing the future. <i>SCIENCE</i> 317 1351 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okleshen Peters, C. L., Shelton, J. &amp; Sharma, P. An investigation of factors that influence the consumption of dietary supplements. <i>Health Mark. Q.</i><b>21</b>, 113 (2003).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1300/J026v21n01_06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15271634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blichfeldt, B. S. &amp; Halkier, H. Mussels, tourism and community development: a case study of place branding through food festivals in rural North Jutland, Denmark. <i>EUR. PLAN. STUD.</i><b>22</b>, 1587 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09654313.2013.784594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildschut, T., Sedikides, C., Arndt, J. &amp; Routledge, C. Nostalgia: content, triggers, functions. <i>J. PERS. SOC. PSYCHOL.</i><b>91</b>, 975 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.91.5.975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17059314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelin&#x10d;i&#x107;, D. A. &amp; Mate&#x10d;i&#x107;, I. Broken but well: healing dimensions of cultural tourism experiences. <i>SUSTAINABILITY-BASEL</i><b>13</b>, 966 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13020966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beames, S., Mackenzie, S. H. &amp; Raymond, E. How can we adventure sustainably? A systematized review of sustainability guidance for adventure tourism operators. <i>J. HOSP. TOUR MANAG</i>. <b>50</b>, 223 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhtm.2022.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, J. &amp; Lv, X. Feeling dark, seeing dark: Mind&#x2013;body in dark tourism. <i>ANN. TOURISM RES.</i><b>86</b>, 103087 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annals.2020.103087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>