<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41902018</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High-Accuracy Wave Direction Estimation Using Kalman Fusion of Interferometric Measurements and Energy Field Reconstruction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1852</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26061852</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Microwave wireless power transfer (MWPT) for space solar power stations (SSPS) requires high-precision beam pointing in order to maintain effective aperture coupling and transmission efficiency under platform motion and disturbances. This paper proposes a dual-link beam pointing estimation framework that integrates guidance-link interferometric angle-of-arrival (AoA) measurements with power-link energy-field reconstruction. The interferometric chain provides high-rate azimuth and elevation observations for dynamic tracking, while the energy-field reconstruction estimates the energy-centroid displacement from the received-aperture power distribution to correct steady-state pointing bias. A Kalman filter (KF) is developed to fuse the asynchronous multi-rate measurements, yielding continuous and robust pointing estimates for closed-loop beam control. Simulation results show that the proposed fusion method achieves azimuth and elevation RMSEs of 0.0069&#xb0; and 0.006&#xb0; with interferometric and energy-centroid error levels of approximately 0.05&#xb0; and 0.02&#xb0;, respectively, significantly reducing high-frequency fluctuations. In addition, a sensitivity model is established to quantify the impact of angular errors on capture efficiency. The expected efficiency improves from approximately 0.988 and 0.998 for the individual methods to nearly unity for the fusion output. Quantitative accuracy thresholds corresponding to different efficiency requirements are further derived, providing practical guidelines for SSPS MWPT system design.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Caicheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-0105-7803</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Microelectronics and Communication Engineering, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5966-8185</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center of Communication and Tracking Telemetry Command, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xue</LastName><ForeName>Linshan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Academy of Space Technology (CAST), Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CYK2025-01-13</GrantID><Agency>Key Laboratory of Intelligent Spatial Perception Technology and Application (Space Engineering University), Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CSTB2024TIAD-KPX0105</GrantID><Agency>Chongqing Key Project of Technology Innovation and Application Development: Research and Application of Key Technologies for Structural Safety Monitoring of Super High-Rise Buildings in Mountainous Cities</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beam pointing estimation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy-field reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interferometric angle measurement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microwave wireless power transfer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13029887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26061852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26061852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Glaser P.E. An overview of the solar power satellite option. IEEE Trans. Microw. Theory Tech. 1992;40:1230&#x2013;1238. doi: 10.1109/22.141356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/22.141356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown W.C., Eves E.E. Beamed microwave power transmission and its application to space. IEEE Trans. Microw. Theory Tech. 1992;40:1239&#x2013;1250. doi: 10.1109/22.141357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/22.141357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strassner B., Chang K. Microwave power transmission: Historical milestones and system components. Proc. IEEE. 2013;101:1379&#x2013;1396. doi: 10.1109/JPROC.2013.2246132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2013.2246132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui Q., Jin K., Zhu X. Directional radiation technique for maximum receiving power in microwave power transmission system. IEEE Trans. Ind. Electron. 2019;67:6376&#x2013;6386. doi: 10.1109/TIE.2019.2941150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIE.2019.2941150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T., Sasaki T., Homma Y., Sasaki M., Tanaka K. Phased Array System for High Efficiency and High Accuracy Microwave Power Transmission. IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ARRAY.2016.7832563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patwary A.B., Mahbub I. 4&#xd7;4 UWB phased array antenna with &gt;51&#xb0; far-field scanning range for wireless power transfer application. IEEE Open J. Antennas Propag. 2024;2:5. doi: 10.1109/OJAP.2023.3349358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/OJAP.2023.3349358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B., Chen X., Chu J., Shinohara N. A 5.8-GHz phased array system using power-variable phase-controlled magnetrons for wireless power transfer. IEEE Trans. Microw. Theory Tech. 2020;68:4951&#x2013;4959. doi: 10.1109/TMTT.2020.3007187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMTT.2020.3007187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinohara N. Beam control technologies with a high-efficiency phased array for microwave power transmission in Japan. Proc. IEEE. 2013;101:1448&#x2013;1463. doi: 10.1109/JPROC.2013.2253062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2013.2253062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J., Li W., Wu W., Zhang Y. Multi-objective structural optimization and attitude control for space solar power station. Aerospace. 2025;13:9. doi: 10.3390/aerospace13010009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/aerospace13010009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito M., Funane T., Tanabe Y., Sasaki S. Investigation on received power of space solar power systems using large planar satellites in quasi-geostationary earth orbit. Trans. Jpn. Soc. Aeronaut. Space Sci. 2025;68:232&#x2013;241. doi: 10.2322/tjsass.68.232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2322/tjsass.68.232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B., Shinohara N. Microwave power transmission technologies for space solar power stations. Chin. Space Sci. Technol. 2025;45:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.16708/j.cnki.1000-758X.2025.0017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16708/j.cnki.1000-758X.2025.0017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki S., Tanaka K., Maki K. Microwave power transmission technologies for solar power satellites. Proc. IEEE. 2013;101:1438&#x2013;1447. doi: 10.1109/JPROC.2013.2246851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2013.2246851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X., Dong S., Wang Y., Hou X., Zhao W. Prediction and compensation of position and attitude deviation of ultra-large scale antenna arrays for space solar power station; Proceedings of the 2025 IEEE Wireless Power Technology Conference and Expo (WPTCE); San Diego, CA, USA. 2&#x2013;5 June 2025;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/WPTCE62521.2025.11062183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto H. Research on solar power satellites and microwave power transmission in Japan. IEEE Microw. Mag. 2002;3:36&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1109/MMW.2002.1145674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MMW.2002.1145674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi T., Mizuno T., Sawa M., Sasaki T., Tanaka K. Development of phased array for high accurate microwave power transmission; Proceedings of the 2011 IEEE MTT-S International Microwave Workshop Series on Innovative Wireless Power Transmission: Technologies, Systems, and Applications; Kyoto, Japan. 12&#x2013;13 May 2011;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/IMWS.2011.5877112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X., Zhao W., Dong S., Wang Y., Hou X. Position and attitude error forecasting technology of microwave power transmitting arrays for space solar power station; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE Wireless Power Technology Conference and Expo (WPTCE); Kyoto, Japan. 8&#x2013;11 May 2024; pp. 419&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/WPTCE59894.2024.10557322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Xi Z., Ye K., Liu C. Improvement of phased antenna array applied in focused microwave breast hyperthermia. Sensors. 2024;24:2682. doi: 10.3390/s24092682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24092682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11085649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38732788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Lu M., Kwan B. Wireless charging for low-power mobile devices based on retro-reflective beamforming; Proceedings of the 2014 IEEE Antennas and Propagation Society International Symposium (APSURSI); Memphis, TN, USA. 6&#x2013;11 July 2014;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/APS.2014.6905031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L. High-precision bi-directional beam-pointing measurement method based on space solar power station system. Sensors. 2024;24:6135. doi: 10.3390/s24186135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24186135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11435495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39338880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z., Chen X., Peng C. Research on microwave energy beam control technology with clear field distribution; Proceedings of the 2022 International Conference on Computer Science, Electronic Information Engineering and Intelligent Control Technology (CEI); Fuzhou, China. 23&#x2013;25 September 2022; pp. 167&#x2013;170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong S., Hou X., Wang X. Retro-directive microwave power beam steering technology for space solar power station. Chin. Space Sci. Technol. 2022;42:91&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Lu M. Wireless power transmission based on retro-reflective beamforming technique. Space Solar Power Wireless Transm. 2024;1:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1016/j.sspwt.2023.08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sspwt.2023.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouk J.D., Demars K.J. Kalman filtering with uncertain and asynchronous measurement epochs. Navigation. 2024;71:29. doi: 10.33012/navi.652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33012/navi.652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Jiao Y., Gao Z., Mao F., Zhang H. Study on improving the direction-finding accuracy of rotary baseline phase interferometer; Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE 4th Advanced Information Management, Communicates, Electronic and Automation Control Conference (IMCEC); Chongqing, China. 18&#x2013;20 June 2021; pp. 1480&#x2013;1484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/IMCEC51613.2021.9482367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y., Qi C., Wang W. A method of solving ambiguity based on single baseline rotating interferometer; Proceedings of the 2021 CIE International Conference on Radar (Radar); Haikou, China. 15&#x2013;19 December 2021; pp. 3336&#x2013;3340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/Radar53847.2021.10028030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doan S.V., Vesely J., Janu P., Frolka J. Optimized Algorithm for Solving Phase Interferometer Ambiguity. IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/IRS.2016.7497353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Luo Y., Zhao C. Phase difference method for DOA estimation. J. Mar. Sci. Appl. 2010;9:415&#x2013;419. doi: 10.1007/s11804-010-1032-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11804-010-1032-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Yu T. An analysis method for solving ambiguity in direction finding with phase interferometers. Circuits Syst. Signal Process. 2021;40:1420&#x2013;1437. doi: 10.1007/s00034-020-01536-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00034-020-01536-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S. Research on a high-dynamics acquisition algorithm for new binary offset carrier signal in UAV communication. Drones. 2024;8:548. doi: 10.3390/drones8100548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones8100548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Cao Y., Wang W. B-spline surface fitting with knot position optimization. Comput. Graph. 2016;58:73&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/j.cag.2016.05.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cag.2016.05.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M., Li B., Guo Q., Zhu C., Hu P. Progressive iterative approximation for regularized least square bivariate B-spline surface fitting. J. Comput. Appl. Math. 2017;327:175&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1016/j.cam.2017.06.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cam.2017.06.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenz D., Yeh R., Mahadevan V., Bui T. Customizable adaptive regularization techniques for B-spline modeling. J. Comput. Sci. 2023;71:102037. doi: 10.1016/j.jocs.2023.102037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocs.2023.102037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Duan B., Zhang Y., Song J. Optimal design of aperture illuminations for microwave power transmission with annular collection areas. Engineering. 2023;11:63&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1016/j.eng.2023.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eng.2023.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>