<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41926534</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unsupervised cross domain adaptive anomaly detection network for Internet of Things traffic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0344009</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0344009</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0344009</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0344009</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid growth of networks of connected devices demands robust methods for detecting anomalies in multivariate traffic. Traditional approaches often fail when data distributions shift across environments or when labeled anomalies are scarce. We introduce the Unsupervised Cross Domain Adaptive Anomaly Detection Network called CDA-ADN. This framework employs a conditional variational sequence encoder with temporal attention to learn domain invariant representations of traffic sequences. Domain specific adaptation layers align input and output distributions by applying transformations guided by latent features. A contrastive learning mechanism at both local time steps and global sequence levels separates normal patterns from anomalies. Training occurs in two stages. In the first stage the model learns general normal behavior on a source environment using only normal samples. In the second stage a very small number of unlabeled normal samples from the target environment are used for lightweight fine tuning of the adaptation layers, without requiring any labeled anomaly samples in the target domain. Experiments on two benchmark Internet of Things traffic datasets demonstrate that CDA-ADN outperforms auto encoder and variational auto encoder methods by a wide margin in accuracy Matthews correlation coefficient and sensitivity under label scarce conditions. These results confirm the efficacy of the unsupervised cross domain approach for real world IoT security.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Yuan et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Tiange</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-0555-2334</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Of Nuclear Power Operation, China Nuclear Power Operation Technology Corporation, LTD., Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Di</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Of Nuclear Power Operation, China Nuclear Power Operation Technology Corporation, LTD., Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Anchao</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Of Nuclear Power Operation, China Nuclear Power Operation Technology Corporation, LTD., Wuhan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020407" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41926534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13046153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0344009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-28923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;rner K, Scrivner O, Cross LE, Gallant M, Ma S, Martin AS, et al. Mapping the co-evolution of artificial intelligence, robotics, and the internet of things over 20 years (1998-2017). PLoS One. 2020;15(12):e0242984. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0242984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0242984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7710114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook AA, Misirli G, Fan Z. Anomaly detection for IoT time-series data: a survey. IEEE Internet Things J. 2020;7(7):6481&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2019.2958185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2019.2958185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Shami A. A lightweight concept drift detection and adaptation framework for IoT data streams. IEEE Internet Things M. 2021;4(2):96&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1109/iotm.0001.2100012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/iotm.0001.2100012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma B, Sharma L, Lal C. Anomaly detection techniques using deep learning in IoT: a survey. 2019 International Conference on Computational Intelligence and Knowledge Economy (ICCIKE); 2019. p. 146&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provotar OI, Linder YM, Veres MM. Unsupervised anomaly detection in time series using LSTM-based autoencoders. 2019 IEEE International Conference on Advanced Trends in Information Theory (ATIT); 2019. p. 513&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma DP, Welling M. Auto-encoding variational Bayes. arXiv:13126114 [Preprint]. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Liu S, Chen A, Chen H. Learning in CubeRes model space for anomaly detection in 3D GPR data. In: Larson K, editor. Proceedings of the Thirty-Third International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, IJCAI-24. International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence Organization; 2024. p. 5662&#x2013;70. Available from: 10.24963/ijcai.2024/626</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24963/ijcai.2024/626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Liu S, Chen A, Chen Q, Xiong F, Wang Y, et al. Underground anomaly detection in GPR data by learning in the C3 model space. IEEE Trans Geosci Remote Sens. 2023;61:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1109/tgrs.2023.3326737</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tgrs.2023.3326737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S, Clark R, Birke R, Sch&#xf6;nborn S, Trigoni N, Roberts S. Anomaly detection for time series using VAE-LSTM hybrid model. ICASSP 2020 - 2020 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP); 2020. p. 4322&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nizam H, Zafar S, Lv Z, Wang F, Hu X. Real-time deep anomaly detection framework for multivariate time-series data in industrial IoT. IEEE Sensors J. 2022;22(23):22836&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1109/jsen.2022.3211874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jsen.2022.3211874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Dong Z, Huang Y. Multivariate time series anomaly detection with adaptive Transformer-CNN architecture fusing adversarial training. 2024 IEEE 13th Data Driven Control and Learning Systems Conference (DDCLS); 2024. p. 1387&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alturif G, Saleh W, El-Bary AA, Osman RA. Towards efficient IoT communication for smart agriculture: a deep learning framework. PLoS One. 2024;19(11):e0311601. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0311601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0311601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11581226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39570960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babbar H, Rani S, Driss M. Effective DDoS attack detection in software-defined vehicular networks using statistical flow analysis and machine learning. PLoS One. 2024;19(12):e0314695. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0314695</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0314695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11654938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39693292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Wu H, Wang J, Long M. Anomaly transformer: time series anomaly detection with association discrepancy. arXiv:211002642 [Preprint]. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriram S, Vinayakumar R, Alazab M, Soman KP. Network flow based IoT botnet attack detection using deep learning. IEEE INFOCOM 2020 - IEEE Conference on Computer Communications Workshops (INFOCOM WKSHPS); 2020. p. 189&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Zhang H, Zhu L, Wang Y, Deng J. ResADM: a transfer-learning-based attack detection method for cyber&#x2013;physical systems. Appl Sci. 2023;13(24):13019. doi: 10.3390/app132413019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app132413019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan MA, Granelli F. Harnessing 1D-CNN for received power prediction in sub-6 GHz RIS: Part I. 2025 IEEE International Conference on Communications Workshops (ICC Workshops). IEEE; 2025. p. 917&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan MA, Granelli F. Deep learning-driven optimal beam prediction for drone connectivity via flying-RIS and base station. 2025 IEEE 101st Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2025-Spring); 2025. p. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamanzadeh Darban Z, Webb GI, Pan S, Aggarwal C, Salehi M. Deep learning for time series anomaly detection: a survey. ACM Comput Surv. 2024;57(1):1&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1145/3691338</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3691338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M, Koh HY, Wen Q, Zambon D, Alippi C, Webb GI, et al. A survey on graph neural networks for time series: forecasting, classification, imputation, and anomaly detection. IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell. 2024;46(12):10466&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2024.3443141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2024.3443141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39141471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H, Queen O, Koker T, Cuevas C, Tsiligkaridis T, Zitnik M. Domain adaptation for time series under feature and label shifts. International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR; 2023. p. 12746&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Xu Y, Yang J, Chen Z, Wu M, Li X, et al. Sensor alignment for multivariate time-series unsupervised domain adaptation. AAAI. 2023;37(8):10253&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v37i8.26221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v37i8.26221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39150801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arjovsky M, Chintala S, Bottou L. Wasserstein GAN. arXiv:170107875 [Preprint]. 2017. 10.48550/arXiv.1701.07875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1701.07875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulrajani I, Ahmed F, Arjovsky M, Dumoulin V, Courville AC. Improved training of wasserstein gans. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2017;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zolanvari M, Teixeira MA, Gupta L, Khan KM, Jain R. Machine learning-based network vulnerability analysis of industrial Internet of Things. IEEE Internet Things J. 2019;6(4):6822&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2019.2912022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2019.2912022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastian N, Bierbrauer D, McKenzie M, Nack E. ACI IoT Network Traffic Dataset 2023; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moustafa N. A new distributed architecture for evaluating AI-based security systems at the edge: network TON_IoT datasets. Sustain Cities Soc. 2021;72:102994. doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2021.102994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2021.102994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chicco D, Jurman G. The Matthews correlation coefficient (MCC) is more reliable than balanced accuracy, bookmaker informedness, and markedness in two-class confusion matrix evaluation. Bioinformatics. 2020;36(8):250&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33541410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma DP, Ba J. Adam: a method for stochastic optimization. arXiv:14126980 [Preprint]. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakurada M, Yairi T. Anomaly detection using autoencoders with nonlinear dimensionality reduction. Proceedings of the MLSDA 2014 2nd Workshop on Machine Learning for Sensory Data Analysis; 2014. p. 4&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng A, Hooi B. Graph neural network-based anomaly detection in multivariate time series. AAAI. 2021;35(5):4027&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v35i5.16523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v35i5.16523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>