<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41573362</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2047-2501</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health information science and systems</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Inf Sci Syst</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Consistent explainable image quality assessment for medical imaging.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>31</StartPage><MedlinePgn>31</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">31</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13755-025-00411-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Medical image quality assessment is crucial, as poor-quality images can lead to misdiagnosis. Manual quality labeling is tedious for large studies and may produce misleading results. While automated analysis of image quality has been studied, little focus has been given to explaining and quantifying methodologies. This study proposes an explainable image quality assessment system, validated in two contexts: foreign object detection in Chest X-Rays (Object-CXR) and Left Ventricular Outflow Tract (LVOT) detection in Cardiac MRI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our explainable pipeline employs NormGrad, an algorithm that efficiently localizes image quality issues by comparing the classifier's saliency maps against several baseline saliency detectors. Additionally, a novel metric, the Difference of Means (DoM), is introduced to assess the consistency of saliency detectors across different network architectures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We compare NormGrad with a range of saliency detection methods and demonstrate its superior performance in measuring the faithfulness of the saliency detectors. Specifically, NormGrad achieved a repeated Pointing Game score of 0.863 for Object-CXR and 0.778 for LVOT datasets, significantly outperforming other saliency detectors. Furthermore, our explainable pipeline shows strong consistency, with DoM scores of 0.001 for Object-CXR and 0.005 for LVOT datasets, indicating high reliability across different reproduced models. The code and experiments are publicly available at https://github.com/canerozer/explainable-iqa.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The proposed system, powered by NormGrad, significantly improves the reliability of automated medical image quality evaluations. The introduction of the Difference of Means metric offers a unique way to assess saliency detector consistency, supporting NormGrad's potential for widespread clinical adoption.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozer</LastName><ForeName>Caner</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9044-143X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer Engineering Department, Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, 34467 T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/059636586</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.10516.33</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2174 543X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Mathematics, University of Twente, Enschede, 7522 the Netherlands.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/006hf6230</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.6214.1</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0399 8953</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guler</LastName><ForeName>Arda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mehmet Akif Ersoy Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery Training Research Hospital, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/00nwc4v84</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.414850.c</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0642 8921</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turkvatan Cansever</LastName><ForeName>Aysel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mehmet Akif Ersoy Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery Training Research Hospital, Istanbul, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/00nwc4v84</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.414850.c</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0642 8921</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oksuz</LastName><ForeName>Ilkay</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer Engineering Department, Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, 34467 T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/059636586</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.10516.33</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2174 543X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Engineering and Imaging Sciences, King's College London, London, SE1 7EH UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0220mzb33</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.13097.3c</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2322 6764</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Health Inf Sci Syst</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101638060</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2047-2501</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Consistency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Foreign object detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Image quality assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interpretability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LVOT detection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestAll authors certify that they have no affiliations with or involvement in any organization or entity with any financial interest or non-financial interest in the subject matter or materials discussed in this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41573362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12819959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13755-025-00411-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma JJ, Nakarmi U, Kin CYS, Sandino CM, Cheng JY, Syed AB, Wei P, Pauly JM, Vasanawala SS. Diagnostic image quality assessment and classification in medical imaging: Opportunities and challenges. IEEE ISBI.&#xa0;10.1109/ISBI45749.2020.9098735</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7710391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33274013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oksuz I, Clough JR, Ruijsink B, Anton EP, Bustin A, Cruz G, et al. Deep learning-based detection and correction of cardiac mr motion artefacts during reconstruction for high-quality segmentation. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2020;39(12):4001&#x2013;10. 10.1109/TMI.2020.3008930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMI.2020.3008930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oksuz I, Ruijsink B, Puyol-Ant&#xf3;n E, Clough JR, Cruz G, Bustin A, et al. Automatic cnn-based detection of cardiac MR motion artefacts using k-space data augmentation and curriculum learning. Med Image Anal. 2019;55:136&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.media.2019.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2019.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6688894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31055126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman LW. Principles of ct: radiation dose and image quality. J Nucl Med Technol. 2007;35(4):213&#x2013;25. 10.2967/jnmt.106.037846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnmt.106.037846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18006597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Bovik AC, Sheikh HR, Simoncelli EP. Image quality assessment: from error visibility to structural similarity. IEEE Trans Image Process. 2004;13(4):600&#x2013;12. 10.1109/TIP.2003.819861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2003.819861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15376593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reisenhofer R, Bosse S, Kutyniok G, Wiegand T. A haar wavelet-based perceptual similarity index for image quality assessment. Signal Process Image Commun. 2018;61:33&#x2013;43. 10.1016/j.image.2017.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.image.2017.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding K, Ma K, Wang S, Simoncelli EP. Image quality assessment: unifying structure and texture similarity. IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell. 2022;44(5):2567&#x2013;81. 10.1109/TPAMI.2020.3045810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2020.3045810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33338012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoneyama K, Vavere AL, Cerci R, Ahmed R, Arai AE, Niinuma H, et al. Influence of image acquisition settings on radiation dose and image quality in coronary angiography by 320-detector volume computed tomography: the core320 pilot experience. Heart Int. 2012;7(2):2012&#x2013;11. 10.4081/hi.2012.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/hi.2012.e11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3504303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23185678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow LS, Paramesran R. Review of medical image quality assessment. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2016;27:145&#x2013;54. 10.1016/j.bspc.2016.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2016.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JFHealthcare: Automatic detection of foreign objects on chest X-rays. Github. Accessed on 11/27/2020 (2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oksuz I, Ruijsink B, Puyol-Ant&#xf3;n E, Sinclair M, Rueckert D, Schnabel JA, King AP. Automatic left ventricular outflow tract classification for accurate cardiac mr planning. In: IEEE ISBI, 2018, pp. 462&#x2013;465. 10.1109/ISBI.2018.8363616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Velden BHM, Kuijf HJ, Gilhuijs KGA, Viergever MA. Explainable artificial intelligence (XAI) in deep learning-based medical image analysis. Med Image Anal. 2022;79:102470. 10.1016/j.media.2022.102470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2022.102470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35576821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaube S, Suresh H, Raue M, Lermer E, Koch TK, Hudecek MFC, et al. Non-task expert physicians benefit from correct explainable AI advice when reviewing x-rays. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):1383. 10.1038/s41598-023-28633-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-28633-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9876883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36697450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arun N, Gaw N, Singh P, Chang K, Aggarwal M, Chen B, et al. Assessing the trustworthiness of saliency maps for localizing abnormalities in medical imaging. Radiology: Artificial Intelligence. 2021;3(6):200267. 10.1148/ryai.2021200267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/ryai.2021200267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8637231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin W, Li X, Fatehi M, Hamarneh G. Guidelines and evaluation of clinical explainable ai in medical image analysis. Med Image Anal. 2022. 10.1016/j.media.2022.102684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2022.102684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36516555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adebayo J, Gilmer J, Muelly M, Goodfellow I, Hardt M, Kim B. Sanity checks for saliency maps. In: NIPS, 2018, pp. 9525&#x2013;9536. https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper/2018/hash/294a8ed24b1ad22ec2e7efea049b8737-Abstract.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petsiuk V, Das A, Saenko K. RISE: randomized input sampling for explanation of black-box models. In: BMVC, 2018, p. 151. http://bmvc2018.org/contents/papers/1064.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Bargal SA, Lin Z, Brandt J, Shen X, Sclaroff S, et al. Top-down neural attention by excitation backprop. Int J Computer Vis. 2018;126(10):1084&#x2013;102. 10.1007/978-3-319-46493-0_33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-46493-0_33</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez T, Fr&#xe9;our T, Mouch&#xe8;re H. Metrics for saliency map evaluation of deep learning explanation methods. In: El-Yacoubi MA, Granger E, Yuen PC, Pal U, Vincent N, editors. Pattern Recognition and Artificial Intelligence - Third International Conference, ICPRAI 2022, Paris, France, June 1-3, 2022, Proceedings, Part I. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2022, vol. 13363, pp. 84&#x2013;95. Springer, 10.1007/978-3-031-09037-0_8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englebert A, Cornu O, Vleeschouwer CD. Backward recursive class activation map refinement for high resolution saliency map. In: 26th International Conference on Pattern Recognition, ICPR 2022, Montreal, QC, Canada, August 21-25, 2022, 2022, pp. 2444&#x2013;2450. IEEE, 10.1109/ICPR56361.2022.9956711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanfredi RB, Arora A, Drew T, Schroeder JD, Tasdizen T. Comparing radiologists&#x2019; gaze and saliency maps generated by interpretability methods for chest x-rays. CoRR, 2021. arXiv:2112.11716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebuffi S-A, Fong R, Ji X, Vedaldi A. There and back again: Revisiting backpropagation saliency methods. In: IEEE CVPR,, 2020, pp. 8836&#x2013;8845. 10.1109/CVPR42600.2020.00886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozer C, Oksuz I. Explainable image quality analysis of chest x-rays. In: Medical Imaging with Deep Learning 2021. https://openreview.net/forum?id=ln797A8lAb0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sujit SJ, Gabr RE, Coronado I, Robinson M, Datta S, Narayana PA. Automated image quality evaluation of structural brain magnetic resonance images using deep convolutional neural networks. In: 9th Cairo Int Biomed Eng Conf, 2018, pp. 33&#x2013;36. 10.1109/CIBEC.2018.8641830</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Zhang C, Zhou K, Gao S. Chest x-ray diagnostic quality assessment: how much is pixel-wise supervision needed? IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2022;41(7):1711&#x2013;23. 10.1109/TMI.2022.3149171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMI.2022.3149171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35120002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortamet B, Bernstein MA, Jack CR Jr, Gunter JL, Ward C, Britson PJ, et al. Automatic quality assessment in structural brain magnetic resonance imaging. Magn Reson Med. 2009;62(2):365&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mrm.21992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2780021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19526493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdi AH, Luong C, Tsang T, Jue J, Gin K, Yeung D, Hawley D, Rohling R, Abolmaesumi P. Quality assessment of echocardiographic cine using recurrent neural networks: Feasibility on five standard view planes. In: MICCAI 2017 Proceedings, Part III, 2017, pp. 302&#x2013;310. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg. 10.1007/978-3-319-66179-7_35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi S, Hamedani KA, Moghaddam ME, Abin AA, Frangi AF. Statistical Distance-Guided Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Automated Multi-Class Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance Image Quality Assessment 2024. https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.00375</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi S, Hamedani KA, Moghaddam ME, Abin AA, Frangi AF. Multiple Teachers-Meticulous Student: A Domain Adaptive Meta-Knowledge Distillation Model for Medical Image Classification 2024. https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.11226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Min X, Duan H, Zhu Y, Zhai G. Muiqa: Image quality assessment database and algorithm for medical ultrasound images. In: IEEE ICIP, 2021, pp. 2958&#x2013;2962.10.1109/ICIP42928.2021.9506431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Zhang X, Ren S, Sun J. Deep residual learning for image recognition. In: IEEE CVPR, 2016, pp. 770&#x2013;778. 10.1109/CVPR.2016.90</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Shen L, Sun G. Squeeze-and-excitation networks. In: IEEE CVPR, 2018, pp. 7132&#x2013;7141. 10.1109/CVPR.2018.00745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottani S, Burgos N, Maire A, Wild A, Str&#xf6;er S, Dormont D, et al. Automatic quality control of brain T1-weighted magnetic resonance images for a clinical data warehouse. Med Image Anal. 2022;75:102219. 10.1016/j.media.2021.102219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2021.102219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34773767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagoski B, Xu J, Wighton P, Tisdall MD, Frost R, Lo W-C, et al. Automated detection and reacquisition of motion-degraded images in fetal HASTE imaging at 3 T. Magn Reson Med. 2022;87(4):1914&#x2013;22. 10.1002/mrm.29106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mrm.29106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8810713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi S, Hashemi M, Ebrahimi Moghaddam M, Abin AA, Frangi AF. Automated cardiac coverage assessment in cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging using an explainable recurrent 3D dual-domain convolutional network. Med Phys. 2024;51(12):8789&#x2013;803. 10.1002/mp.17411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mp.17411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39312585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabavi S, Simchi H, Moghaddam ME, Abin AA, Frangi AF. A generalised deep meta-learning model for automated quality control of cardiovascular magnetic resonance images. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2023;242:107770. 10.1016/j.cmpb.2023.107770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2023.107770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37714020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Y, Ruan J, Yang B, Gao Y, Jin J, Dong F, et al. Automated quality assessment of chest radiographs based on deep learning and linear regression cascade algorithms. Eur Radiol. 2022;32(11):7680&#x2013;90. 10.1007/s00330-022-08771-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-022-08771-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35420306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xun S, Sun Y, Chen J, Yu Z, Tong T, Liu X, Wu M, Tan T. MedIQA: A scalable foundation model for prompt-driven medical image quality assessment . In: Proceedings of Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention &#x2013; MICCAI 2025, 2025. Springer</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeiler MD, Fergus R. Visualizing and understanding convolutional networks. In: Fleet D, Pajdla T, Schiele B, Tuytelaars T, editors. ECCV, 2014, pp. 818&#x2013;833. Springer, Cham. 10.1007/978-3-319-10590-1_53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonyan K, Zisserman A. Very deep convolutional networks for large-scale image recognition. In: ICLR 2015. http://arxiv.org/abs/1409.1556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springenberg JT, Dosovitskiy A, Brox T, Riedmiller MA. Striving for simplicity: The all convolutional net. In: ICLR 2015. http://arxiv.org/abs/1412.6806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrikumar A, Greenside P, Kundaje A. Learning important features through propagating activation differences. In: Precup D, Teh YW, editors. ICML. PMLR, 2017, vol. 70, pp. 3145&#x2013;3153. http://proceedings.mlr.press/v70/shrikumar17a.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvaraju RR, Cogswell M, Das A, Vedantam R, Parikh D, Batra D. Grad-cam: visual explanations from deep networks via gradient-based localization. Int J Comput Vis. 2020;128(2):336&#x2013;59. 10.1007/S11263-019-01228-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S11263-019-01228-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundararajan M, Taly A, Yan Q. Axiomatic attribution for deep networks. In: Precup D, Teh YW, editors. ICML, 2017, vol. 70, pp. 3319&#x2013;3328. PMLR. http://proceedings.mlr.press/v70/sundararajan17a.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Wang Z, Du M, Yang F, Zhang Z, Ding S, Mardziel P, Hu X. Score-cam: Score-weighted visual explanations for convolutional neural networks. In: IEEE CVPRW 2020. 10.1109/CVPRW50498.2020.00020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smilkov D, Thorat N, Kim B, Vi&#xe9;gas FB, Wattenberg M. Smoothgrad: removing noise by adding noise. CoRR, 2017. arXiv:1706.0382510.48550/arXiv.1706.03825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM, Lee S. A unified approach to interpreting model predictions. In: Guyon I, Luxburg U, Bengio S, Wallach HM, Fergus R, Vishwanathan SVN, Garnett R, editors. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 30: Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems 2017, December 4-9, 2017, Long Beach, CA, USA, 2017, pp. 4765&#x2013;4774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro MT, Singh S, Guestrin C. "why should I trust you?": Explaining the predictions of any classifier. In: Krishnapuram B, Shah M, Smola AJ, Aggarwal CC, Shen D, Rastogi R, editors. Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, San Francisco, CA, USA, August 13-17, 2016, 2016, pp. 1135&#x2013;1144. ACM. 10.1145/2939672.2939778</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Q-H, Niu Y-W, Sui J, Zhao W-D, Zhuo C, Calhoun VD. Sspnet: an interpretable 3d-cnn for classification of schizophrenia using phase maps of resting-state complex-valued fmri data. Med Image Anal. 2022;79:102430. 10.1016/j.media.2022.102430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2022.102430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35397470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J-K, Jung S, Park J, Han SW. Arrhythmia detection model using modified densenet for comprehensible grad-cam visualization. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2022;73:103408. 10.1016/j.bspc.2021.103408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2021.103408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S, Kim G, Oh Y, Seo JB, Lee SM, Kim JH, et al. Multi-task vision transformer using low-level chest x-ray feature corpus for covid-19 diagnosis and severity quantification. Med Image Anal. 2022;75:102299. 10.1016/j.media.2021.102299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2021.102299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8566090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34814058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Lyu J, Cheng P, Tam R, Tang X. Ssit: Saliency-guided self-supervised image transformer for diabetic retinopathy grading. CoRR, 2022. arXiv:2210.10969, 10.48550/arXiv.2210.10969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38319784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh J, Kim J, Jung E, Rhee W. Evaluating feature attribution methods for electrocardiogram. CoRR 2022. arXiv:2211.1270210.48550/arXiv.2211.12702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byra M, Dobruch-Sobczak K, Piotrzkowska-Wroblewska H, Klimonda Z, Litniewski J. Explaining a deep learning based breast ultrasound image classifier with saliency maps. J Ultrasonography. 2022;22(89):70&#x2013;5. 10.15557/JoU.2022.0013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15557/JoU.2022.0013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9231514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35811586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Kim M, Ro YM. Interpretation of lesional detection via counterfactual generation. In: 2021 IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2021, pp. 96&#x2013;100. 10.1109/ICIP42928.2021.9506282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M, Le QV. Efficientnet: Rethinking model scaling for convolutional neural networks. In: Chaudhuri K, Salakhutdinov R, editors. ICML, 2019, vol. 97, pp. 6105&#x2013;6114. PMLR. http://proceedings.mlr.press/v97/tan19a.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Dong W, Socher R, Li L, Kai L, Li F-F. Imagenet: A large-scale hierarchical image database. In: IEEE CVPR, 2009, pp. 248&#x2013;255. 10.1109/CVPR.2009.5206848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K, Zhang X, Ren S, Sun J. Delving deep into rectifiers: Surpassing human-level performance on imagenet classification. In: IEEE ICCV, 2015, pp. 1026&#x2013;1034. 10.1109/ICCV.2015.123</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gretton A, Borgwardt KM, Rasch MJ, Sch&#xf6;lkopf B, Smola A. A kernel two-sample test. J Mach Learn Res. 2012;13(25):723&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samarasinghe G, Jameson M, Vinod S, Field M, Dowling J, Sowmya A, et al. Deep learning for segmentation in radiation therapy planning: a review. J Med Imaging Radiat Oncol. 2021;65(5):578&#x2013;95. 10.1111/1754-9485.13286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1754-9485.13286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34313006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>