<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41544159</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Manipulating metal growth in hollow ionic-electronic conductor for anode-free lithium metal batteries.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadt2630</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadt2630</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadt2630</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adt2630</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Anode-free lithium metal batteries (AFLMBs) demonstrate promising high energy density yet suffer from irregular Li deposition, parasitic reactions, and severe volume expansion. The current anode modulation strategies such as tailored solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) and lithiophilic host architectures can hardly simultaneously resolve all above issues, especially at high-capacity Li deposition. Here, we design a Li-rich, hollow ionic-electronic conductor (HIEC) interlayer, which integrates metallic Li encapsulation and interfacial protection, thus guiding highly reversible thick Li deposition (5 milliampere-hours per square centimeter). In addition, the built-in electron-deficient domains in the HIEC facilitate the formation of the hierarchical SEI and further mitigate active Li corrosion. These synergistic effects of the interlayer enable stable cycling in batteries under both anode-less and anode-free configurations, attaining &gt;99% coulombic efficiency under industrial-level cathode loading and lean electrolyte conditions. This study highlights the significance of interlayers in integrating the SEI and host functions and provides a viable and scalable solution for energy-dense batteries.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Lianqiang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-1592-4612</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academy for Advanced Interdisciplinary Studies, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xi</LastName><ForeName>Zihang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yawen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ning</LastName><ForeName>Yujie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0625-9892</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontiers Science Center for New Organic Matter, Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Materials Chemistry (Ministry of Education), State Key Laboratory of Advanced Chemical Power Sources, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academy for Advanced Interdisciplinary Studies, Nankai University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Haihe Laboratory of Sustainable Chemical Transformations, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41544159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12810650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adt2630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dunn B., Kamath H., Tarascon J. M., Electrical energy storage for the grid: A battery of choices. Science 334, 928&#x2013;935 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22096188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Y., Yang H. J., Chang Z., Deng H., Li X., Zhou H. S., 
A high-energy-density and long-life initial-anode-free lithium battery enabled by a Li<sub>2</sub>O sacrificial agent. Nat. Energy
6, 
653&#x2013;662 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Bao Z. N., Cui Y., Dufek E. J., Goodenough J. B., Khalifah P., Li Q. Y., Liaw B. Y., Liu P., Manthiram A., Meng Y. S., Subramanian V. R., Toney M. F., Viswanathan V. V., Whittingham M. S., Xiao J., Xu W., Yang J. H., Yang X.-Q., Zhang J.-G., Pathways for practical high-energy long-cycling lithium metal batteries. Nat. Energy 4, 180&#x2013;186 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y.-G., Fujiki S., Jung C., Suzuki N., Yashiro N., Omoda R., Ko D.-S., Shiratsuchi T., Sugimoto T., Ryu S., Ku J. H., Watanabe T., Park Y., Aihara Y., Im D., Han I. T., High-energy long-cycling all-solid-state lithium metal batteries enabled by silver&#x2013;carbon composite anodes. Nat. Energy 5, 299&#x2013;308 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagos T. M., Bezabh H. K., Huang C.-J., Jiang S.-K., Su W.-N., Hwang B. J., A powerful protocol based on anode-free cells combined with various analytical techniques. Acc. Chem. Res. 54, 4474&#x2013;4485 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34763425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanda S., Gupta A., Manthiram A., Anode-free full cells: A pathway to high-energy density lithium-metal batteries. Adv. Energy Mater. 11, 2000804 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louli A. J., Eldesoky A., Weber R., Genovese M., Coon M., deGooyer J., Deng Z., White R. T., Lee J., Rodgers T., Petibon R., Hy S., Cheng S. J., Dahn J. R., Diagnosing and correcting anode-free cell failure via electrolyte and morphological analysis. Nat. Energy 5, 693&#x2013;702 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu G. X., Nai J., Luan D. Y., Tao X. Y., Lou X. W., Surface engineering toward stable lithium metal anodes. Sci. Adv. 9, eadf1550 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10075991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37018409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horstmann B., Shi J. Y., Amine R., Werres M., He X., Jia H., Hausen F., Cekic-Laskovic I., Wiemers-Meyer S., Lopez J., Galvez-Aranda D., Baakes F., Bresser D., Su C.-C., Xu Y. B., Xu W., Jakes P., Eichel R.-A., Figgemeier E., Krewer U., Seminario J. M., Balbuena P. B., Wang C. M., Passerini S., Shao-Horn Y., Winter M., Amine K., Kostecki R., Latz A., Strategies towards enabling lithium metal in batteries: Interphases and electrodes. Energy Environ. Sci. 14, 5289&#x2013;5314 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H., Wu J., Li M., Zhao J., Li Z., Wang M., Li X., Li C., Chen X., Li X., Mai Y.-W., Chen Y., Heterogeneous structure design for stable Li/Na metal batteries: Progress and prospects. eScience 5, 100281 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou B. X., Bonakdarpour A., Sto&#x161;evski I., Fang B. Z., Wilkinson D. P., Modification of Cu current collectors for lithium metal batteries&#x2014;A review. Prog. Mater. Sci. 130, 100996 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao J., Li Q. Y., Bi Y. J., Cai M., Dunn B., Glossmann T., Liu J., Osaka T., Sugiura R., Wu B. B., Yang J. H., Zhang J.-G., Whittingham M. S., Understanding and applying coulombic efficiency in lithium metal batteries. Nat. Energy 5, 561&#x2013;568 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu C. J., Lee H., Chen S. R., Li Q. Y., Du J., Xu W., Zhang J.-G., Whittingham M. S., Xiao J., Liu J., High-energy lithium metal pouch cells with limited anode swelling and long stable cycles. Nat. Energy 4, 551&#x2013;559 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N. W., Yin Y. X., Yang C. P., Guo Y. G., An artificial solid electrolyte interphase layer for stable lithium metal anodes. Adv. Mater. 28, 1853&#x2013;1858 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26698171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S. M., Huang J. L., Cui Y., Liu S. H., Chen Z. R., Huang W., Li C. F., Liu R. L., Fu R. W., Wu D. C., A robust all-organic protective layer towards ultrahigh-rate and large-capacity Li metal anodes. Nat. Nanotechnol. 17, 613&#x2013;621 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35469010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H., Yang Y. F., Boyle D. T., Jeong Y. K., Xu R., de Vasconcelos L. S., Huang Z. J., Wang H. S., Wang H. X., Huang W. X., Li H. Q., Wang J. Y., Gu H. K., Matsumoto R., Motohashi K., Nakayama Y. R., Zhao K. J., Cui Y., Free-standing ultrathin lithium metal-graphene oxide host foils with controllable thickness for lithium batteries. Nat. Energy 6, 790&#x2013;798 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R., Cheng X.-B., Yan C., Zhang X.-Q., Xiao Y., Zhao C.-Z., Huang J.-Q., Zhang Q., Artificial interphases for highly stable lithium metal anode. Matter 1, 317&#x2013;344 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y., Yan Z. F., Gray J. L., He X., Wang D. W., Chen T. H., Huang Q. Q., Li Y. C., Wang H. Y., Kim S. H., Mallouk T. E., Wang D. H., Polymer&#x2013;inorganic solid&#x2013;electrolyte interphase for stable lithium metal batteries under lean electrolyte conditions. Nat. Mater. 18, 384&#x2013;389 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30858569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W., Wang J. L., Ding F., Chen X. L., Nasybulin E., Zhang Y. H., Zhang J.-G., Lithium metal anodes for rechargeable batteries. Energy Environ. Sci. 7, 513&#x2013;537 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Zeng W., Hong L., Xu W. W., Yang H. K., Wang F., Duan H. G., Tang M., Jiang H. Q., Stress-driven lithium dendrite growth mechanism and dendrite mitigation by electroplating on soft substrates. Nat. Energy 3, 227&#x2013;235 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang C. C., Lu B. Y., Pawar G., Zhang M. H., Cheng D. Y., Chen S. R., Ceja M., Doux J.-M., Musrock H., Cai M., Liaw B., Meng Y. S., Pressure-tailored lithium deposition and dissolution in lithium metal batteries. Nat. Energy 6, 987&#x2013;994 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H. M., Liao X. B., Guan Y. P., Xiang Y., Li M., Zhang W. F., Zhu X. Y., Ming H., Lu L., Qiu J. Y., Huang Y. Q., Cao G. P., Yang Y. S., Mai L. Q., Zhao Y., Zhang H., Lithiophilic-lithiophobic gradient interfacial layer for a highly stable lithium metal anode. Nat. Commun. 9, 3729 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6137161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30213936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Y.-C., Yu Z.-L., Ma Z.-Y., Zhang T.-W., Lu Y.-Y., Ma T., Zhou F., Yao H.-B., Yu S.-H., Bio-inspired low-tortuosity carbon host for high-performance lithium-metal anode. Natl. Sci. Rev. 6, 247&#x2013;256 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8291544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34691863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma S. B., Zhao J. T., Xiao H., Gao Q. X., Li F., Song C. Y., Li G. X., Modulating the inner helmholtz plane towards stable solid electrolyte interphase by anion&#x2013;&#x3c0; interactions for high-performance anode-free lithium metal batteries. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 137, e202412955 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39319374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak R., Chen K., Wu F., Mane A. U., Bugga R. V., Elam J. W., Qiao Q., Zhou Y., Advanced strategies for the development of porous carbon as a Li host/current collector for lithium metal batteries. Energy Storage Mater. 41, 448&#x2013;465 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y., Zhang S. L., Wu Z.-P., Luan D., Lou X. W., A highly stable lithium metal anode enabled by Ag nanoparticle-embedded nitrogen-doped carbon macroporous fibers. Sci. Adv. 7, eabg3626 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34020959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng G. Y., Lee S. W., Liang Z., Lee H.-W., Yan K., Yao H. B., Wang H. T., Li W. Y., Chu S., Cui Y., Interconnected hollow carbon nanospheres for stable lithium metal anodes. Nat. Nanotechnol. 9, 618&#x2013;623 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25064396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M. S., Yao Z. G., Yang Q. F., Li C. L., Consecutive nucleation and confinement modulation towards Li plating in seeded capsules for durable Li-metal batteries. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 133, 14159&#x2013;14169 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33837636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y. M., Wang Z. Q., Li X. Y., Yao X., Wang C., Li Y. T., Xue W. J., Yu D. W., Kim S. Y., Yang F., Kushima A., Zhang G. G., Huang H. T., Wu N., Mai Y.-W., Goodenough J. B., Li J., Li metal deposition and stripping in a solid-state battery via Coble creep. Nature 578, 251&#x2013;255 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan K., Lu Z. D., Lee H.-W., Xiong F., Hsu P.-C., Li Y. Z., Zhao J., Chu S., Cui Y., Selective deposition and stable encapsulation of lithium through heterogeneous seeded growth. Nat. Energy 1, 1&#x2013;8 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X. W., Zhang X. Y., Ma Q. T., Guan X. Z., Wang W., Luo J. Y., Revisiting the electroplating process for lithium-metal anodes for lithium-metal batteries. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 59, 6665&#x2013;6674 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S. Q., Zhang L., Liu T. T., Zhang Y. W., Guo C., Wang Y., Du F. H., 
A dendrite-free lithium-metal anode enabled by designed ultrathin MgF<sub>2</sub> nanosheets encapsulated inside nitrogen-doped graphene-like hollow nanospheres. Adv. Mater.
34, 
e2201801 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35417929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J. J., Cheng Y., Zhang H. H., Yan X. L., Sun Z. F., Ye W. B., Li W. Q., Zhang M. Y., Gao H. W., Han J. J., Peng D.-L., Yang Y., Wang M.-S., Enhanced cyclability of lithium metal anodes enabled by anti-aggregation of lithiophilic seeds. Nano Lett. 22, 5874&#x2013;5882 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35763376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin S., Ye Y. D., Niu Y. J., Xu Y. S., Jin H. C., Wang J. X., Sun Z. W., Cao A. M., Wu X. J., Luo Y., Ji H. X., Wan L. J., Solid-solution-based metal alloy phase for highly reversible lithium metal anode. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 142, 8818&#x2013;8826 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32310653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Fan X. L., Ji X., Chen J., Hou S., Wang C. S., High-energy Li metal battery with lithiated host. Joule 3, 732&#x2013;744 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Huang J., Saito N., Zhang Z. X., Yang L., Hirano S. I., Hirano S.-i., Search for stable host materials as low-voltage anodes for lithium-ion batteries: A mini-review. Energy Storage Mater. 55, 364&#x2013;387 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbonaite S., Wachtmeister S., Mirguet C., Coronel E., Zou W. Y., Csillag S., Svensson G., EELS studies of carbide derived carbons. Carbon 45, 2047&#x2013;2053 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Z. Q., Ni K., Chen G. X., Zeng W. C., Tao Z. C., Ikram M., Zhang Q. B., Wang H. J., Sun L. T., Zhu X. J., Wu X. J., Ji H. X., Ruoff R. S., Zhu Y. W., 
Incorporating pyrrolic and pyridinic nitrogen into a porous carbon made from C<sub>60</sub> molecules to obtain superior energy storage. Adv. Mater.
29, 
1603414 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27991689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q. Q., Deng B., Zhang H. M., Wang B. Y., Zhang W. F., Wen Y. H., Ming H., Zhu X. Y., Guan Y. P., Xiang Y., Li M., Cao G. P., Yang Y. S., Peng H. L., Zhang H., Huang Y. Q., Heterogeneous nucleation and growth of electrodeposited lithium metal on the basal plane of single-layer graphene. Energy Storage Mater. 16, 419&#x2013;425 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Y. L., He G., Hu W., Yang H., Yang Z. Z., Yu H. S., Zhang Q. H., Shi J. N., Lin Z. F., Yuan J., Zhu B. Y., Gu L., Li H., Jin K., 
The effects of oxygen in spinel oxide Li<sub>1+x</sub>Ti<sub>2&#x2212;x</sub>O<sub>4&#x2212;&#x3b4;</sub> thin films. Sci. Rep.
8, 
3995 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5838103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29507404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y. X., Lian J., Sun Z. Z., Zhao M. L., Shi Y. J., Song H. N., 
The first-principles study for the novel optical properties of LiTi<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, Li<sub>4</sub>Ti<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub>, Li<sub>2</sub>Ti<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Li<sub>7</sub>Ti<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub>. Chem. Phys. Lett.
677, 
114&#x2013;119 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paste R., Hanmandlu C., Su P.-Y., Hou C.-H., Chen H.-A., Pao C.-W., Shyue J.-J., Chen K.-H., Wu H.-L., Lin H.-C., Chu C. W., 
Intimate interaction of TFSI<sup>&#x2212;</sup> anions with MoO<sub>3-x</sub> oxygen vacancies boost ionic conductivity of cathode-supported solid polymer electrolyte. Chem. Eng. J.
452, 
139088 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou W. S., Feng P. L., Guo X., Wang Z. H., Bai Z., Bai Y., Wang G. X., Sun K. N., Catalytic mechanism of oxygen vacancies in perovskite oxides for lithium&#x2013;sulfur batteries. Adv. Mater. 34, e2202222 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35534022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masias A., Felten N., Garcia-Mendez R., Wolfenstine J., Sakamoto J., Elastic, plastic, and creep mechanical properties of lithium metal. J. Mater. Sci. 54, 2585&#x2013;2600 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monroe C., Newman J., The impact of elastic deformation on deposition kinetics at lithium/polymer interfaces. J. Electrochem. Soc. 152, A396 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H. D., Zhu Z. Y., Huang J., He X., Chen Y., Zhang R., Lin R. Q., Li Y. J., Yu S. C., Xing X., Yan Q. Z., Li X. G., Frost M. J., An K., Feng J., Kostecki R., Xin H. L., Ong S. P., Liu P., 
Elucidating the limit of Li insertion into the spinel Li<sub>4</sub>Ti<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub>. ACS Mater. Lett.
1, 
96&#x2013;102 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang J., Kang I., Choi J., Jeong H., Yi K. W., Hong J., Lee M., Molecularly tailored lithium&#x2013;arene complex enables chemical prelithiation of high-capacity lithium-ion battery anodes. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 59, 14473&#x2013;14480 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32400120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J., Jeong H., Jang J., Jeon A.-R., Kang I., Kwon M., Hong J., Lee M., 
Weakly solvating solution enables chemical prelithiation of Graphite&#x2013;SiO<i>x</i> anodes for high-energy Li-ion batteries. J. Am. Chem. Soc.
143, 
9169&#x2013;9176 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34111352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X. L., Su Z. P., Wu C., Cong H. J., Ai X. P., Yang H. X., Qian J. F., 
Exfoliation of MoS<sub>2</sub> nanosheets enabled by a redox-potential-matched chemical lithiation reaction. Nano Lett.
22, 
2956&#x2013;2963 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Zhao C.-Z., Huang J.-Q., Zhang Q., The timescale identification decoupling complicated kinetic processes in lithium batteries. Joule 6, 1172&#x2013;1198 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer D. M., Duwe P., Indris S., Heitjans P., Tracer diffusion measurements in solid lithium: A test case for the comparison between NMR in static and pulsed magnetic field gradients after upgrading a standard solid state NMR spectrometer. Solid State Nucl. Magn. Reson. 26, 74&#x2013;83 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15276637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi P. R., Ma J. B., Liu M., Guo S. K., Huang Y. F., Wang S. W., Zhang L. H., Chen L. K., Yang K., Liu X. T., Li Y. H., An X. F., Zhang D. F., Cheng X., Li Q. D., Lv W., Zhong G. M., He Y.-B., Kang F. Y., A dielectric electrolyte composite with high lithium-ion conductivity for high-voltage solid-state lithium metal batteries. Nat. Nanotechnol. 18, 602&#x2013;610 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36894781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Y.-L., Wang X.-L., Yuan H., Li Y.-J., Xu C.-M., Li S., Hu J.-K., Yang S.-J., Deng F., Liu J., Huang J.-Q., Ultrafast Li-rich transport in composite solid-state electrolytes. Adv. Mater. 37, 2419782 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39887311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z. H., Wang C. Y., Hui Z. Y., Liu H. D., Wang S., Yu S. C., Xing X., Holoubek J., Miao Q. S., Xin H. L., Liu P., Growing single-crystalline seeds on lithiophobic substrates to enable fast-charging lithium-metal batteries. Nat. Energy 8, 340&#x2013;350 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng S. T., Zhang X., Yang G. J., Zhang S. M., Ma B. Y., Liu Q. Y., Liu Y., Peng C. X., Chen H. X., Yu H. L., Fan X. L., Cheng T., Chen L. Q., Li Y. J., Wang Z. X., Wang X. F., 
Temperature-dependent interphase formation and Li<sup>+</sup> transport in lithium metal batteries. Nat. Commun.
14, 
4474 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10368715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37491340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L.-Q., Li Z., Fan Z.-Y., Li K., Li J., Huang D. B., Li A. J., Yang Y., Xie W. W., Zhao Q., Unveiling the role of fluorination in hexacyclic coordinated ether electrolytes for high-voltage lithium metal batteries. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 146, 5964&#x2013;5976 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38381843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z. C., Li R. H., Zhang S. Q., Lv L., Deng T., Zhang H., Zhang R. X., Liu J. J., Ding S. H., Fan L. W., Chen L. X., Fan X. L., Deciphering and modulating energetics of solvation structure enables aggressive high-voltage chemistry of Li metal batteries. Chem 9, 650&#x2013;664 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y. J., Wang C. S., Galvanostatic intermittent titration technique for phase-transformation electrodes. J. Phys. Chem. C 114, 2830&#x2013;2841 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickol A., Schied T., Heubner C., Schneider M., Michaelis A., Bobeth M., Cuniberti G., GITT analysis of lithium insertion cathodes for determining the lithium diffusion coefficient at low temperature: Challenges and pitfalls. J. Electrochem. Soc. 167, 090546 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heitkam S., Drenckhan W., Fr&#xf6;hlich J., Packing spheres tightly: Influence of mechanical stability on close-packed sphere structures. Phys. Rev. Lett. 108, 148302 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22540826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z. Z., Zhu G. S., Xu H. R., Yu A. B., 
Amorphous Li<sub>4</sub>Ti<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub> thin film with enhanced lithium storage capability and reversibility for lithium-ion batteries. Energ. Technol.
2, 
767&#x2013;772 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing X., Li Y. J., Wang S., Liu H. D., Wu Z. H., Yu S. C., Holoubek J., Zhou H., Liu P., Graphite-based lithium-free 3D hybrid anodes for high energy density all-solid-state batteries. ACS Energy Lett. 6, 1831&#x2013;1838 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S., Kim D. Y., Lee J. I., Kang J., Lee H., Kim G., Seo D. H., Park S., Highly reversible lithium host materials for high-energy-density anode-free lithium metal batteries. Adv. Funct. Mater. 32, 2208629 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Yang P. Z., Wang Y., Wang S. Z., High entropy alloy nanoparticles decorated carbon-based electrode as interfacial Li-ion localized accelerators for anode-free lithium metal batteries. Carbon 228, 119432 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W., Ning D., Zhang J. H., Liu G. D., Zeng L. X., Yao H. D., Wang M., Deng L. B., Yao L., Ultralight lithiophilic three-dimensional lithium host for stable high-energy-density anode-free lithium metal batteries. Energy Storage Mater. 63, 102974 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon H., Lee J.-H., Roh Y., Baek J., Shin D. J., Yoon J. K., Ha H. J., Kim J. Y., Kim H.-T., An electron-deficient carbon current collector for anode-free Li-metal batteries. Nat. Commun. 12, 5537 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8452779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34545077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wondimkun Z. T., Tegegne W. A., Shi-Kai J., Huang C.-J., Sahalie N. A., Weret M. A., Hsu J.-Y., Hsieh P.-L., Huang Y.-S., Wu S.-H., Su W. N., Hwang B. J., Highly-lithiophilic Ag@PDA-GO film to suppress dendrite formation on Cu substrate in anode-free lithium metal batteries. Energy Storage Mater. 35, 334&#x2013;344 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Wang Y., Lu X. M., Qian J., Yang C., Manke I., Song H., Liao J. X., Wang S. Z., Chen R., Ultra-sleek high entropy alloy tights: Realizing superior cyclability for anode-free battery. Adv. Mater. 36, 2308257 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38102857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Liu M., Thijs M., Ooms F. G., Ganapathy S., Wagemaker M., High dielectric barium titanate porous scaffold for efficient Li metal cycling in anode-free cells. Nat. Commun. 12, 6536 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8585873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34764287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X., Liu C., Zhang A. Y., Ding L., Zeng T. Y., Lu Y., Ou Y., Hou W. H., Zhou P., Cao Q. B., Yan S. S., Liu Z., Peng X. W., Zhou H. Y., Xia Y. C., Zhang W. L., Liu H., Liu K., Interphasial chemistry design for seamless lithium deposition in anode-free lithium metal batteries. Adv. Mater. 37, e2500478 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40275697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan J., Deng L. Q., Liu Y. Y., Hao M. J., Wang Z. F., Dong L.-T., Yang Y. S., Song K. P., Qi D. Q., Wang J. J., Wang S. H., Liu H., Zhou W. J., Chen H., Self-selective (220) directional grown copper current collector design for cycling-stable anode-less lithium metal batteries. Adv. Mater. 37, 2413420 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39676390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Wang J. H., Overcoming copper substrate thermodynamic limitations in anode-free lithium pouch cells via in situ seed implantation. Nano Lett. 23, 10251&#x2013;10258 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37781986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J. R., Zhang S., Li J. D., Xie B., Ma J., Dong S. M., Cui G. L., Robust transport: An artificial solid electrolyte interphase design for anode-free lithium-metal batteries. Adv. Mater. 35, e2209404 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36573477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. B., Luo H., Liu Z. Y., Wang S. H., Zhou X. F., Liu Z. P., 
A chemical lithiation induced Li<sub>4.4</sub>Sn lithiophilic layer for anode-free lithium metal batteries. J. Mater. Chem. A
10, 
9670&#x2013;9679 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L.-Y., Chang S.-H., 
Lithiophilic Cu<sub>1.94</sub>S microporous coating via breath figure templating for dendrite suppression in anode-free lithium metal batteries. Electrochim. Acta
536, 
146690 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan K., Wu S.-H., Wu Y.-S., Chang J.-K., Jose R., Yang C.-C., Tuning intrinsic lithiophilicity of copper foil to improve electrochemical performance of anode-free Li metal battery. J. Energy Storage 84, 110880 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S. S., Fan X. L., Wang C. S., A tin-plated copper substrate for efficient cycling of lithium metal in an anode-free rechargeable lithium battery. Electrochim. Acta 258, 1201&#x2013;1207 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X., Wu J., Liang J. N., Sun Y. P., Ren X. Z., Ouyang X. P., Wu D. Z., Li Y. L., Zhang L., Hu J. T., Zhang Q. L., Liu J. H., Locally fluorinated electrolyte medium layer for high-performance anode-free Li-metal batteries. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 14, 53788&#x2013;53797 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36441596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>