<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41388697</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Advancing Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting with Z-Scheme Heterojunctions by Interfacial Manipulation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e15717</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e15717</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202515717</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Photocatalytic overall water splitting (POWS), as a promising technology for large-scale solar hydrogen production, has propelled the development of advanced photocatalysts. Z-scheme heterojunctions are believed to be ideal candidates for efficient POWS due to the reconcilable benefits of broad solar spectrum absorption and sufficient redox potentials. POWS by Z-scheme heterojunctions involves multiple-step charge transfer processes happening at the interfaces, thereby making interfacial manipulation crucial to improving the photocatalytic performance. This review delves into the intricate details of interfacial manipulation in Z-scheme heterojunctions with an emphasis on the semiconductor-semiconductor interfaces and the semiconductor-water interfaces. First, the basic charge transfer processes are explored at the interfaces, and then summarize and explore the effective manipulation strategies to promote the interfacial charge transfer processes for enhanced POWS performance. Further, the advanced characterization techniques are introduced for understanding these interfacial processes. Finally, the current challenges and future directions are provided for the development of efficient Z-scheme heterojunctions for POWS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Research Center for Renewable Energy, State Key Laboratory of Multiphase Flow in Power Engineering, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Jiaotong University Suzhou Academy, Suzhou, 215123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering and Technology, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guan</LastName><ForeName>Xiangjiu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Research Center for Renewable Energy, State Key Laboratory of Multiphase Flow in Power Engineering, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Jiaotong University Suzhou Academy, Suzhou, 215123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Daming</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Advanced Energy, Shenzhen Campus of Sun Yat-sen University, Shenzhen, 518107, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory for Nonequilibrium Synthesis and Modulation of Condensed Matter, School of Physics, National Innovation Platform (Center) for Industry-Education Integration of Energy Storage Technology, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Shaohua</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8536-7386</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Research Center for Renewable Energy, State Key Laboratory of Multiphase Flow in Power Engineering, Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, 710049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Jiaotong University Suzhou Academy, Suzhou, 215123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22432003</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52225606</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52302308</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021YFF0501900</GrantID><Agency>National Key R&amp;D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024CY-GJHX-28</GrantID><Agency>Key R&amp;D Program of Shaanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025SYS-SYSZD-075</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Basic Research Plan in Shaanxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Z&#x2010;scheme heterojunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">charge extraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">charge separation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interfacial manipulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">photocatalytic overall water splitting</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41388697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202515717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>A. Slamer&#x161;ak, G. Kallis, D. W. O'Neill, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 6932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Chen, S. Shen, L. Guo, S. S. Mao, Chem. Rev. 2010, 110, 6503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, H. Suzuki, J. Xie, O. Tomita, D. J. Martin, M. Higashi, D. Kong, R. Abe, J. Tang, Chem. Rev. 2018, 118, 5201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, S. Fang, H. Sun, R.&#x2010;J. Chung, X. Fang, J.&#x2010;H. He, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2203019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. K. Lee, D. Lee, M. A. Lumley, K.&#x2010;S. Choi, Chem. Soc. Rev. 2019, 48, 2126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Chen, T. Takata, K. Domen, Nat. Rev. Mater. 2017, 2, 17050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Nishiyama, T. Yamada, M. Nakabayashi, Y. Maehara, M. Yamaguchi, Y. Kuromiya, Y. Nagatsuma, H. Tokudome, S. Akiyama, T. Watanabe, R. Narushima, S. Okunaka, N. Shibata, T. Takata, T. Hisatomi, K. Domen, Nature 2021, 598, 304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Wang, T. Hisatomi, Q. Jia, H. Tokudome, M. Zhong, C. Wang, Z. Pan, T. Takata, M. Nakabayashi, N. Shibata, Y. Li, I. D. Sharp, A. Kudo, T. Yamada, K. Domen, Nat. Mater. 2016, 15, 611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Zhao, Y. Wang, C.&#x2010;L. Dong, Y.&#x2010;C. Huang, J. Chen, F. Xue, S. Shen, L. Guo, Nat. Energy 2021, 6, 388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Maeda, K. Domen, J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2010, 1, 2655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Zhao, Y. Yang, V. Binas, S. Shen, Fundam. Res. 2024, 5, 2204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Takata, J. Jiang, Y. Sakata, M. Nakabayashi, N. Shibata, V. Nandal, K. Seki, T. Hisatomi, K. Domen, Nature 2020, 581, 411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. A. Nasir, A. Munir, N. Ahmad, T. u. Haq, Z. Khan, Z. Rehman, Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2105195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Sasaki, A. Iwase, H. Kato, A. Kudo, J. Catal. 2008, 259, 133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kato, M. Hori, R. Konta, Y. Shimodaira, A. Kudo, Chem. Lett. 2004, 33, 1348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Sasaki, H. Nemoto, K. Saito, A. Kudo, J. Phys. Chem. C 2009, 113, 17536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, G. Liu, Z.&#x2010;G. Chen, F. Li, L. Wang, G. Q. Lu, H.&#x2010;M. Cheng, Chem. Commun. 2009, 3452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Zhao, X. Guan, S. Shen, Environ. Chem. Lett. 2022, 20, 3505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Jia, A. Iwase, A. Kudo, Chem. Sci. 2014, 5, 1513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Wang, X. Zheng, L. Chen, Y. Xiong, H. Xu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2018, 57, 3454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Melo Jr., Z. Wu, B. A. Nail, A. T. De Denko, A. F. Nogueira, F. E. Osterloh, Nano Lett. 2018, 18, 805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, Y. Luo, T. Hisatomi, J. J. M. Vequizo, S. Suzuki, S. Chen, M. Nakabayashi, L. Lin, Z. Pan, N. Kariya, A. Yamakata, N. Shibata, T. Takata, K. Teshima, K. Domen, Nat. Commun. 2021, 12, 1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, Y. Li, X. Xin, Y. Wang, P. Guo, R. Wang, B. Wang, W. Huang, A. J. Sobrido, X. Li, Nat. Energy 2023, 8, 504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Jiang, Z. Wang, G. Wei, S. Wu, L. Huang, D. Li, X. Ruan, Y. Liu, C. Jiang, F. Ren, ACS Energy Lett. 2024, 9, 1915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B.&#x2010;J. Ng, L. K. Putri, X. Y. Kong, Y. W. Teh, P. Pasbakhsh, S.&#x2010;P. Chai, Adv. Sci. 2020, 7, 1903171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Maeda, ACS Catal. 2013, 3, 1486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Chen, C. Li, K. Domen, F. Zhang, Joule 2023, 7, 2445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wei, Z. Zhang, W. Wang, Z. Song, M. Cai, S. Sun, ChemPhysChem 2023, 24, 202300216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Low, C. Jiang, B. Cheng, S. Wageh, A. A. Al&#x2010;Ghamdi, J. Yu, Small Methods 2017, 1, 1700080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Zhou, J. Yu, M. Jaroniec, Adv. Mater. 2014, 26, 4920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, Chin. J. Catal. 2025, 68, 213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zhang, J. T. Yates Jr., Chem. Rev. 2012, 112, 5520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, B. Mei, J. Chen, J. Catal. 2022, 408, 270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, L. Zhang, Z. Lam, H. B. Tao, Z. Zeng, H. B. Yang, J. Luo, L. Ma, B. Li, J. Zheng, S. Jia, Z. Wang, Z. Zhu, B. Liu, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2016, 138, 3183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Hill, J. Kim, N. Bodappa, A. J. Bard, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2017, 139, 6114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. S. Ahn, A. J. Bard, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2015, 54, 13753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Liu, X. Zhao, J. Yu, I. P. Parkin, A. Fujishima, K. Nakata, J. Photochem. Photobiol. C Photochem. Rev. 2019, 39, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhang, B. Zhu, L. Zhang, J. Yu, Chem. Commun. 2023, 59, 688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Othonos, J. Appl. Phys. 1998, 83, 1789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Schneider, M. Matsuoka, M. Takeuchi, J. Zhang, Y. Horiuchi, M. Anpo, D. W. Bahnemann, Chem. Rev. 2014, 114, 9919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Friedmann, C. Mendive, D. Bahnemann, Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2010, 99, 398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Karmakar, M. Durairaj, R. Madhu, A. De, H. N. Dhandapani, M. J. S. Spencer, S. Kundu, ACS Mater. Lett. 2024, 6, 3050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Li, Z. Xie, J. Liu, J. Ni, M. Deng, Y. Tu, S. Jiang, J. Liu, G. Chen, L. Li, Z. Wei, J. Phys. Chem. C 2025, 129, 3031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. K. N&#xf8;rskov, T. Bligaard, A. Logadottir, J. R. Kitchin, J. G. Chen, S. Pandelov, U. Stimming, J. Electrochem. Soc. 2005, 152, J23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Hinnemann, P. G. Moses, J. Bonde, K. P. J&#xf8;rgensen, J. H. Nielsen, S. Horch, I. Chorkendorff, J. K. N&#xf8;rskov, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2005, 127, 5308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Xiong, B. Wang, H. Cai, H. Hao, J. Li, T. Yang, S. Yang, Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2021, 295, 120283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Liu, M. Liu, R. Nakamura, Y. Tachibana, Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2021, 296, 120226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Hu, Y. Hu, B. Zhang, H. Zhang, X. Bao, J. Zhang, P. Yuan, Electrochem. Energy Rev. 2024, 7, 19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. C. Man, H.&#x2010;Y. Su, F. Calle&#x2010;Vallejo, H. A. Hansen, J. I. Mart&#xed;nez, N. G. Inoglu, J. Kitchin, T. F. Jaramillo, J. K. N&#xf8;rskov, J. Rossmeisl, ChemCatChem 2011, 3, 1159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. C. L. McCrory, S. Jung, I. M. Ferrer, S. M. Chatman, J. C. Peters, T. F. Jaramillo, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2015, 137, 4347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Zhang, S. Yu, Y. Dai, X. Huang, L. Chou, G. Lu, G. Dong, Y. Bi, Nat. Commun. 2021, 12, 6969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. W. Kim, K.&#x2010;S. Choi, Science 2014, 343, 990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Zuo, Y. Wang, W. L. Teo, Q. Xian, Y. Zhao, Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2021, 291, 120126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Wei, Y. Ding, Z. Li, Int. J. Hydrog. Energy 2020, 45, 17320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, Z. Cao, Y. Zhang, H. Xu, S. Cao, R. Zhang, Chem. Eng. J. 2020, 385, 123782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Ma, X. Jiang, R. Sun, J. Yang, X. Jiang, Z. Liu, M. Xie, E. Xie, W. Han, Chem. Eng. J. 2020, 382, 123020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhu, J. Ren, G. Huang, C.&#x2010;L. Dong, Y.&#x2010;C. Huang, P. Lu, H. Tang, Y. Liu, S. Shen, D. Yang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2311623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, L. Xu, T. Wang, R. Li, Y. Zhang, J. Zhang, T. Peng, Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 11, 2003575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Xu, L. Meng, J. Zhang, S. Yang, C. Sun, H. Li, J. Li, Y. Zhu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202308597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Liu, R. Shi, Z. Wang, Y. Weng, C.&#x2010;M. Che, Y. Chen, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2019, 58, 11791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Shi, F. Liu, Z. Wang, Y. Weng, Y. Chen, Chem. Commun. 2019, 55, 12531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Zhu, Z. Sun, M. Fujitsuka, T. Majima, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2018, 57, 2160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Chu, S. Liu, B.&#x2010;B. Luan, Y. Zhang, Y. Xi, L.&#x2010;H. Shao, F.&#x2010;M. Zhang, Y.&#x2010;Q. Lan, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 64, 202422940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Sun, R. Gao, X. Liu, L. Pan, C. Shi, Z. Jiang, X. Zhang, J.&#x2010;J. Zou, Sci. Bull. 2022, 67, 389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Bai, W. Jiang, Z. Li, Y. Xiong, ChemNanoMat 2015, 1, 223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Li, T. Takata, B. Zhang, C. Feng, Q. Wu, C. Cui, Z. Zhang, K. Domen, Y. Li, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, 202313537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, X. Wu, Z.&#x2010;H. Wang, Y. Peng, Y. Liu, S. Yang, C. Sun, X. Xu, X. Zhang, J. Kang, S.&#x2010;H. Wei, P. F. Liu, S. Dai, H. G. Yang, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2024, 146, 6618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Lin, Y. Wang, Z. Peng, Y.&#x2010;C. Huang, F. Meng, J.&#x2010;L. Chen, C.&#x2010;L. Dong, Q. Zhang, R. Wang, D. Zhao, J. Chen, L. Gu, S. Shen, Adv. Energy Mater. 2022, 12, 2200716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Zhang, T. Tachikawa, M. Fujitsuka, T. Majima, J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2016, 7, 1173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Zhumabay, J. A. Bau, R. Ahmad, L. Braic, H. Zhang, L. Cavallo, M. Rueping, Small Struct. 2025, 6, 2400283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Wang, S. Shen, L. Guo, ChemCatChem 2016, 8, 798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Qi, J. Zhang, Y. Kong, Y. Zhao, S. Chen, D. Li, W. Liu, Y. Chen, T. Xie, J. Cui, C. Li, K. Domen, F. Zhang, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhu, L. Ding, R. Sun, J. Li, W. Li, R. Xu, L. Xiang, F. Fang, K. Chang, J. Catal. 2025, 448, 116160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhang, H. Wang, T. Wu, W. Chang, Y. Li, J. Wang, Y. Yang, L. Wang, Chem. Eng. J. 2025, 507, 160059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Liu, G. Zhang, X. Liang, Z. Pan, D. Zheng, S. Wang, Z. Yu, Y. Hou, X. Wang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, 202304694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Dionigi, P. C. K. Vesborg, T. Pedersen, O. Hansen, S. Dahl, A. Xiong, K. Maeda, K. Domen, I. Chorkendorff, J. Catal. 2012, 292, 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Tao, Y. Zhao, S. Wang, C. Li, R. Li, Chem. Soc. Rev. 2022, 51, 3561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Maeda, K. Teramura, D. Lu, N. Saito, Y. Inoue, K. Domen, J. Phys. Chem. C 2007, 111, 7554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Higashi, K. Seki, Y. Sasaki, Y. Pihosh, V. Nandal, M. Nakabayashi, N. Shibata, K. Domen, Chem.&#x2010;Eur. J. 2023, 29, 202204058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Maeda, K. Domen, J. Phys. Chem. C 2007, 111, 7851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Takata, C. Pan, M. Nakabayashi, N. Shibata, K. Domen, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2015, 137, 9627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, R. Li, H. Jing, J. Xiao, H. Xie, F. Hong, N. Ta, X. Zhang, J. Zhu, C. Li, Nat. Catal. 2023, 6, 80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. She, J. Wu, H. Xu, J. Zhong, Y. Wang, Y. Song, K. Nie, Y. Liu, Y. Yang, M.&#x2010;T. F. Rodrigues, R. Vajtai, J. Lou, D. Du, H. Li, P. M. Ajayan, Adv. Energy Mater. 2017, 7, 1700025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yang, M. Qiu, L. Li, Y. Pi, G. Yan, L. Yang, Sol. RRL 2018, 2, 1800148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Sun, T. Hisatomi, Q. Wang, S. Chen, G. Ma, J. Liu, S. Nandy, T. Minegishi, M. Katayama, K. Domen, ACS Catal. 2018, 8, 1690.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Xie, Y. Zhao, H. Li, Y. Xu, X. Chen, J. Mater. Sci. 2019, 54, 10836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Ding, D. Wei, R. He, R. Yuan, T. Xie, Z. Li, Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2019, 258, 117948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Shen, L. Zhang, N. Li, Z. Lou, T. Ma, P. Zhang, Y. Li, X. Li, ACS Catal. 2022, 12, 9994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Xue, Y. Si, C. Cheng, W. Fu, X. Chen, S. Shen, L. Wang, M. Liu, Nano Energy 2022, 103, 107799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Liu, F. Xue, C. Zhang, K. Lu, G. Chen, X. Ye, W. Chen, L. Guo, M. Liu, Mater. Today Energy 2022, 30, 101180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Shen, G. Liang, L. Hao, P. Zhang, X. Li, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2303649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Zuo, S. Ma, Z. Yin, W. Chen, Y. Wang, Q. Ji, Q. Xian, S. Yang, H. He, Small 2023, 19, 2207031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Le Huec, A. L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;Franc&#xe9;s, I. Ab&#xe1;nades L&#xe1;zaro, S. Naval&#xf3;n, H. G. Baldov&#xed;, M. Gim&#xe9;nez&#x2010;Marqu&#xe9;s, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 20201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Nawaz, Y. Mu, Y. Gao, S. Jiang, X. Liu, R. Tao, Z. Chu, X. Fan, C. Xu, Int. J. Hydrog. Energy 2025, 124, 84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Shao, Y. Wang, J. Xu, R. Li, T. Peng, Energy Fuels 2025, 39, 2203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Shao, C. Luo, D. Lu, X. Li, R. Li, T. Peng, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 18399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Chen, R. Wu, J. Yue, D. Kong, C. Zhang, S. Wei, Int. J. Hydrog. Energy 2025, 126, 56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Du, J. Huang, Z. Ye, C. Zhen, J. Liu, Y. Yang, Z. Ren, L. Yin, L. Wang, G. Liu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2312888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Li, Y. Gong, Y. Wang, T. He, Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2022, 24, 19659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Liao, C. Li, S.&#x2010;Y. Liu, B. Fang, H. Yang, Phys. Rep. 2022, 983, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Kahn, Mater. Horiz 2016, 3, 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Liu, Y. Liu, N. Liu, Y. Han, X. Zhang, H. Huang, Y. Lifshitz, S.&#x2010;T. Lee, J. Zhong, Z. Kang, Science 2015, 347, 970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Lin, R. Jacobs, T. Ma, D. Chen, J. Booske, D. Morgan, Phys. Rev. Appl. 2023, 19, 037001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Maku&#x142;a, M. Pacia, W. Macyk, J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2018, 9, 6814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Low, B. Dai, T. Tong, C. Jiang, J. Yu, Adv. Mater. 2019, 31, 1802981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, X. Wang, J. Huang, S. Li, A. Meng, Z. Li, Nat. Commun. 2021, 12, 4112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Chen, F. Fan, T. Dittrich, C. Li, Chem. Soc. Rev. 2018, 47, 8238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Zhu, W.&#x2010;L. Fu, J.&#x2010;K. Qu, Z. Gao, Z.&#x2010;Y. Zhang, T. Zhang, X.&#x2010;Y. Ye, N.&#x2010;N. Ma, X.&#x2010;J. Guan, L.&#x2010;J. Guo, Rare Met. 2025, 44, 8644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Sun, M. Song, F. Liu, H. Peng, T. Zhao, S.&#x2010;F. Yin, P. Chen, Appl. Catal. B Environ. 2024, 342, 123436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Chen, C. Ni, J. Zhu, F. Fan, C. Li, Nat. Protoc. 2024, 19, 2250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Dittrich, S. Fiechter, A. Thomas, Appl. Phys. Lett. 2011, 99, 084105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Jiang, H.&#x2010;Y. Chen, J.&#x2010;Y. Li, J.&#x2010;F. Liao, H.&#x2010;H. Zhang, X.&#x2010;X. Wang, D.&#x2010;B. Kuang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020, 30, 2004293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Zhang, J. Zhang, J. Yu, H. Garc&#xed;a, Nat. Rev. Chem. 2025, 9, 328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Liao, C. Li, S.&#x2010;Y. Liu, B. Fang, H. Yang, Trends Chem 2022, 4, 111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Wang, Y. Mao, L. Li, Z. Shen, X. Luo, K. Wu, P. An, H. Wang, L. Su, Y. Li, S. Zhan, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2019, 58, 11329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yang, D. Wang, H. Han, C. Li, Acc. Chem. Res. 2013, 46, 1900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zhang, B. Zhu, X. Guan, J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2022, 13, 2356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zach&#xe4;us, F. F. Abdi, L. M. Peter, R. van de Krol, Chem. Sci. 2017, 8, 3712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Meng, Z. Lv, W. Xu, W. Tian, L. Li, Adv. Sci. 2023, 10, 2206729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Wenderich, G. Mul, Chem. Rev. 2016, 116, 14587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. He, X. Hong, Y. Wang, Z. Xing, J. Geng, P. Guo, J. Su, S. Shen, Eng. 2023, 25, 128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Li, C. Ni, J. Cui, C. Li, F. Fan, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2025, 147, 9103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Zhang, L. Zhang, Q. Zheng, P. Gao, J. Zhao, J. Yang, J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2018, 9, 5419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Liu, Y. Yao, Z. Liang, Z. Gong, J. Li, Z. Tang, X. Wei, J. Phys. Chem. C 2024, 128, 9894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Fu, K. Lu, A. Hu, J. Huang, L. Guo, J. Zhou, J. Zhao, O. V. Prezhdo, M. Liu, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2023, 145, 28166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, S. Zhang, C. He, H. Yao, C. Guo, W. Wang, Y. Hu, ACS Catal. 2025, 15, 2315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.&#x2010;M. Wu, P. Schmuki, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2414889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Tunala, S. Zhai, F. Wu, Y.&#x2010;H. Chen, Sci. China Chem. 2025, 68, 3415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Pan, Z. Jiang, Z. Zuo, F. He, F. Wang, L. Li, Q. Chang, B. Guan, Y. Li, Nano Today 2021, 39, 101213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Sato, T. Sugimoto, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2024, 146, 24800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Prajapati, C. Hahn, I. M. Weidinger, Y. Shi, Y. Lee, A. N. Alexandrova, D. Thompson, S. R. Bare, S. Chen, S. Yan, N. Kornienko, Nat. Commun. 2025, 16, 2593.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>