<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41878636</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2639-5274</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research (Washington, D.C.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Research (Wash D C)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Asymmetric Diffusion Metasurface-Based Lensless Monitoring and Uniform Illumination Systems for Optical Lithography.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1197</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1197</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1197</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.34133/research.1197</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The long-standing trade-off between illumination performance (such as uniformity) and optical system complexity has hindered the development of compact lithographic tools. Here, we overcome this limitation by introducing a metasurface-enabled lensless illumination system that seamlessly combines light homogenization and monitoring capabilities. Using an asymmetric diffusion metasurface integrated with intelligent optimization algorithms, we achieve precise light field control and self-adaptive feedback without relying on conventional lens assemblies. When deployed on a self-developed large-field lithography platform, the system demonstrates uniform ultraviolet illumination with nonuniformity below 3% and successfully exposes patterns across a range of feature sizes. A gray-level to power-level mapping algorithm enables real-time assessment of light-emitting diode performance, providing diagnostic alerts and adaptively reconfigurable exposure configurations to circumvent defective emitters. This synergy between metasurface optics and algorithmic intelligence establishes a new paradigm for compact, low-cost, and scalable lithographic illumination, offering a pathway toward next-generation intelligent manufacturing systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Guangbiao Wang et&#xa0;al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Guangbiao</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4556</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Information Technology, Sun Yat-Sen University, Guangzhou 510275, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Yanhua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronic and Information Engineering, Harbin Institute of Technology (Shenzhen), Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pi</LastName><ForeName>Yazhi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Wenchao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0040</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Laboratory of Solid State Microstructures, School of Physics, and Collaborative Innovation, Center of Advanced Microstructures, Nanjing University, Nanjing 210093, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Photoelectronic Imaging Technology and System of Ministry of Education of China, School of Optics and Photonics, Beijing Institute of Technology, Beijing 100081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Fan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Information Technology, Sun Yat-Sen University, Guangzhou 510275, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Zizheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Integrated Circuits, ZJ U-Hangzhou Global Scientific and Technological Innovation Center, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Institute for Advanced Study, Zhejiang University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Shaohua</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0193</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peng Cheng Laboratory, Shenzhen 518055, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Research (Wash D C)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101747148</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2639-5274</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41878636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13006733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/research.1197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Liu K, Gao Y, Wang C, Cao L. Advancements and challenges in inverse lithography technology: A review of artificial intelligence-based approaches. Light Sci Appl. 2025;14(1):250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12287475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40701983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Li Y, Wang Y, Chen H, Ozcan A. Optical generative models. Nature. 2025;644(8078):903&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12390839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40866675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X-K, Ma JX, Li XY, Hu JJ, Ding CY, Han FK, Guo XM, Tan X, Jin XM. High-efficiency reinforcement learning with hybrid architecture photonic integrated circuit. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10844654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38316815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Xu K, Yuan D, Hu J, Wang X, Xu S. Sub-wavelength patterned pulse laser lithography for efficient fabrication of large-area metasurfaces. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):5823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9530239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36192549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell M, Sharp D, Harrison M, Denning R, Turberfield A. Fabrication of photonic crystals for the visible spectrum by holographic lithography. Nature. 2000;404(6773):53&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10716437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weichelt T, Bourgin Y, Zeitner U. Mask aligner lithography using laser illumination for versatile pattern generation. Opt Express. 2017;25(18):20983&#x2013;20992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29041508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelkel R. Micro-optics: Enabling technology for illumination shaping in optical lithography. Optical Microlithography XXVII. 2014;9052:530&#x2013;540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levinson HJ. <i>Principles of lithography</i>. Bellingham (USA): SPIE Press; Fourth Edition. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuerzebecher L, Fuchs F, Zeitner UD, Tuennermann A. High-resolution proximity lithography for nano-optical components. Microelectron Eng. 2015;132:120&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DG. Illumination in microlithography. In: <i>International Optical Design Conference 2014</i>. SPIE; 2014. Vol. 9293, p. 397&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelkel R, Vogler U, Bramati A. Advanced mask aligner lithography (AMALITH). Optical Microlithography XXVIII. 2015;9426:422&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelkel R, Vogler U, Bich A, Pernet P, Weible KJ, Hornung M, Zoberbier R, Cullmann E, Stuerzebecher L, Harzendorf T, et al. Advanced mask aligner lithography: New illumination system. Opt Express. 2010;18(20):20968&#x2013;20978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20940992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Nan Y, Li T, Zhang Z, Li Y. Allocation method of micromirror array for deep ultraviolet illumination system. In: <i>Eighth International Workshop on Advanced Patterning Solutions (IWAPS 2024)</i>. SPIE; 2024. Vol. 13423, p. 169&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hase T. Illumination system and exposure apparatus. US Patent 7,236,239. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kita N. Optical integrator, illumination optical device, photolithograph, photolithography, and method for fabricating device. US Patent 11/793,448. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelkel R, Vogler U, Bramati A, Weichelt T, Stuerzebecher L, Zeitner U, Motzek K, Erdmann A, Hornung M, Zoberbier R. Advanced mask aligner lithography (AMALITH). Optical Microlithography XXV (SPIE). 2012;8326:677&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Mizutani. Illumination optical apparatus and device manufacturing method. US Patent 10,133,185. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuyama T, Ohmura Y, Williamson DM. The lithographic lens: Its history and evolution. Optical Microlithography XIX (SPIE). 2006;6154:24&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland JP, Davies MA, Suleski TJ, Evans C, Bauer A, Lambropoulos JC, Falaggis K. Freeform optics for imaging. Optica. 2021;8(2):161&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu R, Feng Z, Zheng Z, Liang R, Ben&#xed;tez P, Mi&#xf1;ano JC, Duerr F. Design of freeform illumination optics. Laser Photonics Rev. 2018;12(7):1700310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerpentier J, Meuret Y. Freeform surface topology prediction for prescribed illumination via semi-supervised learning. Opt Express. 2024;32(4):6350&#x2013;6365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38439340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou D, He Z, Chen M, Yan L, Guo Y, Gao G, Li C, Piao Y, Cheng X, Chan PKL. Dry lithography patterning of monolayer flexible field effect transistors by 2D mica stamping. Adv Mater. 2023;35(20):2211600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36841244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N, Wang Q, Shen C, Wei Z, Yu H, Zhao J, Lu X, Wang G, He C, Xie L, et al. Large-scale flexible and transparent electronics based on monolayer molybdenum disulfide field-effect transistors. Nat Electron. 2020;3(11):711&#x2013;717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Wang S, Wu Z-S. Photolithographic microfabrication of microbatteries for on-chip energy storage. Nano-Micro Lett. 2025;17(1):105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11711423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39775337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D, Oh B, Park J, Moon SW, Shin K, Kim SM, Rho J. Wide field-of-hearing metalens for aberration-free sound capture. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):3044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11001966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38589347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Huang S-X, Chan KF, Wu G-B, Chan CH. 3D-printed aberration-free terahertz metalens for ultra-broadband achromatic super-resolution wide-angle imaging with high numerical aperture. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11699036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39753564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim I, Jang J, Kim G, Lee J, Badloe T, Mun J, Rho J. Pixelated bifunctional metasurface-driven dynamic vectorial holographic color prints for photonic security platform. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):3614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8203667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34127669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Q, Liu X, Qiu C-W, Genevet P. Vectorial metasurface holography. Appl Phys Rev. 2022;9(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Li H, Zhao W, Huang PS, Lin YT, Yao J, Li W, Zhao Q, Wu PC, Li B, et al. High-security learning-based optical encryption assisted by disordered metasurface. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):2607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10960874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38521827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Ji X, Li X, Zhang S, Wang H, Li J, Li X, Wang Y, Huang L. Spatial varying vectorial holography and polarization encryption based on birefringent metasurface. Adv Funct Mater. 2024;34(41):2404196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colburn S, Zhan A, Majumdar A. Metasurface optics for full-color computational imaging. Sci Adv. 2018;4(2): Article eaar2114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5817919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29487913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Muhammad N, Zhao R, Chen Y, Geng G, Li J, Li X, Li X, Wang Y, Huang L. Metasurface enabled broadband, high numerical aperture Laplace differentiator under multiple polarization illumination. PhotoniX. 2025;6(1):10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Pietila J, Singh HJ, Caglayan H. Phase-shifting structured illumination with a polarization-encoded metasurface. Nano Lett. 2025;25(30):11696&#x2013;11702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12314901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40674606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Fan X, Liu Y, Xu K, Zhou Y, Zhang Z, Chen F, Yu X, Deng L, Gao H, et al. 3D nanolithography via holographic multi-focus metalens. Laser Photonics Rev. 2024;18(11):2400181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi E, Kim G, Yun J, Jeon Y, Rho J, Baek SH. 360&#xb0; structured light with learned metasurfaces. Nat Photonics. 2024;18(8):848&#x2013;855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S-H, Su HP, Chen CY, Lin YC, Yang Z, Shi Y, Song Q, Wu PC. Microcavity-assisted multi-resonant metasurfaces enabling versatile wavefront engineering. Nat Commun. 2024;15(1):9658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11543841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39511215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Zhu W, Huo P, Feng L, Song M, Zhang C, Chen L, Lezec HJ, Lu Y, Agrawal A, et al. Multifunctional metasurfaces enabled by simultaneous and independent control of phase and amplitude for orthogonal polarization states. Light Sci Appl. 2021;10(1):107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8149653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34035215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solntsev AS, Agarwal GS, Kivshar YS. Metasurfaces for quantum photonics. Nat Photonics. 2021;15(5):327&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z, Liang C, Chen C, Wang X, Zhou E, Bian X, Yang Y, You R, Zhao X, Zhao J, et al. High-efficiency dynamic terahertz deflector utilizing a mechanically tunable metasurface. Research. 2023;6:0274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10907017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38434248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia C, Lu Z, Zhang Y, Tan J. Broadband high optical transparent intelligent metasurface for adaptive electromagnetic wave manipulation. Research. 2024;7:0334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10927547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38476476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun YL, Zhang XG, Huang Z, Tian HW, Cui TJ, Jiang WX. Intelligent transmissive microwave metasurface with optical sensing and transparency. Research. 2024;7:0514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11491669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39434839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu H, Xiong X, Fang NX, Wu F, Jia R, Peng R, Wang M, Lai Y. Matte surfaces with broadband transparency enabled by highly asymmetric diffusion of white light. Sci Adv. 2024;10(11): Article eadm8061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10942103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38489370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua AL-S, Benedek NA, Chen L, Finnis MW, Sutton AP. A genetic algorithm for predicting the structures of interfaces in multicomponent systems. Nat Mater. 2010;9(5):418&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20190770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salley D, Keenan G, Grizou J, Sharma A, Mart&#xed;n S, Cronin L. A nanomaterials discovery robot for the Darwinian evolution of shape programmable gold nanoparticles. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):2771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7265452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32488034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong S, Yang B, Huang H. Illumination uniformity correction by using dynamic gray filters in a lithography system. Appl Opt. 2022;61(10):2706&#x2013;2714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35471341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin D-Z, Lee C-M, Zhang Z-J, Yu P-H, Jeng J-Y. Development of a quasi-collimated UV LED backlight for producing uniform and smooth 3D printing objects. Opt Express. 2022;30(9):14759&#x2013;14769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35473213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murakami S, Saito M, Yoshida O. Optimization of resolution by FDTD analysis in aligner lithography. Precis Eng. 2016;44:171&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelkel R, Vogler U, Bramati A, Hennemeyer M, Zoberbier R, Voigt A, Gr&#xfc;tzner G, &#xdc;nal N, Hofmann U. Advanced mask aligner lithography (AMALITH) for thick photoresist. Microsyst Technol. 2014;20(10):1839&#x2013;1842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernasconi J, Scharf T, Vogler U, Herzig HP. High-power modular LED-based illumination systems for mask-aligner lithography. Opt Express. 2018;26(9):11503&#x2013;11512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29716068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Partel S, Zoppel S, Hudek P, Bich A, Vogler U, Hornung M, Voelkel R. Contact and proximity lithography using 193 nm excimer laser in mask aligner. Microelectron Eng. 2010;87(5&#x2013;8):936&#x2013;939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C, Xu W, Liu B, Wang H, Sun Q, Shi C, Wang T, Zhang H, Weng Z, Xu J. Method for improving illumination uniformity of a digital mask-less scanning lithography system. Opt Laser Technol. 2025;185: Article 112595.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>