<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41479236</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1542-0086</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>125</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biophysical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biophys J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanosensitivity of the talin molecular clutch.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>913</StartPage><EndPage>927</EndPage><MedlinePgn>913-927</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bpj.2025.12.036</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0006-3495(25)03532-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cells sense substrate mechanical properties through the integrin-talin-F-actin linkage. Talin's N-terminal head domain binds &#x3b2;-integrin, whereas its C-terminal domain connects to F-actin directly via two actin-binding sites (ABSs) and indirectly through cryptic vinculin-binding sites (VBSs) within rod domain bundles. Force-induced unfolding of these &#x3b1;-helical bundles exposes VBSs, recruiting vinculin to strengthen the talin-actin bond. This system is sensitive to the loading rate and is influenced by rates of F-actin movement and substrate stiffness. Although the components of this pathway are well studied, how talin, vinculin, and actin synergize to mechanically buffer loads and mediate cellular stiffness sensing remains incompletely understood. We developed a multiscale stochastic finite element model to simulate talin unfolding during interactions with retrograde actin flows and analyzed the contributions of ABS2, ABS3, and VBSs to talin mechanosensitivity. Vinculin attachments strengthened the force-bearing capacity in talin, stabilized the actin-talin contact, and regulated binding site activity at RD3. Lifetime of the dynamic bond formed between talin and actin decreased with an increase in actin flow velocity. Higher substrate stiffness enhanced the lifetime at low actin flow velocity but negatively impacted it at higher velocities. ABS3 primarily mediated force transfer from actin to talin at rapid actin flows, whereas vinculin and ABS2 reinforced the F-actin bond under slower flows. Stiffer substrates enhanced force transmission through VBSs. Our results show that stretch rate modulates force feedback between the unfolding of talin rod domains and VBS attachments, driving the sensitivity of talin to substrate stiffness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Biophysical Society. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaddivada</LastName><ForeName>Siddhartha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Driscoll</LastName><ForeName>Tristan</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Biomedical Engineering, FAMU-FSU College of Engineering, Tallahassee, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwartz</LastName><ForeName>Martin A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale Cardiovascular Research Center, Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gundiah</LastName><ForeName>Namrata</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India. Electronic address: namrata@iisc.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL171773</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R35 GM155264</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biophys J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370626</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0006-3495</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016608">Talin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>125361-02-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016596">Vinculin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000199">Actins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016608" MajorTopicYN="Y">Talin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016596" MajorTopicYN="N">Vinculin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000199" MajorTopicYN="N">Actins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001665" MajorTopicYN="N">Binding Sites</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055595" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011485" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Binding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008958" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Molecular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058767" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Unfolding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040542" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mechanotransduction, Cellular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41479236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2142077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12885044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpj.2025.12.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0006-3495(25)03532-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bershadsky AD, Tint IS, Neyfakh AA Jr, and Vasiliev JM. 1985. Focal contacts of normal and RSV-transformed quail cells. Hypothesis of the transformation-induced deficient maturation of focal contacts. Exp Cell Res. 158:433&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2988988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamir E, Katz BZ, Aota S, Yamada KM, Geiger B, and Kam Z. 1999. Molecular diversity of cell-matrix adhesions. J Cell Sci. 112 (Pt 11):1655&#x2013;1669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10318759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riveline D, Zamir E, Balaban NQ, Schwarz US, Ishizaki T, Narumiya S, Kam Z, Geiger B, and Bershadsky AD. 2001. Focal contacts as mechanosensors: externally applied local mechanical force induces growth of focal contacts by an mDia1-dependent and ROCK-independent mechanism. J Cell Biol. 153:1175&#x2013;1186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11402062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponti A, Machacek M, Gupton SL, Waterman-Storer CM, and Danuser G. 2004. Two distinct actin networks drive the protrusion of migrating cells. Science. 305:1782&#x2013;1786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15375270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hynes RO 2002. Integrins: bidirectional, allosteric signaling machines. Cell. 110:673&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12297042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz MA, Schaller MD, and Ginsberg MH. 1995. Integrins: emerging paradigms of signal transduction. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 11:549&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8689569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brakebusch C, and F&#xe4;ssler R. 2003. The integrin-actin connection, an eternal love affair. EMBO J. 22:2324&#x2013;2333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12743027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bershadsky A, Chausovsky A, Becker E, Lyubimova A, and Geiger B. 1996. Involvement of microtubules in the control of adhesion-dependent signal transduction. Curr Biol. 6:1279&#x2013;1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8939572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driscoll TP, Ahn SJ, Huang B, Kumar A, and Schwartz MA. 2020. Actin flow-dependent and -independent force transmission through integrins. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 117:32413&#x2013;32422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7768777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33262280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderwood DA, Yan B, de Pereda JM, Alvarez BG, Fujioka Y, Liddington RC, and Ginsberg MH. 2002. The phosphotyrosine binding-like domain of talin activates integrins. J Biol Chem. 277:21749&#x2013;21758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goult BT, Brown NH, and Schwartz MA. 2021. Talin in mechanotransduction and mechanomemory at a glance. J Cell Sci. 134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8697387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34708856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Critchley DR 2009. Biochemical and structural properties of the integrin-associated cytoskeletal protein talin. Annu Rev Biophys. 38:235&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19416068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanchanawong P, Shtengel G, Pasapera AM, Ramko EB, Davidson MW, Hess HF, and Waterman CM. 2010. Nanoscale architecture of integrin-based cell adhesions. Nature. 468:580&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21107430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Wang Y, Goh WI, Goh H, Baird MA, Ruehland S, Teo S, Bate N, Critchley DR, Davidson MW, and Kanchanawong P. 2015. Talin determines the nanoscale architecture of focal adhesions. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 112:E4864&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4568271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26283369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>del Rio A, Perez-Jimenez R, Liu R, Roca-Cusachs P, Fernandez JM, and Sheetz MP. 2009. Stretching single talin rod molecules activates vinculin binding. Science. 323:638&#x2013;641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9339221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19179532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case LB, and Waterman CM. 2015. Integration of actin dynamics and cell adhesion by a three-dimensional, mechanosensitive molecular clutch. Nat Cell Biol. 17:955&#x2013;963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6300998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klapholz B, and Brown NH. 2017. Talin - the master of integrin adhesions. J Cell Sci. 130:2435&#x2013;2446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28701514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M, Goult BT, Klapholz B, Hu X, Toseland CP, Guo Y, Cong P, Sheetz MP, and Yan J. 2016. The mechanical response of talin. Nat Commun. 7:11966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4941051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27384267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan CE, and Odde DJ. 2008. Traction dynamics of filopodia on compliant substrates. Science. 322:1687&#x2013;1691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19074349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangasser BL, Rosenfeld SS, and Odde DJ. 2013. Determinants of maximal force transmission in a motor-clutch model of cell traction in a compliant microenvironment. Biophys J. 105:581&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3736748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23931306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elosegui-Artola A, Oria R, Chen Y, Kosmalska A, P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez C, Castro N, Zhu C, Trepat X, and Roca-Cusachs P. 2016. Mechanical regulation of a molecular clutch defines force transmission and transduction in response to matrix rigidity. Nature Cell Biology. 18:540&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27065098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaro RJ, Lin K &amp; Zhu Q, Mechanosensitivity occurs along the adhesome&#x2019;s force train and affects traction stress. Biophys J. 117, 1599&#x2013;1614 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31604520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaddivada S, Mechanobiology of cell-substrate interactions, Doctoral dissertation, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azizi L, Cowell AR, Mykuliak VV, Goult BT, Turkki P, and Hyt&#xf6;nen VP. 2021. Cancer associated talin point mutations disorganise cell adhesion and migration. Sci Rep. 11:347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33431906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang G, Giannone G, Critchley DR, Fukumoto E, and Sheetz MP. 2003. Two-piconewton slip bond between fibronectin and the cytoskeleton depends on talin. Nature. 424:334&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12867986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldmann WH, Guttenberg Z, Kaufmann S, Hess D, Ezzell RM, and Isenberg G. 1997. Examining F-actin interaction with intact talin and talin head and tail fragment using static and dynamic light scattering. Eur J Biochem. 250:447&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9428697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia-Rojo R, Alonso-Caballero A, and Fernandez JM. 2020. Direct observation of a coil-to-helix contraction triggered by vinculin binding to talin. Sci Adv. 6:eaaz4707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7244311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32494739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Wang Q, Dai X, Pei L, Wang J, Zhao W, Johnson HE, Yao M, and Efremov AK. 2025. Elastic properties of force-transmitting linkages determine multistable mechanosensitive behaviour of cell adhesion. Nature Physics. 21:1431&#x2013;1443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang DL, Bax NA, Buckley CD, Weis WI, and Dunn AR. 2017. Vinculin forms a directionally asymmetric catch bond with F-actin. Science. 357:703&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5821505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28818948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell GI 1978. Models for the specific adhesion of cells to cells. Science. 200:618&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">347575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillespie DT 1977. Exact stochastic simulation of coupled chemical reactions. J. Phys. Chem 81:2340&#x2013;2361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M, Goult BT, Chen H, Cong P, Sheetz MP, and Yan J. 2014. Mechanical activation of vinculin binding to talin locks talin in an unfolded conformation. Scientific Reports. 4:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3980218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24714394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringer P, Wei&#xdf; A, Cost A-L, Freikamp A, Sabass B, Mehlich A, Tramier M, Rief M, and Grashoff C. 2017. Multiplexing molecular tension sensors reveals piconewton force gradient across talin-1. Nature Methods. 14:1090&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28945706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan SJ, Chang AC, Anderson SM, Miller CM, Prahl LS, Odde DJ, and Dunn AR. 2020. Regulation and dynamics of force transmission at individual cell-matrix adhesion bonds. Science advances. 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32440534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goult BT, Zacharchenko T, Bate N, Tsang R, Hey F, Gingras AR, Elliott PR, Roberts GCK, Ballestrem C, Critchley DR, and Barsukov IL. 2013. RIAM and vinculin binding to talin are mutually exclusive and regulate adhesion assembly and turnover. The Journal of biological chemistry. 288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23389036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardel ML, Sabass B, Ji L, Danuser G, Schwarz US, and Waterman CM. 2008. Traction stress in focal adhesions correlates biphasically with actin retrograde flow speed. The Journal of cell biology. 183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2600750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19075110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexandrova AY, Arnold K, Schaub S, Vasiliev JM, Meister JJ, Bershadsky AD, and Verkhovsky AB. 2008. Comparative dynamics of retrograde actin flow and focal adhesions: formation of nascent adhesions triggers transition from fast to slow flow. PloS one. 3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2535565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18800171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Cohen DM, Choudhury DM, Kioka N, and Craig SW. 2005. Spatial distribution and functional significance of activated vinculin in living cells. J Cell Biol. 169:459&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2171941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaCroix AS, Lynch AD, Berginski ME, and Hoffman BD. 2018. Tunable molecular tension sensors reveal extension-based control of vinculin loading. Elife. 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6053308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30024378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton P, Stutchbury B, Wang D-Y, Jethwa D, Tsang R, Meiler-Rodriguez E, Wang P, Bate N, Zent R, Barsukov IL, Goult BT, Critchley DR, and Ballestrem C. 2015. Vinculin controls talin engagement with the actomyosin machinery. Nat Commun. 6:10038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4686655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26634421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahikainen R, &#xd6;hman T, Turkki P, Varjosalo M, and Hyt&#xf6;nen VP. 2019. Talin-mediated force transmission and talin rod domain unfolding independently regulate adhesion signaling. J Cell Sci. 132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans E, and Ritchie K. 1999. Strength of a weak bond connecting flexible polymer chains. Biophys J. 76:2439&#x2013;2447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1300216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10233061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrion-Vazquez M, Oberhauser AF, Fowler SB, Marszalek PE, Broedel SE, Clarke J, and Fernandez JM. 1999. Mechanical and chemical unfolding of a single protein: A comparison. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 96:3694&#x2013;3699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC22356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10097099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe1;konard&#xf3;ttir GK, L&#xf3;pez-Ceballos P, Herrera-Reyes AD, Das R, Coombs D, and Tanentzapf G. 2015. In vivo quantitative analysis of Talin turnover in response to force. Mol Biol Cell. 26:4149&#x2013;4162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4710244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26446844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Ouyang M, Van den Dries K, McGhee EJ, Tanaka K, Anderson MD, Groisman A, Goult BT, Anderson KI, and Schwartz MA. 2016. Talin tension sensor reveals novel features of focal adhesion force transmission and mechanosensitivity. J Cell Biol. 213:371&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4862330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27161398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austen K, Ringer P, Mehlich A, Chrostek-Grashoff A, Kluger C, Klingner C, Sabass B, Zent R, Rief M, and Grashoff C. 2015. Extracellular rigidity sensing by talin isoform-specific mechanical linkages. Nat Cell Biol. 17:1597&#x2013;1606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4662888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26523364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omachi T, Ichikawa T, Kimura Y, Ueda K, and Kioka N. 2017. Vinculin association with actin cytoskeleton is necessary for stiffness-dependent regulation of vinculin behavior. PLoS One. 12:e0175324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5384775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28388663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahikainen R, von Essen M, Schaefer M, Qi L, Azizi L, Kelly C, Ihalainen TO, Wehrle-Haller B, Bastmeyer M, Huang C, and Hyt&#xf6;nen VP. 2017. Mechanical stability of talin rod controls cell migration and substrate sensing. Sci Rep. 7:3571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5472591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28620171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderwood DA, Campbell ID, and Critchley DR. 2013. Talins and kindlins: partners in integrin-mediated adhesion. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 14:503&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4116690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23860236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirata H, Tatsumi H, Lim CT, and Sokabe M. 2014. Force-dependent vinculin binding to talin in live cells: a crucial step in anchoring the actin cytoskeleton to focal adhesions. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 306:C607&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24452377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thievessen I, Thompson PM, Berlemont S, Plevock KM, Plotnikov SV, Zemljic-Harpf A, Ross RS, Davidson MW, Danuser G, Campbell SL, and Waterman CM. 2013. Vinculin-actin interaction couples actin retrograde flow to focal adhesions, but is dispensable for focal adhesion growth. J Cell Biol. 202:163&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23836933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangasser BL, Shamsan GA, Chan CE, Opoku KN, T&#xfc;zel E, Schlichtmann BW, Kasim JA, Fuller BJ, McCullough BR, Rosenfeld SS, and Odde DJ. 2017. Shifting the optimal stiffness for cell migration. Nature Communications. 8:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5458120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28530245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golji J, and Mofrad MRK. 2014. The talin dimer structure orientation is mechanically regulated. Biophys J. 107:1802&#x2013;1809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25418161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen LM, Bax NA, Weis WI, and Dunn AR. 2022. The C-terminal actin-binding domain of talin forms an asymmetric catch bond with F-actin. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 119:e2109329119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8915792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35245171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura R, Barnett SFH, Jain K, Huang Z, Goult BT, and Kanchanawong P. 2025. Optogenetic control of mechanotransduction based on light-induced homodimerization of talin. bioRxiv.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41277405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava J, Barreiro G, Groscurth S, Gingras AR, Goult BT, Critchley DR, Kelly MJS, Jacobson MP, and Barber DL. 2008. Structural model and functional significance of pH-dependent talin-actin binding for focal adhesion remodeling. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 105:14436&#x2013;14441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2532973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18780792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grashoff C, Hoffman BD, Brenner MD, Zhou R, Parsons M, Yang MT, McLean MA, Sligar SG, Chen CS, Ha T, and Schwartz MA. 2010. Measuring mechanical tension across vinculin reveals regulation of focal adhesion dynamics. Nature. 466:263&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2901888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20613844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;avdar &#xd6;, Bayraktar A, Adanur S, and Ba&#x15f;a&#x1e7;a HB. 2010. Stochastic finite element analysis of long-span bridges with CFRP cables under earthquake ground motion. Sadhana. 35:341&#x2013;354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baudrimont A, Jaquet V, Wallerich S, Voegeli S, and Becskei A. 2019. Contribution of RNA Degradation to Intrinsic and Extrinsic Noise in Gene Expression. Cell Rep. 26:3752&#x2013;3761.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30917326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yao M, Baker KB, Gough RE, Le S, Goult BT, Yan J. Force-Dependent Interactions between Talin and Full-Length Vinculin. J Am Chem Soc. 2021. Sep 15;143(36):14726&#x2013;14737. doi: 10.1021/jacs.1c06223. Epub 2021 Aug 31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.1c06223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34463480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghibaudo M, Saez A, Trichet L, Xayaphoummine A, Browaeys J, Silberzan P,Buguin A, &amp; Ladoux B (2008). Traction forces and rigidity sensing regulate cell functions. Soft Matter, 4(9), 1836&#x2013;1843.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>