<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41870805</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1750-0680</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Carbon balance and management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Carbon Balance Manag</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How does green transformation of industrial sector affect carbon emissions? Evidence from China.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13021-026-00425-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Industry is the core sector with the most challenging task of carbon emission reduction in China. This paper explores how industrial transformation in China's industrial sector affects carbon emissions. We shed light on the effect of industrial sector transformation on carbon emissions, and divide industrial sector transformation into two aspects: industrial structure optimization and industrial spatial layout.We construct socioeconomic panel data for 30 cities in the urban agglomeration in the middle reaches of the Yangtze River from 2000 to 2020, and explore the influence of industrial transformation on carbon emissions in 33 industrial sectors in China from three dimensions: spatial spillover effect, spatiotemporal heterogeneity, and threshold effect. The results show that: (1) In the industrial structure optimization dimension, industrial rationalization has effect on decreasing carbon emissions, while industrial upgrading increases carbon emissions. In the industrial spatial layout dimension, industrial specialization agglomeration can decline carbon emissions, while industrial diversification agglomeration does not reduce carbon emissions but instead increase carbon emissions.(2)Both industrial structure optimization and industrial spatial layout have spatiotemporal heterogeneous impacts on carbon emissions during the study period.(3) Under different levels of economic development, industrial transformation will have different impacts on carbon emissions. In the future, the Chinese government should increase efforts to promote technological progress and innovation, taking technological progress and independent innovation capabilities as the central link in promoting industrial transformation. Those findings not only provide certain environmental research reference for China's industrial economic development and transformation, but also provide a practical reference for carbon reduction in other developing countries that are undergoing economic transformation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pu</LastName><ForeName>Wenfang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Economy and Management, Zhejiang University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Hangzhou, 310018, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Land Management, Huazhong Agricultural University, Wuhan, 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agricultural Science and Information Institute, Shanghai Academy of Agricultural Sciences, Shanghai, 201403, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Anlu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Land Management, Huazhong Agricultural University, Wuhan, 430070, China. zhanganlu@mail.hzau.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Y202559389</GrantID><Agency>Zhejiang Provincial Department of Education Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2026N041</GrantID><Agency>2026 Research Project of Zhejiang Federation of Social Sciences</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025C25027</GrantID><Agency>the 2025 Zhejiang Province Soft Science Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>04250040</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs in 2025</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>25&amp;ZD171</GrantID><Agency>Major Project of National Social Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Carbon Balance Manag</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271519</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1750-0680</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon emissions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Industrial sector transformation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial spillover effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatiotemporal heterogeneity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Threshold effect</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41870805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-026-00425-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13021-026-00425-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anselin L. Spatial econometrics: methods and models. Springer Science Business Media, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arneth A, Sitch S, Pongratz J, Zaehle S. Historical carbon dioxide emissions caused by land-use changes are possibly larger than assumed. Nat Geosci. 2017;10:79&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1038/NGEO2882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin NI, Lin B. Quantile analysis of CE in China metallurgy industry. J Clean Prod. 2020;243:118534. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.118534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carri&#xf3;n-Flores C, Irwin EG. Identifying spatial interactions in the presence of spatial error autocorrelation: an application to land use spillovers. Resour Energy Econ. 2010;32:135&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.reseneeco.2009.11.009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Jiao S, Gu XY, Li S. Decoding the spatiotemporal effects of industrial clusters on carbon emissions in a Chinese river basin. J Clean Prod. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuai XW, Huang XJ, Zheng ZQ, Zhang M, Liao QL, Lai L, et al. Impact of land use change on terrestrial ecosystem carbon storage in Jiangsu Province. Resour Sci. 2011;33(10):1932&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diez JR. Metropolitan innovation systems: a comparison between Barcelona, Stockholm, and Vienna. Int Reg Sci Rev. 2002;25(1):63&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1177/016001702762039385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong F, Wang Y, Zheng L, Li JY, Xie SX. Can industrial agglomeration promote pollution agglomeration? Evidence from China. J Clean Prod. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.118960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Jin G, Deng XZ. Dynamic interactive effects of urban land-use efficiency, industrial transformation, and CE. J Clean Prod. 2020;270:122547. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.122547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan CH, Zheng RG, Yu DF. The impact of China&#x2019;s industrial structure changes on economic growth and fluctuations. Econ Res, 2011, 46(05): 4&#x2013;16+31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X, Zhang AL, Sun ZL. How regional economic integration influence on urban land use efficiency? A case study of Wuhan metropolitan area, China. Land Use Policy. 2019;90(1):104329. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landusepol.2019.104329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guastella G, Pareglio S, Sckokai P. A spatial econometric analysis of land use efficiency in large and small municipalities. Land Use Policy. 2017;63(4):288&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landusepol.2017.01.023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hairiah K, Noordwijk MV, Sari RR, Saputra DD, Widianto, Suprayogo D, Kurniawan S, Prayogo C, Gusli S. Soil carbon stocks in Indonesian (agro) forest transitions: Compaction conceals lower carbon concentrations in standard accounting. Agriculture Ecosystems and Environment, 2020, 294(6):106879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Chen ZX, Tan CX, Liu HY. Using a three-tier structural decomposition analysis to assess industrial structure transformation and carbon emissions in China. Energy. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.137817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John CK, Ajibade FO, Ajibade TF, Kumar P, Fadugba OG, Adelodun B. The impact of international agreements and government policies on collaborative management of environmental pollution and CE in the transportation sector. Environ Impact Assess Review. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eiar.2025.107930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Chen X, Yuan CX. Does digital government reduce CE? Empirical evidence from global sources. J Environ Manag. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.125081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CW, Li QJ, Hong T. How can local government capacity lift the&#x201c;resource curse?&#x201d; A study from the perspective of industrial structure transformation. J Environ Manag. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.122633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JQ. Spatiotemporal heterogeneity analysis of multi-type clean energy consumption and carbon dioxide emissions in Chinese cities: integrating multiscale geographically and temporally weighted regression with machine learning. Clean Environ Syst. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cesys.2025.100378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin QW, Zhang L, Qiu BK, Zhao Y, Wei C. Spatiotemporal analysis of land use patterns on CE in China. Land. 2021;10(2):10020141. https://doi.org/10.3390/land10020141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YF. Accelerating the development of new-quality productive forces: a perspective from New Structural Economics. J National Mod Stud. 2025;4(02):32&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.20200/j.cnki.gjxdh.2025.02.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YF, Wang Y, Yue WZ, Zhu LJ. Asymmetry of factor substitution and resource allocation efficiency. J Manag World. 2025;41(06):1&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.19744/j.cnki.11-1235/f.2025.0080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Wu KN. Marketization of land resources and upgrading of industrial structure: an investigation based on nonlinear causality and spatiotemporal geographic weighted model. Region Res Develop. 2021;40(03):20&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XP, Zuo L, Hu L, Wang CZ, Sheng SH. Industrial agglomeration, environmental regulation, and carbon emissions reduction under the carbon neutrality goal: threshold effects based on stages of industrialization in China. J Clean Prod. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.140064.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li WW, Fang S, Yan CR, Gong WF, Wang CH. Research on the impact of digital economy on industrial carbon emission efficiency&#x2013;an analysis based on spatial threshold model. J Clean Prod. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu HH, Dai YR, Yin T. Research on small sample carbon emission prediction based on improved Time GAN: a case study of the Yangtez River Delta urban agglomeration in China. J Environ Manage. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.125076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noojipady P, Morton DC, Macedo MN, Forest CE. From cropland expansion in the Brazilian Cerrado biome. Environ Res Lett. 2017;12:025004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang W, Zhou Y, Wang Y. Can command-and-control regulation reduce CE&#x202f;? Evidence from China. Environ Impact Assess Review. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eiar.2024.107802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang QH, Zhai HL, Zhao TX, Zhang L, Chiu YH. How industrial agglomeration and technological innovation affect carbon emission efficiency: evidence from China. Geoenergy Sci Eng. 2026. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoen.2025.214256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouyat R, Groffman P, Yesilonis I, Hernandez L. Soil carbon pools and fluxes in urban ecosystems. Environ Pollut. 2002;116(S1):107&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0269-7491(01)00263-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu W, Liu M, Zhang A. Does industrial green transformation really lead to high land use efficiency? Evidence from China. Land. 2025;14:1110. https://doi.org/10.3390/land14051110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu FT, Lu N, Feng SY. Impact of land use change on CE. China Popul Resour Environ. 2011;21(10):76&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senna AL, Moxot&#xf3; AC. CE and financial performance in the Brazilian stock market. J Environ Manag. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Zhang H, Zhang M. Environmental benefits of resource-based industrial agglomeration in the Yellow River basin: the perspective of proximity effect. Energy. 2026. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2025.139812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan TW. Economic growth and capital accumulation. Econ Rec. 1956;32(2):334&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tay W, He YQ. Detecting land cover and land use change and its impact on biomass carbon emission from 2001 to 2019 in Arkansas, U.S.A. Biogeochemistry. 2023;165(6):29&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu W, Rao CJ, Xiao XP, Hu FY, Goh M. Interactive geographical and temporal weighted regression to explore spatio-temporal characteristics and drivers of carbon emissions. Environ Technol Innov. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eti.2024.103836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaitsos CV. Crisis in regional economic cooperation (integration) among developing countries: a survey. World Dev. 1978;6(6):719&#x2013;69. https://doi.org/10.1016/0305-750X(78)90041-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Han P. The impact of industrial agglomeration on urban green land use efficiency in the Yangtze River Economic Belt. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):974. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-28250-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu BW, Xu YZ. Towards sustainable development: can industrial collaborative agglomeration become an accelerator for green and low-carbon transformation of resource-based cities in China? J Environ Manage. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.125199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue RX, Gu RD, Ong T. How does coupling coordination between industrial structure optimization and ecosystem services dynamically affect carbon emissions in the Yellow River Basin? J Clean Prod. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin CB, Zhou X, Ma H. Economic development, openness, and the impact of industrial co-agglomeration on urban carbon efficiency: An empirical study of threshold effects. Sustain Futures. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sftr.2025.101239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang DW, Wen CH, Luo YH, Zhu YL, Zhao BJ, Wen UF, et al. Digital finance, industrial structure and regional carbon emissions. Int Rev Financ Anal. 2026. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.irfa.2025.104745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Lai L, Huang XJ, Chuai XW, Tan JZ. Study on carbon emission intensity of regional land use type change in China. Resour Sci. 2013;35(04):792&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Zhou GM, Gu L. Carbon footprint and climate mitigation potential of bamboo products in China. Environ Impact Assess Rev. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eiar.2025.107958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang WX, Wu Q, Wang B, Huang J. Multidimensional study on the impact of industrial specialization and diversified agglomeration on urban land use efficiency. Zhongguo Renkou Ziyuan Yu Huanjing. 2019;29(11):100&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>