<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41826621</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Towards realistic electrical double layer capacitor device with elevated energy and power densities designed from plasticized nanocomposite PVA-based electrolyte.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43954-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The current work establishes a breakthrough for the electrical double-layer capacitor (EDLC) device, utilizing biodegradable polymer and non-toxic salt. In this project, polymer electrolytes (PEs) comprising polyvinyl alcohol (PVA), sodium thiocyanate (NaSCN), glycerol (Gly), and various amounts of TiO<sub>2</sub> nanofillers were prepared by solution casting. The electrolyte inserted with 3 wt% TiO<sub>2</sub> showed the maximum DC conductivity, reaching 1.86&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>-3</sup> S/cm. Dielectric analysis revealed a high dielectric constant (8.5&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>6</sup>), indicating efficient charge storage. The AC conductivity pattern demonstrated a low-frequency spike and a flat region, emphasizing the direct current (DC) component. Additional tests on the highset conducting electrolyte verified that ion transport was the primary mechanism (tion&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.976) and that the electrolyte maintained good electrochemical stability around 2.5&#xa0;V. This electrolyte was subsequently employed in the construction of an EDLC device. The cyclic voltammetry (CV) results revealed a non-Faradaic charge storage process characterized by an almost leaf-like profile. Galvanostatic charge-discharge curves close enough to the ideal shape with minimal voltage drop, reinforcing the device's excellent performance. The constructed EDLC exhibited strong performance, delivering 138 F/g in capacitance, with an output power of 4000 W/kg and an energy storage capacity of 17.3 Wh/kg. The Ragone plot showed high power and energy densities comparable to lead-acid and Ni-Cd batteries, highlighting its potential for rapid charge-discharge performance. Finally, the limitations of EDLC devices have been discussed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aziz</LastName><ForeName>Shujahadeen B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Center, University of Sulaimani, Sulaymaniyah, Kurdistan Region, 46001, Iraq. shujahadeenaziz@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hama</LastName><ForeName>Peshawa O</ForeName><Initials>PO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power and Control Engineering, Sulaimani Polytechnic University, Sulaymaniyah, Kurdistan Region, 46001, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murad</LastName><ForeName>Ary R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Science, Charmo University, Chamchamal, Sulaymaniyah, 46023, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdulwahid</LastName><ForeName>Rebar T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, College of Education, University of Sulaimani, Sulaymaniyah, Kurdistan Region, 46001, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Development Center, University of Sulaimani, Sulaymaniyah, Kurdistan Region, 46001, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kadir</LastName><ForeName>Mohd F Z</ForeName><Initials>MFZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, Faculty of Science, Universiti Malaya, 50603, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sangaraju</LastName><ForeName>Sambasivam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Water and Energy Center, United Arab Emirates University, 15551, Al Ain, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yong</LastName><ForeName>Jacky</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Ionics Universiti Malaya, Department of Physics, Faculty of Science, Universiti Malaya, 50603, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woo</LastName><ForeName>H J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Ionics Universiti Malaya, Department of Physics, Faculty of Science, Universiti Malaya, 50603, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy storage EDLC devices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Impedance and electrical studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PVA nanocomposite electrolytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium salt and plasticizer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TiO2 nanofillers</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41826621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43954-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43954-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aziz, S. B. et al. Electrochemical properties of plasticized PVA-based electrolyte inserted with alumina nanoparticles for EDLC application with enhanced dielectric constant. J. Energy Storage 103, 114264. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114264 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Z. et al. Electrochemical energy storage for green grid. Chem. Rev. 111, 3577&#x2013;3613. https://doi.org/10.1021/cr100290v (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hema, M., Selvasekarapandian, S., Arunkumar, D., Sakunthala, A. &amp; Nithya, H. FTIR, XRD and ac impedance spectroscopic study on PVA based polymer electrolyte doped with NH4X (X = Cl, Br, I). J. Non-Cryst. Solids 355, 84&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnoncrysol.2008.10.009 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz, S. B. et al. EDLC supercapacitor with enhanced charge-discharge cycles designed from plasticized biopolymer blend electrolytes: Biomaterials will be the future of energy storage devices. J. Energy Storage 114, 115841. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2025.115841 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright, P. V. Electrical conductivity in ionic complexes of poly(ethylene oxide). Br. Polym. J. 7, 319&#x2013;327. https://doi.org/10.1002/pi.4980070505 (1975).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright, P. V. Polymer electrolytes: The early days. Electrochim. Acta 43, 1137&#x2013;1143. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0013-4686(97)10011-1 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armand, M. Polymer solid electrolytes: An overview. Solid State Ionics 9&#x2013;10, 745&#x2013;754. https://doi.org/10.1016/0167-2738(83)90083-8 (1983).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazali, N. M. &amp; Samsudin, A. S. Progress on biopolymer as an application in electrolytes system: A review study. Mater. Today. Proc. 49, 3668&#x2013;3678. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matpr.2021.09.473 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alipoori, S., Mazinani, S., Aboutalebi, S. H. &amp; Sharif, F. Review of PVA-based gel polymer electrolytes in flexible solid-state supercapacitors: Opportunities and challenges. J. Energy Storage 27, 101072. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2019.101072 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Zhao, Z., Song, S., Ma, Q. &amp; Liu, R. High performance Poly(vinyl alcohol)-based Li-Ion conducting gel polymer electrolyte films for electric double-layer capacitors. Polymers (Basel) 10, 1179. https://doi.org/10.3390/polym10111179 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamsan, M. H. et al. Tailoring polymer electrolytes with PVA for improved performance in electrical double layer capacitors. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.11.035 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohapatra, S. R., Thakur, A. K. &amp; Choudhary, R. N. P. Effect of nanoscopic confinement on improvement in ion conduction and stability properties of an intercalated polymer nanocomposite electrolyte for energy storage applications. J. Power Sources 191, 601&#x2013;613. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2009.01.100 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojur Dennis, J. et al. Effect of ZnO nanofiller on structural and electrochemical performance improvement of solid polymer electrolytes based on Polyvinyl Alcohol&#x2013;Cellulose Acetate&#x2013;Potassium Carbonate composites. Molecules 27, 5528. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules27175528 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap, A. Y. &amp; Liew, C.-W. Structural, thermal, and electrochemical studies on PVA-LiTf-TiO<sub>2</sub> nanocomposite polymer electrolyte and the performance on electric double layer capacitor application. Ionics (Kiel) 28, 4111&#x2013;4128. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-022-04659-4 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoetz, T. et al. Disentangling faradaic, pseudocapacitive, and capacitive charge storage: A tutorial for the characterization of batteries, supercapacitors, and hybrid systems. Electrochim. Acta 412, 140072. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2022.140072 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, I. et al. Pore size-controlled carbon aerogels for EDLC electrodes in organic electrolytes. Curr. Appl. Phys. 16, 665&#x2013;672. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cap.2016.03.019 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, B. et al. High specific surface area activated carbon with well-balanced micro/mesoporosity for ultrahigh supercapacitive performance. Int. J. Electrochem. Sci. 11, 9007&#x2013;9018. https://doi.org/10.20964/2016.11.01 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liew, C.-W., Ramesh, S. &amp; Arof, A. K. Good prospect of ionic liquid based-poly(vinyl alcohol) polymer electrolytes for supercapacitors with excellent electrical, electrochemical and thermal properties. Int. J. Hydrog. Energy 39, 2953&#x2013;2963. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2013.06.061 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, C.-S., Teoh, K. H., Liew, C.-W. &amp; Ramesh, S. Capacitive behavior studies on electrical double layer capacitor using poly (vinyl alcohol)&#x2013;lithium perchlorate based polymer electrolyte incorporated with TiO<sub>2</sub>. Mater. Chem. Phys. 143, 661&#x2013;667. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2013.09.051 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marf, A. S., Aziz, S. B. &amp; Abdullah, R. M. Plasticized H+ ion-conducting PVA:CS-based polymer blend electrolytes for energy storage EDLC application. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Electron. 31, 18554&#x2013;18568. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-020-04399-z (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sravanthi, K., Sundari, G. S. &amp; Erothu, H. Development of bio-degradable based polymer electrolytes for EDLC application. Optik (Stuttg) 241, 166229. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijleo.2020.166229 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanty, R., Mohanty, U. A. &amp; Parida, K. A comprehensive review of ammonium ion hybrid supercapacitors: Exploring recent breakthroughs and future horizons. Energy Fuels 38(15), 13585&#x2013;13611. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02044 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenesi, A. G., Ghorbani, M. &amp; Lashkenari, M. S. High electrochemical performance of PANI/CdO nanocomposite based on graphene oxide as a hybrid electrode materials for supercapacitor application. Int. J. Hydrog. Energy 47, 38849&#x2013;38861. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.09.047 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi, A. K., Ghorbani, M., Lashkenari, M. S. &amp; Nasiri, N. Controllable synthesis of zinc ferrite nanostructure with tunable morphology on polyaniline nanocomposite for supercapacitor application. J. Energy Storage 51, 104579. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2022.104579 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef, A. M., Hasanin, M. S., El-Aziz, M. E. A. &amp; Turky, G. M. Conducting chitosan/hydroxylethyl cellulose/polyaniline bionanocomposites hydrogel based on graphene oxide doped with Ag-NPs. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 167, 1435&#x2013;1444. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2020.11.097 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hama, P. O., Aziz, S. B. &amp; Abdullah, O. G. Structural and ion transport characteristics of transparent proton conducting biopolymer electrolytes based on chitosan and cold water fish skin gelatin. Sci. Rep. 15, 30475. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-15193-4 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machappa, T. &amp; Ambika Prasad, M. V. N. AC conductivity and dielectric behavior of polyaniline/sodium metavenadate (PANI/NaVO3) composites. Phys. B Condens. Matter 404, 4168&#x2013;4172. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2009.07.194 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Justin Raj, C. &amp; Varma, K. B. R. Synthesis and electrical properties of the (PVA)<sub>0.7</sub>(KI)<sub>0.3</sub>&#xb7;xH<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> (0 &#x2264; x &#x2264; 5) polymer electrolytes and their performance in a primary Zn/MnO<sub>2</sub> battery. Electrochim. Acta 56, 649&#x2013;656. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2010.09.076 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hama, P. O. et al. Simulated EIS and Trukhan model to study the ion transport parameters associated with Li<sup>+</sup> ion dynamics in CS based polymer blends inserted with lithium nitrate salt. Results Phys. 46, 106262. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rinp.2023.106262 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, D.-W., Kim, Y.-R., Park, J.-K. &amp; Moon, S.-I. Electrical properties of the plasticized polymer electrolytes based on acrylonitrile-methyl methacrylate copolymers. Solid State Ion 106, 329&#x2013;337. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0167-2738(97)00498-0 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukur, M. F., Ithnin, R. &amp; Kadir, M. F. Z. Electrical characterization of corn starch-LiOAc electrolytes and application in electrochemical double layer capacitor. Electrochim. Acta 136, 204&#x2013;216. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2014.05.075 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvasekarapandian, S., Baskaran, R. &amp; Hema, M. Complex AC impedance, transference number and vibrational spectroscopy studies of proton conducting PVAc&#x2013;NH4SCN polymer electrolytes. Phys. B Condens. Matter 357, 412&#x2013;419. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2004.12.007 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, L. et al. Universal unilateral electro-spinning/spraying strategy to construct water-unidirectional Janus membranes with well-tuned hierarchical micro/nanostructures. Chem. Commun. 56, 478&#x2013;481. https://doi.org/10.1039/C9CC08088K (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramaswamy, M. et al. Development and study of solid polymer electrolyte based on polyvinyl alcohol: Mg(ClO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>. Polym. Plast. Technol. Eng. 56, 992&#x2013;1002. https://doi.org/10.1080/03602559.2016.1247280 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed Ali, T., Padmanathan, N. &amp; Selladurai, S. Effect of nanofiller CeO<sub>2</sub> on structural, conductivity, and dielectric behaviors of plasticized blend nanocomposite polymer electrolyte. Ionics (Kiel) 21, 829&#x2013;840. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-014-1240-y (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz, S. B. et al. Plasticised chitosan: Dextran polymer blend electrolyte for energy harvesting application: Tuning the ion transport and EDLC charge storage capacity through TiO<sub>2</sub> dispersion. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 273, 133203. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.133203 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hama, P. O., Aziz, S. B. &amp; Abdullah, OGh. Role of potato starch replacement with fish skin gelatin (FSG) on ion transport parameters in chitosan-based solid polymer electrolyte. Emergent Mater. https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-025-01156-y (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh, A. Frequency-dependent conductivity in bismuth-vanadate glassy semiconductors. Phys. Rev. B 41, 1479&#x2013;1488. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.41.1479 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekri-Abbes, I. &amp; Srasra, E. Characterization and AC conductivity of polyaniline&#x2013;montmorillonite nanocomposites synthesized by mechanical/chemical reaction. React. Funct. Polym. 70, 11&#x2013;18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.reactfunctpolym.2009.09.008 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Saeedi, S. I. et al. Green biopolymer and plasticizer for solid electrolyte preparation: FTIR, electrochemical properties and EDLC characteristics. Arab. J. Chem. 16, 105046. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2023.105046 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonscher, A. K. Universal relaxation law (Chelsea Dielectrics Press, 1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louati, B., Hlel, F. &amp; Guidara, K. Ac electrical properties and dielectric relaxation of the new mixed crystal (Na<sub>0.8</sub>Ag<sub>0.2</sub>)<sub>2</sub>PbP<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>. J. Alloys Compd. 486, 299&#x2013;303. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2009.06.148 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patriarchi, A. et al. All-solid-state Li-Metal cell using nanocomposite TiO<sub>2</sub>/polymer electrolyte and self-standing LiFePO<sub>4</sub> cathode. Batteries 10, 11. https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10010011 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasikumar, M. et al. Titanium dioxide nano-ceramic filler in solid polymer electrolytes: Strategy towards suppressed dendrite formation and enhanced electrochemical performance for safe lithium ion batteries. J. Alloys Compd. 882, 160709. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2021.160709 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskaran, R., Selvasekarapandian, S., Hirankumar, G. &amp; Bhuvaneswari, M. S. Vibrational, ac impedance and dielectric spectroscopic studies of poly(vinylacetate)&#x2013;N,N&#x2013;dimethylformamide&#x2013;LiClO<sub>4</sub> polymer gel electrolytes. J. Power Sources 134, 235&#x2013;240. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2004.02.025 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukur, M. F., Yusof, Y. M., Zawawi, S. M. M., Illias, H. A. &amp; Kadir, M. F. Z. Conductivity and transport studies of plasticized chitosan-based proton conducting biopolymer electrolytes. Phys. Scr. T157, 14050. https://doi.org/10.1088/0031-8949/2013/t157/014050 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramly MINI, K. &amp; Khiar, A. S. A. Conductivity and dielectric behaviour studies of starch/PEO+x wt-%NH<sub>4</sub>NO<sub>3</sub> polymer electrolyte. Mater. Res. Innov. 15, s82&#x2013;s85. https://doi.org/10.1179/143307511X1303189074 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayathilaka, P. Dielectric relaxation, ionic conductivity and thermal studies of the gel polymer electrolyte system PAN/EC/PC/LiTFSI. Solid State Ionics 156, 179&#x2013;195. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0167-2738(02)00616-1 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz, S. B. Role of dielectric constant on ion transport: Reformulated Arrhenius equation. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2016, 1&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/2527013 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, Y., Creber, K. A. M., Peppley, B. &amp; Tam Bui, V. Chitosan-based solid electrolyte composite membranes. J. Membr. Sci. 280, 666&#x2013;674. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.memsci.2006.02.024 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary, S. &amp; Sengwa, R. J. Effects of different inorganic nanoparticles on the structural, dielectric and ion transportation properties of polymers blend based nanocomposite solid polymer electrolytes. Electrochim. Acta 247, 924&#x2013;941. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2017.07.051 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, H. M., Ramesh, S. &amp; Ramesh, K. Exploration on the P(VP-co-VAc) copolymer based gel polymer electrolytes doped with quaternary ammonium iodide salt for DSSC applications: Electrochemical behaviors and photovoltaic performances. Org. Electron. 22, 132&#x2013;139. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.orgel.2015.03.020 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rag, S. A. et al. Impedance spectroscopic study of biodegradable PVA/PVP doped TBAI ionic liquid polymer electrolyte. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 111, 43&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2022.04.017 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah, A. M. et al. Glycerol as an efficient plasticizer to increase the DC conductivity and improve the ion transport parameters in biopolymer based electrolytes: XRD, FTIR and EIS studies. Arab. J. Chem. 15, 103791. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2022.103791 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idris, N. H., Senin, H. B. &amp; Arof, A. K. Dielectric spectra of LiTFSI-doped chitosan/PEO blends. Ionics (Kiel) 13, 213&#x2013;217. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-007-0093-z (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani, M. S. A., Ahmad, A. &amp; Mohamed, N. S. Influence of nano-sized fumed silica on physicochemical and electrochemical properties of cellulose derivatives-ionic liquid biopolymer electrolytes. Ionics (Kiel) 24, 807&#x2013;814. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-017-2235-2 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi, M. &amp; Tripathi, S. K. Electrical studies on ionic liquid-based gel polymer electrolyte for its application in EDLCs. Ionics (Kiel) 23, 2735&#x2013;2746. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-017-2051-8 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samsi, N. S., Ali, R. M., Zakaria, R., Yahya, M. Z. A. &amp; Ali, A. M. M. Electrical properties of ammonium iodide doped cellulose acetate based polymer electrolyte. In ICGSCE 2014 331&#x2013;338 (Springer Singapore, 2015). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-287-505-1_39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jibreel, U. M., Bhattacharya, B. &amp; Singh, P. K. Synthesis, characterization, and detailed studies on plasticized Poly(ethyl methacrylate): NH<sub>4</sub>I polymer electrolyte. Adv. Polym. Technol. 37, 542&#x2013;546. https://doi.org/10.1002/adv.21693 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, R. M., Harun, N. I., Ali, A. M. M. &amp; Yahya, M. Z. A. Effect of ZnS dispersoid in structural and electrical properties of plasticized CA-NH4I. Phys. Procedia 25, 293&#x2013;298. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phpro.2012.03.086 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, H. et al. Effect of temperature on electrochemical performance of ionic liquid based polymer electrolyte with Li/LiFePO<sub>4</sub> electrodes. Solid State Ion 309, 192&#x2013;199. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssi.2017.07.019 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TianKhoon, L., Ataollahi, N., Hassan, N. H. &amp; Ahmad, A. Studies of porous solid polymeric electrolytes based on poly (vinylidene fluoride) and poly (methyl methacrylate) grafted natural rubber for applications in electrochemical devices. J. Solid State Electrochem. 20, 203&#x2013;213. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-015-3017-2 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monisha, S., Mathavan, T., Selvasekarapandian, S., Benial, A. M. F. &amp; latha, M. P. Preparation and characterization of cellulose acetate and lithium nitrate for advanced electrochemical devices. Ionics 23, 2697&#x2013;2706. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-016-1886-8 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasprzak, D., St&#x119;pniak, I. &amp; Gali&#x144;ski, M. Electrodes and hydrogel electrolytes based on cellulose: Fabrication and characterization as EDLC components. J. Solid State Electrochem. 22, 3035&#x2013;3047. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-018-4015-y (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murashko, K., Nevstrueva, D., Pihlajam&#xe4;ki, A., Koiranen, T. &amp; Pyrh&#xf6;nen, J. Cellulose and activated carbon based flexible electrical double-layer capacitor electrode: Preparation and characterization. Energy 119, 435&#x2013;441. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2016.12.038 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Madrigal, M. M., Edo, M. G. &amp; Alem&#xe1;n, C. Powering the future: Application of cellulose-based materials for supercapacitors. Green Chem. 18, 5930&#x2013;5956. https://doi.org/10.1039/C6GC02086K (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varzi, A., Balducci, A. &amp; Passerini, S. Natural cellulose: A green alternative binder for high voltage electrochemical double layer capacitors containing ionic liquid-based electrolytes. J. Electrochem. Soc. 161, A368&#x2013;A375. https://doi.org/10.1149/2.063403jes (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasprzak, D., St&#x119;pniak, I. &amp; Gali&#x144;ski, M. Acetate- and lactate-based ionic liquids: Synthesis, characterisation and electrochemical properties. J. Mol. Liq. 264, 233&#x2013;241. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2018.05.059 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kant, R. &amp; Singh, M. B. Theory of the electrochemical impedance of mesostructured electrodes embedded with heterogeneous micropores. J. Phys. Chem. C 121, 7164&#x2013;7174. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b01287 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pohlmann, S. et al. Mixtures of Azepanium based ionic liquids and propylene carbonate as high voltage electrolytes for supercapacitors. Electrochim. Acta 153, 426&#x2013;432. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2014.11.189 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajina, A. &amp; Isa, D. symmetrical supercapacitor using coconut shell-based activated carbon. Pertanika J. Sci. Technol. 18, 351&#x2013;363 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya, S., Hu, Y., Moussa, H. &amp; Abidi, N. Preparation and characterization of transparent cellulose films using an improved cellulose dissolution process. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. https://doi.org/10.1002/app.44871 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Li, H., Feng, R., He, L. &amp; Lu, H. Electrochemical double-layer capacitor containing mixtures of ionic liquid, lithium salt, and organic solvent as an electrolyte. Front. Mater. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmats.2021.633460 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendhe, A. &amp; Panda, H. S. A review on electrolytes for supercapacitor device. Discov. Mater. 3, 29. https://doi.org/10.1007/s43939-023-00065-3 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohana, M. S. High Molecular Weight Chitosan as Polymer Electrolyte for Electrochemical Devices (Fakulti Sains, University of Malaya, 2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liew, C.-W., Ramesh, S. &amp; Arof, A. K. Characterization of ionic liquid added poly(vinyl alcohol)-based proton conducting polymer electrolytes and electrochemical studies on the supercapacitors. Int. J. Hydrog. Energy 40, 852&#x2013;862. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2014.09.160 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamsan, M. H., Shukur, M. F. &amp; Kadir, M. F. Z. NH<sub>4</sub>NO<sub>3</sub> as charge carrier contributor in glycerolized potato starch-methyl cellulose blend-based polymer electrolyte and the application in electrochemical double-layer capacitor. Ionics (Kiel) 23, 3429&#x2013;3453. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-017-2155-1 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arof, A. K., Shuhaimi, N. E. A., Alias, N. A., Kufian, M. Z. &amp; Majid, S. R. Application of chitosan/iota-carrageenan polymer electrolytes in electrical double layer capacitor (EDLC). J. Solid State Electrochem. 14, 2145&#x2013;2152. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-010-1050-8 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz, S. B. et al. Plasticized ecofriendly chitosan-potato starch biopolymer electrolyte with enhanced dielectric constant for EDLC application. Emergent Mater. https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00981-x (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey, G. P., Kumar, Y. &amp; Hashmi, S. A. Ionic liquid incorporated PEO based polymer electrolyte for electrical double layer capacitors: A comparative study with lithium and magnesium systems. Solid State Ionics 190, 93&#x2013;98. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ssi.2011.03.018 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;tz, R. &amp; Carlen, M. Principles and applications of electrochemical capacitors. Electrochim. Acta 45, 2483&#x2013;2498. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0013-4686(00)00354-6 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz, S. B. et al. Unlocking high energy density and stable electric double layer capacitor derived from sustainable biodegradable polymer electrolyte based on chitosan:polyvinyl alcohol: Potassium thiocyanate:xGlycerol (10 &#x2264; x &#x2264; 30). Results Eng. 27, 106897. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2025.106897 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hina, M., Bashir, S., Kamran, K., Ramesh, S. &amp; Ramesh, K. Synthesis and characterization of self-healable poly (acrylamide) hydrogel electrolytes and their application in fabrication of aqueous supercapacitors. Polymer (Guildf) 210, 123020. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.polymer.2020.123020 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazuki, N., Abdul Majeed, A. P. P. &amp; Samsudin, A. S. Study on electrochemical properties of CMC-PVA doped NH4Br based solid polymer electrolytes system as application for EDLC. J. Polym. Res. 27, 135. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10965-020-02078-5 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liew, C.-W. &amp; Ramesh, S. Electrical, structural, thermal and electrochemical properties of corn starch-based biopolymer electrolytes. Carbohydr. Polym. 124, 222&#x2013;228. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbpol.2015.02.024 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, C. et al. A review of electrolyte materials and compositions for electrochemical supercapacitors. Chem. Soc. Rev. 44, 7484&#x2013;7539. https://doi.org/10.1039/c5cs00303b (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muzaffar, A., Ahamed, M. B., Deshmukh, K. &amp; Thirumalai, J. A review on recent advances in hybrid supercapacitors: Design, fabrication and applications. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 101, 123&#x2013;145. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2018.10.026 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kularatna, N. Energy Storage Devices for Electronic Systems (Elsevier, 2015). https://doi.org/10.1016/C2012-0-06356-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Permatasari, F. A., Irham, M. A., Bisri, S. Z. &amp; Iskandar, F. Carbon-based quantum dots for supercapacitors: Recent advances and future challenges. Nanomaterials 11, 91. https://doi.org/10.3390/nano11010091 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanty, R. &amp; Parida, K. Carbamide-mediated facile sol&#x2013;gel synthesis of porous flower-like ZnCo<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub> microspheres for high-performance asymmetric coin cell supercapacitors. Electrochim. Acta 491, 144327. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144327 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>