<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41396341</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2948-2933</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of imaging informatics in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Imaging Inform Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AttMamba: Integrating Dual-Attention and Vision Mamba for Diabetic Retinopathy Grading.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10278-025-01774-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetic retinopathy (DR) is the leading cause of blindness among the global working population. It is crucial to early screening and timely diagnosis in mitigating vision deterioration and preventing permanent blindness. The varying sizes and complex structures of different types of DR lesions present challenges for accurate grading. However, existing models suffer from long training time and insufficient extraction of small lesion features, which makes it difficult to learn the subtle differences between adjacent grades of DR images. This paper proposes the AttMamba framework for automatic DR grading, which integrates an attention mechanism with the state space model to improve training efficiency and the ability to extract small lesion features. The efficient 2D scanning module is integrated with VMamba to scan the whole image with fixed step sizes to accelerate the computation speed. Moreover, the squeeze-and-excitation module and global context module are proposed to locate regions of interest and extract channel attention and global attention features. It can learn the fine-grained differences between different grades of DR images for precise grading. Experiments are conducted on three public and one personal datasets. The accuracy of the proposed method achieved 0.832/0.789/0.756/0.889 on APTOS 2019, DDR, FGADR, and RUDR datasets, which improved by 7.4%/9.6%/17.2%/8.5% in accuracy compared to VMamba. The proposed model provides an effective solution for early diagnosis and timely treatment of diabetic retinopathy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s) under exclusive licence to Society for Imaging Informatics in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Yanfei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1652-3861</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Computer Science and Engineering, Qufu Normal University, Rizhao, 276827, China. guo_1992_fei@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chenglong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Computer Science and Engineering, Qufu Normal University, Rizhao, 276827, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenhua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qingdao Central Hospital, University of Health and Rehabilitation Sciences, Qingdao, 266000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuanke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Computer Science and Engineering, Qufu Normal University, Rizhao, 276827, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Dapeng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qingdao Central Hospital, University of Health and Rehabilitation Sciences, Qingdao, 266000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Dewang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Medical Physics and Image Processing, Shandong Engineering Research Center for Medical Physical Imaging Technology, School of Physics and Physical Engineering, Qufu Normal University, Qufu, 273165, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RZ2022ZR64</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Rizhao</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZR2025QC677</GrantID><Agency>Shandong Provincial Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022KJ179</GrantID><Agency>Youth Innovative Research Team in China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Imaging Inform Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918663679206676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2948-2925</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetic retinopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disease classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">State space model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VMamba</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval: This article does not contain any studies with human participants performed by any of the authors. Consent to Participate: Not applicable Consent for Publication: The author confirms that the work described has not been published before (except in the form of an abstract or as part of a published lecture, review, or thesis); that it is not under consideration for publication elsewhere; that its publication has been approved by all co-authors, if any; that its publication has been approved (tacitly or explicitly) by the responsible authorities at the institution where the work was carried out. The author agrees to publication in the Journal indicated below and also to publication of the article in English by Springer in Springer&#x2019;s corresponding English-language journal. The copyright to the English-language article is transferred to Springer effective if and when the article is accepted for publication. The author warrants that his/her contribution is original and that he/she has full power to make this grant. The author signs for and accepts responsibility for releasing this material on behalf of any and all co-authors. The copyright transfer covers the exclusive right to reproduce and distribute to article, including reprints, translations, photographic reproductions, microform, electronic form (offline, online), or any other reproductions of a similar nature. Conflict of Interest: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41396341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-025-01774-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10278-025-01774-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>David A Antonetti, Paolo S Silva, and Alan W Stitt. Current understanding of the molecular and cellular pathology of diabetic retinopathy. NAT REV ENDOCRINOL, 17(4):195&#x2013;206, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sicong Li, Ruiwei Zhao, and Haidong Zou. Artificial intelligence for diabetic retinopathy. CHINESE MED J-PEKING, 135(03):253&#x2013;260, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaemin Son, Joo Young Shin, Hoon Dong Kim, Kyu-Hwan Jung, Kyu Hyung Park, and Sang Jun Park. Development and validation of deep learning models for screening multiple abnormal findings in retinal fundus images. OPHTHALMOLOGY, 127(1):85&#x2013;94, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amit Bhati, Neha Gour, Pritee Khanna, Aparajita Ojha, and Naoufel Werghi. An interpretable dual attention network for diabetic retinopathy grading: Idanet. ARTIF INTELL MED, 149:102782, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.artmed.2024.102782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38462283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeru Hai, Beiji Zou, Xiaoxia Xiao, Qinghua Peng, Junfeng Yan, Wensheng Zhang, and Kejuan Yue. A novel approach for intelligent diagnosis and grading of diabetic retinopathy. COMPUT BIOL MED, 172:108246, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2024.108246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38471350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yongjia Lei, Shuyuan Lin, Zhiying Li, Yachao Zhang, and Taotao Lai. Gnn-fused capsnet with multi-head prediction for diabetic retinopathy grading. ENG APPL ARTIF INTEL, 133:107994, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2024.107994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanfei Guo, Hangli Du, Yuanke Zhang, Fei Ma, and Jing Meng. Lecnet: Lesion semantic feature enhancement and complementary networks for diabetic retinopathy grading. BIOMED SIGNAL PROCES, 107:107813, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2025.107813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandeep Madarapu, Samit Ari, and Kamalakanta Mahapatra. A multi-resolution convolutional attention network for efficient diabetic retinopathy classification. COMPUT ELECTR ENG, 117:109243, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2024.109243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yining Xie, Yuhang Zhang, Jun Long, Nanshuang Que, and Yu Chen. Mplnet: Multi-task supervised progressive learning network for diabetic retinopathy grading. COMPUT ELECTR ENG, 120:109746, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Zang and Hui Ma. Cra-net: Transformer guided category-relation attention network for diabetic retinopathy grading. COMPUT BIOL MED, 170:107993, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui Sun, Yihao Li, Tianzhu Zhang, Zhendong Mao, Feng Wu, and Yongdong Zhang. Lesion-aware transformers for diabetic retinopathy grading. In: Proc. IEEE Comput. Soc. Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit., pages 10938&#x2013;10947, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yijin Huang, Junyan Lyu, Pujin Cheng, Roger Tam, and Xiaoying Tang. Ssit: Saliency-guided self-supervised image transformer for diabetic retinopathy grading. IEEE J BIOMED HEALTH, 28(5):2806&#x2013;2817, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue Liu, Yunjie Tian, Yuzhong Zhao, Hongtian Yu, Lingxi Xie, Yaowei Wang, Qixiang Ye, and Yunfan Liu. Vmamba: Visual state space model. arXiv:2401.10166 , 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Along He, Tao Li, Ning Li, Kai Wang, and Huazhu Fu. Cabnet: Category attention block for imbalanced diabetic retinopathy grading. IEEE T MED IMAGING, 40(1):143&#x2013;153, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Wu, Gonglei Shi, Yang Chen, Fei Shi, Xinjian Chen, Gouenou Coatrieux, Jian Yang, Limin Luo, and Shuo Li. Coarse-to-fine classification for diabetic retinopathy grading using convolutional neural network. ARTIF INTELL MED, 108:101936, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guanghui Yue, Yuan Li, Tianwei Zhou, Xiaoyan Zhou, Yun Liu, and Tianfu Wang. Attention-driven cascaded network for diabetic retinopathy grading from fundus images. BIOMED SIGNAL PROCES, 80:104370, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuiqing Zhao, Yanan Wu, Mengmeng Tong, Yudong Yao, Wei Qian, and Shouliang Qi. Cot-xnet: contextual transformer with xception network for diabetic retinopathy grading. PHYS MED BIOL, 67(24):245003, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhe Chen and Emery N Brown. State space model. Scholarpedia, 8(3):30868, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianghui Zhu, Bencheng Liao, Qian Zhang, Xinlong Wang, Wenyu Liu, and Xinggang Wang. Vision mamba: Efficient visual representation learning with bidirectional state space model. arXiv:2401.09417 , 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaohuan Pei, Tao Huang, and Chang Xu. Efficientvmamba: Atrous selective scan for light weight visual mamba. arXiv:2403.09977 , 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yubiao Yue and Zhenzhang Li. Medmamba: Vision mamba for medical image classification. arXiv:2403.03849 , 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue Cao, Jiarui Xu, Stephen Lin, Fangyun Wei, and Han Hu. Gcnet: Non-local networks meet squeeze-excitation networks and beyond. In: IEEE Int. Conf. Comput. Vis., pages 1&#x2013;10, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jie Hu, Li Shen, and Gang Sun. Squeeze-and-excitation networks. In: Proc. IEEE Comput. Soc. Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit., pages 7132&#x2013;7141, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashish Vaswani, Noam Shazeer, Niki Parmar, Jakob Uszkoreit, Llion Jones, Aidan N Gomez, &#x141;ukasz Kaiser, and Illia Polosukhin. Attention is all you need. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst., 30, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsung-Yi Lin, Priya Goyal, Ross Girshick, Kaiming He, and Piotr Doll&#xe1;r. Focal loss for dense object detection. In: IEEE Int. Conf. Comput. Vis., pages 2980&#x2013;2988, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohier Dane Karthik, Maggie. Aptos 2019 blindness detection, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao Li, Yingqi Gao, Kai Wang, Song Guo, Hanruo Liu, and Hong Kang. Diagnostic assessment of deep learning algorithms for diabetic retinopathy screening. INFORM SCIENCES, 501:511&#x2013;522, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi Zhou, Boyang Wang, Lei Huang, Shanshan Cui, and Ling Shao. A benchmark for studying diabetic retinopathy: segmentation, grading, and transferability. IEEE T MED IMAGING, 40(3):818&#x2013;828, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang Liu and Wei Chi. A cross-lesion attention network for accurate diabetic retinopathy grading with fundus images. IEEE T INSTRUM MEAS, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberto Romero-Ora&#xe1;, Mar&#xed;a Herrero-Tudela, Mar&#xed;a I L&#xf3;pez, Roberto Hornero, and Mar&#xed;a Garc&#xed;a. Attention-based deep learning framework for automatic fundus image processing to aid in diabetic retinopathy grading. COMPUT METH PROG BIO, 249:108160, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KR Niranjan, Nagesh Rangahanumaiah, Beena Ullala Mata BN, Vani Anantharamaiah, et al. A hybrid vision transformer and graph neural network model with attention mechanisms for diabetic retinopathy detection. Journal of Artificial Intelligence and Technology, 5:230&#x2013;241, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaoxin Guo, Guangqi Yang, Chenfangqian Xu, Hongliang Dong, Xiaoying Hu, and Songtian Che. Prior-guided dual-stage diabetic retinopathy grading model based on feature collaboration of lesion and vascular structure. Expert Systems with Applications, 285:128052, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanfei Guo, Chenglong Yang, Hangli Du, Yuanke Zhang, Fei Ma, and Shasha Yuan. Dynamic momentum contrastive learning network for diabetic retinopathy grading. Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence, 151:110604, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiming He, Xiangyu Zhang, Shaoqing Ren, and Jian Sun. Deep residual learning for image recognition. In: IEEE Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit., pages 770&#x2013;778, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Huang, Zhuang Liu, Laurens Van Der Maaten, and Kilian Q Weinberger. Densely connected convolutional networks. In: IEEE Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit., pages 4700&#x2013;4708, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karen Simonyan and Andrew Zisserman. Very deep convolutional networks for large-scale image recognition. In: Int. Conf. Learn. Represent., 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fran&#xe7;ois Chollet. Xception: Deep learning with depthwise separable convolutions. In: IEEE Conf. Comput. Vis. Pattern Recognit., pages 1251&#x2013;1258, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexey Dosovitskiy, Lucas Beyer, Alexander Kolesnikov, Dirk Weissenborn, Xiaohua Zhai, Thomas Unterthiner, Mostafa Dehghani, Matthias Minderer, Georg Heigold, Sylvain Gelly, Jakob Uszkoreit, and Neil Houlsby. An image is worth 16x16 words: Transformers for image recognition at scale. In: Int. Conf. Learn. Represent., 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ze Liu, Yutong Lin, Yue Cao, Han Hu, Yixuan Wei, Zheng Zhang, Stephen Lin, and Baining Guo. Swin transformer: Hierarchical vision transformer using shifted windows. In: IEEE Int. Conf. Comput. Vis., pages 10012&#x2013;10022, 2021.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>