<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41885381</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-808X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Academic medicine : journal of the Association of American Medical Colleges</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acad Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Developing AI-Powered Virtual Patient Chatbots for Diagnostic Reasoning Training.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">wvag094</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/acamed/wvag094</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PROBLEM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Diagnostic reasoning, the cognitive process of interpreting clinical information to arrive at a diagnosis, is a critical competency in medical education, and has been taught using authentic methods such as standardized patients and peer role-playing that simulate real clinical encounters. Although effective, these approaches require substantial time, space, and cost.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="APPROACH" NlmCategory="METHODS">To address the limitations of traditional approaches, AI-powered virtual patient chatbots were developed between April 21-28, 2025, with a chatbot builder that incorporates natural language processing. The design was guided by two core cognitive models of diagnostic reasoning-the dual process model and the memory model. The chatbots simulated authentic physician-patient interactions across three clinical scenarios: fatigue, stomachache, and memory loss. Students can perform differential diagnoses based on various clinical data and received immediate feedback on diagnostic accuracy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The patient chatbots were evaluated through surveys and interviews with faculty (May 2025) and students (November 2025). Findings consistently indicated that the chatbots functioned as an effective (4.50/5) and usable tool (4.46/5) for diagnostic reasoning practice. Participants perceived that the chatbots supported 'core cognitive processes of diagnostic reasoning' by prompting active hypothetico-deductive reasoning, while repeated exposure to different cases was viewed as facilitating pattern recognition. Faculty highlighted the chatbots' cost-efficiency and scalability within curricula, while students emphasized authentic "from-zero" clinical reasoning and the value of reviewing dialogue logs for reflection. Overall, the results demonstrate that the chatbots can provide a feasible and educationally meaningful environment for practicing diagnostic reasoning in medical education.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="NEXT STEPS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Future work should refine AI-powered virtual patient chatbots by incorporating tiered case complexity, patient-centered language, and equity-oriented design. Effective use will require systematic instructional design and learner preparation for emotionally challenging scenarios. Larger empirical studies using both outcome and interaction data are needed to evaluate educational impact and guide integration into clinical training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the AAMC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yejin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2373-3445</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Education &amp; Humanities, College of Medicine, Yeungnam University, Daegu, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Yuyi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5907-3624</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Education, School of Dentistry &amp; Dental Research Institute, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jihyun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9357-5345</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Education, School of Dentistry &amp; Dental Research Institute, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Acad Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904605</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1040-2446</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chatbot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic reasoning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virtual patient</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41885381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/acamed/wvag094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">8541653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>