<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41588178</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Secure aggregation for heterogeneous enterprise data based on federated meta-learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4484</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4484</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4484</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34735-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper proposes a secure and efficient data aggregation approach for heterogeneous enterprise data, leveraging federated meta-learning (FML) and data consolidation. The proposed approach addresses critical challenges in enterprise data, including data privacy, heterogeneous data distributions, and communication constraints. Specifically, the proposed approach enables decentralized devices to collaboratively train local models, which are aggregated by the server into a global model using meta-learning. Then, a consortium blockchain is used to ensure secure, immutable storage of aggregated data through a dual-chain structure: lightweight fluffy chains for temporary storage and heavyweight bulky chains for permanent records. In further, the proposed approach incorporates robust security mechanisms, such as XF authentication, timestamp-based counters to thwart replay attacks, asymmetric encryption for secure key exchange, and a Hampel filter to detect and mitigate model poisoning. Simulations results under Secure Water Treatment (SWaT) dataset are finally provided to demonstrate the superiority of the proposed approach. Specifically, the proposed approach achieves a lower validation delay scaling efficiently with training history size over the competing ones. Additionally, the proposed approach can enhance the system security by increasing the attack failure probability up to 15% over the competing ones.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Chun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Energy Development Research Institute, China Southern Power Grid, Guangzhou, 510663, China. chunyang2022@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Yining</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Energy Development Research Institute, China Southern Power Grid, Guangzhou, 510663, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Data aggregation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Data collection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Federated meta-learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance evaluation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41588178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12865032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34735-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34735-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Zhang, H., Fang, Y. &amp; Yuan, D. Learning-based data transmissions for future 6G enabled industrial IoT: A data compression perspective. <i>IEEE Netw.</i><b>36</b>(5), 180&#x2013;187 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MNET.109.2100384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, S. &amp; Lei, X. Collaborative cache-aided relaying networks: Performance evaluation and system optimization. <i>IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun.</i><b>41</b>(3), 706&#x2013;719 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSAC.2023.3234693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y. et al. Ultra-massive MIMO channel measurements at 5.3 GHz and a general 6G channel model. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>(1), 20&#x2013;34 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3205896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C. et al. Dynamic offloading for multiuser muti-CAP MEC networks: A deep reinforcement learning approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>70</b>(3), 2922&#x2013;2927 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2021.3058995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;ckel, T., Meyer, P., Korf, F. &amp; Schmidt, T. C. Secure time-sensitive software-defined networking in vehicles. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>(1), 35&#x2013;51 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3202368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang, O., Hofbauer, C., Feger, R. &amp; Huemer, M. Range-division multiplexing for MIMO-OFDM joint radar and communications. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>(1), 52&#x2013;65 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3203205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, D. et al. Active device detection and performance analysis of massive non-orthogonal transmissions in cellular internet of things. <i>Sci. China Inf. Sci.</i><b>65</b>(8), 1&#x2013;18 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11432-021-3328-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, A. &amp; Shrestha, R. Low computational-complexity soms-algorithm and high-throughput decoder architecture for QC-LDPC codes. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>(1), 66&#x2013;80 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3203802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, X., He, D., Khan, M. K., Wu, W. &amp; Choo, K. R. An efficient blockchain-based conditional privacy-preserving authentication protocol for VANETs. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>(1), 81&#x2013;92 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3204582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahim, M., Kaddoum, G. &amp; Do, T. N. Joint devices and IRSs association for Terahertz communications in industrial IoT networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Green Commun. Netw.</i><b>8</b>(1), 375&#x2013;390 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGCN.2023.3332571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, S., Shen, C. &amp; Chen, X. Design and analysis of uplink and downlink communications for federated learning. <i>IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun.</i><b>39</b>(7), 2150&#x2013;2167 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSAC.2020.3041388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pejoski, S., Poposka, M. &amp; Hadzi-Velkov, Z. Optimized scheduling transmissions for wireless powered federated learning networks. <i>IEEE Commun. Lett.</i><b>29</b>(3), 640&#x2013;644 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LCOMM.2025.3539543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alishahi, M. et al. Latency minimization for STAR-RIS-aided federated learning networks with wireless power transfer. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>12</b>(7), 8508&#x2013;8522 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3502222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, X., Ye, M. &amp; Du, B. Robust asymmetric heterogeneous federated learning with corrupted clients. <i>IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell.</i><b>47</b>(4), 2693&#x2013;2705 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2025.3527137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40031060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. et al. Stabilizing and accelerating federated learning on heterogeneous data with partial client participation. <i>IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell.</i><b>47</b>(1), 67&#x2013;83 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2024.3469188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39325608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. et al. A credible and fair federated learning framework based on blockchain. <i>IEEE Trans. Artif. Intell.</i><b>6</b>(2), 301&#x2013;316 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAI.2024.3355362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Dong, N., Sun, J., Knottenbelt, W. &amp; Guo, Y. zkFL: Zero-knowledge proof-based gradient aggregation for federated learning. <i>IEEE Trans. Big Data</i><b>11</b>(2), 447&#x2013;460 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBDATA.2024.3403370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. et al. Towards optimal customized architecture for heterogeneous federated learning with contrastive cloud-edge model decoupling. <i>IEEE Trans. Comput.</i><b>74</b>(4), 1123&#x2013;1137 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TC.2024.3514302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhinakaran, D., Srinivasan, L., Sankar, S. M. U. &amp; Selvaraj, D. Quantum-based privacy-preserving techniques for secure and trustworthy Internet of medical Things an extensive analysis. <i>Quantum Inf. Comput.</i><b>24</b>(3 &amp;4), 227&#x2013;266 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhinakaran, D., Kumar, N. J., Ponnuviji, N. P. &amp; Kumar, B. P. Safeguarding confidentiality and privacy in cloud-enabled healthcare systems with spectrasafe encryption and dynamic k-anonymity algorithm. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>279</b>, 127584 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2025.127584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhinakaran, D., Srinivasan, L., Selvaraj, D. &amp; Anish, T. A novel privacy preservation of healthcare data with information entropy-based multi-scheme fully homomorphic encryption and rivest shamir adleman techniques. <i>Biomed. Eng. Appl. Basis Commun.</i> 2450060 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhinakaran, D., Ramani, R., E. R. S., &amp; Selvaraj, D. Enhancing clinical data security with the contextual polynomial-based data protection model (CPDPM). <i>Biomed. Signal Process. Control.</i><b>111</b>, 108329 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhinakaran, D., Prabaharan, G., Valarmathi, K., Sankar, S. M. U. &amp; Sugumar, R. Safeguarding privacy by utilizing SC-DlDA algorithm in cloud-enabled multi party computation. <i>KSII Trans. Internet Inf. Syst.</i><b>19</b>(2), 635&#x2013;656 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A. &amp; Chandrakar, P. Blockchain-driven trust evaluation and secure key agreement protocol for rotating savings and credit association. <i>Int. J. Inf. Technol.</i> 1&#x2013;20 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A., Chandrakar, P., Kumari, S. &amp; Chen, C. Finsec: A consortium blockchain-enabled privacy-preserving and scalable framework for customer data protection in fintech. <i>Peer Peer Netw. Appl.</i><b>18</b>(3), 131 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12083-025-01955-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A. &amp; Chandrakar, P. Truchit: A blockchain-based trusted chit fund system with creditworthiness evaluation. <i>Proc. Comput. Sci.</i><b>235</b>, 1376&#x2013;1385 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2024.04.129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, H., Lin, X., Li, S., Peng, H. &amp; Zhang, B. Global or local adaptation? Client-sampled federated meta-learning for personalized IoT intrusion detection. <i>IEEE Trans. Inf. Forensics Secur.</i><b>20</b>, 279&#x2013;293 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIFS.2024.3516548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, X., Sun, H., Liu, S., Guo, J. &amp; Zheng, H. Federated meta-learning on graph for traffic flow prediction. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>73</b>(12), 19&#xa0;526&#x2013;19&#xa0;538 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang, T. et al. Semantic-aware pseudo-labeling for unsupervised meta-learning. <i>IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell.</i><b>47</b>(7), 5475&#x2013;5488 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2025.3556378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40168195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son, J., Lee, S. &amp; Kim, G. When meta-learning meets online and continual learning: A survey. <i>IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell.</i><b>47</b>(1), 413&#x2013;432 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2024.3463709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39292581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Task augmentation-based meta-learning segmentation method for retinopathy. <i>IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell.</i><b>47</b>(10), 8583&#x2013;8597 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2025.3579271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40504712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, Q., Liu, Z., Yu, H., Liang, X. &amp; Fang, Y. Autonomous landing of the quadrotor on the mobile platform via meta reinforcement learning. <i>IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng.</i><b>22</b>, 2269&#x2013;2280 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2024.3377810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q., You, L., Qu, H., Abdelmoniem, A. M. &amp; Yuen, C. AFML: An asynchronous federated meta-learning mechanism for charging station occupancy prediction with biased and isolated data. <i>IEEE Trans. Big Data</i><b>11</b>(4), 1772&#x2013;1786 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBDATA.2024.3484651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepahi, A., Cai, L., Yang, W. &amp; Pan, J. Livestream Meta-DAMS: Multipath scheduler using hybrid meta reinforcement learning for live video streaming. <i>IEEE Trans. Cogn. Commun. Netw.</i><b>11</b>(4), 2739&#x2013;2754 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCCN.2024.3502512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, K. et al. Meta-learning empowered graph neural networks for radio resource management. <i>IEEE Trans. Commun.</i><b>73</b>(9), 7584&#x2013;7598 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2025.3552302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khisa, S., Elhattab, M., Assi, C. &amp; Sharafeddine, S. Optimizing multi-user uplink cooperative rate-splitting multiple access: Efficient user pairing and resource allocation with gradient-based meta learning. <i>IEEE Trans. Commun.</i><b>73</b>(9), 7366&#x2013;7380 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2025.3550371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh, J., Adepu, S., Junejo, K. N. &amp; Mathur, A. A dataset to support research in the design of secure water treatment systems. <i>Lect. Notes Comput. Sci.</i><b>10242</b>, 88&#x2013;99 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-71368-7_8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>