<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41617769</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2948-1570</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NPP - digital psychiatry and neuroscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>NPP Digit Psychiatry Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A probabilistic deep learning approach for choroid plexus segmentation in autism spectrum disorder.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s44277-026-00056-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The choroid plexus serves as the primary barrier between the brain's blood and cerebrospinal fluid and mediates neuroimmune function. A subset of individuals with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) may exhibit morphological alterations of the choroid plexus. However, to power larger population analyses, an automated tool capable of accurately segmenting the choroid plexus based on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is needed. Automated Segmentation of CHOroid PLEXus (ASCHOPLEX) is a deep learning tool that enables finetuning using new, patient-specific, training data, allowing its usage across cohorts for which the model was not originally trained. We evaluated ASCHOPLEX's generalizability to individuals with ASD by performing finetuning on a local dataset of ASD and control (CON) participants. To assess generalizability, we implemented a probabilistic version of the algorithm, which allowed us to quantify the uncertainty in choroid plexus segmentation and evaluate the model's confidence. ASCHOPLEX generalized well to our local dataset, in which all participants were adults. To further assess its performance, we tested the algorithm on the Autism Brain Imaging Data Exchange (ABIDE) dataset, which includes data from children and adults. While ASCHOPLEX performed well in adults, its accuracy declined in children, suggesting limited generalizability to different age groups without additional finetuning. Our findings show that the incorporation of a probabilistic approach during finetuning can strengthen the use of this deep learning tool by providing confidence metrics which allow assessing model reliability. Overall, our findings demonstrate that ASCHOPLEX can generate accurate choroid plexus segmentations in previously unseen data.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Bargagna</LastName><ForeName>Filippo</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A.A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Ingegneria dell'Informazione, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bioengineering Unit, Fondazione Toscana Gabriele Monasterio, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Morin</LastName><ForeName>Thomas M</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4120-0669</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A.A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Brandeis University, Waltham, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Chin</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A.A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lurie Center for Autism, Massachusetts General Hospital, Lexington, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lila</LastName><ForeName>Ylind</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A.A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, University Hospital Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tseng</LastName><ForeName>Chieh-En J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0592-335X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A.A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santarelli</LastName><ForeName>Maria F</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNR Institute of Clinical Physiology, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vanello</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dipartimento di Ingegneria dell'Informazione, University of Pisa, Pisa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDougle</LastName><ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lurie Center for Autism, Massachusetts General Hospital, Lexington, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hooker</LastName><ForeName>Jacob M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A.A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lurie Center for Autism, Massachusetts General Hospital, Lexington, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Z&#xfc;rcher</LastName><ForeName>Nicole R</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>A.A. Martinos Center for Biomedical Imaging, Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. nzurcherwimmer@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lurie Center for Autism, Massachusetts General Hospital, Lexington, MA, USA. nzurcherwimmer@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>NPP Digit Psychiatry Neurosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918843683806676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2948-1570</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>The choroid plexus plays an important role in brain health and immunity and may be altered in autism spectrum disorder (ASD). To analyze large imaging datasets, a method to automatically delineate this structure is needed. We adapted an existing artificial intelligence tool, ASCHOPLEX, for use in individuals with ASD and made it probabilistic to probe the confidence of its automated segmentations. The results show that ASCHOPLEX can generate accurate choroid plexus segmentations in ASD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare the following financial interests and personal relationships: TMM is a paid consultant for Rocket Science Health. CJM is a paid consultant for Acadia Pharmaceuticals and receives royalty payments from Oxford University Press and Springer Publishing. JMH is co-founder of and equity holder in Eikonizo Therapeutics and Sensorium Therapeutics, where he also serves as CEO. He is an advisor to Rocket Science Health, Human Health, Delix Therapeutics and Psy Therapeutics. All other authors have nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41617769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12858829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44277-026-00056-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s44277-026-00056-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bitanihirwe BKY, Lizano P, Woo TUW. Deconstructing the functional neuroanatomy of the choroid plexus: an ontogenetic perspective for studying neurodevelopmental and neuropsychiatric disorders. Mol Psychiatry. 2022;27:3573&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-022-01623-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9133821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35618887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J, Shipley FB, Shannon ML, Alturkistani O, Dani N, Webb MD, et al. Inflammation of the embryonic choroid plexus barrier following maternal immune activation. Dev Cell. 2020;55:617&#x2013;628.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.devcel.2020.09.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kertser A, Baruch K, Deczkowska A, Weiner A, Croese T, Kenigsbuch M, et al. Corticosteroid signaling at the brain-immune interface impedes coping with severe psychological stress. Sci Adv. 2019;5:eaav4111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.aav4111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6541460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31149632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunis G, Baruch K, Rosenzweig N, Kertser A, Miller O, Berkutzki T, et al. IFN-&#x3b3;-dependent activation of the brain&#x2019;s choroid plexus for CNS immune surveillance and repair. Brain. 2013;136:3427&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awt259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24088808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rau A, Gonzalez-Escamilla G, Schroeter N, Othman A, Dressing A, Weiller C, et al. Inflammation-Triggered enlargement of choroid plexus in subacute COVID-19 patients with neurological symptoms. Ann Neurol. 2024;96:715&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.27016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38934493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Althubaity N, Schubert J, Martins D, Yousaf T, Nettis MA, Mondelli V, et al. Choroid plexus enlargement is associated with neuroinflammation and reduction of blood brain barrier permeability in depression. NeuroImage: Clin. 2022;33:102926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2021.102926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34972034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baruch K, Deczkowska A, David E, Castellano JM, Miller O, Kertser A, et al. Aging. Aging-induced type I interferon signaling at the choroid plexus negatively affects brain function. Science. 2014;346:89&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1252945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4869326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25147279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner G, Gajwani R, Gross J, Gumley A, Timmerman RH, Taylor R, et al. Choroid plexus morphology in schizophrenia and early-stage psychosis: a cross-sectional study. Schizophrenia Res. 2025;275:107&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2024.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39693679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleischer V, Gonzalez-Escamilla G, Ciolac D, Albrecht P, K&#xfc;ry P, Gruchot J, et al. Translational value of choroid plexus imaging for tracking neuroinflammation in mice and humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2021;118:e2025000118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2025000118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8433504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34479997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gi&#xe3;o T, Teixeira T, Almeida MR, Cardoso I. Choroid plexus in alzheimer&#x2019;s disease&#x2014;the current state of knowledge. Biomedicines. 2022;10:224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomedicines10020224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8869376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm J, Hansen SI, H&#xf8;ier-Madsen M, Bostad L. High-affinity folate binding in human choroid plexus. Characterization of radioligand binding, immunoreactivity, molecular heterogeneity and hydrophobic domain of the binding protein. Biochem J. 1991;280:267&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/bj2800267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1130630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1660267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizano P, Lutz O, Ling G, Lee AM, Eum S, Bishop JR, et al. Choroid plexus enlargement is associated with cognitive, inflammatory and structural phenotypes across the psychosis spectrum. Am J Psychiatry. 2019;176:564&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2019.18070825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6676480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31164007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller J, Sinnecker T, Wendebourg MJ, Schl&#xe4;ger R, Kuhle J, Sch&#xe4;delin S, et al. Choroid plexus volume in multiple sclerosis vs neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2022;9:e1147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000001147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8883575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35217580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricigliano VAG, Louapre C, Poirion E, Colombi A, Yazdan Panah A, Lazzarotto A, et al. Imaging characteristics of choroid plexuses in presymptomatic multiple sclerosis: a retrospective study. Neurol - Neuroimmunology Neuroinflammation. 2022;9:e200026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000200026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9562043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Lorenzo S, Konings J, van der Pol S, Kamermans A, Amor S, van Horssen J, et al. Inflammation of the choroid plexus in progressive multiple sclerosis: accumulation of granulocytes and T cells. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2020;8:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-020-0885-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6998074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32014066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt-Mengin M, Ricigliano VAG, Bodini B, Morena E, Colombi A, Hamzaoui M, et al. Axial multi-layer perceptron architecture for automatic segmentation of choroid plexus in multiple sclerosis. In: Medical Imaging 2022: Image Processing. 2022:6. 10.1117/12.2612912</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadayon E, Moret B, Sprugnoli G, Monti L, Pascual-Leone A, Santarnecchi E, et al. Improving choroid plexus segmentation in the healthy and diseased brain: relevance for Tau-PET imaging in dementia. J Alzheimer&#x2019;s Dis. 2020;74:1057&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-190706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32144979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdan-Panah A, Schmidt-Mengin M, Ricigliano VAG, Soulier T, Stankoff B, Colliot O. Automatic segmentation of the choroid plexuses: method and validation in controls and patients with multiple sclerosis. Neuroimage Clin. 2023;38:103368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nicl.2023.103368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10011049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36913908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaddad A, Desrosiers C, Toews M. Multi-scale radiomic analysis of sub-cortical regions in MRI related to autism, gender and age. Sci Rep. 2017;7:45639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep45639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5374503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28361913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levman J, Vasung L, MacDonald P, Rowley S, Stewart N, Lim A, et al. Regional volumetric abnormalities in pediatric autism revealed by structural magnetic resonance imaging. Int J Developmental Neurosci. 2018;71:34&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijdevneu.2018.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30110650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lila Y, Tseng CJ, Johnston EG, Canales C, McDougle CJ, Hooker JM, et al. Choroid plexus alterations in autism spectrum disorder: a PET-MRI study. Brain, Behavior, Immun. 2025;130:106110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2025.106110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40957533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDougle CJ, Landino SM, Vahabzadeh A, O'Rourke J, Zurcher NR, Finger BC, et al. Toward an immune-mediated subtype of autism spectrum disorder. Brain Res. 2015;1617:72&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2014.09.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25445995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisma JJ, McKnight CD, Hett K, Elenberger J, Han CJ, Song AK, et al. Deep learning segmentation of the choroid plexus from structural magnetic resonance imaging (MRI): validation and normative ranges across the adult lifespan. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2024;21:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12987-024-00525-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10903155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38424598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischl B. FreeSurfer. NeuroImage. 2012;62:774&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2012.01.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3685476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22248573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visani V, Veronese M, Pizzini FB, Colombi A, Natale V, Marjin C, et al. <i>ASCHOPLEX: A Generalizable Approach for the Automatic Segmentation of Choroid Plexus</i>. Preprints. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39326265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdar M, Pourpanah F, Hussain S, Rezazadegan D, Liu L, Ghavamzadeh M, et al. A review of uncertainty quantification in deep learning: techniques, applications and challenges. Inf Fusion. 2021;76:243&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2021.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng CJ, Canales C, Marcus RE, Parmar AJ, Hightower BG, Mullett JE, et al. In vivo translocator protein in females with autism spectrum disorder: a pilot study. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2024;49:1193&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-024-01859-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11109261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38615126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng CEJ, Guma E, McDougle CJ, Hooker JM, Z&#xfc;rcher NR. Regional skull translocator protein elevation in autistic adults detected by PET-MRI. Brain, Behavior, Immun. 2025;126:70&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2025.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39904469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z&#xfc;rcher NR, Loggia ML, Mullett JE, Tseng C, Bhanot A, Richey L, et al. [11C]PBR28 MR-PET imaging reveals lower regional brain expression of translocator protein (TSPO) in young adult males with autism spectrum disorder. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26:1659&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-020-0682-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8159742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32076115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders. 5th ed.; 2013. Accessed January 22, 2025. 10.1176/appi.books.9780890425596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Martino A, Yan CG, Li Q, Denio E, Castellanos FX, Alaerts K, et al. The autism brain imaging data exchange: towards a large-scale evaluation of the intrinsic brain architecture in autism. Mol Psychiatry. 2014;19:659&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2013.78</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4162310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23774715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Martino A, O'connor D, Chen B, Alaerts K, Anderson JS, Assaf M, et al. Enhancing studies of the connectome in autism using the autism brain imaging data exchange II. Sci Data. 2017;4:170010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sdata.2017.10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28291247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava N, Hinton G, Krizhevsky A, Sutskever I, Salakhutdinov R. Dropout: a simple way to prevent neural networks from overfitting. J Mach Learn Res. 2014;15:1929&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gal Y, Ghahramani Z. Dropout as a bayesian approximation: representing model uncertainty in deep learning. In: Proceedings of The 33rd International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR48; 2016:1050-9. Accessed January 22, 2025. https://proceedings.mlr.press/v48/gal16.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall A, Gal Y. What Uncertainties Do We Need in Bayesian Deep Learning for Computer Vision? In: Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems. Vol 30. Curran Associates, Inc.; 2017. Accessed March 12, 2025. https://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2017/hash/2650d6089a6d640c5e85b2b88265dc2b-Abstract.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucs&#xe1;nyi B, Kirchhof M, Oh SJ. Benchmarking uncertainty disentanglement: specialized uncertainties for specialized tasks. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2024;37:50972&#x2013;1038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha AA, Hanbury A. Metrics for evaluating 3D medical image segmentation: analysis, selection, and tool. BMC Med Imaging. 2015;15:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12880-015-0068-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4533825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26263899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhn M, Johnson K. Over-Fitting and Model Tuning. In: Kuhn M, Johnson K, eds. Applied Predictive Modeling. Springer; 2013:61-92. 10.1007/978-1-4614-6849-3_4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethlehem R, Seidlitz J, White SR, Vogel JW, Anderson KM, Adamson C, et al. Brain charts for the human lifespan. Nature. 2022;604:525&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-022-04554-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35388223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannai D, Cao Y, Keshavan M, Reuter M, Lizano P. Manual segmentation of the human choroid plexus using brain MRI. J Vis Exp. 2023. 10.3791/65341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/65341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38163279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>