<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41875021</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relationship Between Exercise Training-Induced Changes in Oxygen Uptake Kinetics and the Power-Duration Relationship.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003991</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to determine the relationships between training-induced changes in the variable values of the power-duration relationship (CP and W') and those of pulmonary oxygen uptake (V&#x307;O2) kinetics (the fundamental phase time constant; &#x3c4;VO2, and the slow component amplitude; V&#x307;O2sc).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eleven healthy untrained males underwent 2 weeks of severe-intensity exercise training. Before and after training, V&#x307;O2max was assessed via an incremental exercise test on a cycle ergometer, CP and W' were assessed via constant power determination trials, and V&#x307;O2 kinetics were assessed during exercise at a PO 10% above CP (post-training at the same absolute and relative intensity as pre-training). A previously described and validated computer model of the human skeletal muscle bioenergetic system was used to provide further insight into training-induced changes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">CP and &#x3c4;VO2were strongly inversely correlated before and after training, and their training-induced changes were also correlated. Computer simulations suggested that increased oxidative phosphorylation activity (kOX) was the main factor determining the training-induced changes in CP and &#x3c4;VO2. Exercise training increased W' and reduced the amplitude of the V&#x307;O2sc, however, the training-induced changes in W' and the V&#x307;O2sc were not correlated. Model simulations suggested that variations in kOX, the accessible phosphate (+creatine) pool (Pacc), and the peak inorganic phosphate (Pi) concentrations attained prior to task failure (Pipeak) could explain the observed training-induced alterations in W' and the V&#x307;O2sc.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The present study suggests that the bioenergetic mechanisms underpinning CP and &#x3c4;VO2are similar, whereas the relationship between W' and the V&#x307;O2sc appears somewhat more complex.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Tze-Huan</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Hubei Normal University, Huangshi, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vos</LastName><ForeName>Luuk</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering and Physics, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, THE NETHERLANDS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>I-Lin</ForeName><Initials>IL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Hubei Normal University, Huangshi, CHINA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koga</LastName><ForeName>Shunsaku</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Physiology Laboratory, Kobe Design University, Kobe, JAPAN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marwood</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Liverpool Hope University, Liverpool, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korzeniewski</LastName><ForeName>Bernard</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BioSimulation Center, Krakow, POLAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goulding</LastName><ForeName>Richie P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Sciences, Faculty of Behavioral and Movement Sciences, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, Amsterdam Movement Sciences, Amsterdam, THE NETHERLANDS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COMPUTER MODEL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CRITICAL POWER</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EXERCISE BIOENERGETICS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OXYGEN UPTAKE KINETICS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">POWER-DURATION RELATIONSHIP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">W'</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest and Funding Source: RPG was supported by Nederlandse Organisatie voor Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek Award Number: https://doi.org/10.61686/CTDKS25250 and De Nederlandse organisatie voor gezondheidsonderzoek en zorginnovatie Award Number: 10091012410013. Acknowledgements: The authors thank the participants for their efforts during this study. RPG was supported by Nederlandse Organisatie voor Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek Award Number: https://doi.org/10.61686/CTDKS25250 and De Nederlandse organisatie voor gezondheidsonderzoek en zorginnovatie Award Number: 10091012410013. THL and RPG contributed to conceptualization and design. THL and ILW were responsible for data collection. THL, RPG, LV, ILW, SK, SM and BK were responsible for data analysis, interpretation and drafting of the article. All authors reviewed the article and provided critical feedback. All authors approved the final manuscript. There are no conflicts of interest to report. The results of this study are presented clearly, honestly, and without fabrication, falsification, or inappropriate data manipulation. The results of the present study do not constitute endorsement by the American College of Sports Medicine. The data are available upon request.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41875021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-990000000-01031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>