<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41656237</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction is associated with increased corticospinal excitability and rate of force development.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01577-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">After anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, asymmetries in central activation are suspected to prevent complete functional recovery. This cross-sectional study investigated the motor function of both lower limbs in ACLR patients using morphological, mechanical, and neurophysiological measures after surgical repair with a semitendinosus-gracilis graft.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ten male patients (age 20-31 years; 6/4 right/left knee surgery; 6-12 months after ACLR) were recruited. Muscle trophism was quantified through ultrasound estimates of quadriceps volume and mid-thigh circumference; knee extensors' rate of force development (RFD), maximum torque and voluntary activation (interpolated twitch technique, ITT) were assessed through dynamometry during maximal isometric effort; spinal excitability was measured with the Soleus H-reflex; transcranial magnetic stimulation was used to assess corticospinal excitability (resting motor threshold (rMT) and recruitment curve of motor evoked potentials (MEP) during submaximal contraction) and intracortical excitability (short-interval intracortical inhibition (SICI)) of the Vastus medialis (VM) and Tibialis anterior (TA) muscles.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The quadriceps muscle on the operated side showed significant volume loss (mean [SD] of 2264.6 [345.1] cm&#xb3; and 2082.9 [386.2] cm&#xb3; for the non-operated and operated sides, respectively; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.035) and mid-thigh circumference (52.2 [2.7] cm and 50.2 [3.3] cm; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.035). In the VM recruitment curves, the increase in MEP amplitude with increasing stimulation intensity was steeper on the operated side (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001). The operated limb also showed a higher RFD (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.026). No inter-limb differences were found for the remaining outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The steeper rise of knee extensor torque, paralleled by an increased corticospinal excitability of the operated side VM muscle, suggests that an increased drive from the motor cortex is needed to engage the quadriceps in fast contractions following ACLR. This may represent a compensatory phenomenon aimed at counteracting the decline in muscle power associated with reduced muscle mass and altered quadriceps morphology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov NCT04837417 (submitted On 2021-03-31).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scarano</LastName><ForeName>Stefano</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation Sciences, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Ospedale San Luca, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caronni</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation Sciences, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Ospedale San Luca, Milan, Italy. a.caronni@auxologico.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, University of Milan, Milan, Italy. a.caronni@auxologico.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menon</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Laboratory of Applied Biomechanics, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical and Community Sciences, Graduate School of Health Statistics and Biometrics, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rota</LastName><ForeName>Viviana</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation Sciences, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Ospedale San Luca, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amadei</LastName><ForeName>Maurizio</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation Sciences, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Ospedale San Luca, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perucca</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation Sciences, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Ospedale San Luca, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brevi</LastName><ForeName>Elena</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maione</LastName><ForeName>Alessio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>U.O.C. 1&#xb0; Clinica Ortopedica, ASST Gaetano Pini-CTO, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrua</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>U.O.C. 1&#xb0; Clinica Ortopedica, ASST Gaetano Pini-CTO, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tesio</LastName><ForeName>Luigi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation Sciences, IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Ospedale San Luca, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Randelli</LastName><ForeName>Pietro Simone</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>U.O.C. 1&#xb0; Clinica Ortopedica, ASST Gaetano Pini-CTO, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>REsearch Center for Adult and Pediatric Rheumatic Diseases (RECAP-RD), Department of Biomedical Sciences for Health, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano, Via Mangiagalli 31, Milan, 20133, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04837417</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACL reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Joint torque</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-invasive brain stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps hypotrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial magnetic stimulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the Ethical Committee of the IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano and by the Comitato Etico Milano Area 2. The studies were conducted in accordance with the local legislation and institutional requirements. The participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41656237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12983487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01577-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01577-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mather RC, Koenig L, Kocher MS, Dall TM, Gallo P, Scott DJ, et al. Societal and economic impact of anterior cruciate ligament tears. J Bone Joint Surg. 2013;95(19):1751&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.L.01705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24088967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zantop T, Herbort M, Raschke MJ, Fu FH, Petersen W. The role of the anteromedial and posterolateral bundles of the anterior cruciate ligament in anterior tibial translation and internal rotation. Am J Sports Med. 2007;35(2):223&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546506294571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17158275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay SR, Grindem H. Evidence-based recommendations for the management of anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) rupture. Best practice and research: clinical rheumatology. Volume 33. Bailliere Tindall Ltd; 2019. p. 33&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1016/j.berh.2019.01.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31431274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekhar A, Pilar A, Ponnanna KM, Tapasvi S. ACL repair for athletes? J Orthop. 2022;31:61&#x2013;6. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35464814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9018522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35464814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic M, Indelli PF, Lovrekovic B, Volcarenghi J, Juric D, Hakam HT et al. Graft Selection in Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Comprehensive Review of Current Trends. Medicina (Kaunas). 2024;60(12). Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/39768969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11678177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39768969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flanigan DC, Everhart JS, Pedroza A, Smith T, Kaeding CC. Fear of reinjury (Kinesiophobia) and persistent knee symptoms are common factors for lack of return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc - J Arthroscopic Relat Surg. 2013;29(8):1322&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2013.05.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23906272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Jurgensmeier K, Lamba A, Yang L, Hevesi M, Camp CL et al. Posttraumatic Arthritis After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury: Machine Learning Comparison Between Surgery and Nonoperative Management. Am J Sports Med. 2025;53(5):1050&#x2013;60. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/40079334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40079334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LJ, Zeng N, Yan ZP, Li JT, Ni GX. Post-traumatic osteoarthritis following ACL injury. Arthritis Research and Therapy. Volume 22. BioMed Central Ltd.; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rips L, Koovit T, Luik M, Saar H, Kuik R, Kartus JT et al. In the medium term, more than half of males report kinesiophobia after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J ISAKOS. 2024 Oct;9(5):100309. doi: 10.1016/j.jisako.2024.100309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39159822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullock GS, Sell TC, Zarega R, Reiter C, King V, Wrona H, et al. Kinesiophobia, knee Self-Efficacy, and fear avoidance beliefs in people with ACL injury: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Medicine. Volume 52. Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH; 2022. p. 3001&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35963980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster KE, Feller JA, Lambros C. Development and preliminary validation of a scale to measure the psychological impact of returning to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery. Phys Ther Sport. 2008;9(1):9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2007.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JH, Eun SP, Park DH, Kwak HB, Chang E. The effects of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction on individual quadriceps muscle thickness and Circulating biomarkers. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019 Dec 4;16(24):4895. doi: 10.3390/ijerph16244895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6950292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Grooms DR, Burland JP, Davi SM, Kinsella-Shaw JM, Lepley LK. Quadriceps muscle function following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: systemic differences in neural and morphological characteristics. Exp Brain Res. 2019;237(5):1267&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-019-05499-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30852644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisee C, Lepley AS, Birchmeier T, O&#x2019;Hagan K, Kuenze C. Quadriceps Strength and Volitional Activation After Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Sports Health. 2019;11(2):163&#x2013;79. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30638441</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30638441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart HF, Culvenor AG, Collins NJ, Ackland DC, Cowan SM, Machotka Z, et al. Knee kinematics and joint moments during gait following anterior cruciate ligament econstruction: A systematic review and meta-analysis. British Journal of Sports Medicine. Volume 50. BMJ Publishing Group; 2016. p. 597&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26265562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins AJ, Grandhi RK, Schneider DK, Stanfield D, Webster KE, Myer GD. Risk of secondary injury in younger athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. American Journal of Sports Medicine. Volume 44. SAGE Publications Inc.; 2016. p. 1861&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5501245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26772611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingenen B, Gokeler A. Optimization of the Return-to-Sport paradigm after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A critical step back to move forward. Sports Medicine. Volume 47. Springer International Publishing; 2017. p. 1487&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapreli E, Athanasopoulos S. The anterior cruciate ligament deficiency as a model of brain plasticity. Med Hypotheses. 2006;67(3):645&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2006.01.063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16698187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valeriani M, Restuccia D, Di Lazzaro V, Franceschi F, Fabbriciani C, Tonali P. Central nervous system modifications in patients with lesion of the anterior cruciate ligament of the knee. Brain. 1996;119 (Pt 5):1751&#x2013;62. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8931595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8931595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JL, Glaviano NR, Norte GE. Assessment of quadriceps corticomotor and Spinal-Reflexive excitability in individuals with a history of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A systematic review and Meta-analysis. Sports Medicine. Volume 51. Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH; 2021. p. 961&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33400217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez KM, Palmieri-Smith RM, Krishnan C. How does anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction affect the functioning of the brain and spinal cord? A systematic review with meta-analysis. Journal of Sport and Health Science. Volume 10. Elsevier B.V.; 2021. p. 172&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32707098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turpeinen JT, Freitas TT, Rubio-Arias J&#xc1;, Jordan MJ, Aagaard P. Contractile rate of force development after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction&#x2014;a comprehensive review and meta-analysis. Vol. 30, Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports. Blackwell Munksgaard; 2020. p. 1572&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32478931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Brito Santana MV, Baptista AF. Corticospinal and intracortical excitability in individuals with anterior cruciate ligament injury and ligament reconstruction: a meta-analysis. Physiother Theory Pract. 2025;41(3):664&#x2013;81. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/39992686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39992686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal MD, Moore JH, Stoneman PD, DeBerardino TM. Neuromuscular excitability changes in the Vastus medialis following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 2009;49(1):43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19280799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Gribble PA, Thomas AC, Tevald MA, Sohn DH, Pietrosimone BG. Quadriceps neural alterations in anterior cruciate ligament reconstructed patients: A 6-month longitudinal investigation. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(6):828&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25693627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrosimone BG, Lepley AS, Ericksen HM, Clements A, Sohn DH, Gribble PA. Neural excitability alterations after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2015;50(6):665&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-50.1.11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4527451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25844855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luc-Harkey BA, Harkey MS, Pamukoff DN, Kim RH, Royal TK, Blackburn JT, et al. Greater intracortical Inhibition associates with lower quadriceps voluntary activation in individuals with ACL reconstruction. Exp Brain Res. 2017;235(4):1129&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-017-4877-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28144695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheurer SA, Sherman DA, Glaviano NR, Ingersoll CD, Norte GE. Corticomotor function is associated with quadriceps rate of torque development in individuals with ACL surgery. Exp Brain Res. 2020;238(2):283&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-019-05713-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31897518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarzycki R, Morton SM, Charalambous CC, Pietrosimone B, Williams GN, Snyder-Mackler L. Athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction demonstrate asymmetric intracortical facilitation early after surgery. J Orthop Res. 2021;39(1):147&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.24666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32181907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Ericksen HM, Sohn DH, Pietrosimone BG. Contributions of neural excitability and voluntary activation to quadriceps muscle strength following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Knee. 2014;21(3):736&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2014.02.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24618459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenze CM, Hertel J, Weltman A, Diduch D, Saliba SA, Hart JM. Persistent neuromuscular and corticomotor quadriceps asymmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Athl Train. 2015;50(3):303&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-49.5.06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4477927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25622244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarzycki R, Morton SM, Charalambous CC, Marmon A, Snyder-Mackler L. Corticospinal and intracortical excitability differ between athletes early after ACLR and matched controls. J Orthop Res. 2018;36(11):2941&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.24062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29846002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lepley AS, Ly MT, Grooms DR, Kinsella-Shaw JM, Lepley LK. Corticospinal tract structure and excitability in patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: A DTI and TMS study. Neuroimage Clin. 2020;25:102157. doi: 10.1016/j.nicl.2019.102157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6948362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31901791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanbancha A, Tretriluxana J, Limroongreungrat W, Sinsurin K. Decreased supraspinal control and neuromuscular function controlling the ankle joint in athletes with chronic ankle instability. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(9):2041&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-019-04191-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31321512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhmann R, Trajano GS, Kerr GK, Shield AJ. Increased short interval intracortical Inhibition in participants with previous hamstring strain injury. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2022;122(2):357&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04839-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34729636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollerbach MJ, Flash T. Dynamic interactions between limb segments during planar arm movement. Biol Cybern. 1982;44(1):67&#x2013;77. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/7093370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7093370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obr&#x119;bska P, Skubich J, Piszczatowski S. Gender differences in the knee joint loadings during gait. Gait Posture. 2020;79:195&#x2013;202. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32438266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32438266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerrigan DC, Todd MK, Della Croce U. Gender differences in joint biomechanics during walking: normative study in young adults. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 1998;77(1):2&#x2013;7. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/9482373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9482373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malinzak RA, Colby SM, Kirkendall DT, Yu B, Garrett WE. A comparison of knee joint motion patterns between men and women in selected athletic tasks. Clin Biomech (Bristol, Avon). 2001;16(5):438&#x2013;45. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11390052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11390052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddara R, Harandi VJ, Lee PVS. Anterior cruciate ligament agonist and antagonist muscle force differences between males and females during perturbed walking. J Biomech. 2020;110:109971. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32827793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32827793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancino F, Gabr A, Plastow R, Haddad FS. Anterior cruciate ligament injuries in female athletes. Bone Joint J. 2023;105&#x2013;B(10):1033&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.105B10.BJJ-2023-0881.R1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37777208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung A, Kantak S, Hammoud S, Abraham R, Zarzycki R. Sex differences in corticospinal excitability and quadriceps performance after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Res. 2024;42(4):769&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.25725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10978293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37938095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaunat M, Fayard JM, Sonnery-Cottet B. Hamstring tendons or bone-patellar tendon-bone graft for anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Volume 105. Orthopaedics and Traumatology: Surgery and Research. Elsevier Masson SAS; 2019. pp. S89&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30130660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataoka K, Hoshino Y, Nukuto K. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: recent evolution and technical improvement. J Joint Surg Res. 2023;1(1):97&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jjoisr.2023.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sollberger VD, Korthaus A, Barg A, Pagenstert G. Long-term results after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using patellar tendon versus hamstring tendon autograft with a minimum follow-up of 10 years&#x2014;a systematic review. Archives of Orthopaedic and Trauma Surgery. Volume 143. Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH; 2023. p. 4277&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10293370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36441213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartigan EH, Axe MJ, Snyder-Mackler L. Time line for noncopers to pass return-to-sports criteria after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2010;40(3):141&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2010.3168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3613129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawasreh Z, Logerstedt D, Cummer K, Axe MJ, Risberg MA, Snyder-Mackler L. Do patients failing Return-to-Activity criteria at 6 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction continue demonstrating deficits at 2 years? Am J Sports Med. 2017;45(5):1037&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546516680619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5376235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28125899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J. Arthroscopic Release of Severe Flexion- and Extension-Impeding Knee Stiffness With Inaccessible Joint. Arthrosc Tech. 2021;10(12):e2753&#x2013;65. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35004158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8719267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35004158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tegner Y, Lysholm J. Rating systems in the evaluation of knee ligament injuries. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1985;(198):43&#x2013;9. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/4028566</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4028566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arangio GA, Chen C, Kalady M, Reed JF. Thigh muscle size and strength after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and rehabilitation. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1997;26(5):238&#x2013;43. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/9353686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9353686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birchmeier T, Lisee C, Kane K, Brazier B, Triplett A, Kuenze C. Quadriceps muscle size following ACL injury and reconstruction: A systematic review. J Orthop Res. 2020;38(3):598&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.24489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31608490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyatani M, Kanehisa H, Ito M, Kawakami Y, Eukunaga T. The accuracy of volume estimates using ultrasound muscle thickness measurements in different muscle groups. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;91(2&#x2013;3):264&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14569399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catino L, Malloggi C, Scarano S, Cerina V, Rota V, Tesio L. Quadriceps activation during maximal isometric and isokinetic contractions: the minimal real difference and its implications. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2021;29(3):277&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-203241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan C, Theuerkauf P. Effect of knee angle on quadriceps strength and activation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2015;119(3):223&#x2013;31. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25997949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4526702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25997949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malloggi C, Catino L, Rota V, Scarano S, Tesio L. Measuring voluntary activation of the quadriceps femoris during isokinetic concentric contractions. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2019;27(2):125&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/IES-182224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Place N, Maffiuletti NA, Martin A, Lepers R. Assessment of the reliability of central and peripheral fatigue after sustained maximal voluntary contraction of the quadriceps muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2007;35(4):486&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.20714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17221875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kufel TJ, Pineda LA, Jeffery Mador M. Comparison of potentiated and unpotentiated twitches as an index of muscle fatigue. Muscle Nerve. 2002;25(3):438&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.10047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11870723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert RD, Gandevia SC. Twitch interpolation in human muscles: mechanisms and implications for measurement of voluntary activation. J Neurophysiol]. 1999;82(5):2271&#x2013;83. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/10561405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10561405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelozzi M, Madama M, Corsica C, Calvisi V, Properzi G, McCaw ST, et al. Rate of force development as an adjunctive outcome measure for return-to-sport decisions after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(9):772&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.3780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahaly R, Vandewalle H, Driss T, Monod H. Maximal voluntary force and rate of force development in humans - Importance of instruction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;85(3&#x2013;4):345&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210100451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11560090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe5;lberg E, van Dijk H, Falck B, Kimura J, Neuwirth C, Pitt M, et al. Standards for quantification of EMG and neurography. Clinical Neurophysiology. Volume 130. Elsevier Ireland Ltd; 2019. p. 1688&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31213353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumbhare D, Robinson L, Buschbacher R. Buschbacher&#x2019;s manual of nerve conduction studies. Third edition. Demos Medical Publishing, LLC.; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crone C, Krarup C. Neurophysiological approach to disorders of peripheral nerve. Handb Clin Neurol. 2013;115:81&#x2013;114. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23931776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23931776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binder-Macleod BI, Buchanan TS. Tibialis anterior volumes and areas in ACL-injured limbs compared with unimpaired. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(9):1553&#x2013;7. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16960514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devanne H, Lavoie BA, Capaday C. Input-output properties and gain changes in the human corticospinal pathway. Exp Brain Res. 1997;114(2):329&#x2013;38. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/9166922</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9166922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemlin C, Moulton E, Leder S, Houot M, Meunier S, Rosso C et al. Redundancy Among Parameters Describing the Input-Output Relation of Motor Evoked Potentials in Healthy Subjects and Stroke Patients. Front Neurol. 2019;10(MAY):535. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31178817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31178817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih Y, Powers CM, Fisher BE. Reliability of a method to assess corticomotor excitability of lower limb muscles using a normalized EMG motor thresholding procedure. Sci Rep. 2024 Jan 24;14(1):2052. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-51622-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38267437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher BE, Lee YY, Pitsch EA, Moore B, Southam A, Faw TD, et al. Method for assessing brain changes associated with gluteus Maximus activation. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2013;43(4):214&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2013.4188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23485621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesar TM, Stinear JW, Wolf SL. The use of transcranial magnetic stimulation to evaluate cortical excitability of lower limb musculature: challenges and opportunities. Restorative Neurology and Neuroscience. Volume 36. IOS; 2018. pp. 333&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6106786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29758954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kujirai T, Caramia MD, Rothwell JC, Day BL, Thompson PD, Ferbert A et al. Corticocortical inhibition in human motor cortex. J Physiol]. 1993;471:501&#x2013;19. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8120818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1143973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8120818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez MA, Lungholt BKS, Nyborg K, Nielsen JB. Motor skill training induces changes in the excitability of the leg cortical area in healthy humans. Exp Brain Res. 2004;159(2):197&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-004-1947-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15549279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RJ, Nakamura Y, Bestmann S, Rothwell JC, Bostock H. Two phases of intracortical Inhibition revealed by transcranial magnetic threshold tracking. Exp Brain Res. 2002;143(2):240&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-001-0988-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daikuya S, Ono A, Suzuki T, Yabe K. Silent period and H reflex from soleus muscle as an index in a neuro-muscular function after reconstruction of anterior cruciate ligament. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 2009;49(4):177&#x2013;86. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19534296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19534296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri RM, Ingersoll CD, Hoffman MA. The hoffmann reflex: methodologic considerations and applications for use in sports medicine and athletic training research. J Athl Train. 2004;39(3):268&#x2013;77. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16558683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC522151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White MS, Graham MC, Janatova T, Hawk GS, Thompson KL, Noehren B. Effect of Sampling Rate, Filtering, and Torque Onset Detection on Quadriceps Rate of Torque Development and Torque Steadiness. Sensors (Basel)]. 2024;24(13). Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/39001029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11243863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39001029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayfur B, Keneen Johnson A, Palmieri-Smith R. Changes in quadriceps rate of torque development after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and association to Single-Leg hop distance. Sports Health. 2024;16(5):808&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381231205295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11346242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37873996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Horne S, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Aagaard P. Effect of contraction mode of slow-speed resistance training on the maximum rate of force development in the human quadriceps. Muscle Nerve. 2008;38(3):1133&#x2013;1046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.21021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18642358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen JB, Farup J, Lind M, Dalgas U. Muscle strength and functional performance is markedly impaired at the recommended time point for sport return after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in recreational athletes. Hum Mov Sci. 2015;39:73&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2014.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Buckthorpe MW, Hannah R. Human capacity for explosive force production: neural and contractile determinants. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(6):894&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25754620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebaugh JL, Mccray PD. Defining the linear portion of a sigmoid-shaped curve: bend points. Pharmaceut Statist. 2003;2:167&#x2013;74. Available from: https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/pst.62</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer PC, Madhavan S. Characterization of stimulus response curves obtained with transcranial magnetic stimulation from bilateral tibialis anterior muscles post stroke. Neurosci Lett. 2019;713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7226675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31585209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conover WJ. On Methods of Handling Ties in the Wilcoxon Signed-Rank Test. J Am Stat Assoc. 1973;68(344):985. Available from: https://www.jstor.org/stable/2284536?origin=crossref</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritz CO, Morris PE, Richler JJ. Effect size estimates: current use, calculations, and interpretation. J Exp Psychol Gen. 2012;141(1):2&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0024338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21823805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julian J. Faraway. Extending the Linear Model with R Generalized Linear, Mixed Effects and Nonparametric Regression Models. Second Edition. New York: Chapman and Hall/CRC; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown VA. An Introduction to Linear Mixed-Effects Modeling in R. Adv Methods Pract Psychol Sci. 2021;4(1). Available from: https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/2515245920960351</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesio L, Caronni A, Russo C, Felisari G, Banco E, Simone A et al. Reversed Mirror Therapy (REMIT) after Stroke-A Proof-of-Concept Study. Brain Sci. 2023;13(6):847. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/37371327. cited 2023 Jun 21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10296617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37371327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y. Controlling the False Discovery Rate: A Practical and Powerful Approach to Multiple Testing. J R Stat Soc Series B Stat Methodol. 1995;57(1):289&#x2013;300. Available from: https://academic.oup.com/jrsssb/article/57/1/289/7035855</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SY, Feng Z, Yi X. A general introduction to adjustment for multiple comparisons. J Thorac Dis. 2017;9(6):1725&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jtd.2017.05.34</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28740688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and environment for statistical computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wobbrock JO, Findlater L, Gergle D, Higgins JJ. The aligned rank transform for nonparametric factorial analyses using only anova procedures. In: Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. New York, NY, USA: ACM; 2011. pp. 143&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox J, Weisberg S. Visualizing Fit and Lack of Fit in Complex Regression Models with Predictor Effect Plots and Partial Residuals. J Stat Softw. 2018;87(9). Available from: http://www.jstatsoft.org/v87/i09/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konishi Y, Ikeda K, Nishino A, Sunaga M, Aihara Y, Fukubayashi T. Relationship between quadriceps femoris muscle volume and muscle torque after anterior cruciate ligament repair. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2007;17(6):656&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2006.00619.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17331086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendias CL, Lynch EB, Davis ME, Sibilsky Enselman ER, Harning JA, Dewolf PD, et al. Changes in Circulating biomarkers of muscle atrophy, inflammation, and cartilage turnover in patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and rehabilitation. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41(8):1819&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546513490651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4086614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23739685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri-Smith P RM, Thomas AC, Wojtys EM. Maximizing quadriceps strength after ACL reconstruction. Clin Sports Med. 2008;27:405&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csm.2008.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18503875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh SG, Ahn A, Davi SM, Lepley LK, Kwon OS. Quadriceps muscle atrophy after non-invasive anterior cruciate ligament injury: evidence linking to autophagy and mitophagy. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1341723. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/38496299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10940348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38496299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White MS, Ogier AC, Chenevert TL, Zucker E, Stoneback L, Michel CP, et al. Beyond weakness: exploring intramuscular fat and quadriceps atrophy in ACLR recovery. J Orthop Res. 2024;42(11):2485&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.25910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38824275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas AC, Wojtys EM, Brandon C, Palmieri-Smith RM. Muscle atrophy contributes to quadriceps weakness after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19(1):7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2014.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4500756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25683732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White MS, Mancini LM, Stoneback L, Palmieri-Smith RM, Lepley LK. Chronic adaptions in quadriceps fascicle mechanics are related to altered knee biomechanics after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Appl Biomech. 2024;40(4):346&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jab.2023-0252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39013455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbach D, Awiszus F. Impaired ability of voluntary quadriceps activation bilaterally interferes with function testing after knee injuries. A twitch interpolation study. Int J Sports Med. 2002;23(4):231&#x2013;6. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12015621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12015621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urbach D, Nebelung W, Becker R, Awiszus F. Effects of reconstruction of the anterior cruciate ligament on voluntary activation of quadriceps femoris a prospective twitch interpolation study. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2001;83(8):1104&#x2013;10. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11764420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11764420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams GN, Buchanan TS, Barrance PJ, Axe MJ, Snyder-Mackler L. Quadriceps weakness, atrophy, and activation failure in predicted noncopers after anterior cruciate ligament injury. Am J Sports Med. 2005;33(3):402&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546504268042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15716256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarkou A, Stackhouse S, Binder-Macleod SA, Lee SCK. Comparison of techniques to determine human skeletal muscle voluntary activation. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2017;36:8&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2017.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28649011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush JL, Norte GE, Lepley AS. Limb differences in hamstring muscle function and morphology after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Phys Ther Sport. 2020;45:168&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32781270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkj&#xe6;r T, Simonsen EB, Magnusson SP, Dyhre-Poulsen P, Aagaard P. Antagonist muscle moment is increased in ACL deficient subjects during maximal dynamic knee extension. Knee. 2012;19(5):633&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2011.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22284964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakavas G, Malliaropoulos N, Pruna R, Traster D, Bikos G, Maffulli N. Neuroplasticity and Anterior Cruciate Ligament Injury. Indian J Orthop]. 2020;54(3):275&#x2013;80. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32399146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7205971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32399146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S, Pearce AJ, Pietrosimone B, Bennell K, Clark R, Bryant AL. Neuromuscular deficits after peripheral joint injury: A neurophysiological hypothesis. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51(3):327&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.24463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25255714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criss CR, Lepley AS, Onate JA, Clark BC, Simon JE, France CR et al. Brain activity associated with quadriceps strength deficits after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Sci Rep. 2023 May 17;13(1):8043. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-34260-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10192374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37198275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallett M. Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation: A Primer. Vol. 55, Neuron. 2007. p. 187&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17640522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward SH, Pearce A, Bennell KL, Peitrosimone B, Bryant AL. Quadriceps cortical adaptations in individuals with an anterior cruciate ligament injury. Knee. 2016;23(4):582&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2016.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27162116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>On AY, Uluda&#x11f; B, Ta&#x15f;kiran E, Ertekin C. Differential corticomotor control of a muscle adjacent to a painful joint. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2004;18(3):127&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0888439004269030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15375272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapreli E, Athanasopoulos S, Gliatis J, Papathanasiou M, Peeters R, Strimpakos N, et al. Anterior cruciate ligament deficiency causes brain plasticity: A functional MRI study. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37(12):2419&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546509343201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19940314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grooms DR, Page SJ, Nichols-Larsen DS, Chaudhari AMW, White SE, Onate JA. Neuroplasticity associated with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47(3):180&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.7003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27817301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando R, Saito A, Umemura Y, Akima H. Local architecture of the Vastus intermedius is a better predictor of knee extension force than that of the other quadriceps femoris muscle heads. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2015;35(5):376&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24915999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammann C, Guida P, Caballero-Insaurriaga J, Pineda-Pardo JA, Oliviero A, Foffani G. A framework to assess the impact of number of trials on the amplitude of motor evoked potentials. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33293541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling WG, Wolf SL, Butler AJ. Variability of motor potentials evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation depends on muscle activation. Exp Brain Res. 2006;174(2):376&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-006-0468-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3582032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16636787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldissera F, Campadelli P, Cavallari P, Piccinelli L, Tesio L. How motoneurones control velocity of tension development. Journal of Physiology. Volume 598. Blackwell Publishing Ltd; 2020. pp. 1109&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32010982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldissera F, Campadelli P. How motoneurones control development of muscle tension. Nature. 1977;268(5616):146&#x2013;7. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/593307</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">593307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldissera F, Campadelli P, Tesio L. Frequency coding of input signal transients in alpha motoneurones of cat. Brain Res. 1979;160(1):155&#x2013;8. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/758220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">758220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace B, Janz J. Implications of Motor Unit Activity on Ballistic Movement. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2009;4(2):285&#x2013;92. Available from: https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1260/174795409788549490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2002;93(4):1318&#x2013;26. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12235031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noehren B, Andersen A, Hardy P, Johnson DL, Ireland ML, Thompson KL, et al. Cellular and morphological alterations in the Vastus lateralis muscle as the result of ACL injury and reconstruction. J Bone Joint Surg - Am Volume. 2016;98(18):1541&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.16.00035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5026157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27655981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medler S. Mixing it up: the biological significance of hybrid skeletal muscle fibers. Journal of Experimental Biology. Volume 22. Company of Biologists Ltd; 2019. p. 1OBITUARY.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31784473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming JD, Ritzmann R, Centner C. Effect of an anterior cruciate ligament rupture on knee proprioception within 2 years after Conservative and operative treatment: A systematic review with Meta-Analysis. Sports Medicine. Volume 52. Springer Science and Business Media Deutschland GmbH; 2022. p. 1091&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9023382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34854058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. Methodological issues with the interpolated twitch technique. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2007;17(3):317&#x2013;27. Available from: https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1050641106000691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16798011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madrid A, Madinabeitia-Mancebo E, Robles-Garc&#xed;a V, Chouza-Insua M, Cudeiro J, Arias P. Effect of stimulation timing on testing voluntary muscle force generation. Heliyon. 2020;6(10):e05179. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33088951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7560577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33088951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maganaris CN, Reeves ND, Rittweger J, Sargeant AJ, Jones DA, Gerrits K, et al. Adaptive response of human tendon to paralysis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33(1):85&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.20441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16216011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansfield CJ, Culiver A, Briggs M, Schmitt LC, Grooms DR, O&#xf1;ate J. The effects of knee osteoarthritis on neural activity during a motor task: A scoping systematic review. Gait and Posture. Volume 96. Elsevier B.V.; 2022. p. 221&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35700640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;roux ME, Tremblay F. Corticomotor excitability associated with unilateral knee dysfunction secondary to anterior cruciate ligament injury. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2006;14(9):823&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-006-0063-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16502299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tohidirad Z, Ehsani F, Bagheri R, Jaberzadeh S. Priming effects of anodal transcranial direct current stimulation on the effects of conventional physiotherapy on balance and muscle performance in athletes with anterior cruciate ligament injury. J Sport Rehabil. 2023;32(3):315&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36623509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>