<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41792148</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Elucidating activity-stability trade-offs in nano-fingerprint carbon anchoring single atoms and clusters in oxygen reduction reaction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70446-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hybrid sites (M<sub>1+x</sub>) that incorporate single atoms (M<sub>1</sub>) with clusters (M<sub>x</sub>) hold great potential for overcoming linear scaling relations in electrocatalysis, but spatial decoupling of M<sub>1</sub> from M<sub>x</sub> fundamentally hampers intercomponent synergy. Here, we report a composite electrocatalyst (Zn<sub>1</sub>Fe<sub>1+x</sub>/f-NC) featuring Fe<sub>x</sub> clusters encapsulated within nano-fingerprint carbon layers and surrounded by densely dispersed Fe/Zn-N<sub>4</sub> atomic sites. Decoupling experiments revealed that Fe<sub>1</sub>/Zn<sub>1</sub> atomic sites mainly initiate catalytic activity, while Fe<sub>x</sub> clusters further boost intrinsic activity, whereas nano-fingerprint carbon facilitates the confinement and stabilization of M<sub>1+x</sub>. The Zn<sub>1</sub>Fe<sub>1+x</sub>/f-NC demonstrates competitive oxygen reduction reaction performance, achieving a half-wave potential of 0.93&#x2009;V and stability over 50&#x2009;h. Zinc-air batteries with Zn<sub>1</sub>Fe<sub>1+x</sub>/f-NC air cathode exhibit a peak power density of 263.82&#x2009;mW&#xb7;cm<sup>-2</sup> and robust stability exceeding 2200&#x2009;h at 10&#x2009;mA&#x2009;cm<sup>-2</sup>. Density functional theory calculations reveal that the atomic Zn sites, Fe<sub>x</sub> clusters and nano-fingerprint carbon layers jointly enhance the catalytic activity and stability by modulating the electronic structure of Fe-N<sub>4</sub> sites and optimizing the adsorption energy of the key intermediate, especially OH*.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Qikang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Shanshan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Beijing Key Laboratory for Optical Materials and Photonic Devices, Capital Normal University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yongning</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dou</LastName><ForeName>Sixin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Yanyang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1913-6173</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Biopharmaceutical Preparation and Delivery, Institute of Process Engineering, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Haidian District, Beijing, P. R. China. chenchang25@ipe.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yuquan Road, Beijing, P. R. China. chenchang25@ipe.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Wenming</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0501-7066</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Beijing Key Laboratory for Optical Materials and Photonic Devices, Capital Normal University, Beijing, China. swm@mail.sdu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4347-0235</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Basic Discipline Research Center for Clean Energy and Catalysis, Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, China. chenzh07@mail.ahnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22505267</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41792148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70446-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70446-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q. et al. Covalent organic framework&#x2013;based porous ionomers for high-performance fuel cells. Science 378, 181&#x2013;186 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, D. et al. Active sites of nitrogen-doped carbon materials for oxygen reduction reaction clarified using model catalysts. Science 351, 361&#x2013;365 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J.-W. et al. Pseudo-adsorption and long-range redox coupling during oxygen reduction reaction on single atom electrocatalyst. Nat. Commun. 13, 1734 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, J. et al. Carbon-based single atom catalysts for tailoring the ORR pathway: a concise review. J. Mater. Chem. A 9, 24803&#x2013;24829 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suen, N.-T. et al. Electrocatalysis for the oxygen evolution reaction: recent development and future perspectives. Chem. Soc. Rev. 46, 337&#x2013;365 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn, C.-Y. et al. Differences in the electrochemical performance of Pt-based catalysts used for polymer electrolyte membrane fuel cells in liquid half- and full-cells. Chem. Rev. 121, 15075&#x2013;15140 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, J. et al. A review on fundamentals for designing oxygen evolution electrocatalysts. Chem. Soc. Rev. 49, 2196&#x2013;2214 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. A theory-guided x-ray absorption spectroscopy approach for identifying active sites in atomically dispersed transition-metal catalysts. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 143, 20144&#x2013;20156 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, F. et al. Site-density engineering of single-atomic iron catalysts for high-performance proton exchange membrane fuel cells. Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 302, 120860 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehmood, A. et al. High loading of single atomic iron sites in Fe&#x2013;NC oxygen reduction catalysts for proton exchange membrane fuel cells. Nat. Catal. 5, 311&#x2013;323 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. Hydrogenation of levulinic acid into gamma-valerolactone over in situ reduced CuAg bimetallic catalyst: Strategy and mechanism of preventing Cu leaching. Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 232, 1&#x2013;10 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, G. et al. Highly dispersed Ru clusters toward an efficient and durable hydrogen oxidation reaction. Chem. Commun. 58, 11839&#x2013;11842 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, S. et al. Chemical synthesis of single atomic site catalysts. Chem. Rev. 120, 11900&#x2013;11955 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. Recent developments of microenvironment engineering of single-atom catalysts for oxygen reduction toward desired activity and selectivity. Adv. Funct. Mater. 31, 2103857 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, L. et al. Atomically dispersed iron with densely exposed active sites as bifunctional oxygen catalysts for zinc&#x2013;air flow batteries. Small 18, 2105387 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H. et al. Carbon-supported catalysts with atomically dispersed metal sites for oxygen electroreduction: present and future perspectives. J. Mater. Chem. A 9, 15919&#x2013;15936 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, K. M. et al. Insight into the mechanism of axial ligands regulating the catalytic activity of Fe&#x2013;N4 sites for oxygen reduction reaction. Adv. Energy Mater. 12, 2103588 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, J. et al. Insights into the determining effect of carbon support properties on anchoring active sites in Fe&#x2013;N&#x2013;C catalysts toward the oxygen reduction reaction. ACS Cat. 12, 1601&#x2013;1613 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao, Z. et al. Effective approaches for designing stable M-N<sub>x</sub>/C oxygen-reduction catalysts for proton-exchange-membrane fuel cells. Adv. Mater. 34, 2200595 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. Enhanced oxygen reduction with single-atomic-site iron catalysts for a zinc-air battery and hydrogen-air fuel cell. Nat. Commun. 9, 5422 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. Optimizing microenvironment of asymmetric N,S-coordinated single-atom Fe via axial fifth coordination toward efficient oxygen electroreduction. Small 18, 2105387 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramaswamy, N., Tylus, U., Jia, Q. &amp; Mukerjee, S. Activity descriptor identification for oxygen reduction on nonprecious electrocatalysts: linking surface science to coordination chemistry. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 135, 15443&#x2013;15449 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, Y. et al. Tailoring the d-orbital splitting manner of single atomic sites for enhanced oxygen reduction. Adv. Mater. 35, 2210757 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. Mesoporous nitrogen-doped graphitized carbon for recyclable oxidation of cyclohexene. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 5, 11723&#x2013;11730 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, H. et al. High durability of Fe-N-C single-atom catalysts with carbon vacancies toward the oxygen reduction reaction in alkaline media. Adv. Mater. 35, 2210714 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. et al. Single-atom copper catalyst for the S-arylation reaction to produce diaryl disulfides. Chem. Sci. 14, 4620&#x2013;4626 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, Y. &amp; Chen, S. Electrocatalysts based on metal@carbon core@shell nanocomposites: an overview. Green. Energy Environ. 3, 335&#x2013;351 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, S. A. et al. Thermal synthesis of FeNi@nitrogen-doped graphene dispersed on nitrogen-doped carbon matrix as an excellent electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction. ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 2, 4075&#x2013;4083 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Yu, M. &amp; Feng, X. Electronic structure regulation of noble metal-free materials toward alkaline oxygen electrocatalysis. eScience 3, 100141 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, L. et al. Assembling molybdenum-doped platinum clusters into a coral-like nanostructure for highly enhanced oxygen reduction. eScience 4, 100187 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan, R., Song, Y., Ma, C. &amp; Shi, J. In situ growth of N-doped carbon nanotubes in Fe-N<sub>x</sub>/Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>-encapsulated carbon sheets for efficient bifunctional oxygen catalysis. Appl. Catal. B: Environ. 327, 122443 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, G. et al. Iron carbide allured lithium metal storage in carbon nanotube cavities. Energy Storage Mater. 36, 459&#x2013;465 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, D. et al. Enhanced oxygen evolution catalyzed by in situ formed Fe-doped Ni oxyhydroxides in carbon nanotubes. J. Mater. Chem. A 10, 16007&#x2013;16015 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. Synergetic function of the single-atom Ru&#x2013;N<sub>4</sub> site and ru nanoparticles for hydrogen production in a wide pH range and seawater electrolysis. ACS Appl. Mater. Inter. 14, 15250&#x2013;15258 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, Z. et al. Understanding the inter-site distance effect in single-atom catalysts for oxygen electroreduction. Nat. Cat. 4, 615&#x2013;622 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. et al. Combining Fe nanoparticles and pyrrole-type Fe-N<sub>4</sub> sites on less-oxygenated carbon supports for electrochemical CO<sub>2</sub> reduction. Nat. Commun. 14, 5108 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, X. et al. Iron atom&#x2013;cluster interactions increase activity and improve durability in Fe&#x2013;N&#x2013;C fuel cells. Nat. Commun. 13, 2963 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zitolo, A. et al. Identification of catalytic sites for oxygen reduction in iron- and nitrogen-doped graphene materials. Nat. Mater. 14, 937&#x2013;942 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. et al. Atomically dispersed iron sites with a nitrogen&#x2013;carbon coating as highly active and durable oxygen reduction catalysts for fuel cells. Nat. Energy 7, 652&#x2013;663 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, Y. et al. Unraveling the electronic structure and dynamics of the atomically dispersed iron sites in electrochemical CO<sub>2</sub> reduction. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 145, 15600&#x2013;15610 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. et al. Acidic oxygen reduction by single-atom Fe catalysts on curved supports. Nature 644, 668&#x2013;675 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, S. et al. Dual-ligand and hard-soft-acid-base strategies to optimize metal-organic framework nanocrystals for stable electrochemical cycling performance. Nati. Sci. Rev. 9, nwab197 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, X. et al. Confining iodine into metal-organic framework derived metal-nitrogen-carbon for long-life aqueous zinc-iodine batteries. Adv. Mater. 36, 1408317 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, Y. et al. Thiosalicylic-acid-mediated coordination structure of nickel center via thermodynamic modulation for aqueous Ni-Zn batteries. Adv. Mater. 36, 2406094 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, Y. et al. Regulating intramolecular electron transfer of nickel-based coordinations through ligand engineering for aqueous batteries. Adv. Mater. 35, 2307003 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, L. J. et al. d-orbital electron delocalization realized by axial Fe<sub>4</sub>C atomic clusters delivers high-performance Fe-N-C catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction. Adv. Mater. 35, 2305945 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng J., Zhang Z., Sun W. Curvature effects regulate the oxygen evolution reaction performance of M-NC single-atom site catalysts: a theoretical study. Preprint ChemRxiv. https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2025-s1xjc (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dronskowski, R. &amp; Bloechl, P. E. Crystal orbital Hamilton populations (COHP): energy-resolved visualization of chemical bonding in solids based on density-functional calculations. J. Phys. Chem. 97, 8617&#x2013;8624 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson, R. et al. LOBSTER: Local orbital projections, atomic charges, and chemical-bonding analysis from projector-augmented-wave-based density-functional theory. J. Comput. Chem. 41, 1931&#x2013;1940 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, W., Bu, Y. &amp; Wang, Y. Interaction between glycine/glycine radicals and intrinsic/boron-doped (8, 0) single-walled carbon nanotubes: a density functional theory study. J. Phys. Chem. B 112, 15442 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, W., Bu, Y. &amp; Wang, Y. On the binding strength sequence for nucleic acid bases and C<sub>60</sub> with density functional and dispersion-corrected density functional theories: whether C<sub>60</sub> could protect nucleic acid bases from radiation-induced damage. J. Phys. Chem. C. 115, 3220 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q. et al. Tailoring the surface curvature of the supporting carbon to tune the d-band center of Fe-N-C single-atom catalysts for zinc-urea-air. Batteries. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e202422920 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Strain regulation of bond length in single Ru sites via curving support surface for enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction. Appl. Catal. B: Environ. Energy 353, 124088 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Anchoring Fe species on the highly curved surface of S and N co-doped carbonaceous nanosprings for oxygen electrocatalysis and a flexible zinc-air battery. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 63, e202313034 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, G. et al. Regulating Fe-spin state by atomically dispersed Mn-N in Fe-N-C catalysts with high oxygen reduction activity. Nat. Commun. 12, 1734 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C. et al. Regulating electronic structure of CoN<sub>4</sub> with axial Co-S for promoting oxygen reduction and Zn-air battery performance. Nano Res 16, 4211&#x2013;4218 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M. et al. A &#x201c;pre-constrained metal twins&#x201d; strategy to prepare efficient dual-metal-atom catalysts for cooperative oxygen electrocatalysis. Adv. Mater. 34, 2107421 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, X. et al. Long-range interconnected nanoporous Co/Ni/C composites as bifunctional electrocatalysts for long-life rechargeable zinc-air batteries. Electrochim. Acta 413, 140183 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, Y., Lei, H., Wang, S., Wang, Z. &amp; Mai, W. Pt/Zn heterostructure as efficient air-electrocatalyst for long-life neutral Zn-air batteries. Chin. J. Catal. 42, 1451&#x2013;1458 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, H.-L., Tan, A.-D., Hu, S.-Z., Piao, J.-H. &amp; Fu, Z.-Y. Efficient spinel iron-cobalt oxide/nitrogen-doped ordered mesoporous carbon catalyst for rechargeable zinc-air batteries. Chin. J. Catal. 42, 1451&#x2013;1458 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, L. et al. Cobalt-doped basic iron phosphate as bifunctional electrocatalyst for long-life and high-power-density rechargeable zinc-air batteries. Appl. Catal. B-Environ. 300, 120712 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B. et al. Space-confined yolk-shell construction of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> nanoparticles inside N-doped hollow mesoporous carbon spheres as bifunctional electrocatalysts for long-term rechargeable Zinc&#x2013;Air batteries. Adv. Funct. Mater. 30, 2005834 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C. et al. Engineering the multiscale structure of bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for highly efficient and ultrastable zinc-air battery. Energy Storage Mater. 24, 402&#x2013;411 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C. et al. Engineering molecular heterostructured catalyst for oxygen reduction reaction. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 145, 21273&#x2013;21283 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, L. et al. A rechargeable calcium&#x2013;oxygen battery that operates at room temperature. Nature 626, 313&#x2013;318 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, W. et al. A rechargeable zinc-air battery based on zinc peroxide chemistry. Science 371, 46&#x2013;51 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funke, H., Scheinost, A. C. &amp; Chukalina, M. Wavelet analysis of extended x-ray absorption fine structure data. Phys. Rev. B 71, 094110 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longa, S. D., Arcovito, A., Girasole, M., Hazemann, J. L. &amp; Benfatto, M. Quantitative analysis of x-ray absorption near edge structure data by a full multiple scattering procedure: the Fe-CO geometry in photolyzed carbonmonoxy-myoglobin single crystal. Phys. Rev. Lett. 87, 155501 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, P. et al. Atomically dispersed manganese on biochar derived from a hyperaccumulator for photocatalysis in organic pollution remediation. Environ. Sci. Technol. 56, 8034&#x2013;8042 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannozzi, P. et al. QUANTUM ESPRESSO: a modular and open-source software project for quantum simulations of materials. J. Phys. Condens. Matter 21, 395502 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannozzi, P. et al. Advanced capabilities for materials modelling with quantum ESPRESSO. J. Phys. Condens. Matter 29, 465901 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdew, J. P. et al. Restoring the density-gradient expansion for exchange in solids and surfaces. Phys. Rev. Lett. 100, 136406 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdew, J. P., Burke, K. &amp; Ernzerhof, M. Generalized gradient approximation made simple. Phys. Rev. Lett. 77, 3865 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prandini, G., Marrazzo, A., Castelli, I. E., Mounet, N. &amp; Marzari, N. Precision and efficiency in solid-state pseudopotential calculations. Npj Comput. Mater. 4, 72 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lejaeghere, K. et al. Reproducibility in density functional theory calculations of solids. Science 351, aad3000 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzari, N. et al. Thermal contraction and disordering of the Al(110) surface. Phys. Rev. Lett. 82, 3296 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimme, S., Antony, J., Ehrlich, S. &amp; Krieg, H. A consistent and accurate ab initio parameterization of density functional dispersion correction (DFT-D) for the 94 elements H-Pu. J. Chem. Phys. 132, 154104 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudarev, S. L. et al. Electron-energy-loss spectra and the structural stability of nickel oxide: An LSDA&#x2009;+&#x2009;U study. Phys. Rev. B 57, 1505 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paier, J., Penschke, C. &amp; Sauer, J. Oxygen defects and surface chemistry of ceria: quantum chemical studies compared to experiment. Chem. Rev. 113, 3949 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabris, S., de Gironcoli, S., Baroni, S., Vicario, G. &amp; Balducci, G. Taming multiple valency with density functionals: A case study of defective ceria. Phys. Rev. B 71, 041102 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf8;rskov, J. K. et al. Origin of the overpotential for oxygen reduction at a fuel-cell cathode. J. Phys. Chem. B 108, 17886 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xf8;rskov, J. K. et al. Trends in the exchange current for hydrogen evolution. J. Electrochem. Soc. 152, J23 (2005).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>