<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41751669</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-4300</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Entropy (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Entropy (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>GD-DAMNet: Real-Time UAV-Based Overhead Power-Line Presence Recognition Using a Lightweight Knowledge Distillation with Mamba-GhostNet v2 and Dual-Attention.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">166</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/e28020166</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Power-line presence recognition technology for unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) is one of the key research directions in the field of UAV remote sensing. With the rapid development of UAV technology, the application of UAVs in various fields has become increasingly widespread. However, when flying in urban and rural areas, UAVs often face the danger of obstacles such as power lines, posing challenges to flight safety and stability. To address this issue, this study proposes a novel method for presence recognition in UAVs for power lines using an improved GhostNet v2 knowledge distillation dual-attention mechanism convolutional neural network. The construction of a real-time UAV power-line presence recognition system involves three aspects: dataset acquisition, a novel network model, and real-time presence recognition. First, by cleaning, enhancing, and segmenting the power-line data collected by UAVs, a UAV power-line presence recognition image dataset is obtained. Second, through comparative experiments with multi-attention modules, the dual-attention mechanism is selected to construct the CNN, and the UAV real-time power-line presence recognition training is conducted using the SGD optimiser and Hard-Swish activation function. Finally, knowledge distillation is employed to transfer the knowledge from the dual-attention mechanism-based CNN to the nonlinear function and Mamba-enhanced GhostNet v2 network, thereby reducing the model's parameter count and achieving real-time recognition performance suitable for mobile device deployment. Experiments demonstrate that the UAV-based real-time power-line presence recognition method proposed in this paper achieves real-time recognition accuracy rates of over 91.4% across all regions, providing a technical foundation for advancing the development and progress of UAV-based real-time power-line presence recognition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Shuyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering &amp; Technical, Chengdu University of Technology, Leshan 614000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Yingnan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering &amp; Technical, Chengdu University of Technology, Leshan 614000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Gaoping</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mathematics, Southwest Minzu University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yuyan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, Southwest Minzu University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1186-7289</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mathematics, Southwest Minzu University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Jundong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, Southwest Minzu University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yifan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, Southwest Minzu University, Chengdu 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024YFFK0362</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project in Sichuan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24ZYZYTS0226</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project in Sichuan</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024CXTD19</GrantID><Agency>Scientific and Technological Innovation Team for Qinghai-Tibetan Plateau Research in Southwest Minzu University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Entropy (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101243874</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1099-4300</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep neural network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dual-attention mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile devices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">real-time power-line presence recognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41751669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12939282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e28020166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">e28020166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Fan J., Liu Y., Li E., Peng J., Liang Z. A review on state-of-the-art power line inspection techniques. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2020;69:9350&#x2013;9365. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2020.3031194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2020.3031194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huda A.G., Reza A., Hai D. Improved method of pectoral muscle detection based on two straight line fitting algorithm; Proceedings of the 2014 International Conference on Industrial Automation, Information and Communications Technology; Bali, Indonesia. 28&#x2013;30 August 2014; p. 6922088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen V.N., Jenssen R., Roverso D. Automatic autonomous vision-based power line inspection: A review of current status and the potential role of deep learning. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 2018;99:107&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1016/j.ijepes.2017.12.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2017.12.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foudeh H.A., Luk P.C.K., Whidborne J.F. An advanced unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) approach via learning-based control for overhead power line monitoring: A comprehensive review. IEEE Access. 2021;9:130410&#x2013;130433. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3110159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3110159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schofield O.B., Iversen N., Ebeid E. Autonomous power line detection and tracking system using UAVs. Microprocess. Microsyst. 2022;94:104609. doi: 10.1016/j.micpro.2022.104609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.micpro.2022.104609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhassan A.B., Zhang X., Shen H., Xu H. Power transmission line inspection robots: A review, trends and challenges for future research. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 2020;118:105862. doi: 10.1016/j.ijepes.2020.105862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2020.105862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Wang H., Yao R. A Fast Sea-sky Line Detection Method Based on EDLines; Proceedings of the 2021 2nd International Conference on Electronics, Communications and Information Technology (CECIT); Sanya, China. 27&#x2013;29 December 2021; pp. 48&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diniz L.F., Pinto M.F., Melo A.G., Hon&#xf3;rio L.M. Visual-based assistive method for uav power line inspection and landing. J. Intell. Robot. Syst. 2022;106:41. doi: 10.1007/s10846-022-01725-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10846-022-01725-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminifar F., Rahmatian F. Unmanned aerial vehicles in modern power systems: Technologies, use cases, outlooks, and challenges. IEEE Electrif. Mag. 2020;8:107&#x2013;116. doi: 10.1109/MELE.2020.3026505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MELE.2020.3026505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y., Yu X., Yang D., Zhou B. A survey of intelligent transmission line inspection based on unmanned aerial vehicle. Artif. Intell. Rev. 2023;56:173&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1007/s10462-022-10189-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-022-10189-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Gao Q., Xu J., Li D. Advances in Guidance, Navigation and Control: Proceedings of 2020 International Conference on Guidance, Navigation and Control, ICGNC 2020, Tianjin, China, 23&#x2013;25 October 2020. Springer; New York, NY, USA: 2022. A review of UAV power line inspection; pp. 3147&#x2013;3159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan H., Sun X., Su Y., Hu T., Wang H., Wang H., Peng C., Guo Q. UAV-lidar aids automatic intelligent powerline inspection. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 2021;130:106987. doi: 10.1016/j.ijepes.2021.106987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2021.106987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S., Fan Q., Yu W.J., Wang L.T., Ni S., Chen J. Multi-Sensor fusion and data analysis for operating conditions of low power transmission lines. Measurement. 2022;190:110586. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2021.110586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2021.110586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri M.H., Pourgholi M., Hashjin N.M., Ardakani M.K. Monitoring UAV status and detecting insulator faults in transmission lines with a new classifier based on aggregation votes between neural networks by interval type-2 TSK fuzzy system. Soft Comput. 2024;28:12141&#x2013;12174. doi: 10.1007/s00500-024-09913-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00500-024-09913-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Zhang Y., Wu H., Suzuki S., Namiki A., Wang W. Design and application of a UAV autonomous inspection system for high-voltage power transmission lines. Remote Sens. 2023;15:865. doi: 10.3390/rs15030865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15030865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diwan T., Anirudh G., Tembhurne J.V. Object detection using YOLO: Challenges, architectural successors, datasets and applications. Multimed. Tools Appl. 2023;82:9243&#x2013;9275. doi: 10.1007/s11042-022-13644-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-022-13644-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9358372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35968414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L., Chen Z., Wang R., Liu L., Chi H. Yolo-inspection: Defect detection method for power transmission lines based on enhanced YOLOv5s. J. Real-Time Image Process. 2023;20:104. doi: 10.1007/s11554-023-01360-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11554-023-01360-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magdy A., Moustafa M.S., Ebied H.M., Tolba M.F. Lightweight faster R-CNN for object detection in optical remote sensing images. Sci. Rep. 2024;15:16163. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-99242-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-99242-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12064737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40346125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Miao X. Distribution line pole detection and counting based on YOLO using UAV inspection line video. J. Electr. Eng. Technol. 2020;15:441&#x2013;448. doi: 10.1007/s42835-019-00230-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42835-019-00230-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W., Dong Q., Zuo Z. A method combining line detection and semantic segmentation for power line extraction from unmanned aerial vehicle images. Remote Sens. 2022;14:1367. doi: 10.3390/rs14061367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14061367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Wu H., Wang Q., Wang W., Suzuki S., Namiki A. Small UAV Urban Overhead Transmission Line Autonomous Correction Inspection System Based on Radar and RGB Camera. IEEE Sens. J. 2024;24:5593&#x2013;5608. doi: 10.1109/JSEN.2023.3317076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2023.3317076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damodaran S., Shanmugam L., Jothi Swaroopan N. Overhead power line detection from aerial images using segmentation approaches. J. Control. Meas. Electron. Comput. Commun. 2024;65:261&#x2013;288. doi: 10.1080/00051144.2023.2296798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00051144.2023.2296798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao X., Xiang B., Liu Z., Tu S. Simulation analysis and experimental research on the safety distance of UAV inspection on transmission lines. AIP Adv. 2022;12:025009. doi: 10.1063/5.0083674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0083674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Han K., Guo J., Xu C., Xu C., Wang Y. GhostNetv2: Enhance cheap operation with long-range attention. Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst. 2022;35:9969&#x2013;9982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu A., Dao T. Mamba: Linear-time sequence modeling with selective state spaces. arXiv. 2023 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2312.00752.2312.00752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2312.00752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo S., Park J., Lee J.Y., Kweon I.S. Cbam: Convolutional block attention module; Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV); Munich, Germany. 8&#x2013;14 September 2018; pp. 3&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau K.W., Po L.M., Rehman Y.A.U. Large separable kernel attention: Rethinking the large kernel attention design in cnn. Expert Syst. Appl. 2024;236:121352. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2023.121352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.121352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G., Zhang J., Zhang M., Wu R., Cao X., Liu W. Efficient depthwise separable convolution accelerator for classification and UAV object detection. Neurocomputing. 2022;490:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1016/j.neucom.2022.02.071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2022.02.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segu M., Tonioni A., Tombari F. Batch normalization embeddings for deep domain generalization. Pattern Recognit. 2023;135:109115. doi: 10.1016/j.patcog.2022.109115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patcog.2022.109115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong X., Ma Y., Ma A., Hou Z., Zhang M., Zhong Y. HSRoadNet: Hard-swish Activation Function and Improved Squeeze-excitation Module Network for Road Extraction Using Satellite Remote Sensing Imagery. IEEE J. Sel. Top. Appl. Earth Obs. Remote Sens. 2025;18:4907&#x2013;4920. doi: 10.1109/JSTARS.2025.3533196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSTARS.2025.3533196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M.H., Xu T.X., Liu J.J., Liu Z.N., Jiang P.T., Mu T.J., Zhang S.H., Martin R.R., Cheng M.M., Hu S.M. Attention mechanisms in computer vision: A survey. Comput. Vis. Media. 2022;8:331&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1007/s41095-022-0271-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41095-022-0271-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing J., Jinhang C., Zhang H., Zhang W. Boundedness and Convergence of Mini-batch Gradient Method with Cyclic Dropconnect and Penalty. Neural Process. Lett. 2024;56:113. doi: 10.1007/s11063-024-11581-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11063-024-11581-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottou L., Curtis F.E., Nocedal J. Optimization methods for large-scale machine learning. SIAM Rev. 2018;60:223&#x2013;311. doi: 10.1137/16M1080173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1137/16M1080173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dereich S., Graeber R., Jentzen A. Non-convergence of Adam and other adaptive stochastic gradient descent optimization methods for non-vanishing learning rates. arXiv. 20242407.08100</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou J., Yu B., Maybank S.J., Tao D. Knowledge distillation: A survey. Int. J. Comput. Vis. 2021;129:1789&#x2013;1819. doi: 10.1007/s11263-021-01453-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11263-021-01453-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S., Naseer M., Hayat M., Zamir S.W., Khan F.S., Shah M. Transformers in vision: A survey. ACM Comput. Surv. (CSUR) 2022;54:200. doi: 10.1145/3505244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3505244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han K., Wang Y., Tian Q., Guo J., Xu C., Xu C. Ghostnet: More features from cheap operations; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Seattle, WA, USA. 13&#x2013;19 June 2020; pp. 1580&#x2013;1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K., Zhang X., Ren S., Sun J. Deep residual learning for image recognition; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Las Vegas, NV, USA. 27&#x2013;30 June 2016; pp. 770&#x2013;778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng L., Suo H., Li D. Deepfake Video Detection Based on EfficientNet-V2 Network. Comput. Intell. Neurosci. 2022;2022:3441549. doi: 10.1155/2022/3441549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/3441549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9033321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35463269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Xie L., Chai B., Wang Z., Yang H. Spatial-frequency convolutional self-attention network for EEG emotion recognition. Appl. Soft Comput. 2022;122:108740. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2022.108740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2022.108740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>