<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41576048</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2767-3375</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLOS global public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLOS Glob Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the multilevel determinants of low birth weight in Bangladesh: Understanding implications for targeted public health interventions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0005823</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0005823</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0005823</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pgph.0005823</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Low birth weight (LBW), a key indicator of impaired fetal growth, is strongly associated with infant morbidity, mortality, and long-term health problems, particularly in developing countries such as Bangladesh. LBW reflects complex public health challenges shaped by interlinked factors across health, education, and socioeconomic sectors, where low maternal education, limited household income, poor nutrition, inadequate healthcare access, and insufficient antenatal care contribute to adverse birth outcomes. Understanding these multilevel determinants is essential for designing effective public health interventions. This study examined the prevalence and determinants of LBW in Bangladesh while accounting for both individual- and community-level factors using data from the 2022 Bangladesh Demographic and Health Survey. The analysis included 5,342 newborns with recorded birth weights from births occurring within the five years preceding the survey. Birth weight was classified as LBW, defined as less than 2,500 grams, or normal birth weight of at least 2,500 grams. Binary logistic regression was applied to identify associated risk factors, and adjusted odds ratios with 95% confidence intervals were reported using a significance level of p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05. Multilevel logistic regression models were additionally employed to capture community-level variation and improve model fit and predictive performance. The prevalence of LBW was 9.15%, with significant associations observed for administrative division, place of residence, household wealth index, mode of delivery, number of antenatal care visits, and place of delivery. Random-effects estimates showed reduced cluster-level variability across models, with the intraclass correlation coefficient declining from 10.65% to 6.66% and the median odds ratio decreasing from 1.81 to 1.58, indicating improved explanatory power after adjustment. Overall, LBW in Bangladesh is influenced by maternal characteristics, socioeconomic conditions, healthcare utilization, and contextual factors, underscoring the need for targeted interventions that strengthen maternal healthcare services, expand antenatal care coverage, and address socioeconomic disparities to reduce LBW prevalence and related risks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Ali et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Akher</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Data Science, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasan</LastName><ForeName>Md Kamrul</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Data Science, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amin</LastName><ForeName>Ruhul</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-2325-1400</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Data Science, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kabir</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Alamgir</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Data Science, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Junaid</LastName><ForeName>Sheikh Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-6074-3098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics and Data Science, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLOS Glob Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918283779606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2767-3375</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41576048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12829852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0005823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PGPH-D-25-00823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Avwerhota O, Avwerhota M, Daniel E, Popoola T, Popoola I, Ogun A, et al. Bayesian Spatial Analysis of Risk Factors Affecting Low Birth Weight in Nigeria. JFMHC. 2024;10(3):40&#x2013;50. doi: 10.11648/j.jfmhc.20241003.11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11648/j.jfmhc.20241003.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grbic D, Supic ZT, Todorovic J, Nesic D, Karic S, Jurisic A, et al. Factors associated with low birth weight in low-income populations in the Western Balkans: insights from the multiple indicator cluster survey. Front Public Health. 2024;12. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2024.1394060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1394060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11666434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39720813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngwira A, Stanley CC. Determinants of Low Birth Weight in Malawi: Bayesian Geo-Additive Modelling. PLoS One. 2015;10(6):e0130057. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0130057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0130057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4482619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26114866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahumud RA, Sultana M, Sarker AR. Distribution and Determinants of Low Birth Weight in Developing Countries. J Prev Med Public Health. 2017;50(1):18&#x2013;28. doi: 10.3961/jpmph.16.087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3961/jpmph.16.087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5327679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28173687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muchemi OM, Echoka E, Makokha A. Factors associated with low birth weight among neonates born at Olkalou District Hospital, Central Region, Kenya. Pan Afr Med J. 2015;20:108. doi: 10.11604/pamj.2015.20.108.4831</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj.2015.20.108.4831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26090056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballot DE, Chirwa T, Ramdin T, Chirwa L, Mare I, Davies VA, et al. Comparison of morbidity and mortality of very low birth weight infants in a Central Hospital in Johannesburg between 2006/2007 and 2013. BMC Pediatr. 2015;15(1). doi: 10.1186/s12887-015-0337-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-015-0337-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4373031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25885283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manyeh AK, Kukula V, Odonkor G, Ekey RA, Adjei A, Narh-Bana S, et al. Socioeconomic and demographic determinants of birth weight in southern rural Ghana: evidence from Dodowa Health and Demographic Surveillance System. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2016;16(1):160. doi: 10.1186/s12884-016-0956-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-016-0956-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4946169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27417308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hack M, Flannery DJ, Schluchter M, Cartar L, Borawski E, Klein N. Outcomes in young adulthood for very-low-birth-weight infants. N Engl J Med. 2002;346(3):149&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa010856</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa010856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11796848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal P, Garg S, Upadhyay HP. Prevalence of low birth weight babies and its association with socio-cultural and maternal risk factors among the institutional deliveries in Bharatpur, Nepal. Asian J Med Sci. 2018;10(1):77&#x2013;85. doi: 10.3126/ajms.v10i1.21665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/ajms.v10i1.21665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knop MR. Birth Weight and Risk of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus, Cardiovascular Disease, and Hypertension in Adults: A Meta-Analysis of 7 646 267 Participants From 135 Studies,&#x201d; J Am Heart Assoc, vol. 7, no. 23, Dec. 2018. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.118.008870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.118.008870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6405546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30486715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO, UNICEF. Low birthweight estimates. Low birthweight prevalence, by country and region, 2020. https://data.unicef.org/topic/nutrition/low-birthweight/. 2023. 2023 September 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blencowe H, Krasevec J, de Onis M, Black RE, An X, Stevens GA, et al. National, regional, and worldwide estimates of low birthweight in 2015, with trends from 2000: a systematic analysis. Lancet Glob Health. 2019;7(7):e849&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30565-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30565-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6560046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larroque B, Bertrais S, Czernichow P, L&#xe9;ger J. School difficulties in 20-year-olds who were born small for gestational age at term in a regional cohort study. Pediatrics. 2001;108(1):111&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1542/peds.108.1.111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.108.1.111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11433062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risnes KR, Vatten LJ, Baker JL, Jameson K, Sovio U, Kajantie E, et al. Birthweight and mortality in adulthood: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Epidemiol. 2011;40(3):647&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1093/ije/dyq267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyq267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21324938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mediani HS. Predictors of Stunting Among Children Under Five Year of Age in Indonesia: A Scoping Review. GJHS. 2020;12(8):83. doi: 10.5539/gjhs.v12n8p83</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5539/gjhs.v12n8p83</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa P, Poudyal A, Poudel R, Upadhyaya DP, Timalsina A, Bhandari R, et al. Prevalence of low birth weight and its associated factors: Hospital based cross sectional study in Nepal. PLOS Glob Public Health. 2022;2(11):e0001220. doi: 10.1371/journal.pgph.0001220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0001220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10021178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam MJ, Islam MM, Maniruzzaman M, Ahmed NAMF, Tawabunnahar M, Rahman MJ, et al. Socioeconomic inequality in the prevalence of low birth weight and its associated determinants in Bangladesh. PLoS One. 2022;17(10):e0276718. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0276718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0276718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9612499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36301890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam Pollob SMA, Abedin MdM, Islam MdT, Islam MdM, Maniruzzaman Md. Predicting risks of low birth weight in Bangladesh with machine learning. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(5):e0267190. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0267190</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0267190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9135259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35617201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samsury SF, Tengku Ismail TA, Hassan R. Low birth weight infant among teenage pregnancy in Terengganu, Malaysia: A cross-sectional study. Malays Fam Physician. 2022;17(1):44&#x2013;51. doi: 10.51866/oa.59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51866/oa.59</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9004437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35440959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter RM, Billah SM, Lyons GR, Siraj MS, Rahman QS, Thorsten V, et al. U-Shaped Association between Maternal Hemoglobin and Low Birth Weight in Rural Bangladesh. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2021;106(2):424&#x2013;31. doi: 10.4269/ajtmh.21-0268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.21-0268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8832918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34844203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahammed B, Maniruzzaman Md, Ferdausi F, Abedin MM, Hossain MT. Socioeconomic and Demographic Factors Associated with Low Birth Weight in Nepal. Asian Journal of Social Health and Behavior. 2020;3(4):158&#x2013;65. doi: 10.4103/shb.shb_46_20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/shb.shb_46_20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan N, Mozumdar A, Kaur S. Determinants of low birth weight in India: An investigation from the National Family Health Survey. Am J Hum Biol. 2020;32(3):e23355. doi: 10.1002/ajhb.23355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajhb.23355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31746504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoodi Z, Karimlou M, Sajjadi H, Dejman M, Vameghi M, Dolatian M. Working conditions, socioeconomic factors and low birth weight: path analysis. Iran Red Crescent Med J. 2013;15(9):836&#x2013;42. doi: 10.5812/ircmj.11449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/ircmj.11449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3929821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24616796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Md Asaduzzman -, Rahman MS. Maternal Socioeconomic Factors Affecting Birth Weight of New Born Babies Born in Combined Military Hospital Dhaka. Anwer Khan Mod Med Coll J. 2019;10(2):138&#x2013;42. doi: 10.3329/akmmcj.v10i2.44126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/akmmcj.v10i2.44126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury N, Ahmed SM. Maternal care practices among the ultra poor households in rural Bangladesh: a qualitative exploratory study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2011;11:15. doi: 10.1186/1471-2393-11-15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2393-11-15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21362164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali N, Sultana M, Sheikh N, Akram R, Mahumud RA, Asaduzzaman M, et al. Predictors of Optimal Antenatal Care Service Utilization Among Adolescents and Adult Women in Bangladesh. Health Serv Res Manag Epidemiol. 2018;5:2333392818781729. doi: 10.1177/2333392818781729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2333392818781729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6069020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30083573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessema ZT, Tamirat KS, Teshale AB, Tesema GA. Prevalence of low birth weight and its associated factor at birth in Sub-Saharan Africa: A generalized linear mixed model. PLoS One. 2021;16(3):e0248417. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0248417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0248417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7951905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33705473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kader M, Tripathi N. Determinants of low birth weight in rural Bangladesh. Int J Reprod Contracept Obstet Gynecol. 2013;2(2):130. doi: 10.5455/2320-1770.ijrcog20130604</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5455/2320-1770.ijrcog20130604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaheen R, Roy M, Anny A, Shova NY, Hema T. Prevalence of Low Birth Weight in Urban Dhaka and its Association with Maternal Age and Socioeconomic Status. Dr Sulaiman Al Habib Medical Journal. 2020;2(4):162&#x2013;6. doi: 10.2991/dsahmj.k.200905.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2991/dsahmj.k.200905.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Arya S, Chellani H, Aggarwal KC, Pandey RM. Prediction model for low birth weight and its validation. Indian J Pediatr. 2014;81(1):24&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1007/s12098-013-1161-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12098-013-1161-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23949869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MM, Rahman MJ, Chandra Roy D, Maniruzzaman M. Automated detection and classification of diabetes disease based on Bangladesh demographic and health survey data, 2011 using machine learning approach. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2020;14(3):217&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.dsx.2020.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsx.2020.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32193086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlKaabi LA, Ahmed LS, Al Attiyah MF, Abdel-Rahman ME. Predicting hypertension using machine learning: Findings from Qatar Biobank Study. PLoS One. 2020;15(10):e0240370. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0240370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0240370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33064740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haumann T, Kassemeier R, Wieseke J. Multilevel Modeling. Handbook of Market Research. Springer International Publishing. 2021. 369&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1007/978-3-319-57413-4_18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-57413-4_18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok O-M, Underhill AT, Berry JW, Luo W, Elliott TR, Yoon M. Analyzing longitudinal data with multilevel models: An example with individuals living with lower extremity intra-articular fractures. Rehabilitation Psychology. 2008;53(3):370&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1037/a0012765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0012765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2613314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19649151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marete I, Ekhaguere O, Bann CM, Bucher SL, Nyongesa P, Patel AB, et al. Regional trends in birth weight in low- and middle-income countries 2013-2018. Reprod Health. 2020;17(Suppl 3):176. doi: 10.1186/s12978-020-01026-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-020-01026-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7745347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee AC, Blencowe H, Lawn JE. Small babies, big numbers: global estimates of preterm birth. Lancet Glob Health. 2019;7(1):e2&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30484-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(18)30484-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30389450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan JR, Islam MM, Awan N, Muurlink O. Analysis of low birth weight and its co-variants in Bangladesh based on a sub-sample from nationally representative survey. BMC Pediatr. 2018;18(1):100. doi: 10.1186/s12887-018-1068-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-018-1068-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29510673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MZ, Chowdhury MRK, Kader M, Billah B, Islam MS, Rashid M. Determinants of low birth weight and its effect on childhood health and nutritional outcomes in Bangladesh. J Health Popul Nutr. 2024;43(1):64. doi: 10.1186/s41043-024-00565-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-024-00565-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11092222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38741173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tariqujjaman M, Tanha AF, Rahman M, Karmakar G, Mahfuz M, Hasan MM, et al. Geographical variation, socioeconomic inequalities of low birth weight, and its relationship with maternal dietary diversity: Insights from the maternal infant and young child nutrition programme in Bangladesh. J Glob Health. 2024. Oct;14:04209. doi: 10.7189/jogh.14.04209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.14.04209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11467772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39391893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatun MA, Khatun S. Maternal&#x2019; Awareness of Antenatal Care on Impact of Mothers&#x2019; and Newborn Health in Bangladesh. OJN. 2018;08(01):102&#x2013;13. doi: 10.4236/ojn.2018.81009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojn.2018.81009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundu RN, Ghosh A, Chhetri B, Saha I, Hossain MG, Bharati P. Regional with urban-rural variation in low birth weight and its determinants of Indian children: findings from National Family Health Survey 5 data. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2023;23(1):616. doi: 10.1186/s12884-023-05934-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-023-05934-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37641012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xe9;lix E, Esther NUM, Val&#xe8;re MK, Laurentine G, Samuel O, Pascal F. Maternal and Foetal Outcomes Associated with Caesarean Deliveries in Patients with Severe Preeclampsia in Two Teaching Hospitals, Yaound&#xe9;. OJOG. 2018;08(13):1271&#x2013;81. doi: 10.4236/ojog.2018.813129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojog.2018.813129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Zhang H, Jiang Y, Mzayek F, Arshad H, Karmaus W. Maternal Birth Weight and BMI Mediate the Transgenerational Effect of Grandmaternal BMI on Grandchild&#x2019;s Birth Weight. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2020;28(3):647&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1002/oby.22680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.22680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32012478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayode GA, Amoakoh-Coleman M, Agyepong IA, Ansah E, Grobbee DE, Klipstein-Grobusch K. Contextual risk factors for low birth weight: a multilevel analysis. PLoS One. 2014;9(10):e109333. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0109333</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0109333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4215836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25360709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shifti DM, Chojenta C, G Holliday E, Loxton D. Individual and community level determinants of short birth interval in Ethiopia: A multilevel analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15(1):e0227798. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0227798</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0227798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6959604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31935262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>