<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41866468</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-2875</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Malaria journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Malar J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A systematic review of entomological outcomes and sampling approaches used in the evaluation of cluster randomised controlled trials for malaria vector control products.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12936-026-05866-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Entomological outcomes are critical for understanding the biological mechanisms and operational performance of malaria vector control interventions. However, the quality and consistency of how these outcomes are measured and reported in cluster randomised controlled trials (cRCTs) is unclear. We conducted a systematic review of design features, sampling methods, and metrics used for measuring entomological outcomes in malaria vector control cRCTs. Our aims were to assess the consistency and quality of entomological study designs and examine how key design features influence the precision of reported entomological effect sizes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Malaria cRCTs in the published literature were identified in four databases and two trial registries. We extracted information on entomological outcomes measured, entomological sampling strategies and trial design&#xa0;features. To evaluate overall design quality, we created an Entomological Study Design Risk (ESDR) metric that assessed trials across four domains related to power analysis and sampling design; with domain ratings combined to generate an overall ESDR score. We also used a linear mixed-effects model (LMM) to examine how the use of power analysis and the number of clusters and sampling points in entomological sampling influenced the precision of main entomological outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Sixty-two cRCTs of malaria vector control interventions were identified between 1992 and 2021; with 74% being conducted in Africa. Thirteen different entomological outcomes and 12 sampling methods were used across trials: with considerable variation in the frequency of entomological sampling within trials. In total, 70% of the cRCTs were categorized as having high potential entomological design risk based on a combination of the lack of power analyses and inadequate or unclear randomisation of sampling points. The only significant predictor of the precision of entomological outcomes was the number of entomological clusters in which data were collected (greater precision as cluster number increased).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">There is substantial variation in how entomological outcomes are measured and reported in cRCTs, and limited incorporation of key design features such as power analysis and random selection of sampling points for outcome measurement. Standardization&#xa0;where possible and clearer reporting guidelines for entomological components are therefore needed to improve the quality, comparability, and policy relevance for future trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Githu</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biodiversity, One Health and Veterinary Medicine, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK. v.githu.1@research.gla.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Health, and Ecological Sciences Department, Ifakara Health Institute, Kiko Avenue, Mikocheni, Dar es Salaam, United Republic of Tanzania. v.githu.1@research.gla.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michael</LastName><ForeName>Praise</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Health, and Ecological Sciences Department, Ifakara Health Institute, Kiko Avenue, Mikocheni, Dar es Salaam, United Republic of Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biggs</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Statistics and Epidemiology Group, Department of Infectious Disease Epidemiology and International Health, London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cook</LastName><ForeName>Jackie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Statistics and Epidemiology Group, Department of Infectious Disease Epidemiology and International Health, London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiware</LastName><ForeName>Samson</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Health, and Ecological Sciences Department, Ifakara Health Institute, Kiko Avenue, Mikocheni, Dar es Salaam, United Republic of Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McConnachie</LastName><ForeName>Alex</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Wellbeing, Robertson Centre for Biostatistics, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biodiversity, One Health and Veterinary Medicine, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ferguson</LastName><ForeName>Heather M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biodiversity, One Health and Veterinary Medicine, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/W006049/1</GrantID><Agency>MRC Trials Methodology Research Partnership Doctoral Training Partnership</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>INV 070227</GrantID><Agency>The Gates Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Malar J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101139802</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1475-2875</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cluster randomised controlled trials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Entomological outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malaria vector control</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41866468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-026-05866-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12936-026-05866-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chala B, Hamde F. Emerging and re-emerging vector-borne infectious diseases and the challenges for control: a review. Front Public Health. 2021;9:715759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation WHO. World malaria report 2025: Addressing the threat of antimalarial drug resistance. Geneva: World Health Organisation; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation, W.H.O. Malaria vaccines: WHO position paper. Wkly Epidemiol Rec. 2024;19(99):225&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson AL, et al. The importance of vector control for the control and elimination of vector-borne diseases. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2020;14(1):e0007831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation WHO. Larval source management: a supplementary measure for malaria vector control: an operational manual. Geneva: World Health Organisation; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh PF, et al. Impact of insecticide resistance on malaria vector competence: a literature review. Malar J. 2023;22(1):19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez MH. Residual malaria: limitations of current vector control strategies to eliminate transmission in residual foci. J Infect Dis. 2021;223(12 Suppl 2):S55&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin JT, et al. Reducing Plasmodium falciparum malaria transmission in Africa: a model-based evaluation of intervention strategies. PLoS Med. 2010. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1000324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson AL, et al. Evidence-based vector control? Improving the quality of vector control trials. Trends Parasitol. 2015;31(8):380&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes RJ, Moulton LH, et al. Cluster randomised trials. In: Jones B, et al., editors. Biostatistics series. Boca Raton: Chapman &amp; Hall/CRC; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo NF, et al. Modern vector control. Woodbury: Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenwood BM. The epidemiology of Malaria. Ann Trop Med Parasitol. 1997;91(7):763&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation WHO. Design of epidemiological trials for vector control products. Geneva: World Health Organisation; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Straat B, et al. A global assessment of surveillance methods for dominant malaria vectors. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):15337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hul N, Braks M, Van Bortel W. A systematic review to understand the value of entomological endpoints for assessing the efficacy of vector control interventions. EFSA Support Publ. 2021;18(11):6954E.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkot TR, et al. A global analysis of National Malaria Control Programme vector surveillance by elimination and control status in 2018. Malar J. 2019;18(1):399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell MJ, Donner A, Klar N. Developments in cluster randomized trials and Statistics in Medicine. Stat Med. 2007;26(1):2&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Githu V et al. A systematic review of entomological indicators and sampling approaches used in the evaluation of cluster randomised trials for malaria vector control products. PROSPERO, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Team RC. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. 2024, R Foundation for Statistical Computing: Vienna, Austria.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. ggplot2: elegant graphics for data analysis. New York: Springer-Verlag; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, et al. Fitting linear mixed-effects models Usinglme4. J Stat Softw. 2015;67(1):1-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoenig JM, Heisey DM. The abuse of power. Am Stat. 2001;55(1):19&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accrombessi M, et al. Efficacy of pyriproxyfen-pyrethroid long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLINs) and chlorfenapyr-pyrethroid LLINs compared with pyrethroid-only LLINs for malaria control in Benin: A cluster-randomised, superiority trial. Lancet. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(22)02319-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afrane YA, et al. Evaluation of long-lasting microbial larvicide for malaria vector control in Kenya. Malar J. 2016;15(1):577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio-Nkondjio C, et al. High efficacy of microbial larvicides for malaria vectors control in the city of Yaounde Cameroon following a cluster randomized trial. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):17101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bousema T, et al. The Impact of hotspot-targeted interventions on malaria transmission in Rachuonyo South District in the Western Kenyan Highlands: a cluster-randomized controlled trial. Plos Med. 2016;13(4):e1001993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaumeau V, et al. Outdoor residual spraying for malaria vector-control in Kayin (Karen) state, Myanmar: a cluster randomized controlled trial. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(9):e0274320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cisse MBM, et al. A village level cluster-randomized entomological evaluation of combination long-lasting insecticidal nets containing pyrethroid plus PBO synergist in Southern Mali. Malar J. 2017;16(1):477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbel V, et al. Combination of malaria vector control interventions in pyrethroid resistance area in Benin: A cluster randomised controlled trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2012;12(8):617&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer EY, et al. Measuring effects of ivermectin-treated cattle on potential malaria vectors in Vietnam: A cluster-randomized trial. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0012014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis CF, et al. A comparison of use of a pyrethroid either for house spraying or for bednet treatment against malaria vectors. Trop Med Int Health. 1998;3(8):619&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabira ED, et al. Mass drug administration of ivermectin and dihydroartemisinin-piperaquine against malaria in settings with high coverage of standard control interventions: a cluster-randomised controlled trial in The Gambia. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00557-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djenontin A, et al. Durability of the deltamethrin-treated polypropylene long-lasting net LifeNet in a pyrethroid resistance area in south western Benin: A phase III trial. PLoS ONE. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0291755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foy BD, et al. Efficacy and risk of harms of repeat ivermectin mass drug administrations for control of malaria (RIMDAMAL): a cluster-randomised trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10180):1517&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giesbrecht D, et al. Durable wall lining for malaria control in Liberia: results of a cluster randomized trial. Malar J. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12936-022-04429-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimnig JE, et al. Impact of permethrin-treated bed nets on entomologic indices in an area of intense year-round malaria transmission. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2003;68(4 SUPPL.):16&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habluetzel A, et al. Do insecticide-treated curtains reduce all-cause child mortality in Burkina Faso? Trop Med Int Health. 1997. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-3156.1997.d01-413.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafy HT, et al. Impact of insecticide resistance in Anopheles arabiensis on malaria incidence and prevalence in Sudan and the costs of mitigation. PNAS. 2017;114(52):E11267&#x2013;E11275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenea O, et al. Impact of combining indoor residual spraying and long-lasting insecticidal nets on Anopheles arabiensis in Ethiopia: Results from a cluster randomized controlled trial. Malar J. 2019;18(1):182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby MJ, et al. Effect of two different house screening interventions on exposure to malaria vectors and on anaemia in children in The Gambia: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2009. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(09)60871-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroeger A, Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Ord&#xf3;&#xf1;ez-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. Insecticide-treated materials for malaria control in Latin America: To use or not to use? Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 1999;93(6):565&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magbity BE, et al. Effects of community-wide use of lambdacyhalothrin-impregnated bednets on malaria vectors in rural Sierra Leone. Med Vet Entomol. 1997;11(1):79&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiteki-Sebuguzi C, et al. Effect of long-lasting insecticidal nets with and without piperonyl butoxide on malaria indicators in Uganda (LLINEUP): final results of a cluster-randomised trial embedded in a national distribution campaign. Lancet Infect Dis. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(22)00469-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCann RS, et al. The effect of community-driven larval source management and house improvement on malaria transmission when added to the standard malaria control strategies in Malawi: a cluster-randomized controlled trial. Malar J. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12936-021-03769-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minakawa N, et al. Effectiveness of screened ceilings over the current best practice in reducing malaria prevalence in Western Kenya: a cluster randomized-controlled trial. Parasitology. 2022;149(7):944&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minakawa N, et al. Long-lasting insecticidal nets incorporating piperonyl butoxide reduce the risk of malaria in children in Western Kenya: a cluster randomized controlled trial. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2021;105(2):461&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra SP, et al. Spray versus treated nets using deltamethrin&#x2014;A community randomized trial in India. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 1999;93(5):456&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal PK, et al. Evaluation of the impact of ZeroFly&#xae;, an insecticide incorporated plastic sheeting on malaria incidence in two temporary labour shelters in India. J Vector Borne Dis. 2011;48:138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosha JF, et al. Effectiveness and cost-effectiveness against malaria of three types of dual-active-ingredient long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLINs) compared with pyrethroid-only LLINs in Tanzania: a four-arm, cluster-randomised trial. Lancet (London, England). 2022. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02499-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutero CM, et al. Evaluating the impact of larviciding with Bti and community education and mobilization as supplementary integrated vector management interventions for malaria control in Kenya and Ethiopia. Malar J. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12936-020-03464-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngufor C, et al. Community evaluation of VECTRON TM T500, a broflanilide insecticide, for indoor residual spraying for malaria vector control in central Benin; a two arm non-inferiority cluster randomised trial. Sci Rep. 2023;13,17852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochomo EO, et al. Effect of a spatial repellent on malaria incidence in an area of western Kenya characterised by high malaria transmission, insecticide resistance, and universal coverage of insecticide treated nets (part of the AEGIS Consortium): a cluster-randomised, controlled trial. Lancet. 2025;405(10473):147&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinder M, et al. Efficacy of indoor residual spraying with dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane against malaria in Gambian communities with high usage of long-lasting insecticidal mosquito nets: a cluster-randomised controlled trial. Lancet (London, England). 2015;385(9976):1436&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pretorius E et al. Evaluating the entomological effects of adjunctive ivermectin mass drug administration for malaria control in the bijagos archipelago, guinea-bissau: a cluster-randomised trial (Matamal). 2020;103(5 SUPPL).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Protopopoff N, et al. Effectiveness of a long-lasting piperonyl butoxide-treated insecticidal net and indoor residual spray interventions, separately and together, against malaria transmitted by pyrethroid-resistant mosquitoes: a cluster, randomised controlled, two-by-two factorial design trial. Lancet. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30427-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Protopopoff N, et al. Combination of insecticide treated nets and indoor residual spraying in Northern Tanzania provides additional reduction in vector population density and malaria transmission rates compared to insecticide treated nets alone: a randomised control trial. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(11):e0142671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohani A, et al. Comparative field evaluation of residual-sprayed deltamethrin WG and deltamethrin WP for the control of malaria in Pahang, Malaysia. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health. 2006;37:1139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland M, et al. Indoor residual spraying with alphacypermethrin controls malaria in Pakistan: a community-randomized trial. Trop Med Int Health. 2000. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-3156.2000.00581.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma KS, et al. Field evaluation of Olyset nets: a long-lasting insecticidal net against malaria VectorsAnopheles culicifaciesandAnopheles fluviatilisin a Hyperendemic Tribal Area of Orissa. India J Med Entomol. 2009;46(2):342&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma SK, et al. Wash-resistance and field evaluation of alphacypermethrin treated long-lasting insecticidal net (Interceptor) against malaria vectors Anopheles culicifacies and Anopheles fluviatilis in a tribal area of Orissa, India. Acta Trop. 2010. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actatropica.2010.05.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sochantha T, et al. Insecticide-treated bednets for the prevention of Plasmodium falciparum malaria in Cambodia: a cluster-randomized trial. Trop Med Int Health. 2006. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-3156.2006.01673.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternberg ED, et al. Impact and cost-effectiveness of a lethal house lure against malaria transmission in central Cote d&#x2019;Ivoire: a two-arm, cluster-randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00250-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutanto I et al. Efficacy of permethrin-impregnated bed nets on malaria control in a hyperendemic area in Irian Jaya, Indonesia: influence of seasonal rainfall fluctuations. 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syafruddin D, et al. Efficacy of a spatial repellent for control of malaria in Indonesia: a cluster-randomized controlled trial. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020;103(1):344&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traore MM, et al. Large-scale field trial of attractive toxic sugar baits (ATSB) for the control of malaria vector mosquitoes in Mali, West Africa. Malar J. 2020;19(1):72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagman J, et al. Entomological effects of attractive targeted sugar bait station deployment in Western Zambia: vector surveillance findings from a two-arm cluster randomized phase III trial. Malar J. 2024;23(1):214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagman JM, et al. Reduced exposure to malaria vectors following indoor residual spraying of pirimiphos-methyl in a high-burden district of rural Mozambique with high ownership of long-lasting insecticidal nets: entomological surveillance results from a cluster-randomized trial. Malar J. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12936-021-03583-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav RS, et al. House-scale evaluation of Bifenthrin indoor residual spraying for malaria vector control in India. Vector Control Pest Manag Resist. 2003;40(1):58&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biggs J, et al. A systematic review of sample size estimation accuracy on power in malaria cluster randomised trials measuring epidemiological outcomes. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2024;24(1):238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryce J, et al. Insecticide space spraying for preventing malaria transmission. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018;11(11):CD012689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryce J, Medley N, Choi L. Indoor residual spraying for preventing malaria in communities using insecticide-treated nets. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022;1(1):CD012688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryce J, Richardson M, Lengeler C. Insecticide-treated nets for preventing malaria. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD000363.pub3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox T, et al. House modifications for preventing malaria. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD013398.pub4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messenger LA, et al. Vector control for malaria prevention during humanitarian emergencies: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Glob Health. 2023;11(4):E534&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation WHO. World malaria report 2024: Addressing inequity in the global malaria response.&#xa0;Geneva: World Health Organisation; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vector Control Advisory Group - World Health Organization, V.C.A.G.-WHO. How to Design Vector Control Efficacy Trials, Guidance on phase III vector control field trial design provided by the Vector Control Advisory Group. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulibaly ZI, et al. Strengthening adult mosquito surveillance in Africa for disease control: learning from the present. Curr Opin Insect Sci. 2023;60:101110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemingway C, et al. Evaluation of a digital entomological surveillance planning tool for malaria vector control: three country mixed methods pilot study. PLoS ONE. 2025;20(3):e0303915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso S, et al. Cost and cost-effectiveness of indoor residual spraying with pirimiphos-methyl in a high malaria transmission district of Mozambique with high access to standard insecticide-treated nets. Malar J. 2021;20(1):143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves LF, et al. Regime shifts and heterogeneous trends in malaria time series from Western Kenya Highlands. Parasitology. 2012;139(1):14&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biggs J, et al. Characterisation of between-cluster heterogeneity in malaria cluster randomised trials to inform future sample size calculations. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):6615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson PC, et al. Power analysis for generalized linear mixed models in ecology and evolution. Methods Ecol Evol. 2015;6(2):133&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DL, et al. The entomological inoculation rate and Plasmodium falciparum infection in African children. Nature. 2005;438(7067):492&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>