<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41826622</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comprehensive enhancement of blasting performance and dust suppression in open-pit mines using a modified mudstone-fly ash geopolymer stemming material.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43442-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In response to the severe dust pollution, high operational cost, and short-lived effectiveness associated with conventional water-spraying dust suppression in large open-pit coal mines in grassland regions, this study proposes a source-control strategy grounded in solid waste reutilization. Drill cuttings of mudstone obtained from a representative overburden bench in the study area were utilized as the primary precursor, and a modified mudstone-fly ash geopolymer stemming material was developed via an alkali-activated rapid-setting process. The proposed material enables synergistic optimization of explosive energy confinement and dust suppression at the source during blasting operations.The dust-suppression mechanism of the proposed material was systematically investigated through mechanical performance testing, SEM, XRD, EDS, and smoothed particle hydrodynamics (SPH) simulations.Results show that optimal performance is obtained with a 30% accelerator concentration, a water-glass modulus of 1.50&#xa0;mol/L at 40&#xa0;g/L dosage, and a mixing time of 5&#xa0;min, yielding good flowability and setting times within 30&#xa0;min. Dynamic tests indicate superior toughness, with initiation and propagation fracture toughness of 0.80-2.41&#xa0;MPa m<sup>1/2</sup> and 0.61-2.56&#xa0;MPa m<sup>1/2</sup>, respectively, and a peak stress approximately 7.5% higher than that of in-situ mudstone. Microstructural analyses reveal that synergistic formation of C-S-H and C-A-S-H gels produces a dense and stable matrix.SPH simulations identify an optimal stemming length of 2.5&#xa0;m for uniform energy distribution. Field trials demonstrate reductions of 40.0% in peak dust concentration and 0.346&#xa0;cm/s in maximum vibration velocity, alongside improved fragmentation and suppressed blowout holes. The results demonstrate that the proposed geopolymer stemming material enables a technological transition from conventional post-blast water spraying to in-blast active solidification control. By enhancing explosive energy utilization while achieving source-level dust suppression, the material provides a green, cost-effective, and durable solution for blasting optimization in grassland open-pit coal mines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohua</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yuansong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China. 1535452186@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Zhihao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Linyou</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou, 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023YFC2907305</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52174131</GrantID><Agency>Supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dust-suppression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geopolymer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mudstone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solid waste utilization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41826622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43442-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43442-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Zhou, W., Jiskani, I. M., Yan, J. &amp; Luo, H. Optimizing open-pit coal mining operations: Leveraging meteorological conditions for dust removal and diffusion. Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol. 11, 54 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J. et al. Characterization of dust pollution distribution in large-scale open-pit coal mines in Northern China. J. Environ. Eng. Asce. 151, 4025061 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xianfeng, A. I., Changqing, S., Jianying, Y. &amp; Yanqing, Z. Mining rights setting of open-pit coal mines based on Gis and environmental impacts in arid areas. J. Resour. Ecol. 14, 717&#x2013;726 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Wang, Z. &amp; Wang, R. Characteristics of dust pollution and its influencing factors during cold period of open-pit coal mines in Northern China. Front. Earth Sci. 13, 1458847 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, J. et al. Impact and elastic modulus of coal mining on terrestrial ecosystems. Sci. Rep. 15, 9454 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, S., Chen, H., Ding, X., Liao, Z. &amp; Lu, X. Development of dust emission prediction model for open-pit mines based on Shpb experiment and image recognition method. Atmosphere 15, 1118 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kung, H., Lin, W., Huang, B., Mutuku, J. K. &amp; Chang-Chien, G. Techniques for suppressing mineral dust aerosol from raw material stockpiles and open pit mines: A review. Aerosol Air Qual. Res. 24, 230166 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeimi, M. &amp; Chu, J. Comparison of conventional and bio-treated methods as dust suppressants. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 24, 23341&#x2013;23350 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piechota, T. C., van Ee, J., Batista, J. R., Stave, K. A. &amp; James, D. E. Potential Environmental Impacts of Dust Suppressants: "Avoiding Another Times Beach". (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha, S. &amp; Banerjee, S. P. Characterization of haul road dust in an Indian opencast iron ore mine. Atmos. Environ. 31, 2809&#x2013;2814 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, H. et al. Development of environmental friendly dust suppressant based on the modification of soybean protein isolate. Processes 7, 165 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, Y., Dai, J. &amp; Shi, C. Mechanical properties of alkali-activated concrete: A state-of-the-art review. Constr. Build. Mater. 127, 68&#x2013;79 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daramola, S. O., Hingston, E. &amp; Demlie, M. A review of lateritic soils and their use as landfill liners. Environ. Earth Sci. 83, 118 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sheltawy, S. T. &amp; Al-Sakkari, E. G. Recent trends in solid waste utilization for biodiesel production. J. Solid Waste Technol. Manag. 42, (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitkov, N. Conceivable Environmental and Energy Benefits of the Solid Municipal Waste Utilization for Energy Production in Bulgaria. In 2019 11th Electrical Engineering Faculty Conference (BulEF): IEEE, 1&#x2013;5. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marciniak, T. J. &amp; Holtz, R. E. Solid Waste Utilization in Integrated Community Energy Systems.: Argonne National Lab., IL, (1978).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. et al. Utilization of Solid Waste Derivative Materials in Soft Soils Re-Engineering. In International Congress and Exhibition" Sustainable Civil Infrastructures&#x201d;. 49&#x2013;57, (Springer, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S., Monjezi, M., Bakhtavar, E. &amp; Mousavi, A. Prediction of dust emission due to open pit mine blasting using a hybrid artificial neural network. Nat. Resour. Res. 30, 4773&#x2013;4788 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q. &amp; Li, L. Technology and application of damage reduction mining and ecosystem restoration of open-pit coal mines in Eastern Grassland area. Coal Sci. Technol. 51, 484&#x2013;492 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, H. et al. Optimization of external spray negative-pressure mist-curtain dust suppression devices for roadheaders based on a multi-factor orthogonal experiment. J. Clean. Prod. 275, 123603 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, Z. et al. Synthesis of starch-based super absorbent polymer with high agglomeration and wettability for applying in road dust suppression. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 183, 982&#x2013;991 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halt, J. A. &amp; Kawatra, S. K. Review of organic binders for iron ore concentrate agglomeration. Min. Metall. Explor. 31, 73&#x2013;94 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan, P., Lessard, J. J., Moore, J. S. &amp; Sottos, N. R. Rapid gelation of dicyclopentadiene resins for additive manufacturing of thermoset polymers. ACS Macro Lett. 14, 570&#x2013;575 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Optimization and field application of an eco-friendly molasses-based dust suppressant for open-pit coal mine haul roads. Sci. Rep. 15, 26039 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianlin, H. U., Tianyi, Z., Faguang, L., Yongxiang, Z. &amp; Xiuli, D. U. Mechanical properties and strength prediction of alkali activated slag fly ash based geopolymer stabilized soil. Acta Mater. Compos. Sin. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami, O., Raihan, H. M. &amp; Rahman, S. M. Influence of Ggbs&#x2013;Fly Ash Binder Composition On the Strength of Geopolymer Concrete with Natural and Recycled Concrete Aggregate. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, X. et al. Geopolymer-based modification of blasting sealing materials and optimization of blasting block size in coal seams of open pit mines. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 33, 1551&#x2013;1562 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, J., Su, X., Guo, Y. &amp; Fu, X. Polymer-Ggbs-cement amended reused blasting slag: Towards eco-friendly and resilient open-pit road surface. Environ. Res. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2025.122541 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biddle, S. K., LaGrange, M. T., Harris, B. S., Egenhoff, S. &amp; Gingras, M. K. Current concepts in mudstone description and deposition: A synthesis for mudstone initiates. Sedimentologika. 3, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anburuvel, A. Deployment perspectives of precursors in Geopolymer synthesization: A review from their utilization prospects. Innov. Infrastruct. Solut. 8, 264 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, M., Li, F., Zhou, L., Ning, J. &amp; Zhang, Z. Effects of sodium carbonate, sodium hydroxide and water glass composite activation on properties of geopolymer cementitious materials. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 43, 929&#x2013;937 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilar, F. A. et al. Optimization of alkaline activator on the strength properties of geopolymer concrete. Polymers 14, 2434 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Effects of sodium aluminate and quicklime on the properties of CSA grouting materials. J. Build. Eng. 58, 105060 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naqash, J. A., Bhat, Z. B., Malik, M. I., Ahmad, S. &amp; Kumar, D. Effect of accelerating admixture on properties of concrete. IOSR J. Eng. 4, 48&#x2013;55 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P. et al. Research on the flow characteristics of blasthole stemming slurry in open-pit mining. Front. Earth Sci. 12, 1430046 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, H. et al. Study on modification of natural hydraulic lime historical building repair mortar. J. Build. Eng. 97, 110583 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, L., Bi, Y. &amp; Liu, T. Effects of AMF inoculation on accumulation of plant-soil nutrients and colonization of native DSE in eastern grassland opencast mining area. J. China Coal Soc. 49, 4603&#x2013;4616 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Mechanism of the effect of chitosan combined with eicp on the erosion resistance of slopes in open-pit mine dump. J. China Coal Soc. 49, 4713&#x2013;4727 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, S. &amp; Alghamdi, S. A. A statistical approach to optimizing concrete mixture design. Sci. World J. 2014, 561539 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurel, B., Nahmany, M., Frage, N., Stern, A. &amp; Sadot, O. Split hopkinson pressure bar tests for investigating dynamic properties of additively manufactured Alsi10Mg alloy by selective laser melting. Addit. Manuf. 22, 823&#x2013;833 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P., Yin, T., Li, X., Zhang, S. &amp; Bai, L. Dynamic properties of thermally treated granite subjected to cyclic impact loading. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 52, 991&#x2013;1010 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, Y. et al. Strain rate effect and energy dissipation characteristics of sandstone in coal measures under impact loading. J. China Coal Soc. 46, 2281&#x2013;2293 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser, M., Mayrhofer, P. H., Ross, I. M. &amp; Rainforth, W. M. Microstructure and mechanical properties of sputtered intermetallic Al&#x2013;Au coatings. J. Appl. Phys. 102, (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deressa, G. W., Choudhary, B. S. &amp; Jilo, N. Z. Optimizing blast design and bench geometry for stability and productivity in open pit limestone mines using experimental and numerical approaches. Sci. Rep. 15, 5796 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, L. &amp; Jing, L. Smoothed particle hydrodynamics simulation of fluid flow in rock fractures. ISRM SINOROCK: ISRM, 2013&#x2013;2074. (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraga Filho, C. A. D., Fraga Filho, C. A. D. &amp; Castro. Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics, (Springer, 2019)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan, V. T. Improvement in engineering properties of mudstone in Southwestern Taiwan through compaction and a cement additive. Geotech. Geol. Eng. 36, 1833&#x2013;1843 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. et al. Crack and failure behaviors of sandstone subjected to dynamic loads visualized by micro-computed tomography. J. Rock Mech. Geotech. Eng. 17, 1459&#x2013;1473 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jajam, K. C. &amp; Tippur, H. V. Quasi-static and dynamic fracture behavior of particulate polymer composites: A study of nano-Vs. micro-size filler and loading-rate effects. Compos. Part B Eng. 43, 3467&#x2013;3481 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanner, A., Rizzo, G. &amp; Kromp, K. Quasi-ductile behaviour of carbon-reinforced carbon. In Toughening Mechanisms in Quasi-Brittle Materials 405&#x2013;423 (Springer, 1991).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>