<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41786063</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7568</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta biomaterialia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Biomater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dual crosslinked thermosensitive hydrogel engineered with multiple dynamic hydrogen bonds for enhanced photodynamic antibacterial activity and wound healing.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1742-7061(26)00141-8</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.actbio.2026.03.002</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To address the challenges posed by bacterial infection and the persistent oxidative microenvironment in diabetic wounds, a multifunctional intelligent hydrogel dressing (SPC) was developed, comprising sodium alginate (SA) , poly (N-isopropylacrylamide) (PNIPAM) , and an encapsulated photosensitizer. This hydrogel features a dual-crosslinked network and supported by hydrogen bond relay system. The results demonstrate that SPC exhibits unique thermosensitivity, with its lower critical solution temperature (LCST) precisely regulated to 26.8 &#xb0;C through hydrogen bonding. This thermoresponsive behavior enables spontaneous contraction at body temperature, generating mechanical forces that promote wound closure. The hydrogel exhibits outstanding broad-spectrum antibacterial activity, achieving bactericidal efficiencies of 99.63% and 98.95% against MRSA and ESBL E.coli, respectively, and a 94.3% inhibition rate against MRSA biofilms under light irradiation. This enhanced antibacterial performance is attributed to a narrowed bandgap (&#x394;Eg) and the formation of a hydrophobic microenvironment by PNIPAM, which together promote C3AC, aggregation, and significantly elevate ROS generation. Notably, the hydrogel exhibits significant antioxidant activity, efficiently scavenging excessive ROS to alleviate oxidative stress. This capability synergizes with its immunomodulatory function of regulating macrophage polarization by downregulating the pro-inflammatory M1 phenotype and upregulating the anti-inflammatory M2 phenotype, thereby comprehensively remodeling the wound microenvironment and promoting tissue regeneration. In vivo evaluations confirmed that SPC significantly accelerates the healing of infected wounds, achieving a 94.1% closure within 14 days, while enhancing collagen deposition, angiogenesis, and M2 macrophage polarization. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: We present a dynamic "hydrogen-bonded relay" hydrogel dressing, synthesized from temperature-responsive poly (N-isopropylacrylamide) , a coumarin-based photosensitizer (C3AC) , and biocompatible sodium alginate, which functions as a "Dual-Engine" system to synergistically accelerate the healing of infected diabetic wounds. Unlike conventional passive hydrogels, our material uniquely combines thermo-mechanical-autonomous contraction with enhanced photodynamic antibacterial activity. The dynamic hydrogen-bond network among these components not only fine-tunes the phase transition to body temperature for effective wound closure but also creates a hydrophobic microenvironment that promotes photosensitizer aggregation and dramatically boosts reactive oxygen species generation. This leads to exceptional antibacterial efficacy against drug-resistant strains and robust anti-biofilm performance. Furthermore, the hydrogel actively modulates macrophage polarization to resolve inflammation and promotes collagen deposition and angiogenesis. This work provides an innovative design strategy for intelligent, multifunctional wound dressings with broad implications for regenerative medicine.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Acta Materialia Inc. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Peipei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Jingnan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Surgical Intensive Care Unit, Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Baijie</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ruixue</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xueying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Baoyue</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhongxu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Qianjin</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Gang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Surgical Intensive Care Unit, Xinhua Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200092, China. Electronic address: zhaogang1234@sjtu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guang</LastName><ForeName>Shanyi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China. Electronic address: syg@dhu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Hongyao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, PR China; School of Materials and Chemical Engineering, Fuyang University of Technology, Fuyang 236000, China. Electronic address: hongyaoxu@dhu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Biomater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101233144</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1742-7061</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrogen-bonded relay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PDT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Temperature responsive</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wound healing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41786063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2026.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1742-7061(26)00141-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>