<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41814083</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A deep-SVM hybrid framework with enhanced EEG feature engineering and SHAP-based explainability for Alzheimer's classification.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43431-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate classification among Alzheimer's Disease (AD), Fronto Temporal Dementia (FTD), and Cognitively Normal (CN) adults from EEG remains challenging. We propose a multi-class classification method that fuses interpretable spectral/connectivity biomarkers (band power, spectral entropy, &#x3b1;-coherence) with compact temporal embeddings from a customized lightweight one Dimensional Convolutional Neural Network (1D-CNN). The fused features are reduced by Principal Component Analysis (PCA) and classified with Support Vector Machine (SVM). All data-dependent steps like Synthetic Minority Over Sampling Technique (SMOTE), z-scoring and PCA are fit strictly on training folds to prevent leakage. Hyperparameters including PCA dimensionality and SMOTE neighbors were selected via inner-loop grid sweeps that maximized macro-F1; full grids and class distributions before/after SMOTE (inner-train only) are reported in the Supplement. On OpenNeuro ds004504 (eyes-closed; [Formula: see text]; 36 AD/23 FTD/29 CN) the model achieved 94.5% accuracy, macro-F1 [Formula: see text], and AUC [Formula: see text]. Robustness was examined on two public datasets using the identical preprocessing/segmentation: (i) cross-condition testing on ds006036 (eyes-open recordings from the same participants) and (ii) zero-shot transfer to an independent OSF dataset with different instrumentation and demographics. SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) analyses provided global, class-wise, and subject-level attributions aligned with known electrophysiology (e.g., reduced &#x3b1;-coherence, elevated &#x3b8;), supporting clinical interpretability. These results indicate that a transparent hybrid feature design can deliver accurate, leakage-safe, and explainable EEG-based differentiation of AD, FTD, and CN with preliminary external checks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akbar</LastName><ForeName>Frnaz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Creative Technologies, Faculty of Computing and AI, Air University, Islamabad, 44000, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alkhrijah</LastName><ForeName>Yazeed</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University (IMSIU), 11623, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Usman</LastName><ForeName>Syed Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, Bahria School of Engineering and Applied Sciences (BSEAS), Bahria University, Islamabad, 44000, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalid</LastName><ForeName>Shehzad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, Bahria School of Engineering and Applied Sciences (BSEAS), Bahria University, Islamabad, 44000, Pakistan. shehzad@bahria.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer and Information Sciences Research Center (CISRC), Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University (IMSIU), 11623, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. shehzad@bahria.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ihsan</LastName><ForeName>Imran</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Creative Technologies, Faculty of Computing and AI, Air University, Islamabad, 44000, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alawad</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University (IMSIU), 11623, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IMSIU-DDRSP2601</GrantID><Agency>Deanship of Scientific Research, Imam Mohammed Ibn Saud Islamic University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41814083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43431-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43431-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Reyes, L.-M., Rodr&#xed;guez-Res&#xe9;ndiz, J., Avecilla-Ram&#xed;rez, G. N., Garc&#xed;a-Gomar, M.-L. &amp; Robles-Ocampo, J.-B. Impact of EEG parameters detecting dementia diseases: A systematic review. IEEE Access 9, 78060&#x2013;78074 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaopeng, Z. et al. Global burden of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other dementias in adults aged 65 years and older, 1991&#x2013;2021: Population-based study. Front. Public Health 13, 1585711 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, M. &amp; Chen, J. Trend analysis and future predictions of global burden of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other dementias: A study based on the global burden of disease database from 1990 to 2021. BMC Med. 23, 378 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hata, M. et al. Accurate deep-learning model to differentiate dementia severity and diagnosis using a portable electroencephalography device. Sci. Rep. 15, 26304 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hameed, I., Khan, D. M., Ahmed, S. M., Aftab, S. S. &amp; Fazal, H. Enhancing motor imagery EEG signal decoding through machine learning: A systematic review of recent progress. Comput. Biol. Med. 185, 109534 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;eker, M., &#xd6;zbek, Y., Yener, G. &amp; &#xd6;zerdem, M. S. Complexity of EEG dynamics for early diagnosis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease using permutation entropy neuromarker. Comput. Methods Programs Biomed. 206, 106116 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hadithy, S. S., Abdalkafor, A. S. &amp; Al-Khateeb, B. Emotion recognition in EEG signals: Deep and machine learning approaches, challenges, and future directions. Comput. Biol. Med. 196, 110713 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar, F. et al. Unlocking the potential of EEG in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease research: Current status and pathways to precision detection. Brain Res. Bull. 111281 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, S., Bornot, J. M. S., Wong-Lin, K. &amp; Prasad, G. M/EEG-based bio-markers to predict the mci and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: A review from the ml perspective. IEEE Trans. Biomed. Eng. 66, 2924&#x2013;2935 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayana, B. et al. EEG-based neurodegenerative disease diagnosis: comparative analysis of conventional methods and deep learning models. Sci. Rep. 15, 15950 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aviles, M., S&#xe1;nchez-Reyes, L. M., &#xc1;lvarez-Alvarado, J. M. &amp; Rodr&#xed;guez-Res&#xe9;ndiz, J. Machine and deep learning trends in EEG-based detection and diagnosis of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review. Eng 5, 1464&#x2013;1484 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tigga, N. P., Kumari, N. &amp; Tigga, A. J. Integrating advanced EEG features with graph convolution transformers for Alzheimer&#x2019;s detection. Proc. Comput. Sci. 258, 3241&#x2013;3250 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghassemkhani, K., Saroka, K.&#xa0;S. &amp; Dotta, B.&#xa0;T. Evaluating EEG complexity and spectral signatures in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and frontotemporal dementia: Evidence for rostrocaudal asymmetry. NPJ Aging. 11, 50 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chetty, C. A. et al. EEG biomarkers in Alzheimer&#x2019;s and prodromal Alzheimer&#x2019;s: A comprehensive analysis of spectral and connectivity features. Alzheimer&#x2019;s Res. Ther. 16, 236 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibilano, E. et al. An attention-based deep learning approach for the classification of subjective cognitive decline and mild cognitive impairment using resting-state EEG. J. Neural Eng. 20, 016048 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gkintoni, E., Aroutzidis, A., Antonopoulou, H. &amp; Halkiopoulos, C. From neural networks to emotional networks: A systematic review of EEG-based emotion recognition in cognitive neuroscience and real-world applications. Brain Sci. 15, 220 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nhu, D. et al. Deep learning for automated epileptiform discharge detection from scalp EEG: A systematic review. J. Neural Eng. 19, 051002 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C., Bian, N., Zhao, Z., Wang, H. &amp; Schuller, B. W. Multi-view domain-adaptive representation learning for EEG-based emotion recognition. Inf. Fusion 104, 102156 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar, F. et al. Unlocking the potential of EEG in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease research: Current status and pathways to precision detection. Brain Res. Bull. 111281 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Machine learning based on functional and structural connectivity in mild cognitive impairment. Magn. Reson. Imaging 109, 10&#x2013;17 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, F. et al. Learning spatial-spectral-temporal EEG representations with deep attentive-recurrent-convolutional neural networks for pain intensity assessment. Neuroscience 481, 144&#x2013;155 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbar, F. et al. Unlocking the potential of EEG in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease research: Current status and pathways to precision detection. Brain Res. Bull. 111281 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R. et al. Artificial intelligence-based methodologies for early diagnostic precision and personalized therapeutic strategies in neuro-ophthalmic and neurodegenerative pathologies. Brain Sci. 14, 1266 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moya, J. A.&#xa0;B. Addressing the gaps in early dementia detection: A path towards enhanced diagnostic models through machine learning. arXiv:2409.03147 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Q. et al. Intelligent biomaterials in diagnostic systems. In Intelligent Biomaterials: Fundamentals, Principles and Applications, 337&#x2013;406 (Springer, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adebisi, A. T., Lee, H.-W. &amp; Veluvolu, K. C. EEG-based brain functional network analysis for differential identification of dementia-related disorders and their onset. IEEE Trans. Neural Syst. Rehabil. Eng. 32, 1198&#x2013;1209 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiyeb Khosroshahi, M. et al. Explainable artificial intelligence in neuroimaging of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Diagnostics 15, 612 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanola, A., Tshimanga, L.&#xa0;F., Del Pup, F., Baiesi, M. &amp; Atzori, M. xeegnet: Towards explainable ai in EEG dementia classification. J. Neural Eng. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miltiadous, A. et al. A dataset of scalp EEG recordings of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, frontotemporal dementia and healthy subjects from routine EEG. Data 8, 95 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutanche, M., Farah, M.&#xa0;J. et al. Openneuro dataset: EEG in Alzheimer&#x2019;s, ftd, and controls. https://openneuro.org/datasets/ds004504 (2021) (accessed 14 Jun 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaee, K. &amp; Zhu, M. Diagnose Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and mild cognitive impairment using deep cascadenet and handcrafted features from EEG signals. Biomed. Signal Process. Control 99, 106895 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, R. &amp; Meena, H. K. Graph based novel features for detection of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease using EEG signals. Biomed. Signal Process. Control 103, 107380 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cejnek, M., Vysata, O., Valis, M. &amp; Bukovsky, I. Novelty detection-based approach for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and mild cognitive impairment diagnosis from EEG. Med. Biol. Eng. Comput. 59, 2287&#x2013;2296 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullen, T. R. et al. Real-time neuroimaging and cognitive monitoring using wearable dry EEG. IEEE Trans. Biomed. Eng. 62, 2553&#x2013;2567 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straetmans, L., Holtze, B., Debener, S., Jaeger, M. &amp; Mirkovic, B. Neural tracking to go: Auditory attention decoding and saliency detection with mobile EEG. J. Neural Eng. 18, 066054 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pion-Tonachini, L., Kreutz-Delgado, K. &amp; Makeig, S. Iclabel: An automated electroencephalographic independent component classifier, dataset, and website. Neuroimage 198, 181&#x2013;197 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, W. et al. Removal of ocular and muscular artifacts from multi-channel EEG using improved spatial-frequency filtering. IEEE J. Biomed. Health Inform. 28, 3466&#x2013;3477 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitham, E. M. et al. Scalp electrical recording during paralysis: quantitative evidence that EEG frequencies above 20 hz are contaminated by EMG. Clin. Neurophysiol. 118, 1877&#x2013;1888 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong, J. EEG dynamics in patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Clin. Neurophysiol. 115, 1490&#x2013;1505 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urig&#xfc;en, J. A. &amp; Garcia-Zapirain, B. EEG artifact removal-state-of-the-art and guidelines. J. Neural Eng. 12, 031001 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch, P. The use of fast fourier transform for the estimation of power spectra: A method based on time averaging over short, modified periodograms. IEEE Trans. Audio Electroacoust. 15, 70&#x2013;73 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-de Pablo, V. et al. Integrative and interpretable framework to unveil the neurophysiological fingerprint of alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and mild cognitive impairment: A machine learning-shap approach. Biocybern. Biomed. Eng. 45, 438&#x2013;450 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puri, D. V., Gawande, J. P., Kachare, P. H. &amp; Al-Shourbaji, I. Optimal time-frequency localized wavelet filters for identification of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease from EEG signals. Cogn. Neurodyn. 19, 12 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, M. et al. Shared and disease-specific pathways in frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer&#x2019;s and Parkinson&#x2019;s diseases. Nat. Med. 1&#x2013;11 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanou, K. et al. A novel CNN-based framework for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease detection using EEG spectrogram representations. J. Pers. Med. 15, 27 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miltiadous, A. et al. A dataset of scalp EEG recordings of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, frontotemporal dementia and healthy subjects from routine EEG. Data 8, 95 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. &amp; Holtzman, D. M. Emerging roles of innate and adaptive immunity in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Immunity 55, 2236&#x2013;2254 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lal, U., Chikkankod, A. V. &amp; Longo, L. A comparative study on feature extraction techniques for the discrimination of frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease with electroencephalography in resting-state adults. Brain Sci. 14, 335 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemant, M.&#xa0;S., Jagadabhi, S.&#xa0;R., Vidapu, B. &amp; KG, S. Multimodal classification of cognitive states in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. In TENCON 2023&#x2013;2023 IEEE Region 10 Conference (TENCON), 1356&#x2013;1361 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>