<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41776686</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-7283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The dark side of AI transparency: investigating AI-induced anxiety, technostress, and consumer satisfaction through a hybrid SEM-ANN approach.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40359-026-04147-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As AI-driven technologies transform customer interactions, understanding their impact on consumer satisfaction is crucial. This study investigates the relationship between artificial intelligence (AI) transparency and consumer satisfaction, incorporating AI-induced anxiety and technostress as mediators and consumer digital literacy as a moderator. A hybrid methodology combining structural equation modelling and artificial neural network (SEM-ANN) was employed to analyse data from 341 e-commerce consumers from China. The SEM results reveal that AI transparency positively influences consumer satisfaction, while AI-induced anxiety and technostress mediate this relationship negatively. However, the moderating role of consumer digital literacy is not significant. The ANN findings identify consumer digital literacy as the most influential factor, highlighting its critical role in shaping consumer responses to AI-powered interactions. These results provide novel insights into the psychological impact of AI transparency on consumers and offer theoretical and practical implications for enhancing AI-driven customer service strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Weichen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Media and Law, NingboTech University, Ningbo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehta</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed Muneeb</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hailey College of Banking and Finance, University of the Punjab, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wittenborg University of applied sciences, Apeldoorn, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Media and Law, NingboTech University, Ningbo, China. hanchao9128@nbt.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asif</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0408-7628</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UE Business School, University of Education, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahzad</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Farrukh</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6578-4139</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Economics and Management, Beijing University of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-7283</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI transparency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-induced anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial neural network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Consumer satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Technostress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: All participants provided informed consent before taking part in the survey. They were assured of voluntary participation, confidentiality, and the use of data solely for research purposes. This study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and was approved by the Institutional Review Board of the University of the Punjab, Lahore, Pakistan. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41776686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-026-04147-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40359-026-04147-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abrardi L, Cambini C, Rondi L. Artificial intelligence, firms and consumer behavior: A survey. J Economic Surveys. 2022;36(4):969&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addai P, Delle E, Okyere I, Amponsah R, Govina SE. Disrupting cognitive capacity through excessive technology use among academic staff: examining technostress, ethical decision-making, emotional exhaustion, and ethical climate. SN Bus Econ. 2025;5(10):149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Emran M, Mezhuyev V, Kamaludin A. Towards a conceptual model for examining the impact of knowledge management factors on mobile learning acceptance. Technology in Society. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.techsoc.2020.101247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sharafi MA, Iranmanesh M, Al-Emran M, Alzahrani AI, Herzallah F, Jamil N. Determinants of cloud computing integration and its impact on sustainable performance in SMEs: anempirical investigation using the SEM-ANN approach. Heliyon. 2023;9(5):e16299. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e16299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam MMD, Alam MZ, Rahman SA, Taghizadeh SK. Factors influencing mHealth adoption and its impact on mental well-being during COVID-19 pandemic: A SEM-ANN approach. J Biomed Inform. 2021;116:103722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali K, Johl SK, Muneer A, Alwadain A, Ali RF. Soft and hard total quality management practices promote industry 4.0 readiness: a SEM-neural network approach. Sustainability. 2022;14(19):11917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali RF, Jahankhani H, Ali K, Hassan B. Blockchain-Based security factors on sustainable supply chain management in UK manufacturing firms: A hybrid SEM-ANN approach. Systems. 2024;12(6):208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkawsi GA, Ali N, Mustafa AS, Baashar Y, Alhussian H, Alkahtani A, Tiong SK, Ekanayake J. A hybrid SEM-neural network method for identifying acceptance factors of the smart meters in malaysia: challenges perspective. Alexandria Eng J. 2021;60(1):227&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alowais SA, Alghamdi SS, Alsuhebany N, Alqahtani T, Alshaya AI, Almohareb SN, Aldairem A, Alrashed M, Bin Saleh K, Badreldin HA. Revolutionizing healthcare: the role of artificial intelligence in clinical practice. BMC Med Educ. 2023;23(1):689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apell P, Eriksson H. Artificial intelligence (AI) healthcare technology innovations: the current state and challenges from a life science industry perspective. Technol Anal Strateg Manag. 2023;35(2):179&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arpaci I. A multi-analytical SEM-ANN approach to investigate the social sustainability of AI chatbots based on cybersecurity and protection motivation theory. IEEE Trans Eng Manage. 2023;71:1714&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif M, Fazel H. (2024). Factors influencing tourists&#x2019; technology adoption in Saudi Arabia: examining determinants for effective use of mobile apps in tourism. Global Knowledge, Memory and Communication, ahead-ofhttp://-print(ahead-of-print)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif M, Sarwar F. Customer relationship management, financial literacy, and online banking adoption: social influence moderation-insights from technology adoption. RADS J Bus Manage. 2023;5(2):129&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif M, Sarwar F. Impact of customer relationship management, financial literacy and social influence on online banking adoption: the moderating role of personal innovativeness. Asia-Pacific J Bus Adm. 2024;17(3):744&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek TH, Kim M. Is ChatGPT scary good? How user motivations affect creepiness and trust in generative artificial intelligence. Telematics Inform. 2023;83:102030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedu&#xe9; P, Fritzsche A. Can we trust AI? An empirical investigation of trust requirements and guide to successful AI adoption. J Enterp Inform Manage. 2022;35(2):530&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell S, Greenwood M, Prior S, Shearer T, Walkem K, Young S, Bywaters D, Walker K. Purposive sampling: complex or simple? Research case examples. J Res Nurs. 2020;25(8):652&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Hu W, Wei X. From anxiety to action: exploring the impact of artificial intelligence anxiety and artificial intelligence self-efficacy on motivated learning of undergraduate students. Interact Learn Environ. 2025;33(4):3162&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong AY-L. A two-staged SEM-neural network approach for Understanding and predicting the determinants of m-commerce adoption. Expert Syst Appl. 2013;40(4):1240&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly SJ, Hearn G, Papageorgiou K. Sensemaking with AI: how trust influences human-AI collaboration in health and creative industries. Social Sci Humanit Open. 2025;11:101346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daud NM. From innovation to stress: analyzing hybrid technology adoption and its role in technostress among students. Int J Educational Technol High Educ. 2025;22(1):31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donmez O, Sefero&#x11f;lu SS. The role of ICT Self-Efficacy, Technostress, individual innovativeness and mindset on artificial intelligence literacy: artificial intelligence literacy. Int J Curriculum Instruction. 2025;17(3):950&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong CD. Modeling the determinants of HEI students&#x2019; continuance intention to use ChatGPT for learning: a stimulus&#x2013;organism&#x2013;response approach. J Res Innovative Teach Learn. 2024;17(2):391&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eppler MJ, Mengis J. The concept of information overload: A review of literature from organization science, accounting, marketing, MIS, and related disciplines. Inform Soc. 2004;20(5):325&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Buchner A, Lang A-G. Statistical power analyses using G* power 3.1: tests for correlation and regression analyses. Behav Res Methods. 2009;41(4):1149&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felzmann H, Villaronga EF, Lutz C, Tam&#xf2;-Larrieux A. Transparency you can trust: transparency requirements for artificial intelligence between legal norms and contextual concerns. Big Data Soc. 2019;6(1):2053951719860542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhang W, Zhang H, Gao R, Fang X. Global digital compact: a mechanism for the governance of online discriminatory and misleading content generation.&#xa0;Int J Hum Comput Interact. 2025;41(2):1381&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1080/10447318.2024.2314350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flavi&#xe1;n C, P&#xe9;rez-Rueda A, Belanche D, Casal&#xf3; LV. Intention to use analytical artificial intelligence (AI) in services&#x2013;the effect of technology readiness and awareness. J Service Manage. 2022;33(2):293&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornell C, Larcker DF. Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. J Mark Res. 1981;18(1):39&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank D-A, Chrysochou P, Mitkidis P, Otterbring T, Ariely D. Navigating uncertainty: exploring consumer acceptance of artificial intelligence under self-threats and high-stakes decisions. Technol Soc. 2024;79:102732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gefen D, Straub D, Boudreau M-C. Structural equation modeling and regression: guidelines for research practice. Commun Association Inform Syst. 2000;4(1):1&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn ED, Ang SH. From the editors: new directions in the reporting of statistical results in the. J World Bus. 2017;52(2):125&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair JF, Sarstedt M, Ringle CM. Rethinking some of the rethinking of partial least squares. Eur J Mark. 2019;53(4):566&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haleem A, Javaid M, Qadri MA, Singh RP, Suman R. Artificial intelligence (AI) applications for marketing: A literature-based study. Int J Intell Networks. 2022;3:119&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henseler J, Ringle CM, Sarstedt M. A new criterion for assessing discriminant validity in variance-based structural equation modeling. J Acad Mark Sci. 2015;43:115&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hentzen JK, Hoffmann A, Dolan R, Pala E. Artificial intelligence in customer-facing financial services: a systematic literature review and agenda for future research. Int J Bank Mark. 2022;40(6):1299&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornung O, Smolnik S. AI invading the workplace: negative emotions towards the organizational use of personal virtual assistants. Electron Markets. 2022;32(1):123&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MA, Agnihotri R, Rushan MRI, Rahman MS, Sumi SF. Marketing analytics capability, artificial intelligence adoption, and firms&#x2019; competitive advantage: evidence from the manufacturing industry. Ind Mark Manage. 2022;106:240&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu P, Zeng Y, Wang D, Teng H. Too much light blinds: the transparency-resistance paradox in algorithmic management. Comput Hum Behav. 2024;161:108403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain I, Sabir MR, ur Rehman N, Ghaffar I, Majeed KB. A Spatial of digital Technology, digital Literacy, performance expectancy and techno stress in pandemic conditions in technological institutes. J Disaster Recovery Bus Continuity. 2022;13(1):140&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issa H, Jaber J, Lakkis H. Navigating AI unpredictability: exploring technostress in AI-powered healthcare systems. Technol Forecast Soc Chang. 2024;202:123311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johl SK, Ali K, Shirahada K, Oyewale OI. Green servitization, circular economy, and sustainability a winning combination analysis through hybrid SEM&#x2010;ANN approach.&#xa0;Bus Strategy Environ. 2024;33(8):8978&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Park H, Kim H, Kim J, Seo K. Technostress causes cognitive overload in high-stress people: eye tracking analysis in a virtual kiosk test. Inf Process Manag. 2022;59(6):103093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kock N. Common method bias in PLS-SEM: A full collinearity assessment approach. Int J e-Collaboration (ijec). 2015;11(4):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kock N, Lynn GS. Lateral collinearity and misleading results in variance-based SEM: an illustration and recommendations. J Association Inform Syst. 2012;13(7):546&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohnke L, Zou D, Moorhouse BL. Technostress and english Language teaching in the age of generative AI. Educational Technol Soc. 2024;27(2):306&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulal A, Rahiman HU, Suvarna H, Abhishek N, Dinesh S. Enhancing public service delivery efficiency: exploring the impact of AI. J Open Innovation: Technol Market Complex. 2024;10(3):100329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Rajan B, Salunkhe U, Joag SG. Relating the dark side of new-age technologies and customer technostress. Psychol Mark. 2022;39(12):2240&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larbi-Siaw O, Xuhua H, Owusu E, Owusu-Agyeman A, Fulgence BE, Frimpong SA. Eco-innovation, sustainable business performance and market turbulence moderation in emerging economies. Technol Soc. 2022;68:101899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus RS. Stress, appraisal, and coping. Volume 445. Springer; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann CA, Haubitz CB, F&#xfc;gener A, Thonemann UW. The risk of algorithm transparency: how algorithm complexity drives the effects on the use of advice. Prod Oper Manage. 2022;31(9):3419&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong L-Y, Hew J-J, Lee V-H, Tan GW-H, Ooi K-B, Rana NP. An SEM-ANN analysis of the impacts of blockchain on competitive advantage. Industrial Manage Data Syst. 2023;123(3):967&#x2013;1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Liu Z, Chen Y, Ren A. Consumer avoidance toward message stream advertising on mobile social media: a stimulus-organism-response perspective. Inform Technol People. 2025;38(1):23&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowry PB, Gaskin J. Partial least squares (PLS) structural equation modeling (SEM) for Building and testing behavioral causal theory: when to choose it and how to use it. IEEE Trans Prof Commun. 2014;57(2):123&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu W. Inevitable challenges of autonomy: ethical concerns in personalized algorithmic decision-making. Humanit Social Sci Commun. 2024;11(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier C, Laumer S, Thatcher JB, Wirth J, Weitzel T. Trial-period technostress: A conceptual definition and mixed-methods investigation. Inform Syst Res. 2022;33(2):489&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra G, Kharub M. Elevating logistics performance: Harnessing the power of artificial intelligence in e-commerce. Int J Logistics Manage. 2025;36(1):290&#x2013;321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrabian A, Russell JA. The basic emotional impact of environments. Percept Mot Skills. 1974;38(1):283&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milo&#x161;evi&#x107; I, Ruso J, Glogovac M, Arsi&#x107; S, Raki&#x107; A. An integrated SEM-ANN approach for predicting QMS achievements in industry 4.0. Total Qual Manage Bus Excellence. 2022;33(15&#x2013;16):1896&#x2013;912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogaji E, Jain V. How generative AI is (will) change consumer behaviour: postulating the potential impact and implications for research, practice, and policy. J Consumer Behav. 2024;23(5):2379&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monod E, Mayer A-S, Straub D, Joyce E, Qi J. From worker empowerment to managerial control: the devolution of AI tools&#x2019; intended positive implementation to their negative consequences. Inf Organ. 2024;34(1):100498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtas G, Pedeliento G. Investigating the customer journey in Second-Hand fashion platforms: implications for luxury brand management. J Consumer Behav. 2025;24(2):655&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nizette F, Hammedi W, van Riel AC, Steils N. Why should I trust you? Influence of explanation design on consumer behavior in AI-based services. J Service Manage. 2025;36(1):50&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okeleke PA, Ajiga D, Folorunsho SO, Ezeigweneme C. Predictive analytics for market trends using AI: A study in consumer behavior. Int J Eng Res Updates. 2024;7(1):36&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omoge AP, Gala P, Horky A. Disruptive technology and AI in the banking industry of an emerging market. Int J Bank Mark. 2022;40(6):1217&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park K, Yoon HY. Beyond the code: the impact of AI algorithm transparency signaling on user trust and relational satisfaction. Public Relations Rev. 2024;50(5):102507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y, Wang Y, Li J, Yang Q. Impact of AI-oriented live-streaming E-commerce service failures on consumer disengagement&#x2014;empirical evidence from China. J Theoretical Appl Electron Commer Res. 2024;19(2):1580&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsakoff PM, MacKenzie SB, Lee J-Y, Podsakoff NP. Common method biases in behavioral research: a critical review of the literature and recommended remedies. J Appl Psychol. 2003;88(5):879&#x2013;903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priporas CV, Hussain S, Khaneja S, Rahman H. Technology distraction in generation Z: the effects on consumer responses, sensory overload, and discomfort. Int J Inf Manag. 2024;75:102751.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringle CM, Sarstedt M. Gain more insight from your PLS-SEM results: the importance-performance map analysis. Industrial Manage Data Syst. 2016;116(9):1865&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez TW, Brenman M, Ye X. The ethical concerns of artificial intelligence in urban planning. J Am Plann Association. 2024;91(2):294&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzad F, Xiu G, Khan MAS, Shahbaz M. Predicting the adoption of a mobile government security response system from the user&#x2019;s perspective: an application of the artificial neural network approach. Technol Soc. 2020;62:101278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahzad MF, Xu S, An X, Zahid H, Asif M. Learning and teaching in the era of generative artificial intelligence technologies: an In-Depth exploration using Multi&#x2010;Analytical SEM&#x2010;ANN approach. Eur J Educ. 2025;60(1):e70050. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejed.70050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Gupta B. Investigating the role of technostress, cognitive appraisal and coping strategies on students&#x2019; learning performance in higher education: a multidimensional transactional theory of stress approach. Inform Technol People. 2023;36(2):626&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiau W-L, Huang L-C. Scale development for analyzing the fit of real and virtual world integration: an example of Pok&#xe9;mon go. Inform Technol People. 2023;36(2):500&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin D, Kee KF, Shin EY. Algorithm awareness: why user awareness is critical for personal privacy in the adoption of algorithmic platforms? Int J Inf Manag. 2022;65:102494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddik AB, Yong L, Rahman MN. The role of fintech in circular economy practices to improve sustainability performance: a two-staged SEM-ANN approach. Environ Sci Pollut Res. 2023;30(49):107465&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P, Singh V. The power of AI: enhancing customer loyalty through satisfaction and efficiency. Cogent Bus Manage. 2024;11(1):2326107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sison AJG, Daza MT, Gozalo-Brizuela R, Garrido-Merch&#xe1;n EC. ChatGPT: more than a weapon of mass deception ethical challenges and responses from the human-centered artificial intelligence (HCAI) perspective. Int J Human&#x2013;Computer Interact. 2024;40(17):4853&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song L, Yao S, Liu L, Tso G. Investigating binge-watching and its effect on paid subscription: A mixed&#x2010;method study based on SOR theory. J Consumer Behav. 2025;24(1):20&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suh A, Prophet J. The state of immersive technology research: A literature analysis. Comput Hum Behav. 2018;86:77&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suhail F, Adel M, Al-Emran M, AlQudah AA. Are students ready for robots in higher education? Examining the adoption of robots by integrating UTAUT2 and TTF using a hybrid SEM-ANN approach. Technol Soc. 2024;77:102524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweller J. Cognitive load during problem solving: effects on learning. Cogn Sci. 1988;12(2):257&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong H, Yu J, Shou M. Mitigating the effect of AI anxiety on employees&#x2019; creativity: A social cognitive perspective. J Digit Manage. 2025;1(1):7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y-Y, Wang Y-S. Development and validation of an artificial intelligence anxiety scale: an initial application in predicting motivated learning behavior. Interact Learn Environ. 2022;30(4):619&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanner J, Herm L-V, Heinrich K, Janiesch C. The effect of transparency and trust on intelligent system acceptance: evidence from a user-based study. Electron Markets. 2022;32(4):2079&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willems J, Schmid MJ, Vanderelst D, Vogel D, Ebinger F. AI-driven public services and the privacy paradox: do citizens really care about their privacy? Public Manage Rev. 2023;25(11):2116&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu R, Ishfaq K, Hussain S, Asmi F, Siddiquei AN, Anwar MA. Investigating e-retailers&#x2019; intentions to adopt cryptocurrency considering the mediation of technostress and technology involvement. Sustainability. 2022;14(2):641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X-Y, Jia Q-D, Tayyab SMU. Exploring the stimulating role of augmented reality features in E-commerce: A three-staged hybrid approach. J Retailing Consumer Serv. 2024;77:103682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Li D, Hu P. Decoding algorithm fatigue: the role of algorithmic literacy, information cocoons, and algorithmic opacity. Technol Soc. 2024;79:102749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Xiong Y. Harnessing AI potential in E-Commerce: improving user engagement and sales through deep learning-based product recommendations. Curr Psychol. 2024;43(38):30379&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Zhang Z. AI in teacher education: unlocking new dimensions in teaching support, inclusive learning, and digital literacy. J Comput Assist Learn. 2024;40(4):1871&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu J, Chen H, Jiang Y. Enhancing trust and empathy in marketing: Strategic AI and human influencer selection for optimized content persuasion.&#xa0;J Consum Behav. 2025;24(2):866&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1002/cb.2423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Tang D, Mehta AM, Yu Y, Shahzad MF, Asif M. Adoption of green technologies, smart energy use, and public environmental awareness: A SEM&#x2010;ANN model for sustainable energy transition. Environmental Progress &amp; Sustainable Energy. 2025:e70291. https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.70291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Li H, Wang F-K, He W, Tian Z. How online reviews affect purchase intention: a new model based on the stimulus-organism-response (S-O-R) framework. Aslib J Inform Manage. 2020;72(4):463&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>