<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41682111</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2073-4360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Polymers</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Polymers (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Numerical Simulation of Failure Modes of Solid Propellants with Internal Cavities Under Various Loading Conditions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">404</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/polym18030404</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The reliability of solid rocket motors depends primarily on the structural integrity of their propellants. Internal cavity defects in the widely used hydroxyl-terminated polybutadiene (HTPB) propellant, formed during manufacturing and service, significantly degrade its mechanical properties and compromise motor safety. This study developed a constitutive model for HTPB propellant based on the generalized incremental stress-strain damage model (GISSMO). The validity of the constitutive model was verified through uniaxial tensile tests conducted at various tensile rates. Based on this constitutive model, numerical simulations were performed to examine the effects of initial modulus, impact rate, and cavity confining pressure on the failure modes of propellants containing cavities with radii from 40 to 100 mm. The results show that the simulation's force-displacement curve agrees well with the test. The simulation accurately captures the propellant's transition from elastic-plastic plateau at low rates to elastic response at high rates. The prediction error for the maximum tensile force is less than 5%. For cavities of 80 mm and 100 mm, local stress concentration causes damage to the inner wall, followed by rapid cavity extrusion, collapse, and possible cross-shaped matrix fracture. However, cavities of 40 mm and 60 mm show greater stability, experiencing only volume compression, which rarely causes overall damage. When the propellant's initial modulus is higher than 24 MPa, damage propagation in large cavities over 80 mm is suppressed. A low modulus worsens structural deformation. At low impact velocity, cavity compression is significant, and the structure remains conformal. At high impact velocity (4000 MPa/s), the cavity stays conformal, the matrix collapses, and the damage value decreases. For 60 mm cavities, damage is localized, and the overall structure is most stable within a confining pressure of 5 to 9.5 MPa. This study clarifies the interaction between engineering parameters and cavity size, providing a basis for optimizing the safety of the propellant structure.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Graduate College for Elite Engineers, Beihang University, Beijing 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Institute of Xi'an Areospace Solid Propusion Technology, Xi'an 710025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Qingchun</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2202-7541</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Astronautics, Beihang University, Beijing 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Beijing University of Technology, Beijing 100124, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jianru</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academy of Aerospace Solid Propulsion Technology, Xi'an 710025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5645-734X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Beijing University of Technology, Beijing 100124, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52578543</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Polymers (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2073-4360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GISSMO model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cavity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">failure mode</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impact</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">propellant</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41682111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12899833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym18030404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">polym18030404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li L., Ingabire C., Liang D., Li J., Zhou Y., Jiang Y., Shen D. Comparative study on mechanical properties and combustion characteristics of additive manufacturing/casting composite solid propellants. Acta Astronaut. 2025;229:43&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1016/j.actaastro.2025.01.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actaastro.2025.01.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lajoie J.A., Jones B., Lawrence A.R., Barkley S.J., Sippel T.R. On-demand microwave growth of porosity within a granular composite energetic material: Void formation via a dielectric loss phase change binder additive for propellant burning rate control. Propellants Explos. Pyrotech. 2024;49:e202300229. doi: 10.1002/prep.202300229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/prep.202300229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo F., Nie J., Zhang S., Liang J., Liu R., Zou Y., Han Y. Effects of Thermal Damage on Impact Response Characteristics of High-Energy Propellants. Polymers. 2024;16:748. doi: 10.3390/polym16060748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym16060748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10974251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38543354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Xu J., Han J., He Y. Effect of Microstructure on Micro-Mechanical Properties of Composite Solid Propellant. Micromachines. 2021;12:1378. doi: 10.3390/mi12111378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mi12111378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8619534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34832790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei S., Qiang H., Wang X., Wang J., Li S. Micromechanical Behavior of HTPB Propellant Bonding Interface under Uniaxial Tensile Loading. Propellants Explos. Pyrotech. 2022;47:e202200106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu R., Prakash C., Tomar V., Harr M., Gunduz I.E., Oskay C. Experimentally-validated mesoscale modeling of the coupled mechanical&#x2013;thermal response of AP&#x2013;HTPB energetic material under dynamic loading. Int. J. Fract. 2017;203:277&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Wang N., Zhang Y., Xia H., Shang Y., Liu X., Wu Y. Dynamic mechanical response and failure behavior of solid propellant under shock wave impact. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2024;164:108700. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dollet B., Marmottant P., Garbin V. Bubble Dynamics in Soft and Biological Matter. Annu. Rev. Fluid Mech. 2019;51:331&#x2013;355. doi: 10.1146/annurev-fluid-010518-040352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-fluid-010518-040352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., McGhee A., Radtke G., Mauro Rodriguez J., Franck C. Estimating viscoelastic, soft material properties using a modified Rayleigh cavitation bubble collapse time. Phys. Fluids. 2024;36:017136. doi: 10.1063/5.0179368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0179368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y., Xi H., Gu Z., Yan X. Cavitation-driven bubble evolution and load mechanisms in particle-wall multiphase interactions. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2025;120:107461. doi: 10.1016/j.ultsonch.2025.107461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2025.107461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12284372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40680605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Zhan J., Li Y. Numerical simulation of cavitation-bubble expansion and collapse inside a bottle subjected to impact on its topside. Eng. Appl. Comput. Fluid Mech. 2021;15:1440&#x2013;1451. doi: 10.1080/19942060.2021.1976279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19942060.2021.1976279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawlor B.P., Gandhi V., Ravichandran G. Full-field quantitative visualization of shock-driven pore collapse and failure modes in PMMA. J. Appl. Phys. 2024;136:225901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moschopoulos P., Spyridakis A., Varchanis S., Dimakopoulos Y., Tsamopoulos J. The concept of elasto-visco-plasticity and its application to a bubble rising in yield stress fluids. J. Non-Newton. Fluid Mech. 2021;297:104670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanjay V., Lohse D., Jalaal M. Bursting bubble in a viscoplastic medium. J. Fluid Mech. 2021;922:A2. doi: 10.1017/jfm.2021.489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/jfm.2021.489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vial C., Narchi I. Development of a Model Foamy Viscous Fluid. Oil Gas Sci. Technol. 2014;69:481&#x2013;497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin D., Zou Q., Lei S., Wang W., Li Z. Cavitation Dynamics and Inertial Cavitation Threshold of Lipid Coated Microbubbles in Viscoelastic Media with Bubble&#x2013;Bubble Interactions. Micromachines. 2021;12:1125. doi: 10.3390/mi12091125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mi12091125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34577768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moschopoulos P., Spyridakis A., Dimakopoulos Y., Tsamopoulos J. Unravelling the existence of asymmetric bubbles in viscoelastic fluids. J. Fluid Mech. 2024;985:A30. doi: 10.1017/jfm.2024.316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/jfm.2024.316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Yuan W., Mei M., Li Y., Li M., Aubry N. On the flow of a bubble pair rising in temperature-sensitive gel propellants. Phys. Fluids. 2023;35:083104. doi: 10.1063/5.0160995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0160995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Yuan W., Li Y., Massoudi M., Wu W. On the flow of a single bubble rising in temperature-sensitive gelled propellants. J. Non-Newton. Fluid Mech. 2023;319:105085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z., Wang C., Zhang K., Zhai C., Wang H., Zhu F., Wang X. Mesoscopic damage evolution and rate-dependent porosity prediction model of a composite propellant by in situ X-ray tomography. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2025;270:111267. doi: 10.1016/j.compscitech.2025.111267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2025.111267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Qiang H., Zhang Y., Wang Z., Zhu Z. Damage softening constitutive model of HTPB propellant for biaxial loading. Int. J. Non-Linear Mech. 2023;154:104426. doi: 10.1016/j.ijnonlinmec.2023.104426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijnonlinmec.2023.104426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng P., Fan Z., Yu P., Shen Z. Tensile-Compressive Asymmetric Mechanical Properties and Constitutive Model of HTPB Propellant. Appl. Compos. Mater. 2025;32:1183&#x2013;1196. doi: 10.1007/s10443-025-10305-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10443-025-10305-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Qiang H., Wang G., Huang Q. Tensile mechanical properties and constitutive model for HTPB propellant at low temperature and high strain rate. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2015;132:42104. doi: 10.1002/app.42104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.42104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K., Dong Z., Zhai C., Wang C., Li Q., Wang X. Damage analysis of solid propellants with default defects based on macro-microscopic approach. Mater. Des. 2024;245:113261. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2024.113261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2024.113261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing R., Wang L., Zhang F., Hou C. Mechanical behavior and constitutive model of NEPE solid propellant in finite deformation. Mech. Mater. 2022;172:104383. doi: 10.1016/j.mechmat.2022.104383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mechmat.2022.104383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei M., Chen E., Zhao Z., Wen L., Xiao J., Hou X. A temperature/strain-rate-dependent finite deformation constitutive and failure model for solid propellants. Sci. China-Phys. Mech. Astron. 2023;66:294611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Li Z., He H., Chen L., Miao Y. Mechanical Behaviors and Constitutive Relations under wide strain rate range for CMDB propellant. Polym. Test. 2022;116:107806. doi: 10.1016/j.polymertesting.2022.107806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymertesting.2022.107806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateos D., Boakye-Yiadom S. Effect of stress state on adiabatic shear banding in Al2024-T351. Int. J. Impact Eng. 2023;178:104602. doi: 10.1016/j.ijimpeng.2023.104602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijimpeng.2023.104602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadiri M.M., Agyapong J., Boakye-Yiadom S., Jian C. Rate dependence of high strength steels mechanical behavior: Characterization, modelling and impact applications. Int. J. Impact Eng. 2025;206:105454. doi: 10.1016/j.ijimpeng.2025.105454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijimpeng.2025.105454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Zhu B., Wu Z., Hu B., Li Y., Guo Y. Deformation and failure behavior of 2024-T42 sheet under impact loading. Thin-Walled Struct. 2024;203:112230. doi: 10.1016/j.tws.2024.112230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tws.2024.112230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadian P., Kortenaar L.T., Omer K., Butcher C., Worswick M.J. Fracture characterization of tailored Usibor&#xae; 1500-AS and damage modelling based on a coupled-micromechanical-phenomenological strategy. Eng. Fract. Mech. 2020;223:106785. doi: 10.1016/j.engfracmech.2019.106785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2019.106785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Kiran R., Hu J., Hector L.G., Jr., Bower A.F. Analysis and design of a three-phase TRIP steel microstructure for enhanced fracture resistance. Int. J. Fract. 2020;221:53&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1007/s10704-019-00405-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10704-019-00405-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neukamm F., Feucht M., Roll K., Haufe A. On closing the Constitutive Gap between Forming and Crash Simulation; Proceedings of the 10th International LS-DYNA&#xae; Users Conference; Dearborn, MI, USA. 8&#x2013;10 June 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neukamm F., Haufe A., Feucht M. Consistent Damage Modelling in the Process Chain of Forming to Crashworthiness Simulations; Proceedings of the 7th European LS-DYNA Conference; Salzburg, Austria. 14&#x2013;15 May 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao K., Toussaint G., Komrakova A., Hogan J.D. High-velocity impact failure modeling of Armox 500T steel: Model validation and application to structural design. Int. J. Impact Eng. 2024;183:104790. doi: 10.1016/j.ijimpeng.2023.104790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijimpeng.2023.104790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickhey F., Park T., Hong S. Damage prediction in thermoplastics under impact loading using a strain rate-dependent GISSMO. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2023;149:107246. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J., Zhou J., Song D., Shi Z., Miao C. A stress state-dependent phase-field model of ductile fracture for visco-elastic&#x2013;plastic materials. Eng. Fract. Mech. 2025;326:111409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livermore Software Technology Corporation (LSTC)  LS-DYNA, Version R11.1.  [(accessed on 20 May 2024)].  Available online:  https://www.lstc.com/products/ls-dyna.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danas K., Ponte C.P. Influence of the lode parameter and the stress triaxiality on the failure of elasto-plastic porous materials. Int. J. Solids Struct. 2012;49:1325&#x2013;1342. doi: 10.1016/j.ijsolstr.2012.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsolstr.2012.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8;rvik T., Hopperstad O.S., Berstad T., Langseth M. A computational model of viscoplasticity and ductile damage for impact and penetration. Eur. J. Mech. A/Solids. 2001;20:685&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1016/S0997-7538(01)01157-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0997-7538(01)01157-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemaitre J. A Continuous Damage Mechanics Model for Ductile Fracture. J. Eng. Mater. Technol. 1985;107:83&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1115/1.3225775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.3225775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y., Xu J., Zhou C., Chen X. Microstructural simulations of debonding, nucleation, and crack propagation in an HMX-MDB propellant. Mater. Des. 2021;207:109854. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2021.109854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2021.109854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Chang H., Li X., Wu X., He Q. The effect of strain rate on compressive behavior and failure mechanism of CMDB propellant. Def. Technol. 2022;18:467&#x2013;475. doi: 10.1016/j.dt.2021.02.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dt.2021.02.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai G.D., Sang L.P., Bian Y.L., Xie H.L., Liu J.H., Chai H.W. Interfacial debonding and cracking in a solid propellant composite under uniaxial tension: An in situ synchrotron X-ray tomography study. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2024;256:110743. doi: 10.1016/j.compscitech.2024.110743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2024.110743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji Y., Cao L., Li Z., Chen G., Cao P., Liu T. Numerical Conversion Method for the Dynamic Storage Modulus and Relaxation Modulus of Hydroxy-Terminated Polybutadiene (HTPB) Propellants. Polymers. 2023;15:3. doi: 10.3390/polym15010003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15010003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9824529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36616352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan H., Wu Y., Yang K., Maimaitituersun W., Wang N., Chen J.S., Huang F. An experimental study on dynamic deformation and ignition response of a novel propellant under impact loading. Polym. Test. 2022;107:107472. doi: 10.1016/j.polymertesting.2022.107472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymertesting.2022.107472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>