<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41807628</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sensitivity-informed framework for enrichment distribution in MNR for thermal performance enhancement.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43564-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As interest in space exploration and remote power systems grows, Micro Nuclear Reactors (MNRs) are being explored for their compactness, long operational life, and inherent safety. However, challenges such as Radial Power Peaking (RPP), structural integrity, and fuel utilization under high-temperature conditions remain inadequately addressed. In this study, the issues of RPP, uneven power distribution, and related safety concerns have been analyzed. RPP occurs because neutron flux and subsequent fission rates decrease while moving from the core center toward the periphery. In the annular-fueled MNR core presented, a maximum power peaking factor of 1.28 is observed. RPP poses a significant design challenge as it induces geometric distortion, reduces the fuel clad gap, and may lead to Fuel Clad Mechanical Interaction (FCMI), which is treated as a design-basis operational constraint for long-term autonomous operation of the reactor presented in this study. Consequently, the designed 1 MWth core power must be reduced in proportion to the peaking factor, limiting the allowable operating power to 738 kWth to ensure local thermal-mechanical limits are not exceeded. This study proposes a novel, zone-based, sensitivity-informed non-uniform fuel enrichment framework that mitigates RPP without any physical design changes. For the annular-fueled MNR core, the strategy reduces RPP by 75%, enabling a 28.7% increase in safe operating power from 738 kWth to approximately 950 kWth.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aziz</LastName><ForeName>Umair</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechatronics Engineering, Air University, Islamabad, Pakistan. umair.aziz@au.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Hamda</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sciences and Humanities, National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences, Islamabad, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussain</LastName><ForeName>Zahid</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechatronics Engineering, Air University, Islamabad, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ullah</LastName><ForeName>Khalil</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sciences and Humanities, National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences, Islamabad, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Imran</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechatronics Engineering, Air University, Islamabad, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jung</LastName><ForeName>Dong-Won</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Applied Energy System, Major of Mechanical Engineering, Jeju National University, 102 Jejudaehak-ro, Jeju-Si, 63243, Republic of Korea. jdwcheju@jejunu.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025-RISE-17-001</GrantID><Agency>Regional Innovation System &amp; Education (RISE) program through the (Jeju Rise Center), funded by the Ministry of Education (MOE)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FCMI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fuel-clad mechanical interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Micro nuclear reactor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-uniform fuel distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OpenMC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radial power peaking</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41807628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43564-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43564-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Testoni, R., Bersano, A. &amp; Segantin, S. Review of nuclear microreactors: Status, potentialities and challenges. Prog. Nucl. Energy. 138, 103822 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fakhrul Islam, M. A. S. Conceptual Design and Preliminary Safety Analysis of a Proposed Nuclear Microreactor for Mobile Application. https://scholarcommons.sc.edu/etd</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Genk, M. S. Conceptual Design of HP-STMCs Space Reactor Power System for 110 kWe. 658&#x2013;672 (2004). https://doi.org/10.1063/1.1649628</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poston, D. I., Kapernick, R. J. &amp; Guffee, R. M. Design and analysis of the SAFE-400 space fission reactor in 578&#x2013;588 (AIP Publishing, 2007). https://doi.org/10.1063/1.1449775</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poston, D. I., Gibson, M. &amp; McClure, P. Kilopower reactors for potential space exploration missions. in Nuclear and Emerging Technologies for Space, American Nuclear Society Topical Meeting. ANSRichland, WA, USA, (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zohuri, B. Nuclear Micro Reactors. Nuclear Micro Reactors (Springer International Publishing, 2020). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-47225-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi, Y. Comparative Assessment of Small Modular Reactor Passive Safety System Design via Integration of Dynamic Methods of Analyses. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett, G. Space Nuclear Power: Opening the Final Frontier. in 4th International Energy Conversion Engineering Conference and Exhibit (IECEC)American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Reston, Virigina, (2006). https://doi.org/10.2514/6.2006-4191</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Genk, M. S. &amp; Tournier, J. Conceptual design of HP&#x2010;STMCs space reactor power system for 110 kWe. in AIP Conference Proceedings vol. 699 658&#x2013;672American Institute of Physics, (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Neutronic design study of an integrated space nuclear reactor with Stirling engine. Ann. Nucl. Energy. 142, 107382 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz, U. &amp; A study of critical ity and ther mal load ing in a con cep tual micronuclear heat pipere actor. 35, 208&#x2013;215 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayat, A. Developing a practical optimization of the refueling program for ordinary research reactors using a modified simulated annealing method. Prog. Nucl. Energy. 76, 191&#x2013;205 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamarsh, J. R. Introduction to Nuclear Reactor Theory (American Nuclear Society, 2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, H. et al. Conceptual design and analysis of a multipurpose micro nuclear reactor power source. Ann. Nucl. Energy. 121, 118&#x2013;127 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zohuri, B. Nuclear Industry Trend Toward Small and Micro Nuclear Power Plants. in Nuclear Micro Reactors 41&#x2013;97Springer, (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. et al. Performance analysis of heat pipe radiator unit for space nuclear power reactor. Ann. Nucl. Energy. 103, 74&#x2013;84 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs, M. H., Gibson, M. A. &amp; Sanzi, J. Electrically heated testing of the Kilowatt Reactor Using Stirling TechnologY (KRUSTY) experiment using a depleted uranium core. 15th International Energy Conversion Engineering Conference, (2017). https://doi.org/10.2514/6.2017-4610 (2017) doi:10.2514/6.2017-4610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Genk, M. &amp; Tournier, J. M. Uses of liquid-metal and water heat pipes in space reactor power systems. Frontiers Heat. Pipes (FHP) 2, (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz, U., Koreshi, Z. U., Khan, H. &amp; Sheikh, S. R. Non-uniform fuel distribution and thermo-mechanical analysis of a 1&#xa0;MW thermal power micronuclear heat pipe reactor. Heliyon 10, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Research on power flattening method and neutron characteristic analysis of a megawatt-class space gas-cooled fast reactor. Ann. Nucl. Energy. 161, 108456 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poston, D. I., Gibson, M. A., Godfroy, T. &amp; McClure, P. R. KRUSTY Reactor Design. Nucl. Technol. 206, 13&#x2013;30 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano, P. et al. OpenMC Doc. (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. Thermal-hydraulic analysis of dual-cooled annular fuel element. in Progress report on nuclear science and technology in China (Vol. 6). Proceedings of academic annual meeting of China Nuclear Society in No. 3&#x2013;Nuclear Energy and Power sub-volume (2020). (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, D., Hejzlar, P. &amp; Kazimi, M. S. Thermal-hydraulic design of high-power-density annular fuel in PWRs. Nucl. Technol. 160, 16&#x2013;44 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, H. E. &amp; Ahmed, M. I. Thermal performance of annulus with its applications; A review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 71, 170&#x2013;190 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harto, A. W. et al. Neutronic characteristic analysis of the GAMA microreactor. Heliyon 10, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stauff, N. E., Lee, C. H., Wells, A. &amp; Filippone, C. Design optimization of the holos-quad micro-reactor concept. in International Conference on Physics of Reactors: Transition to a Scalable Nuclear Future, PHYSOR 2020 vols 2020-March 44&#x2013;53 (EDP Sciences - Web of Conferences, (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todreas, N. E. &amp; Kazimi, M. S. Nuclear Systems Volume I: Thermal Hydraulic Fundamentals (CRC, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incropera, F. P., DeWitt, D. P., Bergman, T. L. &amp; Lavine, A. S. Fundamentals of Heat and Mass Transfer. vol. 6Wiley New York, (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boley, B. A. &amp; Weiner, J. H. Theory of Thermal Stresses (Wiley, 1962).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timoshenko, S. &amp; Goodier, J. Theory of Elasticity. McGraw-Hill Book. Co. Inc (1951).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, S. L., Thomas, J. K. &amp; Peddicord, K. L. Material Property Correlations for Uranium Mononitride II. Mechanical Properties. Journal Nuclear Materials 171 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lew, B. S. Safety Analysis of LOCA Events for Small Compact Reactors in Space Using UN Fuel (University of California, 1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, S. L., Thomas, J. K. &amp; Peddicord, K. L. Material property correlations for uranium mononitride: II. Mechanical properties. J. Nucl. Mater. 171, 271&#x2013;288 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, H. et al. Mechanical and microstructural responses in molybdenum-rhenium alloys under hot compressions. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 30, 3877&#x2013;3885 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee, A. S. M. H. Properties and Selection: Nonferrous Alloys and Special-Purpose Materials (ASM international, 1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo, W. &amp; Laafz, E. NASt TM X-2838 CASE FILE COPY CALCULATED POWER DISTRIBUTION OF A THERMIONIC, BERYLLIUM OXIDE REFLECTED, FAST-SPECTRUM REACTOR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun, S., Baek, M. H., Yoo, J. &amp; Kim, S. J. Effect of Reflector Material on the Neutronic Characteristics of the Small Sodium-Cooled Fast Reactor. Transactions Korean Nuclear Soc. Spring Meeting Jeju.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>