<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600470</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leveraging Machine Learning Classifiers in Transfer Learning for Few-Shot Modulation Recognition.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">674</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020674</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid advancement of communication systems has heightened the demand for efficient and robust modulation recognition. Conventional deep learning-based methods, however, often struggle in practical few-shot scenarios where acquiring sufficient labeled training data is prohibitive. To bridge this gap, this paper proposes a hybrid transfer learning (HTL) approach that synergistically combines the representation power of deep feature extraction with the flexibility and stability of traditional machine learning (ML) classifiers. The proposed method capitalizes on knowledge transferred from large-scale auxiliary datasets through pre-training, followed by few-shot adaptation using simple ML classifiers. Multiple classical ML classifiers are incorporated and evaluated within the HTL framework for few-shot modulation recognition (FSMR). Comprehensive experiments demonstrate that HTL consistently outperforms existing baseline methods in such data-scarce settings. Furthermore, a detailed analysis of several key parameters is conducted to assess their impact on performance and to inform deployment in practical environments. Notably, the results indicate that the K-nearest neighbor classifier, owing to its instance-based and non-parametric nature, delivers the most robust and generalizable performance within the HTL paradigm, offering a promising solution for reliable FSMR in real-world applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Song</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9724-9325</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Tracking and Telecommunications Technology, Beijing 100094, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Tracking and Telecommunications Technology, Beijing 100094, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Tracking and Telecommunications Technology, Beijing 100094, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Institute of Tracking and Telecommunications Technology, Beijing 100094, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">few-shot learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">modulation recognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transfer learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12846240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xiao W., Luo Z., Hu Q. A review of research on signal modulation recognition based on deep learning. Electronics. 2022;11:2764. doi: 10.3390/electronics11172764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics11172764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-haryqy N., Madini Z., Zouine Y. A review of deep learning techniques for enhancing spectrum sensing and prediction in cognitive radio systems: Approaches, datasets, and challenges. Int. J. Comput. Appl. 2024;46:1104&#x2013;1128. doi: 10.1080/1206212X.2024.2414042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1206212X.2024.2414042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Chikha H., Alaerjan A., Jabeur R. Automatic classification of 5G waveform-modulated signals using deep residual networks. Sensors. 2025;25:4682. doi: 10.3390/s25154682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25154682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12349226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40807847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbruggen D., Sallouha H., Pollin S. Distributed deep learning for modulation classification in 6G cell-free wireless networks; Proceedings of the IEEE International Symposium on Dynamic Spectrum Access Networks; Washington, DC, USA. 13&#x2013;16 May 2024; pp. 114&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J., Yu Z., Yang J. A lightweight deep learning architecture for automatic modulation classification of wireless internet of things. IET Commun. 2024;18:1220&#x2013;1230. doi: 10.1049/cmu2.12823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/cmu2.12823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu N., Ding G., Fu Y., Zhang J., He D. Toward space&#x2013;air&#x2013;ground information networks: Next frontier for wireless communications. Space Sci. Technol. 2025;5:395. doi: 10.34133/space.0395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/space.0395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felix E.A., Lee S.P. Systematic literature review of preprocessing techniques for imbalanced data. IET Softw. 2019;13:479&#x2013;496. doi: 10.1049/iet-sen.2018.5193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-sen.2018.5193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmutalab A., Assaleh K., El-Tarhuni M. Automatic modulation classification based on high order cumulants and hierarchical polynomial classifiers. Phys. Commun. 2016;21:10&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/j.phycom.2016.08.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phycom.2016.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson K., Goldschneider J.R., Cazzanti L., Pitton J.W. Feature-based modulation classification using circular statistics; Proceedings of the IEEE Military Communications Conference; Monterey, CA, USA. 31 October&#x2013;3 November 2004; pp. 765&#x2013;771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Shea T.J., Corgan J., Clancy T.C. Convolutional radio modulation recognition networks; Proceedings of the 17th International Conference on Engineering Applications of Neural Networks; Aberdeen, Scotland, UK. 2&#x2013;5 September 2016; pp. 213&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser E., Moran M.K., Hillen E., Li D., Wu Z. Automatic modulation classification via instantaneous features; Proceedings of the National Aerospace and Electronics Conference; Dayton, OH, USA. 15&#x2013;19 June 2015; pp. 218&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng S., Jiang H., Wang H., Alwageed H., Zhou Y., Sebdani M.M., Yao Y.D. Modulation classification based on signal constellation diagrams and deep learning. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 2018;30:718&#x2013;727. doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2018.2850703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2018.2850703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30047904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Liu L., Zhao Z. DTFTCNet: Radar modulation recognition with deep time-frequency transformation. IEEE Trans. Cogn. Commun. Netw. 2023;9:1200&#x2013;1210. doi: 10.1109/TCCN.2023.3280949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCCN.2023.3280949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghauri S.A. KNN based classification of digital modulated signals. IIUM Eng. J. 2016;17:71&#x2013;82. doi: 10.31436/iiumej.v17i2.641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31436/iiumej.v17i2.641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabatabaei T.S., Krishnan S., Anpalagan A. SVM-based classification of digital modulation signals; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man and Cybernetics; Istanbul, Turkey. 10&#x2013;13 October 2010; pp. 277&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West N.E., O&#x2019;shea T. Deep architectures for modulation recognition; Proceedings of the IEEE International Symposium on Dynamic Spectrum Access Networks; Baltimore, MD, USA. 6&#x2013;9 March 2017; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Liu M., Yang J., Gui G. Data-driven deep learning for automatic modulation recognition in cognitive radios. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2019;68:4074&#x2013;4077. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2019.2900460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2019.2900460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd-Elaziz O.F., Abdalla M., Elsayed R.A. Deep learning-based automatic modulation classification using robust CNN architecture for cognitive radio networks. Sensors. 2023;23:9467. doi: 10.3390/s23239467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23239467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10708862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38067839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He K., Zhang X., Ren S., Sun J. Deep residual learning for image recognition; Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Las Vegas, NV, USA. 26 June&#x2013;1 July 2016; pp. 770&#x2013;778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Shea T.J., Roy T., Clancy T.C. Over-the-air deep learning based radio signal classification. IEEE J. Sel. Top. Signal Process. 2018;12:168&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1109/JSTSP.2018.2797022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSTSP.2018.2797022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh-The T., Hua C.H., Pham Q.V., Kim D.S. MCNet: An efficient CNN architecture for robust automatic modulation classification. IEEE Commun. Lett. 2020;24:811&#x2013;815. doi: 10.1109/LCOMM.2020.2968030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LCOMM.2020.2968030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S., Pei Y., Liang P.P., Liang Y.C. Robust modulation classification under uncertain noise condition using recurrent neural network; Proceedings of the IEEE Global Communications Conference; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates. 9&#x2013;13 December 2018; pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Z., Vikalo H. Real-time radio technology and modulation classification via an LSTM auto-encoder. IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun. 2021;21:370&#x2013;382. doi: 10.1109/TWC.2021.3095855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TWC.2021.3095855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., Gao G., Li B., Wang W., Ghannouchi F.M. A novel lightweight grouped gated recurrent unit for automatic modulation classification. IEEE Wirel. Commun. Lett. 2024;13:2135&#x2013;2139. doi: 10.1109/LWC.2024.3402975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LWC.2024.3402975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamidi-Rad S., Jain S. MCformer: A Transformer based deep neural network for automatic modulation classification; Proceedings of the IEEE Global Communications Conference; Madrid, Spain. 7&#x2013;11 December 2021; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai J., Gan F., Cao X., Liu W. Signal modulation classification based on the Transformer network. IEEE Trans. Cogn. Commun. Netw. 2022;8:1348&#x2013;1357. doi: 10.1109/TCCN.2022.3176640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCCN.2022.3176640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Zhu Y., Zhu Z. Automatic modulation classification using ResNeXt-GRU with deep feature fusion. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2023;72:2519710. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2023.3290301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2023.3290301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Zhang W., Zhao Z., Tang P., Zhang Z. Robust automatic modulation classification via a lightweight temporal hybrid neural network. Sensors. 2024;24:7908. doi: 10.3390/s24247908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24247908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11679410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39771646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S., Khan S., Porikli F. A unified approach for conventional zero-shot, generalized zero-shot, and few-shot learning. IEEE Trans. Image Process. 2018;27:5652&#x2013;5667. doi: 10.1109/TIP.2018.2861573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2018.2861573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30072324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Bai J., Wang Y., Jiao L., Zheng S., Shen W., Xu J., Yang X. Few-shot electromagnetic signal classification: A data union augmentation method. Chin. J. Aeronaut. 2022;35:49&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1016/j.cja.2021.07.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cja.2021.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J., Sun P., Jiang Y., Wen Z., Guo F., Wu Y., Hong Z., Duan H., Huang Y., Ranjan R., et al. A semantic-consistent few-shot modulation recognition framework for IoT applications. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 2025;36:8100&#x2013;8111. doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2024.3441597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2024.3441597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Xu H., Jiang L., Qi Z. ConvLSTMAE: A spatiotemporal parallel autoencoders for automatic modulation classification. IEEE Commun. Lett. 2022;26:1804&#x2013;1808. doi: 10.1109/lcomm.2022.3179003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/lcomm.2022.3179003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Zhou F., Wu Q., Al-Dhahir N. SSwsrNet: A semi-supervised few-shot learning framework for wireless signal recognition. IEEE Trans. Commun. 2024;72:5823&#x2013;5836. doi: 10.1109/TCOMM.2024.3385921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2024.3385921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Huang J., Cheng Q., Meng H., Han Z. Automatic modulation recognition: A few-shot learning method based on the capsule network. IEEE Wirel. Commun. Lett. 2021;10:474&#x2013;477. doi: 10.1109/LWC.2020.3034913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LWC.2020.3034913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Bai J., Xiao Z., Zhou H., Jiao L. MsmcNet: A modular few-shot learning framework for signal modulation classification. IEEE Trans. Signal Process. 2022;70:3789&#x2013;3801. doi: 10.1109/TSP.2022.3191783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSP.2022.3191783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che J., Wang L., Bai X., Liu C., Zhou F. Spatial-temporal hybrid feature extraction network for few-shot automatic modulation classification. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2022;71:13387&#x2013;13392. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2022.3196103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3196103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu M., Ma J., Yang Z., Wang J., Wu Z. Multi-component feature extraction for few-sample automatic modulation classification. IEEE Commun. Lett. 2023;27:3043&#x2013;3047. doi: 10.1109/LCOMM.2023.3318288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LCOMM.2023.3318288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H., Zhang Z., Li Y., Shi X., Zhou F. Multi-scale feature fusion and distribution similarity network for few-shot automatic modulation classification. IEEE Signal Process. Lett. 2024;31:2890&#x2013;2894. doi: 10.1109/LSP.2024.3470762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LSP.2024.3470762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang F., Qi Z., Duan K., Xi D., Zhu Y., Zhu H., Xiong H., He Q. A comprehensive survey on transfer learning. Proc. IEEE. 2021;109:43&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1109/JPROC.2020.3004555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JPROC.2020.3004555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng F., Chen P., Wu L., Wang X. Automatic modulation classification: A deep learning enabled approach. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2018;67:10760&#x2013;10772. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2018.2868698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2018.2868698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Du P., Yang J., Wang G., Lei J., Hou C. Transferred deep learning based waveform recognition for cognitive passive radar. Signal Process. 2019;155:259&#x2013;267. doi: 10.1016/j.sigpro.2018.09.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sigpro.2018.09.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W., Hou D., Huang J., Li L., Han Z. Transfer learning for automatic modulation recognition using a few modulated signal samples. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2023;72:12391&#x2013;12395. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2023.3267270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2023.3267270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao X., Feng Z., Yang S., Wang M., Jiao L. Automatic modulation classification via meta-learning. IEEE Internet Things J. 2023;10:12276&#x2013;12292. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2023.3247162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2023.3247162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang B., Gou X., Zhu Z., Long L., Zhang H. Prototypical network with residual attention for modulation classification of wireless communication signals. Electronics. 2023;12:5005. doi: 10.3390/electronics12245005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics12245005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z., Fang S., Fan Y., Hou S., Xu Z. Tackling few-shot challenges in automatic modulation recognition: A multi-level comparative relation network combining class reconstruction strategy. Sensors. 2024;24:4421. doi: 10.3390/s24134421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24134421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11244464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39001199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller A.C., Guido S. Introduction to Machine Learning with Python: A Guide for Data Scientists. O&#x2019;Reilly Media, Inc.; Sebastopol, CA, USA: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klambauer G., Unterthiner T., Mayr A., Hochreiter S. Self-normalizing neural networks; Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems; Long Beach, CA, USA. 4&#x2013;9 December 2017; pp. 972&#x2013;981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma D.P., Ba J. Adam: A method for stochastic optimization; Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference for Learning Representations; San Diego, CA, USA. 7&#x2013;9 May 2015; pp. 1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scikit-Learn Developers  Scikit-Learn API Documentation, Version 1.6.1. 2025.  [(accessed on 30 November 2025)].  Available online:  https://scikit-learn.org/1.6/api/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora S., Hu W., Kothari P.K. An analysis of the t-SNE algorithm for data visualization; Proceedings of the 31st Conference on Learning Theory; Stockholm, Sweden. 6&#x2013;9 July 2018; pp. 1455&#x2013;1462.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>