<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41332468</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2297-7775</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in sociology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Sociol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sociological and religious interpretations of Adinkra symbols: qualitative analysis of the 2025 inaugural outfit of Ghana's president.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1642863</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1642863</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1642863</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fsoc.2025.1642863</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Adinkra symbols, deeply embedded in Ghanaian culture, serve as potent non-verbal communicative tools that convey philosophical, religious, and sociopolitical meanings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study explores the sociological, religious, and fashion interpretations of the Adinkra symbols incorporated into the 2025 inaugural outfit of Ghana's President. Anchored in a qualitative research design and aligned with a constructivist research philosophical position, the study draws on insights from 28 purposively selected participants, including traditional leaders, fashion designers, museum curators, and cultural preservatists.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS AND DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings reveal that "Sankofa", "Gye Nyame", "Nyame Dua", and "Dwennimmen", key symbols present in the attire, collectively signify governance introspection, divine authority, ethical leadership, and humility in power. Through the lens of Symbolic Interactionism and the Semiotic Theory of Fashion, the study demonstrates how these symbols serve as ideological markers, reinforcing national identity, political philosophy, and ethical governance. The results highlight the critical role of indigenous symbolism in shaping public perceptions of leadership, fostering national unity, and maintaining cultural continuity in Ghana's political landscape. The study calls for the integration of traditional symbols into governance, education, and leadership training to strengthen national identity and ethical governance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Mensah, Bordoh, Acquah, Bruce-Amartey Jnr and Nunoo.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mensah</LastName><ForeName>Ronald Osei</ForeName><Initials>RO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Media Technology and Liberal Studies, Social Development Department, Takoradi Technical University, Takoradi, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bordoh</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Studies Education, University of Education, Winneba, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Acquah</LastName><ForeName>Andrews</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Research into Basic Education, University of Education, Winneba, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bruce-Amartey Jnr</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Textile Design and Technology Department, Faculty of Applied Arts and Technology, Takoradi Technical University, Takoradi, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunoo</LastName><ForeName>Papa Kofi</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Political Science and History Department, University of Ghana, Accra, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Sociol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101777459</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2297-7775</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adinkra symbols</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ghanaian culture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inaugural attire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">political symbolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">semiotic theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symbolic interactionism</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The reviewer ET declared a shared affiliation with the author AB to the handling editor at the time of review</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41332468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12666525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsoc.2025.1642863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aboagyewaa-Ntiri J., Campion C. B., Kemevor A. K. (2018). Extension of knowledge on Ghanaian Adinkra symbols in relation to Maslow's theory. Int. J. Afr. Soc. Cult. Tradit. 6, 25&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adom D., Opoku M., Newton J. P., Yeboah A. (2018). Adinkra cultural symbols for environmental sustainability education in Ghana. World Environ. 8, 36&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aflakpui B., Ama T., Gilbert K., Johnson J. (2023). The iconography and iconology of adinkra symbols: an authentic source of themes for teaching drama in education at the University of Ghana. Am. Res. J. Hum. Soc. Sci. 9, 43&#x2013;51. doi: 10.21694/2378-7031.23007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21694/2378-7031.23007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinbileje T. Y. (2014). Symbolic values of clothing and textiles art in traditional and contemporary Africa. Int. J. Dev. Sustain. 3, 626&#x2013;641.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akou H. M. (2004). Nationalism Without a Nation: Understanding the Dress of Somali Women in Minnesota. Legon: Indiana University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allman J. (2004). Fashioning Africa: Power and the Politics of Dress. Bloomington: Indiana University Press. doi: 10.2979/1653, 0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2979/1653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoateng K. (2018). Engaging theology and theological education in the majority world: recognizing visual and symbolic theology from the Akan people's illustrations. Engaging Theol. Theolog. Educ. Majority World 6, 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ankora M. W. E. (2022). Material culture, African textiles and national identity (thesis). University of Guelph, Ontario, Canada.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansong R. A. (2022). The text(tiles) of Adinkra symbols: West African art, gender, &amp; poetic translations (dissertation). University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI, United States.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anyigor J. I., Olekaibe C. (2022). The implications of symbols and symbolism in African traditional religion; a phenomenological review. KW&#xc9; J&#x1ecc;NAL 15, 23&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur G. K. (2017). Cloth as Metaphor:(Re) Reading the Adinkra Cloth: Symbols of the Akan of Ghana. Ghana: iUniverse.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur L. B. (2001). Fashion and its social agendas: class, gender and identity in clothing. Soc. Forces 80, 367&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1353/sof.2001.0059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/sof.2001.0059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asiedu E. (2022). Adinkra symbols in logo designs: a clenched fist, philosophical echoes of selected institutional logos in Ghana. Int. J. Innovative Res. Multidiscip. Field 8, 161&#x2013;170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barthes R. (1990). The Fashion System. Berkeley: University of California Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnke A. (2016). The International Politics of Fashion: Being fab in a Dangerous World. London: Routledge. doi: 10.4324/9781315765082</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9781315765082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blount T. N., Brookins C. C. (2022). Adinkra symbolism, printmaking, and the cultural identity of Ghanaian emerging young adults. J. Creat. Mental Health 17, 374&#x2013;393. doi: 10.1080/15402021, 1911724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15402021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boero M. (2023). &#x201c;Socio-semiotics of fashion: theory, trends, and communication tools,&#x201d; in Paper Presented at the 5th International Conference on Language, Linguistics, and Literature, Atlantis (London: ). doi: 10.2991/978-2-38476-140-1_2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2991/978-2-38476-140-1_2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouska M. L., Jr., Beatty P. A. (1978). Clothing as a symbol of status: its effect on the control of interaction territory. Bull. Psychonomic Soc. 235&#x2013;238. doi: 10.3758/BF03336817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BF03336817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks-Yip M. (2023). Meaning making, labeling, and self in symbolic interactionism: teacher identity and everyday life. J. Commun. Cult. Inquiry Educ. 2, 3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter M. J., Fuller C. (2015). Symbolic interactionism. Sociopedia 1, 1&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1177/205684601561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/205684601561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter M. J., Fuller C. (2016). Symbols, meaning, and action: the past, present, and future of symbolic interactionism. Curr. Sociol. 64, 931&#x2013;961. doi: 10.1177/0011392116638396</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0011392116638396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danzy J. (2009). Adinkra symbols: an ideographic writing system (dissertation). The Graduate School, Stony Brook University, Stony Brook, NY.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deguara J., Nutbrown C. (2018). Signs, symbols and schemas: Understanding meaning in a child's drawings. Int. J. Early Years Educ. 26, 4&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1080/09669760.2017.1369398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09669760.2017.1369398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis A. (2018). Promoting Ghana's traditional cultural aesthetics in Ghana's most beautiful reality television show. Legon J. Humanit. 29, 176&#x2013;196. doi: 10.4314/ljh.v29i2.7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ljh.v29i2.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzokoto V., Hill A., Twum-Asante M., Hayfron A. E. (2018). Saying more than goodbye: emotion messages in Adinkra symbols. J. Visual Literacy, 37, 255&#x2013;275. doi: 10.1080/1052018.1500199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1052018.1500199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzramedo B. E., Ahiabor R., Gbadegbe R. (2013). The relevance and symbolism of clothes within traditional institutions and their modern impacts on the Ghanaian culture. Arts and Design Studies, 13, 1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ennin D., Mensah R. O. (2022). Cybercrime in Ghana and victims' accounts. Mediterr. J. Soc. Sci. 13, 1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.36941/mjss-2022-0019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36941/mjss-2022-0019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essel O. Q. (2013). Evolution of Ghana's dress culture (thesis). University of Education, Winneba.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusch P. I., Ness L. R. (2015). Are we there yet? Data saturation in qualitative research. Qual. Rep. 20, 1408&#x2013;1416. doi: 10.46743/2160-3715/2015.2281</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46743/2160-3715/2015.2281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes A. G. D. (2020). Researcher positionality&#x2013;a consideration of its influence and place in qualitative research&#x2013;a new researcher guide. Shanlax Int. J. Educ. 8, 1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.34293/education.v8i4.3232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34293/education.v8i4.3232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honeycutt R. L. (2021). DNA barcodes: controversies, mechanisms, and future applications. Front. Ecol. Evol. 9:718865. doi: 10.3389/fevo.2021.718865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fevo.2021.718865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husin S. S., Rahman A. A., Mukhtar D. (2021). The symbolic interactionism theory: a systematic literature review of current research. Int. J. Modern Trends Soc. Sci. 4, 113&#x2013;126. doi: 10.35631/IJMTSS.417010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35631/IJMTSS.417010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inayatullah F., Wahjudi D. (2023). Analysis of Roland Barthes' semiotic theory as an approach to assessing urban fashion. Edunity 2, 1080&#x2013;1082. doi: 10.57096/edunity.v2i9.154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.57096/edunity.v2i9.154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jecty R. (2022). Mastering Adinkra symbols: an establishment of positive Ghanaian personality in the next generation. Global J. Hum. Soc. Sci. Ling. Educ. 22, 27&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karunaratne P. V. M. (2018). &#x201c;Exploring fashion semiotics: communicating meanings in fashion in dress literature review,&#x201d; in Proceedings of 8th International Symposium (Oluvil: University Park; ), 182&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khrystych N. (2019). Semiotics of fashion speak. Res. Trends Modern Ling. Lit. 2, 38&#x2013;50. doi: 10.29038/2617-6696.2019.2.38.50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29038/2617-6696.2019.2.38.50</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kissi S. B., Fening P. A., Adom D. (2019). The philosophy of adinkra symbols in Asante textiles, jewellery, and other art forms. J. Asian Sci. Res. 9, 29&#x2013;39. doi: 10.18488/journal.2.2019.94.29.39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18488/journal.2.2019.94.29.39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotarba J. A. (2014). Symbolic interaction and applied social research: a focus on translational science. Symb. Interact. 37, 412&#x2013;425. doi: 10.1002/symb.111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/symb.111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4159952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25221375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwornu-Adjaottor J. E. T., Appiah G., Nartey M. (2016). The philosophy behind some Adinkra symbols and their communicative values in Akan. Philos. Papers Rev. 7, 22&#x2013;33. doi: 10.5897/PPR2015.0117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/PPR2015.0117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labode O. J., Braide O. O. (2022). Symbolic designs of textile art in African fabrics. Polish J. Arts Cult. 16, 71&#x2013;86. doi: 10.4467/24506249PJ.22.010.16833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4467/24506249PJ.22.010.16833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mardon A. A., Singh J., Bilal H., Schuler M., Kneppers A., Tang M., et al. (2021). Symbolic Interactionism. Edmonton: Golden Meteorite Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martino A. J. (2018). Stamping history: stories of social change in Ghana's Adinkra cloth (dissertation). University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, United States.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mato D. (2001). Not exotic, but too familiar?. Inter Asia Cult. Stud. 2, 487&#x2013;490. doi: 10.1080/14649370120111037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14649370120111037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mawuli C. A. (2019). Transmission and embodiment of heritage: an analysis of Adinkra symbology on traditional clothing in Ghana (thesis). Central European University, Budapest.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah Bonsu F., Wragg N., Phillipson S., Waller C. (2025). Ghanaian graphic design education: redefining Western influences and reclaiming Indigenous cultures. Int. J. Art Design Educ. 44, 80&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1111/jade.12526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jade.12526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah R. O., Korankye V. (2025). The role of fashion in crime symbolism in Ghana, West Africa. Deviant Behav. 46, 347&#x2013;364. doi: 10.1080/01639625.2024.2346330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01639625.2024.2346330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah R. O., Obeel C., Babah P. A. (2020). The philosophical and sociological implications behind the adinkra symbol &#x201c;Ny&#xe0;m&#xe9; w&#xfa; n&#xe0; m&#xe0;w&#xf9;&#x201d;. Int. J. Afr. Soc. Cult. Traditions 8, 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikerina D. (2016). Semiotics and fashion studies: limits and possibilities of a systemic approach to contemporary fashion (dissertation). Faculty of Humanities, Charles University, Czechia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moses T., Elzey Mercer L. (2022). Examining the influence of positionality on the facilitation of design processes. Dialectic 3. doi: 10.3998/dialectic.14930003, 105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3998/dialectic.14930003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motulsky S. L. (2021). Is member checking the gold standard of quality in qualitative research? Qual. Psychol. 8, 389&#x2013;395. doi: 10.1037/qup0000215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/qup0000215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neema Amani U. (2025). Fashion as a form of political expression. Sciences 4, 1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.59298/RIJCRHSS/2025/4115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59298/RIJCRHSS/2025/4115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ofori E. A., Tawiah B., Asinyo B. K., Adomako K. A., Eghan B. (2023). The exploration of near-extinct indigenous Ghanaian cultural symbols for interior decoration. Cogent Arts Humanit. 10, 1&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1080/2332023.2243715</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2332023.2243715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oladumiye E. B. (2018). Cultural symbols and African symbolism: the efficacy in product advertisement. J. Fine Arts 1, 16&#x2013;23. doi: 10.22259/2637-5885.0102003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22259/2637-5885.0102003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owusu P. (2019). Adinkra symbols as a &#x201c;multivocal&#x201d; pedagogical/socialization tool. Contemp. J. Afr. Stud. 6, 46&#x2013;58. doi: 10.4314/contjas.v6i1.3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/contjas.v6i1.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers L. B., Adams F., Brown W. (2013). Story of Nations. New York, NY: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders M. (2014). Research Methods for Business Students. New Jersey: McGraw-Hill.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner J. (2013). The Interview: An Ethnographic Approach. UK: A &amp; C Black.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stryker S. Annual Reviews (2008). From mead to a structural symbolic interactionism and beyond. Ann. Rev. Sociol. 34, 15&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1146/annurev.soc.34.040507.134649</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.soc.34.040507.134649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunday A. C., Ugochukwu O. S., Victor O. O., Chukwuma O. J., Ikechukwu O. B. (2024). The import of symbolism in African religious experience. Eur. J. Interdiscip. Stud. 10, 144&#x2013;159. doi: 10.26417/tbnpkd31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26417/tbnpkd31</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udechukwu G. I. (2019). The significance and use of cultural symbols in the contemporary African society: igbo symbols as a paradigm. J. Afr. Stud. 8, 110&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Burg E., Cornelissen J., Stam W., Jack S. (2022). Advancing qualitative entrepreneurship research: leveraging methodological plurality for achieving scholarly impact. Entrepreneurship Theory Pract. 46, 3&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1177/1042258720943051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1042258720943051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent M. M. (2022). The intersection of fashion and politics: A semiotic analysis of Vogue magazine covers surrounding election seasons (thesis: ). Brigham Young University, Utah.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis W. B. (1998). The Adinkra Dictionary: A Visual Primer on the Language of Adinkra. Washington, DC: Pyramid Complex.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yankah K. (1995). Speaking for the Chief: Okyeame and the Politics of Akan Royal Oratory. Legon: Indiana University Press. doi: 10.2979/3032.0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2979/3032.0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>