<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41545491</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A novel Hankel norm approximation-based AGC for a hydro-dominated power system.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5522</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5522</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5522</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35235-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Analyzing power system disturbances for automatic generation control (AGC) requires solving a large set of differential equations, which remains computationally demanding even in linearized form and hence limits the practical implementation of most control strategies. In addition, the presence of time constants and delays further complicates the modeling by influencing the response of generators, governors, and control mechanisms especially for hydro dominated power systems. To address these challenges, Model Order Reduction (MOR) techniques play an important role in solving these issues for higher order and complex systems. This paper applies the Hankel norm approximation (HNA) method to develop reduced-order models for AGC in a hydro-dominated power system. An eleventh-order model is reduced to seventh, eighth and ninth-order representations. Stability margins of these reduce order models are evaluated through eigenvalue analysis, and the dynamic responses of the reduced order models are compared against the original model. Results demonstrate that the reduced order models preserve the essential dynamics while substantially lowering computational effort in AGC. To further assess the effectiveness of HNA, a Truncation-based reduction approach is also applied, and comparative results are offered to show the benefits of the proposed work.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naqvi</LastName><ForeName>Sadaf</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Jamia Millia Islamia, New Delhi, 110025, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibraheem</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Netaji Subhas University of Technology, New Delhi, 110078, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Gulshan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical &amp; Electronic Engineering Technology, University of Johannesburg, Johannesburg, 2006, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Rajesh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Anatomy and Physiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Johannesburg, Johannesburg, 2094, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Malaviya National Institute of Technology, Jaipur, 302017, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Sachin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, 576104, Karnataka, India. Sachin.sharma@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Automatic generation control (AGC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hankel norm approximation (HNA)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydro turbine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Model order reduction (MOR) techniques</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Modeling &amp; simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multivariable system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Truncation method</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41545491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12886902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35235-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35235-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chinesta, F., Huerta, A., Rozza, G., Willcox, K. &amp; Hughes model order reduction. In <i>Encyclopaedia of Computational Mechanics</i>. (eds Erwin Stein, Ren&#xb4;e de Borst and Thomas J. R). (John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd., 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, H., Bazaz, M. A. &amp; Nahvi, S. A. Singular perturbation-based model reduction of power electronic circuits. <i>IET Circuits Devices Syst.</i><b>13 no</b> (4), 471&#x2013;478 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-cds.2018.5234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustafa, M., Iqbal, M., Sarumathi, S., Jothi, K. R. &amp; Brindadevi, A. Model order reduction of heavy duty gas turbine power plants with field test parameters. <i>Int. Trans. Electr. Energy Syst.</i><b>29</b>, 1&#x2013;13 (2019). e2703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safiullah, Y. K., Gupta, Prajapati, B. S. &amp; Control, I. Reduced order modelling using singular perturbation method. In <i>International Conference on Power Energy, Environment, and (PEEIC)</i> (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsalis, G. &amp; Shamma, J. S. A counterexample to aggregation based model reduction of hidden Markov models. In <i>50th Conference (CDC-ECC) Orlando, FL, USA</i>. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Techakesari, O. &amp; Nurdin, H. I. Tangential interpolatory projection for model reduction of linear quantum stochastic systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Automat. Control</i><b>62</b>, 1, (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radic-Weissenfeld, L., Ludwig, S., Mathis, W. &amp; John, W. Model order reduction of linear time invariant systems. <i>Adv. Radio Sci.</i><b>6</b>, 129&#x2013;132 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/ars-6-129-2008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veerasamy, V. et al. A Hankel matrix based reduced order model for stability analysis of hybrid power system using PSO-GSA optimized cascade PI-PD controller for automatic load frequency control. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>8</b>, 71422&#x2013;71446 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2987387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C. D. &amp; Yeh, F. B. An efficient algorithm on optimal Hankel- norm approximation for multivariable systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Automatic Control</i>. <b>37</b> (6), 815&#x2013;820 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/9.256340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, C. D. &amp; Yeh, F. B. One-step extension approach to optimal Hankel- norm approximation and H&#x221e;- optimization problems. <i>IEEE Trans. Automatic Control</i>. <b>38</b> (5), 674&#x2013;688 (1993).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/9.277233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, K. Weighted optimal Hankel norm model reduction.In <i>Proceedings of the 32nd Conference on Decision and Control, San Antonio, Texas</i> pp. 33&#x2013;54 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benner, P., Quintana-Orti, E. S. &amp; Quintana-Orti, G. Computing optimal Hankel norm approximations of large-scale systems. In <i>Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Decision and Control</i> pp.1&#x2013;12 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arif, D. K., Adzkiya, D., Roziq, M. K., Aditya, P. &amp; Fadhilah, H. N. Model reduction analysis using Hankel norm approximation on discrete-time linear system with the special shape of matrix A. <i>IOP Conf. Ser. J. Phys. Conf. Ser.</i><b>1218 012050</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangi, S., Jain, S. &amp; Arya, Y. Utilization of energy storage devices with optimal controller for multi-area hydro-hydro power system under deregulated environment. <i>Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess.</i><b>52</b>, 102191 (2022). part C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arya, Y., Gupta, S. K. &amp; Singh, N. Optimal power-Frequency control in deregulated Thermal, hydro and hydrothermal power systems with AC-DC links. <i>Recent. Adv. Electr. Electron. Eng.</i><b>12</b> (5), 414&#x2013;424 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibraheem, P., Kumar, S. &amp; Ahmad. dynamic performance enhancement of hydro-power systems with asynchronous tie-lines IE(I). <i>J. -EL</i><b>85</b>, (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panwar, G., Sharma, I., Nasiruddin &amp; Bansal, R. C. Frequency stabilization of hydro&#x2013;hydro power system using hybrid bacteria foraging PSO with UPFC and HAE. <i>Electr. Power Syst. Res.</i><b>161</b>, 74&#x2013;85 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2018.03.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, M., Sharma, G. &amp; &#xc7;elik, E. Load frequency control of hydro-hydro power system using fuzzy-PSO-PID with application of UC and RFB. <i>Electr. Power Compon. Syst.</i> 1&#x2013;15, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panwar, A., Agarwal, V., Sharma, G. &amp; Sharma, S. Design of a novel AGC action for a linked hydro governing system. <i>Electr. Power Compon. Syst.</i><b>49</b> (15), 1201&#x2013;1211 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15325008.2022.2050447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benner, P. Werner Hankel-norm approximation of large-scale descriptor systems. <i>Adv. Comput. Math.</i><b>46</b> (40), 1&#x2013;31 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, N. Reduction of linear dynamic systems using Hankel norm approximation. <i>Control Intell. Syst.</i><b>41</b> (4), 1&#x2013;8 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, K. Frequency weighted L&#x2009;&#x221e;&#x2009;norm and optimal Hankel norm model reduction. <i>IEEE Trans. Automatic Control</i>. <b>40</b> (10), 16871699 (1995).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>