<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41894528</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dimensionally constrained adversarial attack and defense in wind power forecasting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0345284</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0345284</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0345284</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0345284</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Deep neural networks (DNNs) have achieved remarkable success in wind power forecasting, but DNNs are vulnerable to adversarial attacks that can severely degrade forecast accuracy. Existing studies primarily emphasize attack effectiveness and pay limited attention to attack stealthiness. In this paper, a dimension-constrained momentum iterative fast gradient sign method (DC-MI-FGSM) is proposed for wind power forecasting, which generates highly stealthy perturbations by applying the momentum update mechanism during attack optimization and limiting the perturbation dimensions of input samples. To defend against this attack, a denoising autoencoder (DAE)-based preprocessing defense strategy is developed for wind power forecasting, which resists adversarial attacks by mapping adversarial samples back to their corresponding clean forms. The effectiveness of the proposed attack and defense methods is validated on the public SDWPF dataset under both white-box and black-box scenarios. Compared with existing attacks, DC-MI-FGSM achieves a lower average perturbation percentage (APP), indicating superior attack stealthiness. Meanwhile, it causes more severe degradation in forecasting accuracy, as measured by MAPE, RMSE, and MAE, demonstrating stronger attack effectiveness. For defense, the proposed DAE-based preprocessing strategy effectively mitigates adversarial perturbations, significantly reducing forecasting errors while preserving the original accuracy on clean data. Moreover, it consistently outperforms adversarial training in terms of robustness and usability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Min et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Min</LastName><ForeName>Yangming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-6280-3941</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of electrical engineering, Guizhou University, GuiYang, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Congmei</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6477-5580</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of electrical engineering, Guizhou University, GuiYang, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guizhou University Survey and Design Institute Co., Ltd., Guiyang, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electric Power Science Research Institute, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Liangheng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zunyi Power Supply Bureau, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Xiankui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electric Power Science Research Institute, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu</LastName><ForeName>Junling</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of electrical engineering, Guizhou University, GuiYang, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of electrical engineering, Guizhou University, GuiYang, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014919" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wind</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005544" MajorTopicYN="N">Forecasting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41894528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13029804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0345284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-28488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Suman A. Role of renewable energy technologies in climate change adaptation and mitigation: a brief review from Nepal. Renew Sustain Energy Rev. 2021;151:111524. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2021.111524</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2021.111524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boadu S, Otoo E. A comprehensive review on wind energy in Africa: challenges, benefits and recommendations. Renew Sustain Energy Rev. 2024;191:114035. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2023.114035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2023.114035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazi R, Kouravand S, Hassan-Beygi R. Analysis of wind turbine usage in greenhouses: wind resource assessment, distributed generation of electricity and environmental protection. Energy Sourc Part A: Recov Utilizat Environ Effects. 2019;45(3):7846&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1080/15567036.2019.1677810</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15567036.2019.1677810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Du Z, Jin K, Li H, Wang S. Spatiotemporal wind power forecasting approach based on multi-factor extraction method and an indirect strategy. Appl Energy. 2023;350:121749. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2023.121749</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2023.121749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han S, He M, Zhao Z, Chen D, Xu B, Jurasz J, et al. Overcoming the uncertainty and volatility of wind power: day-ahead scheduling of hydro-wind hybrid power generation system by coordinating power regulation and frequency response flexibility. Appl Energy. 2023;333:120555. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2022.120555</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2022.120555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashir T, Wang H, Tahir M, Zhang Y. Wind and solar power forecasting based on hybrid CNN-ABiLSTM, CNN-transformer-MLP models. Renew Energy. 2025;239:122055. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2024.122055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2024.122055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Zou H. Short-Term Wind Power Prediction Based on Data Reconstruction and Improved Extreme Learning Machine. Arab J Sci Eng. 2022;47(3):3669&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1007/s13369-020-05311-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-020-05311-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowell J, Pinson P. Very-short-term probabilistic wind power forecasts by sparse vector autoregression. IEEE Trans Smart Grid. 2015;1&#x2013;1. doi: 10.1109/tsg.2015.2424078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tsg.2015.2424078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahouar A, Ben Hadj Slama J. Hour-ahead wind power forecast based on random forests. Renew Energy. 2017;109:529&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2017.03.064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2017.03.064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh PK, Singh N, Negi R. Wind power forecasting using hybrid ARIMA-ANN technique. In: Advances in intelligent systems and computing. Springer Singapore; 2019. 209&#x2013;20. 10.1007/978-981-13-5934-7_19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-13-5934-7_19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Ye L, Pinson P, Tang Y, Lu P. Correlation-constrained and sparsity-controlled vector autoregressive model for spatio-temporal wind power forecasting. IEEE Trans Power Syst. 2018;33(5):5029&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1109/tpwrs.2018.2794450</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tpwrs.2018.2794450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ate&#x15f; KT. Estimation of short-term power of wind turbines using artificial neural network (ANN) and swarm intelligence. Sustainability. 2023;15(18):13572. doi: 10.3390/su151813572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151813572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahid F, Zameer A, Muneeb M. A novel genetic LSTM model for wind power forecast. Energy. 2021;223:120069. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2021.120069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2021.120069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Guan F, Lv C, Huang Y. Ultra&#x2010;short&#x2010;term multi&#x2010;step wind power forecasting based on CNN&#x2010;LSTM. IET Renewable Power Gen. 2021;15(5):1019&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1049/rpg2.12085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/rpg2.12085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei D, Tian Z. A Comprehensive multivariate wind speed forecasting model utilizing deep learning neural networks. Arab J Sci Eng. 2024;49(12):16809&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1007/s13369-024-09203-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-024-09203-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Yun S, Jia L, Guo J, Meng Y, He N, et al. Hybrid VMD-CNN-GRU-based model for short-term forecasting of wind power considering spatio-temporal features. Eng Applicat Artificial Intellig. 2023;121:105982. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2023.105982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2023.105982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zhou J. Short-term wind power forecasting based on multivariate/multi-step LSTM with temporal feature attention mechanism. Appl Soft Comput. 2024;150:111050. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2023.111050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2023.111050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia M, Shao H, Ma X, de Silva CW. A stacked GRU-RNN-based approach for predicting renewable energy and electricity load for smart grid operation. IEEE Trans Ind Inf. 2021;17(10):7050&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1109/tii.2021.3056867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tii.2021.3056867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H-T, Pan L, Wang J, Fan X-B, Li J, Liu Z. Short-term wind power prediction method based on TCN-GRU combined model. In: 2021 IEEE sustainable power and energy conference (iSPEC), 2021. 3764&#x2013;9. 10.1109/ispec53008.2021.9735991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ispec53008.2021.9735991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Liu Y, Li Q, Wang T, Chu F. Short-term multi-step wind power forecasting based on spatio-temporal correlations and transformer neural networks. Energy Conver Manag. 2023;283:116916. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2023.116916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2023.116916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhtar N, Mian A. Threat of adversarial attacks on deep learning in computer vision: a survey. IEEE Access. 2018;6:14410&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1109/access.2018.2807385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2018.2807385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Tan Y, Zhang B. Exploiting vulnerabilities of load forecasting through adversarial attacks. In: Proceedings of the Tenth ACM International conference on future energy systems, 2019. 1&#x2013;11. 10.1145/3307772.3328314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3307772.3328314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi A, Nabipour M, Taheri S, Mohammadi-Ivatloo B, Vahidinasab V. A new false data injection attack detection model for cyberattack resilient energy forecasting. IEEE Trans Ind Inf. 2023;19(1):371&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1109/tii.2022.3151748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tii.2022.3151748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan J, Wang L, Chen S, Zang T, Qiu Y, Liang G, et al. Robust universal adversarial perturbation attacks on renewable energy forecasting. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12(11):18451&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2025.3558522</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2025.3558522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinrich R, Scholz C, Vogt S, Lehna M. Targeted adversarial attacks on wind power forecasts. Mach Learn. 2023;113(2):863&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1007/s10994-023-06396-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10994-023-06396-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao R, Han Z, Liu X, Zhou C, Du M. A gradient-based wind power forecasting attack method considering point and direction selection. IEEE Trans Smart Grid. 2024;15(3):3178&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1109/tsg.2023.3325390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tsg.2023.3325390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan J, Wang Q, Chen S, Lyu H, Liang G, Zhao J, et al. On vulnerability of renewable energy forecasting: adversarial learning attacks. IEEE Trans Ind Inf. 2024;20(3):3650&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1109/tii.2023.3313526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tii.2023.3313526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Jiang C, Yu M, Wen X, Zhang J, Rong N, et al. Adversarial black-box attack and defense for convolutional neural network-based power quality disturbance classification. Eng Appl Artificial Intellig. 2025;162:112411. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2025.112411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2025.112411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Ding Z, Wen Q, Wang Y. Robust load forecasting towards adversarial attacks via bayesian learning. IEEE Trans Power Syst. 2023;38(2):1445&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1109/tpwrs.2022.3175252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tpwrs.2022.3175252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akter K, Rahman MA, Islam MdR, Sheikh MdRI, Hossain MJ. Attack-resilient framework for wind power forecasting against civil and adversarial attacks. Electric Power Syst Res. 2025;238:111065. doi: 10.1016/j.epsr.2024.111065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsr.2024.111065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow IJ, Shlens J, Szegedy C. Explaining and harnessing adversarial examples. arXiv preprint. 2014; 6572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z-H, Wang C-T, Wei H-L, Zeng B, Li M, Song X-P. A wavelet-LSTM model for short-term wind power forecasting using wind farm SCADA data. Expert Syst Appl. 2024;247:123237. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren K, Zheng T, Qin Z, Liu X. Adversarial attacks and defenses in deep learning. Engineering. 2020;6(3):346&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/j.eng.2019.12.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eng.2019.12.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darvish Rouani B, Samragh M, Javidi T, Koushanfar F. Safe machine learning and defeating adversarial attacks. IEEE Secur Privacy. 2019;17(2):31&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1109/msec.2018.2888779</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/msec.2018.2888779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahay R, Mahfuz R, Gamal AE. Combatting adversarial attacks through denoising and dimensionality reduction: a cascaded autoencoder approach. In: 2019 53rd Annual Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS), 2019. 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/ciss.2019.8692918</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ciss.2019.8692918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini H, Chen Y, Kannan S, Zhang B, Poovendran R. Blocking transferability of adversarial examples in black-box learning systems. arXiv preprint. 2017. https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.04318</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Y, Liao F, Pang T, Su H, Zhu J, Hu X, et al. Boosting adversarial attacks with momentum. In: 2018 IEEE/CVF conference on computer vision and pattern recognition. 2018. 9185&#x2013;93. 10.1109/cvpr.2018.00957</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/cvpr.2018.00957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlini N, Wagner D. Towards evaluating the robustness of neural networks. In: 2017 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP), 2017. 39&#x2013;57. 10.1109/sp.2017.49</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/sp.2017.49</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Zhang H, Sharma Y, Yi J, Hsieh CJ. ZOO: Zeroth order optimization based black-box attacks to deep neural networks without training substitute models. In: Proceedings of the 10th ACM workshop on artificial intelligence and security, 2017. 15&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S, Jun TJ, Oh B, Kim D. DAPAS&#xa0;: denoising autoencoder to prevent adversarial attack in semantic segmentation. In: 2020 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), 2020. 1&#x2013;8. 10.1109/ijcnn48605.2020.9207291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ijcnn48605.2020.9207291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Jiang C, Pang A. Black-box attacks and defense for DNN-based power quality classification in smart grid. Energy Rep. 2022;8:12203&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.egyr.2022.09.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2022.09.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent P, Larochelle H, Bengio Y, Manzagol P-A. Extracting and composing robust features with denoising autoencoders. In: Proceedings of the 25th international conference on Machine learning - ICML &#x2019;08, 2008. 1096&#x2013;103. 10.1145/1390156.1390294</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/1390156.1390294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahay R, Zhang M, Love DJ, Brinton CG. Defending adversarial attacks on deep learning-based power allocation in massive MIMO using denoising autoencoders. IEEE Trans Cogn Commun Netw. 2023;9(4):913&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1109/tccn.2023.3261307</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tccn.2023.3261307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Lu X, Xiao Y, Tang J, Su J, Li Y, et al. SDWPF: a dataset for spatial dynamic wind power forecasting over a large turbine array. Sci Data. 2024;11(1):649. doi: 10.1038/s41597-024-03427-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-024-03427-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11187227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38898114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Zhang S, Zhang Z. A privacy-preserving framework integrating federated learning and transfer learning for wind power forecasting. Energy. 2024;286:129639. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.129639</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.129639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Jiang C, Chai Z, He Y. Adversarial attack and training for deep neural network based power quality disturbance classification. Eng Appl Artificial Intellig. 2024;127:107245. doi: 10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107245</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2023.107245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian J, Wang B, Li J, Wang Z. Adversarial attacks and defense for CNN based power quality recognition in smart grid. IEEE Trans Netw Sci Eng. 2022;9(2):807&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1109/tnse.2021.3135565</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tnse.2021.3135565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>