<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41738030</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>In vitro modeling of nutritional and mitochondria-targeted therapies for osteosarcoma.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2026.02.19.706776</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.64898/2026.02.19.706776</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Osteosarcoma is the most common pediatric bone tumor yet has limited treatment options, especially for metastatic cases with a 20% adjusted 5-year survival rate. Current therapies are non-specific, involving primary tumor resection with DNA-damaging chemotherapies like methotrexate, doxorubicin, and cisplatin. Few effective treatment options exist for metastases. Targeting metabolism involving cancers reduced mitochondrial functionality remains underexplored in osteosarcoma. We investigated the therapeutic potential in human osteosarcoma primary and metastatic cell lines of metabolic modulating drugs including metformin, cycloheximide, mitochondrial ETC inhibitors (antimycin A, metformin), dichloroacetate, and imipridones (ONC201, ONC206) on mitochondrial function and cell viability, individually and combined under various nutrient conditions across our lines. Results confirmed osteosarcoma cells are more dependent on glucose than osteoblasts but also require mitochondrial function for survival, highlighting the therapeutic potential of metabolic pathways. Osteosarcoma cell viability was reduced when any metabolic drug treatment was combined with conditions forcing reliance on mitochondrial OXPHOS capacity. Combination metabolic therapies, particularly ONC201/ONC206/metformin in 143B cells, and to a lesser extent DCA and ONC201 with either ONC206 or antimycin A, showed enhanced cytotoxicity compared to single agents, with a good therapeutic index based on minimal toxicity to normal osteoblast cells. The degree of effectiveness varied across cell lines, underscoring the importance of personalized treatment strategies. RNA-Seq transcriptome analysis revealed that effective nutrient and metabolic drug treatments triggered widespread regulatory changes in osteosarcoma cells involving increased translation/splicing with decreased mitochondrial processes such as cholesterol biosynthesis. These results demonstrate the utility of developing combined metabolic and chemotherapeutic treatments for osteosarcoma.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keith</LastName><ForeName>Kelsey</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7451-5117</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dalwadi</LastName><ForeName>Shrey</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>Vernon E</ForeName><Initials>VE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Resnick</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falk</LastName><ForeName>Marni J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41738030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12927527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.64898/2026.02.19.706776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2026.02.19.706776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>