<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41571714</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sustainable cooling solutions in Dubai: the impact of incident radiation and panel angles on solar AC performance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5999</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5999</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5999</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-36069-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rising demand for air conditioning units driven by climate change underscores the importance of using sustainable energy sources, which help reduce greenhouse gas emissions and mitigate environmental impact. The present work focuses on the design and construction of a solar air conditioning system by integrating photovoltaic panels or solar thermal collectors to power the cooling cycle, providing a sustainable and eco-friendly alternative to conventional systems. A solar air conditioning unit entails the design, integration, and performance evaluation of a system that harnesses solar energy to provide space cooling. This study focuses on the design and construction of a solar air conditioning unit for cooling a defined space, with performance evaluated under varying solar radiation levels and panel tilt angles. Thermal comfort parameters and power factors were analyzed to determine the system's overall efficiency. Experiments were carried out under Dubai's climatic conditions by varying the incident solar radiation from 700 to 1400&#xa0;W/m<sup>2</sup> and adjusting the panel inclination angle between 15&#xb0; and 25&#xb0; which determined the performance parameters and the thermal comfort. The unit achieved maximum values for moisture removal rate, thermal efficiency, and solar coefficient of performance at 0.74&#xa0;g/s, 95%, and 1.03, respectively. Power ratios were observed to decrease with increasing incident radiation. A solar panel tilt angle of 25&#xb0; yielded the highest moisture removal rate 0.78&#xa0;g/s, solar coefficient of performance 1.1, and solar direct consumption ratio 0.61. Thermal comfort parameters, including the Predicted Mean Vote (PMV) and Predicted Percentage of Dissatisfied (PPD), were calculated to be - 0.21 and 12.7%, respectively, both falling within acceptable comfort ranges.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salins</LastName><ForeName>Sampath Suranjan</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Dubai Campus, Dubai, 345050, UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Shiva</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, 576104, India. shiva.kumar@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prasad</LastName><ForeName>Krishna</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Dubai Campus, Dubai, 345050, UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cooling performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predicted mean vote</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predicted percentage of dissatisfied</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sloar panel tilt angle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solar COP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thermal comfort</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41571714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12902107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-36069-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-36069-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Villarini, M., Tascioni, R., Arteconi, A. &amp; Cioccolanti, L. Influence of the incident radiation on the energy performance of two small-scale solar organic Rankine cycle trigenerative systems: A simulation analysis. <i>Appl. Energy</i>. <b>242</b>, 1176&#x2013;1188 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.03.066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubaiee, S. &amp; Fazal, M. A. The influence of various solar radiations on the efficiency of a photovoltaic solar module integrated with a passive cooling system. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b> (24), 9584 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15249584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaik, F., Lingala, S. S. &amp; Veeraboina, P. Effect of various parameters on the performance of solar PV power plant: a review and the experimental study. <i>Sustain. Energy Res.</i><b>10</b> (1), 6 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40807-023-00076-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasrin, R., Hasanuzzaman, M. &amp; Rahim, N. A. Effect of high irradiation on photovoltaic power and energy. <i>Int. J. Energy Res.</i><b>42</b> (3), 1115&#x2013;1131 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/er.3907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamun, M. A. A., Islam, M. M., Hasanuzzaman, M. &amp; Selvaraj, J. Effect of Tilt angle on the performance and electrical parameters of a PV module: comparative indoor and outdoor experimental investigation. <i>Energy Built Environ.</i><b>3</b> (3), 278&#x2013;290 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbenv.2021.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardhana, A. S. J., Damarwan, E. S. &amp; Hakim, M. L. The Effect of Inclination Angle of The Solar Panel on The Resulting Output Voltage. In <i>Journal of Physics: Conference Series</i>, vol. 2111, No. 1, 012053 (IOP Publishing, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo&#x17e;ikov&#xe1;, M. et al. The effect of azimuth and Tilt angle changes on the energy balance of photovoltaic system installed in the Southern Slovakia region. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>11</b> (19), 8998 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11198998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholami, H. &amp; Nils R&#xf8;stvik, H. Dataset for the solar incident radiation and electricity production BIPV/BAPV system on the Northern/Southern fa&#xe7;ade in dense urban areas. <i>Data</i><b>6</b> (6), 57 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/data6060057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqurashi, F., Nciri, R., Alghamdi, A., Ali, C. &amp; Nasri, F. Control of the solar radiation reception rate (SRRR) using a novel Poly-Tilted segmented panel (PTSP) in the region of Makkah. <i>Saudi Arabia Energies</i>. <b>15</b> (7), 2357 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M. S., Ramli, M. A., Sindi, H. F., Hidayat, T. &amp; Bouchekara, H. R. Estimation of solar radiation on a PV panel surface with an optimal Tilt angle using electric charged particles optimization. <i>Electronics</i><b>11</b> (13), 2056 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics11132056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masili, M. &amp; Ventura, L. Local tilt optimization of photovoltaic solar panels for maximum radiation absorption. <i>Int. J. Photoenergy</i>. <b>2019</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqaed, S., Mustafa, J., Almehmadi, F. A. &amp; Jamil, B. Estimation of ideal Tilt angle for solar-PV panel surfaces facing south: a case study for Najran City, Saudi Arabia. <i>J. Therm. Anal. Calorim.</i><b>148</b> (16), 8641&#x2013;8654 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-022-11812-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira, A. C., Menezes, N., Teixeira, I. M., Teixeira, S. F. &amp; Martins, L. A. Influence of typical meteorological years on the optimization of incident solar radiation for PV applications in Portugal. In <i>International Conference on Electronic Engineering and Renewable Energy Systems</i>, 925&#x2013;932 (Springer Nature Singapore, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Z., Ren, Y. &amp; Chen, L. Evaluating urban geometry impacts on incident solar radiation on building envelopes. <i>Environ. Model. Assess.</i><b>26</b>, 113&#x2013;123 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10666-020-09707-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafka, J. &amp; Miller, M. A. The dual angle solar harvest (DASH) method: an alternative method for organizing large solar panel arrays that optimizes incident solar energy in conjunction with land use. <i>Renew. Energy</i>. <b>155</b>, 531&#x2013;546 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2020.03.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivakumar, B., Navakrishnan, S., Cibi, M. R. &amp; Senthil, R. Experimental study on the electrical performance of a solar photovoltaic panel by water immersion. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i><b>28</b>, 42981&#x2013;42989 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-021-15228-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34218373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan, K. et al. A new method for improving the solar photovoltaic unit efficiency through Neem oil as coolant medium for high power applications&#x2014;an experimental investigation. <i>Electr. Eng.</i><b>106</b> (5), 6251&#x2013;6264 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00202-024-02337-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garni, A. The impact of soiling on PV module performance in Saudi Arabia. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b> (21), 8033 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15218033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan, M. K., Alqurashi, I. M., Salama, A. E. &amp; Mohamed, A. F. Investigation the performance of PV solar cells in extremely hot environments. <i>J. Umm Al-Qura Univ. Eng. Archit.</i><b>13</b> (1), 18&#x2013;26 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43995-022-00005-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelgaied, M., Saber, M. A., Bassuoni, M. M. &amp; Khaira, A. M. Performance improvement of solar-assisted air-conditioning systems by using an innovative configuration of a desiccant dehumidifier and thermal recovery unit. <i>J. Therm. Anal. Calorim.</i><b>148</b> (14), 7003&#x2013;7018 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-023-12215-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reda, A. M., Ali, A. H. H., Morsy, M. G. &amp; Taha, I. S. Optimization and performance of a small scale adsorption cooling system fully powered by solar energy for hot arid areas. <i>SN Appl. Sci.</i><b>1</b>, 1&#x2013;14 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-019-1150-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aky&#xfc;z, A., Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m, R., Gungor, A. &amp; Tuncer, A. D. Experimental investigation of a solar-assisted air conditioning system: energy and life cycle climate performance analysis. <i>Therm. Sci. Eng. Progr</i>. <b>43</b>, 101960 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsep.2023.101960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar, F. J., Ruiz, J., Lucas, M. &amp; Vicente, P. G. Performance analysis and optimisation of a solar on-grid air conditioner. <i>Energies</i><b>14</b> (23), 8054 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en14238054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneesamkandi, Z. &amp; Sayeed, A. Performance of solar hybrid cooling operated by solar compound parabolic collectors under weather conditions in Riyadh, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>13</b> (12), 7343 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13127343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayadi, O., Rinchi, B. &amp; Alsaleem, F. Experimental evaluation of a solar-powered air conditioner. <i>Sol. Energy</i>. <b>272</b>, 112466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zayed, M. E., Aboelmaaref, M. M. &amp; Chazy, M. Design of solar air conditioning system integrated with photovoltaic panels and thermoelectric coolers: experimental analysis and machine learning modeling by random vector functional link coupled with white Whale optimization. <i>Therm. Sci. Eng. Progr</i>. <b>44</b>, 102051 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsep.2023.102051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, K. S. et al. Experimental investigation to enhancing the energy efficiency of a solar-powered Visi cooler. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 18327 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-01620-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12106735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40419572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, K. A. M., Osman, Y. K. O. T., El-wahhab, G. G. A., Abdelwahab, T. A. M. &amp; Fodah, A. E. M. Improving solar PV performance under bird-dropping conditions with a dual-cooling approach. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 8211 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-84932-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11894218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40064922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salins, S. S., Reddy, S. K. &amp; Kumar, S. Experimental investigation of the influence of vapor compression refrigeration in a multistage reciprocating dehumidifier test rig. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>199</b>, 117546 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2021.117546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Zhang, G., Lv, G. Z., Zhang, A. N. &amp; Wang, R. Z. Performance study of a solar photovoltaic air conditioner in the hot summer and cold winter zone. <i>Sol. Energy</i>. <b>117</b>, 167&#x2013;179 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2015.04.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, B. J. et al. Design of direct solar PV driven air conditioner. <i>Renew. Energy</i>. <b>88</b>, 95&#x2013;101 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2015.11.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salins, S. S. et al. Performance characterization of an adaptive-controlled air handling unit to achieve thermal comfort in Dubai climate. <i>Energy</i><b>273</b>, 127186 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, G. Y., Han, D. S. &amp; Lee, Z. Solar panel Tilt angle optimization using machine learning model: a case study of Daegu City, South Korea. <i>Energies</i><b>13</b> (3), 529 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en13030529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafarkazemi, F. &amp; Saadabadi, S. A. Optimum tilt angle and orientation of solar surfaces in Abu Dhabi, UAE. <i>Renew. Energy</i><b>56</b>, 44&#x2013;49 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulaiman, A. Y. et al. A solar powered off-grid air conditioning system with natural refrigerant for residential buildings: A theoretical and experimental evaluation. <i>Clean. Energy Syst.</i><b>5</b>, 100077 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cles.2023.100077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahmer, A., Wang, X. &amp; Alam, K. A. Dynamic and economic investigation of a solar thermal-driven two-bed adsorption chiller under Perth Climatic conditions. <i>Energies</i><b>13</b> (4), 1005 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en13041005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>