<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41401012</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1875-9270</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Work (Reading, Mass.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Work</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Workplace safety communication: A systematic review of GHS pictogram comprehension in Iranian work settings.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10519815251398497</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10519815251398497</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/10519815251398497</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>BackgroundDespite the wide usage of Globally Harmonized System (GHS) pictograms in Iranian work settings, there is limited evidence that workers comprehend these signs. Misinterpreting GHS signs can result in hazardous exposures, accidents, and reduced workplace safety.ObjectiveThis study vitally reviews available research to determine the level of comprehension of GHS symbols among Iranian workers.MethodsIn this systematic review, a comprehensive search was performed in international databases (Embase, Scopus, PubMed, and Web of Science) and Persian (SID, IranMedex, Magiran, and IranDoc). Relevant articles in these databases were extracted by searching keywords such as GHS pictograms, chemical labeling comprehension, and Iran from 2015 to 2025. To extract the required data, all parts of the studies were reviewed following the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA) 2020.ResultsOut of the 14 collected articles, 10 articles were selected as final articles, of which five, three, one, and one article dealt with laboratory staff and students, industrial workers, hospital service workers, and farmers, respectively. The signs "flammable substances" (Comprehension Ratio (CR) (%): 39.5-98.8) and "risk of explosion" (CR (%):13-100) had the highest and the signs "skin irritant" (CR (%): 1.6-82) and "gas under pressure" (CR (%): 3.5-88.8) had the lowest comprehension among the GHS signs. Training, safety culture, education level, and gender were among the factors affecting the perception of these pictograms.ConclusionThis systematic review reveals that although GHS pictograms are a critical tool in safety communication, their inadequate perception in Iranian workplaces remains a significant challenge. This review highlights the requirement to review the design (e.g., simplifying signs or adding text labels), training (e.g., local language programs customized to a particular setting), and implementation (e.g., periodic assessments and specific workplace adjustments) of these international signs, taking into account local and cultural characteristics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramezanifar</LastName><ForeName>Soleiman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Health and Safety Engineering, School of Public Health and Safety, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramezanifar</LastName><ForeName>Ehsan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Occupational Health and Safety Engineering, School of Abarkouh Medical Sciences, Shahid Sadoughi University of Medical Sciences, Yazd, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Excellence for Occupational Health and Research, Center of Health Sciences, Hamadan University of Medical Sciences, Hamadan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Work</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9204382</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1051-9815</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GHS compliance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hazard awareness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iranian workplaces</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safety signage effectiveness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Visual warnings</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Workplace hazard perception</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41401012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10519815251398497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>