<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41904655</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-0756</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Postgraduate medical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Postgrad Med J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Accountability in care and cash: a call to quantify the costs of war on global health.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">qgag032</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/postmj/qgag032</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Wars erode human dignity and global solidarity. Take famine-the worst form of death by starvation en masse-for example. Famine is particularly telling and chilling, as in the modern era, the (almost) famine in Gaza and Sudan is predominantly human-made. In addition to acute consequences like deaths, famine also causes long-term damage to people's physical health and psychological well-being, from their susceptibility to cardiovascular diseases, trauma, and suicidality. A growing body of research also indicates that, largely due to high-definition and high-fidelity media coverage of wars with high definition and fidelity, people living in non-war zones can also face prolonged, yet often overlooked, mental health challenges. While the global health community shoulders the majority of the short- and long-term burden of care and cure in armed conflicts, we often have little power to hold warring parties responsible, not least because politicians' careers are often term-based if not short-lived. Using the famine in Gaza and Sudan as examples, this paper sheds light on the imperative of holding warring parties accountable-in care and cash-for the damage they exert on lives and livelihoods worldwide. Wars might be inevitable (almost), famine, and disregard for human dignity and despair are not. Key messages What is already known on this topic? War drives famine, disease outbreaks, psychological trauma, and health system collapse, disproportionately affecting women and children. Starvation has been used as a weapon of war, despite its prohibition under international humanitarian law. What this study adds Emphasizes the need to quantify the full health and economic costs of war, particularly in settings such as Gaza and Sudan experiencing famine and health system collapse. Proposes a Global Conflict Accountability Mechanism to hold warring parties financially responsible for health impacts. Advocates for the formal inclusion of global health professionals in diplomacy and peacebuilding. How this study might affect research, practice, or policy Encourages research on the long-term health and economic consequences of war, including mental health and chronic disease. Supports integrating global health actors into conflict-sensitive humanitarian planning and peace processes to improve equitable access to care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Fellowship of Postgraduate Medicine. All rights reserved. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site&#x2014;for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Zhaohui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2005-9504</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Key Laboratory of Environmental Medicine Engineering, Ministry of Education, Southeast University, Nanjing 210009, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ruijie</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Southeast University, Nanjing 210009, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaburu</LastName><ForeName>Francis Mungai</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, Southeast University, Nanjing 210009, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDonnell</LastName><ForeName>Dean</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Humanities, South East Technological University, Carlow R93 V960, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheshmehzangi</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture, Design and Planning, The University of Queensland, Brisbane 4072, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x160;egalo</LastName><ForeName>Sabina</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Studies, University of Sarajevo, Sarajevo 71000, Bosnia and Herzegovina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Junaid</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Affairs, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Jing-Bao</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioethics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Veiga</LastName><ForeName>Claudimar Pereira</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Funda&#xe7;&#xe3;o Dom Cabral-FDC, Av. Princesa Diana, 760 Alphaville, Lagoa dos Ingleses, Nova Lima, MG 34018-006, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Tao</ForeName><Initials>YT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Psychiatry, Department of Public Health and Medicinal Administration, University of Macau, Macao SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Psychiatry, Department of Public Health and Medicinal Administration, Faculty of Health Sciences; Centre for Cognitive and Brain Sciences, University of Macau, Macao SAR, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>4025002306</GrantID><Agency>The Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Jiangsu Provincial Institute of Health Emergency</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Research Centre for Medical and Health Emergency Rescue</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JSWSYJ-20240102</GrantID><Agency>Xuzhou Medical University Research Projects</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Postgrad Med J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0234135</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0032-5473</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">global health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">right to health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">war</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41904655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/postmj/qgag032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">8555559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>