<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41899905</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-4300</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Entropy (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Entropy (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Event-Driven Spiking Neural Networks for Private Vehicle Parking Prediction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">253</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/e28030253</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Predicting the future parking locations and durations of private vehicles using vehicular edge devices is critical for real-time intelligent transportation services, ranging from instant point-of-interest recommendations to dynamic route planning. Advanced deep neural networks like Transformers demonstrate exceptional performance in mobility prediction; however, their heavy reliance on dense matrix multiplication makes them unsuitable for real-time applications on vehicular edge devices. Spiking neural networks offer a potential solution due to their asynchronous event-driven characteristics and low power consumption. However, existing spiking neural networks face three fundamental challenges: (1) handling heterogeneous inter-event intervals; (2) mitigating quantization errors in regression tasks under limited simulation steps; and (3) efficiently regulating information flow based on external contexts. To address these challenges, we propose an event-driven spiking neural network for private vehicle parking prediction called Spark. First, we design a Time-Adaptive Leaky Integrate-and-Fire neuron with a lookup table-based decay mechanism to efficiently model variable inter-event intervals. Second, an accumulate-based readout strategy is introduced to mitigate quantization errors by integrating discrete spike trains into continuous output values for high-precision regression. Third, a Spiking Contextual Gating module is proposed to selectively regulate spiking information flow across channels based on environmental context. These components are integrated into a unified architecture that maintains high prediction accuracy while remaining computationally efficient. Extensive experiments on real-world datasets demonstrate that Spark achieves an effective balance between prediction accuracy and computational efficiency compared to baselines.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Wangchen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Artificial Intelligence, Zhuhai City Polytechnic, Zhuhai 519090, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6937-8090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Advanced Interdisciplinary Studies, Hunan University of Technology and Business, Changsha 410205, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xiangjiang Laboratory, Changsha 410205, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024KTSCX228</GrantID><Agency>Guangdong Province Characteristic Innovation Projects of Ordinary Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62202160</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24XJJCYJ01001</GrantID><Agency>Major Program of Xiangjiang Laboratory</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Entropy (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101243874</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1099-4300</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">event-driven modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irregular temporal sampling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobility prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spiking neural networks</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>All authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41899905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13025752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e28030253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">e28030253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Jiang W., Wu J., Li K., Li K. Dynamic Personalized POI Sequence Recommendation with Fine-Grained Contexts. ACM Trans. Internet Technol. 2023;23:1&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1145/3583687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3583687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long W., Xiao Z., Wang D., Jiang H., Chen J., Li Y., Alazab M. Unified spatial-temporal neighbor attention network for dynamic traffic prediction. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2023;72:1515&#x2013;1529. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2022.3209242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3209242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Xiao Z., Long W., Li T., Jiang H., Li K. Vehicle trajectory data processing, analytics, and applications: A survey. ACM Comput. Surv. 2025;57:1&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1145/3715902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3715902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez M.C., Hidalgo C.A., Barabasi A.L. Understanding individual human mobility patterns. Nature. 2008;453:779&#x2013;782. doi: 10.1038/nature06958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature06958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18528393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew W., Raposo R., Martins B. UbiComp &#x2019;12: Proceedings of the 2012 ACM Conference on Ubiquitous Computing, Pittsburgh, PA, USA, 5&#x2013;8 September 2012. Association for Computing Machinery; New York, NY, USA: 2012. Predicting future locations with hidden Markov models; pp. 911&#x2013;918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng J., Li Y., Zhang C., Sun F., Meng F., Guo A., Jin D. WWW &#x2019;18: Proceedings of the 2018 World Wide Web Conference, Lyon, France, 23&#x2013;27 April 2018. International World Wide Web Conferences Steering Committee; Geneva, Switzerland: 2018. Deepmove: Predicting human mobility with attentional recurrent networks; pp. 1459&#x2013;1468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long W., Li T., Xiao Z., Wang D., Zhang R., Regan A.C., Chen H., Zhu Y. Location Prediction for Individual Vehicles via Exploiting Travel Regularity and Preference. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2022;71:4718&#x2013;4731. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2022.3151762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3151762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H., Xu J., Wang J., Long M. NIPS &#x2019;21: Proceedings of the 35th International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems, Online, 6&#x2013;14 December 2021. Volume 34. Curran Associates Inc.; Red Hook, NY, USA: 2021. Autoformer: Decomposition transformers with auto-correlation for long-term series forecasting; pp. 22419&#x2013;22430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maass W. Networks of spiking neurons: The third generation of neural network models. Neural Netw. 1997;10:1659&#x2013;1671. doi: 10.1016/S0893-6080(97)00011-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0893-6080(97)00011-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Shi K., Lu C., Liu Y., Zhang M., Qu H. IJCAI &#x2019;23: Proceedings of the Thirty-Second International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Macao, China, 19&#x2013;25 August 2023. Curran Associates, Inc.; Red Hook, NY, USA: 2023. Spatial-Temporal Self-Attention for Asynchronous Spiking Neural Networks; pp. 3085&#x2013;3093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu R.J., Zhang M., Zhao Q., Deng H., Duan Y., Deng L.J. TCJA-SNN: Temporal-Channel Joint Attention for Spiking Neural Networks. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 2025;36:5112&#x2013;5125. doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2024.3377717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2024.3377717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38598397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv C., Wang Y., Han D., Zheng X., Huang X., Li D. Efficient and Effective Time-Series Forecasting with Spiking Neural Networks; Proceedings of the 41st International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML); Vienna, Austria. 21&#x2013;27 July 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng S., Feng W., Gao X., Zhao P., Shen Z. TS-LIF: A Temporal Segment Spiking Neuron Network for Time Series Forecasting; Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR); Singapore. 24&#x2013;28 April 2025; pp. 1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Liu J., Zhao K. SIGIR &#x2019;22: Proceedings of the 45th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, Madrid, Spain, 11&#x2013;15 July 2022. Association for Computing Machinery; New York, NY, USA: 2022. GETNext: Trajectory flow map enhanced transformer for next POI recommendation; pp. 1144&#x2013;1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y., Ye Y., Zhang S., Zhao X., Yu J. Proceedings of the Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, New Orleans, LA, USA, 10&#x2013;16 December 2023. Volume 36. Curran Associates, Inc.; Red Hook, NY, USA: 2023. DiffTraj: Generating gps trajectory with diffusion probabilistic model; pp. 65168&#x2013;65188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Hu T., Zhang H., Wu H., Wang S., Ma L., Long M. iTransformer: Inverted Transformers are Effective for Time Series Forecasting; Proceedings of the Twelfth International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR); Vienna, Austria. 7&#x2013;11 May 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y., Li H., Liao Y., Wang B., Guan Z., Liu H., Cai D. IJCAI&#x2019;17: Proceedings of the 26th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Melbourne, Australia, 19&#x2013;25 August 2017. AAAI Press; Washington, DC, USA: 2017. What to Do Next: Modeling User Behaviors by Time-LSTM; pp. 3602&#x2013;3608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubanova Y., Chen R.T.Q., Duvenaud D.K. Latent Ordinary Differential Equations for Irregularly-Sampled Time Series; Proceedings of the Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS); Vancouver, BC, Canada. 8&#x2013;14 December 2019; pp. 1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo S., Jiang H., Li Z., Martin T., Suk H., Zhao T. ICML&#x2019;20: Proceedings of the 37th International Conference on Machine Learning, Online, 13&#x2013;18 July 2020. JMLR; Norfolk, MA, USA: 2020. Transformer Hawkes Process; pp. 11692&#x2013;11702.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Xia L., Tang J., Xu Y., Shi L., Xia L., Yin D., Huang C. KDD &#x2019;24: Proceedings of the 30th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, Barcelona, Spain, 25&#x2013;29 August 2024. Association for Computing Machinery; New York, NY, USA: 2024. UrbanGPT: Spatio-temporal large language models; pp. 5351&#x2013;5362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masquelier T., Thorpe S.J. Unsupervised Learning of Visual Features through Spike Timing Dependent Plasticity. PLoS Comput. Biol. 2007;3:e311. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.0030031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.0030031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1797822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17305422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilal M., Tariq O., Ahmed H. NOS-Gate: Queue-Aware Streaming IDS for Consumer Gateways under Timing-Controlled Evasion. arXiv. 20262601.00389</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang W., Chen Y., Ding J., Yu Z., Masquelier T., Chen D., Huang L., Zhou H., Li G., Tian Y. SpikingJelly: An open-source machine learning infrastructure platform for spike-based intelligence. Sci. Adv. 2023;9:eadi1480. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.adi1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adi1480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10558124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37801497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horowitz M. Proceedings of the 2014 IEEE International Solid-State Circuits Conference Digest of Technical Papers (ISSCC), San Francisco, CA, USA, 9-13 February 2014. IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2014. 1.1 Computing&#x2019;s energy problem (and what we can do about it) pp. 10&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman M.E. Power laws, Pareto distributions and Zipf&#x2019;s law. Contemp. Phys. 2005;46:323&#x2013;351. doi: 10.1080/00107510500052444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00107510500052444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho E.F., Bordons A.C. Model Predictive Control. Springer Science &amp; Business Media; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarting W., Alonso-Mora J., Rus D. Planning and decision-making for autonomous vehicles. Annu. Rev. Control. Robot. Auton. Syst. 2018;1:187&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1146/annurev-control-060117-105157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-control-060117-105157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>