<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41333968</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1728-869X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise science and fitness</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Sci Fit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of retrograde run training on long jump performances of student athletes: A randomized controlled study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100426</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100426</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100426</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jesf.2025.11.005</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Retrograde run training increases forward run speed and muscle power. However, the effect of retrograde run training on long jump performance is not known. The objective of this study was to investigate the effect of retrograde run training on the long jump performance of physical education (PE) students compared to conventional training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A randomized clinical trial was conducted including 120&#xa0;PE students from Huzhou University Physical Education Faculty. The participants were randomly allocated into an experimental group or control group. Both groups received a conventional long jump training program, however the experimental group received additional retrograde run training (10&#xa0;min 3 times per week for 12 weeks), while the control group received a similar level of forward run training. Changes in long jump and other performances were measured at 4, 8 and 12 weeks of the training program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Over the 12-week intervention, the experimental group demonstrated significantly greater improvements in long jump, take off angle, take off accuracy, standing long jump, single leg stance, 30-m forward sprint and 40-m retrograde shuttle run compared to the control group (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). Within-group analysis confirmed the experimental group improved significantly from baseline in all outcomes (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05). In contrast, the control group showed significant improvement only in long jump performance, take-off angle, and single leg stance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The addition of retrograde run training to traditional long jump training significantly improved long jump performance in PE students and may be used as an alternative method to enhance long jump performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Society of Chinese Scholars on Exercise Physiology and Fitness. Published by Elsevier (Singapore) Pte Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Xinming</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School, Khon Kaen University, Khon Kaen, 40002, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Faculty of Physical Education, Huzhou University, Zhejiang, 313000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manimmanakorn</LastName><ForeName>Nuttaset</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Khon Kaen University, Khon Kaen, 40002, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manimmanakorn</LastName><ForeName>Apiwan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Khon Kaen University, Khon Kaen, 40002, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamlin</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tourism, Sport and Society, Lincoln University, Lincoln, 7647, Christchurch, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Singapore</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Sci Fit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101198241</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1728-869X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Backward run training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long jump distance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Speed</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Take-off</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41333968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12666334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2025.11.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1728-869X(25)00079-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>De Melo R.G. Reggo Edi&#xe7;&#xf5;es; Manaus: 2018. Athletics from Ancient Times to the End of the 19Th Century; pp. 13&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra M.K., Rathore V.S. Speed and agility as predictors of long jump performance of male athletes. Turk J Sports Med. 2016;18(2):27&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngetich E.D., Rintaugu E.G. Assessment of physical fitness components as prediction factors of long jump performance. Int J Curr Res. 2013;5(1):17&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthorne N.P., Guzman M.S., Bridgett L.A. Optimum take-off angle in the long jump. J Sports Sci. 2005;23(7):703&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanis G.C., Tsoukos A., Veligekas P. Improvement of long-jump performance during competition using a plyometric exercise. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(2):235&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27249821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong P. Strength training of long jump athletes. Rev Bras Med do Esporte. 2022;29 0278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xea;ma S., Seixas A., Moreira-Silvam I., et al. Influence of different durations of lower limb static stretching on the performance of long jump athletes: a randomized controlled trial. Sport Sci Health. 2024;20(1):73&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthoff A., Oliver J., Cronin J., et al. Sprint-specific training in youth: Backward running vs. forward running training on speed and power measures in adolescent male athletes. J Strength Condit Res. 2020;34(4):1113&#x2013;1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthoff A., Oliver J., Cronin J., et al. A new direction to athletic performance: understanding the acute and longitudinal responses to backward running. Sports Med. 2018;48:1083&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29498028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthoff A., Oliver J., Cronin J., et al. Backward running: the why and how to program for better athleticism. Strength Condit J. 2019;41(5):48&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M., Krustrup P., Bangsbo J. Match performance of high-standard soccer players with special reference to development of fatigue. J Sports Sci. 2003;21(7):519&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12848386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delextrat A., Cohen D. Strength, power, speed, and agility of women basketball players according to playing position. J Strength Condit Res. 2009;23(7):1974&#x2013;1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiani A., Hellquist E., Ahlqvist K., et al. Prevention of soccer-related knee injuries in teenaged girls. Arch Intern Med. 2010;170(1):43&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20065198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdizadeh S., Arshi A.R., Davids K. Quantifying coordination and coordination variability in backward versus forward running: implications for control of motion. Gait Posture. 2015;42(2):172&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26021460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedhom M.G. Backward walking training improves knee proprioception in non athletic males. Int J Physiother. 2017;4(1):33&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z.H., Ye X.L., Chen W.J., et al. Effectiveness of backward walking for people affected by stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Medicine. 2020;99(27)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Xu J., An R. Effectiveness of backward walking training on balance performance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gait Posture. 2019;68:466&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30616175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kachanathu S.J., Hafez A.R., Zakaria A.R. Efficacy of backward versus forward walking on hamstring strain rehabilitation. Int J Ther Rehabil. 2013;2(1):8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha H.G., Kim T.H., Kim M.K. Therapeutic efficacy of walking backward and forward on a slope in normal adults. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28(6):1901&#x2013;1903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4932084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27390443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedhom M.G. Backward walking training improves knee proprioception in non athletic males. Int J Physiother. 2017;4(1):33&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sammoud S., Bouguezzi R., Uthoff A., et al. The effects of backward vs. forward running training on measures of physical fitness in young female handball players. Front Sports Act Living. 2023;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Athletics  Competition rules and technical rules 2024. World athletics web site. https://worldathletics.org/about-iaaf/documents/book-of-rules</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin-Jimenez N., Perez-Bey A., Cruz-Leon C., et al. Criterion-related validity and reliability of the standing long jump test in adults: the adult-fit project. Eur J Sport Sci. 2024;24(9):1379&#x2013;1392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11369318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39167610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D., Singh S. Effects of vertical, horizontal, and combination depth jump training on long jump performance. Biomed Hum Kinet. 2012;4:107&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins W.G. Spreadsheets for analysis of validity and reliability. Sportscience. 2015;19:36&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkmen N., Taskin H., Sanioglu A., et al. Relationships between balance and functional performance in football players. J Hum Kinet. 2010;26:21&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Ji Z., Jiang G., et al. Correlation among proprioception, muscle strength, and balance. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28(12):3468&#x2013;3472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5276784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28174475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Amat A., Hita-Contreras F., Lomas-Vega R., et al. Effects of 12-week proprioception training program on postural stability, gait, and balance in older adults: a controlled clinical trial. J Strength Condit Res. 2013;27(8):2180&#x2013;2188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linthorne N.P., Guzman M.S., Bridgett L.A. Optimum take-off angle in the long jump. J Sports Sci. 2005;23(7):703&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyfarth A., Blickhan R., Van Leeuwen J.L. Optimum take-off techniques and muscle design for long jump. J Exp Biol. 2000;203(4):741&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10648215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makaruk H., Starzak M., Sadowski J. Does step length adjustment determine take-off accuracy and approach run velocity in long and triple jumps? Hum Mov. 2015;16(3):124&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D.N., Lishman J.R., Thomson J.A. Regulation of gait in long jumping. J Exp Psychol Hum Percept Perform. 1982;8(3):448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montagne G., Cornus S., Glize D., et al. A perception-action coupling type of control in long jumping. J Mot Behav. 2000;32(1):37&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11008270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoogkamer W., Meyns P., Duysens J. Steps forward in understanding backward gait: from basic circuits to rehabilitation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2014;42(1):23&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24188982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>