<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41344003</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-2828</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>124</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ultrasonics sonochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ultrason Sonochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Correlation between the degree of ultrasound-induced cell disintegration and the extraction efficiency of intracellular compounds from purple sweet potato.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107699</StartPage><MedlinePgn>107699</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">107699</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2025.107699</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1350-4177(25)00478-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ultrasound (US) is an effective intensified extraction technology for natural plant resources, but detailed microscale investigations into US-induced plant cell disintegration are lacking. This study explored the correlation between US-induced (P = 0-800&#xa0;W, t&#xa0;=&#xa0;0-40&#xa0;min) cell disintegration degree and the extraction efficiency of intracellular components from purple sweet potato, also discussing extraction selectivity and visualizing the cell micro-disintegration process. Cell disintegration degree was estimated via electrical conductivity (cell permeabilization index, Z<sub>i</sub>) and fractal dimension analysis of damaged cells (cell wall disintegration index, Z<sub>d</sub>). Extraction efficiency was evaluated by using the extraction indexes of carbohydrate (Z<sub>c</sub>), protein (Z<sub>p</sub>), and total phenolic compound (Z<sub>TPC</sub>). Results indicated that US markedly enhanced cell permeabilization and intracellular components release. For example, at the highest intensity (800&#xa0;W, 40&#xa0;min), the enhancement in carbohydrate, protein and TPC contents were approximately 2 to 7 folds, compared to untreated sample (0&#xa0;W, 40&#xa0;min). Extraction efficiencies depended on the applied P and t, with the extractability order was carbohydrate&#xa0;&gt;&#xa0;protein&#xa0;&gt;&#xa0;TPC at each power. Different non-linear correlations between Z<sub>d</sub> with Z<sub>i</sub>, Z<sub>p</sub>, Z<sub>c</sub>, and Z<sub>TPC</sub>, reflecting the differences in the release behaviors of these water-soluble components after US treatment. Additionally, US favored carbohydrate extraction over protein, but stronger US intensity resulted in lower extraction selectivity. The visual microscale model showed that increasing P elevated cell surface acoustic pressure, cell stress and volume strain. Cell micro-disintegration process would initiate at the side and end faces, then gradually spread to the edges.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National R&amp;D Center for Se-rich Agricultural Products Processing, Hubei Engineering Research Center for Deep Processing of Green Se-rich Agricultural Products, School of Modern Industry for Selenium Science and Engineering, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Wangting</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National R&amp;D Center for Se-rich Agricultural Products Processing, Hubei Engineering Research Center for Deep Processing of Green Se-rich Agricultural Products, School of Modern Industry for Selenium Science and Engineering, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yilin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National R&amp;D Center for Se-rich Agricultural Products Processing, Hubei Engineering Research Center for Deep Processing of Green Se-rich Agricultural Products, School of Modern Industry for Selenium Science and Engineering, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Muci</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National R&amp;D Center for Se-rich Agricultural Products Processing, Hubei Engineering Research Center for Deep Processing of Green Se-rich Agricultural Products, School of Modern Industry for Selenium Science and Engineering, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National R&amp;D Center for Se-rich Agricultural Products Processing, Hubei Engineering Research Center for Deep Processing of Green Se-rich Agricultural Products, School of Modern Industry for Selenium Science and Engineering, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China; School of Food Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory for Deep Processing of Major Grain and Oil, Ministry of Education, Hubei Key Laboratory for Processing and Transformation of Agricultural Products, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China. Electronic address: ruizhangwhpu@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Jingren</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National R&amp;D Center for Se-rich Agricultural Products Processing, Hubei Engineering Research Center for Deep Processing of Green Se-rich Agricultural Products, School of Modern Industry for Selenium Science and Engineering, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China; School of Food Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory for Deep Processing of Major Grain and Oil, Ministry of Education, Hubei Key Laboratory for Processing and Transformation of Agricultural Products, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China. Electronic address: jingren.he@whpu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Food Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory for Deep Processing of Major Grain and Oil, Ministry of Education, Hubei Key Laboratory for Processing and Transformation of Agricultural Products, Wuhan Polytechnic University, Wuhan 430023, China. Electronic address: chen.liu@whpu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Ultrason Sonochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9433356</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-4177</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002241">Carbohydrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010636">Phenols</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010940">Plant Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D027723" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ipomoea batatas</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069453" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ultrasonic Waves</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042541" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intracellular Space</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002241" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbohydrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005591" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chemical Fractionation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010636" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010940" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell disintegration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intracellular components</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Purple sweet potato</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Selective extraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasound</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41344003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12720041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2025.107699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1350-4177(25)00478-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Zhao L., Bian X., Guo K., Zhou L., Wei C. Characterization and comparative study of starches from seven purple sweet potatoes. Food Hydrocoll. 2018;80:168&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li A., Xiao R., He S., An X., He Y., Wang C., Yin S., Wang B., Shi X., He J. Research advances of purple sweet potato anthocyanins: extraction, identification, stability, bioactivity, application, and biotransformation. Molecules. 2019;24:3816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6864833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31652733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang C., Han J., Chen D., Zong S., Liu J., Kan J., Qian C., Jin C. Recent advances on the biological activities of purple sweet potato anthocyanins. Food Biosci. 2023;53</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C.-C., Lin C., Chen M.-H., Chiang P.-Y. Stability and quality of anthocyanin in purple sweet potato extracts. Foods. 2019;8:393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31489943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arindra A. The effect of three blanching treatments on purple sweet potato (Ipomea batatas L.) anthocyanin extract retention. Indonesia International Institute for Life Sciences. 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Mena A., Ochoa-Martinez L.A., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Herrera S.M., Rutiaga-Qui&#xf1;ones O.M., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Laredo R.F., Olmedilla-Alonso B., Vega-Maturino S. Coloring potential of anthocyanins from purple sweet potato paste: Ultrasound-assisted extraction, enzymatic activity, color and its application in ice pops. Food Chem. Adv. 2023;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez L., Mu&#xf1;oz-Bernal &#xd3;.A., Fuentes E., Alvarez-Parrilla E., Palomo I., Wall-Medrano A. Phenolic profile, cheminformatics, and antiplatelet aggregation activity of orange and purple sweet potato (Ipomoea batatas L.) storage roots. Food Chem. 2024;454</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadele M.A., Roy V.C., Ho T.C., Chun B.-S. Extraction of anthocyanin from purple sweet potato using ultrasound-assisted natural deep eutectic solvents and its application for smart packaging film. Food Bioprocess Technol. 2025;18:2394&#x2013;2409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W., Yang C., Zhou C., Wen Z., Dong X. An improved microwave-assisted extraction of anthocyanins from purple sweet potato in favor of subsequent comprehensive utilization of pomace. Food Bioprod. Process. 2019;115:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lao F., Cheng H., Wang Q., Wang X., Liao X., Xu Z. Enhanced water extraction with high-pressure carbon dioxide on purple sweet potato pigments: comparison to traditional aqueous and ethanolic extraction. J. CO2 Util. 2020;40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira B.A., Guti&#xe9;rrez E.A., de Souza M.S.da.S., Rigolon T.C.B., Martins E., Pessoa F.L.P., Vidigal M.C.T.R., Stringheta P.C. Design, optimization, and modeling study of ultrasound-assisted extraction of bioactive compounds from purple-fleshed sweet potatoes. Foods. 2024;13:1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11119358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38790797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Lebovka N., Marchal L., Vorobiev E., Grimi N. Comparison of aqueous extraction assisted by pulsed electric energy and ultrasonication: Efficiencies for different microalgal species. Algal Res. 2020;47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karki B., Lamsal B.P., Jung S., van Leeuwen J.H., Pometto A.L., III, Grewell D., Khanal S.K. Enhancing protein and sugar release from defatted soy flakes using ultrasound technology. J. Food Eng. 2010;96:270&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojha K.S., Aznar R., O&#x2019;Donnell C., Tiwari B.K. Ultrasound technology for the extraction of biologically active molecules from plant, animal and marine sources. TrAC Trends Anal. Chem. 2020;122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimi N., Dubois A., Marchal L., Jubeau S., Lebovka N.I., Vorobiev E. Selective extraction from microalgae Nannochloropsis sp. using different methods of cell disruption. Bioresour. Technol. 2014;153:254&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24368274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi C., Chi S., Zhou T., Zhang J., Wang X., Li J., Shi W., Tian B., Huang Z., Liu Y. Effect of low-frequency high-intensity ultrasound (HIU) on the physicochemical properties of chickpea protein. Food Res. Int. 2022;159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui R., Zhu F. Effect of ultrasound on structural and physicochemical properties of sweetpotato and wheat flours. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2020;66</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong T., Liu S., Feng Y., Fan Y., Yu J., Zhang H., Cai M., Ma H., Duan Y. Slit dual-frequency ultrasound-assisted pulping of Lycium barbarum fresh fruit to improve the dissolution of polysaccharides and in situ real-time monitoring. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2023;98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Boussetta N., Lebovka N., Lefebvre C., Vorobiev E. Correlations between disintegration degree of fruit skin cells induced by ultrasound and efficiency of bio-compounds extraction. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2019;52:280&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30555040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebovka N.I., Bazhal M.I., Vorobiev E. Estimation of characteristic damage time of food materials in pulsed-electric fields. J. Food Eng. 2002;54:337&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carullo D., Abera B.D., Casazza A.A., Dons&#x2018;i F., Perego P., Ferrari G., Pataro G. Effect of pulsed electric fields and high pressure homogenization on the aqueous extraction of intracellular compounds from the microalgae Chlorella vulgaris. Algal Res. 2018;31:60&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng J., Sun J., Huang Y., Zhou J., Cen K. Fractal microstructure characterization of wet microalgal cells disrupted with ultrasonic cavitation for lipid extraction. Bioresour. Technol. 2014;170:138&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25128843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B.B. Mandelbrot, The fractal geometry of nature WH Freeman and Co, New York (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng J., Guo H., Qiu Y., Zhang Z., Mao Y., Qian L., Yang W., Park J.-Y. Switchable solvent N, N, N&#x2032;, N&#x2032;-tetraethyl-1, 3-propanediamine was dissociated into cationic surfactant to promote cell disruption and lipid extraction from wet microalgae for biodiesel production. Bioresour. Technol. 2020;312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois M., Gilles K.A., Hamilton J.K., t Rebers P.A., Smith F. Colorimetric method for determination of sugars and related substances. Anal. Chem. 1956;28:350&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradford M.M. A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principle of protein-dye binding. Anal. Biochem. 1976;72:248&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">942051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong S., Chen M., Pei X., Yin J., Oliveira H., Mateus N., Ye S., Wu M., Zhang R., He J. Antiproliferative and antioxidant properties of protein-free and protein-bound phenolics isolated from purple rice (Oryza sativa L.) Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;293</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koubaa M., Barba F.J., Grimi N., Mhemdi H., Koubaa W., Boussetta N., Vorobiev E. Recovery of colorants from red prickly pear peels and pulps enhanced by pulsed electric field and ultrasound. Innov. Food Sci. Emerg. Technol. 2016;37:336&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barba F.J., Grimi N., Vorobiev E. Evaluating the potential of cell disruption technologies for green selective extraction of antioxidant compounds from Stevia rebaudiana Bertoni leaves. J. Food Eng. 2015;149:222&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almohammed F., Koubaa M., Khelfa A., Nakaya M., Mhemdi H., Vorobiev E. Pectin recovery from sugar beet pulp enhanced by high-voltage electrical discharges. Food Bioprod. Process. 2017;103:95&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Boussetta N., Lebovka N., Vorobiev E. Effects of ultrasound treatment and concentration of ethanol on selectivity of phenolic extraction from apple pomace. Int. J. Food Sci. &amp; Technol. 2018;53:2104&#x2013;2109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Boussetta N., Lebovka N., Vorobiev E. Selectivity of ultrasound-assisted aqueous extraction of valuable compounds from flesh and peel of apple tissues. LWT. 2018;93:511&#x2013;516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Marchal L., Lebovka N., Vorobiev E., Grimi N. Two-step procedure for selective recovery of bio-molecules from microalga Nannochloropsis oculata assisted by high voltage electrical discharges. Bioresour. Technol. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethi S., Rathod V.K. Recent advancements in ultrasound-assisted biomolecule extraction from prokaryotic and eukaryotic cells: a review. Prep. Biochem. &amp; Biotechnol. 2024:1&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Ye S., Guo Y., Wu M., Jiang S., He J. Studies on the interaction between homological proteins and anthocyanins from purple sweet potato (PSP): structural characterization, binding mechanism and stability. Food Chem. 2023;400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang T., Zhou J., Liu W., Tao W., He J., Jin W., Guo H., Yang N., Li Y. The anti-inflammatory potential of protein-bound anthocyanin compounds from purple sweet potato in LPS-induced RAW264. 7 macrophages. Food Res. Int. 2020;137</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oladejo A.O., Ma H., Qu W., Zhou C., Wu B. Effects of ultrasound on mass transfer kinetics, structure, carotenoid and vitamin C content of osmodehydrated sweet potato (Ipomea batatas) Food Bioprocess Technol. 2017;10:1162&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pongmalai P., Devahastin S., Chiewchan N., Soponronnarit S. Enhancement of microwave-assisted extraction of bioactive compounds from cabbage outer leaves via the application of ultrasonic pretreatment. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2015;144:37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parniakov O., Barba F.J., Grimi N., Lebovka N., Vorobiev E. Extraction assisted by pulsed electric energy as a potential tool for green and sustainable recovery of nutritionally valuable compounds from mango peels. Food Chem. 2016;192:842&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26304419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barba F.J., Parniakov O., Pereira S.A., Wiktor A., Grimi N., Boussetta N., Saraiva J.A., Raso J., Martin-Belloso O., Witrowa-Rajchert D., et al. Current applications and new opportunities for the use of pulsed electric fields in food science and industry. Food Res. Int. 2015;77:773&#x2013;798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Boussetta N., Lebovka N., Vorobiev E. Cell disintegration of apple peels induced by pulsed electric field and efficiency of bio-compound extraction. Food Bioprod. Process. 2020;122:13&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parniakov O., Rosello-Soto E., Barba F.J., Grimi N., Lebovka N., Vorobiev E. New approaches for the effective valorization of papaya seeds: Extraction of proteins, phenolic compounds, carbohydrates, and isothiocyanates assisted by pulsed electric energy. Food Res. Int. 2015;77:711&#x2013;717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang T., Shuai X., Li J., Yang N., Deng L., Li S., He Y., Guo H., Li Y., He J. Protein-bound anthocyanin compounds of purple sweet potato ameliorate hyperglycemia by regulating hepatic glucose metabolism in high-fat diet/streptozotocin-induced diabetic mice. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2020;68:1596&#x2013;1608. doi: 10.1021/acs.jafc.9b06916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jafc.9b06916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31927925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei X., Wang J., Liu C., Tan Z., Li Y., Wu M., Zhou W., He J., Grimi N., Zhang R. Enhancement of cell disruption and selective recovery of intracellular components from selenium-enriched Konjac fly powder assisted by pulsed electric fields. Food Chem. 2025;X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao P., Hao C., Li B., Jiang H., Liu Y. Effect of ruptured cavitated bubble cluster on the extent of the cell deformation by ultrasound. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2021;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inui A., Honda A., Yamanaka S., Ikeno T., Yamamoto K. Effect of ultrasonic frequency and surfactant addition on microcapsule destruction. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2021;70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Lin L., Cheng M., Jin L., Du L., Han T., Xu L., Yu A.C.H., Qin P. Effect of acoustic parameters on the cavitation behavior of SonoVue microbubbles induced by pulsed ultrasound. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2017;35:176&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X., Cai C., Xu G., Yang Y., Tu J., Huang P., Zhang D. Interaction between cavitation microbubble and cell: a simulation of sonoporation using boundary element method (BEM) Ultrason. Sonochem. 2017;39:863&#x2013;871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28733016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H., Zhou C., Pu Z., Yu H., Li D. Effect of low-frequency ultrasonic field at different power on the dynamics of a single bubble near a rigid wall. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2019;58</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Huang B., Li Y., Chang Q., Qiu S., Su Z., Fu X., Wang G. Numerical simulation of single bubble dynamics under acoustic travelling waves. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2018;42:619&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29429710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>