<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41731836</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the usability of YouTube videos as educational materials in improving patients' metered dose inhaler use skills: A cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e47786</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e47786</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e47786</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000047786</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to analyze the quality, reliability, and content of YouTube videos related to the use technique of metered dose inhalers (MDIs). Considering the increasing use of digital platforms for health education, it is important to evaluate the accuracy and educational value of such online resources. This descriptive and cross-sectional study evaluated 377 YouTube videos retrieved through a systematic search. The video selection process was monitored using the PRISMA flow diagram according to predefined inclusion and exclusion criteria. The videos' content, quality, and reliability were assessed using the Modified DISCERN tool, Global Quality Scale, Patient Education Materials Assessment Tool, and a checklist containing MDI use steps. Statistical analyses were conducted to determine associations between evaluation scores and video characteristics. A total of 12 YouTube videos on MDI use were analyzed. Of these, 33.3% were uploaded in 2022, and 66.7% were produced by associations or unions in the health sector. The mean interaction index was 0.53&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;0.32, and the Video Power Index was 0.08&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;0.15. The mean reliability level of the videos was 2.91&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;0.75, quality level 4.16&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;0.76, understandability level 80.83&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;18.75, actionability level 81.66&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;18.16, information level 77.00&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;15.06, and information accuracy level 76.25&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;15.80. YouTube videos on MDI use were largely adequate in terms of content but demonstrated some deficiencies in reliability. It is recommended that digital health information be produced under professional supervision and in collaboration with health authorities to ensure accuracy and trustworthiness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arslan</LastName><ForeName>Canan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7202-9185</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Services and Techniques, Istanbul Topkapi University, Plato Vocational School, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yildiz</LastName><ForeName>Hicran</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4241-5231</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Uludag University, Institute of Health Sciences, Bursa, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metered Dose Inhalers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061108" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Media</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010353" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Education as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Video Recording</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">educational video</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inhaler</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">material quality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metered dose inhaler</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12928894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000047786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202602200-00093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Scullion J. The nurse practitioners&#x2019; perspective on inhaler education in asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Can Respir J. 2018;2018:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6098863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30154941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zel F, &#xc7;iray G&#xfc;nd&#xfc;zo&#x11f;lu N, Durmaz Akyol A. Ability and satisfaction of COPD and asthmatic patients to use inhalers. ACU Health Sci J. 2018;9:266&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrystyn H, Price DB, Molimard M, et al. Comparison of serious inhaler technique errors made by device-na&#xef;ve patients using three different dry powder inhalers: a randomized, crossover, open-label study. BMC Pulm Med. 2016;16:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4712500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26769482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Association for Respiratory Care. A Guide to Aerosol Delivery Devices for Respiratory Therapists. 5th ed. American Association for Respiratory Care; 2023. Accessed April 25, 2025 https://www.aarc.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/aerosol_guide_rt.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharm KMS, Paradiso VC, Slimmer ML, Campbell DL, Pharm TBT. Evaluation of the prevalence and effectiveness of education on metered-dose inhaler technique. Respir Care. 2017;62:1070&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28351904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arslan V, Oktay Arslan B, &#xd6;zdemir ME. Evaluation of the skills of COPD and asthma patients to use inhalers in primary health care centers. Turk J Fam Med. 2021;25:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swami V, Cho JG, Smith T, Wheatley J, Roberts M. Confidence of nurses with inhaler device education and competency in the device used in a specialized respiratory inpatient unit. Sage Open Nurs. 2021;18:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7983467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33739194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-de-Ara&#xfa;jo A, Teixeira P, Hespanhol V, Correia-de-Sousa J. COPD: misuse of inhaler devices in clinical practice. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2019;14:1209&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6549399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31213798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x15f;lilar S, &#x15e;aylan B, Oluda&#x11f; G, Sariman N. Investigation of inhaler usage skills of patients applying to chest diseases outpatient clinic. Turk J Fam Med. 2018;22:66&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Kalaldeh M, El-Rahman MA, El-Ata A. Effectiveness of nurse-driven inhaler education on inhaler proficiency and compliance among obstructive lung disease patients: a quasi-experimental study. Can J Nurs Res. 2016;48:48&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28841042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takaku Y, Kurashima K, Ohta C, et al. How many instructions are required to correct inhalation errors in asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease patients? Respir Med. 2017;123:110&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28137486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purohit AN, Patel P, Gandhi AM, Desa MK. An evaluation of the impact of educational interventions on the technique of use of metered-dose inhalers by patients. Indian J Pharmacol. 2017;49:194&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5497443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28706334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pothirat C, Chaiwong W, Phetsuk N, Pisalthanapuna S, Chetsadaphan N, Choomuang W. Evaluating inhaler use technique in COPD patients. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2015;10:1291&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4501446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26185435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zkan CG, Ka&#x15f;ik&#xe7;i MK. The nurse&#x2019;s role in managing metered dose inhalers and patient education process. J Health Sci Prof. 2015;2:355&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canbolat O, Dogan Aktas AB, Sipal G, Nurdan K. Evaluating the quality and content of YouTube videos as an educational resource in developing patients&#x2019; inhaler use skills. J Asthma. 2024;61:1006&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38359086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>I&#x15f;ik O, G&#xfc;l G, Bol P, Erbaycu AE. Evaluating outpatients&#x2019; compliance with inhaler use techniques: application of an inhaler drug education unit. J Respir Dis. 2014;24:90&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson SR, Chang A, Johnson CE, Durning SJ, Gruppen LD. Lecture versus web tutorial for pharmacy students&#x2019; learning of MDI technique. Ann Pharmacother. 2003;37:500&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12659603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toumas M, Basheti IA, Bosnic-Anticevich S. Comparison of small-group training with self-directed internet-based training in inhaler techniques. Am J Pharm Educ. 2009;73:85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2739068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19777100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller T, M&#xfc;ller A, H&#xfc;bel C, et al. Optimizing inhalation technique using web-based videos in obstructive lung diseases. Respir Med. 2017;129:140&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28732821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locke ER, Thomas RM, Woo DM, et al. Using video telehealth to facilitate inhaler training in rural patients with obstructive lung disease. Telemed J E Health. 2019;25:230&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6916242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30016216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drozd B, Couvillon E, Suarez A. Medical YouTube videos and methods of evaluation: literature review. JMIR Med Educ. 2018;4:e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5826977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29434018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arklan U, Kartal N. YouTube usage by Y generation as a content consumer: study on usage purposes, usage levels and followed contents. Gumushane Univ Fac Commun Electron J. 2018;6:929&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juntire. YouTube Statistics Popular Picks. 2023. Accessed April 25, 2025. https://juntire.com/blog/YouTube-istatistikleri#YouTubeistatistikleri-populer-secimler-2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasamnis AA, Patil SS. YouTube as a tool for health education. J Educ Health Promot. 2019;8:241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6967149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32002413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon H, Lee GH. Evaluation of Korean-language COVID-19-related medical information on YouTube: cross-sectional infodemiology study. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22:e20775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onder ME, Zengin O. YouTube as a source of information on gout: a quality analysis. Rheumatol Int. 2021;41:1321&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7917371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33646342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi J, Trang T, Doong J, Kang S, Chien AL. Misinformation is prevalent in psoriasis-related YouTube videos. Dermatol Online J. 2016;22:13030/qt7qc9z2m5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28329562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HOY, Bailey A, Huynh D, Chan J. YouTube as a source of information on COVID-19: a pandemic of misinformation? BMJ Glob Health. 2020;5:e002604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Songur MS, &#xc7;itirik M. Epiretinal membrane surgery on YouTube. Van Med J. 2022;29:327&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kind T, Evans Y. Social media for lifelong learning. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2015;27:124&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25906988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>We Are Social. Digital 2023 T&#xfc;rkiye Report. 2023. Accessed March 20, 2025. https://www.guvenliweb.org.tr/dosya/HQTLP.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madathil KC, Rivera-Rodriguez AJ, Greenstein JS, Gramopadhye AK. Healthcare information on YouTube: a systematic review. Health Inform Journal. 2015;21:173&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24670899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sui W, Sui A, Rhodes RE. What to watch: practical considerations and strategies for using YouTube for research. Digit Health. 2022;8:20552076221123707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9465614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36105625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khilnani AK, Thaddanee R, Khilnani G. Learning ENT&#x2019;by YouTube videos: perceptions of third professional MBBS students. Int J Otorhinolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2020;6:1120&#x2013;2224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassona Y, Taimeh D, Marahleh A, Scully C. YouTube is a source of information on mouth (oral) cancer. Oral Dis. 2016;22:202&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26718020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ElKarmi R, Hassona Y, Taimeh D, Scully C. YouTube is a source for parents&#x2019; education on early childhood caries. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2017;27:437&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Liu Y, Zhao Z. Exploring the factors influencing consumer engagement behavior regarding short-form video advertising: a big data perspective. J Retail Consum Serv. 2023;70:103170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen T, Tran L. The authenticity advantage: how influencer authenticity management strategies shape digital engagement with sponsored videos. J Bus Res. 2024;185:114937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stappen L, Baird A, Lienhart M, B&#xe4;tz A, Schuller B. An estimation of online video user engagement from features of time- and value-continuous, dimensional emotions. Front Comput Sci. 2021;4:773154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhabash S, Ma M. A tale of four platforms: motivations and uses of Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Snapchat among college students. Soc Media Soc. 2017;3:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enke N, Borchers NS. Social media influencers in strategic communication: a conceptual framework for strategic social media influencer communication. Int J Strateg Commun. 2019;13:261&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora AS, Bansal S, Kandpal C, Aswani R, Dwivedi YK. Measuring social media influencer index&#x2013;insights from Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram. J Retail Consum Serv. 2019;49:86&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnock D, Shepperd S, Needham G, Gann R. DISCERN:an instrument for judging the quality of written consumer health information on treatment choices. J Epidemiol Community Health. 1999;53:105&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10396471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AG, Singh S, Singh PP. YouTube for information on rheumatoid arthritis &#x2013; a wake-up call? J Rheumatol. 2012;39:899&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22467934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Us YO, Us MC. Evaluation of reliability, quality, accuracy, and content of YouTube videos on bruxism in children-a descriptive study. J Child. 2023;23:69&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard A, Langille M, Hughes S, Rose C, Leddin D, Van Zanten SV. A systematic review of patient inflammatory bowel disease information resources on the World Wide Web. Am J Gastroenterol. 2007;102:2070&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17511753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoemaker SJ, Wolf MS, Brach C. Development of the Patient Education Materials Assessment Tool (PEMAT): a new measure of understandability and actionability for print and audiovisual patient information. Patient Educ Couns. 2014;96:395&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5085258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24973195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takemura M, Kobayashi M, Kimura K, et al. Repeated instruction on inhalation techniques improves adherence to the therapeutic regimen for asthma. J Asthma. 2010;47:202&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20170330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khurana AK, Dubey K, Goyal A, et al. Correcting the inhaler technique decreases the severity of obstruction and improves the quality of life of patients with obstructive airway disease. J Fam Med Prim Care. 2019;8:246&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6396621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30911514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chintalapati N, Daruri VSK. Examining the use of YouTube as a learning resource in higher education: scale development and validation of TAM model. Telemat Inform. 2017;34:853&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed F, Shoufan A. Users&#x2019; experience with health-related content on YouTube: an exploratory study. BMC Public Health. 2024;24:86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38172765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byun U, Jang M, Baek H. The effect of YouTube comment interaction on video engagement: focusing on interactivity centralization and creators&#x2019; interactivity. Online Inf Rev. 2023;47:1083&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allgaier J. Science and medicine on YouTube. In: Second International Handbook of Internet Research. 2020:7&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berk RA. Multimedia teaching with video clips: TV, movies, YouTube, and mtvU in the college classroom. Int J Technol Teach Learn. 2009;5:1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lijo R, Castro JJ, Quevedo E. Comparing educational and dissemination videos in a STEM YouTube channel: a six-year data analysis. Heliyon. 2024;10:e24856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10861978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38352777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison T. How distance education students perceive the impact of teaching videos on their learning. Open Learn. 2020;35:260&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zdemir Zeydanli E, Alkan AA. Era of &#x201c;Dr. YouTube&#x201d;: evaluation of YouTube videos as a valid source for patient education on keratoconus. Eye Contact Lens. 2021;47:526&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34424226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Pandey A, Venkatraman A, Garg N. Are video sharing websites a useful source of information on hypertension? J Am Soc Hypertens. 2014;8:481&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25064770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guthrie GG, Davies RM, Fleming CK, Browning AC. YouTube is a source of information about retinitis pigmentosa. Eye. 2014;28:499&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3983636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24434660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Seo HS, Hong TH. YouTube is a source of patient information on gallstone disease. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:4066&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3983464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24744597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagpal SJ, Karimianpour A, Mukhija D, Mohan D, Brateanu A. YouTube videos as a source of medical information during the Ebola hemorrhagic fever epidemic. SpringerPlus. 2015;4:457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4550615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26322263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae SS, Baxter S. YouTube videos in English as a patient education resource for cataract surgery. Int Ophthalmol. 2018;38:1941&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28849436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou R, Perez-Rosas V, Loeb S, Mihalcea R. Towards automatic detection of misinformation in online medical videos. In: Proceedings of the 2019 International Conference on Multimodal Interaction; 2019:235&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osman W, Mohamed F, Elhassan M, Shoufan A. Is YouTube a reliable source of health-related information? a systematic review. BMC Med Educ. 2022;22:382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9117585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35590410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clifton A, Mann C. Can YouTube enhance student nurse learning? Nurse Educ Today. 2011;31:311&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21036430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendi B. The use of social media in health communication: applications in the world and T&#xfc;rkiye. Marmara Univ Suggest J. 2015;11:275&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo W, Oh SH, Choi DH. Exposure to COVID-19 misinformation across instant messaging apps: moderating roles of news media and interpersonal communication. Int J Commun. 2023;17:712&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes ICF, Siqueira KM, Barbosa MA. Assessment of videos about the inhalation technique for childhood asthma: educational or mediatic? Rev Eletr Enferm. 2018;20:v20a09.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostagiolas PA, Athanasopoulou CA, Niakas D, Sourtzi P. Investigating the information-seeking behavior of patients and families in Greece: a qualitative study. Health Inf Libr J. 2012;29:207&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arikanoglu A, Demir M, Aluclu MU. Analysis of YouTube as a source of information for restless leg syndrome. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2020;78:611&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33111848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozsoy-Unubol T, Alanbay-Yagci E. YouTube is a source of information on fibromyalgia. Int J Rheum Dis. 2021;24:197&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33355406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celik H, Polat O, Ozcan C, Camur S, Kilinc BE, Uzun M. Assessment of the quality and reliability of the information on rotator cuff repair on YouTube. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2020;106:31&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31882329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duran MB, Kizilkan Y. Quality analysis of testicular cancer videos on YouTube. Andrologia. 2021;53:e14118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34009641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary OA, Dhawan J, Sohrabipour S, et al. Assessment of online YouTube videos as a source of information and instruction for pulmonary rehabilitation. Respir Med. 2025;238:107968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39884588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeb S, Sengupta S, Butaney M, et al. Dissemination of misinformative and biased information about prostate cancer on YouTube. Eur Urol. 2019;75:564&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30502104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altun A, Askin A, Sengul I, Aghazada N, Aydin Y. Evaluation of YouTube videos as sources of information about complex regional pain syndrome. Korean J Pain. 2022;35:319&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9251394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bizpinar MO, Olcucuoglu LC. Assessing the quality of YouTube videos as a source of information on mild cognitive impairment. Ann Med Res. 2023;30:1289&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sara&#xe7; Atag&#xfc;n O, Altunta&#x15f; DA, Ustao&#x11f;lu G, Ceylan &#x15e;en S. Evaluating the reliability of YouTube videos about Primary Herpetic Gingivostomatitis. ADO Klinik Bilimler Dergisi. 2024;13:77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>