<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41642902</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1553-7358</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLoS computational biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS Comput Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>FKSUDDAPre: A drug-disease association prediction framework based on F-TEST feature selection and AMDKSU resampling with interpretability analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1013947</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e1013947</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e1013947</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1013947</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In drug discovery and therapeutic research, the prediction of drug-disease associations (DDAs) holds significant scientific and clinical value. Drug molecules exert their effects by precisely identifying disease-related biological targets, systematically modulating the entire pharmacological process from absorption, distribution, and metabolism to final efficacy. Accurate prediction of drug-disease associations not only facilitates an in-depth understanding of molecular mechanisms of drug action but also provides critical theoretical foundations for drug repositioning and personalized medicine. While traditional prediction methods based on in vitro experiments and clinical statistics yield reliable results, they suffer from inherent drawbacks such as long development cycles, substantial resource consumption, and low throughput. In contrast, emerging machine learning techniques offer a promising solution to these bottlenecks, enabling the intelligent and efficient discovery of potential drug-disease association networks and significantly improving drug development efficiency. However, it is noteworthy that existing machine learning methods still face significant challenges in practical applications: the complexity of feature construction raises the threshold for data processing; data sparsity constrains the depth of information mining; and the pervasive issue of sample imbalance poses a severe challenge to the model's predictive accuracy and generalization performance. In this study, we developed an efficient and accurate framework for drug-disease association prediction named FKSUDDAPre. The model employs a multi-modal feature fusion strategy: on one hand, it leverages an ensemble of Mol2vec and K- BERT to deeply capture the semantic features of drug molecular fingerprints; on the other hand, it integrates Medical Subject Headings (MeSH) with DeepWalk to effectively reduce the dimensionality of disease features while preserving their relational structure. To address the class imbalance problem, FKSUDDAPre designed an optimization algorithm called AMDKSU, which combined clustering with an improved distance metric strategy, significantly enhancing the discriminative power of the sample set. For data processing, F-test was employed for feature importance ranking, effectively reducing data dimensionality and improving model generalization. For the predictive architecture, FKSUDDAPre proposed a novel ensemble framework composed of XGBoost, Decision Tree, Random Forest, and HyperFast. By employing a dynamic weight allocation strategy, this ensemble effectively harnesses the complementary strengths of these models to achieve significantly enhanced predictive performance. Rigorous validation demonstrated the system's outstanding performance across multiple evaluation metrics, with an average AUC of 0.9725, improving the AUC by approximately 3.88% compared to the best-performing baseline model. In the prediction of Alzheimer's disease and Parkinson's disease, 80% and 60% of the top 10 candidate drugs recommended by FKSUDDAPre, respectively, had been confirmed by literature, demonstrating the model's good practical application potential. Furthermore, we conducted a LIME-based feature importance analysis on the model's predictions, visualizing the correlations between features and the target variable to demonstrate the model's interpretability. A cross-platform, user-friendly visualization tool had also been developed using the PyQt5 framework.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Zuo et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-4021-3836</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science, Jiangnan University and Engineering Research Center of Intelligent Technology for Healthcare, Ministry of Education, Wuxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chenyi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-9691-5948</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science, Jiangnan University and Engineering Research Center of Intelligent Technology for Healthcare, Ministry of Education, Wuxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hua</LastName><ForeName>Ge</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science, Jiangnan University and Engineering Research Center of Intelligent Technology for Healthcare, Ministry of Education, Wuxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ning</LastName><ForeName>Qiao</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science, Jiangnan University and Engineering Research Center of Intelligent Technology for Healthcare, Ministry of Education, Wuxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiangrong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Technology, National Institute for Data Science in Health and Medicine, Xiamen Key Laboratory of Intelligent Storage and Computing, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Xiangxiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Information Science and Engineering, Hunan University, Yuelu District, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Zhaohong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science, Jiangnan University and Engineering Research Center of Intelligent Technology for Healthcare, Ministry of Education, Wuxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS Comput Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101238922</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1553-734X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019295" MajorTopicYN="Y">Computational Biology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055808" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Discovery</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058492" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Repositioning</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057225" MajorTopicYN="N">Data Mining</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057285" MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41642902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12900433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1013947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PCOMPBIOL-D-25-01644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Campillos M, Kuhn M, Gavin A-C, Jensen LJ, Bork P. Drug target identification using side-effect similarity. Science. 2008;321(5886):263&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1126/science.1158140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1158140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18621671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohapatra M, Sahu C, Mohapatra S. Trends of artificial intelligence (AI) use in drug targets, discovery and development: current status and future perspectives. Curr Drug Targets. 2025;26(4):221&#x2013;42. doi: 10.2174/0113894501322734241008163304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0113894501322734241008163304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39473198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel B, Gelat B, Soni M, Rathaur P. Bioinformatics perspective of drug repurposing. CBIO. 2024;19(4):295&#x2013;315. doi: 10.2174/0115748936264692230921071504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0115748936264692230921071504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z, Zeng X, Lao Y, Zheng H, You Z, Xiang H, et al. A spatial hierarchical network learning framework for drug repositioning allowing interpretation from macro to micro scale. Commun Biol. 2024;7(1):1413. doi: 10.1038/s42003-024-07107-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42003-024-07107-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11525566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39478146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai C, Yang H, Liu X, Dong R, Ding Y, Guo F. MTMol-GPT: de novo multi-target molecular generation with transformer-based generative adversarial imitation learning. PLoS Comput Biol. 2024;20(6):e1012229. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11233020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38924082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng X, Zhu S, Liu X, Zhou Y, Nussinov R, Cheng F. deepDR: a network-based deep learning approach to in silico drug repositioning. Bioinformatics. 2019;35(24):5191&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1093/bioinformatics/btz418</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btz418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31116390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei L, Liao M, Gao Y, Ji R, He Z, Zou Q. Improved and promising identification of human microRNAs by incorporating a high-quality negative set. IEEE/ACM Trans Comput Biol Bioinform. 2014;11(1):192&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1109/TCBB.2013.146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCBB.2013.146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26355518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian J, Han L, Chen M, Xu Y, Chen Z, Zhu T, et al. MFGCN: multi-faceted spatial and temporal specific graph convolutional network for traffic-flow forecasting. Knowl Based Syst. 2024;306:112671. doi: 10.1016/j.knosys.2024.112671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2024.112671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Li C, Chen R, Cao D, Zeng X. Geometric deep learning for drug discovery. Expert Syst Appl. 2024;240:122498. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122498</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlman L, Gottlieb A, Atias N, Ruppin E, Sharan R. Combining drug and gene similarity measures for drug-target elucidation. J Comput Biol. 2011;18(2):133&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1089/cmb.2010.0213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cmb.2010.0213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21314453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z, Zeng X, Lao Y, You Z, Shang Y, Zou Q, et al. Predicting rare drug-drug interaction events with dual-granular structure-adaptive and pair variational representation. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):3997. doi: 10.1038/s41467-025-59431-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-59431-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12041321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40301328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Chen S, Deng N, Wang Y. Drug repositioning by kernel-based integration of molecular structure, molecular activity, and phenotype data. PLoS One. 2013;8(11):e78518. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0078518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0078518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3823875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24244318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar Meher P, Hati S, Sahu TK, Pradhan U, Gupta A, Rath SN. SVM-Root: identification of root-associated proteins in plants by employing the support vector machine with sequence-derived features. CBIO. 2024;19(1):91&#x2013;102. doi: 10.2174/1574893618666230417104543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1574893618666230417104543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Zhai Y, Ding Y, Zou Q. SBSM-Pro: support bio-sequence machine for proteins. Sci China Inf Sci. 2024;67(11):212106. doi: 10.1007/s11432-024-4171-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11432-024-4171-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh M, Ahn J, Yoon Y. A network-based classification model for deriving novel drug-disease associations and assessing their molecular actions. PLoS One. 2014;9(10):e111668. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0111668</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0111668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4214731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25356910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Luo H, Li Y, Wu F-X, Wang J. Overlap matrix completion for predicting drug-associated indications. PLoS Comput Biol. 2019;15(12):e1007541. doi: 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007541</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1007541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6946175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31869322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Ding Y, Tang J, Guo F. Drug&#x2013;disease associations prediction via multiple kernel-based dual graph regularized least squares. Appl Soft Comput. 2021;112:107811. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2021.107811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2021.107811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F, Qiu Y, Li Q, Liu S, Ni F. Predicting drug-disease associations via multi-task learning based on collective matrix factorization. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2020;8:218. doi: 10.3389/fbioe.2020.00218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2020.00218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32373595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H-J, Huang Y-A, You Z-H. SAEROF: an ensemble approach for large-scale drug-disease association prediction by incorporating rotation forest and sparse autoencoder deep neural network. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):4972. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-61616-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-61616-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7080766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathivanan JS, Dhayabaran VV, David MR, Karuna Nidhi MB, Prasath KM, Suvaithenamudhan S. Application of deep learning neural networks in computer-aided drug discovery: a review. CBIO. 2024;19(9):851&#x2013;8. doi: 10.2174/0115748936276510231123121404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0115748936276510231123121404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao J, Jin J, Wang D, Teng S, Zhang J, Yang X, et al. A self-conformation-aware pre-training framework for molecular property prediction with substructure interpretability. Nat Commun. 2025;16(1):4382. doi: 10.1038/s41467-025-59634-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-59634-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12069555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40355450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi R, Liu S, Hui X, Shaytan AK, Liu B. AI in drug development: advances in response, combination therapy, repositioning, and molecular design. Sci China Inf Sci. 2025;68(7). doi: 10.1007/s11432-024-4461-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11432-024-4461-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Wei H, Zhang W, Wu H, Liu B. Multiple types of disease-associated RNAs identification for disease prognosis and therapy using heterogeneous graph learning. Sci China Inf Sci. 2024;67(8). doi: 10.1007/s11432-024-4100-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11432-024-4100-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Pang Y, Liu B. BioSeq-BLM: a platform for analyzing DNA, RNA, and protein sequences based on biological language models. Nucleic Acids Res. 2021;49:e129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8682797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34581805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao W, Lin X, Liu Y, Zeng L, Ma T, Cheng N, et al. Bridging chemical structure and conceptual knowledge enables accurate prediction of compound-protein interaction. BMC Biol. 2024;22(1):248. doi: 10.1186/s12915-024-02049-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12915-024-02049-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11520867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39468510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xuan P, Gao L, Sheng N, Zhang T, Nakaguchi T. Graph convolutional autoencoder and fully-connected autoencoder with attention mechanism based method for predicting drug-disease associations. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2021;25(5):1793&#x2013;804. doi: 10.1109/JBHI.2020.3039502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2020.3039502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33216722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Zhao S, Zhao J, Feng Z. A model for predicting drug-disease associations based on dense convolutional attention network. Math Biosci Eng. 2021;18(6):7419&#x2013;39. doi: 10.3934/mbe.2021367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3934/mbe.2021367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34814256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B-W, Hu L, You Z-H, Wang L, Su X-R. HINGRL: predicting drug-disease associations with graph representation learning on heterogeneous information networks. Brief Bioinform. 2022;23(1):bbab515. doi: 10.1093/bib/bbab515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbab515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34891172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Ma H, Zhang X, Wang Y, Wu Z. Similarity measures-based graph co-contrastive learning for drug-disease association prediction. Bioinformatics. 2023;39(6):btad357. doi: 10.1093/bioinformatics/btad357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btad357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10275904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37261859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Guan S, Zou Q, Wu H, Tiwari P, Ding Y. AMDGT: Attention aware multi-modal fusion using a dual graph transformer for drug&#x2013;disease associations prediction. Knowl Based Syst. 2024;284:111329. doi: 10.1016/j.knosys.2023.111329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2023.111329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He S, Yun L, Yi H. Fusing graph transformer with multi-aggregate GCN for enhanced drug-disease associations prediction. BMC Bioinform. 2024;25(1):79. doi: 10.1186/s12859-024-05705-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12859-024-05705-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10877759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38378479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Hu P, Li D, Zhao B, Niu Z, Herget T, et al. Interpretable identification of cancer genes across biological networks via transformer-powered graph representation learning. Nat Biomed Eng. 2025;9(3):371&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1038/s41551-024-01312-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41551-024-01312-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39789329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Yang Y, Cui Z, Yin H, Hu P, Hu L. LLM-DDI: leveraging large language models for drug-drug interaction prediction on biomedical knowledge graph. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2026;30(1):773&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1109/JBHI.2025.3585290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2025.3585290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40601466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X, Miao R, Zhang S, Jia S, Zhang L, Liang Y, et al. SMPR: a structure-enhanced multimodal drug&#x2012;disease prediction model for drug repositioning and cold start. J Cheminform. 2025;17(1):155. doi: 10.1186/s13321-025-01085-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13321-025-01085-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12519732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41088417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang C, Qiao J, Zeng X, Zou Q, Wei L. Deep generative models in de novo drug molecule generation. J Chem Inf Model. 2024;64(7):2174&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.3c01496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37934070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis AP, Grondin CJ, Johnson RJ, Sciaky D, King BL, McMorran R. The comparative toxicogenomics database: update 2017. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;45:D972&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5210612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27651457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law V, Knox C, Djoumbou Y, Jewison T, Guo AC, Liu Y, et al. DrugBank 4.0: shedding new light on drug metabolism. Nucleic Acids Res. 2014;42(Database issue):D1091-7. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkt1068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkt1068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3965102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24203711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipscomb CE. Medical Subject Headings (MeSH). Bull Med Libr Assoc. 2000;88(3):265&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC35238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10928714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Yue X, Lin W, Wu W, Liu R, Huang F, et al. Predicting drug-disease associations by using similarity constrained matrix factorization. BMC Bioinform. 2018;19(1):233. doi: 10.1186/s12859-018-2220-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12859-018-2220-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6006580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29914348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Gao D, Xie X, Qin J, Li J, Lin H, et al. DeepIDC: a prediction framework of injectable drug combination based on heterogeneous information and deep learning. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2022;61(12):1749&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1007/s40262-022-01180-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40262-022-01180-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaeger S, Fulle S, Turk S. Mol2vec: unsupervised machine learning approach with chemical intuition. J Chem Inf Model. 2018;58(1):27&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1021/acs.jcim.7b00616</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.7b00616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29268609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, Jiang D, Wang J, Zhang X, Du H, Pan L, et al. Knowledge-based BERT: a method to extract molecular features like computational chemists. Brief Bioinform. 2022;23(3):bbac131. doi: 10.1093/bib/bbac131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbac131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35438145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z-H, You Z-H, Huang D-S, Yi H-C, Zheng K, Chen Z-H, et al. MeSHHeading2vec: a new method for representing MeSH headings as vectors based on graph embedding algorithm. Brief Bioinform. 2021;22(2):2085&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1093/bib/bbaa037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbaa037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7986599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32232320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou X, Ren L, Cai P, Zhang Y, Ding H, Deng K, et al. Accurately identifying hemagglutinin using sequence information and machine learning methods. Front Med (Lausanne). 2023;10:1281880. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2023.1281880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2023.1281880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10644030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38020152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David B, Daniel MM, Xavier GN, Alexander GI. HyperFast: instant classification for tabular data. Proceedings of the Thirty-Eighth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Washington (DC): AAAI Press; 2024. 1240 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dao F, Lebeau B, Ling CCY, Yang M, Xie X, Fullwood MJ, et al. RepliChrom: interpretable machine learning predicts cancer-associated enhancer-promoter interactions using DNA replication timing. iMeta. 2025;4(4):e70052. doi: 10.1002/imt2.70052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/imt2.70052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12371266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40860444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie H, Wang L, Qian Y, Ding Y, Guo F. Methyl-GP: accurate generic DNA methylation prediction based on a language model and representation learning. Nucleic Acids Res. 2025;53(6):gkaf223. doi: 10.1093/nar/gkaf223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkaf223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11952970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40156859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H, Hao H, Yu L. Identification of microbe-disease signed associations via multi-scale variational graph autoencoder based on signed message propagation. BMC Biol. 2024;22(1):172. doi: 10.1186/s12915-024-01968-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12915-024-01968-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11328394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39148051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Guo X, Qin J, Gao L, Ju F, Zhao C, et al. Accurate RNA velocity estimation based on multibatch network reveals complex lineage in batch scRNA-seq data. BMC Biol. 2024;22(1):290. doi: 10.1186/s12915-024-02085-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12915-024-02085-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11657662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39696422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Huang Z, Ju F, Zhao C, Yu L. Highly accurate estimation of cell type abundance in bulk tissues based on single-cell reference and domain adaptive matching. Adv Sci (Weinh). 2024;11(7):e2306329. doi: 10.1002/advs.202306329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202306329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10870031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38072669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H-Q, Arif M, Thafar MA, Albaradei S, Cai P, Zhang Y, et al. PMPred-AE: a computational model for the detection and interpretation of pathological myopia based on artificial intelligence. Front Med (Lausanne). 2025;12:1529335. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2025.1529335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1529335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11965940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40182849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S, Wang M, Zheng X, Chen J, Tang C. Hierarchical and dynamic graph attention network for drug-disease association prediction. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2024;28:2416&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1109/JBHI.2024.3363080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2024.3363080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38319783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Liu J-X, Wang J, Shang J, Gao Y-L. A graph representation approach based on light gradient boosting machine for predicting drug-disease associations. J Comput Biol. 2023;30(8):937&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1089/cmb.2023.0078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cmb.2023.0078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37486669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro MT, Singh S, Guestrin C. &#x201c;Why should i trust you?&#x201d;: Explaining the predictions of any classifier. Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining. New York: ACM; 2016. p. 1135&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>