<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41888441</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2948-2933</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of imaging informatics in medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Imaging Inform Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>GHMS-CycleGAN: Graph-Based Hierarchical Multi-stain CycleGAN for Stain Normalization and Classification in Digital Pathology.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10278-026-01854-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The emergence of digital pathology (DP) has provided numerous computer-aided diagnosis (CAD) opportunities and tools based primarily on deep learning (DL) approaches. However, staining variations and distortions caused by DP scanners during image digitization pose challenges and cause performance degradation in DL-based CAD systems. In this work, we introduce novel methods of stain and scan normalization for histopathology, red blood cell (RBC), and white blood cell (WBC) image classification. In particular, we propose a novel framework for multi-stain and color normalization using hierarchical multi-stain cycle-consistent generative adversarial networks (HMS-CycleGAN) and graph-based HMS-CycleGAN (GHMS-CycleGAN). Our method effectively learns image normalization mappings by exploiting underlying hierarchical and network structures in DP images. The proposed framework was validated on histopathology, RBC, and WBC image datasets collected from different scanners and institutions to assess the impact of the proposed CycleGAN-based normalization methods on the downstream task of image classification. The results show that the HMS-CycleGAN normalizer can generate significantly more robust and consistent normalization across diverse staining variations compared to state-of-the-art methods. Also, our normalization methods consistently lead to superior classification performance compared to classifiers trained without image normalization and those using three state-of-the-art methods. HMS-CycleGAN achieved the best classification accuracy (84.05%) on the Wilds Camelyon dataset and the best F1-score for WBC classification (51.06%), while both HMS-CycleGAN and GHMS-CycleGAN excelled in cross-scanner RBC image classification, reaching F1-scores between 80 and 91%. The experimental results highlight the importance of image normalization in building robust and generalizable DL-based models for improved downstream image classification in DP.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s) under exclusive licence to Society for Imaging Informatics in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elmanna</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4469-0077</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering and Systems, Faculty of Engineering, Cairo University, Cairo University St, Giza, 12613, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elsafty</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7067-4962</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PathOlOgics, LLC for Validated Automated Analytical and Post-Analytical Pathology Services, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Yomna</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-5843-0446</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PathOlOgics, LLC for Validated Automated Analytical and Post-Analytical Pathology Services, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rushdi</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9869-0270</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering and Systems, Faculty of Engineering, Cairo University, Cairo University St, Giza, 12613, Egypt. mrushdi@eng1.cu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Information Technology, New Giza University, Giza, 12256, Egypt. mrushdi@eng1.cu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morsy</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0198-2937</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering and Systems, Faculty of Engineering, Cairo University, Cairo University St, Giza, 12613, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Imaging Inform Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918663679206676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2948-2925</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood cell classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CycleGAN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital pathology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Graph-based cycle loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hierarchical cycle loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stain normalization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing Interests: The second and third authors (A.E. &amp; Y.A.) are cofounders of PathOlOgics, a limited-liability company for automated AI-powered analytical and post-analytical pathology processes. The other authors have no relevant financial or non-financial interests to disclose. Use of Generative AI: During the preparation of this work, the first author (M.E.) used ChatGPT-3.5 (GPT-3.5 OpenAI&#x2019;s large-scale language-generation model) to assist in language and grammar checks and refine the manuscript&#x2019;s readability. After using the tool, the authors reviewed and edited the manuscript and took full responsibility for the content of the publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41888441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-026-01854-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10278-026-01854-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Salvi M, Molinari F, Acharya UR, Molinaro L, Meiburger KM: Impact of stain normalization and patch selection on the performance of convolutional neural networks in histological breast and prostate cancer classification. Comput&#xa0;Methods Programs&#xa0;Biomed&#xa0;Update, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpbup.2021.100004 , February 20, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpbup.2021.100004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das A, Nair MS, Peter SD: Computer-aided histopathological image analysis techniques for automated nuclear atypia scoring of breast cancer: a review. J Digit&#xa0;Imaging, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10278-019-00295-z , January 27, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-019-00295-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7573034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michielli N, Caputo A, Scotto M, Mogetta A, Pennisi OA, Molinari F, Balmativola D, Bosco M, Gambella A, Metovic J, Tota D: Stain normalization in digital pathology: Clinical multi-center evaluation of image quality. J Pathol Inform, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpi.2022.100145 , September 30, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpi.2022.100145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36268060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9577129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziaei D, Li W, Lam S, Cheng WC, Chen W: Characterization of color normalization methods in digital pathology whole slide images. Medical Imaging 2020: Digital Pathology, https://doi.org/10.1117/12.2550585 , March 16, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvi M, Branciforti F, Molinari F, Meiburger KM: Generative models for color normalization in digital pathology and dermatology: Advancing the learning paradigm. Expert&#xa0;Syst Appl, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2023.123105 , January 6, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.123105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakasi R, Mwebaze E, Zawedde A: Mobile-aware deep learning algorithms for malaria parasites and white blood cells localization in thick blood smears. Algorithms, https://doi.org/10.3390/a14010017 , January11, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/a14010017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Ruberto C, Loddo A, Putzu L: A region proposal approach for cells detection and counting from microscopic blood images. Proc Int Conf Image Anal Process, https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-30645-8_5 , September 02, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z, Liu X, Yan Z, Gu W, Jiang J: Improved detection performance in blood cell count by an attention-guided deep learning method. OSA Continuum, https://doi.org/10.1364/OSAC.413787 , January 25, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1364/OSAC.413787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobara YM, Akpan IJ, Nam AD, AlMukthar FH, Peter M: Artificial Intelligence and Data Science Methods for Automatic Detection of White Blood Cells in Images. J&#xa0;Imaging&#xa0;Inform Med, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10278-025-01538-y , May 16, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-025-01538-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40379861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12920980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran T, Kwon OH, Kwon KR, Lee SH, Kang KW: Blood cell images segmentation using deep learning semantic segmentation. IEEE international conference on electronics and communication engineering (ICECE), https://doi.org/10.1109/ICECOME.2018.8644754 , February 21, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICECOME.2018.8644754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadafi A, Radolko M, Serafeimidis I, Hadlak S: Red blood cells segmentation: a fully convolutional network approach. IEEE Intl Conf on Parallel &amp; Distributed Processing with Applications, Ubiquitous Computing &amp; Communications, Big Data &amp; Cloud Computing, Social Computing &amp; Networking, Sustainable Computing &amp; Communications, https://doi.org/10.1109/BDCloud.2018.00134 , March 21, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Li X, Xu M, Li Q: RBC semantic segmentation for sickle cell disease based on deformable U-Net. MICCAI 2018, https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-00937-3_79 , September 13, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowal M, &#x17b;ejmo M, Skobel M, Korbicz J, Monczak R: Cell nuclei segmentation in cytological images using convolutional neural network and seeded watershed algorithm. J Digit&#xa0;Imaging, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10278-019-00200-8 , June 03, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-019-00200-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naruenatthanaset K, Chalidabhongse TH, Palasuwan D, Anantrasirichai N, Palasuwan A: Red blood cell segmentation with overlapping cell separation and classification on imbalanced dataset. arXiv preprint arXiv, https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2012.01321 , Dec 2, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyas DA, Hartati S, Harjoko A, Ratnaningsih T: Morphological, texture, and color feature analysis for erythrocyte classification in thalassemia cases. IEEE access, https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2983155 , March 25, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2983155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M, Papageorgiou DP, Abidi SZ, Dao M, Zhao H, Karniadakis GE: A deep convolutional neural network for classification of red blood cells in sickle cell anemia. PLoS&#xa0;Comput Biol, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005746 , October 19, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29084212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5679653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzubaidi L, Fadhel MA, Al-Shamma O, Zhang J, Duan Y: Deep learning models for classification of red blood cells in microscopy images to aid in sickle cell anemia diagnosis. Electronics, https://doi.org/10.3390/electronics9030427 , March 4, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics9030427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almahdawi H, Akbas A, Rahebi J: Deep learning neural network based on PSO for leukemia cell disease diagnosis from microscope images. J&#xa0;Imaging&#xa0;Inform Med, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10278-025-01474-x , March 20, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10278-025-01474-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40113730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12701137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou K, Liu Z, Qiao Y, Xiang T, Loy CC: Domain generalization: A survey. IEEE&#xa0;Trans&#xa0;Pattern&#xa0;Anal Mach Intell, https://doi.org/10.1109/TPAMI.2022.3195549 , August 01, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2022.3195549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35196226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8828679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Lan C, Liu C, Ouyang Y, Qin T, Lu W, Chen Y, Zeng W, Yu PS: Generalizing to unseen domains: A survey on domain generalization. IEEE&#xa0;Trans Knowl&#xa0;Data&#xa0;Eng, https://doi.org/10.1109/TKDE.2022.3178128 , May 26, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TKDE.2022.3178128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macenko M, Niethammer M, Marron JS, Borland D, Woosley JT, Guan X, Schmitt C, Thomas NE: A method for normalizing histology slides for quantitative analysis. Proc&#xa0;IEEE&#xa0;Int Symp Biomed&#xa0;Imaging, https://doi.org/10.1109/ISBI.2009.5193250 , August 07, 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ISBI.2009.5193250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vahadane A, Peng T, Sethi A, Albarqouni S, Wang L, Baust M, Steiger K, Schlitter AM, Esposito I, Navab N: Structure-preserving color normalization and sparse stain separation for histological images. IEEE&#xa0;Trans Med&#xa0;Imaging, https://doi.org/10.1109/TMI.2016.2529665 , April 27, 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMI.2016.2529665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27164577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kablan EB, Ayas S: StainSWIN: Vision transformer-based stain normalization for histopathology image analysis. Eng Appl Artif Intell, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.engappai.2024.108136 , March 2, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2024.108136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jewsbury R, Wang R, Bhalerao A, Rajpoot N, Vu QD: StainFuser: Controlling diffusion for faster neural style transfer in multi-gigapixel histology images. arXiv preprint, https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2403.09302 , Mar 14, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez P&#xe9;rez JC, Otero Baguer D, Maass P: StainCUT: stain normalization with contrastive learning. J Imaging, https://doi.org/10.3390/jimaging8070202 , July 20, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging8070202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35877646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9317097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H, Luo D, Feng W, Zeng S, Quan T, Hu J, Liu X: Stainnet: a fast and robust stain normalization network. Front Med, https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2021.746307 , November 05, 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.746307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoque MZ, Keskinarkaus A, Nyberg P, Sepp&#xe4;nen T: Stain normalization methods for histopathology image analysis: A comprehensive review and experimental comparison. Inform Fusion, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inffus.2023.101997 , September 20, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2023.101997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrera K, Rodellar J, Alferez S, Merino A: Automatic normalized digital color staining in the recognition of abnormal blood cells using generative adversarial networks. Comput&#xa0;Methods Programs&#xa0;Biomed, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb.2023.107629 , June 8, 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2023.107629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37301181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner SJ, Khalili N, Sharma R, Boxberg M, Marr C, De Back W, Peng T: Structure-preserving multi-domain stain color augmentation using style-transfer with disentangled representations. MICCAI 2021, https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-87237-3_25 , September 21, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hetz MJ, Bucher TC, Brinker TJ: Multi-domain stain normalization for digital pathology: A cycle-consistent adversarial network for whole slide images. Med&#xa0;Image&#xa0;Anal, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.media.2024.103149 , April 3, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2024.103149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38574542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doerrich S, Di Salvo F, Ledig C: Self-supervised Vision Transformer are Scalable Generative Models for Domain Generalization. MICCAI 2024, https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-72117-5_60 , October 3, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roux L: Detection of mitosis and evaluation of nuclear atypia score in breast cancer histological images. ICPR 2014, https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:43730491 , 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh PW, Sagawa S, Marklund H, Xie SM, Zhang M, Balsubramani A, Hu W, Yasunaga M, Phillips RL, Gao I, Lee T: Wilds: A benchmark of in-the-wild distribution shifts, ICML 2021, https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2012.07421 , 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litjens G, Bandi P, Ehteshami Bejnordi B, Geessink O, Balkenhol M, Bult P, Halilovic A, Hermsen M, Van de Loo R, Vogels R, Manson QF: 1399 H&amp;E-stained sentinel lymph node sections of breast cancer patients: the CAMELYON dataset. GigaScience, https://doi.org/10.1093/gigascience/giy065 , May 31, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gigascience/giy065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29860392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6007545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubreville M, Stathonikos N, Bertram CA, Klopfleisch R, Ter Hoeve N, Ciompi F, Wilm F, Marzahl C, Donovan TA, Maier A, Breen J: Mitosis domain generalization in histopathology images&#x2014;the MIDOG challenge. Med&#xa0;Image&#xa0;Anal, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.media.2022.102699 , December 1, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.media.2022.102699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36463832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyas DA, Ratnaningsih T, Harjoko A, Hartati S: Erythrocyte (red blood cell) dataset in thalassemia case. Data Brief, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dib.2022.107886 , February 14, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dib.2022.107886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35242901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8857444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Hidalgo M, Guerrero-Pena FA, Herold-Garc&#xed;a S, Jaume-i-Cap&#xf3; A, Marrero-Fern&#xe1;ndez PD: Red blood cell cluster separation from digital images for use in sickle cell disease. IEEE&#xa0;J Biomed&#xa0;Health&#xa0;Inform, https://doi.org/10.1109/JBHI.2014.2356402 , September 08, 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JBHI.2014.2356402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25216490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsafty A, Soliman A, Ahmed Y: 1 Million Segmented Red Blood Cells With 240 K Classified in 9 Shapes and 47 K Patches of 25 Manual Blood Smears. Sci&#xa0;Data, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-024-03570-z , July 02, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-024-03570-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38956115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11220077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achanta R, Shaji A, Smith K, Lucchi A, Fua P, S&#xfc;sstrunk S: SLIC superpixels compared to state-of-the-art superpixel methods. IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell, https://doi.org/10.1109/TPAMI.2012.120 , May 29, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acevedo A, Merino A, Alf&#xe9;rez S, Molina &#xc1;, Bold&#xfa; L, Rodellar J: A dataset of microscopic peripheral blood cell images for development of automatic recognition systems. Data Brief, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dib.2020.105474 , April 22, 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dib.2020.105474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32490099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7262404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kouzehkanan ZM, Saghari S, Tavakoli S, Rostami P, Abaszadeh M, Mirzadeh F, Satlsar ES, Gheidishahran M, Gorgi F, Mohammadi S, Hosseini R: A large dataset of white blood cells containing cell locations and types, along with segmented nuclei and cytoplasm. Sci Rep, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-04426-x , January 21, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-04426-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35064165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8782871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matek C, Schwarz S, Spiekermann K, Marr C: Human-level recognition of blast cells in acute myeloid leukaemia with convolutional neural networks. Nat Mach Intell, https://doi.org/10.1038/s42256-019-0101-9 , November 12, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42256-019-0101-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronneberger O, Fischer P, Brox T: U-net: Convolutional networks for biomedical image segmentation. MICCAI 2015, https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-24574-4_28 , November 18, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M, Le Q: Efficientnet: Rethinking model scaling for convolutional neural networks. ICML 2019, https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1905.11946 , May 28, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z: Image quality assessment: Form error visibility to structural similarity. IEEE Trans Image Process, https://doi.org/10.1109/TIP.2003.819861 , April 30, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2003.819861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15648865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi P, Chalechale A: Pix2pix-based stain-to-stain translation: A solution for robust stain normalization in histopathology images analysis. arXiv preprint arXiv, https://doi.org/10.1109/MVIP49855.2020.9116895 , June 15, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Isola P, Efros AA, Shechtman E, Wang O: The unreasonable effectiveness of deep features as a perceptual metric. CVPR 2018, https://doi.org/10.1109/CVPR.2018.00068 , December 16, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heusel M, Ramsauer H, Unterthiner T, Nessler B, Hochreiter S: GANs trained by a two time-scale update rule converge to a local nash equilibrium. Adv&#xa0;Neural&#xa0;Inf Process Syst, https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1706.08500 , December 04, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1706.08500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi&#x144;kowski M, Sutherland DJ, Arbel M, Gretton A: Demystifying MMD GANs. arXiv preprint arXiv, https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.1801.01401 , January 4, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1801.01401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Qasmieh I: Novel and efficient approach for automated separation, segmentation, and detection of overlapped elliptical red blood cells. Pattern Recognit Image Anal, https://doi.org/10.1134/S1054661818040156 , December 06, 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S1054661818040156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi J, Liu X, Cheng S, Chen L, Zeng S: Multi-scale window transformer for cervical cytopathology image recognition. Comput Struct Biotechnol J, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csbj.2024.04.028 , April 15, 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csbj.2024.04.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39108678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11301231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Wu P, Zhao Z, Yu H: ILViT: An Inception-Linear Attention-Based Lightweight Vision Transformer for Microscopic Cell Classification. J&#xa0;Imaging, https://doi.org/10.3390/jimaging11070219 , July 1, 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging11070219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41590900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12843401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>