<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41705361</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Artificial intelligence in orthopaedics: Enhanced examinations, ambient intelligence and the future of clinical practice.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70339</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Artificial intelligence (AI) continues to rapidly transform the practice of medicine, with clinicians increasingly adopting data-driven decision-making aids and diagnostic support tools. Orthopaedic physicians are well poised to harness the capabilities of AI, with an abundance of quantifiable imaging, biomechanical data, and structured clinical parameters lending themselves to algorithmic interpretation and automation. Namely, AI-augmented vision systems may increase the breadth of information readily available to clinicians, whereas smart exam rooms and automated clinical summaries may soon streamline clinical workflows to decrease administrative burden and allow more time for direct patient care. Personalised education materials and visual aids may improve patient understanding and compliance, with the aim of optimising patient outcomes. Generative medical and orthopaedic event models may soon alter decision-making heuristics and improve patient counselling. While the widespread adaptation of AI into clinical practices is not without limitations, physicians will likely come to share an increasingly symbiotic relationship with these platforms throughout their continued evolution. Accordingly, it is imperative that current and future orthopaedic practitioners become well-versed in harnessing the capabilities of AI and continue to identify new avenues for such technologies to benefit clinicians and patients alike. As such, the current manuscript provides a narrative review of the potential future applications of AI within orthopaedic practices by exploring current and developing technologies and detailing how the continued integration of AI-powered systems may serve to revolutionise the delivery of orthopaedic care. LEVEL OF EVIDENCE: Level V.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouterse</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5068-6635</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Tripler Army Medical Center, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pruneski</LastName><ForeName>James A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Tripler Army Medical Center, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oettl</LastName><ForeName>Felix C</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Balgrist University Hospital, University of Z&#xfc;rich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zsidai</LastName><ForeName>Balint</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Institute of Clinical Sciences, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Sk&#xe5;ne University Hospital, Malm&#xf6;/Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tischer</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Universitymedicine Rostock, Rostock, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic and Trauma Surgery, Malteser Waldkrankenhaus Erlangen, Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Longo</LastName><ForeName>Umile Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>UG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4063-9821</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Campus Bio-Medico, Via Alvaro del Portillo, 200, Roma, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit of Orthopaedic and Trauma Surgery, Department of Medicine and Surgery, Universit&#xe0; Campus Bio-Medico di Roma, Via Alvaro del Portillo, 21, Roma, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seil</LastName><ForeName>Romain</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Centre Hospitalier de Luxembourg, Luxembourg City, Luxembourg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirschmann</LastName><ForeName>Michael T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kantonsspital Baselland, University Department of Orthopaedic Surgery and Traumatology, Bruderholz, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Samuelsson</LastName><ForeName>Kristian</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5383-3370</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sahlgrenska Sports Medicine Center, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Institute of Clinical Sciences, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Orthopaedics, Sahlgrenska University Hospital, M&#xf6;lndal, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">orthopaedics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41705361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abramoff MD, Roehrenbeck C, Trujillo S, Goldstein J, Graves AS, Repka MX, et al. A reimbursement framework for artificial intelligence in healthcare. NPJ Digit Med. 2022;5:72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albrecht M, Shanks D, Shah T, Hudson T, Thompson J, Filardi T,et al. Enhancing clinical documentation with ambient artificial intelligence: a quality improvement survey assessing clinician perspectives on work burden, burnout, and job satisfaction. JAMIA Open. 2025;8:ooaf013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arndt BG, Beasley JW, Watkinson MD, Temte JL, Tuan WJ, Sinsky CA,et al. Tethered to the EHR: primary care physician workload assessment using EHR event log data and time&#x2010;motion observations. Ann Fam Med. 2017;15:419&#x2013;426.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Medical Association. AMA Augmented Intelligence Research&#x2013;Physician Sentiments Around the Use of AI in Health Care: Motivations, Opportunities, Risks, and Use Cases&#x2010;Shifts from 2023 to 2024. American Medical Association; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubert K, Germaneau A, Rochette M, Ye W, Severyns M, Billot M,et al. Development of digital twins to optimize trauma surgery and postoperative management. a case study focusing on tibial plateau fracture. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2021;9:722275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azurmendi I, Gonzalez M, Garc&#xed;a G, Zulueta E, Mart&#xed;n E. Deep learning&#x2010;based postural asymmetry detection through pressure mat. Applied Sciences. 2024;14:12050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balloch J, Sridharan S, Oldham G, Wray J, Gough P, Robinson R,et al. Corrigendum to &#x2018;Use of an ambient artificial intelligence tool to improve quality of clinical documentation&#x2019; Future Healthcare Journal Volume 11, Issue 3, September 2024, 100157. Fut Healthcare J. 2025;12:100247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann LA, Baker J, Elshaug AG. The impact of electronic health record systems on clinical documentation times: a systematic review. Health Policy. 2018;122:827&#x2013;836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhouet J, Samargandi R. Emerging innovations in preoperative planning and motion analysis in orthopedic surgery. Diagnostics. 2024;14:1321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottomley D, Thaldar D. Liability for harm caused by AI in healthcare: an overview of the core legal concepts. Front Pharmacol. 2023;14:1297353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozic KJ, Chenok KE, Schindel J, Chan V, Huddleston JI, Braddock C, et al. Patient, surgeon, and healthcare purchaser views on the use of decision and communication aids in orthopaedic surgery: a mixed methods study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2014;14:366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan M, Puri S, Ozrazgat&#x2010;Baslanti T, Feng Z, Ruppert M, Hashemighouchani H,et al. Comparing clinical judgment with the MySurgeryRisk algorithm for preoperative risk assessment: a pilot usability study. Surgery. 2019;165:1035&#x2013;1045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budd J. Burnout related to electronic health record use in primary care. J Primary Care Commun Health. 2023;14:21501319231166921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casari FA, Navab N, Hruby LA, Kriechling P, Nakamura R, Tori R,et al. Augmented reality in orthopedic surgery is emerging from proof of concept towards clinical studies: a literature review explaining the technology and current state of the art. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2021;14:192&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celi LA, Cellini J, Charpignon ML, Dee EC, Dernoncourt F, Eber R,et al. Sources of bias in artificial intelligence that perpetuate healthcare disparities&#x2010;a global review. PLOS Digital Health. 2022;1:e0000022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cestonaro C, Delicati A, Marcante B, Caenazzo L, Tozzo P. Defining medical liability when artificial intelligence is applied on diagnostic algorithms: a systematic review. Front Med. 2023;10:1305756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Wang L, Hong J, Jiang J, Zhou L. Unmasking bias in artificial intelligence: a systematic review of bias detection and mitigation strategies in electronic health record&#x2010;based models. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2024;31:1172&#x2013;1183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H. Application progress of artificial intelligence and augmented reality in orthopaedic arthroscopy surgery. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18:775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chimenti PC, Mitten DJ. Google glass as an alternative to standard fluoroscopic visualization for percutaneous fixation of hand fractures: a pilot study. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2015;136:328&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiou SY, Liu LS, Lee CW, Kim DH, Al&#x2010;Masni MA, Liu HL,et al. Augmented reality surgical navigation system integrated with deep learning. Bioengineering. 2023;10:617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong PL, Vaigeshwari V, Mohammed Reyasudin BK, Noor Hidayah RA, Tatchanaamoorti P, Yeow JA,et al. Integrating artificial intelligence in healthcare: applications, challenges, and future directions. Future Sci OA. 2025;11:2527505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SM, Baimas&#x2010;George M, Ponce C, Chen N, Bain PA, Ganske IM,et al. Is a picture worth a thousand words? a scoping review of the impact of visual aids on patients undergoing surgery. J Surg Educ. 2024;81:1276&#x2013;1292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cork SC, Hopcroft K. Evaluating ChatGPT for converting clinic letters into patient&#x2010;friendly language: a quantitative study. BJGP Open. 2025;9:BJGPO.2024.0300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosic F, Kimmel L, Edwards E. Health literacy in orthopaedic trauma patients. J Orthop Trauma. 2017;31:e90&#x2013;e95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean MC, Oeding JF, Diniz P, Seil R, Samuelsson K. Leveraging digital twins for improved orthopaedic evaluation and treatment. J Exp Orthop. 2024;11:e70084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diniz P, Grimm B, Garcia F, Fayad J, Ley C, Mouton C,et al. Digital twin systems for musculoskeletal applications: a current concepts review. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:1892&#x2013;1910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fucentese SF, Koch PP. A novel augmented reality&#x2010;based surgical guidance system for total knee arthroplasty. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2021;141:2227&#x2013;2233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway JL, Munroe D, Vohra&#x2010;Khullar PD, Holland C, Solis MA, Moore MA,et al. Impact of an artificial intelligence&#x2010;based solution on clinicians' clinical documentation experience: initial findings using ambient listening technology. J Gen Intern Med. 2024;39:2625&#x2013;2627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goff AJ, De Oliveira Silva D, Merolli M, Bell EC, Crossley KM, Barton CJ. Patient education improves pain and function in people with knee osteoarthritis with better effects when combined with exercise therapy: a systematic review. J Physiotherapy. 2021;67:177&#x2013;189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez&#x2010;Cabello CA, Borna S, Pressman S, Haider SA, Haider CR, Forte AJ. Artificial&#x2010;intelligence&#x2010;based clinical decision support systems in primary care: a scoping review of current clinical implementations. Eur J Investig Health Psychol Educ. 2024;14:685&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo YWJ, Zheng K, Perret D, Pandita D, Tam S Ambient Listening in Clinical Practice: Evaluating EPIC Signal Data Before and After Implementation and Its Impact on Physician Workload. World Congress on Health and Biomedical Informatics; 2025; Taipei, Taiwan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurchiek RD, Choquette RH, Beynnon BD, Slauterbeck JR, Tourville TW, Toth MJ,et al. Open&#x2010;Source Remote Gait Analysis: A Post&#x2010;Surgery Patient Monitoring Application. Sci Rep. 2019;9:17966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauswaldt J, Demmer I, Heinemann S, Himmel W, Hummers E, Pung J,et al. Das Risiko von Re&#x2010;Identifizierung bei der Auswertung medizinischer Routinedaten &#x2013; Kritische Bewertung und L&#xf6;sungsans&#xe4;tze. Z Evid Fortbild Qual Gesundhwes. 2019;149:22&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hein J, Giraud F, Calvet L, Schwarz A, Cavalcanti NA, Prokudin S, et al. Creating a digital twin of spinal surgery: A proof of concept. Paper presented at: Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF conference on computer vision and pattern recognition 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoonakker JD, Adeline&#x2010;Duflot F, Orcel V, Grudzinski ML, Cognet M, Renard V. Use of visual aids in general practice consultations: A questionnaire&#x2010;based survey. PEC Innovation. 2023;2:100159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain SA, Bresnahan M, Zhuang J. The bias algorithm: how AI in healthcare exacerbates ethnic and racial disparities &#x2010; a scoping review. Ethn Health. 2025;30:197&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iscoe MS, Venkatesh AK, Holland ML, Krumholz HM, Sheares KD, Melnick ER. Benchmarking Emergency Physician EHR Time per Encounter Based on Patient and Clinical Factors. JAMA Network Open. 2024;7:e2427389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iseki C, Hayasaka T, Yanagawa H, Komoriya Y, Kondo T, Hoshi M,et al. Artificial Intelligence Distinguishes Pathological Gait: The Analysis of Markerless Motion Capture Gait Data Acquired by an iOS Application (TDPT&#x2010;GT). Sensors. 2023;23:6217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakumar P, Rathouz PJ, Lin E, Trutner Z, Uhler LM, Andrawis J,et al. Shared decision making using digital twins in knee osteoarthritis care: a randomized clinical trial of an AI&#x2010;enabled decision aid versus education alone on decision quality, physical function, and user experience. EClinicalMedicine. 2025;89:103545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadakia RJ, Tsahakis JM, Issar NM, Archer KR, Jahangir AA, Sethi MK,et al. Health literacy in an orthopedic trauma patient population: a cross&#x2010;sectional survey of patient comprehension. J Orthop Trauma. 2013;27:467&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khera P, Kumar N. Role of machine learning in gait analysis: a review. J Med Eng Technol. 2020;44:441&#x2013;467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosravi M, Zare Z, Mojtabaeian SM, Izadi R. Artificial Intelligence and Decision&#x2010;Making in Healthcare: A Thematic Analysis of a Systematic Review of Reviews. Health Serv Res Manag Epidemiol. 2024;11:23333928241234863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SE, Nam JW, Kim JI, Kim JK, Ro DH. Enhanced deep learning model enables accurate alignment measurement across diverse institutional imaging protocols. Knee Surg Relat Res. 2024;36:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konnoth C. AI and data protection law in health. In: Solaiman B, Cohen IGResearch Handbook on Health, AI and the Law. Cheltenham, UK: ElgarOnline; 2024. p. 111&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lex JR, Koucheki R, Toor J, Backstein DJ. Clinical applications of augmented reality in orthopaedic surgery: a comprehensive narrative review. Int Orthop. 2023;47:375&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Liu D, Cai L. Deep learning&#x2010;based upper limb functional assessment using a single kinect v2 sensor. Sensors. 2020;20:1903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majid N, Lee S, Plummer V. The effectiveness of orthopedic patient education in improving patient outcomes: a systematic review protocol. JBI Database Syst Rev Implement Reps. 2015;13:122&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCradden MD, Joshi S, Anderson JA, Mazwi M, Goldenberg A, Zlotnik Shaul R. Patient safety and quality improvement: Ethical principles for a regulatory approach to bias in healthcare machine learning. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2020;27:2024&#x2013;2027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGenity C, Clarke EL, Jennings C, Matthews G, Cartlidge C, Freduah&#x2010;Agyemang H,et al. Artificial intelligence in digital pathology: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of diagnostic test accuracy. NPJ Digit Med. 2024;7:114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaud F, Luaces A, Mouzo F, Cuadrado J. Use of patellofemoral digital twins for patellar tracking and treatment prediction: comparison of 3D models and contact detection algorithms. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2024;12:1347720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery L, Willing R, Lanting B. Virtual joint motion simulator accurately predicts effects of femoral component malalignment during TKA. Bioengineering. 2023;10:503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nong P, Adler&#x2010;Milstein J, Apathy NC, Holmgren AJ, Everson J. Current use and evaluation of artificial intelligence and predictive models in US hospitals. Health Aff. 2025;44:90&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norori N, Hu Q, Aellen FM, Faraci FD, Tzovara A. Addressing bias in big data and AI for health care: a call for open science. Patterns. 2021;2:100347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olatunji IE, Rauch J, Katzensteiner M, Khosla M. A review of anonymization for healthcare data. Big Data. 2024;12:538&#x2013;555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouanes K, Farhah N. Effectiveness of artificial intelligence (AI) in clinical decision support systems and care delivery. J Med Syst. 2024;48:74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palaniappan K, Lin EYT, Vogel S. Global regulatory frameworks for the use of artificial intelligence (AI) in the healthcare services sector. Healthcare. 2024;12:562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh RB, Helmchen LA. Paying for artificial intelligence in medicine. NPJ Digit Med. 2022;5:63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poissant L. The impact of electronic health records on time efficiency of physicians and nurses: a systematic review. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2005;12:505&#x2013;516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruneski JA, Pareek A, Kunze KN, Martin RK, Karlsson J, Oeding JF,et al. Supervised machine learning and associated algorithms: applications in orthopedic surgery. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:1196&#x2013;1202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramkumar PN, Pang M, Polisetty T, Helm JM, Karnuta JM. Meaningless applications and misguided methodologies in artificial intelligence&#x2010;related orthopaedic research propagates hype over hope. Arthroscopy. 2022;38:2761&#x2013;2766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas JT, Jost B, Zipeto C, Budassi P, Zumstein MA. Glenoid component placement in reverse shoulder arthroplasty assisted with augmented reality through a head&#x2010;mounted display leads to low deviation between planned and postoperative parameters. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2023;32:e587&#x2013;e596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotenstein LS, Torre M, Ramos MA, Rosales RC, Guille C, Sen S,et al. Prevalence of burnout among physicians: a systematic review. JAMA. 2018;320:1131&#x2013;1150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupp MC, Moser LB, Hess S, Angele P, Aurich M, Dyrna F,et al. Orthopaedic surgeons display a positive outlook towards artificial intelligence: a survey among members of the AGA Society for Arthroscopy and Joint Surgery. J Exp Orthop. 2024;11:e12080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatini L, Ascani D, Vezza D, Mass&#xe8; A, Cacciola G. Novel surgical technique for total knee arthroplasty integrating kinematic alignment and real&#x2010;time elongation of the ligaments using the NextAR system. J Pers Med. 2024;14:794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shemtob L, Nouri A, Harvey&#x2010;Sullivan A, Qiu CS, Martin J, Martin M,et al. Comparing artificial intelligence&#x2010; vs clinician&#x2010;authored summaries of simulated primary care electronic health records. JAMIA Open. 2025;8:ooaf082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith H, Birchley G, Ives J. Artificial intelligence in clinical decision&#x2010;making: Rethinking personal moral responsibility. Bioethics. 2024;38:78&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart JA, Wood L, Wiener J, Kennedy GD, Chu DI, Lancaster JR,et al. Visual teaching aids improve patient understanding and reduce anxiety prior to a colectomy. Am J Surg. 2021;222:780&#x2013;785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stults CD, Deng S, Martinez MC, Wilcox J, Szwerinski N, Chen KH,et al. Evaluation of an ambient artificial intelligence documentation platform for clinicians. JAMA Netwk Open. 2025;8:e258614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun T, Wang J, Suo M, Liu X, Huang H, Zhang J,et al. The digital twin: a potential solution for the personalized diagnosis and treatment of musculoskeletal system diseases. Bioengineering. 2023;10:627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsahakis JM, Issar NM, Kadakia RJ, Archer KR, Barzyk T, Mir HR. Health literacy in an orthopaedic trauma patient population: improving patient comprehension with informational intervention. J Orthop Trauma. 2014;28:e75&#x2013;e79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Veen D, Van Uden C, Blankemeier L, Delbrouck JB, Aali A, Bluethgen C,et al. Adapted large language models can outperform medical experts in clinical text summarization. Nature Med. 2024;30:1134&#x2013;1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waxler S, Blazek P, White D, Sneider D, Chung K, Nagarathnam M, et al. Generative medical event models improve with scale. arXiv preprint arXiv. 2025;1:2508.12104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler PW, Zsidai B, Hamrin Senorski E, Pruneski JA, Hirschmann MT, Ley C,et al. A practical guide to the implementation of AI in orthopaedic research&#x2010;Part 7: Risks, limitations, safety and verification of medical AI systems. J Exp Orthop. 2025;12:e70247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younis HA, Eisa TAE, Nasser M, Sahib TM, Noor AA, Alyasiri OM,et al. A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of artificial intelligence tools in medicine and healthcare: applications, considerations, limitations, motivation and challenges. Diagnostics. 2024;14:109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef Y, De Wet D, Back DA, Scherer J. Digitalization in orthopaedics: a narrative review. Front Surg. 2024;10:1325423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Liu Q, Usuyama N, Wong C, Naumann T, Poon H. Exploring scaling laws for EHR foundation models. arXiv preprint arXiv. 2025;1:2505.22964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zsidai B, Hilkert AS, Kaarre J, Narup E, Senorski EH, Grassi A,et al. A practical guide to the implementation of AI in orthopaedic research &#x2010; part 1: opportunities in clinical application and overcoming existing challenges. J Exp Orthop. 2023;10:117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zsidai B, Kaarre J, Hilkert AS, Narup E, Senorski EH, Grassi A,et al. Accelerated evidence synthesis in orthopaedics&#x2010;the roles of natural language processing, expert annotation and large language models. J Exp Orthop. 2023;10:99.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>