<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41807409</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of ranking alternatives of micro-cup production from directionally rolled copper rods using the Intuitionistic Fuzzy MARCOS method.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9585</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-29817-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">This study aims to develop a sustainable and efficient simulation-assisted micro-deep drawing framework by integrating the Intuitionistic Fuzzy MARCOS method for multi-criteria decision-making. The focus is on optimizing multiple conflicting performance parameters, including tool force, springback, formability, and thinning rate. An eight-stage micro-deep drawing model was developed and simulated through Finite Element Analysis (FEA) using directionally rolled and recrystallized copper sheets. The Intuitionistic Fuzzy MARCOS (Measurement of Alternatives and Ranking according to Compromise Solution) method was then employed to estimate and rank different process parameter combinations, enabling the systematic selection of the most favorable conditions for high-quality micro-cup production. ANOVA and Goodness-of-Fit metrics were used to validate the model&#x2019;s significance and accuracy. Key parameters&#x2014;clearance, punch radius, draw ratio, and type of dry lubricant&#x2014;were optimized and experimentally validated. The optimal configuration (Clearance: 0.285&#xa0;mm, Punch Radius: 1.5&#xa0;mm, Draw Ratio: 1.69, Graphite lubricant) outperformed others in terms of mechanical stability, dimensional accuracy, and formability. High R<sup>2</sup>, adjusted R<sup>2</sup>, and adequate precision indicated strong model reliability. Experimental validations, including microstructural analysis, surface roughness, hardness, and springback, confirmed the simulation predictions. The study is limited to a specific draw ratio range and material (recrystallized copper), which may affect its broader applicability. Future studies could incorporate more materials and real-time sensing. The approach minimizes trial-and-error, reduces material waste, and supports sustainable micro-manufacturing by improving efficiency and product quality. This research integrates fuzzy optimization with finite element modeling and experimental validation, providing a novel, accurate, and sustainable framework for micro-forming process optimization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-025-29817-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sivam</LastName><ForeName>S P Sundar Singh</ForeName><Initials>SPSS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, College of Engineering and Technology, SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Kattankulathur, Chennai, 603203, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kesavan</LastName><ForeName>Stalin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Marine Engineering, Amet University, East Coast Road, Kanathur, 603 112, Chennai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ajiboye</LastName><ForeName>Tajudeen Kolawole</ForeName><Initials>TK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Faculty of Engineering and Technology, University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria. ajitek@unilorin.edu.ng.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dry lubricants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Finite element analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intuitionistic Fuzzy MARCOS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Micro-cup forming</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Micro-deep drawing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Process optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable manufacturing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41807409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13009493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-29817-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-29817-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anand, D. &amp; Ravi Kumar, D. Effect of sheet thickness and grain size on forming limit diagrams of thin brass sheets. <i>Adv. Intell. Syst. Comput.</i><b>757</b>, 435&#x2013;444. 10.1007/978-981-13-1966-2_39 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-13-1966-2_39</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwekar, S. Determination of strain distribution in single stage deep drawing process by finite element simulation. <i>IOSR J. Mech. Civil Eng.</i><b>4</b> (5), 15&#x2013;22. 10.9790/1684-0451522 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9790/1684-0451522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandyopadhyay, K. et al. Limiting drawing ratio and deep drawing behavior of dual phase steel tailor welded blanks: FE simulation and experimental validation. <i>J. Mater. Process. Technol.</i><b>217</b>, 48&#x2013;64. 10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2014.10.022 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2014.10.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atul, S. &amp; Babu, M. C. L. T. A review on effect of thinning, wrinkling and spring-back on deep drawing process. In <i>Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part B: Journal of Engineering Manufacture</i>. 1011&#x2013;1036. 10.1177/0954405417752509 (SAGE Publications Ltd, 2019). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens, G. et al. Influence of tool geometry variations on the limiting drawing ratio in micro deep drawing. <i>Int.J. Mater. Form.</i><b>9</b> (2), 253&#x2013;258. 10.1007/s12289-015-1228-9 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12289-015-1228-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banabic, D. et al. <i>Advanced Models for the Prediction of Forming Limit Curves</i>. 205&#x2013;300. 10.1007/978-3-319-44070-5_5 (2016). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghassemali, E. et al. Effect of cold-work on the Hall-Petch breakdown in copper based micro-components. <i>Mech. Mater.</i><b>80(Part A)</b>, 124&#x2013;135. 10.1016/j.mechmat.2014.10.003 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mechmat.2014.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel, U. &amp; Eckstein, R. Microforming - From basic research to its realization. <i>J. Mater. Process. Technol.</i> 125&#x2013;126. 10.1016/S0924-0136(02)00415-6 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, J. et al. Microdeep drawing of C1100 microsquare cups using microforming technology. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol.</i><b>82</b> (5&#x2013;8), 1363&#x2013;1369. 10.1007/s00170-015-7476-5 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-015-7476-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, M. W., Wang, J. L. &amp; Korsunsky, A. M. A review of geometrical and microstructural size effects in micro-scale deformation processing of metallic alloy components. <i>Int. J. Mach. Tools Manuf</i>. <b>109</b>, 94&#x2013;125. 10.1016/j.ijmachtools.2016.07.006 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmachtools.2016.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mevlut Fatih Peker. <i>Investigations on the Micro-Scale Surface Interactions At the Tool and Workpiece Interface in Micro-Manufacturing of Bipolar Plates for Proton Exchange Membrane Fuel Cells&#x2019;</i> (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, M. W., Yang, B. &amp; Chan, W. L. Experimental and simulation studies of micro blanking and deep drawing compound process using copper sheet. <i>J. Mater. Process. Technol.</i><b>213</b> (1), 101&#x2013;110. 10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2012.08.007 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2012.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olguner, S. &amp; Bozdana, A. T. The effect of friction coefficient on punch load and thickness reduction in deep drawing process. <i>Int. J. Mater.</i><b>3</b>, 64&#x2013;69 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradowski, B. et al. A sustainable approach for determining compromise ranking based on intuitonistic fuzzy score functions. In <i>Lecture Notes in Business Information Processing</i>. 10.1007/978-3-031-29570-6_10 (2023). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha, A. et al. A dual probabilistic linguistic MARCOS approach based on generalized Dombi operator for decision-making. <i>Iran. J. Fuzzy Syst.</i><b>20</b> (2). 10.22111/ijfs.2023.7558 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irthiea, I. K. <i>Process Analysis and Design in Micro Deep Drawing Utilizing a Flexible Die</i> (University of Glasgow, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phanitwong, W. &amp; Thipprakmas, S. Multi draw radius die design for increases in limiting drawing ratio. <i>Metals</i><b>10</b> (7), 1&#x2013;17. 10.3390/met10070870 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met10070870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H. J. et al. Development of micro metal forming manufacturing system. <i>Mater. Sci. Forum</i> 505&#x2013;507. 10.4028/www.scientific.net/msf.505-507.19 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed, M. et al. Sustainable selection of microwave absorbing materials: A green evaluation under interval-valued intuitionistic fuzzy environment. <i>Clean. Mater.</i>10.1016/j.clema.2024.100236 (2024). 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clema.2024.100236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salimian, S., Mousavi, S. M. &amp; Antucheviciene, J. An interval-valued intuitionistic fuzzy model based on extended VIKOR and MARCOS for sustainable supplier selection in organ transplantation networks for healthcare devices. <i>Sustainability (Switzerland)</i><b>14</b> (7). 10.3390/su14073795 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takalkar, A. S. &amp; Mailan Chinnapandi, L. B. Deep drawing process at the elevated temperature: A critical review and future research directions. <i>CIRP J. Manufact. Sci. Technol.</i><b>27</b>, 56&#x2013;67. 10.1016/j.cirpj.2019.08.002 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cirpj.2019.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vollertsen, F. et al. Size effects in manufacturing of metallic components. <i>CIRP Annals - Manuf. Technol.</i><b>58</b> (2), 566&#x2013;587. 10.1016/j.cirp.2009.09.002 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cirp.2009.09.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takalkar, A. S. &amp; Chinnapandi, L. B. M. Multi-stage deep drawing process of axis-symmetric extra deep drawing steel cylindrical cup. <i>Eng. Res. Express</i><b>2</b> (2). 10.1088/2631-8695/ab872a (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, S. et al. A novel deep drawing process for aluminum alloy sheets at cryogenic temperatures. <i>J. Mater. Process. Technol.</i>10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2020.116743 (2020). 284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2020.116743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkus, D. &amp; Testik, O. M. A novel method for weighting decision makers for failure mode and effect analysis under intuitionistic fuzzy environment. <i>Qual. Reliab. Eng. Int.</i><b>40</b> (4). 10.1002/qre.3510 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aminzadeh, A., Parvizi, A. &amp; Moradi, M. Multi-objective topology optimization of deep drawing dissimilar tailor laser welded blanks; experimental and finite element investigation. <i>Opt. Laser Technol.</i><b>125</b>10.1016/j.optlastec.2019.106029 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaurasiya, R. &amp; Jain, D. Generalized intuitionistic fuzzy entropy on IF-MARCOS technique in multi-criteria decision making. In <i>Communications in Computer and Information Science</i>. 10.1007/978-3-030-81462-5_52 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J., Chai, M. &amp; Wu, M. A new energy vehicle battery supplier selection using SWARA-MEREC-MARCOS approach under probabilistic triangular intuitionistic hesitant fuzzy environment. <i>J. Intell. Fuzzy Syst.</i>10.3233/jifs-231975 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jifs-231975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hezam, I. M. et al. Standard deviation and rank sum-based MARCOS model under intuitionistic fuzzy information for hospital site selection. <i>Kybernetes</i>10.1108/K-01-2023-0136 (2023). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kizielewicz, B. et al. Towards the identification of MARCOS models based on intuitionistic fuzzy score functions. In <i>Proceedings of the 17th Conference on Computer Science and Intelligence Systems</i>. 10.15439/2022F249 (FedCSIS, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, A. R. et al. Assessment of battery energy storage systems using the intuitionistic fuzzy removal effects of criteria and the measurement of alternatives and ranking based on compromise solution method. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b> (20). 10.3390/en15207782 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandyopadhyay, S. A novel multi-criteria decision analysis technique incorporating demanding essential characteristics of existing MCDA techniques. <i>Progress Artif. Intell.</i><b>12</b> (3). 10.1007/s13748-023-00299-5 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frini, A. A multicriteria intelligence aid methodology using MCDA, artificial intelligence, and fuzzy sets theory. <i>Math. Probl. Eng.</i><b>2017</b>10.1155/2017/9281321 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghajari, Y. E., Alesheikh, A. A., Modiri, M., Hosnavi, R. &amp; Abbasi, M. Spatial modelling of urban physical vulnerability to explosion hazards using GIS and fuzzy MCDA. <i>Sustainability (Switzerland)</i><b>9</b> (7). 10.3390/su9071274 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gigovi&#x107;, L., Pamu&#x10d;ar, D., Luki&#x107;, D. &amp; Markovi&#x107;, S. GIS-Fuzzy DEMATEL MCDA model for the evaluation of the sites for ecotourism development: A case study of Dunavski klju&#x10d; region, Serbia. <i>Land Use Policy</i><b>58</b>. 10.1016/j.landusepol.2016.07.030 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabisch, M. &amp; Labreuche, C. Fuzzy measures and integrals in MCDA. In <i>International Series in Operations Research and Management Science</i>. <b>233</b>. 10.1007/978-1-4939-3094-4_14 (2016). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamrani, A., Agarwal, A., Allouhi, A. &amp; McDaniel, D. Applying machine learning to wire Arc additive manufacturing: a systematic data-driven literature review. <i>J. Intell. Manuf.</i>10.1007/s10845-023-02171-8 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10845-023-02171-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indrajayanthan, V., Mohanty, N. K., Elavarasan, R. M. &amp; Mihet-Popa, L. Investigation on current and prospective energy transition scenarios in Indian landscape using integrated SWOT-MCDA methodology. <i>Sustainability (Switzerland)</i><b>14</b> (9). 10.3390/su14094940 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaymaz, &#xc7;. K., &#xc7;ak&#x131;r, &#xc7;., Birinci, S. &amp; K&#x131;z&#x131;lkan, Y. GIS-Fuzzy DEMATEL MCDA model in the evaluation of the areas for ecotourism development: A case study of Uzundere, Erzurum-Turkey. <i>Appl. Geogr.</i><b>136</b>. 10.1016/j.apgeog.2021.102577 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, P., Sharma, R. &amp; Bhaumik, S. MCDA techniques used in optimization of weights and ratings of DRASTIC model for groundwater vulnerability assessment. <i>Data Sci. Manage.</i><b>5</b> (1). 10.1016/j.dsm.2022.03.004 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouma, Y. O., Yabann, C., Kirichu, M. &amp; Tateishi, R. Optimization of urban highway bypass horizontal alignment: A methodological overview of intelligent Spatial MCDA approach using fuzzy AHP and GIS. <i>Adv. Civil Eng.</i><b>2014</b>10.1155/2014/182568 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zkan, B., Sar&#x131;&#xe7;i&#xe7;ek, &#x130;. &amp; &#xd6;zceylan, E. Evaluation of landfill sites using GIS-based MCDA with hesitant fuzzy linguistic term sets. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i><b>27</b> (34). 10.1007/s11356-020-10128-0 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papathanasiou, J. An example on the use and limitations of MCDA: the case of fuzzy VIKOR. <i>Examples Counterexamples</i><b>1</b>10.1016/j.exco.2020.100001 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur, P. et al. A new entropy measurement for the analysis of uncertain data in MCDA problems using intuitionistic fuzzy sets and COPRAS method. <i>Axioms</i><b>10</b> (4). 10.3390/axioms10040335 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yatsalo, B., Korobov, A. &amp; Mart&#xed;nez, L. From MCDA to fuzzy MCDA: violation of basic axiom and how to fix it. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>33</b> (5). 10.1007/s00521-020-05053-9 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yatsalo, B., Radaev, A. &amp; Mart&#xed;nez, L. From MCDA to fuzzy MCDA: presumption of model adequacy or is every fuzzification of an mCDA method justified? <i>Inf. Sci.</i><b>587</b>10.1016/j.ins.2021.12.051 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemba, P. Selection of electric vehicles for the needs of sustainable transport under conditions of uncertainty&#x2014;a comparative study on fuzzy Mcda methods. <i>Energies</i><b>14</b> (22). 10.3390/en14227786 (2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>