<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41900269</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2072-666X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Micromachines</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Micromachines (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Numerical Study on Heat Transfer Characteristics of Microchannel with Ferrofluid Under Influence of Magnetic Intensity.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">383</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/mi17030383</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Effective thermal management is critical for high-power lithium-ion batteries to mitigate excessive heat generation and ensure operational reliability. Failure to maintain a uniform temperature distribution can lead to accelerated capacity fading and severe safety risks, such as thermal runaway. In this study, a ferrofluid-based magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) microchannel cooling system was numerically investigated to elucidate the influence of magnetic intensity, magnet geometry, and electrical boundary conditions on flow behavior and heat transfer performance for battery cooling applications. A fully coupled multiphysics model incorporating electromagnetic, fluid flow, and heat transfer phenomena was developed and validated against experimental and numerical data from the literature. The results show that increasing the applied voltage enhances current density and Lorentz force almost linearly, leading to significant flow acceleration and improved convective heat transfer. Electrical insulation effectively suppresses current leakage into the channel walls, increasing the average current density by up to 222% and the Lorentz force by more than 300%. Compared with a cylindrical magnet, a rectangular magnet provides a more uniform magnetic field distribution and stronger near-wall Lorentz forcing, resulting in superior cooling performance. Under a 4C discharge condition, the insulated rectangular magnet reduces the maximum battery temperature by approximately 30% and increases the average Nusselt number by up to 103% relative to the non-insulated case. The findings reveal the critical roles of magnetic-field-controlled flow symmetry and near-wall forcing in MHD-driven microchannels, and provide practical design guidelines for battery cooling systems with no moving mechanical parts and active electromagnetic flow control.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hwang</LastName><ForeName>Seong-Guk</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Dong-A University, 37 Nakdong-Daero 550, Saha-gu, Busan 49315, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le</LastName><ForeName>Tai Duc</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-1922-1552</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Dong-A University, 37 Nakdong-Daero 550, Saha-gu, Busan 49315, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Moo-Yeon</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8857-4444</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Dong-A University, 37 Nakdong-Daero 550, Saha-gu, Busan 49315, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. P0021944</GrantID><Agency>The Korea Institute for Advancement of Technology (KIAT) grant funded by the Korean government (MOTIE)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>VCDM2502</GrantID><Agency>Korea Industrial Complex Corporation (KICOX)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>20024894</GrantID><Agency>Korea Evaluation Institute of Industrial Technology (KEIT)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025-RISE-02-003</GrantID><Agency>The Regional Innovation System and Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Micromachines (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101640903</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2072-666X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">battery thermal management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ferrofluid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetic intensity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) pump</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microchannel cooling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41900269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13029069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/mi17030383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">mi17030383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>You N., Chinnasamy V., Lee M., Cho H. Correlation analysis between design parameters and cooling performance in 21700 battery module using immersion cooling. Therm. Sci. Eng. Prog. 2025;68:104368. doi: 10.1016/j.tsep.2025.104368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsep.2025.104368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le T.D., Bang Y.M., Nguyen N.H., Lee M.Y. Artificial Neural Network-Based Optimization of an Inlet Perforated Distributor Plate for Uniform Coolant Entry in 10 kWh 24S24P Cylindrical Battery Module. Symmetry. 2025;18:14. doi: 10.3390/sym18010014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym18010014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu N., Qin Y., Liu W., Chen H., Zhou X. Performance optimization of two-phase immersion cooling systems for large-format lithium-ion battery packs. Appl. Therm. Eng. 2025;281:128752. doi: 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2025.128752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2025.128752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang C., Lai X., Shen K., Zheng Y., Xu C., Peng Y., Li J., Wang X., Wang Y., Hong Y., et al. Experimental study on immersion cooling for delaying thermal runaway propagation in lithium-ion battery modules. Process Saf. Environ. Prot. 2026;206:108333. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2025.108333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2025.108333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai L.D., Lee M.Y. Advances in the Battery Thermal Management Systems of Electric Vehicles for Thermal Runaway Prevention and Suppression. Batteries. 2025;11:216. doi: 10.3390/batteries11060216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/batteries11060216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke W., Tong B., Zhang W., Hu T., Gao W., Xu J., Li S., Tan P. Experimental comparison of static immersion cooling and natural air cooling for suppressing thermal runaway triggering in lithium-ion battery modules. J. Energy Storage. 2026;149:120444. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2026.120444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2026.120444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng A., Peng F., Chen Y., Peng Q., Sun X., Li J. Numerical research on baffle-enhanced liquid immersion cooling for thermal regulation in 280 Ah LiFePO4 batteries. Energy. 2025;336:138458. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2025.138458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2025.138458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahab A., Cifterler N., Amjady N., Date A., Kemper H., Khayyam H. Enhancing energy and thermal efficiency of single-phase liquid immersion cooling systems for lithium-ion batteries in electric vehicles. J. Energy Storage. 2025;131:117365. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.117365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.117365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W., Liu S., Yang Y., Luo W., Zhu L. Numerical investigation of flow boiling heat and mass transfer in distributed jet microchannels for lithium-ion battery cooling. Case Stud. Therm. Eng. 2025;76:107446. doi: 10.1016/j.csite.2025.107446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2025.107446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai Y., Ding J., Liu L. Numerical investigation on the cooling performance of lithium-ion battery using liquid cooled-plate with integrated grooves and secondary microchannel structures. Int. J. Therm. Sci. 2025;217:110094. doi: 10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2025.110094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2025.110094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Yang J., Sun Y., Ren X. Performance analysis of battery thermal management system composed of copper foam/paraffin and wavy liquid cooling microchannels. Renew. Energy. 2025;256:123928. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2025.123928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2025.123928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L., Meng F., Wu J., Che B., Song C., Zhang J. Design and experimental study of thermoelectric cooling device for infrared detectors based on the microchannel heat sink. Case Stud. Therm. Eng. 2025;74:106908. doi: 10.1016/j.csite.2025.106908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2025.106908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Wang Y., Yuan X., Wang X., Yang X., Li Q. Design and optimization of a staggered counter-current microchannel liquid-cooled plate. Appl. Therm. Eng. 2025;279:127891. doi: 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2025.127891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2025.127891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Wu Y., Sha H. Study on thermal-hydraulic characteristics of tesla valve-type microchannels in liquid-cooled plates: Experiment and numerical simulation. Int. Commun. Heat Mass Transf. 2025;169:109722. doi: 10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2025.109722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2025.109722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart S.T., Awald C., Lightsey E.G., Romero-Calvo &#xc1;. Magnetohydrodynamically pumped liquid metal loops for CubeSat thermal control. Int. J. Heat. Mass. Transf. 2025;239:126552. doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2024.126552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2024.126552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowak M., Spirzewski M., Czerski K. Optimization of the DC magnetohydrodynamic pump for the Dual Fluid Reactor. Ann. Nucl. Energy. 2022;174:109142. doi: 10.1016/j.anucene.2022.109142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anucene.2022.109142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R., Dou X., Huang J., Zhang D., Xia D., Zhang X. Mechanisms of energy conversion in induction magnetohydrodynamic pumps for transporting conducting liquids. Energy. 2022;244:123157. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2022.123157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2022.123157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Habahbeh O., Al-Saqqa M., Safi M., Abo Khater T. Review of magnetohydrodynamic pump applications. Alex. Eng. J. 2016;55:1347&#x2013;1358. doi: 10.1016/j.aej.2016.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2016.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak J., Kim H.R. Performance analysis of magnetohydrodynamic pump for sodium-cooled fast reactor thermal hydraulic experiment. Ann. Nucl. Energy. 2019;132:191&#x2013;198. doi: 10.1016/j.anucene.2019.04.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anucene.2019.04.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das C., Wang G., Payne F. Some practical applications of magnetohydrodynamic pumping. Sens. Actuators A Phys. 2013;201:43&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.sna.2013.06.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sna.2013.06.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghgoo A.M., Hajihadi Naghash T., Ghassemi M., Bijarchi M.A., Shafii M.B. Magnetic-driven micromixer induced by oscillatory ferrofluid droplets as on-demand soft microactuators. Sens. Actuators A Phys. 2026;400:117475. doi: 10.1016/j.sna.2026.117475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sna.2026.117475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradeniakov&#xe1; K., Hockicko P. Ferrofluids: Properties, preparation and their transport engineering applications. Transp. Res. Procedia. 2025;93:598&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1016/j.trpro.2025.11.090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trpro.2025.11.090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahangar Zonouzi S., Sepehri Rad P., Aminfar H. Transient boiling enhanced thermal transport and magnetically driven circulation in a closed ferrofluid cooling loop. Case Stud. Therm. Eng. 2025;75:107316. doi: 10.1016/j.csite.2025.107316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2025.107316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alazwari M.A., Basem A., AL-bonsrulah H.A., Ajour M.N., Abu-Hamdeh N.H., Milyani A.H., Almitani K.H. Simulation-based analysis of ferrofluid cooling and magnetohydrodynamic effects in a photovoltaic-thermoelectric hybrid system. Results Eng. 2026;29:109189. doi: 10.1016/j.rineng.2026.109189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2026.109189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Hadoui B., Ighris Y., Kaddiri M., Baliti J. Controlled magneto-thermal performance and irreversibilities analysis of complex chambers filled with nanofluids and ferrofluids using experimental variable properties for electronic cooling. Appl. Therm. Eng. 2026;285:129241. doi: 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2025.129241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2025.129241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari P., Haghshenasfard M., Esfahany M.N., Ehsani M. Mass transfer characteristics of ferrofluids flowing through a microchannel under AC magnetic field. Int. Commun. Heat Mass Transf. 2022;139:106436. doi: 10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2022.106436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2022.106436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai T., Sharma K., Marjan R.K., Farhang B., Mahmoud M.H., Fouad H., El-Shafai W. Numerical analysis of the magnetic field impact on hydrothermal characteristics of a microchannel heatsink with Fe3O4 ferrofluid and various pin-fin shapes. J. Magn. Magn. Mater. 2023;585:171102. doi: 10.1016/j.jmmm.2023.171102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmmm.2023.171102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui N.G.J., Stanley C., Nguyen N., Rosengarten G. Ferrofluids for heat transfer enhancement under an external magnetic field. Int. J. Heat Mass Transf. 2018;123:110&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2018.02.100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2018.02.100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ert&#xfc;rk H., Koca T. Investigation of thermal performance of Fe3O4 nanofluid applied with magnetic field under constant heat flux. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2025;150:11339&#x2013;11351. doi: 10.1007/s10973-025-14454-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-025-14454-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzougui M., Boutas L., Zinoubi J. Exploring the thermal efficiency of Fe3O4-H2O flow in a microchannel under the effects of a magnetic field. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2024;149:14433&#x2013;14448. doi: 10.1007/s10973-024-13722-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-024-13722-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmoune I., Bougoul S. Effect of magnetic field and magnetic nanofluid on heat transmission improvement in a curved minichannel. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2024;149:729&#x2013;744. doi: 10.1007/s10973-023-12707-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-023-12707-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrez Z., El Cafsi A. Forced convection Fe3O4/water nanofluid flow through a horizontal channel under the influence of a non-uniform magnetic field. Eur. Phys. J. Plus. 2021;136:451. doi: 10.1140/epjp/s13360-021-01410-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1140/epjp/s13360-021-01410-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya S., Al Taisan N., Khatri S., Souayeh B., Alfannakh H., Vishwakarma D.K. Magneto-hydrodynamic behavior of magnetic nanofluids in mini-channel heat sinks for electronics cooling. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:28861. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-10024-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-10024-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12331920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40775244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartl D.J., Galvan E., Malak R.J., Baur J.W. Parameterized Design Optimization of a Magnetohydrodynamic Liquid Metal Active Cooling Concept. ASME. J. Mech. Des. 2016;138:031402. doi: 10.1115/1.4032268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4032268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J., Zhang Y., Wang J., Chinthavali M.S., Moorthy R.K. Liquid Metal based Cooling for Power Electronics Systems with Inductor Integrated Magnetohydrodynamic Pump (MHD Pump); Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE 8th Workshop on Wide Bandgap Power Devices and Applications (WiPDA); Redondo Beach, CA, USA. 7&#x2013;11 November 2021; pp. 310&#x2013;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yerasimou Y., Pickert V., Ji B., Song X. Liquid Metal Magnetohydrodynamic Pump for Junction Temperature Control of Power Modules. IEEE Trans. Power Electron. 2018;33:10583&#x2013;10593. doi: 10.1109/TPEL.2018.2806622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPEL.2018.2806622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang S.G., Kudriavskyi Y., Garud K.S., Lee M.Y. Numerical Study on Cooling Performance Characteristics of 22 kW Traction Inverter Using MHD Pump-Based Cooling System. Appl. Sci. 2022;13:3189. doi: 10.3390/app13053189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13053189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo J.H., Patil M.S., Panchal S., Lee M.Y. Numerical Investigations on Magnetohydrodynamic Pump Based Microchannel Cooling System for Heat Dissipating Element. Symmetry. 2020;12:1713. doi: 10.3390/sym12101713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym12101713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan M.I., Ali A.J.F., Tufah R.S. Numerical study of the effect of channel geometry on the performance of Magnetohydrodynamic micro pump. Eng. Sci. Technol. Int. J. 2017;20:982&#x2013;989. doi: 10.1016/j.jestch.2017.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jestch.2017.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panchal S., Mathewson S., Fraser R., Culham R., Fowler M. Thermal management of lithium-ion pouch cell with indirect liquid cooling using dual cold plates approach. SAE Int. J. Altern. Powertrains. 2015;4:293&#x2013;307. doi: 10.4271/2015-01-1184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4271/2015-01-1184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemi B., Aminossadati S.M., Raisi A. Magnetic field effect on natural convection in a nanofluid-filled square enclosure. Int. J. Therm. Sci. 2011;50:1748&#x2013;1756. doi: 10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2011.04.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2011.04.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabbi K.M., Saha S., Mojumder S., Rahman M.M., Saidur R., Ibrahim T.A. Numerical investigation of pure mixed convection in a ferrofluid-filled lid-driven cavity for different heater configurations. Alex. Eng. J. 2016;55:127&#x2013;139. doi: 10.1016/j.aej.2015.12.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2015.12.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayat T., Rashid M., Alsaedi A. MHD convective flow of magnetite-Fe3O4 nanoparticles by curved stretching sheet. Results Phys. 2017;7:3107&#x2013;3115. doi: 10.1016/j.rinp.2017.08.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rinp.2017.08.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>COMSOL AB . COMSOL Multiphysics Reference. COMSOL AB; Stockholm, Sweden: 2023. Version 6.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan A.A., Kim K.Y. Evaluation of various channel shapes of a microchannel heat sink. Int. J. Air-Cond. Refrig. 2016;24:1650018. doi: 10.1142/S2010132516500188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S2010132516500188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousofvand R., Derakhshan S., Ghasemi K., Siavashi M. MHD transverse mixed convection and entropy generation study of an electromagnetic pump including a nanofluid using 3D LBM simulation. Int. J. Mech. Sci. 2017;133:73&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2017.08.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2017.08.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garud K.S., Kudriavskyi Y., Lee M.S., Kang E.H., Lee M.Y. Numerical Study on Thermal and Flow Characteristics of Divergent Duct with Different Rib Shapes for Electric-Vehicle Cooling System. Symmetry. 2022;14:1696. doi: 10.3390/sym14081696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym14081696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang S.-G., Lee M.-Y., Ko B.-S. Numerical Analysis on Cooling Performances for Connectors Using Immersion Cooling in Ultra-Fast Chargers for Electric Vehicles. Symmetry. 2025;17:624. doi: 10.3390/sym17040624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym17040624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao G., Jian Y., Chang L., Buren M. Magnetohydrodynamic flow of generalized Maxwell fluids in a rectangular micropump under an AC electric field. J. Magn. Magn. Mater. 2015;387:111&#x2013;117. doi: 10.1016/j.jmmm.2015.03.094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmmm.2015.03.094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemoff A.V., Lee A.P. AC magnetohydrodynamic micropump. Sens. Actuators B Chem. 2000;63:178&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1016/S0925-4005(00)00355-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0925-4005(00)00355-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil M.S., Seo J.-H., Lee M.-Y. A novel dielectric fluid immersion cooling technology for Li-ion battery thermal management. Energy Convers. Manag. 2021;229:113715. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2020.113715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2020.113715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>