<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41743853</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2639-5274</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research (Washington, D.C.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Research (Wash D C)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Self-Decoupling Multimodal Sensor for Enhanced Early Warning of Lithium-Ion Battery Thermal Runaway.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1120</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1120</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1120</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.34133/research.1120</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) are central to sustainable energy systems but are vulnerable to thermal runaway (TR), necessitating robust safety monitoring. Conventional single-sensor systems cannot decouple the coupled electrochemical, thermal, and mechanical processes, while existing multimodal sensors suffer from signal cross-talk and large footprints in practical applications. Here, we introduce an insect-inspired, self-decoupling multimodal sensor, fabricated via maskless laser direct writing, that leverages distinct sensing mechanisms and orthogonal output signals for simultaneous strain, temperature, and gas detection. The sensor achieves reliable intrinsic decoupling of strain and temperature over 20 to 110&#xa0;&#xb0;C, along with an independent gas response. Seamlessly integrated onto lithium iron phosphate (LiFePO<sub>4</sub>) cells, it captures real-time multimodal data during both normal and TR events. Coupled with a bespoke multiphysics model, this platform reconstructs the thermal-mechanical evolution of LIBs. Our work provides a compact and durable strategy for precise real-time monitoring and early warning of battery failure.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Zhenglin Li et&#xa0;al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhenglin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Power Engineering, Shanghai Key Laboratory of Intelligent Sensing and Detection Technology, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Pressure Systems and Safety, Ministry of Education, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiao</LastName><ForeName>Meiyuan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Chemical Engineering, Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Hierarchical Nanomaterials, School of Chemical Engineering, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Power Engineering, Shanghai Key Laboratory of Intelligent Sensing and Detection Technology, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Yangyang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Power Engineering, Shanghai Key Laboratory of Intelligent Sensing and Detection Technology, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1069-2157</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Power Engineering, Shanghai Key Laboratory of Intelligent Sensing and Detection Technology, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Pressure Systems and Safety, Ministry of Education, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lian</LastName><ForeName>Cheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9016</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Chemical Engineering, Shanghai Engineering Research Center of Hierarchical Nanomaterials, School of Chemical Engineering, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Molecular Engineering, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jianrui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Power Engineering, Shanghai Key Laboratory of Intelligent Sensing and Detection Technology, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Pressure Systems and Safety, Ministry of Education, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xuan</LastName><ForeName>Fuzhen</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical and Power Engineering, Shanghai Key Laboratory of Intelligent Sensing and Detection Technology, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Pressure Systems and Safety, Ministry of Education, East China University of Science and Technology, Shanghai 200237, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Research (Wash D C)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101747148</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2639-5274</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41743853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12929815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/research.1120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cano ZP, Banham D, Ye S, Hintennach A, Lu J, Fowler M, Chen Z. Batteries and fuel cells for emerging electric vehicle markets. Nat Energy. 2018;3(4):279&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Yang J, Li L, Zhang J, Wang Z, Wang J, Zhang J. Boron nitride based nanostructure inspired flame retarded thermoplastic polyurethane composites: Comprehensive evaluation and mechanism investigation. Constr Build Mater. 2024;457: Article 139478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Yu K, Xiao P, Li L, Wang C, Wang Z, Guo D, Richard YKK, Lu Y. Killing two birds with one stone strategy inspired advanced batteries with superior thermal safety: A comprehensive evaluation. Chem Eng J. 2025;515: Article 163272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wang C, Sun R, Han C, Li K, Zhang L, Zhang Y, Guo D, Li S, Wang Z, et al. Thermal runaway and jet flame features of 314 ah lithium iron phosphate battery: Mechanism exploration and safety assessment. Appl Therm Eng. 2025;272: Article 126371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palac&#xed;n MR, De Guibert A. Why do batteries fail? Science. 2016;351(6273):1253292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26912708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Yang J, Bai W, Wang Z, Yu K, Lu Y, Han C. Thermal runaway and jet flame features of LIBs undergone high-rate charge/discharge: An investigation. J Energy Chem. 2025;103:826&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drame O, Yahya Z, Sarr A, Mbow C. Soumbedjioune tunnel in Dakar: A case study for CFD modeling of fire-smoke extraction in a sinusoidal floor tunnel. Emergency management. Sci Technol. 2024;4(1): 10.48130/emst-0024-0011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48130/emst-0024-0011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye J, Huang J, Kuang J, Tang J, Liu C, Li R, Tan G. Data-driven methods for early warning of battery thermal runaway: A review of multi-signal fusion and machine learning approaches. J Energy Storage. 2025;133: Article 118043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Ping P, Dai X, Li C, Li Z, Zhuo P, Tang L, Kong D, Yin X. Failure mechanism and thermal runaway behavior of lithium-ion battery induced by arc faults. Renew Sust Energ Rev. 2025;207: Article 114914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Cao Y, Wang Z, Zhao Y, He C, Zhao F, Han C, Yu S. Superior and safer lithium sulfur batteries realized by robust polysulfides-retarding dam with high flame retardance. J Energy Chem. 2024;89:471&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zhu M, Chen M. Comprehensive experimental research on wrapping materials influences on the thermal runaway of lithium-ion batteries. Emerg Manag Sci Technol. 2025;5(1): https://doi.org/10.48130/emst-0025-0005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren D, Feng X, Liu L, Hsu H, Lu L, Wang L, He X, Ouyang M. Investigating the relationship between internal short circuit and thermal runaway of lithium-ion batteries under thermal abuse condition. Energy Storage Mater. 2021;34:563&#x2013;573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z, Wang Z, Liu P, Qin Z, Chen Y, Han Y, Wang P, Bauer P. An online data-driven fault diagnosis and thermal runaway early warning for electric vehicle batteries. IEEE Trans Power Electron. 2022;37(10):12636&#x2013;12646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento M, Ferreira MS, Pinto JL. Real time thermal monitoring of lithium batteries with fiber sensors and thermocouples: A comparative study. Measurement. 2017;111:260&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Y, Darst J, Surelia A, Delafuente D, Finegan DP, Xu J. Deformation and fracture behaviors of cylindrical battery shell during thermal runaway. J Power Sources. 2022;539: Article 231607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan J, Tang X, Dai H, Yang Y, Wu W, Wei X, Huang Y. Building safe lithium-ion batteries for electric vehicles: A review. Electrochem Energy Rev. 2020;3(1):1&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng X, Berecibar M. Emerging sensor technologies and physics-guided methods for monitoring automotive lithium-based batteries. Commun Eng. 2025;4(1):44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11897319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40069374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Albero Blanquer L, Bonefacino J, Logan ER, Dalla Corte DA, Delacourt C, Gallant BM, Boles ST, Dahn JR, Tam H-Y, et al. Operando decoding of chemical and thermal events in commercial Na(Li)-ion cells via optical sensors. Nat Energy. 2020;5(9):674&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei W, Liu Z, Wang C, Wu C, Liu Y, Liu P, Xia X, Xue X, Han X, Sun J, et al. Operando monitoring of thermal runaway in commercial lithium-ion cells via advanced lab-on-fiber technologies. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):5251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10462619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37640698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal-Junior AG, D&#xed;az CAR, Frizera A, Marques C, Ribeiro MRN, Pontes MJ. Simultaneous measurement of pressure and temperature with a single FBG embedded in a polymer diaphragm. Opt Laser Technol. 2019;112:177&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J, Liu C, Li N, Yang L, Yang XG, Dou B, Hou S, Feng X, Jiang H, Li H, et al. Wireless transmission of internal hazard signals in Li-ion batteries. Nature. 2025;641(8063):639&#x2013;645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40369137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Zhao W, Ma Y, Yao Y, Yu T, Zhang W, Guo H, Duan X, Yan R, Xu D, et al. A flexible integrated temperature-pressure sensor for wearable detection of thermal runaway in lithium batteries. Appl Energy. 2025;381: Article 125191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J, Zhao X, Ma J, Meng D, Zhu J, Zhang J, Yan S, Zhang K, Han Z. Enhancing lithium-ion battery monitoring: A critical review of diverse sensing approaches. eTransportation. 2024;22: Article 100360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han S, Alvi NUH, Granl&#xf6;f L, Granberg H, Berggren M, Fabiano S, Crispin X. A multiparameter pressure&#x2013;temperature&#x2013;humidity sensor based on mixed ionic&#x2013;electronic cellulose aerogels. Adv Sci. 2019;6(8):1802128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta J, Gong Z-Y, Mitra A, Liu C-P. Enormous enhancement of thermoelectric properties via piezo-gating effect. Nano Energy. 2023;108: Article 108246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Wang Z, Li Q, Wang Y, Xiao B, Gao Y, Zhu M, Xuan F. All laser micro-fabrication of stretchable sensors. IEEE Sensors J. 2025;25(17):33429&#x2013;33436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin S, Liu J, Cong B. Review of thermal runaway monitoring, warning and protection technologies for lithium-ion batteries. PRO. 2023;11(8):2345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mier FA. Fluid dynamics of lithium ion battery venting failures [thesis]. Socorro (NM): New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olthuis W, Streekstra W, Bergveld P. Theoretical and experimental determination of cell constants of planar-interdigitated electrolyte conductivity sensors. Sensors Actuators B Chem. 1995;24(1):252&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinita VS, Rao RGS, Samuel J, Shabna S, Joslin Ananth N, Shajin Shinu PM, Suresh S, Samson Y, Biju CS. Structural, Raman and optical investigations of barium titanate nanoparticles. Phosphorus Sulfur Silicon Relat Elem. 2022;197(3):169&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao Y, Tondare VN, Davis CS, Gorham JM, Petersen EJ, Gilman JW, Scott K, Vlad&#xe1;r AE, Walker ARH. Comparative study of multiwall carbon nanotube nanocomposites by Raman, SEM, and XPS measurement techniques. Compos Sci Technol. 2021;208: Article 108753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D, Dixit A, Dobal PS. 
Structural, dielectric and ferroelectric characterizations of sol-gel prepared Ba<sub>1-x</sub>Sr<sub>x</sub>TiO<sub>3</sub> nanoceramics. IOP Conf Series Mater Sci Eng. 2022;1272(1):
Article 012026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma PK, Chung JY. Evaluation of polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) as a substrate for the realization of flexible/wearable antennas and sensors. Micromachines. 2023;14(4):735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10143187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37420968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorp JS, Evans D, Al-Naief M, Akhtaruzzaman M. The dielectric properties of aluminium nitride substrates for microelectronics packaging. J Mater Sci. 1990;25(12):4965&#x2013;4971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Zhang J, Wu Y, Xiong X, Yang J, Dickey MD. Liquid metal interdigitated capacitive strain sensor with normal stress insensitivity. Adv Intell Syst. 2022;4(4):2100201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner DW, Charles G, Nguyen T, Javey A, Fahad HM. 
Mitigating lithium-ion cell thermal runaway via selective trace H<sup>2</sup> sensing. Cell Rep Phys Sci. 2025;6(10):
Article 102859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C-H, Chou T-C, Chen W-C, Niu J-S, Lin K-W, Cheng S-Y, Tsai J-H, Liu W-C. 
Study of a WO<sub>3</sub> thin film based hydrogen gas sensor decorated with platinum nanoparticles. Sensors Actuators B Chem. 2020;317:
Article 128145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Q, Zhang Y, Tang M, Wang Z, Zhang D. 
A fast response hydrogen sensor based on the heterojunction of MXene and SnO<sub>2</sub> nanosheets for lithium-ion battery failure detection. Sensors Actuators B Chem. 2024;405:
Article 135229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malepe L, Ndinteh DT, Ndungu P, Mamo MA. Selective detection of methanol vapour from a multicomponent gas mixture using a CNPs/ZnO@ZIF-8 based room temperature solid-state sensor. RSC Adv. 2022;12(42):27094&#x2013;27108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9501866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36276012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain S, Rohit, Kaur S, Katoch A, Jamwal D. (2024). 2D-MoS<sub>2</sub> and WS<sub>2</sub>-based chemical gas sensor. In: Katoch A, Kaur P, Rahul, editors. <i>2D materials. Engineering materials</i>. Singapore: Springer; 2024. p. 21&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin Y, Liu C, Li N, Lyu S, Song W-L, Chen H-S, Jiao S. In-situ monitoring of multiple signals evolution behaviour for commercial lithium-ion batteries during internal short circuit. Appl Energy. 2023;350: Article 121754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y, Zhang B, Fu Y, Shen F, Zheng Q, Chalise D, Miao R, Kaur S, Lubner SD, Tucker MC, et al. Extreme fast charging of commercial Li-ion batteries via combined thermal switching and self-heating approaches. Nat Commun. 2023;14(1):3229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10239438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37270603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomaszewska A, Chu Z, Feng X, O&#x2019;Kane S, Liu X, Chen J, Ji C, Endler E, Li R, Liu L, et al. Lithium-ion battery fast charging: A review. eTransportation. 2019;1: Article 100011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X, Zheng S, Ren D, He X, Wang L, Cui H, Liu X, Jin C, Zhang F, Xu C, et al. Investigating the thermal runaway mechanisms of lithium-ion batteries based on thermal analysis database. Appl Energy. 2019;246:53&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Sun J, Yao X, He X, Wang L, Cui H, Liu X, Jin C, Zhang F, Xu C, et al. Thermal behavior of lithiated graphite with electrolyte in lithium-ion batteries. J Electrochem Soc. 2006;153(2):A329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa CM, Lee Y-H, Kim J-H, Lee S-Y, Lanceros-M&#xe9;ndez S. Recent advances on separator membranes for lithium-ion battery applications: From porous membranes to solid electrolytes. Energy Storage Mater. 2019;22:346&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran M-K, Fowler M. A review of lithium-ion battery fault diagnostic algorithms: Current progress and future challenges. Algorithms. 2020;13(3):62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu K-C, Lin C-H, Yeh S-F, Lin Y-H, Chen K-C. An electrochemical modeling of lithium-ion battery nail penetration. J Power Sources. 2014;251:254&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J-Y, Xia C, Wang H-F, Tang C. Recent advances in electrocatalytic oxygen reduction for on-site hydrogen peroxide synthesis in acidic media. J Energy Chem. 2022;67:432&#x2013;450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong T, Duan X, Shan Y, Huang L. Gas generation in lithium-ion batteries: Mechanisms, failure pathways, and thermal safety implications. Batteries. 2025;11(4):152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Ding T, Xiao B, Gao Y, Xiang Y, Xuan F. Laser micro-fabricated multifunctional sensing layer for structural health monitoring. Smart Mater Struct. 2023;32(9): Article 095008.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>