<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41408386</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AI-driven drone technology and computer vision for early detection of crop disease in large agricultural areas.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2479</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2479</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2479</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-32384-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Timely detection of crop diseases in large, heterogeneous agricultural fields is difficult, as aerial imagery is often corrupted by illumination, weather, and crop-stage variations. This paper introduces AgroVisionNet, an AI-powered drone and computer vision approach that synthesises high-resolution drone imagery with in-field IoT/environmental sensor data to enhance early disease detection. The core of the proposed model is a hybrid CNN-Transformer backbone to extract spatial and contextual data from drone images, and an adaptive fusion layer to fuse time-aligned sensor readings and to make a decision, using visual and environmental evidence. Particularly, a multimodal drone&#x2013;sensor dataset is collected across multiple crops and field conditions. Beyond widely used deep models for plant/crop disease identification, such as VGG16, ResNet50, Inception V3, and DenseNet121, experiments are conducted using the same training and evaluation framework. It is shown that AgroVisionNet achieves higher classification accuracy and F1-score, while inference remains feasible on an NVIDIA Jetson Nano using TensorFlow Lite. Moreover, by generating Grad-CAM plots, the study demonstrates that the proposed approach identifies disease-affected areas and, in this sense, provides interpretable information required by agronomists. These outcomes suggest that AI-based crop health tracking can be robust and field-ready by integrating drone imagery, sensor fusion, and edge computing.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manoj</LastName><ForeName>H M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, BMS Institute of Technology and Management, Autonomous under VTU, Bengaluru, Karnataka, 560119, India. manoj.hmhm@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shanthi</LastName><ForeName>D L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, BMS Institute of Technology and Management, Bangalore, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lakshmi</LastName><ForeName>B N</ForeName><Initials>BN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, BMS Institute of Technology and Management, Bangalore, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Archana</LastName><ForeName>K J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science Engineering, Neil Gogte Institute of Technology, Uppal, Hyderabad, Telangana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venkata Naga Jyothi</LastName><ForeName>Endluri</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of (AI&amp;ML), CMR College of Engineering &amp; Technology, Hyderabad, Telangana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Archana</LastName><ForeName>Kande</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of CSE Malla Reddy College of Engineering, Hyderabad, Telangana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Crop disease detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Edge computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IoT integration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Precision agriculture</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Consent for publication: The authors give consent for their publication. Ethical approval: This research does not involve humans or animals, so no ethical approval is required.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41408386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12820128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-32384-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-32384-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hicham Slimani1, Jamal El Mhamdi1 and Abdelilah Jilbab. Drone-Assisted plant disease identification using artificial intelligence: A critical review. <i>Int. J. Comput. Digit. Syst.</i><b>14</b> (1), 1&#x2013;14 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas, A. et al. Drones in Plant Disease Assessment, Efficient Monitoring, and Detection A Way Forward to Smart Agriculture. <i>Agronomy</i><b>13</b> (6), 1524 (2023). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy13061524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purnama, S. &amp; Sejati, W. Internet of things, big data, and artificial intelligence in the food and agriculture sector. <i>Int. Trans. Artif. Intell.</i><b>1</b> (2), 156&#x2013;174 (2023). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra, N. N. et al. IoT, big data, and artificial intelligence in agriculture and food industry. <i>IEEE Internet things J.</i><b>9</b> (9), 6305&#x2013;6324 (2020). 10.1109/JIOT.2020.2998584</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchelt, A. et al. Exploring artificial intelligence for applications of drones in forest ecology and management. <i>Ecol. Manag</i>. <b>551</b>, 121530 (2024). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta, P. K. &amp; Mitra, S. Application of agricultural drones and IoT to understand food supply chain during post COVID&#x2010;19. <i>Agricultural informatics: automation using the IoT and machine learning</i>, <b>67</b>, 1&#x2013;21 . (2021). 10.1002/9781119769231.ch4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velusamy, P. et al. Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAV) in precision agriculture: Applications and challenges. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b> (1), 217 (2021). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15010217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanaliyeva, G., Si Ammour, M., Yaseen, T., Rossi, V. &amp; Caffi, T. Innovations in disease detection and forecasting: a digital roadmap for sustainable management of fruit and foliar disease. <i>Agronomy</i><b>12</b> (7), 1707 (2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doggalli, G. et al. Drone technology for crop disease resistance: Innovations and challenges. <i>J. Sci. Res. Rep.</i><b>30</b> (8), 174&#x2013;180 (2024). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruben Chin1 &#xb7; Cagatay Catal2 &#xb7; Ayalew Kassahun. Plant disease detection using drones in precision agriculture. <i>Precision Agric.</i><b>24(.)</b>, 1663&#x2013;1682 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wani, J. A. et al. Machine learning and deep learning based computational techniques in automatic agricultural diseases detection: Methodologies, applications, and challenges. <i>Arch. Comput. Methods Eng.</i><b>29</b> (1), 641&#x2013;677 (2022). 10.1007/s11831-021-09588-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11831-021-09588-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, D., Sun, Q., Hu, B. &amp; Zhang, S. A framework for agricultural pest and disease monitoring based on internet-of-things and unmanned aerial vehicles. <i>Sensors</i><b>20</b> (5), 1487 (2020). 10.3390/s20051487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7085563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32182732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, S. A. et al. Application of drone surveillance for advance agriculture monitoring by android application using convolution neural network. <i>Agronomy</i><b>13</b> (7), 1764 (2023). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy13071764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahirwar*, S., Swarnkar, R., Bhukya, S. &amp; Namwade, G. Application of drone in agriculture. <i>Int. J. Curr. Microbiol. Appl. Sci.</i><b>8</b> (1), 2500&#x2013;2505 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20546/ijcmas.2019.801.264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopal Dutta and Purba Goswami. Application of drone in agriculture: A review. <i>Int. J. Chem. Stud.</i><b>8</b> (5), 181&#x2013;187 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22271/chemi.2020.v8.i5d.10529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogili, U. R. &amp; Deepak, B. B. V. L. Review on application of drone systems in precision agriculture. <i>Procedia Comput. Sci.</i><b>133</b>, 502&#x2013;509 (2018). 10.1016/j.procs.2018.07.063</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvesh Kumar, Pal, K., Durgesh, K., Maurya, J., MONITORING &amp; AND DETECTION SMART AGRICULTURE USE IN DRONE TECHNOLOGY. . DISEASE ASSESSMENT,. Social science journal. 13(2), 1&#x2013;12. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puri, V., Nayyar, A. &amp; Raja, L. Agriculture drones: A modern breakthrough in precision agriculture. <i>J. Stat. Manage. Syst.</i><b>20</b> (4), 507&#x2013;518 (2017). 10.1080/09720510.2017.1395171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena, A., Tejada, J. C., Gonzalez-Ruiz, J. D. &amp; Gongora, M. Deep learning to improve the sustainability of agricultural crops affected by phytosanitary events: A financial-risk approach. <i>Sustainability</i><b>14</b> (11), 6668 (2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackulin, C. &amp; Murugavalli, S. A comprehensive review on detection of plant disease using machine learning and deep learning approaches. <i>Measurement: Sens.</i><b>24</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, A., Saraswat, D. &amp; Gamal, E. A A survey on using deep learning techniques for plant disease diagnosis and recommendations for development of appropriate tools. <i>Smart Agricultural Technol.</i><b>3</b>, 100083 (2023). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavithra, A., Kalpana, G., Vigneswaran, T. &amp; RETRACTED, A. R. T. I. C. L. E. Deep learning-based automated disease detection and classification model for precision agriculture. <i>Soft Comput.</i><b>28</b> (Suppl 2), 463&#x2013;463 (2024). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anna Kowalska and Hadeed Ashraf. Advances in deep learning algorithms for agricultural monitoring and management. <i>Appl. Res. Artif. Intell. Cloud Comput.</i><b>4</b> (1), 1&#x2013;21 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latif, G., Abdelhamid, S. E., Mallouhy, R. E., Alghazo, J. &amp; Kazimi, Z. A. Deep learning utilization in agriculture: Detection of rice plant diseases using an improved CNN model. <i>Plants</i><b>11</b> (17), 2230 (2022). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9460897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36079612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamilaris, A. &amp; Prenafeta-Bold&#xfa;, Francesc, X. Deep learning in agriculture: A survey. <i>Comput. Electron. Agric.</i><b>147</b>, 70&#x2013;90 (2018). 10.1016/j.compag.2018.02.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai, Y., Sun, C., Tie, J. &amp; Cai, X. Research on recognition model of crop diseases and insect pests based on deep learning in harsh environments. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>8()</b>, 171686&#x2013;171693. 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3025325 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3025325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, C. et al. Early detection of plant viral disease using hyperspectral imaging and deep learning. <i>Sensors</i><b>21</b> (3), 742 (2021). 10.3390/s21030742</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7866105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33499335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferentinos, K. P. Deep learning models for plant disease detection and diagnosis. <i>Comput. Electron. Agric.</i><b>145</b>, 311&#x2013;318 (2018). 10.1016/j.compag.2018.01.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. H., Go&#xc3;&#xab;au, H. &#xc3;., Bonnet, P. &amp; Joly, A. New perspectives on plant disease characterization based on deep learning. <i>Comput. Electron. Agric.</i><b>170</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2020). 10.1016/j.compag.2020.105220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitali, V., Shewale, Rohin, D. &amp; Daruwala High performance deep learning architecture for early detection and classification of plant leaf disease. <i>J. Agric. Food Res.</i><b>14</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmet, A. L. K. A. N., Muhammed &#xdc;same, A. B. D. U. L. L. A. H. &amp; Hanadi Omaish ABDULLAH2 and Muhammed. A smart agricultural application: automated detection of diseases in vine leaves using hybrid deep learning. <i>Turkish J. Agric. Forestry</i>. <b>45(.)</b>, 717&#x2013;729 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ale, L., Sheta, A., Li, L., Wang, Y. &amp; Zhang, N. Deep Learning Based Plant Disease Detection for Smart Agriculture, IEEE, pp.1&#x2013;6. (2019). 10.1109/GCWkshps45667.2019.90</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatih Bal and Fatih Kayaalp. Review of machine learning and deep learning models in agriculture. <i>Int. Adv. RESEARCHES Eng. J.</i><b>5</b> (2), 309&#x2013;323 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35860/iarej.848458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parez, S., Dilshad, N., Alanazi, T. M. &amp; Lee, J. W. Towards Sustainable Agricultural Systems: A Lightweight Deep Learning Model for Plant Disease Detection. <i>Comput. Syst. Sci. Eng.</i><b>47</b> (1), 515&#x2013;536 (2023). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waleed Albattah1, Javed, A. 2, Nawaz, M. 2 &amp; Momina Masood2 and Saleh Albahl. Artificial Intelligence-Based drone system for multiclass plant disease detection using an improved efficient convolutio. <i>Front. Plant Sci.</i><b>13</b>, 1&#x2013;16 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9218756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35755664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafar, A., Bibi, N., Naqvi, R. A., Sadeghi-Niaraki, A. &amp; Jeong, D. Revolutionizing agriculture with artificial intelligence: plant disease detection methods, applications, and their limitations. <i>Front. Plant Sci.</i><b>15</b>, 1356260 (2024). 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2024.1356260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10965613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38545388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pa&#xe7;al, &#x130;. et al. A systematic review of deep learning techniques for plant diseases. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>57</b>, 304. 10.1007/s10462-024-10944-7 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-024-10944-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacal, I. Enhancing crop productivity and sustainability through disease identification in maize leaves: exploiting a large dataset. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>238</b> (15), 122099. 10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122099 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacal, I. et al. Efficient and autonomous detection of Olive leaf diseases using AI-enhanced metaformer. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>58</b>, 303. 10.1007/s10462-025-11131-y (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-025-11131-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundurac&#x131;o&#x11f;lu, &#x130;. &amp; Pa&#xe7;al, &#x130;. Advancements in deep learning for accurate classification of grape leaves and diagnosis of grape diseases. <i>J. Plant Dis. Prot.</i><b>131</b> (4), 1061&#x2013;1080. 10.1007/s41348-024-00896-z (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41348-024-00896-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shandilya, G. et al. Enhanced maize leaf disease detection and classification using hybrid CNN-ViT model. <i>Food Sci. Nutr.</i>10.1002/fsn3.70513 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/fsn3.70513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12208913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40599357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacal, I. &amp; I&#x15f;&#x131;k, G. Utilizing convolutional neural networks and vision Transformers for precise corn leaf disease identification. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>37</b>, 2479&#x2013;2496. 10.1007/s00521-024-10769-z (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-024-10769-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q., Liu, Y., Gong, C., Chen, Y. &amp; Yu, H. Applications of Deep Learning for Dense Scenes Analysis in Agriculture: A Review. <i>Sensors</i><b>20</b> (5), 1&#x2013;33 (2020). 10.3390/s20051520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7085505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32164200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altalak, M., Ammad uddin, M., Alajmi, A. &amp; Rizg, A. Smart agriculture applications using deep learning technologies: A survey. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>12</b> (12), 5919 (2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H., Gao, L., Tang, N. &amp; Yang, P. Experimental analysis and evaluation of wide residual networks based agricultural disease identification in smart agriculture system. <i>EURASIP J. Wirel. Commun. Netw.</i><b>2019 (1)</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2019). 10.1186/s13638-019-1613-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sambasivam, G. A. O. G. D. &amp; Opiyo, G. D. A predictive machine learning application in agriculture: Cassava disease detection and classification with imbalanced dataset using convolutional neural networks. <i>Egypt. Inf. J.</i><b>22</b> (1), 27&#x2013;34 (2021). 10.1016/j.eij.2020.02.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y. Y., Kong, J. L., Jin, X. B., Wang, X. Y. &amp; Zuo, M. CropDeep: The Crop Vision Dataset for Deep-Learning-Based Classification and Detection in Precision Agriculture. <i>Sensors</i><b>19</b> (5), 1&#x2013;21 (2019). 10.3390/s19051058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6427818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, Y., Chen, L., Wu, H. &amp; Li, L. Advanced agricultural disease image recognition technologies: A review. <i>Inform. Process. Agric.</i><b>9</b>, 48&#x2013;59 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alibabaei, K. et al. A review of the challenges of using deep learning algorithms to support decision-making in agricultural activities. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>14</b> (3), 638 (2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boukhris, L., Ben Abderrazak, J. &amp; Besbes, H. <i>Tailored Deep Learning based Architecture for Smart Agriculture, IEEE, pp.964&#x2013;969.</i> (2020). 10.1109/IWCMC48107.2020.91481</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun Liu;Xuewei Wang. <i>Plant diseases and pests detection based on deep learning: a review. Plant Methods, pp.1&#x2013;18.</i> (2021). 10.1186/s13007-021-00722-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33627131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulibaly, S., Kamsu-Foguem, B., Kamissoko, D. &amp; D Deep learning for precision agriculture: A bibliometric analysis. <i>Intell. Syst. Appl.</i><b>16</b>, 1&#x2013;18 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, C., Kim, D. K. &amp; Jeong, D. A survey of deep learning in agriculture: techniques and their applications. <i>J. Inf. Process. Syst.</i><b>16</b> (5), 1015&#x2013;1033 (2020). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallab Bharman, S. A., Saad, S., Khan &amp; Israt Jahan and Milon Ra. Deep learning in agriculture: A review. <i>Asian J. Res. Comput. Sci.</i><b>13</b> (2), 28&#x2013;47 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ajrcos/2022/v13i230311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D. et al. A review of deep learning in multiscale agricultural sensing. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>14</b> (3), 559 (2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang,C. et al. A review of deep learning used in the hyperspectral image analysis for agriculture. <i>Artif. Intell. Rev.</i><b>54</b> (7), 5205&#x2013;5253 (2021). 10.1007/s10462-021-10018-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-021-10018-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao,Y. et al. An effective automatic system deployed in agricultural Internet of Things using Multi-Context Fusion Network towards crop disease recognition in the wild. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>89</b>, 106128 (2020). 10.1016/j.asoc.2020.106128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2020.106128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma,P., Berwal, Y. P. S. &amp; Ghai, W. Performance analysis of deep learning CNN models for disease detection in plants using image segmentation. <i>Inform. Process. Agric.</i><b>7</b> (4), 566&#x2013;574 (2020). 10.1016/j.inpa.2019.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inpa.2019.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang,Z., Liu, H., Meng, Z. &amp; Chen, J. Deep learning-based automatic recognition network of agricultural machinery images. <i>Comput. Electron. Agric.</i><b>166</b>, 104978 (2019). 10.1016/j.compag.2019.104978</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2019.104978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan,R. I., Yusuf, S. M. &amp; Alzubaidi, L. Review of the state of the art of deep learning for plant diseases: A broad analysis and discussion. <i>Plants</i><b>9</b> (10), 1302 (2020). 10.3390/plants9101302
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants9101302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33019765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmalek Bouguettaya, H., Zarzour, A., Kechida &amp; Amine Mohammed Taber. Deep learning techniques to classify agricultural crops through UAV imagery a review. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>34</b>, 9511&#x2013;9536 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-022-07104-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8898032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35281624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Amin, M., Karim, D. Z., Bushra &amp; Tasfia Anika. <i>Prediction of Rice Disease from Leaves using Deep Convolution Neural Network towards a Digital Agricultural System, IEEE, pp.1&#x2013;10.</i> (2019). 10.1109/iccit48885.2019.90382</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihar Ranjan Pradhan1, Hritwik Ghosh1, Rahat, I. S. &amp; Janjhyam Venkata, N. Enhancing agricultural sustainability with deep learning: A case study of cauliflower disease classification. <i>EAI Endorsed Transactionson Internet Thin</i>. <b>10</b>, 1&#x2013;8 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakhmatulin, I., Kamilaris, A. &amp; Andreasen, C. Deep neural networks to detect weeds from crops in agricultural environments in real-time: A review. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>13</b> (21), 4486 (2021). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13214486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ya&#x11f;, &#x130;. &amp; Altan, A. Artificial intelligence-based robust hybrid algorithm design and implementation for real-time detection of plant diseases in agricultural environments. <i>Biology</i><b>11</b> (12), 1732 (2022). 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology11121732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9775035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36552243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkamahadevi, C. &amp; Adaickalam, V. An effective deep learning framework for diseases prediction to enrich paddy production. <i>Int. J. Syst. Assur. Eng. Manage.</i><b>16</b> (11), 3685&#x2013;3694 (2025). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13198-025-02885-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neupane, K. &amp; Baysal-Gurel, F. Automatic identification and monitoring of plant diseases using unmanned aerial vehicles: A review. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>13</b> (19), 3841 (2021). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhanya, V. G., Subeesh, A. &amp; Kushwaha, N. L. Deep learning based computer vision approaches for smart agricultural applications. <i>Artif. Intell. Agric.</i><b>6</b>, 211&#x2013;229 (2022). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., Zhang, S. &amp; Wang, B. Plant disease detection and classification by deep learning&#x2014;a review. <i>IEEE access.</i><b>9</b>, 56683&#x2013;56698 (2021). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3069646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Materne, N. &amp; Inoue, M. <i>IoT Monitoring System for Early Detection of Agricultural Pests and Diseases, IEEE, pp.1&#x2013;5.</i> (2018). 10.1109/SEATUC.2018.8788860</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bini Darwin;Pamela Dharmaraj;Shajin Prince;Daniela Elena Popescu;Duraisamy Jude Hemanth. <i>Recognition of Bloom/Yield in Crop Images Using Deep Learning Models for Smart Agriculture: A Review. Agronomy, pp.1&#x2013;22.</i> (2021). 10.3390/agronomy11040646</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez, D. et al. Advancing common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L.) disease detection with YOLO driven deep learning to enhance agricultural AI. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b> (1), 15596 (2024). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11227504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38971939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fountsop,A. N., Fendji, E. K., Atemkeng, M. &amp; J. L., &amp; Deep learning models compression for agricultural plants. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>10</b> (19), 6866 (2020). 10.3390/app10196866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10196866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storey, G., Meng, Q. &amp; Li, B. Leaf disease segmentation and detection in apple orchards for precise smart spraying in sustainable agriculture. <i>Sustainability</i><b>14</b> (3), 1458 (2022). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14031458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ChauChung Song;ChihLun Wang;YiFeng Yang. <i>Automatic Detection and Image Recognition of Precision Agriculture for Citrus Diseases. 2020 IEEE Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering (ECICE), pp.1&#x2013;4.</i> (2020). 10.1109/ecice50847.2020.93019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph, K. &amp; Mhango;Edwin, W. Harris;Richard Green;James M. Monaghan;. <i>Mapping Potato Plant Density Variation Using Aerial Imagery and Deep Learning Techniques for Precision Agriculture. Remote Sensing, pp.1&#x2013;17.</i> (2021). 10.3390/rs13142705</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jashraj Karnik and Dr. Anil Suthar. Agricultural Plant Leaf Disease Detection Using Deep Learning Techniques. <i>International Conference on Communication and Information Processing</i>, pp.1&#x2013;7. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer, A. et al. <i>Combining computer vision and deep learning to enable ultra-scale aerial phenotyping and precision agriculture: A case study of lettuce production. Horticulture Research, 6(1), pp.1&#x2013;12.</i> (2019). 10.1038/s41438-019-0151-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31231528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenneth Li-Minn Ang;Jasmine Kah Phooi Seng. <i>Big Data and Machine Learning With Hyperspectral Information in Agriculture. IEEE Access, pp.1&#x2013;20.</i> (2021). 10.1109/access.2021.3051196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey, A. &amp; Shanmugasudaram, M. Agricultural plant disease detection and identification. <i>Int. J. Electr. Eng. Technol. (IJEET)</i>. <b>11</b> (3), 354&#x2013;363 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isiaka, A. B. et al. Harnessing artificial intelligence for early detection and management of infectious disease outbreaks. <i>Int. J. Innovative Res. Dev.</i><b>13</b> (2), 1&#x2013;14 (2024). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatti, M. A. et al. Advanced Plant Disease Segmentation in Precision Agriculture using Optimal Dimensionality Reduction with Fuzzy C-Means C. <i>IEEE</i>, pp.1&#x2013;14. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahi, T. B., Xu, C. Y., Neupane, A. &amp; Guo, W. Recent advances in crop disease detection using UAV and deep learning techniques. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>15</b> (9), 2450 (2023). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15092450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prayaga Siddappa. Artificial intelligence based drone controlled detection of plant disease. <i>Int. J. Creative Res. Thoughts (IJCRT)</i>. <b>6</b> (2), 1&#x2013;4 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Av&#x15f;ar, E. &amp; Mowla, M. N. Wireless communication protocols in smart agriculture: A review on applications, challenges and future trends. <i>Ad Hoc Netw.</i><b>136</b>, 102982 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.adhoc.2022.102982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mowla, M. N. &amp; G&#xf6;k, M. Weeds detection networks. 2021 Innovations in Intelligent Systems and Applications Conference (ASYU). IEEE. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, M. &amp; Le, Q. V. EfficientNetV2: Smaller Models and Faster Training. <i>Proceedings of the 38th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2021)</i>, PMLR 139:10096&#x2013;10106. (2021). https://arxiv.org/abs/2104.00298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Swin Transformer: Hierarchical Vision Transformer using Shifted Windows. <i>IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV 2021)</i>, 10012&#x2013;10022. (2021). 10.1109/ICCV48922.2021.00986</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis, M. &amp; Deisy, C. <i>Disease Detection and Classification in Agricultural Plants Using Convolutional Neural Networks &#x2014; A Visual Understanding, IEEE, pp.1063&#x2013;1068.</i> (2019). 10.1109/SPIN.2019.8711701</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>