<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41601471</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2813-0146</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in health services</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Health Serv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The power of researcher-practitioner partnerships in implementation science: a community case study in sexual violence prevention program evaluation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1700115</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1700115</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1700115</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/frhs.2025.1700115</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Many institutions of higher education recognize the importance of sexual violence prevention efforts. However, often practitioners tasked with offering prevention efforts lack the time and expertise to assess programs. Researcher-practitioner partnerships offer a solution that provides mutual benefits and is reinforced by implementation science. Through our own experiences in a six-year collaboration between a university research center and a small private college's sexual violence prevention team we discovered the value of researcher-practitioner partnerships. Our partnership focused on evaluating a multi-year, required sexual violence prevention curriculum, currently implementing best-practice skill-building and prevention-techniques for college students at a small private college. Robust evaluation efforts, made possible through the researcher-practitioner partnership, have been essential in gaining key insights and making data-informed improvements to ensure effectiveness of the curriculum. The manuscript provides background on the importance of sexual violence prevention on college campuses and how implementation science and effective researcher-practitioner partnerships can address challenges. Findings from the evaluation project will be shared in future publications, allowing this article to focus on best practices, methodology, and lessons learned related to the researcher-practitioner partnership that align with key implementation science constructs. We aim to offer actionable methods and strategies for other researchers, evaluators, and practitioners to strengthen prevention efforts in higher education settings and beyond.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Barthelmes, Childress, Gillis, Lee and Stapleton.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barthelmes</LastName><ForeName>Caitlin K</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Wellness Center, Health and Wellness Division, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Childress</LastName><ForeName>Amanda</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Wellness Center, Health and Wellness Division, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillis</LastName><ForeName>Dawn E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Wellness Center, Health and Wellness Division, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Chaehyun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Wellness Center, Health and Wellness Division, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stapleton</LastName><ForeName>Jane G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prevention Innovations Research Center, University of New Hampshire, Durham, NH, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Health Serv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918334887706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2813-0146</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">higher education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">program evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">researcher-practitioner partnership</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sexual violence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41601471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12833006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frhs.2025.1700115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McMahon S, Wood L, Cusano J, Macri LM. Campus sexual assault: future directions for research. Sex Abuse. (2019) 31(3):270&#x2013;95. 10.1177/1079063217750864</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1079063217750864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29320942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile KC, DeGue S, Jones K, Freire K, Dills J, Smith SG, et al. 
STOP SV: a technical package to prevent sexual violence. Atlanta, GA: National Center for Injury Prevention and Control, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (U.S.) (2016). p. 1&#x2013;43. Available online at: https://stacks.cdc.gov/view/cdc/39126 (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeGue S, Fowler D, Randall A. Preventing sexual violence on college and university campuses: lessons from research and practice. Atlanta, GA: National Center for Injury Prevention and Control (U.S.). Division of Violence Prevention, United States. Department of Justice;  (2014). p. 1&#x2013;40. Available online at: https://stacks.cdc.gov/view/cdc/43896 (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantor D, Fisher B, Chibnall S, Harps S, Townsend R. Report on the AAU Campus Climate Survey on Sexual Assault and Misconduct: The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Available online at:
https://safe.unc.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/1110/2020/06/University-of-North-Carolina-at-Chapel-Hill_Report-and-Appendices-.pdf
(Accessed November 24, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantor D, Fisher B, Chibnall S, Harps S, Townsend R. Report on the AAU Climate Survey on Sexual Assault and Sexual Misconduct. Available online at:
https://www.nsvrc.org/resource/report-aau-climate-survey-sexual-assault-and-sexual-misconduct/
(Accessed November 24, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griner SB, Vamos CA, Thompson EL, Logan R, V&#xe1;zquez-Otero C, Daley EM. The intersection of gender identity and violence: victimization experienced by transgender college students. J Interpers Violence. (2020) 35(23&#x2013;24):5704&#x2013;25. 10.1177/0886260517723743</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260517723743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein LB, Dawes HC, James G, Hall WJ, Rizo CF, Potter SJ, et al. Sexual and relationship violence among LGBTQ+ college students: a scoping review. Trauma Violence Abuse. (2023) 24(4):2196&#x2013;209. 10.1177/15248380221089981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15248380221089981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35465778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothman EF, Exner D, Baughman AL. The prevalence of sexual assault against people who identify as gay, lesbian, or bisexual in the United States: a systematic review. Trauma Violence Abuse. (2011) 12(2):55&#x2013;66. 10.1177/1524838010390707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524838010390707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21247983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiding MJ, Chen J, Walters ML. The national intimate partner and sexual violence survey (NISVS); 2010 findings on victimization by sexual orientation. Atlanta, GA: National Center for Injury Prevention and Control (U.S.) D of V Prevention;  (2013). p. 1&#x2013;87. Available online at: https://stacks.cdc.gov/view/cdc/12362 (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas KM, Balbo J, Duval K, Beverly EA. Neurobiology of sexual assault and osteopathic considerations for trauma-informed care and practice. JAOA J Am Osteopath Assoc. (2018) 118(2):e2&#x2013;10. 10.7556/jaoa.2018.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7556/jaoa.2018.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29227505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullman S, Najdowski C. Correlates of Suicidal Ideation and Attempts in Female Sexual Assault Survivors. Rochester, NY: Social Science Research Network;  (2009). Available online at:
https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=3215929 (Accessed November 24, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullman SE, Relyea M, Peter-Hagene L, Vasquez AL. Trauma histories, substance use coping, PTSD, and problem substance use among sexual assault victims. Addict Behav. (2013) 38(6):2219&#x2013;23. 10.1016/j.addbeh.2013.01.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2013.01.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3622163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23501138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;vesque S, Rodrigue C, Beaulieu-Pr&#xe9;vost D, Blais M, Boislard MA, L&#xe9;vy JJ. Intimate partner violence, sexual assault, and reproductive health among university women. Can J Hum Sex. (2016) 25(1):9&#x2013;20. 10.3138/cjhs.251-A5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3138/cjhs.251-A5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banyard VL, Demers JM, Cohn ES, Edwards KM, Moynihan MM, Walsh WA, et al. Academic correlates of unwanted sexual contact, intercourse, stalking, and intimate partner violence: an understudied but important consequence for college students. J Interpers Violence. (2020) 35(21&#x2013;22):4375&#x2013;92. 10.1177/0886260517715022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260517715022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengo C, Black BM. Violence victimization on a college campus: impact on GPA and school dropout. J Coll Stud Retent Res Theory Pract. (2016) 18(2):234&#x2013;48. 10.1177/1521025115584750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1521025115584750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin H, Uggen C, Blackstone A. The economic and career effects of sexual harassment on working women. Gend Soc. (2017) 31(3):333&#x2013;58. 10.1177/0891243217704631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0891243217704631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29056822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson C, DeGue S, Florence C, Lokey CN. Lifetime economic burden of rape among U.S. adults. Am J Prev Med. (2017) 52(6):691&#x2013;701. 10.1016/j.amepre.2016.11.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2016.11.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5438753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter S, Howard R, Murphy S, Moynihan MM. Long-term impacts of college sexual assaults on women survivors&#x2019; educational and career attainments. J Am Coll Health. (2018) 66(6):496&#x2013;507. 10.1080/07448481.2018.1440574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2018.1440574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29447618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards KM, Sylaska KM. The perpetration of intimate partner violence among LGBTQ college youth: the role of minority stress. J Youth Adolesc. (2013) 42(11):1721&#x2013;31. 10.1007/s10964-012-9880-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10964-012-9880-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23233160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mennicke A, Geiger E, Brewster M. Interpersonal violence prevention considerations for sexual minority college students: lower campus connection, worse perceptions of institutional support, and more accurate understandings of sexual consent. J Fam Violence. (2020) 35(6):589&#x2013;601. 10.1007/s10896-019-00089-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10896-019-00089-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer IH. Prejudice, social stress, and mental health in lesbian, gay, and bisexual populations: conceptual issues and research evidence. Psychol Bull. (2003) 129(5):674&#x2013;97. 10.1037/0033-2909.129.5.674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.129.5.674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2072932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12956539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Htun M, Jensenius FR, Dominguez MS, Tinkler J, Contreras C. Effects of mandatory sexual misconduct training on university campuses. Socius. (2022) 8:23780231221124574. 10.1177/23780231221124574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23780231221124574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeGue S, Valle LA, Holt MK, Massetti GM, Matjasko JL, Tharp AT. A systematic review of primary prevention strategies for sexual violence perpetration. Aggress Violent Behav. (2014) 19(4):346&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.avb.2014.05.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.avb.2014.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5875446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29606897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dills J, Fowler D, Payne G. Sexual violence on campus: strategies for prevention. Atlanta, GA: National Center for Injury Prevention and Control (U.S.). Division of Violence Prevention;  (2016). p. 1&#x2013;24. Available online at: https://stacks.cdc.gov/view/cdc/43899 (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ, Aron DC, Keith RE, Kirsh SR, Alexander JA, Lowery JC. Fostering implementation of health services research findings into practice: a consolidated framework for advancing implementation science. Implement Sci. (2009) 4:50. 10.1186/1748-5908-4-50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-4-50</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2736161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19664226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk MA, Kelley C, Yankey N, Birken SA, Abadie B, Damschroder L. A systematic review of the use of the consolidated framework for implementation research. Implement Sci. (2016) 11(1):72. 10.1186/s13012-016-0437-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-016-0437-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4869309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orchowski LM. Advancing sexual assault prevention through implementation science. Psychol Violence. (2024) 14(6):491&#x2013;500. 10.1037/vio0000561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/vio0000561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12456237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40994612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soicher RN, Becker-Blease KA, Bostwick KCP. Adapting implementation science for higher education research: the systematic study of implementing evidence-based practices in college classrooms. Cogn Res. (2020) 5(1):1&#x2013;15. 10.1186/s41235-020-00255-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41235-020-00255-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7644597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33152095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess PM, Mullen EJ. Practitioner-Researcher Partnerships: Building Knowledge from, in, and for Practice. Washington, D.C.: National Association of Social Workers Press; (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan TP, Willie TC, Fisher BS. Highlights and Lowlights of Researcher-Practitioner Collaborations in the Criminal Justice System, Findings from the Researcher-Practitioner Partnerships Study (RPPS). Washington, D.C.: U.S. Department of Justice, National Institute of Justice; (2013). Report No.: 243914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto RM, Spector AY, Rahman R. Nurturing practitioner-researcher partnerships to improve adoption and delivery of research-based social and public health services worldwide. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2019) 16(5):862. 10.3390/ijerph16050862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16050862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6427324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30857292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson JC, Peruggia G, Miller-Walfish S, Talis J, Burrell C, Hayes M, et al. A case series measuring campus and clinic level factors during implementation of a sexual violence prevention intervention in campus health and counseling centers: does environment matter? Implement Sci Commun. (2023) 4(1):88. 10.1186/s43058-023-00467-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43058-023-00467-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37525258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson-Gordon R, Dariotis JK, Fisher BS, Dickman-Burnett V. Implementing sexual violence primary prevention programs: a case study of implementer perspectives. J Youth Dev. (2022) 17(4):126&#x2013;44. 10.5195/jyd.2022.1272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5195/jyd.2022.1272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rycroft-Malone J, Burton C, Wilkinson J, Harvey G, McCormack B, Baker R, et al. Collective action for knowledge mobilisation: a realist evaluation of the collaborations for leadership in applied health research and care. Health Serv Deliv Res. (2015) 3(44):1&#x2013;68. 10.3310/hsdr03440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3310/hsdr03440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26677504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmark M, Markstr&#xf6;m U, Richter Sundberg L, Rosenberg D. Implementing evidence-based practices in rural areas: development and testing of a researcher practitioner collaboration in mental health. J Evid-Based Soc Work. (2025) 22(1):35&#x2013;57. 10.1080/26408066.2024.2430567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/26408066.2024.2430567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39562849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojcik MLT, Rubenstein BY, Petkus AA, Racadio M, Anderson VR, Fisher BS, et al. Coming together in the fight against intimate partner violence: lessons learned from a researcher&#x2013;practitioner collaboration evaluating cincinnati&#x2019;s domestic violence enhanced response team (DVERT). J Contemp Crim Justice. (2021) 37(2):221&#x2013;43. 10.1177/1043986221999861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1043986221999861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell BJ, McMillen JC, Proctor EK, Carpenter CR, Griffey RT, Bunger AC, et al. A compilation of strategies for implementing clinical innovations in health and mental health. Med Care Res Rev MCRR. (2012) 69(2):123&#x2013;57. 10.1177/1077558711430690</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077558711430690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3524416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22203646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke JG, Hess S, Hoffmann K, Guizzetti L, Loy E, Gielen A, et al. Translating community-based participatory research principles into practice. Prog Community Health Partnersh Res Educ Action. (2013) 7(2):115&#x2013;22. 10.1353/cpr.2013.0025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/cpr.2013.0025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4138529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23793242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonas MA, Garrettson M, Gielen A, Parker EA. Integrating principles of community-based participatory research (CBPR) with the injury prevention and control agenda. Inj Prev. (2013) 19(2):149. 10.1136/injuryprev-2013-040788</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/injuryprev-2013-040788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4880993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23513036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nygaard P, Saltz RF. Communication between researchers and practitioners: findings from a qualitative evaluation of a large-scale college intervention. Subst Use Misuse. (2010) 45(1&#x2013;2):77&#x2013;97. 10.3109/10826080902864985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10826080902864985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3640309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20025440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deming WE. Out of the Crisis. Cambridge, MA, USA: MIT Press; (2000). p. 524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor MJ, McNicholas C, Nicolay C, Darzi A, Bell D, Reed JE. Systematic review of the application of the plan-do-study-act method to improve quality in healthcare. BMJ Qual Saf. (2014) 23(4):290&#x2013;8. 10.1136/bmjqs-2013-001862</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2013-001862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24025320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>