<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41516725</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Occlusion Avoidance for Harvesting Robots: A Lightweight Active Perception Model.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">291</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26010291</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Addressing the issue of fruit recognition and localization failures in harvesting robots due to severe occlusion by branches and leaves in complex orchard environments, this paper proposes an occlusion avoidance method that combines a lightweight YOLOv8n model, developed by Ultralytics in the United States, with active perception. Firstly, to meet the stringent real-time requirements of the active perception system, a lightweight YOLOv8n model was developed. This model reduces computational redundancy by incorporating the C2f-FasterBlock module and enhances key feature representation by integrating the SE attention mechanism, significantly improving inference speed while maintaining high detection accuracy. Secondly, an end-to-end active perception model based on ResNet50 and multi-modal fusion was designed. This model can intelligently predict the optimal movement direction for the robotic arm based on the current observation image, actively avoiding occlusions to obtain a more complete field of view. The model was trained using a matrix dataset constructed through the robot's dynamic exploration in real-world scenarios, achieving a direct mapping from visual perception to motion planning. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed lightweight YOLOv8n model achieves a mAP of 0.885 in apple detection tasks, a frame rate of 83 FPS, a parameter count reduced to 1,983,068, and a model weight file size reduced to 4.3 MB, significantly outperforming the baseline model. In active perception experiments, the proposed method effectively guided the robotic arm to quickly find observation positions with minimal occlusion, substantially improving the success rate of target recognition and the overall operational efficiency of the system. The current research outcomes provide preliminary technical validation and a feasible exploratory pathway for developing agricultural harvesting robot systems suitable for real-world complex environments. It should be noted that the validation of this study was primarily conducted in controlled environments. Subsequent work still requires large-scale testing in diverse real-world orchard scenarios, as well as further system optimization and performance evaluation in more realistic application settings, which include natural lighting variations, complex weather conditions, and actual occlusion patterns.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou 450011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Jiaxi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou 450011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Jinxing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou 450011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhengyi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou 450011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Le</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou 450011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Huan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-9541-6301</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou 450011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 231111112700</GrantID><Agency>Henan Province Key Research and Development Special Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 32401692</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 242102110336</GrantID><Agency>Henan Province R&amp;D Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 25B416001</GrantID><Agency>Key Research Programs of Higher Education Institutions in Henan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">active per ception strategy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">harvesting robot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lightweight YOLOv8n</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occlusion avoidance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest. The funders had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the manu script, or in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41516725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12788279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26010291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26010291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sun T., Zhang W., Gao X., Zhang W., Li N., Miao Z. Efficient Occlusion Avoidance Based on Active Deep Sensing for Harvesting Robots. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2024;225:109135. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2024.109360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2024.109360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Jia J., Gui G., Hao X., Gao W., Wang M. Deep Learning Based Improved Classification System for Designing Tomato Harvesting Robot. IEEE Access. 2018;6:67940&#x2013;67950. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2018.2879324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2018.2879324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha K., Doshi A., Patel P., Shah M. A comprehensive review on automation in agriculture using artificial intelligence. Artif. Intell. Agric. 2019;2:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.aiia.2019.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aiia.2019.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem M.H., Potgieter J., Arif K.M. Automation in agriculture by machine and deep learning techniques: A review of recent developments. Precis. Agric. 2021;22:2053&#x2013;2091. doi: 10.1007/s11119-021-09806-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11119-021-09806-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Wang X., Au W., Kang H., Chen C. Intelligent robots for fruit harvesting: Recent developments and future challenges. Precis. Agric. 2022;23:1856&#x2013;1907. doi: 10.1007/s11119-022-09913-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11119-022-09913-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Q., Li S., Yang J., Song Q., Li Z., Zhang X. Object detection recognition and robot grasping based on machine learning: A survey. IEEE Access. 2020;8:181855&#x2013;181879. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3028740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3028740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji W., Zhang T., Xu B., He G. Apple recognition and picking sequence planning for harvesting robot in a complex environment. J. Agric. Eng. 2024;55:1549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I&#xf1;iguez R., Palacios F., Barrio I., Hern&#xe1;ndez I., Guti&#xe9;rrez S., Tardaguila J. Impact of Leaf Occlusions on Yield Assessment by Computer Vision in Commercial Vineyards. Agronomy. 2021;11:1003. doi: 10.3390/agronomy11051003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy11051003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe9;-Mola J., Sanz-Cortiella R., Rosell-Polo J.R., Escol&#xe0; A., Gregorio E. In-Field Apple Size Estimation Using Photogrammetry-Derived 3D Point Clouds: Comparison of 4 Different Methods Considering Fruit Occlusions. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2021;188:106343. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2021.106343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2021.106343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Follmann P., K&#xf6;nig R., H&#xe4;rtinger P., Klostermann M., B&#xf6;ttger T. Learning to See the Invisible: End-to-End Trainable Amodal Instance Segmentation; Proceedings of the IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV); Waikoloa, HI, USA. 7&#x2013;11 January 2019; pp. 1328&#x2013;1336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., He X., Wu M., Wu X., Lu B. Detection of Tomato Organs Based on Convolutional Neural Network Under the Overlap and Occlusion Backgrounds. Mach. Vis. Appl. 2020;31:41. doi: 10.1007/s00138-020-01081-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00138-020-01081-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan G.N., Apostolides P.F., Harnett M.T., Xu N.-L., Druckmann S., Magee J.C. Active Dendritic Integration and Mixed Neocortical Network Representations during an Adaptive Sensing Behavior. Nat. Neurosci. 2018;21:1583&#x2013;1590. doi: 10.1038/s41593-018-0254-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-018-0254-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6203624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Wang C., Meng M.Q.-H., de Silva C.W. Attention-Driven Active Sensing with Hybrid Neural Network for Environmental Field Mapping. IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng. 2022;19:2135&#x2013;2152. doi: 10.1109/TASE.2021.3077689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2021.3077689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zapotezny-Anderson P., Lehnert C. Towards Active Robotic Vision in Agriculture: A Deep Learning Approach to Visual Servoing in Occluded and Unstructured Protected Cropping Environments; Proceedings of the 1st IFAC Conference on Sensing, Control and Automation Technologies for Agriculture; Virtual. 14&#x2013;16 December 2020; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Kao S.-H., He H., Zhuo W., Wen S., Lee C.-H., Chan S.-H.G. Run, Don&#x2019;t Walk: Chasing Higher FLOPS for Faster Neural Networks; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR); Vancouver, BC, Canada. 17&#x2013;24 June 2023; pp. 12001&#x2013;12011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J., Shen L., Sun G., Albanie S. Squeeze-and-Excitation Networks. IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell. 2020;42:2011&#x2013;2023. doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2019.2913372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPAMI.2019.2913372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molchanov P., Tyree S., Karras T., Aila T., Kautz J. Pruning Convolutional Neural Networks for Resource Efficient Transfer Learning. arXiv. 20161611.06440</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>