<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41834706</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2060</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Addressing free rider issues in academic authorship in medical education.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2625580</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2625580</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/07853890.2026.2625580</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Authorship is a key marker for&#xa0;academic achievement, yet its integrity&#xa0;is increasingly compromised by "free riding," whereby individuals are listed&#xa0;as co-authors without making any substantive contributions. This commentary examines the nature, drivers, and ethical implications of free riding in academic publishing and proposes strategies to promote fairness, accountability, and integrity in authorship practices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This commentary draws on existing literature, international authorship guidelines (including those of the International Committee of Medical Journal Editors), and ethical frameworks in scholarly publishing. Through narrative analysis, it explores the characteristics, motivations, and consequences of free riding in authorship, with particular attention to institutional, cultural, and power-related influences. Emerging challenges related to Generative Artificial Intelligence and authorship integrity are also examined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Five primary forms of free riding in authorship are identified: coercive, reciprocal, gratitude, purchased, and entitlement authorship. These practices are driven by pressures to publish, increasing multi-authorship, ambiguous authorship norms, and incentive structures that prioritize quantity over quality. Despite established guidelines, honorary and coercive authorship persist, undermining accountability and trust in scholarly communication. The use of Generative Artificial Intelligence introduces&#xa0;additional complexities regarding contribution attribution and authorship legitimacy. Institutions and journals play a critical role in addressing these issues through clear authorship policies, transparent contribution tracking (e.g.,&#xa0;the CRediT taxonomy), ethical training, mentorship, and technologies that verify individual contributions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Free riding in academic authorship represents an ethical challenge that threatens the credibility, fairness, and trustworthiness of scientific knowledge. Addressing this issue requires coordinated reform across institutions, journals, and researcher training. By strengthening accountability mechanisms, and fostering a culture of ethical authorship, the academic community can ensure that authorship accurately reflects genuine intellectual and practical contributions. Confronting free riding in academic publishing is essential not only for maintaining ethical integrity and fairness but also for preserving public trust and the validity of scientific knowledge.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewis</LastName><ForeName>Kadriye O</ForeName><Initials>KO</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5947-409X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Universidad San Francisco de Quito USFQ, Quito, Ecuador.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foong</LastName><ForeName>Chan Choong</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4790-005X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education and Research Development Unit (MERDU), Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fatima</LastName><ForeName>Syeda Sadia</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3164-0225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological and Biomedical Sciences, The Aga Khan University, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8906388</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0785-3890</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001319" MajorTopicYN="Y">Authorship</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011643" MajorTopicYN="Y">Publishing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000941" MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Education, Medical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000941" MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035081" MajorTopicYN="N">Editorial Policies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017408" MajorTopicYN="N">Guidelines as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Free riding in academic authorship, where individuals receive credit without substantive intellectual contribution, undermines the integrity, fairness, and credibility of scholarly research.Different forms of free riding, including coercive, reciprocal, gratitude, purchased, and entitlement authorship compromise both scientific rigor and ethical integrity in academic publishing.As a result of technological advancements, additional challenges have arisen in academic authorship such as the use of artificial intelligence in research.Preventing free riding in authorship requires a collective commitment from institutions, journals, and research teams, grounded in proactive leadership, ethics education, transparent authorship policies, and open dialogue, to foster a culture in which integrity is expected and accountability is shared.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Authorship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">academic publications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">accountability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">free riders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">free riding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical education research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scientific journals</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41834706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2026.2625580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>