<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41715243</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-7283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The AI-powered entrepreneur: how ChatGPT adoption amplifies the impact of education on digital entrepreneurial intention via self-efficacy and perceived control?</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">416</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40359-026-04195-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Digital transformation is reshaping entrepreneurship and the educational ecosystem. It creates new opportunities but also raises questions about the psychological mechanisms that shape digital entrepreneurship intentions and the role of artificial intelligence tools. This study aims to test an integrated model of planned behavior theory and social cognitive theory to assess the role of ChatGPT adoption on entrepreneurship education and digital entrepreneurial intention. Data were collected via an online survey of 718 university students across various fields and analyzed using structural equation modeling with SmartPLS 4. The results show that entrepreneurship education enhances perceived behavioral control and self-efficacy. At the same time, both factors promote digital entrepreneurship intentions, with perceived behavioral control being a stronger predictor. Notably, ChatGPT adoption strengthens the TPB - SCT framework by enhancing perceived behavioral control and self-efficacy, thereby reinforcing the psychological mechanisms underlying digital entrepreneurial intention. This study suggests directions for building entrepreneurship education programs that incorporate AI technology to improve training efficiency.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Nga Quynh Thi</ForeName><Initials>NQT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-3122-7493</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Financial and Banking Technology, University of Finance - Marketing, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. phamnga@ufm.edu.vn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Anh Phuong Ha</ForeName><Initials>APH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-4553-4439</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fulbright University Vietnam, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Thi Minh Thi</ForeName><Initials>TMT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-5021-3903</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fulbright University Vietnam, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Hoang Minh</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-2995-8196</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fulbright University Vietnam, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-7283</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ChatGPT adoption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital entrepreneurial intention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Entrepreneurial education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perceived behaviour control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-Efficacy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The 1964 Helsinki Declaration and its ensuing amendments, as well as the institutional research committee's ethical guidelines, were followed in the conduct of this study. As part of the execution of an applied research project at the university level, the study was approved by the University Council of the University of Finance &#x2013; Marketing under Decision No. 609/H&#x110;-DHTCM-QLKH&#x110;MST, dated August 25, 2025. Before participation, all individuals were fully informed about the purpose and procedures of the study and provided their written informed consent. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41715243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13023167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-026-04195-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40359-026-04195-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Herman E. The interplay between digital entrepreneurship and sustainable development in the context of the EU digital economy: A multivariate analysis. Mathematics. 2022;10(10):1682. 10.3390/math10101682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10101682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia G, Margherita A, Passiante G. Digital entrepreneurship ecosystem: how digital technologies and collective intelligence are reshaping the entrepreneurial process. Technol Forecast Soc Chang. 2019;150:119791. 10.1016/j.techfore.2019.119791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2019.119791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson E, Vaast E.Digital Entrepreneurship and Its Sociomaterial Enactment. In: 2010 43rd Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences. 2010:1&#x2013;10. 10.1109/hicss.2010.150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nambisan S. Digital entrepreneurship: toward a digital technology perspective of entrepreneurship. Entrepreneurship Theory Pract. 2016;41(6):1029&#x2013;55. 10.1111/etap.12254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/etap.12254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branca E, Vanderstraeten J, Slabbinck H, Maes IMR. The impact of entrepreneurial education on key entrepreneurial competencies: A systematic review of learning strategies and tools. Int J Manage Educ. 2025;23(2):101144. 10.1016/j.ijme.2025.101144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijme.2025.101144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham M, Lam BQ, Nguyen ATT, Dinh TKT, Tran HY. How do environment and innovativeness affect digital entrepreneurial intention through education? An explanation from the social cognitive career theory. Social Sci Humanit Open. 2024b;10:101179. 10.1016/j.ssaho.2024.101179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssaho.2024.101179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhunia AK, Shome MK. Impact of social capital on entrepreneurial intention of Polytechnic students: the mediating role of innovativeness. Int J Innovative Res Sci Stud. 2023c;6(2):358&#x2013;65. 10.53894/ijirss.v6i2.1439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53894/ijirss.v6i2.1439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen I. The theory of planned behavior. Organ Behav Hum Decis Process. 1991;50(2):179&#x2013;211. 10.1016/0749-5978(91)90020-T.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0749-5978(91)90020-T</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan A, Haenlein M. Siri, Siri, in my hand: who&#x2019;s the fairest in the land? On the interpretations, illustrations, and implications of artificial intelligence. Bus Horiz. 2019;62(1):15&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bushor.2018.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong CD, Nguyen TH, Chu TV, Van Pham T, Diep N, DO. Whether ChatGPT adoption inspires higher education students&#x2019; digital entrepreneurial intention? An integrated model of the SCCT and the TPB. Int J Innov Sci. 2024;17(5):1210&#x2013;34. 10.1108/ijis-01-2024-0020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/ijis-01-2024-0020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnell JA, Gopalkrishnan S. Entrepreneurship teaching exercises: integrating generative AI. Discover Educ. 2024;3(1). 10.1007/s44217-024-00261-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social cognitive theory of self-regulation. Organ Behav Hum Decis Process. 1991;50(2):248&#x2013;87. 10.1016/0749-5978(91)90022-l.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0749-5978(91)90022-l</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd NG, Vozikis GS. The influence of self-efficacy on the development of entrepreneurial intentions and actions. Entrepreneurship Theory Pract. 1994;18(4):63&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/104225879401800404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson F, Kickul J, Marlino D. Gender, entrepreneurial Self&#x2013;Efficacy, and entrepreneurial career intentions: implications for entrepreneurship education. Entrepreneurship Theory Pract. 2007;31(3):387&#x2013;406. 10.1111/j.1540-6520.2007.00179.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1540-6520.2007.00179.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachmann N, Rose R, Maul V, H&#xf6;lzle K. What makes for future entrepreneurs? The role of digital competencies for entrepreneurial intention. J Bus Res. 2024;174:114481. 10.1016/j.jbusres.2023.114481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbusres.2023.114481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardoyo C, Narmaditya BS, Qurrata VA, Satrio YD, Sahid S. Are students ready for digital business? Antecedents of entrepreneurial intentions among Indonesian students using a serial mediation. Social Sci Humanit Open. 2024;11:101213. 10.1016/j.ssaho.2024.101213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssaho.2024.101213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li&#xf1;&#xe1;n F, Chen Y. Development and Cross&#x2013;Cultural application of a specific instrument to measure entrepreneurial intentions. Entrepreneurship Theory Pract. 2009;33(3):593&#x2013;617. 10.1111/j.1540-6520.2009.00318.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1540-6520.2009.00318.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mamary YHS, Alraja MM. Understanding entrepreneurship intention and behavior in the light of TPB model from the digital entrepreneurship perspective. Int J Inform Manage Data Insights. 2022;2(2):100106. 10.1016/j.jjimei.2022.100106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jjimei.2022.100106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TT, Dao TT, Tran TB, Nguyen HTT, Le LTN, Pham NTT. Fintech literacy and digital entrepreneurial intention: mediator and moderator effect. Int J Inform Manage Data Insights. 2024;4(1):100222. 10.1016/j.jjimei.2024.100222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jjimei.2024.100222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elnadi M, Gheith MH. The role of individual characteristics in shaping digital entrepreneurial intention among university students: evidence from Saudi Arabia. Think Skills Creativity. 2023;47:101236. 10.1016/j.tsc.2023.101236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tsc.2023.101236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir AA, Hassan S, Khan SJ. Understanding digital entrepreneurial intentions: A capital theory perspective. Int J Emerg Markets. 2022;18(12):6165&#x2013;91. 10.1108/ijoem-05-2021-0687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/ijoem-05-2021-0687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aloulou W, Ayadi F, Ramadani V, Dana L-P. Dreaming digital or chasing new real pathways? Unveiling the determinants shaping Saudi youth&#x2019;s digital entrepreneurial intention. Int J Entrepreneurial Behav Res. 2023;30(2/3):709&#x2013;34. 10.1108/IJEBR-10-2022-0942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJEBR-10-2022-0942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin B, Ma X. Gamifying online entrepreneurship education and digital entrepreneurial intentions: an empirical study. Entertainment Comput. 2023;46:100552. 10.1016/j.entcom.2023.100552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.entcom.2023.100552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahra SA, Liu W, Si S. How digital technology promotes entrepreneurship in ecosystems. Technovation. 2022;119:102457. 10.1016/j.technovation.2022.102457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.technovation.2022.102457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Seibert SE, Hills GE. The mediating role of Self-Efficacy in the development of entrepreneurial intentions. J Appl Psychol. 2005;90(6):1265&#x2013;72. 10.1037/0021-9010.90.6.1265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.90.6.1265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16316279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori E, Winkler C, Vanevenhoven J, Winkel D, James M. Entrepreneurship as a career choice: intentions, attitudes, and outcome expectations. J Small Bus Entrepreneurship. 2019;32(4):311&#x2013;31. 10.1080/08276331.2019.1600857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08276331.2019.1600857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipto Wardoyo, Narmaditya BS, Qurrata VA, Satrio YD, Sahid S. Are students ready for digital business? Antecedents of entrepreneurial intentions among Indonesian students using a serial mediation. Social Sci Humanit Open. 2024;11:101213. 10.1016/j.ssaho.2024.101213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssaho.2024.101213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen PND, Nguyen HH. Unveiling the link between digital entrepreneurship education and intention among university students in an emerging economy. Technol Forecast Soc Chang. 2024;201:123330. 10.1016/j.techfore.2024.123330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2024.123330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wibowo A, Narmaditya BS, Saptono A, Effendi MS, Mukhtar S, Mohd Shafiai MH. Does digital entrepreneurship education matter for students&#x2019; digital entrepreneurial intentions? The mediating role of entrepreneurial alertness. Cogent Educ. 2023;10(1). 10.1080/2331186X.2023.2221164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mack A, Carter-Rogers K, Bahaw P, et al. Entrepreneurial knowledge and skill exposure in vocational education: development of a new assessment scale. Discov Educ. 2024;3:237. 10.1007/s44217-024-00331-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44217-024-00331-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otache I, Edopkolor JE, Sani IA, Umar K. Entrepreneurship education and entrepreneurial intentions: do entrepreneurial self-efficacy, alertness and opportunity recognition matter? Int J Manage Educ. 2024;22(1):100917. 10.1016/j.ijme.2023.100917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijme.2023.100917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong CD, Nguyen TH, Chu TV, Pham TV, Do ND. Whether ChatGPT adoption inspires higher education students&#x2019; digital entrepreneurial intention? An integrated model of the SCCT and the TPB. Int J Innov Sci. 2024;16(3):445&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debarliev S, Janeska-Iliev A, Stripeikis O, Zupan B. What can education bring to entrepreneurship? Formal versus non-formal education. J Small Bus Manage. 2022;60(1):219&#x2013;52. 10.1080/00472778.2019.1700691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00472778.2019.1700691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheshwari G, Kha KL. Investigating the relationship between educational support and entrepreneurial intention in vietnam: the mediating role of entrepreneurial self-efficacy in TPB. Int J Manage Educ. 2021;19(3):100553. 10.1016/j.ijme.2021.100553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijme.2021.100553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlaegel C, Koenig M. Determinants of entrepreneurial intent: A Meta-Analytic test and integration of competing models. Entrepreneurship: Theory Pract. 2014;38(2):291&#x2013;332. 10.1111/etap.12087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/etap.12087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pushkarskaya H, Yi H, Zheng Y, Aldrich H. Enhancing measures of ESE to incorporate aspects of place: personal reputation and place-based social legitimacy. J Bus Ventur. 2021;36(3):106004. 10.1016/j.jbusvent.2020.106004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbusvent.2020.106004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8691730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34949901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zulfiqar S, Sarwar B, Huo C, Zhao X, Mahasbi HU. AI-powered education: driving entrepreneurial spirit among university students. Int J Manage Educ. 2025;23(2):101106. 10.1016/j.ijme.2024.101106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijme.2024.101106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong CD. Opening a career door! The role of ChatGPT adoption in shaping digital entrepreneurial intention. Int J Inform Manage Data Insights. 2025;10(1):100045. 10.1016/j.jjimei.2025.100326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jjimei.2025.100326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong CD, Nguyen TH. How ChatGPT adoption stimulates digital entrepreneurship: A stimulus-organism-response perspective. Int J Manage Educ. 2024;22(3):101019. 10.1016/j.ijme.2024.101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijme.2024.101019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X-H, You X, Wang H-P, Wang B, Lai W-Y, Su N. The effect of entrepreneurship education on entrepreneurial intention: mediation of entrepreneurial Self-Efficacy and moderating model of psychological capital. Sustainability. 2023;15(3):2562. 10.3390/su15032562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15032562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair JF, Hult GTM, Ringle CM, Sarstedt M. A primer on partial least squares structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM). 3rd ed. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE Publications; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu L, Bentler PM. Cutoff criteria for fit indexes in covariance structure analysis: conventional criteria versus new alternatives. Struct Equation Modeling: Multidisciplinary J. 1999;6(1):1&#x2013;55. 10.1080/10705519909540118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10705519909540118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne BM. Structural equation modeling with AMOS: basic concepts, applications, and programming, second edition (2nd ed.). Routledge. 2010. 10.4324/9780203805534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair JF, Risher JJ, Sarstedt M, Ringle CM. When to use and how to report the results of PLS-SEM. Eur Bus Rev. 2019;31(1):2&#x2013;24. 10.1108/EBR-11-2018-0203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/EBR-11-2018-0203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kock N. Common method bias in PLS-SEM: A full collinearity assessment approach. Int J e-Collaboration. 2015;11(4):1&#x2013;10. 10.4018/ijec.2015100101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4018/ijec.2015100101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhunia AK, Shome MK. Interrelation between personality characteristics and social capital in formation of entrepreneurial intention: a conceptual framework. Int J Prof Bus Rev. 2023;8(3):Article 1124. 10.26668/businessreview/2023.v8i3.1124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tchokot&#xe9; ID, Bawack R, Nana A. Attitude over norms: reevaluating the dominance of attitude in shaping entrepreneurial intentions among higher education students in global South countries. Int J Manage Educ. 2025;23(2):101129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Qadasi N, Zhang G, Al-Jubari I, Al-Awlaqi MA, Aamer AM. Entrepreneurship education and entrepreneurial behaviour: do self-efficacy and attitude matter? Int J Manage Educ. 2024;22(1):100945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauch A, Hulsink W. Putting entrepreneurship education where the intention to act lies: an investigation into the impact of entrepreneurship education on entrepreneurial behavior. Acad Manage Learn Educ. 2015;14(2):187&#x2013;204. 10.5465/amle.2012.0293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amle.2012.0293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi S, Biemans HJA, Lans T, Chizari M, Mulder M. The impact of entrepreneurship education: A study of Iranian students&#x2019; entrepreneurial intentions and opportunity identification. J Small Bus Manage. 2016;54(1):187&#x2013;209. 10.1111/jsbm.12137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsbm.12137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utami HN. Entrepreneurship education and its impact on entrepreneurial self-efficacy and entrepreneurial intentions among university students. Int J Innov Creativity Change. 2020;14(3):620&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Planning and Investment (MPI). Digital transformation in businesses for a sustainable digital economy. 2024. Available from: https://www.mpi.gov.vn/en/Pages/2024-10-11/Digital-transformation-in-businesses-for-a-sustainegpc5n.aspx. Accessed 23 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>