<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41407848</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on cloud-edge-end distributed collaborative computing based on deep reinforcement learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2909</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2909</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2909</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-32813-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>With the large-scale integration of renewable energy sources, the number of data acquisition terminals and the sampling frequency in distribution networks have increased rapidly, placing higher demands on the system&#x2019;s computing and communication resource scheduling capabilities. This paper focuses on collaborative resource management and intelligent scheduling under a cloud&#x2013;edge&#x2013;device distributed architecture, and conducts a study on collaborative computing based on deep reinforcement learning. Firstly, an optimization model is formulated with the objective of maximizing the volume of data collaboratively processed by the cloud&#x2013;edge&#x2013;device system. The Lyapunov optimization theory is introduced to transform the long-term optimization problem into an online optimization problem that relies only on current time-slot information, enabling a joint guarantee of queuing delay control and long-term average data acquisition. Secondly, an improved Deep Q-Network (DQN) algorithm is proposed. By incorporating a greedy strategy-based Q-value sorting mechanism and a double experience replay mechanism, the algorithm enhances sample diversity and training stability, thereby improving convergence performance and decision robustness in multi-terminal resource scheduling scenarios. This also effectively mitigates resource conflicts caused by processing coupling among terminals. Finally, simulation results demonstrate that the proposed algorithm can effectively adapt to high-density, high-frequency data acquisition loads, providing excellent scheduling adaptability and system performance assurance. This work offers theoretical support and technical pathways for intelligent perception via cloud&#x2013;edge collaboration in distribution networks.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Chunpeng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Electric Power Research Institute Co., Ltd, Beijing, 100192, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Qinghe</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Electric Power Research Institute Co., Ltd, Beijing, 100192, China. dky_paper2025@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Electric Power Research Institute Co., Ltd, Beijing, 100192, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Dengkai</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Electric Power Research Institute Co., Ltd, Beijing, 100192, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wenli</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Electric Power Research Institute Co., Ltd, Beijing, 100192, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Xingguo</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Electric Power Research Institute Co., Ltd, Beijing, 100192, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>5700- 202358842A-4-3-WL</GrantID><Agency>science and technology program of State grid Corporation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Business processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cloud-side-end collaboration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep reinforcement learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-frequency acquisition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lyapunov optimization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41407848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12828047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-32813-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-32813-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen Yapeng, L. et al. Autonomous collaborative decision-making for power elastic optical network oriented to service reliable bearing. <i>Trans. China Electrotechnical Soc.</i><b>38</b> (21), 5821&#x2013;5831 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Pattern recognition method for detecting partial discharge in oil-paper insulation equipment using optical F-P sensor array based on KAN-CNN algorithm. <i>J. Lightwave Technol.</i><b>43</b> (12), 6004&#x2013;6012 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JLT.2025.3552628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, S. et al. A distinctive eocene Asian monsoon and modern biodiversity resulted from the rise of Eastern Tibet. <i>Sci. Bull.</i><b>67</b> (21), 2245&#x2013;2258 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scib.2022.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36546000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xian, P. et al. Network security constrained distributed smart grid edge-cloud collaborative optimization scheduling. <i>Trans. China Electrotechnical Soc.</i><b>39</b> (19), 61046118 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Coordinated planning model for multi-regional ammonia industries leveraging hydrogen supply chain and power grid integration: A case study of Shandong. <i>Appl. Energy</i>. <b>377</b>, 124456 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.124456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, N. et al. Cloud computing based scheduling method for sudden data processing in power system. <i>Autom. Instrum. </i><b>8</b>(8): 56&#x2013;59. (2021). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Fault diagnosis method for OLTC defects based on Dual-Cantilever beam fiber Bragg grating sensing. <i>Opt. Laser Technol.</i><b>193</b>, 114169 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2025.114169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Peng, X. &amp; Wei, L. Analysis of key issues and prospect for digital transformation of distribution networks based on edge computing. <i>Autom. Electr. Power Syst.</i><b>48</b> (6), 29&#x2013;41 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Comparison of different coupling types of fiber optic fabry-perot ultrasonic sensing for detecting partial discharge faults in oil-paper insulated equipment. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>73</b>, 9519612 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2024.3481543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changjie Guo, Lejiaqi Zhang, Qi Zhang, Congcong Ni, Ning Deng, Xin Huang. Efficient Adsorptive Removal of Phosphonate Antiscalant HEDP by Mg-Al LDH." Separations 12, no. 10 (2025): 259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Weifeng, Y. et al. Task cooperative offloading for vehicle edge computing. <i>Adv. Eng. Sci.</i><b>56</b> (1), 89&#x2013;98 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Junna, B. et al. A dependent task offloading method for joint time delay and energy consumption. <i>J. Comput. Res. Dev.</i><b>60</b> (12), 2770&#x2013;2782 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, N. et al. Motion and appearance decoupling representation for event cameras. <i>IEEE Trans. Image Process.</i> 2025, <b>34</b>, 5964-5977. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40953414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Haiyuan, Assis, K. D. R. et al. DRL-based long-term resource planning for task offloading policies in multiserver edge computing networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Netw. Serv. Manage.</i><b>19</b> (4), 4151&#x2013;4164 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSM.2022.3191748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Zeyu, F. et al. Energy management strategy for hybrid electric vehicle based on the deep reinforcement learning method. <i>Trans. China Electrotechnical Soc.</i><b>37</b> (23), 6157&#x2013;6168 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di, Z. et al. Synergistic gas&#x2013;slag scheme to mitigate CO2 emissions from the steel industry. <i>Nat. Sustain.</i><b>8</b>, 763&#x2013;772 (2025). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changjin Guo, Yinghao Xu, Ning Deng, Xin Huang. Efficient degradation of organophosphorus pesticides and in situ phosphate recovery via NiFe-LDH activated peroxymonosulfate. J.Chem. Eng. <b>524</b>(15),169107 (2025). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Shiquan, Y. &amp; Xuguo Multi-objective task offloading algorithm based on deep Q-network. <i>J. Comput. Appl.</i><b>42</b> (6), 16681674 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Qiang, Y. et al. Dependent task offloading and resource allocation based on A3C in mobile edge computing. <i>Comput. Eng.</i><b>49</b> (6), 42&#x2013;52 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Haijun, Z. et al. Learning-based queue-aware task offloading and resource allocation for space air ground-integrated power IoT. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>8</b> (7), 5250&#x2013;5263 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2021.3058236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Ultrasonic localization method based on Chan-WLS algorithm for detecting power transformer partial discharge faults by fibre optic F-P sensing array. <i>High. Voltage</i>. <b>9</b> (6), 1234&#x2013;1245 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/hve2.12472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Mian, G. et al. Delay-optimal scheduling of VMs in a queueing cloud computing system with heterogeneous workloads. <i>IEEE Trans. Serv. Comput.</i><b>15</b> (1), 110&#x2013;123 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSC.2019.2920954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Kaihao, Wenhan Luo, Yiran Zhong, Lin Ma, Wei Liu, and Hongdong Li. "Adversarial spatio-temporal learning for video deblurring." IEEE Transactions on Image Processing <b>28</b>(1), 291-301 (2018). 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2018.2867733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30176588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Congcong Ni, Qi Zhang, Bin Xu, Ning Deng, Xin Huang. The Role of Solid Electrolytes in Suppressing Joule Heating Effect for Scalable H2O2 Electrosynthesis. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng <b>13</b>(42),17958-17968 (2025). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, Cao, Hongxiu Liu, Lixun Chen, Jintian Wang, Xuewei Chen, and Geng Wang. Characteristic analysis and model predictive-improved active disturbance rejection control of direct-drive electro-hydrostatic actuators. Expert Syst Appl <b>301, </b>130565 (2026). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2025.130565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaleel, M. I. et al. Energy-latency trade-off analysis for scientific workflow in cloud environments: the role of processor utilization ratio and mean grey Wolf optimizer. <i>Eng. Sci. Technol. Int. J.</i><b>50</b>, 101611 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaleel, M. I. et al. Combinatorial metaheuristic methods to optimize the scheduling of scientific workflows in green DVFS-enabled edge-cloud computing. <i>Alexandria Eng. J.</i><b>86</b>, 458&#x2013;470 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2023.11.074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaleel, M. I. et al. A hybrid many-objective optimization algorithm for job scheduling in cloud computing based on merge-and-split theory. <i>MDPI Math.</i><b>11</b> (16), 3563 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math11163563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>