<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41601576</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2632-3524</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Palliative care and social practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Palliat Care Soc Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>"Cicely and David": Exploring the transformative power of theatre to communicate palliative care among university students.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26323524251410610</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26323524251410610</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26323524251410610</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/26323524251410610</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Many people still lack a clear understanding of what palliative care is and the value it brings. Although recognized by the World Health Organization as a fundamental human right, palliative care remains inaccessible to many. This lack of awareness and genuine understanding hinders its integration into health systems. Art-and theatre in particular-can offer innovative ways to connect with the public.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To explore how a theatrical performance about the origins of palliative care can influence students' understanding and attitudes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A qualitative descriptive study with an interpretivist approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study examined the impact of the play Cicely and David on university students. The play dramatizes the early development of palliative care through imagined dialogues between Cicely Saunders and David Tasma. Audience members (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;42) completed an open online questionnaire, and data were analysed using inductive thematic analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Students reported improved understanding of palliative care and its historical foundations. The performance evoked strong emotional responses and personal reflection. Key values such as empathy, accompaniment, and focus on quality of life were highlighted. Theatre was perceived as an effective and transformative way to convey the principles of palliative care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Theatrical performance is an innovative and effective tool to raise awareness and educate about palliative care. Beyond knowledge transfer, it fostered empathy and personal motivation to engage with this field. These findings underscore the potential of art-based strategies to promote palliative care understanding and engagement among younger generations, contributing to broader societal awareness and support.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Centeno</LastName><ForeName>Irene</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-5222-0964</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cl&#xed;nica Universidad de Navarra, Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zapata</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-0438-5155</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unidad de Cuidados Continuos, Oncocenter Per&#xfa; SAC, Facultad de Medicina, Universidad de San Mart&#xed;n de Porres, Lima, Peru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Centeno</LastName><ForeName>Carlos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3395-7039</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cl&#xed;nica Universidad de Navarra, Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ATLANTES Global Observatory of Palliative Care, Institute for Culture and Society, University of Navarra, Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Investigaci&#xf3;n Sanitaria de Navarra (IdISNA), Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arantzamendi</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2406-0668</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ATLANTES Global Observatory of Palliative Care, Institute for Culture and Society, University of Navarra, Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Investigaci&#xf3;n Sanitaria de Navarra (IdISNA), Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Palliat Care Soc Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101754997</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2632-3524</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>How a theatre play helped university students understand and feel the meaning of palliative care Why was the study done? Many people are still unsure about what palliative care really means. It is more than care at the end of life, it is about improving quality of life, relieving suffering, and offering emotional and social support. Because palliative care is often misunderstood, it remains underused in many health systems. The research team wanted to see whether theatre could help young people understand and connect emotionally with this topic. What did the researchers do? We invited university students to watch Cicely and David, a play that tells the story of how palliative care began, through imagined conversations between Cicely Saunders, the founder of modern palliative care and David Tasma, a patient whose story inspired her work. After the performance, 42 students completed an online questionnaire about their reactions and reflections. We then analyzed their written responses to identify key themes and insights. What did the researchers find? Theatre helped students understand palliative care in a new and personal way. Many said the play moved them emotionally and made them think deeply about empathy, dignity, and the importance of supporting others. Students also valued learning about the historical roots of palliative care. They described the play as both educational and transformative, showing that art can make complex or sensitive topics more approachable. What do the findings mean? This study suggests that theatre can be a powerful way to raise awareness and encourage empathy about palliative care among young people. Artistic experiences like this can complement traditional education, helping future professionals and citizens to see the human side of care and to value compassion in health and society.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medicine in the arts</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">theatre</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41601576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12833168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/26323524251410610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_26323524251410610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organisation (WHO). Palliative care [Internet], https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/palliative-care (2020, accessed 5 May 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Strengthening of palliative care as a component of comprehensive care throughout the life course. In: 67th World Health Assembly, Geneva, Switzerland, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivastava SR, Shrivastava PS, Ramasamy J. Palliative care: an integral component of human right to health. Int J Prev Med 2016; 13: 7&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4755215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26941916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel P, Lyons L. Examining the knowledge, awareness, and perceptions of palliative care in the general public over time: a scoping literature review. Am J Hosp Palliat Care 2020; 37(6): 481&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31690088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrasco JM, G&#xf3;mez-Baceiredo B, Navas A, et al. Social representation of palliative care in the Spanish printed media: a qualitative analysis. PLoS One 2019; 14(1): e0211106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6347435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30682109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIlfatrick S, Slater P, Beck E, et al. Examining public knowledge, attitudes and perceptions towards palliative care: a mixed method sequential study. BMC Palliat Care 2021; 20(1): 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7971949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33731087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seymour J. The impact of public health awareness campaigns on the awareness and quality of palliative care. J Palliat Med 2018; 21(S1): S30&#x2013;S36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5733664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29283867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santha S. Impact of pain and palliative care services on patients. Indian J Palliat Care 2011; 17(1): 24&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3098540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21633618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernon E, Hughes MC, Kowalczyk M. Measuring effectiveness in community-based palliative care programs: a systematic review. Soc Sci Med 2022; 296:114731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35131612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seymour J, Kennedy S, Arthur A, et al. Public attitudes to death, dying and bereavement: a systematic synthesis. Nottingham, UK: University of Nottingham, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turton BM, Williams S, Burton CR, et al. Arts-based palliative care training, education and staff development: a scoping review. Palliat Med 2018; 32(2): 559&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weitkamp E, Almeida C. Science &amp; theatre: communicating science and technology with performing arts. Bingley, UK: Emerald Publishing, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Clark DG.
Cicely and David: a play [Internet], https://davidgrahamclark.net/cicely-and-david-a-play/ (2024, accessed 18 July 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Clark DG.
Cicely y David: my play in Spanish [Internet], https://davidgrahamclark.net/2024/03/20/cicely-y-david-my-play-in-spanish/ (2024, accessed 18 July 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. Whatever happened to qualitative description? Res Nurs Health 2000; 23(4): 334&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10940958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. What&#x2019;s in a name? Qualitative description revisited. Res Nurs Health 2010; 33(1): 77&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20014004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien BC, Harris IB, Beckman TJ, et al. Standards for reporting qualitative research: a synthesis of recommendations. Acad Med 2014; 89(9): 1245&#x2013;1251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Toward good practice in thematic analysis: Avoiding common problems and be(com)ing a knowing researcher. Int J Transgend Health 2022; 24(1): 1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9879167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36713144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne D. A worked example of Braun and Clarke&#x2019;s approach to reflexive thematic analysis. Qual Quant 2022; 56: 1391&#x2013;1412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
International Association for Hospice &amp; Palliative Care (IAHPC). Principles of palliative care [Internet], https://iahpc.org/resources/publications/getting-started/principles-of-palliative-care/ (n.d., accessed 14 June 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radbruch L, De Lima L, Knaul F, et al. Redefining palliative care: a new consensus-based definition. J Pain Symptom Manage 2020; 60(4): 754&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8096724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindqvist O, Tishelman C. Room for Death &#x2013; International museum-visitors&#x2019; preferences regarding the end of their life. Soc Sci Med 2015; 139: 1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Chang C.
Before I die [Internet], https://www.candychang.com/beforeidie/ (2014, accessed 7 May 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan MKB, Barnes A. Dying matters &#x2013; innovating spaces to foster end-of-life discussions with applied theatre. Arts Health 2024: 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39428943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koufopoulos G, Georgakarakos E, Keskinis C, et al. Theatrical performance in medical education: a fast-track differential approach of emergency cases. Hippokratia 2020; 24(3): 127&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8256782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34239290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Taylor RM, Lobel B, Thompson K, et al. BRIGHTLIGHT researchers as &#x201c;dramaturgs&#x201d;: creating <i>There is a Light</i> from complex research data. Res Involv Engagem
2020; 6: 48.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32789023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hundt L, Stuttaford MC, Bryanston C, et al. &#x201c;Research usually sits on shelves, through the play it was shared.&#x201d; Co-producing knowledge through post-show discussions of research-based theatre. Front Sociol 2019; 4: 48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8022462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33869371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asante E. Theatre: an innovative approach to public health education. Int J Innov Res Adv Stud 2016; 3(7): 366&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>