<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41902142</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing Forest Aboveground Biomass Models with Multi-Parameter Integration.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1974</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26061974</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Forests constitute a fundamental component of terrestrial carbon stocks and play a pivotal role in mitigating climate change through carbon sequestration. Accurate estimation of aboveground biomass (AGB) is essential for quantifying carbon budgets and informing ecosystem models. This study takes Wolong Nature Reserve in Sichuan Province, China, a mountainous area with high vegetation coverage and diverse forest types dominated by coniferous and mixed forests, as the study area, and constructs and evaluates AGB estimation models by integrating canopy height, leaf area index (LAI), vegetation indices (VIs), and topographic variables. Initially, univariate parametric models (linear, exponential, logarithmic, power, and polynomial) were established to relate canopy height to field-measured AGB. Subsequently, multivariate regression models incorporating VIs, LAI, and topographic metrics were developed. Finally, a decision tree-based machine learning framework was implemented to exploit the combined predictor set. Comparative analysis revealed that both canopy height-based and conventional multivariate regression models tended to overestimate AGB, limiting their applicability for large-scale assessments. In contrast, the optimized decision tree model, following parameter tuning and cross-validation, achieved superior predictive accuracy.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xinyi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6712-4599</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Engineering, Chengdu Technological University, Chengdu 611730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-2923-4221</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Geography and Planning, Chengdu University of Technology, Chengdu 610059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023RC056</GrantID><Agency>Talent Program of Chendu Technological University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24SKGH328</GrantID><Agency>Chongqing Municipal Education Commission Humanities and Social Sciences Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7440-44-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002244">Carbon</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018533" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomass</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065928" MajorTopicYN="Y">Forests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="N">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018515" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Leaves</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002244" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forest AGB estimation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multi-parameter</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13030503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26061974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26061974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Deng Y.R., Wang Y.H., Zhao Y.J., Gu P., Xiao J., Zhou J., Li Z., Yu Z., Peng P. Research progress and prospects of carbon dioxide sequestration under the background of carbon neutrality. Earth Sci. Front. 2023;30:429&#x2013;439. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Chen Q. Study on the economic value assessment of forest carbon sink: Taking Fujian Province as an example. J. Southwest Univ. (Nat. Sci. Ed.) 2021;43:121&#x2013;128. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu N.N., Yang B.S., Dong Z. A Novel Framework for Forest Vegetation Carbon Stock Estimation Based on Remote Sensing. Natl. Remote Sens. Bull. 2025;29:134&#x2013;146. doi: 10.11834/jrs.20244210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11834/jrs.20244210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zou Y., Wang Y. Remote Sensing of Forest Above-Ground Biomass Dynamics: A Review. Forests. 2025;16:821. doi: 10.3390/f16050821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f16050821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan W., Li L., Gao Z., Zhang X., Tang D. Study on biological yield and productivity in the Cunninghamia lanceolata plantation ecosystem. Hunan For. Sci. Technol. 1978 (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y., Ouyang Z., Wang X. A review of biomass equations for China&#x2019;s tree species. Earth Syst. Sci. Data. 2020;12:21&#x2013;40. doi: 10.5194/essd-12-21-2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-12-21-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastor J., Aber J.D., Melillo J.M. Biomass prediction using generalized allometric regressions for some northeast tree species. For. Ecol. Manag. 1984;7:265&#x2013;274. doi: 10.1016/0378-1127(84)90003-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-1127(84)90003-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ter-Mikaelian M.D., Korzukhin M.D. Biomass equations for sixty-five North American tree species. For. Ecol. Manag. 1997;97:1&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/S0378-1127(97)00019-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-1127(97)00019-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D.S., Chen Q., Wang G.X., Liu L., Li G., Moran E. A survey of remote sensing-based aboveground biomass estimation methods in forest ecosystems. Int. J. Digit. Earth. 2016;9:63&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1080/17538947.2014.990526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17538947.2014.990526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar L., Sinha P., Taylor S., Alqurashi A.F. Review of the use of remote sensing for biomass estimation to support renewable energy generation. J. Appl. Remote Sens. 2015;9:097696. doi: 10.1117/1.JRS.9.097696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1117/1.JRS.9.097696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majasalmi T., Rautiainen M., Stenberg P., Manninen T. Validation of MODIS and GEOV1 fPAR Products in a Boreal Forest Site in Finland. Remote Sens. 2015;7:1359&#x2013;1379. doi: 10.3390/rs70201359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs70201359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang T., Ou G., Wu Y., Zhang X., Liu Z., Xu H., Xu X., Wang Z., Xu C. Estimating the Aboveground Biomass of Various Forest Types with High Heterogeneity at the Provincial Scale Based on Multi-Source Data. Remote Sens. 2023;15:3550. doi: 10.3390/rs15143550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15143550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruening J.M., May P., Armston J., Dubayah R. Precise and unbiased biomass estimation from gedi data and the us forest inventory. Front. For. Glob. Change. 2023;6:1149153. doi: 10.3389/ffgc.2023.1149153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ffgc.2023.1149153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X.G. Doctoral Dissertation. Northeast Institute of Geography and Agroecology, Graduate University of Chinese Academy of Sciences; Changchun, China: 2013. Study on Inversion of Forest Aboveground Biomass Based on LiDAR and Multispectral Remote Sensing Data. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu C.Y. Doctoral Dissertation. Chinese Academy of Forestry; Beijing, China: 2018. Study on Estimation of Mountain Forest Parameters by Coupling Geometric-Optical Models with Multi-Source Remote sensing Data. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baret F., Weiss M., Lacaze R., Camacho F., Makhmara H., Pacholcyzk P., Smets B. GEOV1: LAI and FAPAR essential climate variables and FCOVER global time series capitalizing over existing products. Part 1: Principle and algorithm. Remote Sens. Environ. 2013;137:299&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1016/j.rse.2012.12.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2012.12.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang H., Baret F., Plummer S., Schaepman-Strub G. An overview of global leaf area index (LAI): Methods, products, validation, and applications. Rev. Geophys. 2019;57:739&#x2013;799. doi: 10.1029/2018RG000608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2018RG000608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamahewage S.H.G., Witharana C., Riemann R., Fahey R., Worthley T. Aboveground biomass estimation using multimodal remote sensing observations and machine learning in mixed temperate forest. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:31120. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-15585-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-15585-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12375767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40850968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng D., Rademacher J., Chen J., Crow T., Bresee M., Le Moine J., Ryu S.-R. Estimating aboveground biomass using Landsat 7 ETM+ data across a managed landscape in northern Wisconsin, USA. Remote Sens. Environ. 2004;93:402&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1016/j.rse.2004.08.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2004.08.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Yin J., Zhang X., Hao D., Ferreira M.P., Yan W., Tian Y., Zhang D., Tan S., Nie S., et al. Tree-level carbon stock estimations across diverse species using multi-source remote sensing integration. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2025;231:109904. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2025.109904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2025.109904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S., Garg R.D., Govil H., Kushwaha S.P.S. PolSAR-Decomposition-Based Extended Water Cloud Modeling for Forest Aboveground Biomass Estimation. Remote Sens. 2019;11:2287. doi: 10.3390/rs11192287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs11192287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson R., Krabill W., Tonelli J. Estimating forest biomass and volume using airborne laser data. Remote Sens. Environ. 1988;24:247&#x2013;267. doi: 10.1016/0034-4257(88)90028-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0034-4257(88)90028-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Toan T., Beaudoin A., Riom J., Guyon D. Relating forest biomass to SAR data. IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens. 1992;30:403&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1109/36.134089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/36.134089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun G., Ranson K.J., Kharuk V.I. Radiometric slope correction for forest biomass estimation from SAR data in the Western Sayani Mountains, Siberia. Remote Sens. Environ. 2002;79:279&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1016/S0034-4257(01)00279-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0034-4257(01)00279-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefsky M.A., Cohen W.B., Harding D.J., Parker G.G., Acker S.A., Gower S.T. Lidar remote sensing of above-ground biomass in three biomes. Glob. Ecol. Biogeogr. 2002;11:393&#x2013;399. doi: 10.1046/j.1466-822x.2002.00303.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1466-822x.2002.00303.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudreau J., Nelson R.F., Margolis H.A., Beaudoin A., Guindon L., Kimes D.S. Regional aboveground forest biomass using airborne and spaceborne LiDAR in Qu&#xe9;bec. Remote Sens. Environ. 2008;112:3876&#x2013;3890. doi: 10.1016/j.rse.2008.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2008.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du L.M., Pang Y. LiDAR biomass index-based method for aboveground biomass calculation of larch subcompartments. Natl. Remote Sens. Bull. 2025;29:2933&#x2013;2943. doi: 10.11834/jrs.20243386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11834/jrs.20243386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saatchi S.S., Houghton R.A., dos Santos Alval&#xe1; R.C., Soares J.V., Yu Y. Distribution of aboveground live biomass in the Amazon basin. Glob. Change Biol. 2007;13:816&#x2013;837. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2486.2007.01323.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2486.2007.01323.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L.D., Fu B.J., Liu X.H. Landscape structure design and species conservation in nature reserves: A case study of Wolong Nature Reserve. J. Nat. Resour. 2000;15:164&#x2013;169. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Tao J.P., Li Z.F., Zhang W., Ding Y. Study on characteristics of subalpine dark coniferous forest gaps in Wolong Nature Reserve. Chin. J. Appl. Ecol. 2004;15:1989&#x2013;1993. (In Chinese)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15707300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song L.X., Tao J.P., Wang W., Xi Y., Wang Y., Ran C. Structural characteristics of Fargesia nitida ramet populations under different canopy environments in subalpine dark coniferous forests of Wolong. Acta Ecol. Sin. 2006;26:730&#x2013;736. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu T., Zhou S.Q., Huang J.Y., Liu D., Taylor A.H., Luo S., Zhang Y., Qu Y., Wu D., Zhang H. Variation characteristics of woody plant diversity in Abies-fabrica forests during the regeneration process of Fargesia denudata in Wolong Nature Reserve. Chin. J. Appl. Environ. Biol. 2019;26:442&#x2013;450. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong L., Liu G.H., Li Z.S., Ye X., Wang H. Variation characteristics of the relationship between soil organic carbon components and nitrogen along an altitude gradient in Abies faxoniana forests of Wolong, western Sichuan. Acta Ecol. Sin. 2017;37:4696&#x2013;4705. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Han W.Y., Liu D., Liu G.H. How do forest gaps affect plant diversity along an altitude gradient in Wolong Nature Reserve? Acta Geogr. Sin. 2019;29:1081&#x2013;1097. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang Z.Y., Liu J.G., Xiao H., Tan Y., Zhang H. Habitat evaluation for giant pandas in Wolong Nature Reserve. Acta Ecol. Sin. 2001;21:1869&#x2013;1874. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Y.H., Fu B.J., Liu S.L., Chen L.D. Comprehensive functional evaluation of Wolong Nature Reserve. Acta Ecol. Sin. 2002;23:571&#x2013;579. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song A.Y., Liu S.R., Shi Z.M., Dong L.S. Numerical classification and ordination of subalpine meadows in Wolong Nature Reserve. Chin. J. Appl. Ecol. 2006;17:28&#x2013;32. (In Chinese)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17044487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J.Y., Xu J.Y., Fan F.F. Vegetation coverage change and its response to topographic factors in Wolong Nature Reserve. Resour. Environ. Yangtze Basin. 2019;28:440&#x2013;449. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., He L., He Z., Wei Y. Estimation of Forest Leaf Area Index Based on GEE Data Fusion Method. IEEE J. Sel. Top. Appl. Earth Obs. Remote Sens. 2025;18:4510&#x2013;4524. doi: 10.1109/JSTARS.2025.3528429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSTARS.2025.3528429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., He L., He Z., Wei Y. Estimation of Broadleaf Tree Canopy Height of Wolong Nature Reserve Based on InSAR and Machine Learning Methods. Forests. 2022;13:1282. doi: 10.3390/f13081282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f13081282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Y., Meng J., Wan H., Li Y. Preliminary study on integrated wireless smart terminals for leaf area index measurement. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2016;129:56&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2016.09.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2016.09.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong C., Qu Y. Comparison of smartphone app and digital hemispherical photography for estimating leaf area index. J. Beijing Norm. Univ. (Nat. Sci.) 2023;59:125&#x2013;135. doi: 10.12202/j.0476-0301.2021232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12202/j.0476-0301.2021232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Liang S. Fusion of Multiple Gridded Biomass Datasets for Generating a Global Forest Aboveground Biomass Map. Remote Sens. 2020;12:2559. doi: 10.3390/rs12162559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12162559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Liang S., Yang L. A Review of Regional and Global Gridded Forest Biomass Datasets. Remote Sens. 2019;11:2744. doi: 10.3390/rs11232744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs11232744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Han D., Wang X. Spectral analysis in crop cultivation management. In: Huang H., Li Y., editors. Spectral Analysis Technology and Its Application. 1st ed. Science Press; Beijing, China: 2006. p. 196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z., Li W., Shen S., Ma J. Application of HJ and GF-1 data in extraction of rice planting area. Jiangsu J. Agric. Sci. 2016;3:7&#x2013;13. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1000-4440.2016.01.017. (In Chinese)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1000-4440.2016.01.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Shen R., Yang X. Comparative study on estimation of vegetation coverage using different vegetation indices. Remote Sens. Land Resour. 2012;24:6&#x2013;11. doi: 10.6046/gtzyyg.2012.04.16. (In Chinese)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6046/gtzyyg.2012.04.16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H. A new index-based remote sensing index for built-up land and its eco-environmental significance. Remote Sens. Technol. Appl. 2007;22:8. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1004-0323.2007.03.001. (In Chinese)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1004-0323.2007.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitelson A., Kaufman Y., Merzlyak M. Use of a green channel in remote sensing of global vegetation from eos-modis. Remote Sens. Environ. 1996;58:289&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1016/S0034-4257(96)00072-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0034-4257(96)00072-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe6;sset E., Bollands&#xe5;s O.M., Gobakken T. Comparing regression methods in estimation of biophysical properties of forest stands from two different inventories using laser scanner data. Remote Sens. Environ. 2005;94:541&#x2013;553. doi: 10.1016/j.rse.2004.11.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2004.11.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Zhang W., Ji Y., Marino A., Li C., Wang L., Zhao H., Wang M. Estimation of Aboveground Biomass for Different Forest Types Using Data from Sentinel-1, Sentinel-2, ALOS PALSAR-2, and GEDI. Forests. 2024;15:215. doi: 10.3390/f15010215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f15010215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padalia H., Prakash A., Watham T. Modelling aboveground biomass of a multistage managed forest through synergistic use of Landsat-OLI, ALOS-2 L-band SAR and GEDI metrics. Ecol. Inform. 2023;77:102234. doi: 10.1016/j.ecoinf.2023.102234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2023.102234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saim A.A., Aly M.H. Machine Learning and Multisensor Data Fusion for Forest above Ground Biomass Estimation in Arkansas. Earth Syst. Environ. 2025:1&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1007/s41748-025-00713-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41748-025-00713-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayad I., Baghdadi N., Alvares C.A., Stape J.L., Bailly J.-S., Scolforo H.F. Terrain Slope Effect on Forest Height and Wood Volume Estimation from GEDI Data. Remote Sens. 2021;13:2136. doi: 10.3390/rs13112136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13112136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanga O., Masenyama A., Sibanda M. Spectral saturation in the remote sensing of high-density vegetation traits: A systematic review of progress, challenges, and prospects. ISPRS J. Photogramm. Remote Sens. 2023;198:297&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2023.03.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2023.03.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Su Y., Hu T., Yang Q., Liu B., Deng Y., Tang H., Tang Z., Fang J., Guo Q. Neural network guided interpolation for mapping canopy height of China&#x2019;s forests by integrating GEDI and ICESat-2 data. Remote Sens. Environ. 2022;269:112844. doi: 10.1016/j.rse.2021.112844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2021.112844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>