<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41733438</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-3115</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Disability and rehabilitation. Assistive technology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fidelity of power mobility interventions for young children with disabilities: a systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>24</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-24</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/17483107.2026.2631058</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Purpose:</b> To describe the study characteristics, intervention components, and intervention fidelity measurement of power mobility interventions for children three years and younger with mobility disabilities. <b>Methods:</b> We conducted a systematic review of studies that provided a power mobility device and in-person training over more than one session. PubMed, Web of Science, PsycINFO, and Google Scholar (April 2025) were searched. Data were extracted for study characteristics, intervention components, and intervention fidelity measurement (adherence, dosage, quality of delivery, participant responsiveness, program differentiation), including interventionist training and reliability procedures. When not explicitly measured, intervention fidelity were inferred using An et al. <b>Results:</b> Thirty-six studies met eligibility criteria. Samples were small, most involving children with cerebral palsy. Modified ride-on cars with switch access were common, and training occurred in both clinical and community settings. Intervention frequency and duration varied widely (3-36 sessions, 10-120&#x2009;min), and device use outside sessions was inconsistently reported. Caregiver education appeared in just over half of studies, and goal-directed activities, exploration, and prompting were the most frequent instructional strategies. Few studies explicitly referenced evidence or theory to guide design. One case report systematically measured intervention fidelity; in the remainder, measurement was limited, most often to dosage (sessions completed) or participant responsiveness (developmental outcomes). <b>Conclusions:</b> Fidelity measurement in power mobility interventions for young children is sparse and inconsistent, limiting interpretation, replication, and clinical translation. Future work should define core intervention ingredients, ground design in evidence and developmental theory, and apply intervention fidelity measurements to improve transparency, rigour, and clinical implementation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sloane</LastName><ForeName>Bethany M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7975-323X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute on Development &amp; Disability, Department of Pediatrics, Oregon Health &amp; Science University, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Create for Research and Education on Accessible Technology and Experiences, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Logan</LastName><ForeName>Samuel W</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8153-0967</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Exercise, Sport, and Health Sciences, Oregon State University, Corvallis, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101255937</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-3107</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText><b>Power mobility interventions cannot advance without measuring intervention fidelity.</b> Measuring what was planned versus delivered, and how much occurred, is essential for replication and translation into practice.<b>Engagement and delivery quality must be measured.</b> Capturing how children and caregivers respond during sessions ensures interventions are meaningful and feasible in real-world contexts.<b>Define the core components</b>. Clearly distinguishing power mobility intervention components from usual care or comparison intervention makes them replicable, scalable, and implementable across rehabilitation settings.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power mobility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention fidelity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paediatrics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41733438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2026.2631058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>