<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41671210</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AI-powered detection of cyberbullying in short-form video content: A hybrid deep learning framework.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0338799</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0338799</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0338799</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0338799</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The explosive rise of short-form video platforms such as Instagram Reels, TikTok, and YouTube Shorts has transformed digital expression while intensifying the spread of cyberbullying. Unlike video abuse conveys multimodal cues visual, text-based harassment, auditory, and textual that challenge conventional detection methods. This study presents a hybrid deep-learning framework that integrates Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) for spatial features, Bidirectional Long Short Term Memory (BiLSTM) networks for temporal acoustic patterns, and a Transformer-based textual encoder to analyze synchronized video, audio, and caption streams. A semantic-consistency validation layer enforces cross-modal alignment using attention-based similarity constraints, ensuring that incongruent cues are penalized during classification. Experiments on two benchmark datasets, CAVD and SocialVidMix, demonstrate state-of-the-art performance accuracy 91.6%, precision 89.7%, recall 93.0%, and F1-score 91.3% with consistent results across Instagram, TikTok, and YouTube Shorts. The framework's, interpretability, robustnessand scalability indicate strong potential for real-time deployment in automated content-moderation systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Mazhar et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazhar</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Communication, University of Sharjah, Sharjah, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zada</LastName><ForeName>Islam</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6472-8795</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Computing &amp; IT, Department of Software Engineering, International Islamic University Islamabad, Islamabad, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aldhayan</LastName><ForeName>Manal</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer Science Department College of Computer and IT, Shaqra University Shaqra, Shaqra, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsalamah</LastName><ForeName>Seetah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, College of Computer and Information Sciences, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asiri</LastName><ForeName>Mashael M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Technical and Engineering Specializations Unit, Applied College at Mahayil, King Khalid University, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayadi</LastName><ForeName>Manel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Information Systems, College of Computer and Information Sciences, Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alshahrani</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, College of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077321" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deep Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077224" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cyberbullying</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014741" MajorTopicYN="Y">Video Recording</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061108" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Media</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41671210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12893605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0338799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-36601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Malik NI, Ramzan MM, Malik Z, Tariq I. The Rise of Reels: Analyzing the Communicative Power of Short-Form Videos on Social Media. QJSS. 2025;6(2):138&#x2013;45. doi: 10.55737/qjss.vi-ii.25350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55737/qjss.vi-ii.25350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;akar-Meng&#xfc; S, Meng&#xfc; M. Cyberbullying as a manifestation of violence on social media. Multidisciplinary Perspectives in Educational and Social Sciences. 2023;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar D. Cyberbullying: Types and the effects of victimization. Mindful Media: Mental Health Challenges in the Digital Age. 2024. 285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altayeva A, Abdrakhmanov R, Toktarova A, Tolep A. Cyberbullying Detection on Social Networks Using a Hybrid Deep Learning Architecture Based on Convolutional and Recurrent Models. International Journal of Advanced Computer Science &amp; Applications, 2024;15(10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daraghmi E-Y, Qadan S, Daraghmi Y-A, Yousuf R, Cheikhrouhou O, Baz M. From Text to Insight: An Integrated CNN-BiLSTM-GRU Model for Arabic Cyberbullying Detection. IEEE Access. 2024;12:103504&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1109/access.2024.3431939</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2024.3431939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh NM, Sharma SK. An efficient automated multi-modal cyberbullying detection using decision fusion classifier on social media platforms. Multimed Tools Appl. 2023;83(7):20507&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1007/s11042-023-16402-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-023-16402-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Harigy LM, Al-Nuaim HA, Moradpoor N, Tan Z. Building towards Automated Cyberbullying Detection: A Comparative Analysis. Comput Intell Neurosci. 2022;2022:4794227. doi: 10.1155/2022/4794227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/4794227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35789611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hee C, Jacobs G, Emmery C, Desmet B, Lefever E, Verhoeven B, et al. Automatic detection of cyberbullying in social media text. PLoS One. 2018;13(10):e0203794. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0203794</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0203794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6175271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30296299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraj A, Utku S. Comparative Analysis of Word Embeddings for Multiclass Cyberbullying Detection. UHD J SCI TECH. 2024;8(1):55&#x2013;63. doi: 10.21928/uhdjst.v8n1y2024.pp55-63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21928/uhdjst.v8n1y2024.pp55-63</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastrati Z, Imran AS. Performance analysis of machine learning classifiers on improved concept vector space models. Future Generation Computer Systems. 2019;96:552&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.future.2019.02.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.future.2019.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Garcia JA, Carvalho JP. A survey of textual cyber abuse detection using cutting-edge language models and large language models. arXiv preprint. 2025. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2501.05443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2501.05443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acheampong FA, Nunoo-Mensah H, Chen W. Transformer models for text-based emotion detection: a review of BERT-based approaches. Artif Intell Rev. 2021;54(8):5789&#x2013;829. doi: 10.1007/s10462-021-09958-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-021-09958-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tembhurne JV, Diwan T. Sentiment analysis in textual, visual and multimodal inputs using recurrent neural networks. Multimed Tools Appl. 2020;80(5):6871&#x2013;910. doi: 10.1007/s11042-020-10037-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-020-10037-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv M, Xu W, Chen T. A hybrid deep convolutional and recurrent neural network for complex activity recognition using multimodal sensors. Neurocomputing. 2019;362:33&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/j.neucom.2019.06.051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2019.06.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda R, Malheiro R, Paiva RP. Audio Features for Music Emotion Recognition: A Survey. IEEE Trans Affective Comput. 2023;14(1):68&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1109/taffc.2020.3032373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/taffc.2020.3032373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh P, Srivastava R, Rana KPS, Kumar V. A multimodal hierarchical approach to speech emotion recognition from audio and text. Knowledge-Based Systems. 2021;229:107316. doi: 10.1016/j.knosys.2021.107316</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knosys.2021.107316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohmad Dar GH, Delhibabu R. Speech Databases, Speech Features, and Classifiers in Speech Emotion Recognition: A Review. IEEE Access. 2024;12:151122&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1109/access.2024.3476960</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2024.3476960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao F, Zhang C, Geng B. Deep Multimodal Data Fusion. ACM Comput Surv. 2024;56(9):1&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1145/3649447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3649447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Yang Z, He X, Deng L. Multimodal Intelligence: Representation Learning, Information Fusion, and Applications. IEEE J Sel Top Signal Process. 2020;14(3):478&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1109/jstsp.2020.2987728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jstsp.2020.2987728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J, Wang J, Wang Q, Yang D, Gu J, Tang Y, et al. A multimodal fusion emotion recognition method based on multitask learning and attention mechanism. Neurocomputing. 2023;556:126649. doi: 10.1016/j.neucom.2023.126649</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2023.126649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam F, Cresci S, Chakraborty T, Silvestri F, Dimitrov D, Da San Martino G, et al. A survey on multimodal disinformation detection. arXiv preprint. 2021. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2103.12541</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2103.12541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Akhtar MS, Nakov P, Chakraborty T. DISARM: Detecting the victims targeted by harmful memes. arXiv preprint. 2022. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2205.05738</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2205.05738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufchi S, Yadav A, Ahmed T. A comprehensive survey of multimodal fake news detection techniques: advances, challenges, and opportunities. Int J Multimed Info Retr. 2023;12(2). doi: 10.1007/s13735-023-00296-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13735-023-00296-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul J, Mallick S, Mitra A, Roy A, Sil J. Multi-modal Twitter Data Analysis for Identifying Offensive Posts Using a Deep Cross-Attention&#x2013;based Transformer Framework. ACM Trans Knowl Discov Data. 2025;19(3):1&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1145/3713077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3713077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Li J, Gao G, Lu H, Yang J, Yue D. Lightweight Real-Time Semantic Segmentation Network With Efficient Transformer and CNN. IEEE Trans Intell Transport Syst. 2023;24(12):15897&#x2013;906. doi: 10.1109/tits.2023.3248089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tits.2023.3248089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C-S, Tsai C-N, Jwo J-S, Lee C-H, Wang X. Heterogeneous Student Knowledge Distillation From BERT Using a Lightweight Ensemble Framework. IEEE Access. 2024;12:33079&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1109/access.2024.3372568</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2024.3372568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoletti G, Ferreira CHG, Vassio L, Rocha L, Almeida JM. Tracing the 2024 U.S. election debate on Telegram with LLMs and graph analysis. Soc Netw Anal Min. 2025;15(1). doi: 10.1007/s13278-025-01504-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13278-025-01504-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves TD. Branding English, Shaping Perceptions: Language Ideologies and Professional Positioning Among Brazilian ELT Influencers on Instagram. The University of Alabama. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh S, Singh GV, Arora J, Ekbal A. Benchmarking Cyber Harassment Dialogue Comprehension through Emotion-Informed Manifestations-Determinants Demarcation. AAAI. 2024;38(20):22040&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1609/aaai.v38i20.30207</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1609/aaai.v38i20.30207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Tao Y, Cai H, Hu B. Behavioral Information Feedback With Large Language Models for Mental Disorders: Perspectives and Insights. IEEE Trans Comput Soc Syst. 2024;11(3):3026&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1109/tcss.2024.3397403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tcss.2024.3397403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, S R, Akhtar MdS, Chakraborty T. Emotion-Aware Multimodal Fusion for Meme Emotion Detection. IEEE Trans Affective Comput. 2024;15(3):1800&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1109/taffc.2024.3378698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/taffc.2024.3378698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Li F, Zhu L, Li J, Zhang Z, Shen HT. Cross-Modal Retrieval: A Systematic Review of Methods and Future Directions. Proc IEEE. 2024;112(11):1716&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1109/jproc.2024.3525147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jproc.2024.3525147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G, Yang Z, Zhang J. Progressive Dynamic Interaction Network With Audio Supplement for Video Moment Localization. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12(24):53108&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1109/jiot.2025.3615180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jiot.2025.3615180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amerini I, Barni M, Battiato S, Bestagini P, Boato G, Bruni V, et al. Deepfake Media Forensics: Status and Future Challenges. J Imaging. 2025;11(3):73. doi: 10.3390/jimaging11030073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jimaging11030073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11943306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40137185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sar A, Roy S, Choudhury T, Abraham A. Zero-shot visual deepfake detection: can AI predict and prevent fake content before it&#x2019;s created?. arXiv preprint. 2025. doi: arXiv:2509.18461</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamayreh OKA. Detection of Fake and Recontextualized Media against Disinformation. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng KC, Ke PF, So MKP, Tam KY. Augmenting fake content detection in online platforms: A domain adaptive transfer learning via adversarial training approach. Production and Operations Management. 2023;32(7):2101&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1111/poms.13959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/poms.13959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy SD, Mel T, Zeng W, Li S. Socialtransfer: cross-domain transfer learning from social streams for media applications. In: Proceedings of the 20th ACM International Conference on Multimedia, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardar S, Vijay TS. Social Media Influencers and Purchase Intention: A Review and Research Agenda. Int J Consumer Studies. 2025;49(3). doi: 10.1111/ijcs.70046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcs.70046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Luo B, Liu J, Nie H, Su X. LOSA: Learnable Online Style Adaptation for Test-Time Domain Adaptive Object Detection. IEEE Trans Geosci Remote Sensing. 2025;63:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1109/tgrs.2025.3576444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tgrs.2025.3576444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoumplekas G, Li V, Sarigiannidis P, Argyriou V. A complete survey on contemporary methods, emerging paradigms and hybrid approaches for few-shot learning. arXiv preprint. 2024. doi: arXiv:2402.03017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng C, Li L, Peng D. A Method-Oriented Review of Explainable Artificial Intelligence for Neurological Medical Imaging. Expert Systems. 2025;42(9). doi: 10.1111/exsy.70111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exsy.70111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S. XAI-based data visualization in multimodal medical data. bioRxiv. 2025;:2025.07.11.664302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poppi S. Responsible AI in Vision and Language: Ensuring Safety, Ethics, and Transparency in Modern Models. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y. Efficient and adaptive language-conditioned robot learning: From end-to-end training to modularity and in-context learning. Arizona State University. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Mu Q, Liu C, Wang S, Sun J. Technical system of electroencephalography-based brain-computer interface: Advances, applications, and challenges. Neural Regen Res. 2025;:10.4103/NRR.NRR-D-25&#x2013;00217. doi: 10.4103/NRR.NRR-D-25-00217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/NRR.NRR-D-25-00217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40903968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onikoyi BQ. Exploring Predictive Models of Consumer Behaviour Using Machine Learning, NLP, and Data Mining. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegge M, Pad&#xf3; S. Investigating topic bias in emotion classification. Universit&#xe4;t Stuttgart. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motupally S. Cyber bullying classification using modified self-attention BERT and deep learning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vylomova E, Haslam N. Semantic changes in harm-related concepts in English. Computational approaches to semantic change. 2021;6:93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S. Human-centeredness in understanding and detecting online harassment. Georgia Institute of Technology. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Shen Z, Li D, Zhong P, Chen Y. Probability-Based Graph Embedding Cross-Domain and Class Discriminative Feature Learning for Domain Adaptation. IEEE Trans Image Process. 2023;32:72&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1109/TIP.2022.3226405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2022.3226405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37015526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Wang J, Huang C, Wang Y, Xu Y. Cigar: Cross-modality graph reasoning for domain adaptive object detection. In: Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv P, Wang Y, Liu M, Zhang Z, Ma Y, Liu L, et al. CiSeg: Unsupervised Cross-Modality Adaptation for 3D Medical Image Segmentation via Causal Intervention. IEEE Trans Med Imaging. 2025;PP:10.1109/TMI.2025.3620585. doi: 10.1109/TMI.2025.3620585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMI.2025.3620585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41082440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang Y, Huang K, Huo J, Yan Y, Huang S, Liu D, et al. Explainable and interpretable multimodal large language models: A comprehensive survey. arXiv preprint. 2024. doi: arXiv:2412.02104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo M, Vidal M-E. Towards an Ontology-Driven Approach to Document Bias. jair. 2025;83. doi: 10.1613/jair.1.19388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1613/jair.1.19388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khreich W, Doughman J. Genderly: a data-centric gender bias detection system. Complex Intell Syst. 2025;11(7). doi: 10.1007/s40747-025-01859-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40747-025-01859-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenneth MO, Khosmood F, Edalat A. Systematic literature review: Computational approaches for humour style classification. arXiv preprint. 2024. doi: arXiv:2402.01759</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labadie Tamayo R. Challenges in humor recognition: Cross-language perspective and hurtfulness analysis. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yigitcanlar T, Mehmood R, Corchado JM. Green Artificial Intelligence: Towards an Efficient, Sustainable and Equitable Technology for Smart Cities and Futures. Sustainability. 2021;13(16):8952. doi: 10.3390/su13168952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13168952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Z, Yan Z, Wen S. Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence in Sustainability: A Review of SDGs, Renewable Energy, and Environmental Health. Sustainability. 2023;15(18):13493. doi: 10.3390/su151813493</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151813493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Bruwaene D, Huang Q, Inkpen D. A multi-platform dataset for detecting cyberbullying in social media. Lang Resources &amp; Evaluation. 2020;54(4):851&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1007/s10579-020-09488-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10579-020-09488-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philipo AG, Sarwatt DS, Ding J, Daneshmand M, Ning H. Cyberbullying detection: Exploring datasets, technologies, and approaches on social media platforms. In: 2024. https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.12154</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alomar K, Aysel HI, Cai X. CNNs, RNNs and Transformers in human action recognition: a survey and a hybrid model. Artif Intell Rev. 2025;58(12). doi: 10.1007/s10462-025-11388-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10462-025-11388-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali Z. A comprehensive overview and comparative analysis of CNN, RNN-LSTM and transformer. RNN-LSTM and Transformer. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sha Q. Hybrid deep learning for financial volatility forecasting: An LSTM-CNN-transformer model. Transactions on Computational and Scientific Methods. 2024;4(11).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashir T, Wang H, Tahir M, Zhang Y. Wind and solar power forecasting based on hybrid CNN-ABiLSTM, CNN-transformer-MLP models. Renewable Energy. 2025;239:122055. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2024.122055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2024.122055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ali EM, Hajji Y, Said Y, Hleili M, Alanzi AM, Laatar AH, et al. Solar Energy Production Forecasting Based on a Hybrid CNN-LSTM-Transformer Model. Mathematics. 2023;11(3):676. doi: 10.3390/math11030676</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math11030676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinterreiter A, Ruch P, Stitz H, Ennemoser M, Bernard J, Strobelt H, et al. ConfusionFlow: A Model-Agnostic Visualization for Temporal Analysis of Classifier Confusion. IEEE Trans Vis Comput Graph. 2022;28(2):1222&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1109/TVCG.2020.3012063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVCG.2020.3012063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaeikheybari G, El-Harasis M, Gupta A, Shoemaker MB, Barnard J, Hunter J, et al. Artificial intelligence&#x2013;based feature analysis of pulmonary vein morphology on computed tomography scans and risk of atrial fibrillation recurrence after catheter ablation: A multi-site study. Circulation: Arrhythmia and Electrophysiology. 2024;17(12):e012679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11662226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39624901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>