<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41929636</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2297-7775</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in sociology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Sociol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gender differences in access to extension services and major farm inputs among paddy seed growers in Rautahat district of Nepal.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1705290</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1705290</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1705290</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fsoc.2026.1705290</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Extension services for paddy seed farmers are essential for boosting agricultural productivity; however, significant gender gaps in access to these services exist in Nepal. This study, carried out in 2024 in Rautahat district, explored the role of gender and socio-economic characteristics in determining access to paddy seed extension services and major agricultural inputs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A convergent parallel mixed-methods research design was used. Two hundred and sixty-five farmers were surveyed with a structured questionnaire using a multistage sampling method. Qualitative data were gathered through focus group discussions and key informant interviews. Data analysis included descriptive statistics and binary logistic regression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results showed that gender, income, age, ethnicity, and farm type influenced access to extension services, with the logistic model explaining 41.6% of the variation. Although men had higher access to these services, women were more likely to utilize them once accessed. Education, farm size, and off-farm employment had limited influence on perceived access. The farm inputs access model accounted for 42.0% of the variation, with participation level, farm type, and ethnicity being the strongest predictors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Perception analysis revealed that women held more positive attitudes toward extension services but faced structural and social barriers, such as fewer female extension agents, financial constraints, and limited decision-making power, which hindered their ability to make data-driven decisions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings highlight the need for gender-sensitive and appropriate extension strategies to ensure equitable access for all farmers, ultimately improving access and productivity, especially for women and marginalized groups.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Timalsina, Paudel, Panta, Subedi and Chaurasia.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timalsina</LastName><ForeName>Sandeep</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Sociology, Institute of Agriculture and Animal Sciences, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paudel</LastName><ForeName>Rajesh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Sociology, Institute of Agriculture and Animal Sciences, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panta</LastName><ForeName>Hari Krishna</ForeName><Initials>HK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Economics, Institute of Agriculture and Animal Sciences, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Subedi</LastName><ForeName>Milan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Sociology, Institute of Agriculture and Animal Sciences, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaurasia</LastName><ForeName>Jay</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Sociology, Institute of Agriculture and Animal Sciences, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Sociol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101777459</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2297-7775</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">farm inputs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gender</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paddy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seed</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41929636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13038595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsoc.2026.1705290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abate G. T., Bernard T., Makhija S., Spielman D. J. (2023). Accelerating technical change through ICT: evidence from a video-mediated extension experiment in Ethiopia. World Dev. 161:106089. doi: 10.1016/j.worlddev.2022.106089,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2022.106089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9693707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36597414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya K. K., Zafarullah H. (2020). Institutionalising federalism in Nepal: operationalising obstacles, procrastinated progress. Public Adm. Policy 23, 125&#x2013;139. doi: 10.1108/PAP-03-2020-0013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/PAP-03-2020-0013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A., Coleman F., Hoddinott J., Menon P., Parvin A., Pereira A., et al. (2023). Comparing delivery channels to promote nutrition-sensitive agriculture: a cluster-randomized controlled trial in Bangladesh. Food Policy 118:102484. doi: 10.1016/j.foodpol.2023.102484,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodpol.2023.102484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10398750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37547489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvi M., Barooah P., Gupta S., Saini S. (2021). Women's access to agriculture extension amidst COVID-19: insights from Gujarat, India and dang, Nepal. Agric. Syst. 188:103035. doi: 10.1016/j.agsy.2020.103035,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agsy.2020.103035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9757924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36570044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu S. C., Sah R. P. (2019). &#x201c;Agricultural research and extension system in Nepal: an organizational review&#x201d; in Agricultural transformation in Nepal: Trends, prospects, and policy options (Singapore: Springer Singapore; ), 291&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baul T., Karlan D., Toyama K., Vasilaky K. (2024). Improving smallholder agriculture via video-based group extension. J. Dev. Econ. 169:103267. doi: 10.1016/j.jdeveco.2024.103267,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdeveco.2024.103267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11636748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39669541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen M. J., Lemma M. (2011). Agricultural extension services and gender equality: An institutional analysis of four districts in Ethiopia (IFPRI discussion paper 01094). Washington, D.C., USA: International Food Policy Research Institute, 1&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. W. (2014). Research design: Qualitative, quantitative, and mixed methods approaches. 4th Edn. California, USA: SAGE Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtin H. M., Reynolds T., Tobin D. (2024). Gender, access to agricultural extension, and seed sourcing among small-scale farmers in Uganda. J. Int. Agric. Ext. Educ. 31, 109&#x2013;126. doi: 10.4148/2831-5960.1157</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4148/2831-5960.1157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dar M. H., Waza S. A., Nayak S., Chakravorty R., Zaidi N. W., Hossain M. (2020). Gender focused training and knowledge enhances the adoption of climate resilient seeds. Technol. Soc. 63:101388. doi: 10.1016/j.techsoc.2020.101388,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techsoc.2020.101388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devkota D. (2005). Gender and ethnicity dimensions in relation to access to and control over household resources in Nepal. J. Inst. Agric. Anim. Sci. 26, 135&#x2013;141. doi: 10.3126/jiaas.v26i0.666</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jiaas.v26i0.666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devkota N., Phuyal R. K., Shrestha D. L. (2018). Perception, determinants and barriers for the adoption of climate change adaptation options among Nepalese rice farmers. Agricultual Sciecnces 9, 272&#x2013;278. doi: 10.4236/as.2018.93021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/as.2018.93021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhakal S., Mishra B. P. (2022). Adoption of new improved rice varieties among smallholder farmers in Lamjung district, Nepal. Nepalese J. Agric. Sci. 22, 55&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhungana J. (2022). Determinants for adoption of foundation rice seed production: evidence from Kailali district of Nepal. J. Agric. For. Univ. 5, 53&#x2013;60. doi: 10.3126/jafu.v5i1.48442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jafu.v5i1.48442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doss C. R. (2001). Designing agricultural technology for African women farmers: lessons from 25 years of experience. World Dev. 29, 2075&#x2013;2092. doi: 10.1016/S0305-750X(01)00088-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0305-750X(01)00088-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO (2019). Country gender assessment of agriculture and the rural sector in Nepal. Kathmandu: Food and Agricultural Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gali&#xe8; A., Mulema A., Mora Benard M. A., Onzere S. N., Colverson K. E. (2015). Exploring gender perceptions of resource ownership and their implications for food security among rural livestock owners in Tanzania, Ethiopia, and Nicaragua. Agric. Food Secur. 4:2. doi: 10.1186/s40066-015-0021-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40066-015-0021-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gartaula H. N., Niehof A., Visser L. (2012). Socio-cultural dispositions and wellbeing of the women left behind: a case of migrant households in Nepal. Soc. Indic. Res. 108, 401&#x2013;420. doi: 10.18848/1833-1882/CGP/v05i02/51588</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18848/1833-1882/CGP/v05i02/51588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3400758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22875999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautam D., Dhakal S. C., Kattel R. R., Khanal N. P. (2025). Determinants of improved seed adoption and intensity in lentil farming: evidence from Terai region of Nepal. Cogent Food Agric. 11:2545596. doi: 10.1080/23311932.2025.2545596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311932.2025.2545596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gezimu G. G., Isoda H., Bahadur R. D., Yuichiro A., Hisako N. (2021). Gender differences in agricultural productivity: evidence from maize farm households in southern Ethiopia. GeoJournal. 86, 843&#x2013;864. doi: 10.1007/s10708-019-10098-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10708-019-10098-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8550121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34720354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurung B. (2023). Role of gender, improved agricultural technology and non-farm employment in household wellbeing in Nepal. USA: Michigan State University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaishi M., Allen R., Sahi L. (2015). Challenges and issues of decentralized agriculture service at the VDC level: experiences from Okhaldhunga district. J. Inst. Agric. Anim. Sci. 33, 79&#x2013;90. doi: 10.3126/jiaas.v33i0.20689</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jiaas.v33i0.20689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi B. K., Sapkota S., Poudyal K., Singh D., Ghimire K. H., Paudel M. N. (2016). Bibliography of agricultural plant genetic resources in Nepal. Kathmandu: National Agriculture Genetic Resources Center, Nepal Agricultural Research Council, Khumaltar.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koirala S. (2022). Women&#x2019;s land ownership and gender equality in Nepal. J. Appl. Soc. Sci. 16, 533&#x2013;547. doi: 10.1177/19367244221077624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19367244221077624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecoutere E., Spielman D. J., Van Campenhout B. (2023). Empowering women through targeting information or role models: evidence from an experiment in agricultural extension in Uganda. World Dev. 167:106240. doi: 10.1016/j.worlddev.2023.106240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2023.106240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odame H. H., Hafkin N., Wesseler G., Boto I. (2002). Gender and agriculture in the information society. The Hague, The Netherlands: International Service for National Agricultural Research (ISNAR).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozcatalbas O., Ozkan B. (2003). The role of women in agriculture and rural development in Turkey. Asian J. Womens Stud. 9, 114&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1080/12259276.2003.11665961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/12259276.2003.11665961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paudel G. P., Gartaula H., Craufurd P. (2020). Gender differentiated small-scale farm mechanization in Nepal hills: an application of exogenous switching treatment regression. Technol. Soc. 61:101250. doi: 10.1016/j.techsoc.2020.101250,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techsoc.2020.101250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7249500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32476696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paudyal B. R., Chanana N., Khatri-Chhetri A., Sherpa L., Kadariya I., Aggarwal P. (2019). Gender integration in climate change and agricultural policies: the case of Nepal. Front. Sustain. Food Syst. 3, 1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.3389/fsufs.2019.00066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2019.00066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quisumbing A. R., Meinzen-Dick R., Raney T. L., Croppenstedt A., Behrman J. A., Peterman A. (2014). &#x201c;Closing the knowledge gap on gender in agriculture&#x201d; in Gender in agriculture. eds. Quisumbing A. R., Meinzen-Dick R., Raney T. L., Croppenstedt A., Behrman J. A., Peterman A. (Dordrecht, Netherlands: Springer Netherlands; ), 3&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragasa C., Berhane G., Tadesse F., Taffesse A. S. (2013). Gender differences in access to extension services and agricultural productivity. J. Agric. Educ. Extens. 19, 437&#x2013;468. doi: 10.1080/1389224X.2013.817343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1389224X.2013.817343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman T., Ara S., Khan N. A. (2020). Agro-information service and information-seeking behaviour of small-scale farmers in rural Bangladesh. Asia Pac. J. Rural Dev. 30, 175&#x2013;194. doi: 10.1177/1018529120977259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1018529120977259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penchansky R., Thomas J. W. (1981). The concept of access: definition and relationship to consumer satisfaction. Medical care. 19, 127&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7206846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saurman E. (2016). Improving access: modifying Penchansky and Thomas&#x2019;s theory of access. J. Health Serv. Res. Policy 21, 36&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1177/1355819615600001,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1355819615600001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26377728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha A., Gartoulla R. P. (2015). Socio-cultural causes of gender disparity in Nepalese society. J. Adv. Acad. Res. 2, 100&#x2013;111. doi: 10.3126/jaar.v2i1.16601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jaar.v2i1.16601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulaiman R. V. (2010). &#x201c;Extension and innovation systems in agricultural development&#x201d; in Agricultural innovation systems: An investment sourcebook (Washington DC: World Bank; ), 119&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamang S. (2019). Feminisation of local communities and its impact on food security in rural Nepal. Doctoral dissertation, UNSW Sydney. Sydney, Australia: The University of New South Wales.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tambo J. A., Matimelo M., Ndhlovu M., Mbugua F., Phiri N. (2021). Gender-differentiated impacts of plant clinics on maize productivity and food security: evidence from Zambia. World Dev. 145:105519. doi: 10.1016/j.worlddev.2021.105519</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2021.105519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa S., Jamkatel D. P., Bharati S., Bam S. (2020). Survey on gender role in rice production by farmers of Nuwakot district, Nepal. Arch. Agric. Environ. Sci. 5, 164&#x2013;167. doi: 10.26832/24566632.2020.0502012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26832/24566632.2020.0502012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa A., Shrestha D., Baudhacharya N., Ramtel R., Thapa S., Poudel S. (2020). Information and communication technology (ICT) mediated extension services in agriculture in Nepal-a review. Acta Inform. Malays. 4, 33&#x2013;36. doi: 10.26480/aim.02.2020.33.36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26480/aim.02.2020.33.36</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timalsina S., Shrestha B. (2023). Effect of priming on seed germination characteristics of spring rice (<i>Oryza sativa</i> cv. Hardinath Hybrid-1) in Chandrapur, Rautahat, Nepal. J. Res. Appl. Sci. Biotechnol.
2, 94&#x2013;100. doi: 10.55544/jrasb.2.6.13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55544/jrasb.2.6.13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timsina K. P., Subedi S., Pandey S., Devkota D., Aryal A., Lamichhane J. (2023). Reforming agricultural extension system in Nepal: what can we adopt from selected agriculture led countries. J. Nepal Agric. Res. Counc. 9, 1&#x2013;21. doi: 10.3126/jnarc.v9i1.61513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jnarc.v9i1.61513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari P., Shingh S. (2020). Gender inequality in Nepalese agriculture: issues concerning sustainability and food security. Int. J. Environ. Agric. Biotechnol. 5, 451&#x2013;458. doi: 10.22161/ijeab.52.19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22161/ijeab.52.19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upreti B. R., Ghale Y., Shivakoti S., Acharya S. (2018). Feminization of agriculture in the Eastern Hills of Nepal: a study of women in cardamom and ginger farming. SAGE Open 8:2158244018817124. doi: 10.1177/2158244018817128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2158244018817128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>