<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41663565</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leveraging zeta potential as a surface charge metric for trapping and killing of airborne bacteria.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8115</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-38958-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Airborne microorganisms significantly contribute to hospital-associated infections (HAIs), particularly causing respiratory tract infections (RTIs). The spread of Multi-Drug Resistant (MDR) airborne bacteria further complicates disease prevention, challenging existing infection control strategies. Current air decontamination technologies are found to have limitations, necessitating novel approaches. In this study, we demonstrated the utility of zeta potential, a natural physicochemical electro-kinetic property of bacteria as a key target, which can be exploited to trap and eliminate MDR airborne bacteria. Multiple respiratory pathogens were included in the study, harbouring various resistance phenotypes. Zeta potentials of these clinical isolates were measured and compared against corresponding ATCC strains. Clinical isolates were aerosolized in a certified BSL-2 setting containing a ZeBox-powered air sterilization device. Viable bacteria were enumerated at various time points, before and after exposure to the air decontamination device. Our analyses revealed that Zeta potential is relatively independent of the origin and antibiotic susceptibility of the tested isolates. Exposure to ZeBox powered device for 5&#xa0;min resulted in a minimum of 5 log reduction (99.999%) among majority of the isolates, irrespective of their genus and origin. Zeta potential measurements correlated to the kill kinetics of ZeBox technology. The current study underscores the reliability of zeta potential based air decontamination technologies such as ZeBox for potential elimination of diverse, airborne respiratory pathogens in healthcare and domestic settings, offering a promising strategy to combat HAIs in post antibiotic and post pandemic era.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-38958-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Peketi</LastName><ForeName>Arun Sai Kumar</ForeName><Initials>ASK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Sri Sathya Sai Institute of Higher Learning, Vidyagiri, Prasanthi Nilayam, Puttaparthi, 515134, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Svl</LastName><ForeName>Sai Kushal Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SKK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Sri Sathya Sai Institute of Higher Learning, Vidyagiri, Prasanthi Nilayam, Puttaparthi, 515134, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P</LastName><ForeName>Kennedy Kumar</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Sri Ramachandra Medical Center, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Porur, Chennai, 600116, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rangineni</LastName><ForeName>Jayaprada</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Sri Venkateswara Institute of Medical Sciences, Tirupati, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veeraraghavan</LastName><ForeName>Balaji</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Microbiology, Christian Medical College, Vellore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bulagonda</LastName><ForeName>Eswarappa Pradeep</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Sri Sathya Sai Institute of Higher Learning, Vidyagiri, Prasanthi Nilayam, Puttaparthi, 515134, Andhra Pradesh, India. bepradeep@sssihl.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Air sterilization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ESKAPE pathogens.</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-drug resistant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory tract infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zeta potential</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted following approval from the Institutional Ethics Committee (IEC) of Sri Sathya Sai Institute of Higher Learning (SSSIHL/IEC/PSN/BS/2014/03) and Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Porur, Chennai (IEC-NI/20/JAN/73/04) in accordance with the ethical standards of the Declaration of Helsinki. informed consent was obtained from all subjects and/or their legal guardian(s).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41663565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12960660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-38958-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-38958-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ghimire, P., Gachhadar, R., Piya, N., Shrestha, K. &amp; Shrestha, K. Prevalence and factors associated with acute respiratory infection among under-five children in selected tertiary hospitals of Kathmandu Valley. <i>PLOS ONE</i>. <b>17</b>, e0265933. 10.1371/journal.pone.0265933 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0265933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8989212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35390028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regha, I. &amp; B, S. Bacteriological profile and antibiotic susceptibility patterns of lower respiratory tract infections in a tertiary care hospital, central Kerala. <i>IP Int. J. Med. Microbiol. Trop. Dis.</i><b>4</b>, 186&#x2013;190 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray, C. J. L. et al. Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance in 2019: a systematic analysis. <i>Lancet</i><b>399</b>, 629&#x2013;655. 10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02724-0 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02724-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8841637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35065702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshwara, V. K., Mukhopadhyay, C. &amp; Rello, J. Community-acquired bacterial pneumonia in adults: an update. <i>Indian J. Med. Res.</i><b>151</b>, 287&#x2013;302. 10.4103/ijmr.IJMR_1678_19 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijmr.IJMR_1678_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7371062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32461392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dandona, L. et al. Nations within a nation: variations in epidemiological transition across the States of India, 1990&#x2013;2016 in the global burden of disease study. <i>Lancet</i><b>390</b>, 2437&#x2013;2460. 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32804-0 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32804-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5720596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29150201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmah, N., Sarmah, A. &amp; Das, D. K. A study on the Microbiological profile of respiratory tract infection (RTI) in patients attending Gauhati medical college &amp; hospital. <i>Annals Int. Med. Dent. Res.</i><b>2</b>, MB11&#x2013;MB15 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21276/aimdr.2016.2.5.MB3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phadke, K. S. et al. Novel Non intrusive continuous use ZeBox technology to trap and kill airborne microbes. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>11</b>, 22779. 10.1038/s41598-021-02184-4 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-02184-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8610990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34815494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayan, R., Kundu, D., Ghatak, A., Tripathi, S. &amp; Datta, S. Efficient elimination of airborne pathogens: a study on aerosolized <i>Mycobacterium tuberculosis</i> and SARS-CoV-2 using ZeBox technology. <i>J. Hosp. Infect.</i><b>129</b>, 17&#x2013;21. 10.1016/j.jhin.2022.07.021 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhin.2022.07.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9354421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35940288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soon, R. L. et al. Different surface charge of colistin-susceptible and -resistant <i>Acinetobacter baumannii</i> cells measured with zeta potential as a function of growth phase and colistin treatment. <i>J. Antimicrob. Chemother.</i><b>66</b>, 126&#x2013;133. 10.1093/jac/dkq422 (2010).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3001852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21081544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito, F. et al. Detection of Colistin-Resistant MCR-1-Positive <i>Escherichia coli</i> by use of assays based on Inhibition by EDTA and zeta potential. <i>J. Clin. Microbiol.</i><b>55</b>, 3454&#x2013;3465. 10.1128/jcm.00835-17 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jcm.00835-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5703812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28978685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavoie, T., Daffinee, K. E., Vicent, M. L. &amp; LaPlante, K. L. <i>Staphylococcus</i> biofilm dynamics and antibiotic resistance: insights into biofilm stages, zeta potential dynamics, and antibiotic susceptibility. <i>Microbiol. Spectr.</i><b>13</b>, e02915&#x2013;02924. 10.1128/spectrum.02915-24 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/spectrum.02915-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12054104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40135862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CLSI. Performance Standards for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing, 34th Edition. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute USA. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magiorakos, A. P. et al. Multidrug-resistant, extensively drug-resistant and pandrug-resistant bacteria: an international expert proposal for interim standard definitions for acquired resistance. <i>Clin. Microbiol. Infection: Official Publication Eur. Soc. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.</i><b>18</b>, 268&#x2013;281. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03570.x (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03570.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21793988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaraj, S. et al. Effectiveness of a novel, non-intrusive, continuous-use air decontamination technology to reduce microbial contamination in clinical settings: a multi-centric study. <i>J. Hosp. Infect.</i><b>123</b>, 15&#x2013;22. 10.1016/j.jhin.2022.02.002 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhin.2022.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35181400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>