<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41446341</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2055-2076</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sensory-driven micro-interventions for improved health and wellbeing.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20552076251408522</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20552076251408522</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20552076251408522</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20552076251408522</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The five senses are gateways to our wellbeing and their decline is considered a significant public health challenge, which is linked to multiple conditions that contribute significantly to morbidity and mortality. Modern technology, with its ubiquitous nature and fast data processing, has the ability to leverage the power of the senses to transform our approach to day-to-day healthcare, with positive effects on our quality of life. Here, we introduce the idea of 'sensory-driven micro-interventions' for preventive, personalised healthcare. Micro-interventions are targeted, timely, minimally invasive strategies that seamlessly integrate into our daily lives. This idea harnesses humans' sensory capabilities, leverages technological advances in sensory stimulation, and real-time processing ability for "sensing the senses." The collection of sensory data from our continuous interaction with technology (e.g. tone of voice, gait movement, and smart home behaviour) opens up a shift towards personalised technology-enabled, sensory-focused healthcare interventions, coupled with the potential of early detection and timely treatment of sensory deficits that can signal critical health insights, especially for neurodegenerative diseases such as Parkinson's disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdalla</LastName><ForeName>Youssef</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCL School of Pharmacy, Research Department of Pharmaceutics, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gatti</LastName><ForeName>Elia</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orlu</LastName><ForeName>Mine</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCL School of Pharmacy, Research Department of Pharmaceutics, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obrist</LastName><ForeName>Marianna</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4009-1627</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101690863</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-2076</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Senses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hearing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">micro-intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personal health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personalised wellbeing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory integration therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory substitution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensory training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smell</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">taste</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">touch</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vision</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: M.Ob. is Chief Scientific Officer (CSO) and co-founder of Hynt Labs Limited, developing digitally controlled multi-channel scent-delivery devices that are validated for smell testing and olfactory training.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41446341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12722656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076251408522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20552076251408522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shams L, Beierholm U. Humans&#x2019; multisensory perception, from integration to segregation, follows Bayesian inference. In: Sensory cue integration. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2011, pp.251&#x2013;261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence C. Scent and the cinema. Iperception 2020; 11: 2041669520969710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7691926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33282170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard JR, Officer A, de Carvalho IA, et al. The World report on ageing and health: a policy framework for healthy ageing. Lancet 2016; 387: 2145&#x2013;2154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4848186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26520231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HJ, Kim JS, Kim YJ, et al. Sensory impairment and health-related quality of life. Iran J Public Health 2015; 44: 772&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4524301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26258089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine SE, Philpott CM. An unmet need: patients with smell and taste disorders. Clin Otolaryngol 2020; 45: 197&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31856420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel T, Rissom K, Reden J, et al. Effects of olfactory training in patients with olfactory loss. Laryngoscope 2009; 119: 496&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19235739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Be&#x15f;evli C, Dawes C, Brianza G, et al. Nose gym: an interactive smell training solution. In: Extended Abstracts of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, 2023, Article 464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desiato VM, Levy DA, Byun YJ, et al. The prevalence of olfactory dysfunction in the general population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Rhinol Allergy 2021; 35: 195&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32746612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlosser RJ, Desiato VM, Storck KA, et al. A community-based study on the prevalence of olfactory dysfunction. Am J Rhinol Allergy 2020; 34: 661&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7705196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32345032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornbury JM, Mistretta CM. Tactile sensitivity as a function of age. J Gerontol 1981; 36: 34&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7451834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer SW, Harrison AL. Aging of the somatosensory system: a translational perspective. Phys Ther 2007; 87: 193&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17244695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wormald RP, Wright LA, Courtney P, et al. Visual problems in the elderly population and implications for services. Br Med J 1992; 304: 1226&#x2013;1229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1881785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1515797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XZ, Yan D. Ageing and hearing loss. J Pathol 2007; 211: 188&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17200945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross H, Armitage CJ, Dawes P, et al. &#x201c;We&#x2019;re just winging it&#x201d;. Identifying targets for intervention to improve the provision of hearing support for residents living with dementia in long-term care: an interview study with care staff. Disabil Rehabil 2024; 46: 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11259204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37641847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS. Symptoms of transient ischemic attack. Front Neurol Neurosci 2014; 33: 82&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24157558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jariyakosol S, Peragallo JH. The effects of primary brain tumors on vision and quality of life in pediatric patients. Semin Neurol 2015; 35: 587&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26444404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai RE, Feller DJ, Galetta KM, et al. Vision in multiple sclerosis: the story, structure-function correlations, and models for neuroprotection. J Neuroophthalmol 2011; 31: 362&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3427931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacova A, Shotliff K. Eye problems in people with diabetes: more than just diabetic retinopathy. Pract Diabetes 2022; 39: 34&#x2013;9a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai N, Maggioni E, Obrist M, et al. Scent-delivery devices as a digital healthcare tool for olfactory training: a pilot focus group study in Parkinson's disease patients. Digit Health 2022; 8: 20552076221129061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9530561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36204704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Cheng C, Lu L, et al. Hearing loss in neurological disorders. Front Cell Dev Biol 2021; 9: 716300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8385440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34458270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langdon R, McGuire J, Stevenson R, et al. Clinical correlates of olfactory hallucinations in schizophrenia. Br J Clin Psychol 2011; 50: 145&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21545448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haehner A, Hummel T, Reichmann H. Olfactory loss in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsons Dis 2011; 2011: 450939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3109349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21687752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopper R, Popa D, Maggioni E, et al. Multi-channel portable odor delivery device for self-administered and rapid smell testing. Commun Eng 2024; 3: 141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11470141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39394479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paredes P, Gilad-Bachrach R, Czerwinski M, et al. (eds) PopTherapy: coping with stress through pop-culture. In: Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Pervasive Computing Technologies for Healthcare, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinlschmidt G, Lee J-H, Stalujanis E, et al. Smartphone-based psychotherapeutic micro-interventions to improve mood in a real-world setting. Front Psychol 2016; 7: 1112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4963605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27516747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elefant AB, Contreras O, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, et al. Microinterventions produce immediate but not lasting benefits in mood and distress. Internet Interv 2017; 10: 17&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5734669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29270366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller-Tyszkiewicz M, Richardson B, Lewis V, et al. A randomized trial exploring mindfulness and gratitude exercises as eHealth-based micro-interventions for improving body satisfaction. Comput Human Behav 2019; 95: 58&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malouff J, Johnson C. Effects of a micro-intervention aimed at reducing the level of unpleasant dreams. Int J Dream Res 2020; 13: 115&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Witte M, Knapen A, Stams G-J, et al. Development of a music therapy micro-intervention for stress reduction. Arts Psychother 2022; 77: 101872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kattenberg K. Supporting nurses&#x2019; daily self-regulated learning behaviour via an online micro-intervention. Enschede: University of Twente, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Entenberg GA, Mizrahi S, Walker H, et al. AI-based chatbot micro-intervention for parents: meaningful engagement, learning, and efficacy. Front Psychiatry 2023; 14: 1080770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9895389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36741110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahum-Shani I, Smith SN, Spring BJ, et al. Just-in-Time Adaptive Interventions (JITAIs) in mobile health: key components and design principles for ongoing health behavior support. Ann Behav Med 2017; 52: 446&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5364076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27663578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cloutier R, Horr S, Niemi JB, et al. Prolonged mechanical noise restores tactile sense in diabetic neuropathic patients. Int J Low Extrem Wounds 2009; 8: 6&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19129201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochoa N, Gogola GR, Gorniak SL. Contribution of tactile dysfunction to manual motor dysfunction in type II diabetes. Muscle Nerve 2016; 54: 895&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6645679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27061801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simoneau GG, Ulbrecht JS, Derr JA, et al. Role of somatosensory input in the control of human posture. Gait Posture 1995; 3: 115&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley S. Perception and action: alternative views. Synthese 2001; 129: 3&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aman JE, Elangovan N, Yeh I-L, et al. The effectiveness of proprioceptive training for improving motor function: a systematic review. Front Hum Neurosci 2015; 8: 1075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4309156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25674059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelbaum LG, Lu Y, Khanna R, et al. The effects of sports vision training on sensorimotor abilities in collegiate softball athletes. Athl Train Sports Health Care 2016; 8: 154&#x2013;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Runge M, Rehfeld G, Resnicek E. Balance training and exercise in geriatric patients. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 2000; 1: 61&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15758528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton-Fletcher G, Alvarez J, Obrist M, et al. Soundsight: a mobile sensory substitution device that sonifies colour, distance, and temperature. J Multimodal User Interf 2022; 16: 107&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macpherson F. Sensory substitution and augmentation: An introduction. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deroy O, Auvray M. Reading the world through the skin and ears: a new perspective on sensory substitution. Front Psychol 2012; 3: 457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3491585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23162506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenay C, Canu S, Villon P. (eds) Technology and perception: the contribution of sensory substitution systems. In: Proceedings Second International Conference on Cognitive Technology Humanizing the Information Age, 25&#x2013;28 August 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach-y-Rita P. Tactile sensory substitution studies. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2004; 1013: 83&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15194608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanayakkara S, Taylor E, Wyse L, et al. An enhanced musical experience for the deaf: design and evaluation of a music display and a haptic chair. In: Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, 2009, pp.337&#x2013;346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frid E, Lindetorp H. (eds) Haptic music: exploring whole-body vibrations and tactile sound for a multisensory music installation. In: Sound and Music Computing Conferencem Torino, 24&#x2013;26 June 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith T, Mruzek DW, Mozingo D. Sensory integration therapy. Controversial therapies for autism and intellectual disabilities. London: Routledge, 2015, pp.247&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh H, Kim K. Effect of a multi-sensory play therapy program on the attention and learning of children with ADHD. J Korean Soc Integr Med 2019; 7: 23&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez M, Kross E. Sensory emotion regulation. Trends Cogn Sci 2023; 27: 379&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36805103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodabakhshi MK, Malekpour M, Abedi A. The effect of sensory integration therapy on social interactions and sensory and motor performance in children with autism. Iran J Cognit Educ 2014; 1: 39&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packheiser J, Hartmann H, Fredriksen K, et al. A systematic review and multivariate meta-analysis of the physical and mental health benefits of touch interventions. Nat Hum Behav 2024; 6: 1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11199149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38589702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumel A, Fleming T, Schueller SM. Digital micro interventions for behavioral and mental health gains: core components and conceptualization of digital micro intervention care. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e20631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7661243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33118946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz RF, Bunge EL, Chen K, et al. Massive open online interventions: a novel model for delivering behavioral-health services worldwide. Clin Psychol Sci 2015; 4: 194&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasser AT, Kushalnagar KR, Kushalnagar RS. (eds) Feasibility of using automatic speech recognition with voices of deaf and hard-of-hearing individuals. In: Proceedings of the 19th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelio P, Vi CT, Brianza G, et al. Smell and taste-based interactions enabled through advances in digital technology. In: Handbook of human computer interaction. Switzerland: Springer, 2023, pp.1&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velasco C, Obrist M. Multisensory experiences: where the senses meet technology. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristj&#xe1;nsson &#xc1;, Moldoveanu A, J&#xf3;hannesson &#xd3;I, et al. Designing sensory-substitution devices: principles, pitfalls and potential 1. Restor Neurol Neurosci 2016; 34: 769&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5044782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27567755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaczmarek KA. The tongue display unit (TDU) for electrotactile spatiotemporal pattern presentation. Sci Iran 2011; 18: 1476&#x2013;1485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5523951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28748231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancar L, D&#xed;az A, Barrientos A, et al. Tactile-sight: a sensory substitution device based on distance-related vibrotactile flow. Int J Adv Rob Syst 2013; 10: 272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzaei M, K&#xe1;n P, Kaufmann H. (eds) Head up visualization of spatial sound sources in virtual reality for deaf and hard-of-hearing people. In: 2021 IEEE Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces (VR), 2021. IEEE.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher MD. Can haptic stimulation enhance music perception in hearing-impaired listeners? Front Neurosci 2021; 15: 723877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8439542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34531717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cie&#x15b;la K, Wolak T, Lorens A, et al. Effects of training and using an audio-tactile sensory substitution device on speech-in-noise understanding. Sci Rep 2022; 12: 3206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8881456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35217676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green CS, Bavelier D. Effect of action video games on the spatial distribution of visuospatial attention. J Exp Psychol Hum Percept Perform 2006; 32: 1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2896828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17154785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merzenich MM, Jenkins WM, Johnston P, et al. Temporal processing deficits of language-learning impaired children ameliorated by training. Science 1996; 271: 77&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8539603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey LM, Matyas TA, Oke LE. Sensory loss in stroke patients: effective training of tactile and proprioceptive discrimination. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 1993; 74: 602&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8503750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miotto R, Wang F, Wang S, et al. Deep learning for healthcare: review, opportunities and challenges. Brief Bioinform 2018; 19: 1236&#x2013;1246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6455466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28481991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzo A, Seah SA, Drinkwater BW, et al. Holographic acoustic elements for manipulation of levitated objects. Nat Commun 2015; 6: 8661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26505138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>