<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41403492</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2249-4863</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of family medicine and primary care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Family Med Prim Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and link of academic stress and depressive symptoms among school-going adolescents in Manipur, India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4783</StartPage><EndPage>4792</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4783-4792</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_890_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Academic stress and depressive symptoms are major mental health concerns among adolescents globally and in India. However, limited research has examined their association in Manipur, a northeastern state of India. This study assessed the prevalence of academic stress and depressive symptoms, their association, and group differences by sociodemographic variables among school-going adolescents in Manipur.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A cross-sectional survey was conducted among 861 students in grades 9-12 from six private schools in Manipur. Data were collected via self-administered questionnaires between August and October 2024. Analyses included descriptive statistics, Pearson's correlation, multiple linear regression, <i>t</i>-tests, and ANOVA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">All participants reported moderate to high academic stress, and a majority experienced mild to severe depressive symptoms. Academic stress was positively correlated with depressive symptoms and significantly predicted them (&#x3b2; =0.37, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001), indicating that higher stress levels were associated with higher depressive symptom scores. Female students and those with the lowest academic results (3<sup>rd</sup> division: 33%-45%) reported significantly higher depressive symptoms (&#x3b2; =1.90, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001; &#x3b2; =2.33, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The model showed moderate explanatory power (<i>R</i> = 0.571, <i>R</i> <sup>2</sup> = 0.326, <i>F</i> = 45.81, <i>P</i> &lt; 0.001). Significant group differences were found across gender (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01), hometown (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01), and grade (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Academic stress levels were alarmingly high and significantly associated with depressive symptoms among adolescents. Future studies should explore school-based interventions to address academic stress and promote mental health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khumanlambam</LastName><ForeName>Ravina</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Education and Behavioral Sciences, Faculty of Public Health, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pengpid</LastName><ForeName>Supa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Education and Behavioral Sciences, Faculty of Public Health, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kengganpanich</LastName><ForeName>Mondha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Education and Behavioral Sciences, Faculty of Public Health, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peltzer</LastName><ForeName>Karl</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Education and Behavioral Sciences, Faculty of Public Health, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, College of Medical and Health Science, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Rajkumar Lenin</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Regional Institute of Medical Sciences, Imphal, Manipur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Family Med Prim Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610082</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2249-4863</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Academic stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">correlation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-sectional study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depressive symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">school-going adolescents</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41403492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12705016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_890_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JFMPC-14-4783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Guo H, Yang W, Cao Y, Li J, Siegrist J. Effort-reward imbalance at school and depressive symptoms in Chinese adolescents: The role of family socioeconomic status. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2014;11:6085&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4078567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24919130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neseliler S, Tannenbaum B, Zacchia M, Larcher K, Coulter K, Lamarche M, et al. Academic stress and personality interact to increase the neural response to high-calorie food cues. Appetite. 2017;116:306&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28487246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wunsch K, Kasten N, Fuchs R. The effect of physical activity on sleep quality, well-being, and affect in academic stress periods. Nat Sci Sleep. 2017;9:117&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5414656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs. Policy Brief No. 153. New York: United Nations;  [Last accessed on 2023 Apr 07]. India overtakes China as the world's most populous country. Available from:https://desapublications.un.org/file/18475/download .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNICEF/Das. Empowering adolescent girls and boys in India.  Available from:https://www.unicef.org/india/what-we-do/adolescent-development-participation .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb S, Strodl E, Sun J. Academic stress, parental pressure, anxiety and mental health among indian high school students. Int J Psychol Behav Sci. 2015;5:26&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George AS. Insights into the competitive landscape of indian entrance exam market: A comprehensive survey. Partn Univ Int Innov J. 2023;01:63&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences. Bengaluru: NIMHANS Publication, Ministry of Health and Family Welfare, Government of India; 2016. National Mental Health Survey of India, 2015&#x2013;16: Prevalence, Patterns and Outcomes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilpa DM, Sulochanadevi BC, Shashirekha B. Influence of academic stress and home environment on adolescent mental health. J Ecophysiol Occup Health. 2025;25:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schimelpfening N. Common Causes of Depression. Verywell Mind. 2023.  [Last updated on 2023 Jun 16].  Available from:https://www.verywellmind.com/common-causes-of-depression-1066772 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonam, Mahapatra AK, Rajagopala S, Kumar A, Gupta PK, Rishabh, et al. Prevalence of depression and anxiety among school going adolescents of Delhi: A cross-sectional study. J Family Med Prim Care. 2025;14:592&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11922383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40115585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanthi P, Thirunavukarasu M, Rajkumar R. Academic stress and depression among adolescents: A cross-sectional study. Indian Pediatr. 2015;52:217&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25848997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoa DT, Deb S, Dunne M, Baker P, Sun H. Analyzing the role of parents in the association between academic stress and depression among Indian adolescents. Viet J Prev Med. 2016;26:64&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Oh Y. The mediator role of perceived stress in the relationship between academic stress and depressive symptoms among e-learning students with visual impairments. J Vis Impair Blind. 2017;111:123&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena SK, Mani RN, Dwivedi AK, Ryali V, Timothy A. Association of educational stress with depression, anxiety, and substance use among medical and engineering undergraduates in India. Ind Psychiatry J. 2019;28:160&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7660013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33223707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;fstedt P, Garc&#xed;a-Moya I, Corell M, Paniagua C, Samdal O, V&#xe4;limaa R, et al. School satisfaction and school pressure in the WHO European Region and North America: An Analysis of Time Trends (2002&#x2013;2018) and Patterns of Co-occurrence in 32 Countries. J Adolesc Health. 2020;66((6, Supplement)):S59&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang NY, Westwood P. Worry, General self-efficacy and school achievement: An exploratory study with chinese adolescents. Aust J Guid Couns. 2007;17:68&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragusa A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Bernal J, Trigueros R, Caggiano V, Navarro N, Minguez-Minguez L, et al. Effects of academic self-regulation on procrastination, academic stress and anxiety, resilience and academic performance in a sample of Spanish secondary school students. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1073529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9936312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36818079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Crime Records Bureau MoHA, Govt of India. Year-wise Details of Incidence and Rate of Accidental Deaths in India from 2012 to 2022. 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganguly S, Samanta M, Roy P, Chatterjee S, Kaplan DW, Basu B. Patient health questionnaire-9 as an effective tool for screening of depression among Indian adolescents. J Adolesc Health. 2013;52:546&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23299020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dandona R, Kumar GA, Dhaliwal RS, Naghavi M, Vos T, Shukla DK, et al. Gender differentials and state variations in suicide deaths in India: The Global Burden of Disease Study 1990-2016. Lancet Public Health. 2018;3:e478&#x2013;e89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6178873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30219340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Geneva: WHO; Mental health of adolescents. Available from:https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/adolescent-mental-health .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alee NT, Hasan A, Aijaz A. Mental health and psychological problems in north east India. IAHRW Int J Soc Sci. 2018;6:817&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar KS, Akoijam BS. Depression, Anxiety and stress among higher secondary school students of Imphal, Manipur. Indian J Community Med. 2017;42:94&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5427869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28553025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konjengbam E, Bigyabati R, Suriya P, Rajkumari B. Mental health issues among adolescents in Manipur: A cross sectional study. Int J Acad Med Pharm. 2023;5:893&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh SM. Academic stress among government and private high school students. Int J Indian Psychol. 2016;3:119&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Council of Higher Secondary Education Manipur. 2024 Student census. 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Board of Secondary School Manipur, 2024 student census. 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriati A, Lukman M, Agustina HS. Relation of academic stress levels and internet addiction in adolescents: A cross-sectional study. Malays J Med Health Sci. 2022;18:110&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Dunne MP, Hou XY, Xu AQ. Educational stress scale for adolescents: Development, validity, and reliability with chinese students. J Psychoeduc Assess. 2011;29:534&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ-9: Validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16:606&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K. PHQ-9: Global uptake of a depression scale. World Psychiatry. 2021;20:135&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33432739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JG, Harris ES, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The patient health questionnaire for adolescents: Validation of an instrument for the assessment of mental disorders among adolescent primary care patients. J Adolesc Health. 2002;30:196&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11869927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeelani A, Dkhar SA, Quansar R, Khan SM. Prevalence of depression and anxiety among school-going adolescents in Indian Kashmir valley during COVID-19 pandemic. Middle East Curr Psychiatry. 2022;29:18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santhamma R, Shaji H, Indira S. Prevalence and determinants of academic stress among higher secondary adolescents in South Kerala. Afr J Biol Sci. 2024;6:4644&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandal RK, Goel NK, Sharma MK, Bakshi RK, Singh N, Kumar D. Prevalence of depression, anxiety and stress among school going adolescent in Chandigarh. J Family Med Prim Care. 2017;6:405&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5749094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29302555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Haegele JA, Liu H, Yu F. Academic stress, physical activity, sleep, and mental health among chinese adolescents. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:7257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8304898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chingtham T. Necessary evils of private tuition: A case study. IOSR J Res Method Educ. 2015;5:6&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meitei KT, Ranjan KS, Devi TC, Singh HS. Prevalence of depression among school-going adolescents of Manipur: A preliminary study. Front Anthropol. 2023;11:59&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laporte N, Soenens B, Brenning K, Vansteenkiste M. Adolescents as active managers of their own psychological needs: The role of psychological need crafting in adolescents&#x2019; mental health. J Adolesc. 2021;88:67&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33662706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hilawani Y. The quality of life of normal-achieving and low-achieving participants: Is it associated with IQ and metacognition? Int J Disabil Hum Dev. 2018;17:279&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakola F. Culture, institutions and power: Institutionalisation of cross-border co-operation as a municipal development strategy in Northern Finland. Nordia Geogr Publ. 2019;48:114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang D, Zhang D, Chen Y, He Z, Gao Q, Gu R, et al. Trait anxiety and probabilistic learning: Behavioral and electrophysiological findings. Biol Psychol. 2018;132:17&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29100909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Keung VM, Cheung CK, Lo AS, Chan SC, Pang WS, et al. Factors associated with mental health among Hong Kong children: A population-based study of 4884 individuals. Child Care Health Dev. 2024;50:e13196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37965880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burdzovic Andreas J, Brunborg GS. Individual, family, and community characteristics associated with COVID-19-specific worry and lack of worry among norwegian high school students in first pandemic year. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e220337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8874346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35201311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh MM, Gupta M, Grover S. Prevalence and factors associated with depression among schoolgoing adolescents in Chandigarh, north India. Indian J Med Res. 2017;146:205&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5761030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29265021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamath P, Dsouza SM, Mahapatra S, Jayakumar S. Prevalence of depression among school going adolescents in India: A systematic review and meta-analysis of cross-sectional studies. Int J Community Med Public Health. 2021;8:833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angold A, Costello EJ, Worthman CM. Puberty and depression: The roles of age, pubertal status and pubertal timing. Psychol Med. 1998;28:51&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9483683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasla M. Adolescence depression in Pakistan: A new horizon for research. J Pak Med Stud. 2012;2:160&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava A, K&#xfc;hnen U, Simunovic D, Boehnke K. &#x201c;More&#x201d;or &#x201c;enough&#x201d;?Rural-urban differences in maximizing: The case of India. Curr Res Ecol Soc Psychol. 2023;5:100140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew S. A comparative study on academic stress and coping strategies between adolescents studying in selected urban and rural colleges at Mangalore. Indian J Clin Anat Physiol. 2017;2:124&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa MC, Preethi C. Academic stress and emotional maturity among higher secondary school students of working and non-working mothers. Int J Basic Adv Res. 2012;1:40&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S, Dash AK, Santhakumari R, Yasmeen N, Siddique AR, Khan AD. Depression, anxiety and stress among junior science college students. Int J Health Sci Res. 2017;27:25&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayar DN, Deshpande M, Mudgal S, Pandey R. Depression, anxiety, perceived loneliness among school-going adolescents: A comparative study between hostellers and day boarders. J Med Sci Clin Res. 2018;6:344&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behera S, Paluri S, Mishra A. Mental health status of students pursuing professional training: A questionnaire-based study. J Educ Health Promot. 2021;10:399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8641754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34912935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sri KT, Donipudi PC, Sravya T, Rao RN. A study on prevalence and risk factors of depression among adolescents (16-19 years) in the urban area of Andhra Pradesh. Natl Board Exam J Med Sci. 2024;2:704&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations. New York: United Nations; 2023. The Sustainable Development Goals Report 2023: Special Edition.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>