<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41697165</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2037-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of translational myology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Transl Myol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of foot fixation on muscle activation and power output during the Wingate test in cyclists.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4081/ejtm.2026.14638</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study examined the effect of simulated foot fixation on neuromuscular activation and power output during a 30-second isokinetic Wingate-type test in trained cyclists. Sixteen well-trained male cyclists and triathletes completed two randomized crossover trials under distinct pedal-foot interface conditions: fixed-foot, using standard athletic shoes secured to flat pedals with elastic bandage to restrict vertical movement, and free-foot, using standard shoes without fixation. Surface Electromyography (sEMG) was recorded from the vastus lateralis, vastus medialis, rectus femoris, biceps femoris, and tibialis anterior to quantify muscle activation, while an isokinetic ergometer continuously measured mechanical power. Compared with the free-foot condition, simulated fixation produced significantly higher peak power (1365.3 &#xb1; 153.5 W vs. 1299.0 &#xb1; 150.7 W, p = 0.016, d = 0.68) and mean power (900.6 &#xb1; 88.4 W vs. 838.3 &#xb1; 98.3 W, p &lt; 0.001, d = 1.35), but also a greater fatigue index (47.8 &#xb1; 8.0 % vs. 37.2 &#xb1; 8.5 %, p &lt; 0.001, d = 1.25). Integrated EMG (iEMG) values increased across all monitored muscles, particularly in the rectus femoris, biceps femoris, and tibialis anterior, indicating altered neuromuscular coordination and enhanced activation of biarticular and stabilizing muscles. These findings suggest that mechanical stabilization of the foot-pedal interface enhances torque transmission and short-term power generation but concurrently accelerates fatigue development due to elevated neuromuscular and metabolic demands. The results emphasize a trade-off between instantaneous performance gains and fatigue progression, relevant for interpreting Wingate-type tests and optimizing sprint-specific cycling training and equipment configurations.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Putala</LastName><ForeName>Mat&#xfa;&#x161;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Outdoor Sports and Swimming, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, Comenius University Bratislava.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brunovsk&#xfd;</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Outdoor Sports and Swimming, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, Comenius University Bratislava.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buzgo</LastName><ForeName>Gabiel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological and Medical Sciences, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, Comenius University Bratislava.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliva</LastName><ForeName>Viktor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological and Medical Sciences, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport, Comenius University Bratislava.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Italy</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Transl Myol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576208</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2037-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Foot fixation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cycling biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isokinetic Wingate test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power output</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface EMG</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41697165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ejtm.2026.14638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>1. Neptune RR, Herzog W. Adaptation of muscle coordination to altered task mechanics during steady-state cycling. J Biomech 2000;33:165-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>2. Dorel S, Couturier A, Hug F. Intra-session repeatability of lower limb muscles activation pattern during pedaling. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 2008;18:857-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>3. Hug F, Dorel S. Electromyographic analysis of pedaling: a review. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 2009;19:182-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>4. Korff T, Romer LM, Mayhew I, Martin JC. Effect of pedaling technique on mechanical effectiveness and efficiency in cyclists. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2007;39:991-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>5. Mornieux G, Stapelfeldt B, Gollhofer A, Belli A. Effects of pedal type and pull-up action during cycling. Int J Sports Med 2008;29:817-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>6. Bini RR, Hume PA, Croft JL, Kilding AE. Pedal force effectiveness in cycling: a review of constraints and training effects. Sports Biomech 2013;12:343-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>7. Inbar O, Bar-Or O, Skinner JS. The Wingate anaerobic test. Champaign (IL): Human Kinetics; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>8. Winter EM, Fowler N. Exercise defined and quantified according to the Syst&#xe8;me International d&#x2019;Unit&#xe9;s. J Sports Sci 2009;27:447-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>9. Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Muscle fatigue: what, why and how it influences muscle function. J Physiol 2008;586:11-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>10. Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor-placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 2000;10:361-74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>11. Stewart DG, Macaluso A, De Vito G. Muscle fiber conduction velocity during a 30-s Wingate test. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 2011;21:1072-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>12. Hopkins WG. A scale of magnitudes for effect statistics. Sports Sci 2002;6:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>13. Gaitanos GC, Williams C, Boobis LH, Brooks S. Human muscle metabolism during intermittent maximal exercise. J Appl Physiol 1993;75:712-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>14. Sahlin K. Muscle energetics during explosive activities and potential effects of nutrition and training. Sports Med 2014;44:167-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>15. Martin JC, Brown NAT. Joint-specific power production and fatigue during maximal cycling. J Biomech 2009;42:474-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>16. Arnin J, Yamsa-Ard T, Triponyuwasin P, Wongsawat Y. Development of practical functional electrical stimulation cycling systems based on an electromyography study of the Cybathlon 2016. Eur J Transl Myol 2017;27:7111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>17. Coste CA, Bergeron V, Berkelmans R, et al. Comparison of strategies and performance of functional electrical stimulation cycling in spinal cord injury pilots for competition in the first ever CYBATHLON. Eur J Transl Myol 2017;27:7219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>18. Sanderson DJ, Black A. The effect of prolonged cycling on pedal forces. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2003;35:1607-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>19. Driss T, Vandewalle H. The measurement of maximal (anaerobic) power output on a cycle ergometer: a critical review. Sports Med 2013;43:647-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>20. Hamar, D., Gazovic, O., &amp; Schickhofer, P.. Isokinetic cycle ergometer--application in sports medicine. Wiener medizinische Wochenschrift, 1995;145 22, 606-10.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>