<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41704981</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Shared System-Level Drivers of Unprofessional Conduct During Clinical Rotations Among Medical and Dental Students: An Interpretive Description Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101650</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101650</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101650</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101650</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Unprofessional conduct in clinical education refers to behaviours that deviate from accepted professional norms. These behaviours undermine learner well-being, patient dignity, and the development of professional identity. Findings from previous literature suggest that unprofessional conduct is common in Pakistani clinical training and may be reinforced within clinical environments, potentially through the influence of negative elements of the hidden curriculum. While individual incidents are often reported, less is known about how institutional and system-level factors interact to normalise or hinder mistreatment in low-resource clinical education settings. Therefore, this study aimed to explore final-year medical and dental students' perceptions of shared, system-level drivers of unprofessional conduct during clinical rotations, with the goal of producing practice-oriented recommendations for clinical education. Methodology This interpretive description study was conducted at a private medical and dental college in Multan, Pakistan. Participants were recruited with purposive sampling that included final-year Bachelor of Medicine, Bachelor of Surgery (MBBS) and Bachelor of Dental Surgery (BDS) students who had completed clinical rotations and consented to audio-recording. Data collection continued until interpretive sufficiency was reached. Semi-structured, in-depth interviews were conducted face-to-face using a pilot-tested, expert-validated guide. Recordings were transcribed manually, and data were analysed using iterative immersion, open coding, constant comparison, development of analytic categories, and construction of higher-order themes consistent with interpretive description. Results Interviews revealed five interrelated thematic patterns: (1) hierarchy and power, including unchecked senior authority, social bias, and unfair treatment with paramedical staff; (2) hidden curriculum and norms, including silence and obedience, compensatory acts by clinicians, haphazard training, and informal practices that contradicted formal professionalism teaching; (3) systemic pressures and drivers, including excessive patient loads, resource scarcity and dual-practice incentives which shifted faculty priorities away from clinical teaching and promoted expedient, and instrumental behaviours; (4) challenges to patient-centred practice, where patients were often objectified during teaching, with inadequate communication, privacy breaches, and gendered biases; and (5) student impact and coping, where exposure to unprofessional conduct produced shame, moral distress, and withdrawal, while some students expressed a strong desire for institutional change. Together, these themes indicate that unprofessional behaviour is systemically embedded and socially learned rather than solely individual failings. Conclusions Unprofessional conduct during clinical rotations reflects the combined influence of unregulated power, negative role-modelling in hidden curricula, and system-level constraints rather than isolated individual failings. Addressing these issues requires institutional strategies that protect teaching time, promote respectful supervision, and provide safe, confidential reporting mechanisms. Such approaches can strengthen learner well-being, uphold patient dignity, and reinforce professionalism in clinical education.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Jan et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jan</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Operative Dentistry, Peshawar Dental College, Peshawar, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zain Ul Abideen</LastName><ForeName>Malik</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Education and Research, Bakhtawar Amin Medical and Dental College, Multan, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malik</LastName><ForeName>Maira Sahar</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, Foundation University Medical College, Islamabad, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ajmal</LastName><ForeName>Laila</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paedodontics, CIMS Dental College, Multan, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ul Haq</LastName><ForeName>Usman</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, Wah Medical College, Wah Cantt, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehfooz</LastName><ForeName>Qurat Ul Ain</ForeName><Initials>QUA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Education, Bakhtawar Amin Medical and Dental College, Multan, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tareen</LastName><ForeName>Jawad</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Education and Research, Bakhtawar Amin Medical and Dental College, Multan, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical rotations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health professions education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hidden curriculum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">professionalism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unprofessional behaviour</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Research Board of Bakhtawar Amin Medical and Dental College issued approval 652/24/COD. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41704981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12908510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Professionalism today. Al-Rubaish AM. J Family Community Med. 2010;17:1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3195071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22022663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurturing professional behaviours and ethical practice: from students to professionals. Samarasekera DD, Findyartini A, Soemantri D. Ann Acad Med Singap. 2023;52:444&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38920189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Examining the perception of undergraduate health professional students of their learning environment, learning experience and professional identity development: a mixed-methods study. Mukhalalati B, Aly A, Yakti O, et al. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24:886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11330008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39152424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The graduating European dentist-domain I: professionalism. McLoughlin J, Zijlstra-Shaw S, Davies JR, Field JC. Eur J Dent Educ. 2017;21:11&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29205780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring social responsibility in medical and dental education: a multicenter analysis of faculty perspectives. Abideen MZ, Sheikh GM, Al Zubaidi SM, et al.  https://www.podj.com.pk/index.php/podj/article/view/825 Pak Oral Dent J. 2025;45:33&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intra- and interprofessional practices through fresh eyes: a qualitative analysis of medical students' early workplace experiences. Leedham-Green KE, Knight A, Iedema R. BMC Med Educ. 2019;19:287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6664560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31357970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Community of practice and student interaction at an acute medical ward: an ethnographic study. H&#xe4;gg-Martinell A, Hult H, Henriksson P, Kiessling A. Med Teach. 2016;38:793&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What we don't know we are teaching: unveiling the hidden curriculum. Gofton W, Regehr G. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2006;449:20&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16735868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring professional identity formation among early-career dentists: a qualitative multi-institutional study. Abideen MZ, Sheikh GM, Zubaidi SM, et al.  https://www.podj.com.pk/index.php/podj/article/view/827 Pak Oral Dent J. 2025;45:33&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The hidden curriculum in undergraduate medical education: qualitative study of medical students' perceptions of teaching. Lempp H, Seale C. BMJ. 2004;329:770&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC520997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15459051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Descriptors for unprofessional behaviours of medical students: a systematic review and categorisation. Mak-van der Vossen M, van Mook W, van der Burgt S, Kors J, Ket JC, Croiset G, Kusurkar R. BMC Med Educ. 2017;17:164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5603020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28915870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A narrative review of the unprofessional behaviors of physicians at workplace. Majeed N, Soneye M, Okedere T, et al.  https://journals.uol.edu.pk/medicaleducator/article/view/123 Health Prof Educ J. 2021;4:27&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Professionalism and ethics in medical and dental education: a survey of student perceptions and experiences. Noor S, Ali AN, Ejaz A, et al. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11745842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39840154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring medical professionalism in undergraduate medical students - a cross sectional study. Alamgir N, Khan MA, Mashhadi SF, Naqvi SA. Pak J Med Sci. 2025;41:1586&#x2013;1591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12223745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40621536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A behavioral and systems view of professionalism. Lesser CS, Lucey CR, Egener B, Braddock CH 3rd, Linas SL, Levinson W. JAMA. 2010;304:2732&#x2013;2737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21177508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The experiences of unprofessionalism among students in dental education: a qualitative study. Keshmiri F. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25:24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11706114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39762791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The analytic challenge in interpretive description. Thorne SE, Reimer-Kirkham S, O&#x2019;Flynn-Magee K. Int J Qual Methods. 2004;3:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canva. 2024. https://www.canva.com/ https://www.canva.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exploring unprofessional behaviors and biased perceptions in the clinical environment: students' perspectives. Song X, Willy MJ. Med Sci Educ. 2024;34:1049&#x2013;1057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11496485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39450026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriers to medical error reporting. Poorolajal J, Rezaie S, Aghighi N. Int J Prev Med. 2015;6:97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4629296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role modeling kindness at the bedside. Fine L, Takla T, Rajput V. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11046334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38681372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incentives for clinical teachers: on why their complex influences should lead us to proceed with caution. Wisener KM, Driessen EW, Cuncic C, Hesse CL, Eva KW. Med Educ. 2021;55:614&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33222291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An internal perspective: the psychological impact of mistreatment. Yau BN, Chen AS, Montgomery KB, Dubuque N, McDowelle DM. Acad Psychiatry. 2021;45:308&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33709287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emotional experiences of undergraduate medical students: a qualitative perspective. Khan SA, Sethi A. Khyber Med Univ J. 2020;12:272&#x2013;277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical students&#x2019; perception of teaching evaluation and feedback: a study at Oman Medical College. El-Sayed M, Simon MA, El-Wasify M, et al. Middle East Curr Psychiatry. 2018;25:131&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>