<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41487607</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2296-2565</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>"Remember, we don't have race categories here": contradictions and reflections on racism, environment, and health from an interview study among Black German researchers, educators, and care providers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1658436</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1658436</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1658436</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1658436</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The global reckoning on race and racism in 2020 ushered in new or enhancement of existing governmental anti-discrimination and anti-racism initiatives at EU and German Federal levels. However, the role of racism, particularly structural racism, in health appears to be missing from community health and medical training and research, and from larger policy debates on environmental justice and health equity in Germany.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN/METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Participants were purposively recruited across 10 German cities selected to represent regional variability in racial diversity and engaged in semi-structured in-depth interviews that were audio-recorded and transcribed verbatim. Using thematic analysis, these qualitative interviews with 14 anti-racism researchers, community-based advocates and educators knowledgeable about environmental justice, racism, public health who identified as Black or Afro-German and/or work on behalf of racialized communities in Germany were analyzed to explore the challenges faced by minoritized communities in Germany in relation to environmental justice and health inequities, as well as strategies for addressing these issues.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Participants enumerated a number environmental conditions likely disproportionately impacting racialized minority groups in Germany. The extent of these issues is not known due to lack of data and empirical studies. Participants pointed to the myriad ways racism is structured in Germany, tracing how racialized and racially hierarchical values and beliefs become actualized through racially discriminatory policies and practices embedded in social institutions such as the government, the economy, the education system and the healthcare system which lead to racialized outcomes in health and environmental conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Interview participants identified pathways toward more effective research and policy initiatives on racism, environmental justice, community health and environmental heath equity in Germany including: collecting better data that is informed by structural theories of race/racialization and power; addressing history and national narratives; supporting more community-based participatory action research; engaging with existing civil society and non-governmental organizations that serve and advocate on behalf of minoritized communities; and building upon past and present progressive social movements.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Payne-Sturges.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Payne-Sturges</LastName><ForeName>Devon C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Health Sciences, University of Michigan School of Public Health, Ann Arbor, MI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Global, Environmental, and Occupational Health, University of Maryland School of Public Health, College Park, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101616579</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-2565</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063505" MajorTopicYN="Y">Racism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007407" MajorTopicYN="N">Interviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012108" MajorTopicYN="Y">Research Personnel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006282" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Personnel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044383" MajorTopicYN="Y">Black People</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000091383" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Justice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054624" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Status Disparities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069576" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Equity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">African diaspora</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Germany</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">environmental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">environmental justice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structural racism</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declares that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41487607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12757308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1658436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO Regional Office for Europe. Environmental Inequalities in National Reporting on the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development: An Analysis of Voluntary National Reviews in the WHO European Region. Copenhagen: WHO Regional Office for Europe</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Environment Agency. Unequal Exposure and Unequal Impacts: Social Vulnerability to Air Pollution, Noise and Extreme Temperatures in Europe. Copenhagen: European Environment Agency; (2018). p. 97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gee GC, Payne-Sturges DC. Environmental health disparities: a framework integrating psychosocial and environmental concepts. Environ Health Perspect. (2004) 112:1645&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1289/ehp.7074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/ehp.7074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1253653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15579407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne-Sturges DC, Taiwo TK, Ellickson K, Mullen H, Tchangalova N, Anderko L, et al. Disparities in toxic chemical exposures and associated neurodevelopmental outcomes: a scoping review and systematic evidence map of the epidemiological literature. Environ Health Perspect. (2023) 131:96001. doi: 10.1289/EHP11750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/EHP11750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10525348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37754677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon GM, Morello-Frosch R, Zeise L, Faust JB. Cumulative environmental impacts: science and policy to protect communities. Annu Rev Public Health. (2016) 37:83&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032315-021807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032315-021807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26735429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant . B. (ed.). Environmental Justice: Issues, Policies and Solutions. Washington, D.C.: Island Press; (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bullard RD, Mohai P, Saha R, Wright B. Toxic Wastes and Race and Toxic Wastes and Race at Twenty. Cleveland, OH: United Church of Christ. (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heike K, S&#xe9;verine D, Andrea R, Anders M, Walker G. Environmental justice in Western Europe. In:Ryan Holifield JC, Gordon W, editors. The Routledge Handbook of Environmental Justice. London: Routledge; (2017). p. 14. doi: 10.4324/9781315678986-50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9781315678986-50</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imeh I, Lisa TH. The Elephant in the Room &#x2013; Environmental Racism in Germany. Berlin: Heinrich B&#xf6;ll Stiftung; (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Statistical Office (Destatis). Bev&#xf6;lkerung und Erwerbst&#xe4;tigkeit. Bev&#xf6;lkerung mit Migrationshintergrund. Ergebnisse des Mikrozensus 2020 (Population and employment. Population with a Migration Background. Results of the 2020 microcensus.). Wiesbaden: Statistisches Bundesamt (Destatis) (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kajikhina K, Koschollek C, Sarma N, Bug M, Wengler A, Bozorgmehr K, et al. Recommendations for collecting and analysing migration-related determinants in public health research. J Health Monit. (2023) 8:52&#x2013;72. doi: 10.25646/11144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25646/11144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10091044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37064417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elrick J, Farah Schwartzman L. From statistical category to social category: organized politics and official categorizations of &#x2018;persons with a migration background' in Germany. Ethn Racial Stud. (2015) 38:1539&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1080/01419870.2014.996240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01419870.2014.996240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner J. En Route to Greater Visibility. Frankfurt am Main: deutschland.de (2021) Available online at: https://www.deutschland.de/en/topic/life/black-people-in-germany-new-research-project (Retrieved November 23, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aikins MA, Bremberger T, Aikins JK, Gyamerah D, Yildirim-Caliman D. Afrozensus 2020: Perspectives, Experiences of Anti-Black Racism and Engagement of Black, African and Afro-diasporic People in Germany. Berlin: Each One Teach One. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Union Agency for Fundamental Rights. Second <i>European Union Minorities and Discrimination Survey Being Black in the EU</i>. Luxembourg: European Union (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nationalen Diskriminierungs- und Rassismusmonitors (NaDiRa) (National Monitoring of Discrimination and Racism) . Rassismus und seine Symptome. Berlin: Deutsches Zentrum f&#xfc;r Integrationsund Migrationsforschung (DeZIM) (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kajikhina K, Koschollek C, Bozorgmehr K, Sarma N, Hovener C. Racism and discrimination in the context of health inequalities-a narrative review. Bundesgesundheitsblatt Gesundheitsforschung Gesundheitsschutz. (2023) 66:1099&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1007/s00103-023-03764-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00103-023-03764-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10539181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37735190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susanne Bartig, Dorina Kalkum, Ha Mi Le, Lewicki A. Risks of Discrimination and Protection Against Discrimination in the Health Care System&#x2014;State of Knowledge and Research Needs for Anti-discrimination Research. Berlin: Antidiskriminierungsstelle des Bundes (Federal Anti-Discrimination Agency) (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkmann F, Diebner HH, Matenar C, Schlegtendal A, Eitner L, Timmesfeld N, et al. Seroconversion rate and socio-economic and ethnic risk factors for SARS-CoV-2 infection in children in a population-based cohort, Germany, June 2020 to February 2021. Euro Surveill. (2022) 27: 2101028. doi: 10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2022.27.37.2101028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2022.27.37.2101028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9479468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36111557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graevskaia A, Menke K, Rumpel A. Institutioneller Rassismus in Beh&#xf6;r-den&#x2014;Rassistische Wissensbest&#xe4;nde in Polizei, Gesundheitsversorgung und Arbeitsverwaltung (Institutional Racism in Public Authorities&#x2014;Racist Bodies of Knowledge in the Police, Health Care and Employment Administration). Duisburg: Institut Arbeit und Qualifikation Fakult&#xe4;t f&#xfc;r Gesellschaftswissenschaften. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosen R. Ein Anhaltendes Problem mit Rassistischer Diskriminierung (A Persistent Problem with Racial Discrimination). Bonn: Deutsche Welle; (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statement: SARS-CoV-2 and the (un)equal vulnerability of people [press release] . Council for Migration eV (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tour&#xe9; A, Habeck R. Discrimination in Germany: let's unlearn racism! Berlin: Taz (2020). Available online at: https://taz.de/Diskriminierung-in-Deutschland/!5687742/ (accessed January 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AK Pohlers. Germans Push to Hold Police Accountable After Global GeorgeFloyd Protests. New York: NBC News Online; (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel M, Critchfield-Jain I, Boykin M, Owens A. Actual racial/ethnic disparities in COVID-19 mortality for the non-hispanic black compared to non-hispanic white population in 35 US States and their association with structural racism. J Racial Ethn Health Disparities. (2022) 9:886&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1007/s40615-021-01028-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-021-01028-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8077854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33905110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan SB, deSouza P, Raifman M. Structural Racism and COVID-19 in the USA: a county-level empirical analysis. J Racial Ethn Health Disparities. 2021:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1007/s40615-020-00948-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-020-00948-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7815192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33469868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yearby R, Mohapatra S. Law, structural racism, and the COVID-19 pandemic. J Law Biosci. (2020) 7:lsaa036. doi: 10.1093/jlb/lsaa036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jlb/lsaa036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7313873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32879732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zalla LC, Martin CL, Edwards JK, Gartner DR, Noppert GA, A. Geography of Risk: Structural racism and coronavirus disease 2019 mortality in the United States. Am J Epidemiol. (2021) 190:1439&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1093/aje/kwab059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwab059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33710272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey ZD, Moon JR. Racism and the political economy of COVID-19: will we continue to resurrect the past? J Health Polit Policy Law. (2020) 45:937&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1215/03616878-8641481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1215/03616878-8641481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32464657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce-Jones E. Race in the Shadow of Law: State Violence in Contemporary Europe. London: Routledge. (2017). doi: 10.4324/9781315625867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9781315625867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicken MT, Miles L, Haile S, Esposito M. Linking history to contemporary state-sanctioned slow violence through cultural and structural racism. Ann Am Acad Pol Soc Sci. (2021) 694:48&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1177/00027162211005690</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00027162211005690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8386285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34446942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H. How does structural racism operate (in) the contemporary US criminal justice system? Ann Rev riminol (2024) 7:233&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1146/annurev-criminol-022422-015019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-criminol-022422-015019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamed S, Thapar-Bjorkert S, Bradby H, Ahlberg BM. Racism in European health care: structural violence and beyond. Qual Health Res. (2020) 30:1662&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1177/1049732320931430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732320931430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7410275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey ZD, Feldman JM, Bassett MT. How structural racism works&#x2014;racist policies as a root cause of US. Racial Health In N Engl J Med. (2021) 384:768&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1056/NEJMms2025396</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMms2025396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11393777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33326717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeman RR, Homan PA, Chantarat T, Davis BA, Brown TH. Improving the measurement of structural racism to achieve antiracist health policy. Health Aff. (2022) 41:179&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1377/hlthaff.2021.01489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2021.01489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9680533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission. A Union of Equality: EU Anti-racism Action Plan 2020&#x2013;2025. Brussels: European Commission; (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x201c;We All Have to Be Anti-racists!&#x201d; [press release] . Berlin (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furstenau M. Racism in Germany is Part of Everyday Life. Bonn: Deutsche Welle [Internet] (2022). Available online at: https://www.dw.com/en/racism-in-germany-is-part-of-everyday-life/a-61700339 (accessed Januar 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher E. Germany's Controversial New Anti-Discrimination Commissioner. Bonn: Deutsche Welle; (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nationaler Diskriminierungs- und Rassismusmonitor (National Discrimination and Racism Monitor) . Rassismusforschung I: Theoretische und interdisziplin&#xe4;re Perspektiven (Racism Research I: Theoretical and Interdisciplinary Perspectives). Bielefeld: Nationaler Diskriminierungs- und Rassismusmonitor; (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Union Agency for Fundamental Rights. Being Black in the EU: Experiences of People of African Descent. Vienna: Publications Office of the European Union; (2023). p. 126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu B, Hagen LM, Kohlmeyer K, Oker S, Schultz E, Ziehrer-L&#xe4;ttner J. Parallelbericht an den UN-Ausschuss f&#xfc;r die Beseitigung der Rassendiskriminierung (ICERD) zum 23&#x2013;26 Bericht der Bundesrepublik Deutschland (Parallel report to the UN Committee for the Elimination of Racial Discrimination (ICERD) to the 23rd&#x2212;26th Report of the Federal Republic of Germany). Berlin: der Eberhard-Schultz-Stiftung f&#xfc;r soziale Menschenrechte und Partizipation (Eberhard Schultz Foundation for Social Human Rights and Participation). (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CP. Confronting institutionalized racism. Phylon. (2002) 50:7&#x2013;22. doi: 10.2307/4149999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/4149999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gee GC, Ford CL. Structural racism and health inequities. Old issues, new directions. Du Bois Rev. (2011) 8:115&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1017/S1742058X11000130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1742058X11000130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4306458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25632292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello-Frosch R. Discrimination and the political economy of environmental inequality. Environ Plan C Gov Policy. (2002) 20:477&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1068/c03r</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1068/c03r</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morello-Frosch R, Shenassa ED. The environmental &#x201c;riskscape&#x201d; and social inequality: implications for explaining maternal and child health disparities. Environ Health Perspect. (2006) 114:1150&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1289/ehp.8930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/ehp.8930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1551987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16882517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellow DN. Environmental inequality formation: towards a theory of environmental injustice. Am Behav Sci. (2000) 43:581&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1177/0002764200043004004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0002764200043004004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd RW, Lindo EG, Weeks LD, McLemore MR. Health Affairs Blog [Internet] (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan M, Mita C, Bellavia A, Parker M, James-Todd T. Racial/ethnic disparities in pregnancy and prenatal exposure to endocrine-disrupting chemicals commonly used in personal care products. Curr Environ Health Rep. (2021) 8:98&#x2013;112. doi: 10.1007/s40572-021-00317-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40572-021-00317-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8208930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34046860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cushing L, Faust J, August LM, Cendak R, Wieland W, Alexeeff G. Racial/ethnic disparities in cumulative environmental health impacts in California: evidence from a statewide environmental justice screening tool (CalEnviroScreen 1. 1). Am J Public Health. (2015) 105:2341&#x2013;8. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2015.302643</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2015.302643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4605180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohai P, Lantz PM, Morenoff J, House JS, Mero RP. Racial and socioeconomic disparities in residential proximity to polluting industrial facilities: evidence from the Americans' Changing Lives Study. Am J Public Health. (2009) 99(Suppl 3):S649&#x2013;56. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2007.131383</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2007.131383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2774179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen VK, Kahana A, Heidt J, Polemi K, Kvasnicka J, Jolliet O, et al. A comprehensive analysis of racial disparities in chemical biomarker concentrations in United States women, 1999&#x2013;2014. Environ Int. (2020) 137:105496. doi: 10.1016/j.envint.2020.105496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2020.105496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7137529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32113086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tessum CW, Paolella DA, Chambliss SE, Apte JS, Hill JD, Marshall JD. PM2.5 polluters disproportionately and systemically affect people of color in the United States. Sci Adv. (2021) 7:eabf4491. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.abf4491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abf4491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11426197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger N. Embodying inequality: a review of concepts, measures, and methods for studying health consequences of discrimination. Int J Health Serv. (1999) 29:295&#x2013;352. doi: 10.2190/M11W-VWXE-KQM9-G97Q</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2190/M11W-VWXE-KQM9-G97Q</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10379455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravlee CC. How race becomes biology: embodiment of social inequality. Am J Phys Anthropol. (2009) 139:47&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1002/ajpa.20983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajpa.20983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19226645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger N. Theories for social epidemiology in the 21st century: an ecosocial perspective. Int J Epidemiol. (2001) 30:668&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1093/ije/30.4.668</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/30.4.668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11511581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey ZD, Krieger N, Ag&#xe9;nor M, Graves J, Linos N, Bassett MT. Structural racism and health inequities in the USA: evidence and interventions. Lancet. (2017) 389:1453&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)30569-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)30569-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28402827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams DR, Mohammed SA. Racism and health I: pathways and scientific evidence. Am Behav Sci. (2013) 57:2764213487340. doi: 10.1177/0002764213487340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0002764213487340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3863357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24347666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradies Y, Ben J, Denson N, Elias A, Priest N, Pieterse A, et al. Racism as a determinant of health: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. (2015) 10:e0138511. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0138511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0138511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4580597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26398658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty J, Maantay JA, Brender JD. Disproportionate proximity to environmental health hazards: methods, models, and measurement. Am J Public Health. (2011) 101(Suppl 1):S27&#x2013;36. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2010.300109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2010.300109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3222485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21836113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulido L, Kohl E, Cotton N-M. State regulation and environmental justice: the need for strategy reassessment. Capital Nat Social. (2016) 27:12&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1080/10455752.2016.1146782</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10455752.2016.1146782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell JA. Structural racism: building upon the insights of John Calmore. North Carol Law Rev. (2008) 86:791&#x2013;816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Needham BL, Ali T, Allgood KL, Ro A, Hirschtick JL, Fleischer NL. Institutional racism and health: a framework for conceptualization, measurement, and analysis. J Racial Ethn Health Disparities. (2023) 10:1997&#x2013;2019. doi: 10.1007/s40615-022-01381-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-022-01381-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9395863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35994173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner MF. Towards a critical global race theory. Sociol Compass Melissa F Weiner. (2012) 6:332&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1111/j.1751-9020.2012.00457.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1751-9020.2012.00457.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gee GC, Hicken MT. Structural racism: the rules and relations of inequity. Ethn Dis. 2021;31(Suppl):293&#x2013;300. doi: 10.18865/ed.31.S1.293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18865/ed.31.S1.293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34045831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>German Federal Government. Bericht der Bundesregierung:Kabinettausschuss zur Bek&#xe4;mpfung von Rechtsextremismus und Rassismus (Report of the Federal Government: Cabinet Committee Against Right-Wing Extremism and Racism). Berlin: German Federal Government; (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris L, Noack R, Beck L. Merkel says racism a &#x2018;poison' Germany must face as 10 killed in far-right shooting. The Washington Post (2020) (accessed February 20, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>euronews . &#x2018;<i>Racism is a Poison': Angela Merkel Reacts to Hanau Shisha Bar Murders</i> (2020) Available online at: https://www.euronews.com/2020/02/20/racism-is-a-poison-angela-merkel~reacts-to-hanau-shisha-bar-murders (Retrieved August 25, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner F. Germany shooting: investigation into &#x2018;deeply racist' gunman's links. BBC. (2020). Available online at: https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-51577196 (Retrieved January 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuetze CF, Eddy M. Killing of German Politician is Treated as Possible Terrorist Act. The New York Times. (2019) (accessed June 17, 2019; Sect. A).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunman kills 2 after targeting German synagogue: Al Jazeera (2019). Available online at: https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2019/10/9/gunman-kills-2-after-targeting-german-synagogue (Retrieved May 27, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wissensnetzwerk Rassismusforschung (WinRa) Berlin: DeZIM Institute  (2024) Available online at: https://www.winra.org/ (Retrieved August 5, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>InRa-Studie: Forchungsinstitut Gesellschaftlicher Zusammenhalt: The Research Institute for Social Cohesion . Available online at: https://fgz-risc.de/forschung/inra-studie (Retrieved October 24, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabinettausschusses zur Bek&#xe4;mpfung von Rechtsextremismus und Rassismus (Cabinet Committee on the Combating right-wing extremism and racism) . Ma&#xdf;nahmenkatalog (Catalogue of Measures). Berlin: Bundesregierung (German Federal Government) (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Die Beauftragte der Bundesregierung f&#xfc;r Migration FuI Die Die Beauftragte der Bundesregierung f&#xfc;r Antirassismus (The Federal Government Commissioner for Migration Refugees and Integration The The Federal Government Commissioner for Anti-Racism) . Situation Report on Racism in Germany: Initial Situation, Fields of Action, Measures. Berlin: Bundesregierung f&#xfc;r Migration, Fl&#xfc;chtlinge und Integration January 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher E. &#x2018;Racism Poses a Threat to Germany's Democracy'
Berlin: Deutsche Welle;  (2023). Available online at: https://www.dw.com/en/racism-poses-a-threat to-germanys-democracy/a-64354347 (accessed January 11, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Die Beauftragte der Bundesregierung f&#xfc;r Migration FuI, Die Beauftragte der Bundesregierung f&#xfc;r Antirassismus. Expert<sup>*</sup>innenrat Antirassismus nimmt Arbeit auf (Expert Council on Anti-Racism begins work) (2023). Available online at: https://www.integrationsbeauftragte.de/ib de/staatsministerin/expert-innenrat-2194024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergin J. Racism Can Make You Sick. Bonn: Deutsche Welle. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinkartz S. Berlin: Deutsche Welle [Internet] (2023). Available online at: https://www.dw.com/en/germany-hostility-toward-muslims-is-widespread/a-66069446 (accessed Januaryy 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glucroft WN. Berlin: Deutsche Welle (2022). Available online at: https://www.dw.com/en/report-uncovers-germanys-structural-racism-against-muslims/a 63116871 (accessed January 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hans Vogt. Racism in German Medical Education&#x2014;Perspectives of Racialized Physicians and Medical Students. 15th European Public Health Conference. Berlin/Oxford: European Journal Of Public Health (2022). p. 647. doi: 10.1093/eurpub/ckac131.106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurpub/ckac131.106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gangarova T. Training Peer Researchers for CBPR on Racism in Health Care in Germany. 15th European Public Health Conference. Berlin/Oxford: European Journal Of Public Health (2022). p. 647. doi: 10.1093/eurpub/ckac129.610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurpub/ckac129.610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahlberg BM, Hamed S, Thapar-Bjorkert S, Bradby H. Invisibility of racism in the global neoliberal era: implications for researching racism in healthcare. Front Sociol. (2019) 4:61. doi: 10.3389/fsoc.2019.00061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsoc.2019.00061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8022523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33869384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin R. From Rasse to Race: On the Problem of Difference in the Federal Republic of Germany. New Jersey: Institute for Advanced Study (2011). p. 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odzakovic E, Huus K, Ahlberg BM, Bradby H, Hamed S, Thaper-Bjorkert S, et al. Discussing racism in healthcare: A qualitative study of reflections by graduate nursing students. Nurs Open. (2023) 10:3677&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1002/nop2.1619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.1619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10170953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36692244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ituen I, Hey LT. The Elephant in the Room&#x2014;Environmental Racism in Germany. Berlin: Heinrich B&#xf6;ll Foundation; (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechert L, Dodo, Kartal S. Colonialism and the Climate Crisis: Over 500 Years of Resistance. Berlin: Jugend im Bund f&#xfc;r Umwelt und Naturschutz Deutschland e.V. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller UA. Far away so close: race, whiteness, and German identity. Identities. (2011) 18:620&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1080/1070289X.2011.672863</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1070289X.2011.672863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradby H, Thapar-Bj&#xf6;rkert S, Hamed S, Ahlberg BM. &#x2018;You are still a guest in this country!': Understanding racism through the concepts of hospitality and hostility in healthcare encounters in Sweden. Sociology. (2022) 57:957&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1177/00380385221124827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00380385221124827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alana H-P, Jamiu OB. Systemic anti-blackness and racism in healthcare: a European perspective. Healthc Pap. (2023) 21:25&#x2013;30. doi: 10.12927/hcpap.2023.27195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12927/hcpap.2023.27195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37887166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theo Goldberg D. Racial europeanization. Ethn Racial Stud. (2006) 29:331&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1080/01419870500465611</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01419870500465611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo M, Nimako K. Mobilizing history: racism, enslavement and public debate in contemporary Europe. In:Tate SA, Rodr&#xed;guez EG, editors. The Palgrave Handbook of Critical Race and Gender. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan; (2022). p. 449&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-83947-5_23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-83947-5_23</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulila SC. Race and racial denial in Switzerland. Ethn Racial Stud. (2018) 42:1401&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1080/01419870.2018.1493211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01419870.2018.1493211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan W. Coronavirus: Its Impact Cannot be Explained Away Through the Prism of Race 2020. Available online at: https://theconversation.com/coronavirus-its-impact-cannot-be-explained away-through-the-prism-of-race-138046. doi: 10.64628/AB.qedyjghe3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.64628/AB.qedyjghe3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeboah A. Rassismus und psychische Gesundheit in Deutschland (Racism and mental health in Germany). In:Fereidooni K, El M, editors. Rassismuskritik und Widerstandsformen (Critique of racism and forms of resistance). Wiesbaden: Springer Fachmedien Wiesbaden; (2017). p. 143&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1007/978-3-658-14721-1_9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-658-14721-1_9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunett R. Rassismus und Gesundheit (Racism and Health). Jahrbuch f&#xfc;r Kritische Medizin und Gesundheitswissenschaften (Yearbook for Critical Medicine and Health Sciences). Hamburg: Argument Verlag mit Ariadne; (2016). p. 54&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helberg-Proctor A. &#x2018;Ras' speelt ten onrechte rol in klinische besluitvorming (&#x2018;Race' plays an undue role in clinical decision-making). Med Contact. (2019) 14:225. Available online at: https://www.medischcontact.nl/actueel/laatste-nieuws/artikel/ras-speelt-ten-onrechte-rol-in-klinische-besluitvorming (Retrieved June 3, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The The Transdisciplinary Resistance Collective for Research Policy. Neely AN, Ivey AS, Duarte C, Poe J, Irsheid S. Building the transdisciplinary resistance collective for research and policy: implications for dismantling structural racism as a determinant of health inequity. Ethn Dis. (2020) 30:381&#x2013;8. doi: 10.18865/ed.30.3.381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18865/ed.30.3.381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32742140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee H. The Sum of Us: What Racism Costs Everyone and How We Can Prosper Together. New York: One World. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. (2006) 3:77&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne D. A worked example of Braun and Clarke's approach to reflexive thematic analysis. Qual Quant. (2021) 56:1391&#x2013;412. doi: 10.1007/s11135-021-01182-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11135-021-01182-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumivero . NVivo (Version 14) (2024). Available online at: www.lumivero.com</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grijalva CG, Rolfes MA, Zhu Y, McLean HQ, Hanson KE, Belongia EA, et al. Transmission of SARS-CoV-2 infections in households&#x2014;tennessee and wisconsin, April&#x2013;September 2020. Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. (2020) 69:1631&#x2013;34. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6944e1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm6944e1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7643897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accorsi EK, Samples J, McCauley LA, Shadbeh N. Sleeping within six feet: challenging Oregon's labor housing COVID-19 guidelines. J Agromedicine. (2020):1&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1080/1059924X.2020.1815622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1059924X.2020.1815622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33079005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong N, Asare AO. Assessing the effect of socio-economic features of low-income communities and COVID-19 related cases: an empirical study of New York City. Glob Public Health. (2020):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1080/17441692.2020.1850830</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17441692.2020.1850830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33222624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S, Jenkins S, Addo K, Heidarinejad M, Romo SA, Layne A, et al. Ventilation and laboratory confirmed acute respiratory infection (ARI) rates in college residence halls in College Park, Maryland. Environ Int. (2020) 137:105537. doi: 10.1016/j.envint.2020.105537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2020.105537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32028176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuben A, Manczak EM, Cabrera LY, Alegria M, Bucher ML, Freeman EC, et al. The interplay of environmental exposures and mental health: setting an agenda. Environ Health Perspect. (2022) 130:25001. doi: 10.1289/EHP9889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/EHP9889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35171017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans GW. The built environment and mental health. J Urban Health. (2003) 80:536&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1093/jurban/jtg063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jurban/jtg063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3456225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14709704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard MF, Bellinger DC, Weuve J, Matthews-Bellinger J, Gilman SE, Wright RO, et al. Blood lead levels and major depressive disorder, panic disorder, and generalized anxiety disorder in US young adults. Arch Gen Psychiatry. (2009) 66:1313&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1001/archgenpsychiatry.2009.164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archgenpsychiatry.2009.164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2917196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Anikeeva O. Impacts of climate change and related weather events on the health and wellbeing of culturally and linguistically diverse communities: a systematic review. J Racial Ethn Health Disparities. (2025). doi: 10.1007/s40615-025-02527-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-025-02527-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40571869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decolonize Dortmund Dortmund Germany (2024). Available online at: http://decolonizedortmund.de/bismarckstrasse/bismarkstrasse-english/ (accessed December 5, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes S. How Activists are Radically Interrogating Berlin's Colonial Past&#x2014;And Reshaping Its Future. Time [Internet] (2021). Available online at: https://time.com/6075827/berlin-colonial-history-dekoloniale/ (accessed October 25, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulea A. Hamburg Wanted to &#x2018;Decolonise' Its Bismarck Statue&#x2014;Finding a Solution Wasn't So Easy. Euro News [Internet] (2023). . Available from: https://www.euronews.com/culture/2023/07/13/hamburg-wanted-to-decolonise-its-bismarck statue-finding-a-solution-wasnt-so-easy (accessed December 5, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>German Historical Institute in L, F&#xf6;rster S, Mommsen WJ, Robinson R. Bismarck, Europe, and Africa: The Berlin Africa Conference 1884&#x2013;1885 and the Onset of Partition. Oxford: Oxford University Press; (1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;ussler M, Janik E. The Herero Genocide: War, Emotion, and Extreme Violence in Colonial Namibia, 1 ed. Ney York: Berghahn Books (2021). doi: 10.2307/j.ctv2tsx91h</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctv2tsx91h</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerer J, Zeller J, editors. Genocide in German South-West Africa: The Colonial War (1904&#x2013;1908) in Namibia and Its Aftermath, 1st English ed. Monmouth, Wales: Merlin Press; (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerer J. From Windhoek to Auschwitz?: Reflections on the Relationship between Colonialism and National Socialism. Berlin; Boston, MA: De Gruyter Oldenbourg; (2024). p. 342. doi: 10.1515/9783110754513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9783110754513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath K. Migration background&#x2014;statistical classification and the problem of implicitly ethnicising categorisation in educational contexts. Ethnicities. (2019) 19:558&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1177/1468796819833432</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1468796819833432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migration and Integration: Population by Migration Background and Gender [Internet] (2025) . Available online at: https://www.destatis.de/EN/Themes/Society/Environment/Population/Migration-Integration/_node.html (accessed January 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosswick W, Bronnenmeyer V, Heckmann F. Integrationsma&#xdf;nahmen der Wohlfahrtsverb&#xe4;nde Gutachten f&#xfc;r die Unabh&#xe4;ngige Kommission &#x201c;Zuwanderung&#x201d; (Integration measures of the welfare associations: Expert opinions for the Independent Commission on Immigration). Bamberg: Europ&#xe4;isches forum f&#xfc;r migrationsstudien (European Forum for Migration Studies) (2001). p.175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xfc;rstenau M. Germany: Study Shows Correlation Between Racism and Poverty. Bonn: Deutsche Welle [Internet] (2024). Available online at: https://www.dw.com/en/germany-study-showscorrelation-between-racism-and-poverty/a-69014238 (accessed May 7, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel BA, Eng E, Schulz AJ, Parker EA, editors. Methods for Community-Based Participatory Research for Health, 2nd ed. New Jersey: Jossey-Bass (2012). p. 736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durham Community Research Team. Community-based Participatory Research: Ethical Challenges. Durham: Centre for Social Justice and Community Action, Durham University; (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumbuya S, Solanki SK. Towards Climate Justice: Rethinking the European Green Deal from a Racial Justice Perspective. Brussels: The Equinox Initiative for Racial Justice; (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg DT. The Racial State. Malden, Massachusetts: Blackwell Publishing; (2002). p. 319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerer J. Erinnerungsk&#xe4;mpfe: Neues deutsches Geschichtsbewusstsein (Memory Wars: New German Historical Consciousness). Ditzingen: Reclam Verlag; (2023). p. 500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurman K. Singing Like Germans: Black Muscisians in the Land of Bach, Beethoven, and Brahms. Ithaca: Cornell University Press; (2021). doi: 10.7591/cornell/9781501759840.001.0001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7591/cornell/9781501759840.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emejulu A, Sobande F, editors. To Exist is to Resist. London: Pluto Press; (2019). doi: 10.2307/j.ctvg8p6cc</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/j.ctvg8p6cc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerer J. From Windhoek to Auschwitz? Reflections on the Relationship between Colonialism and National Socialism. Berlin/Boston: De Gruyter Oldenbourg (2024). doi: 10.1515/9783110754513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9783110754513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nationalen Diskriminierungs- und Rassismusmonitors (NaDiRa) (National Monitoring of Discrimination and Racism) . Schwerpunkt Gesundheit (Focus on Health). Berlin: Deutsches Zentrum f&#xfc;r Integrations- und Migrationsforschung (DeZIM) (2025). Available online at: https://www.rassismusmonitor.de/en/topics/health/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartle-Haring S, Whiting R. Structural racism and the education gradient for early all-cause mortality. SSM Popul Health. (2022) 17:101076. doi: 10.1016/j.ssmph.2022.101076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssmph.2022.101076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geronimus AT, Hicken M, Keene D, Bound J. &#x201c;Weathering&#x201d; and age patterns of allostatic load scores among blacks and whites in the United States. Am J Public Health. (2006) 96:826&#x2013;33. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2004.060749</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2004.060749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1470581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16380565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger N, Jahn JL, Waterman PD. Jim Crow and estrogen-receptor-negative breast cancer: US-born black and white non-Hispanic women, 1992&#x2013;2012. Cancer Causes Control. (2017) 28:49&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1007/s10552-016-0834-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10552-016-0834-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27988896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White EB, Ekenga CC. Multidimensional structural racism and estimated cancer risk from traffic-related air pollution. Cancer. (2024) 130:3699&#x2013;707. doi: 10.1002/cncr.35467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.35467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11698492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39183582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu SY, Fiorentini C, Bailey Z, Huynh M, McVeigh K, Kaplan D. Structural racism and severe maternal morbidity in New York state. Clin Med Insights Womens Health. (2019) 12:1179562&#x2013;19854778. doi: 10.1177/1179562X19854778</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1179562X19854778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8842459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35237092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hailu EM, Maddali SR, Snowden JM, Carmichael SL, Mujahid MS. Structural racism and adverse maternal health outcomes: a systematic review. Health Place. (2022) 78:102923. doi: 10.1016/j.healthplace.2022.102923</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthplace.2022.102923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11216026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36401939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samari G, Catalano R, Alcala HE, Gemmill A. The muslim ban and preterm birth: analysis of U.S. vital statistics data from 2009 to 2018. Soc Sci Med. (2020) 265:113544. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7738384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33261902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehra R, Keene DE, Kershaw TS, Ickovics JR, Warren JL. Racial and ethnic disparities in adverse birth outcomes: differences by racial residential segregation. SSM Popul Health. (2019) 8:100417. doi: 10.1016/j.ssmph.2019.100417</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssmph.2019.100417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6545386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31193960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace M, Crear-Perry J, Richardson L, Tarver M, Theall K. Separate and unequal: structural racism and infant mortality in the US. Health Place. (2017) 45:140&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1016/j.healthplace.2017.03.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthplace.2017.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tayeb F. European Others: Queering Ethnicity in Postnational Europe. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press; (2011). p. 320. doi: 10.5749/minnesota/9780816670154.001.0001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5749/minnesota/9780816670154.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tayeb F. Undeutsch. Die Konstruktion des Anderen in der Postmigrantischen Gesellschaft. (Un-German. The Construction of the other in Postmigrant Society). Bielefeld: Verlag; (2016). p. 256. doi: 10.1515/9783839430743</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/9783839430743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tayeb F. &#x201c;We are Germans, We are Whites, and We Want to Stay White!&#x201d; African Germans and Citizenship in the early 20th Century. Leiden: Brill; (2004). p. 185&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1163/9789004334427_010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/9789004334427_010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>