<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41923103</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of professional course teaching behavior and self-reported professional competence in medical students: the effects of professional identity evaluation and campus environment satisfaction.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12909-026-09096-9</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Guizhou University, Guiyang, Guizhou, 550025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School/Hospital of Stomatology, Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, Guizhou, 550004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Feng Feng</ForeName><Initials>FF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School/Hospital of Stomatology, Guizhou Medical University, Guiyang, Guizhou, 550004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Zhongxian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Guizhou University, Guiyang, Guizhou, 550025, China. gzdzxian@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Henggui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Guizhou University, Guiyang, Guizhou, 550025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guizhou Education Department, Guiyang, Guizhou, 550081, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Guizhou University, Guiyang, Guizhou, 550025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>POWERCHINA Guizhou Electric Power Engineering Co., Ltd., Guiyang, Guizhou, 550000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>gzwkj2025-176</GrantID><Agency>Guizhou Provincial Health Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088679</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6920</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Campus environment satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Professional identity evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-reported professional competence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Teaching behavior evaluation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study strictly adhered to established ethical standards for social science research. Prior to questionnaire administration, all participants were fully informed of the research purpose, content, and data usage policies, with explicit clarification that participation was entirely voluntary and that respondents could withdraw from the survey at any time without adverse consequences. The questionnaires were administered anonymously, with no collection of personally identifiable information such as names or contact details, thereby ensuring strict protection of participant privacy. All data were used exclusively for academic analysis and report preparation, with no commercial or other secondary applications. The research content involved no sensitive or potentially harmful questions and posed no identifiable ethical risks. Informed consent was obtained from all participants for the entire research process, and academic integrity and ethical guidelines were rigorously maintained throughout the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41923103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-026-09096-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12909-026-09096-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Frank JR, Snell LS, Cate OT, Holmboe ES, Carraccio C, Swing SR, et al. Competency-based medical education: theory to practice. Med Teach. 2010;32:638&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.3109/0142159X.2010.501190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmboe ES, Sherbino J, Long DM, Swing SR, Frank JR, For The International Cbme Collaborators. The role of assessment in competency-based medical education. Med Teach. 2010;32:676&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.3109/0142159X.2010.500704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Wei G, Cheng H, Yan Y, Yang S. Establishing a set of qualities for clinical teaching faculty in undergraduate medical internship. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25:298&#x2013;306. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909-025-06868-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao F-F. Teaching behaviours of clinical teachers and professional commitment among nursing students: a moderated mediation model of optimism and psychological well-being. Nurse Educ Today. 2023;125:105774. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nedt.2023.105774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qureshi MA, Khaskheli A, Qureshi JA, Raza SA, Yousufi SQ. Factors affecting students&#x2019; learning performance through collaborative learning and engagement. Interact Learn Environ. 2023;31:2371&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1080/10494820.2021.1884886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Wu Y. The interplay between teacher support, behavioral engagement, and academic performance among Chinese secondary EFL learners. Indian J Lang Linguist. 2024;5:1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.54392/ijll2441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanveer MA, Mildestvedt T, Skj&#xe6;rseth IG, Arntzen HH, Kenne E, Bonnevier A, et al. Peer teaching in undergraduate medical education: what are the learning outputs for the student-teachers? A systematic review. Adv Med Educ Pract. 2023;14:723&#x2013;39. https://doi.org/10.2147/AMEP.S401766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social Fundations of Thought and Action:A Social Cognitive Theory. Englewood Cliffs, NJ, US: Prentice-Hall,Inc; 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neufeld A, Babenko O, Lai H, Svrcek C, Malin G. Why do we feel like intellectual frauds? A self-determination theory perspective on the impostor phenomenon in medical students. Teach Learn Med. 2023;35:181&#x2013;92. https://doi.org/10.1080/10401334.2022.2056741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Z, Qian Y, Zhang W, Hu J, Jiang J, Zeng L, et al. Enhancing psychosomatic medicine skills in general practitioners: insights from ecological systems theory. Int J Gen Med. 2025;18:5591&#x2013;603. https://doi.org/10.2147/IJGM.S527054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shivolo T, Mokiwa HO. Unpacking the practical work inquiry practice framework for improving science practical work and inquiry: A namibian perspective. Int J Res Innov Soc Sci. 2024;VIII(III):1118&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.47772/IJRISS.2024.803084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin S, Ambreen S, Ul-Ain N, Murad T, Sajwani K, Qaiser A. Professionalism program evaluation and its impact on undergraduate medical students. Cureus. 2024:1-7. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.53051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruess RL, Cruess SR, Boudreau JD, Snell L, Steinert Y. Reframing medical education to support professional identity formation: Acad Med. Acad Med. 2014;89:1446&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1097/ACM.0000000000000427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhuiya T, Zhong X, Pollack G, Fornari A, Ahuja TK. Tell me more&#xae;: a medical student focused humanistic communication model to enhance student professional identity formation through meaningful patient encounters. Patient Educ Couns. 2022;105:641&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2021.06.031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sternszus R, Boudreau JD, Cruess RL, Cruess SR, Macdonald ME, Steinert Y. Clinical teachers&#x2019; perceptions of their role in professional identity formation. Acad Med. 2020;95:1594&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1097/ACM.0000000000003369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto CN. Professions, professionalism, and professional identity. Am Soc Clin Lab Sci. 2018;31:142&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.29074/ascls.2018000570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suwadji SA, Lestari R, Muthmainnah DR, Na&#x2019;im A. The determinants of accounting student perceptions of earnings management in indonesia. J Account Invest. 2025;26:1211&#x2013;32. https://doi.org/10.18196/jai.v26i3.27006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faihs V, Heininger S, McLennan S, Gartmeier M, Berberat PO, Wijnen-Meijer M. Professional identity and motivation for medical school in first-year medical students: a cross-sectional study. Med Sci Educ. 2023;33:431&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40670-023-01754-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser CLF, Wilschut JA, Isik U, Van Der Burgt SME, Croiset G, Kusurkar RA. The association of readiness for interprofessional learning with empathy, motivation and professional identity development in medical students. BMC Med Educ. 2018;18:125&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909-018-1248-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Yang X, Han Z, Li K, Yu Y, Mao Z, et al. Professional identity among forensic medicine students: A cross-sectional study in jiangsu province, east China. BMC Med Educ. 2025;25:786&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909-025-07387-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Sullivan A. Urban economics. 8th edition. New York, NY: McGraw-Hill/Irwin; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan KS, Coomarasamy A. A hierarchy of effective teaching and learning to acquire competence in evidenced-based medicine. BMC Med Educ. 2006;6:59&#x2013;67. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6920-6-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason JH. Exploring the influence of high-stakes testing and accountability on teachers' professional identities through the factors of instructional practice, work environment, and teacher efficacy [Dissertation]. Cullowhee: Western Carolina University; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toh RQE, Koh KK, Lua JK, Wong RSM, Quah ELY, Panda A, et al. The role of mentoring, supervision, coaching, teaching and instruction on professional identity formation: a systematic scoping review. BMC Med Educ. 2022;22:531&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909-022-03589-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y, Zhang C. The influence of achievement motivation on the educational practice ability of pre-service teachers: the multiple mediating role of professional identity and learning engagement. Front Psychol. 2024;15:1463557. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1463557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umbach PD, Wawrzynski MR. Faculty do matter: the role of college faculty in student learning and engagement. Res High Educ. 2005;46:153&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11162-004-1598-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin SM, El-Ashry AM, Karim NAHA, Atta MHR, Alqarawi N, Khedr MA, et al. Shaping competence through identity: the mediating role of professional identity in the relationship between clinical learning environment and nursing competence among nursing students. Nurse Educ Today. 2026;157:106905. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nedt.2025.106905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusyidi B, Chen Y-Y, Shih Y-C, McCarthy M, Tseng Y-H. Social work students&#x2019; perception of education quality, commitment, and competence: comparison of indonesia and taiwan. Soc Sci. 2023;12:161&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.3390/socsci12030160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astin AW. Assessment for Excellence: The Philosophy and Practice of Assessment and Evaluation in Higher Education. New York: Macmillan; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuh GD. High-impact educational practices: what they are, who has acces to them, and why they matter. 1st edition. District of Columbia: American Association of Colleges &amp; Universities; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koljatic M, Kuh GD. A longitudinal assessment of college student engagement in good practices in undergraduate education. High Educ. 2001;42:351&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1017993113390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pace CR (CR ). Measuring Outcomes of College: Fifty Years of Findings and Recommendations for the Future. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes AF. Introduction to Mediation, Moderation, and Conditional Process Analysis: A Regression-Based Approach. New York: Guilford publications; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valestrand EA, Whelan B, Eliassen KER, Schei E. Alienation in the teaching hospital: How physician non-greeting behaviour impacts medical students&amp;rsquo; learning and professional identity formation. Perspect Med Educ. 2024;13. https://doi.org/10.5334/pme.1185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luthfianasari L, Pamungkasari EP, Hermasari BK. The relationship between the perception of professional identity and the professionalism level of medical students. Jurnal Pendidikan Kedokteran Indonesia: Indonesian J Med Educ. 2024;13:262&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.22146/jpki.87930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao X, Yu L, Shen Y, Kang Z, Wang X. The role of self-efficacy in mediating between professional identity and self-reported competence among nursing students in the internship period: a quantitative study. Nurse Educ Pract. 2021;57:103252. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nepr.2021.103252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaintance JL, Arnold L, Thompson GS. Development of an instrument to measure the climate of professionalism in a clinical teaching environment. Acad Med. 2008;83(Supplement):S5-8. https://doi.org/10.1097/ACM.0b013e318183e3d4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spoto-Cannons AC, Isom DM, Feldman M, Zwygart KK, Mhaskar R, Greenberg MR. Differences in medical student self-evaluations of clinical and professional skills. Adv Med Educ Pract. 2019;10:835&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.2147/AMEP.S222774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byram JN. The professionalization of medical students: a longitudinal analysis of professional identity formation and professionalism perceptions in second and third year medical students [Dissertation]. Indianapolis: Indiana University; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhalalati B, Aly A, Yakti O, Elshami S, Daud A, Awaisu A, et al. Examining the perception of undergraduate health professional students of their learning environment, learning experience and professional identity development: a mixed-methods study. BMC Med Educ. 2024;24:886&#x2013;911. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12909-024-05875-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai N, Nalliah S, Jutti R, Hla Y, Lim V. The educational environment and self- perceived clinical competence of senior medical students in a malaysian medical school. Educ Health. 2009;22:148.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>