<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41686115</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2405-5018</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JACC. Clinical electrophysiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JACC Clin Electrophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Accuracy of Implantable Loop Recorders: Multicenter, Multidevice Comparison.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2405-500X(26)00003-4</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacep.2025.12.039</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Implantable loop recorders (ILRs) frequently generate false-positive alert transmissions, increasing clinical burden.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study sought to evaluate and compare arrhythmia detection accuracy among currently used ILRs: Medtronic (MDT) LINQ II with AccuRhythm AI, Boston Scientific (BSX) LUX-Dx with a Dual-Stage Algorithm, Biotronik (BIO) Biomonitor III with RhythmCheck, and Abbott (ABT) Confirm Rx (SharpSense).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A multicenter, multivendor database of 437,351 electrocardiogram-verified episodes from 6,756 patients (January 2022 to March 2023, across 25 centers) was used. A random sample of 1,140 patients (&#x223c;283 per device) was selected based on a prospectively determined power analysis. All alerts were independently adjudicated by trained physicians.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study cohort (median age: 69.5 years [IQR: 60.1-77.0]; 39% women) generated 25,826 total alerts, with a median of 5 alerts (IQR: 2-14) per patient. Indications for ILR implant included cryptogenic stroke (21.0%), suspected atrial fibrillation (AF) (11.3%), AF management (23.6%), syncope (23.2%), palpitations (14.9%), ventricular tachycardia (2.1%), and unknown (3.8%). Alerts for atrial tachycardia/AF were most frequent (BIO: 70.8%; MDT: 68.0%; ABT: 55.7%; BSX: 35.7%). After adjudication, BSX had the highest positive predictive values (PPVs), followed by ABT and MDT, which had similar and moderate PPVs, whereas BIO had the lowest (BSX: 0.73; MDT: 0.56; ABT: 0.51; BIO: 0.23). False-positive atrial tachycardia/AF alerts with BIO devices were due to ectopy (75.8%), combined ectopy with oversensing/noise (5.3%), isolated oversensing (5.2%), sinus arrhythmias (3.9%), indeterminate reason (3.7%), noise (3.6%), and bradycardia (2.5%). For bradycardia detection, BSX demonstrated the highest PPV (0.96), whereas MDT had the lowest PPV (0.36; primarily due to undersensing). Pause detection accuracy was lowest for ABT (PPV: 0.01; 79.8% due to undersensing) and highest for BSX (PPV: 0.70). Tachycardia alerts had moderate PPVs for BIO (0.62) and BSX (0.61), with substantially lower PPVs for MDT (0.29) and ABT (0.27).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ILRs demonstrate variable accuracy in arrhythmia detection, with a substantial burden of false-positive alerts across all vendors despite artificial intelligence-based and other algorithmic enhancements. Further improvement of alert algorithms to reduce clinic burdens is needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Crown Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamsani</LastName><ForeName>Suraya H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia; Cardiology Department, National Heart Institute, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Middeldorp</LastName><ForeName>Melissa E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evans</LastName><ForeName>Shaun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russo</LastName><ForeName>Andrea M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Cooper Medical School of Rowan University, Camden, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jayakumar</LastName><ForeName>Mohanaraj</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deering</LastName><ForeName>Thomas F</ForeName><Initials>TF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arrhythmia Center, Piedmont Heart Institute, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahmohamadi</LastName><ForeName>Elnaz</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baykaner</LastName><ForeName>Tina</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Cardiovascular Medicine and Electrophysiology, Stanford University School of Medicine, Palo Alto, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fitzgerald</LastName><ForeName>John L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gopinathannair</LastName><ForeName>Rakesh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kansas City Heart Rhythm Institute, Kansas City, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbas</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varma</LastName><ForeName>Niraj</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freeman</LastName><ForeName>James V</ForeName><Initials>JV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mittal</LastName><ForeName>Suneet</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Snyder Center for Comprehensive Atrial Fibrillation and Department of Cardiology, Valley Health System, Paramus, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanders</LastName><ForeName>Prashanthan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders, Adelaide University and Royal Adelaide Hospital, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia. Electronic address: prash.sanders@adelaide.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JACC Clin Electrophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101656995</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-500X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arrhythmia detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">false-positive alerts</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implantable loop recorder (ILR)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">remote monitoring</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding Support and Author Disclosures This study was supported by the Centre for Heart Rhythm Disorders at the University of Adelaide. Drs Kamsani, Evans, Jayakumar, Shahmohamadi, Fitzgerald, and Abbas are supported by postgraduate scholarships from the University of Adelaide. Dr Baykaner has received research funds from the U.S. National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute and Janssen. Dr Freeman has received by research funding from the American College of Cardiology Foundation; and grants from the U.S. National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute. Dr Sanders is supported by an Investigator Grant from the National Health and Medical Research Council of Australia. Dr Russo has received research funding from Abbott, Boston Scientific, and Medtronic; and honoraria or consulting fees from Abbott, Biotronik, Boston Scientific, Medtronic, Orchestra BioMed, and PaceMate. Dr Deering has served on the advisory board of PaceMate. Dr Baykaner has received consulting fees from Medtronic, Biotronik, Boston Scientific, Abbott, PaceMate, Volta, iRhythm and Johnson &amp; Johnson. Dr Varma is a consultant with Abbott, Biotronik, and Impulse Dynamics. Dr Freeman has received consulting/advisory board fees from Boston Scientific, Medtronic, Abbott, Johnson &amp; Johnson MedTech, and PaceMate. Dr Mittal has served as a consultant to Abbott, Boston Scientific, and Medtronic. Dr Sanders has served on the advisory boards of Medtronic, Abbott Medical, Boston-Scientific, PaceMate, and CathRx. Dr Sanders reports that the University of Adelaide has received on his behalf lecture and/or consulting fees from Medtronic, Boston Scientific, and Abbott Medical. Dr Sanders reports that the University of Adelaide has received on his behalf research funding from Medtronic, Abbott Medical, Boston Scientific, and Becton Dickenson. All other authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41686115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacep.2025.12.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-500X(26)00003-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>