<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41796204</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A techno-economic and ai-based optimization framework for hybrid energy systems supplying rural telecom base stations.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-42926-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper introduces a strict AI-based framework of analysis of HRES in technical and economic dimensions to drive remote BTS.The proposed system delivers a total power output of 1.2&#xa0;kW at -&#x2009;48&#xa0;V and 23&#xa0;A, ensuring compatibility with standard telecom load requirements. A year's worth of hourly simulation data is utilized to train and validate a range of forecasting algorithms, including linear regression, decision tree models, support vector machines (SVM), Gaussian process regression (GPR), kernel-based autoregressive moving average (KARMA) and feedforward neural networks (NN). EMS simulation results showed that hybrid solar-wind accounted for an average of 78.6% of the total daily load served, while fuel-based system usage was reduced by over 76% compared to conventional systems. The results confirm that intelligent forecasting and optimal dispatch strategies significantly improve system efficiency, reduce fossil fuel dependency and enhance the sustainability of HRES in decentralized telecom towers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajendran</LastName><ForeName>Aruna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Adhiparasakthi Engineering College, Melmaruvathur, Tamilnadu, India. arunarajendran41@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J</LastName><ForeName>Raja</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Adhiparasakthi Engineering College, Melmaruvathur, Tamilnadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K</LastName><ForeName>Moorthi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Sri Sairam Engineering College, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial Intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Management System (EMS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HOMER Optimization.</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hybrid Renewable Energy System (HRES)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MATLAB Simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Techno-Economic Analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Telecom Base Transceiver Station (BTS)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: No participation of humans takes place in this implementation process. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41796204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-42926-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-42926-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Louahem M&#x2019;sabah, I., Zerguerras, A., Meziani, S. &amp; Chettouf, M. Evaluation and Development of a Hybrid Renewable Energy System for the Remote Telecommunication Station of Bougaroun, Collo, Algeria, Scientific Bulletin of the Electrical Engineering Faculty 22 (1), 1&#x2013;8, (2022). https://doi.org/10.2478/sbeef-2022-0005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y., Naderi, S. &amp; Josephson, C. Provisioning for Solar-Powered Base Stations Driven by Conditional LSTM Networks. arXiv Oct. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2410.20755 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gangwei Ding, L. et al. Strategy of 5G Base Station Energy Storage Participating in the Power System Frequency Regulation, Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering, 48, 14537&#x2013;14548, (2023). https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-023-07723-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, H., Zhang, L. &amp; Wang, J. A Hybrid Convolutional&#x2013;Long Short-Term Memory&#x2013;Attention Framework for Short-Term Photovoltaic Power Forecasting, Incorporating Data from Neighbouring Stations, Applied Sciences, 14 (12), 5189 (2024). https://doi.org/10.3390/app14125189</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, G., Sun, Y. &amp; Li, W. Hybrid load prediction model of 5G base station based on time series decomposition and GRU network with parameter optimization, IET Generation, Transmission &amp; Distribution, 18 (8), 1548&#x2013;1558 (2024). https://doi.org/10.1049/gtd2.13140</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siva Subrahmanyam, M. &amp; Anil Kumar, E. Viability Study of Stand-Alone Hybrid Energy Systems for Telecom Base Station, in Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Advances in Energy Research (ICAER 2019), Singapore, Oct. 1061&#x2013;1070, (2020). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-15-5955-6_101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreekumar Narayanan, R., Kumar, S., Ramadass &amp; Ramasamy, J. Hybrid Forecasting Model Integrating RNN-LSTM for Renewable Energy Production. Electr. Power Compon. Syst. https://doi.org/10.1080/15325008.2024.2316247 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deenadayalan Venkatraman &amp; Pitchaipillai, V. Deep Learning-Based Auto-LSTM Approach for Renewable Energy Forecasting: A Hybrid Network Model, Thresholds in Signal Processing, 41 (1), 1&#x2013;15, (2024). https://doi.org/10.18280/ts.410148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orji, U., G&#xfc;ven, &#xc7;. &amp; Stowell, D. Enhanced load forecasting with GAT-LSTM: Leveraging grid and temporal features. arXiv Feb. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2502.08376 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guang Wu, Y., Wang, Q., Zhou &amp; Zhang, Z. Enhanced photovoltaic power forecasting: An iTransformer and LSTM-based model integrating temporal and covariate interactions. arXiv Dec. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2412.02302 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perifanis, V., Pavlidis, N., Koutsiamanis, R. A. &amp; Efraimidis, P. S. Federated learning for 5G base station traffic forecasting. arXiv Nov. https://doi.org/10.48550/arXiv.2211.15220 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, B. et al. Short-term output prediction of wind-photovoltaic power based on time-frequency decomposition, Frontiers in Energy Research, 12, 1477657, (2024). https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1477657</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich, M., Klinglmair, P. &amp; Braun, J. A comparative analysis of deep neural network architectures for renewable energy forecasting: Enhancing accuracy with meteorological and time-based features. Discover Sustain. https://doi.org/10.1007/s43621-024-00783-5 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Khozondar, H. et al. Standalone hybrid PV/wind/diesel-electric generator system for a COVID-19 quarantine center. Environ. Prog. Sustain. Energy. https://doi.org/10.1002/ep.14049 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Hameed &amp; El-Fergany, A. A. Optimal techno-economic design of hybrid PV/wind system comprising battery energy storage: Case study for a remote area. Energy. Conv. Manag. 249 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2021.114847 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Zhang, Y., Wang, L. &amp; Chen, H. Hybrid renewable energy system optimization for rural off-grid applications: A techno-economic assessment. Sci. Rep. 15, 94285. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-94285-7 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, P., Sharma, R. &amp; Singh, A. AI-based predictive control for hybrid PV-Wind-Battery systems in rural telecom stations. Sci. Rep. 14, 70663. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-70663-5 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J., Liu, M. &amp; Wang, Y. Multi-objective optimization of hybrid renewable energy systems using metaheuristic approaches. Sci. Rep. 14, 61783. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-61783-z (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, K. et al. Techno-economic feasibility of off-grid PV-Wind-Fuel Cell systems: Case studies and simulations. Ain Shams Eng. J. 13, 101985. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asej.2022.101985 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, T. et al. Renewable energy integration and AI-assisted dispatch for microgrid reliability. Sustainability 14, 16814. https://doi.org/10.3390/su142416814 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. &amp; Rahman, M. Optimization of hybrid renewable energy systems for rural electrification using intelligent forecasting. Sci. Rep. 15, 97088. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-97088-y (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. Economic analysis of hybrid PV-Wind-Battery systems with AI-assisted EMS: Case study in remote areas. Energy. Conv. Manag. 312, 119870. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2025.119870 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, A. et al. AI-driven optimization of hybrid energy systems supplying off-grid telecommunications. Sci. Rep. 15, 88438. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-88438-x (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Performance evaluation of hybrid PV-Wind-Fuel Cell systems with predictive control. Appl. Energy. 354, 124137. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.124137 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, T. et al. Intelligent energy management in hybrid renewable systems for rural BTS: Techno-economic study. Sci. Rep. 15, 31117. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-31117-8 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, K., Yang, J. &amp; Liu, P. Relaying-Assisted Communications for Demand Response in Smart Grid: Cost Modeling, Game Strategies, and Algorithms. IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun. 38 (1), 48&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1109/JSAC.2019.2951972 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, K., Wang, B., Ding, H., Lv, L., Dong, R., Cheng, T.,&#x2026; Gong, F. (2021). Improving Physical Layer Security of Uplink NOMA via Energy Harvesting Jammers. IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security, 16, 786&#x2013;799. doi: 10.1109/TIFS.2020.3023277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, F., Yang, H. &amp; Alouini, M. Energy Consumption Minimization for Data Collection From Wirelessly-Powered IoT Sensors: Session-Specific Optimal Design With DRL. IEEE Sens. J., 22(20), 19886&#x2013;19896. doi: https://doi.org/10.1109/JSEN.2022.3205017 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, N., Luo, L., Sheng, G. &amp; Jiang, X. Scheduling the Imperfect Maintenance and Replacement of Power Substation Equipment: A Risk-Based Optimization Model. IEEE Trans. Power Delivery. 40 (4), 2154&#x2013;2166. https://doi.org/10.1109/TPWRD.2025.3572076 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H., Liang, R., Zheng, Y., Peng, S., Rae, A., Ackom, E.,&#x2026; Johnston, A. J. (2025).Receding Horizon Optimization of Power Demand Response for Production-Oriented Users With Real-Time Operating Status-Awareness. IEEE Transactions on Consumer Electronics,1. doi: 10.1109/TCE.2025.3608740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Q., Hussain, S., He, Y., Lu, J. &amp; Guerrero, J. M. Multi-timescale stochastic optimization for enhanced dispatching and operational efficiency of electric vehicle photovoltaic charging stations. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 172, 111096. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijepes.2025.111096 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, A., Du, C., AL-Bukhaiti, K. &amp; Chen, P. Optimizing combined-cycle power plant operations using an LSTM-attention hybrid model for load forecasting. J. Mech. Sci. Technol. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12206-025-0961-3 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehsan Dorostkar. Quantum computing-artificial intelligence synergy for adaptive urban morphogenesis: Modeling China&#x2019;s hyper-growth cities under uncertainty. J. Chin. Archit. Urbanism 025250046. https://doi.org/10.36922/JCAU025250046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Y., Zhang, J., Miao, P., Zhang, L., Chen, G., Shu, F.,&#x2026; Wong, K. (2025). Hybrid RIS-Enhanced ISAC Secure Systems: Joint Optimization in the Presence of an Extended Target. IEEE Transactions on Communications, 1. doi: 10.1109/TCOMM.2025.3610218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, J., Wu, S. &amp; Lu, T. Portfolio selection and optimal planning for hydrogen energy storage systems composed of heterogeneous electrolyzer and fuel cell technologies in industrial park multi-energy systems. Appl. Energy. 403, 127001. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.127001 (2026).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>