<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41787399</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1478-4505</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health research policy and systems</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Res Policy Syst</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Catalysing vaccines research, development and manufacturing in Nigeria: a qualitative exploration of industry stakeholders' knowledge, perceptions and experience.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12961-026-01442-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The lack of local production of vaccines in Nigeria is a challenge contributing to limited access to healthcare. To address these vulnerabilities, the nation has committed efforts toward vaccine self-sufficiency through local production. However, this initiative has been met with a plethora of constraints. These include inadequate technical capacity, insufficient resources, limited infrastructure, procurement&#xa0;challenges, cold chain&#xa0;management, uncertain market mechanisms and a lack of funding. This study, therefore, aims to bridge this gap by articulating robust strategies for local vaccine production from the perspective of relevant stakeholders across different areas of the vaccine value chain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A qualitative strategy was adopted to explore participants' perspectives on the strategies for sustainable local vaccine manufacturing in Nigeria. The study sample represented stakeholders practising across different areas of the vaccine value chain. Data obtained were analysed thematically to yield themes and sub-themes. Trustworthiness in the study was ensured through recommended frameworks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Following data analysis, nine overarching themes were identified, which articulated the need to build capacity and an enabling environment for vaccine development in Nigeria. The findings showed that inadequate research capacity, weak infrastructure and poor commercialization frameworks constrain vaccine production, necessitating phased production initiation, strengthened research systems, infrastructural development and improved market access. Effective management and advocacy were found to be critical for securing government and stakeholders' commitment, as well as reducing vaccine hesitancy to support sustainable local vaccine production.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study provides in-depth insights into the strategies for expediting the national objective to achieve vaccine self-sufficiency, including the establishment of an enabling policy and legislative environment to attract investment, streamline regulation and secure market access for locally produced vaccines. It emphasizes strengthening research and development capacity beyond fill-and-finish activities, addressing workforce skills gaps through training and technology transfer, and improving infrastructure through reliable power supply and vaccine industrial parks. Overall, the findings highlight the need for sustainable financing, stakeholder&#xa0;coordination, and strong government interventions to ensure the viability of local vaccine manufacturing. These insights can guide effective planning and comprehensive efforts into the requisite areas necessary for sustainable vaccine manufacturing in the country.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Onavbavba</LastName><ForeName>Godspower</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Pharmaceutical Research and Development, Plot 942, Cadastral Zone C16, Idu Industrial District, Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria. onavbavbagodspower@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adigwe</LastName><ForeName>Obi Peter</ForeName><Initials>OP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Pharmaceutical Research and Development, Plot 942, Cadastral Zone C16, Idu Industrial District, Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria. o.p.adigwe@niprd.gov.ng.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Diana Oyin-Mieyebi</ForeName><Initials>DO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Pharmaceutical Research and Development, Plot 942, Cadastral Zone C16, Idu Industrial District, Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ene</LastName><ForeName>Erica Chiamaka</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Pharmaceutical Research and Development, Plot 942, Cadastral Zone C16, Idu Industrial District, Abuja, Federal Capital Territory, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Health Res Policy Syst</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101170481</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1478-4505</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Collaboration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmaceutical manufacturing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Regulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccine self-sufficiency</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Prior to the commencement of data collection, ethical approval was obtained from the National Institute for Pharmaceutical Research and Development Health Research Ethics Committee with Approval Number: NIPRD-HREC17/07/2024-26. Participation in the study was voluntary. Written informed consent was obtained from the respondents prior to the administration of the questionnaires. All information provided was treated with absolute confidentiality. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41787399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12961-026-01442-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12961-026-01442-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Olutuase VO, Iwu-Jaja CJ, Akuoko CP. Medicines and vaccines supply chains challenges in Nigeria: a scoping review. BMC Public Health. 2022;22:11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-021-12361-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajiboye K. Nigeria spends N8bn annually to import vaccines - WAPCMLS secretary. Independent Newspaper Nigeria. 2024. https://independent.ng/nigeria-spends-n8bn-annually-to-import-vaccines-wapcmls-secretary/. Accessed 18 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adigwe OP, Oturu D, Onavbavba G. Healthcare professionals&#x2019; views on access to vaccines in Nigeria: a cross-sectional study. Vaccine X. 2022;12:100235. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvacx.2022.100235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei CR, Kamande S, Lang&#x2019;at GC. Vaccine inequity: a threat to Africa&#x2019;s recovery from COVID-19. Trop Med Health. 2023;51:69. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41182-023-00564-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adejoro L. FG pledges commitment to local vaccine, and medicine production. Punch Newspaper. 2023. http://punchng.com/fg-pledges-commitment-to-local-vaccine-medicine-production. Accessed 18 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Ministry of Health and Social Welfare (FMoH&amp;SW). Nigeria Vaccine Policy. 2021. http://nesgroup.org/download_policy_drafts/Nigeria%20Vaccine%20Policy%20%282021%29_Draft%20I_1661875592.pdf. Accessed 11 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control (NAFDAC). WHO Certifies NAFDAC as ML3 Regulatory Authority. 2022. http://www.nafdac.gov.ng/who-certifies-nafdac-as-MI3-regulatory-authority. Accessed 11 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>This Day. FG Unveils National Vaccine Research Development Plan. 2024. http://www.thisdaylive.com/index.php/2024/01/27/fg-unveils-national-vaccine-research-development-plan. Accessed 30 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Manufacturing, safety and quality control of vaccines. 2020. http://www.who.int/news-room/feature-stories/detail/manufacturing-safety-and-quality-control. Accessed 7 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States Pharmacopoeia (USP). Expanding the capacity to produce vaccines in Africa: Enablers and barriers. 2020. http://www.usp.org/sites/default/files/usp/document/our-work/global-public-health/vaccine-manufacturing-in-africa_white-paper_feb-2023.pdf. Accessed 14 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adepoju P. Africa to Manufacture New Malaria Vaccine? Health Policy Watch. 2023. https://healthpolicy-watch.news/africa-to-manufacture-new-malaria-vaccine/. Accessed 15 Oct. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adigwe OP, Onavbavba G, Adebola OJ, Ayeke A, Sanyaolu SE, Agu KA. Current state and challenges of local production of vaccines in Nigeria. Public Health Chall. 2024. https://doi.org/10.1002/puh2.70006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumraj G, Pathak S, Shah S, Majumder P, Jain J, Bhati D, et&#xa0;al. Capacity building for vaccine manufacturing across developing countries: the way forward. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2022;18:2020529. https://doi.org/10.1080/21645515.2021.2020529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Fonseca EM. How can a policy foster local pharmaceutical production and still protect public health? Lessons from the health-industry complex in Brazil. Glob Public Health. 2018;13:489&#x2013;502. https://doi.org/10.1080/17441692.2017.1396354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmapproach. List of Pharmaceutical Companies in Nigeria. Pharmapproach.com. 2017. https://www.pharmapproach.com/list-of-pharmaceutical-companies-nigeria/. Accessed 11 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oluwayelu D. What it will take to produce vaccines in Nigeria: money&#x2019;s just the first step. 2021. https://doi.org/10.64628/aaj.aq43kg97v.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doua J, Ndembi N, Auerbach J, Kaseya J, Zumla A. Advancing local manufacturing capacities for vaccines within Africa&#x2013;opportunities, priorities and challenges. Vaccine. 2025;50:126829. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaccine.2025.126829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagoev B, Costas J. Interpretive inquiry. In: Neesham C, Reihlen M, Schoeneborn D, editors. Handbook of philosophy of management. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2022. p. 79&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell JW, Poth CN. Qualitative inquiry and research design: choosing among five traditions. Thousand Oaks: Sage Publications; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longhurst R. Semi-structured interviews and focus groups. In: Clifford N, Cope M, Gillespie T, French S, editors. Key methods in geography. 3rd ed. London: Sage; 2016. p. 143&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xe6;raas A. Thematic analysis: making values emerge from texts. In: Espedal G, Jelstad L&#xf8;vaas B, Sirris S, W&#xe6;raas A, editors. Researching values. Cham: Palgrave Macmillan; 2022. p. 153&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln YS, Guba EG. Naturalistic inquiry. Beverly Hills: Sage Publications; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long AH, French DP, Brooks JM. Optimizing the value of the critical appraisal skills programme (CASP) tool for quality appraisal in qualitative evidence synthesis. Res Methods Med Health Sci. 2020;1:31&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogada T. Building a competitive and socially inclusive local pharmaceutical manufacturing in West Africa through enhancing research, innovation and intellectual property. 2019. http://hdl.handle.net/10625/59546. Accessed 17 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obembe TA, Adenipekun AB, Morakinyo OM. Implications of national tax policy on local pharmaceutical production in a south-western state Nigeria &#x2013; qualitative research for the intersection of national pharmaceutical policy on health systems development. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22:264. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-022-07579-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhang D. Innovation policy in China. In: Innovation policy in ASEAN. Singapore: Economic Research Institute for ASEAN and East Asia; 2018. p. 61&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X. The development status and future trends of China&#x2019;s vaccine industry. In: 2022 7th International Conference on Financial Innovation and Economic Development (ICFIED 2022). Amsterdam: Atlantis Press; 2022. 2573&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.2991/aebmr.k.220307.420</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makenga G, Bonoli S, Montomoli E, Carrier T, Auerbach J. Vaccine production in Africa: a feasible business model for capacity building and sustainable new vaccine introduction. Front Public Health. 2019;7:56. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2019.00056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adione JO. Impact of regulatory policy changes on access to medicine in Nigeria, Africa. Int J Sci Res Arch. 2022;6(1):328&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.30574/ijsra.2022.6.1.0134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Recipients of mRNA technology from the WHO mRNA technology transfer hub. 2022. http://www.who.int/initiatives/the-mrna-vaccine-technology-transfer-hub/recipients-of-mrna-technology-from-the-who-mrna-technology-transfer-hub. Accessed 17 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesina F. Nigeria ready to become global hub for vaccine production, distribution &#x2013; President Buhari says at global bio summit in Seoul. Abuja: The State House; 2022 Oct 25. https://statehouse.gov.ng/nigeria-ready-to-become-global-hub-for-vaccine-production-distribution-president-buhari-says-at-global-bio-summit-in-seoul/. Accessed 18 Dec 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owolade AJ, Sokunbi TO, Aremu FO, Omotosho EO, Sunday BA, Adebisi YA, et&#xa0;al. Strengthening Africa&#x2019;s capacity for vaccine research: needs and challenges. Health Promot Perspect. 2022;12:282. https://doi.org/10.34172/hpp.2022.36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CITI Group. Innovative financing for development. 2014. http://www.citigroup.com/rcs/citigpa/akpublic/storage/public/innovative_financing_for_development.pdf. Accessed 17 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubakar I, Dalglish SL, Angell B, Sanuade O, Abimbola S, Adamu AL, et&#xa0;al. The Lancet Nigeria commission: investing in health and the future of the nation. Lancet. 2022;399:1155&#x2013;200. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(21)02488-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Africa CDC. Partnerships for African Vaccine Manufacturing (PAVM) Framework for Action. Africa CDC. 2022. https://africacdc.org/download/partnerships-for-african-vaccine-manufacturing-pavm-framework-for-action/. Accessed 19 Feb 2026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Vaccine Alliance (GAVI). Expanding sustainable vaccine manufacturing in Africa: Priorities for Support. 2024. http://www.gavi.org/news-resources/knowledge-products/expanding-sustainable-vaccine-manufacturing-africa-priorities-support. Accessed 17 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinton Health Access Initiative (CHAI). Current and planned manufacturing in Africa. 2023. http://www.clintonhealthaccess.org/report/current-and-planned-vaccine-manufacturing-in-africa. Accessed 16 Jan 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adigwe OP. COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy and willingness to pay: emergent factors from a cross-sectional study in Nigeria. Vaccine X. 2021;9:100112. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jvacx.2021.100112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adigwe OP, Onavbavba G, Wilson DO, Adebola OJ, Ayeke A, Agu KA. A qualitative exploration of critical issues limiting local vaccines production in Nigeria: lessons from the COVID-19 pandemic. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):4363&#x2013;4363. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-025-24949-6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>