<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41464027</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2076-328X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Behavioral sciences (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Behav Sci (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From Gaze to Music: AI-Powered Personalized Audiovisual Experiences for Children's Aesthetic Education.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1684</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/bs15121684</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The cultivation of aesthetic appreciation through engagement with exemplary artworks constitutes a fundamental pillar in fostering children's cognitive and emotional development, while simultaneously facilitating multidimensional learning experiences across diverse perceptual domains. However, children in early stages of cognitive development frequently encounter substantial challenges when attempting to comprehend and internalize complex visual narratives and abstract artistic concepts inherent in sophisticated artworks. This study presents an innovative methodological framework designed to enhance children's artwork comprehension capabilities by systematically leveraging the theoretical foundations of audio-visual cross-modal integration. Through investigation of cross-modal correspondences between visual and auditory perceptual systems, we developed a sophisticated methodology that extracts and interprets musical elements based on gaze behavior patterns derived from prior pilot studies when observing artworks. Utilizing state-of-the-art deep learning techniques, specifically Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs), these extracted visual-musical correspondences are subsequently transformed into cohesive, aesthetically pleasing musical compositions that maintain semantic and emotional congruence with the observed visual content. The efficacy and practical applicability of our proposed method were validated through empirical evaluation involving 96 children (analyzed through objective behavioral assessments using eye-tracking technology), complemented by qualitative evaluations from 16 parents and 5 experienced preschool educators. Our findings show statistically significant improvements in children's sustained engagement and attentional focus under AI-generated, artwork-matched audiovisual support, potentially scaffolding deeper processing and informing future developments in aesthetic education. The results demonstrate statistically significant improvements in children's sustained engagement (fixation duration: 58.82 &#xb1; 7.38 s vs. 41.29 &#xb1; 6.92 s, <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001, Cohen's d &#x2248; 1.29), attentional focus (AOI gaze frequency increased 73%, <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001), and subjective evaluations from parents (mean ratings 4.56-4.81/5) when visual experiences are augmented by AI-generated, personalized audio-visual experiences.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jiahui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hainan University, Haikou 570228, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shijiazhuang University, Shijiazhuang 050035, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hainan Medical University, Haikou 571199, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7013-5563</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hainan University, Haikou 570228, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>23XJA760002</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Education Humanities and Social Sciences Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Behav Sci (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576826</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2076-328X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-composed music</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-generated music</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">audiovisual cross-modal integration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children&#x2019;s aesthetic education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eye-tracking</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41464027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12729308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs15121684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">bs15121684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Boucher O., Chouinard-Leclaire C., Muckle G., Westerlund A., Burden M. J., Jacobson S. W., Jacobson J. L. An ERP study of recognition memory for concrete and abstract pictures in school-aged children. International Journal of Psychophysiology. 2016;106:106&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2016.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2016.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4966662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27329352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner G., Konrad A., Wang Y., Wattenhofer R. MIDI-VAE: Modeling dynamics and instrumentation of music with applications to style transfer. arXiv. 2018 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1809.07600.1809.07600</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1809.07600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Huang L. Human-computer interaction. Theoretical approaches and design methods. Springer International Publishing; 2022. A systematic review of multimodal interaction in artificial intelligent system supporting children to learn music.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou M.-J., Huang P.-C., Yang C.-H. Same theory, different day: Inquiry into preschool children&#x2019;s multiple intelligence and aesthetics ability. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences. 2014;143:534&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake S. Renaissance music and experimental science. Journal of the History of Ideas. 1970;31(4):483&#x2013;500. doi: 10.2307/2708256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2708256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facoetti A., Trussardi A. N., Ruffino M., Lorusso M. L., Cattaneo C., Galli R., Molteni M., Zorzi M. Multisensory spatial attention deficits are predictive of phonological decoding skills in developmental dyslexia. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience. 2010;22(5):1011&#x2013;1025. doi: 10.1162/jocn.2009.21232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/jocn.2009.21232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19366290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulzele P., Singh R., Kaushik N., Pandey K. A hybrid model for music genre classification using LSTM and SVM; Eleventh International Conference on Contemporary Computing; Noida, India. August 2&#x2013;4; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gage J. Color and culture: Practice and meaning from antiquity to abstraction. University of California Press; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garzotto F., Gelsomini M. Magic room: A smart space for children with neurodevelopmental disorder. IEEE Pervasive Computing. 2018;17(1):38&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1109/MPRV.2018.011591060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MPRV.2018.011591060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guarcello E., Longo A. School children and the challenge of managing AI technologies: Fostering a critical relationship through aesthetic experiences. Taylor &amp; Francis; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi A., Cahn B. R., Damasio A., Damasio H. Neural correlates of accelerated auditory processing in children engaged in music training. Developmental Cognitive Neuroscience. 2016;21:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.dcn.2016.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dcn.2016.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27490304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janik McErlean A. B., Banissy M. J. Color processing in synesthesia: What synesthesia can and cannot tell us about mechanisms of color processing. Topics in Cognitive Science. 2017;9(1):215&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1111/tops.12237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tops.12237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27943645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandinsky W. Concerning the spiritual in art. Digireads.com Publishing; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kattan A., Abdullah R., Salam R. A. Harmony search based supervised training of artificial neural networks; International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Modelling and Simulation; Liverpool, UK. January 27&#x2013;29; 2010. pp. 105&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewald J., Guski R. Cross-modal perceptual integration of spatially and temporally disparate auditory and visual stimuli. Cognitive Brain Research. 2003;16(3):468&#x2013;478. doi: 10.1016/S0926-6410(03)00074-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0926-6410(03)00074-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12706226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas P., Astudillo E., Pel&#xe1;ez E. Designing with computational intelligence. Springer International Publishing; 2017. Human-machine musical composition in real-time based on emotions through a fuzzy logic approach.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magenta Attention RNN song sample [EB/OL] 2016.  [(accessed on 8 November 2025)].  Available online:  https://youtu.be/TgKd8_r-yl8,2016-7-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer G. F., Wuerger S. M. Cross-modal integration of auditory and visual motion signals. Neuroreport. 2001;12(11):2557&#x2013;2560. doi: 10.1097/00001756-200108080-00053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00001756-200108080-00053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11496148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda E. R., editor. Handbook of artificial intelligence for music. Springer; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modrzejewski M., Dorobek M., Rokita P. Artificial intelligence and soft computing. Springer; 2019. Application of deep neural networks to music composition based on MIDI datasets and graphical representation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulvenna C. M. Synaesthesia, the arts and creativity: A neurological connection. Frontiers of Neurology and Neuroscience. 2007;22:206&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17495514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadiku M. N. O., Musa S. M., Chukwu U. C. Artificial intelligence in education. iUniverse; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutz M., Kubovy M. Causality and cross-modal integration. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance. 2009;35(6):1791. doi: 10.1037/a0016455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0016455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19968437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sony CSL  Daddy&#x2019;s car: A song composed by artificial intelligence in the style of the Beatles [EB/OL] 2014.  [(accessed on 8 November 2025)].  Available online:  https://youtu.be/LSHZ_b05W7o.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Southern T. Break free&#x2014;Song composed with AI. Taryn Southern Official Music Video [EB/OL] Aug 21, 2017.  [(accessed on 8 November 2025)].  Available online:  https://youtu.be/XUs6CznN8pw.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spagnolo C. Perceived difficulty in mathematics education; 48th Conference of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education; Santiago, Chile. July 28&#x2013;August 2; 2025. p. 299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spagnolo C., Casalvieri C., Gambini A. Proceedings of ninth international congress on information and communication technology. Springer Nature Singapore; 2024. Different processes for graphical recognition of derivative of a function: An eye-tracker analysis; pp. 551&#x2013;559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence C. Crossmodal correspondences: A tutorial review. Attention, Perception, &amp; Psychophysics. 2011;73(4):971&#x2013;995. doi: 10.3758/s13414-010-0073-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/s13414-010-0073-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21264748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strait D. L., Kraus N. Biological impact of auditory expertise across the life span: Musicians as a model of auditory learning. Hearing Research. 2014;308:109&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1016/j.heares.2013.08.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heares.2013.08.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23988583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeny T. D., Wurnitsch N., Gopnik A., Whitney D. Ensemble perception of size in 4&#x2013;5-year-old children. Developmental Science. 2015;18(4):556&#x2013;568. doi: 10.1111/desc.12239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/desc.12239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5282927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25442844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H., Zhou Y., Tao Q., Rosen J., van Dijken S. Bioinspired multisensory neural network with crossmodal integration and recognition. Nature Communications. 2021;12(1):1120. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-21404-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-21404-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7893014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33602925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker C. M., Bonawitz E., Lombrozo T. Effects of explaining on children&#x2019;s preference for simpler hypotheses. Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review. 2017;24(5):1538&#x2013;1547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28176290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>