<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41464082</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2076-328X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Behavioral sciences (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Behav Sci (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differential Effects of Group Intervention on Psychological Subhealth in University Students: Evidence from Core Predicaments.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1738</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/bs15121738</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Psychological subhealth among university students is a growing concern affecting their development, with insufficient attention to differential intervention effects for students facing distinct core predicaments. This exploratory study investigated the overall and differential effects of a group intervention integrating cognitive behavioral and social support theories on university students with psychological subhealth experiencing trauma, academic pressure, or family dysfunction. After defining these core predicament groups through questionnaire screening, twenty students with psychological subhealth were recruited from each of the three groups (total <i>N</i> = 60) and subsequently randomly assigned to either an 8-week group intervention or a control group. The Symptom Checklist-90 (SCL-90) was used for pre- and post-test assessments. Results showed the intervention significantly improved students' overall psychological health and depressive symptoms. Differential effects were evident: the trauma group markedly improved in interpersonal sensitivity and anxiety; the academic pressure group showed pronounced improvement in obsessive-compulsive and anxiety symptoms; and the family dysfunction group benefited most regarding interpersonal sensitivity and hostility. This study suggests the intervention's effectiveness and its link to students' core predicament types, indicating a need for differentiated strategies based on precise assessment. These findings provide practical implications for precision-oriented mental health services in higher education.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Anxin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-1534-5906</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Law and Political Science, North China Electric Power University (Baoding), Baoding 071003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Yanan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Law and Political Science, North China Electric Power University (Baoding), Baoding 071003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022Y15</GrantID><Agency>2022 Annual 'Great Wall Program' Special Research Project from North China Electric Power University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Behav Sci (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576826</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2076-328X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCL-90</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">core predicaments</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">differential effects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">group intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological subhealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">university students</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41464082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12729880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs15121738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">bs15121738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association . Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders. 5th ed. American Psychiatric Publishing; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bantjes J., Hunt X., Stein D. J. Public health approaches to promoting university students&#x2019; mental health: A global perspective. Current Psychiatry Reports. 2022;24(8):809&#x2013;818. doi: 10.1007/s11920-022-01387-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11920-022-01387-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36399235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbayannis N., Bandari M., Zheng X., Baquerizo H., Pecor K. W., Ming X. Academic stress and mental well-being in college students: Correlations, affected groups, and COVID-19. Frontiers in Psychology. 2022;13:886344. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2022.886344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.886344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9169886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35677139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck A. T., Rush A. J., Shaw B. F., Emery G. Cognitive therapy of depression. Guilford Press; 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck J. S. Cognitive behavior therapy: Basics and beyond. 3rd ed. Guilford Press; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley K. H., Bernstein E. E., Wallace B., Mischoulon D. Treatment for anxiety and comorbid depressive disorders: Transdiagnostic cognitive-behavioral strategies. Psychiatric Annals. 2021;51(5):226&#x2013;230. doi: 10.3928/00485713-20210414-01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/00485713-20210414-01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8382208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34433988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown P., Waite F., Freeman D. Parenting behavior and paranoia: A network analysis and results from the national comorbidity survey-adolescents (NCS-A) Social Psychiatry and Psychiatric Epidemiology. 2021;56(4):593&#x2013;604. doi: 10.1007/s00127-020-01933-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-020-01933-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32812085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerolini S., Zagaria A., Franchini C., Maniaci V. G., Fortunato A., Petrocchi C., Speranza A. M., Lombardo C. Psychological counseling among university students worldwide: A systematic review. European Journal of Investigation in Health, Psychology &amp; Education (EJIHPE) 2023;13(9):1831&#x2013;1849. doi: 10.3390/ejihpe13090133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ejihpe13090133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10528000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37754472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christ C., Schouten M. J., Blankers M., Schaik D. J., van Beekman A. T., Wisman M. A., Stikkelbroek Y. A., Dekker J. J., Schouten M. J. E., van Schaik D. J. F., Beekman A. T. F., Stikkelbroek Y. A. J., Dekker J. J. M., van Schaik D. J. Internet and computer-based cognitive behavioral therapy for anxiety and depression in adolescents and young adults: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Medical Internet Research. 2020;22(9):e17831. doi: 10.2196/17831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/17831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7547394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobb S. Social support as a moderator of life stress. Psychosomatic Medicine. 1976;38(5):300&#x2013;314. doi: 10.1097/00006842-197609000-00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006842-197609000-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">981490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S., Wills T. A. Stress, social support, and the buffering hypothesis. Psychological Bulletin. 1985;98(2):310&#x2013;357. doi: 10.1037/0033-2909.98.2.310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.98.2.310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3901065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari M., Allan S., Arnold C., Eleftheriadis D., Alvarez-Jimenez M., Gumley A., Gleeson J. Digital interventions for psychological well-being in university students: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Medical Internet Research. 2022;24(9):e39686. doi: 10.2196/39686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/39686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9557766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fung H. W., Wong M. Y. C., Moskowitz A., Chien W. T., Hung S. L., Lam S. K. K. Association between psychotic and dissociative symptoms: Further investigation using network analysis. Journal of Trauma &amp; Dissociation. 2023;25(2):279&#x2013;296. doi: 10.1080/15299732.2023.2293776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15299732.2023.2293776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38124492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein E., King C., Crits-Christoph P., Connolly Gibbons M. B. The association between trauma and interpersonal problems in a United States community mental health setting. Journal of Clinical Psychology. 2023;79(4):1192&#x2013;1207. doi: 10.1002/jclp.23467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.23467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36459614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith J. M., Long E. E., Young J. F., Hankin B. L. Co-occurring trajectories of depression and social anxiety in childhood and adolescence: Interactive effects of positive emotionality and domains of chronic interpersonal stress. Journal of Abnormal Child Psychology. 2020;48(6):823&#x2013;837. doi: 10.1007/s10802-020-00634-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10802-020-00634-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargreaves C., Cooke B., McKenna J. Integrating mental health in curriculum design: Reflections from a case study in sport, exercise, and health science. Education Sciences. 2025;15(5):529. doi: 10.3390/educsci15050529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci15050529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu P., Liang P., Liu X., Ouyang Y., Wang J. Parenting styles and obsessive-compulsive symptoms in college students: The mediating role of perfectionism. Frontiers in Psychiatry. 2023;14:1126689. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1126689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2023.1126689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10360192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37484673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Jia G., Zhao Z., Li M., Cao G. The association between family adaptability and adolescent depression: The chain mediating role of social support and self-efficacy. Frontiers in Psychology. 2024;15:1308804. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1308804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1308804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11002239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38596336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Liu L., Yang J. Development and validation of the adolescent self-rating life events checklist [&#x9752;&#x5c11;&#x5e74;&#x751f;&#x6d3b;&#x4e8b;&#x4ef6;&#x91cf;&#x8868;&#x7684;&#x7f16;&#x5236;&#x4e0e;&#x4fe1;&#x6548;&#x5ea6;&#x68c0;&#x9a8c;] Shandong Mental Health Journal. 1997;3:15&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melegkovits E. A., Tang R., Pounds O., Ashcroft K., Jung P., Kennerley H., Fonagy P., Bloomfield M. The experience and role of dissociation in psychosis following developmental trauma: A systematic review. Clinical Psychology Review. 2025;117:102564. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2025.102564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2025.102564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40058297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mofatteh M. Risk factors associated with stress, anxiety, and depression among university undergraduate students. AIMS Public Health. 2021;8(1):36&#x2013;65. doi: 10.3934/publichealth.2021004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3934/publichealth.2021004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7870388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33575406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obando Posada D. P., Cuervo Gil T. J., Sandoval Reyes J. G., Garcia Martin M. B. Perfectionism, academic stress, rumination and worry: A predictive model for anxiety and depressive symptoms in university students from Colombia. Emerging Adulthood. 2023;11(6):1091&#x2013;1105. doi: 10.1177/21676968231188759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21676968231188759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuther E. T., Davis T. E., III, Matthews R. A., Munson M. S., Grills-Taquechel A. E. Fear of anxiety as a partial mediator of the relation between trauma severity and PTSD symptoms. Journal of Traumatic Stress. 2010;23(4):519&#x2013;522. doi: 10.1002/jts.20549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jts.20549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20684018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toseland R. W., Rivas R. F. An introduction to group work practice. 7th ed. Pearson Education Limited; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Niu Z., Xiong J., Chai G., Ye X. The relationship between physical activity and psychological sub-health among high altitude region Tibetan college students. Frontiers in Psychology. 2024;15:1465845. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1465845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1465845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11632234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39664639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization  . World mental health report: Transforming mental health for all. World Health Organization; 2022.  [(accessed on 30 May 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.who.int/teams/mental-health-and-substance-use/world-mental-health-report.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worsley J. D., Pennington A., Corcoran R. Supporting mental health and wellbeing of university and college students: A systematic review of review-level evidence of interventions. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(7):e0266725. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0266725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0266725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9337666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35905058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y., Zeng W., Wan C., Huebner E. S., Zhao X., Shang L. Psychometric properties of the symptom check list 90 (SCL-90) for Chinese undergraduate students. Journal of Mental Health. 2019;28(2):213&#x2013;219. doi: 10.1080/09638237.2018.1521939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638237.2018.1521939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30465457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhou Z., Tao X., Huang L., Zhu E., Yu L., Liu H. Prevalence of subhealth status and its effects on mental health and smartphone addiction: A cross-sectional study among Chinese medical students. Revista da Associacao Medica Brasileira. 2022;68(2):222&#x2013;226. doi: 10.1590/1806-9282.20210977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1806-9282.20210977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35239886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>