<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41591513</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-2218</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Surgical endoscopy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Surg Endosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Machine learning-based models for intraoperative blood loss of retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00464-026-12576-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Intraoperative blood loss (IBL) is a critical precipitating factor of intraoperative and postoperative complications. This study aims to identify risk factors and employ machine learning (ML) techniques to develop models for predicting IBL in patients undergo retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy (RLA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective study was performed with data from patients who underwent unilateral RLA at Beijing Anzhen Hospital from 2014 to 2021. The data were randomly divided into training and validation sets. A volume&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;100&#xa0;ml was defined as high IBL. Model training incorporated feature selection with least absolute shrinkage and selection operator (LASSO) and algorithms including logistic regression (LR), random forest (RF), neural network (NN), K-nearest neighbor (KNN), support vector machine (SVM) and AdaBoost. Various indicators were utilized to evaluate model performance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 530 RLA cases were included. LASSO regression identified gender, surgeons' experience, disease type, lesion diameter and lesion location as predictive factors. Six ML models were derived and evaluated. Among which, LR, RF and NN models exhibited exceptional discriminatory power. The area under the curve (AUC) of the three models were 0.775, 0.769, 0.729 in the validation set, respectively. A nomogram and a online calculator were created. The calibration curve, decision curve analysis and clinical impact curve revealed its excellent clinical utility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study presented and compared the use of various ML models for predicting IBL in RLA, which could assist in assessing surgical risks and tailored treatments without additional examination, and providing insights for the clinical application of ML.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5384-9719</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Undergraduate College, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, No. 2 Anzhen Road, Chaoyang District, Beijing, 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Jiahui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, No. 2 Anzhen Road, Chaoyang District, Beijing, 100029, China. jiahuizhao@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urologic Oncology, Beijing Arion Cancer Center, Mingchun East Road, Daxing District, Beijing, 100070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Mingchuan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, No. 2 Anzhen Road, Chaoyang District, Beijing, 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yili</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, No. 2 Anzhen Road, Chaoyang District, Beijing, 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Dechao</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, No. 2 Anzhen Road, Chaoyang District, Beijing, 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yongxing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, No. 2 Anzhen Road, Chaoyang District, Beijing, 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Zhu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Beijing Anzhen Hospital, Capital Medical University, No. 2 Anzhen Road, Chaoyang District, Beijing, 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Surg Endosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8806653</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0930-2794</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RLA</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Disclosures: Drs. Jing He, Jiahui Zhao, Yong Luo, Mingchuan Li, Yili Han, Dechao Wei, Yongxing Wang and Zhu Hou have no conflicts of interest or financial ties to disclose. Ethical approval: The authors are accountable for all aspects of the work in ensuring that questions related to the accuracy or integrity of any part of the work are appropriately investigated and resolved. The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki (as revised in 2013). Consent for publication: All authors confirm that the work described has not been published previously. The article is not under consideration for publication elsewhere. All authors have read and approved the final manuscript. All authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41591513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-026-12576-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00464-026-12576-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Feciche BO, Barbos V, Big A, Porav-Hodade D, Cumpanas AA, Latcu SC, Zara F, Barb AC, Dumitru CS, Cut TG, Ismail H, Novacescu D (2024) Posterior retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy: an anatomical essay and surgical update. Cancers (Basel). https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers16223841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers16223841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39594796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11593218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Wang Y, Chang X, Han Z (2020) Laparoscopic adrenalectomy (LA) vs open adrenalectomy (OA) for pheochromocytoma (PHEO): a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Surg Oncol 46(6):991&#x2013;998. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejso.2020.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejso.2020.02.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32102743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Li DW, Yan L, Xu ZH, Gu GL (2021) Comparison of lateral transperitoneal and retroperitoneal approaches for homolateral laparoscopic adrenalectomy. BMC Surg 21(1):432. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12893-021-01422-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-021-01422-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34930214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8686258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei K, Wang X, Yang Z, Liu Y, Sun T, Xie W, Ma M (2023) Comparison of the retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy versus transperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy for large (&#x2265;6cm) pheochromocytomas: a single-centre retrospective study. Front Oncol 13:1043753. https://doi.org/10.3389/fonc.2023.1043753</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2023.1043753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36910608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9992891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuncel A, Langenhuijsen J, Erkan A, Mikhaylikov T, Arslan M, Aslan Y, Berker D, Ozgok Y, Gallyamov E, Gozen AS (2021) Comparison of synchronous bilateral transperitoneal and posterior retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy: results of a multicenter study. Surg Endosc 35(3):1101&#x2013;1107. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00464-020-07474-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-020-07474-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32152673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Fang Q, Ding S, Wu X, Zhang P, Cao J, Wu D (2022) The adhesive perinephric fat score is correlated with outcomes of retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy for benign diseases. World J Surg 46(11):2687&#x2013;2694. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00268-022-06671-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00268-022-06671-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35913599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9529704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Yang B, Sun S, Zhang Y (2022) Perioperative factors influencing the difficulty of retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy: a single-center retrospective study. BMC Urol 22(1):22. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12894-022-00976-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12894-022-00976-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35177059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8851746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivas S, Young AJ (2023) Machine learning and artificial intelligence in surgical research. Surg Clin North Am 103(2):299&#x2013;316. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.suc.2022.11.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.suc.2022.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36948720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantinescu G, Schulze M, Peitzsch M, Hofmockel T, Scholl UI, Williams TA, Lenders JWM, Eisenhofer G (2022) Integration of artificial intelligence and plasma steroidomics with laboratory information management systems: application to primary aldosteronism. Clin Chem Lab Med 60(12):1929&#x2013;1937. https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2022-0470</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/cclm-2022-0470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35851438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Zhao J, Luo Y, Wang Y, Li M, Wei D, Yang X, Hou Z, Jiang Y (2023) Establishment and validation of a nomogram for predicting perioperative complications of retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy. Transl Androl Urol 12(4):572&#x2013;585. https://doi.org/10.21037/tau-22-705</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/tau-22-705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37181241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10170273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali Algadiem E, Aleisa AA, Alsubaie HI, Buhlaiqah NR, Algadeeb JB, Alsneini HA (2016) Blood loss estimation using gauze visual analogue. Trauma Mon 21(2):e34131. https://doi.org/10.5812/traumamon.34131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5812/traumamon.34131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27626017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5003499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, Michel V, Thirion B, Grisel O, Blondel M, Prettenhofer P, Weiss R, Dubourg V, Vanderplas J, Passos A, Cournapeau D, Brucher M, Perrot M, Duchesnay &#xc9; (2011) Scikit-learn: Machine learning in python. J Mach Learn Res. 12:2825&#x2013;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop CM (1995) Neural networks for pattern recognition. Oxford University Press</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal M (2005) Random forest classifier for remote sensing classification. Int J Remote Sens 26(1):217&#x2013;222. https://doi.org/10.1080/01431160412331269698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431160412331269698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cover T, Hart P (1967) Nearest neighbor pattern classification. IEEE Trans Inf Theory 13(1):21&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1109/TIT.1967.1053964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIT.1967.1053964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keerthi SS, Shevade SK, Bhattacharyya C, Murthy KRK (2001) Improvements to Platt&#x2019;s SMO algorithm for SVM classifier design. Neural Comput 13(3):637&#x2013;649. https://doi.org/10.1162/089976601300014493</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/089976601300014493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An TK, Kim MH (eds) (2010) A new diverse AdaBoost classifier. 2010 International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Computational Intelligence.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM, Lee S-I (eds) (2017) A unified approach to interpreting model predictions. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems. 30 (NIPS 2017)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise ES, Hocking KM, Polcz ME, Beilman GJ, Brophy CM, Sobey JH, Leisy PJ, Kiberenge RK, Alvis BD (2021) Hemodynamic parameters in the assessment of fluid status in a porcine hemorrhage and resuscitation model. Anesthesiology 134(4):607&#x2013;616. https://doi.org/10.1097/ALN.0000000000003724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000003724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33635950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosele F, Remon J, Mateo J, Westphalen CB, Barlesi F, Lolkema MP, Normanno N, Scarpa A, Robson M, Meric-Bernstam F, Wagle N, Stenzinger A, Bonastre J, Bayle A, Michiels S, Bieche I, Rouleau E, Jezdic S, Douillard JY, Reis-Filho JS, Dienstmann R, Andre F (2020) Recommendations for the use of next-generation sequencing (NGS) for patients with metastatic cancers: a report from the ESMO precision medicine working group. Ann Oncol 31(11):1491&#x2013;1505. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.annonc.2020.07.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2020.07.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao R, Chen HH, Dang Q, Xia LY, Yang ZY, He MF, Hao ZF, Liang Y (2020) Beyond the limitation of targeted therapy: improve the application of targeted drugs combining genomic data with machine learning. Pharmacol Res 159:104932. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phrs.2020.104932</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2020.104932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32473309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo Vercio L, Amador K, Bannister JJ, Crites S, Gutierrez A, MacDonald ME, Moore J, Mouches P, Rajashekar D, Schimert S, Subbanna N, Tuladhar A, Wang N, Wilms M, Winder A, Forkert ND (2020) Supervised machine learning tools: a tutorial for clinicians. J Neural Eng. https://doi.org/10.1088/1741-2552/abbff2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1741-2552/abbff2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33036008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Ojha BD, Aranoff ND, Green P, Tavassolian N (2020) Classification of aortic stenosis using conventional machine learning and deep learning methods based on multi-dimensional cardio-mechanical signals. Sci Rep 10(1):17521. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-74519-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-74519-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33067495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7568576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann M, Kumar C, Zeng WF, Strauss MT (2021) Artificial intelligence for proteomics and biomarker discovery. Cell Syst 12(8):759&#x2013;770. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cels.2021.06.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cels.2021.06.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34411543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill BL, Brown R, Gabel E, Rakocz N, Lee C, Cannesson M, Baldi P, Olde Loohuis L, Johnson R, Jew B, Maoz U, Mahajan A, Sankararaman S, Hofer I, Halperin E (2019) An automated machine learning-based model predicts postoperative mortality using readily-extractable preoperative electronic health record data. Br J Anaesth 123(6):877&#x2013;886. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bja.2019.07.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2019.07.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31627890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6883494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho BJ, Kim KM, Bilegsaikhan SE, Suh YJ (2020) Machine learning improves the prediction of febrile neutropenia in Korean inpatients undergoing chemotherapy for breast cancer. Sci Rep 10(1):14803. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-71927-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-71927-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32908182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7481240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou N, Li M, He L, Xie B, Wang L, Zhang R, Yu Y, Sun X, Pan Z, Wang K (2020) Predicting 30-days mortality for MIMIC-III patients with sepsis-3: a machine learning approach using XGboost. J Transl Med 18(1):462. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12967-020-02620-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-020-02620-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33287854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7720497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsson J, Bjornsson O, Andersson P, Jakobsson A, Cronberg T, Lilja G, Friberg H, Hassager C, Kjaergard J, Wise M, Nielsen N, Frigyesi A (2020) Artificial neural networks improve early outcome prediction and risk classification in out-of-hospital cardiac arrest patients admitted to intensive care. Crit Care 24(1):474. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13054-020-03103-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-020-03103-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32731878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7394679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelham WE, Petras H, Pardini DA (2020) Can machine learning improve screening for targeted delinquency prevention programs? Prev Sci 21(2):158&#x2013;170. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11121-019-01040-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11121-019-01040-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31696355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7041896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Li Z, Yao Q, Mueller RS, Eng JK, Tabb DL, Hervey WJt, Pan C (2018) Sipros ensemble improves database searching and filtering for complex metaproteomics. Bioinformatics 34(5):795&#x2013;802. https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btx601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btx601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29028897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christodoulou E, Ma J, Collins GS, Steyerberg EW, Verbakel JY, Van Calster B (2019) A systematic review shows no performance benefit of machine learning over logistic regression for clinical prediction models. J Clin Epidemiol 110:12&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2019.02.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2019.02.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30763612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y, Xiong Y, Zhou Q, Wu J, Li X, Xiao X (2020) Comparison of machine learning methods and conventional logistic regressions for predicting gestational diabetes using routine clinical data: a retrospective cohort study. J Diabetes Res 2020:4168340. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/4168340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/4168340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32626780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7306091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil A, Al Handawi K, Mohsen Z, Abdel Nour A, Feghali R, Chamseddine I, Kokkolaras M (2022) Weekly nowcasting of new COVID-19 cases using past viral load measurements. Viruses. https://doi.org/10.3390/v14071414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/v14071414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35891394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9317659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou CM, Wang Y, Yang JJ, Zhu Y (2023) Predicting postoperative gastric cancer prognosis based on inflammatory factors and machine learning technology. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak 23(1):53. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12911-023-02150-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-023-02150-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37004065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10067164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers TG, Ramkumar PN, Ricciardi BF, Urish KL, Kipper J, Ketonis C (2020) Artificial intelligence and orthopaedics: an introduction for clinicians. J Bone Joint Surg Am 102(9):830&#x2013;840. https://doi.org/10.2106/JBJS.19.01128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.19.01128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraishi K, Kitahara S, Ito H, Oba K, Ohmi C, Matsuyama H (2019) Transperitoneal versus retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy for large pheochromocytoma: comparative outcomes. Int J Urol 26(2):212&#x2013;216. https://doi.org/10.1111/iju.13838</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iju.13838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30430653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang YL, Qian LJ, Li Z, Wang KE, Zhou XL, Zhou J, Ye CH (2020) Comparison of the retroperitoneal versus transperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy perioperative outcomes and safety for pheochromocytoma: a meta-analysis. BMC Surg 20(1):12. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12893-020-0676-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-020-0676-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31931809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6958587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X, Chen Z, Xia P, Zhang C, Yan K, Fan Y, Wang Y, Ti Y, Bu P (2021) Giant paraganglioma complicated with catecholamine crisis and catecholamine cardiomyopathy: a case report and review of the literature. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 12:790080. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2021.790080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2021.790080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35185782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu SQ, Zhuang CS, Yang XR, Xie WJ, Gong BB, Liu YF, Liu J, Sun T, Ma M (2020) Comparison of robot-assisted retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy versus retroperitoneal laparoscopic adrenalectomy for large pheochromocytoma: a single-centre retrospective study. BMC Surg 20(1):227. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12893-020-00895-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-020-00895-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33028297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7539373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung HS, Kim MS, Yu HS, Hwang EC, Kim SO, Oh KJ, Jung SI, Kang TW, Park K, Kwon DD (2018) Laparoscopic adrenalectomy using the lateral retroperitoneal approach: is it a safe and feasible treatment option for pheochromocytomas larger than 6 cm? Int J Urol 25(5):414&#x2013;419. https://doi.org/10.1111/iju.13524</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iju.13524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisarska-Adamczyk M, Zawadzka K, Wieckowski K, Przeczek K, Major P, Wysocki M, Malczak P, Pedziwiatr M (2021) Risk factors for hemodynamic instability during laparoscopic pheochromocytoma resection: a retrospective cohort study. Gland Surg 10(3):892&#x2013;900. https://doi.org/10.21037/gs-20-783</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/gs-20-783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33842234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8033080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calissendorff J, Juhlin CC, Sundin A, Bancos I, Falhammar H (2021) Adrenal myelolipomas. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 9(11):767&#x2013;775. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2213-8587(21)00178-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(21)00178-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34450092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8851410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decmann A, Perge P, Toth M, Igaz P (2018) Adrenal myelolipoma: a comprehensive review. Endocrine 59(1):7&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12020-017-1473-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-017-1473-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29164520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parnaby CN, Chong PS, Chisholm L, Farrow J, Connell JM, O&#x2019;Dwyer PJ (2008) The role of laparoscopic adrenalectomy for adrenal tumours of 6 cm or greater. Surg Endosc 22(3):617&#x2013;621. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00464-007-9709-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-007-9709-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18071798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiszer P, Toutounchi S, Pogorzelski R, Krajewska E, Sutkowski B, Gierej P, Skorski M (2012) Is tumour size a contraindication to laparoscopic adrenalectomy? Case report. Wideochir Inne Tech Maloinwazyjne 7(2):144&#x2013;146. https://doi.org/10.5114/wiitm.2011.25931</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/wiitm.2011.25931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23256018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakobpon T, Santi-Ngamkun A, Usawachintachit M, Ratchanon S, Sowanthip D, Panumatrassamee K (2021) Laparoscopic transperitoneal adrenalectomy in the large adrenal tumor from single center experience. BMC Surg 21(1):68. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12893-021-01080-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-021-01080-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33522915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7849150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conzo G, Gambardella C, Candela G, Sanguinetti A, Polistena A, Clarizia G, Patrone R, Di Capua F, Offi C, Musella M, Iorio S, Bellastella G, Pasquali D, De Bellis A, Sinisi A, Avenia N (2018) Single center experience with laparoscopic adrenalectomy on a large clinical series. BMC Surg 18(1):2. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12893-017-0333-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-017-0333-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29325527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5765650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim WW, Lee YM, Chung KW, Hong SJ, Sung TY (2019) Comparison of robotic posterior retroperitoneal adrenalectomy over laparoscopic posterior retroperitoneal adrenalectomy: a single tertiary center experience. Int J Endocrinol 2019:9012910. https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/9012910</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/9012910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31885564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6914928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan S, Li K, Wang C, Chen S, Wang H, Luo Y, Li X, Yang L (2023) Which surgical approach is more favorable for pheochromocytoma of different sizes (&lt; 6 cm vs. &gt;/= 6 cm)? A single retrospective center experience. World J Surg Oncol 21(1):285. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12957-023-03164-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12957-023-03164-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37697366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10494336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai YJ, Yu HW, Song RY, Kim SJ, Choi JY, Lee KE (2019) Lateral transperitoneal adrenalectomy versus posterior retroperitoneoscopic adrenalectomy for benign adrenal gland disease: randomized controlled trial at a single tertiary medical center. Ann Surg 269(5):842&#x2013;848. https://doi.org/10.1097/SLA.0000000000002603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000002603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito H, Makiyama K, Kawahara T, Osaka K, Izumi K, Yokomizo Y, Nakaigawa N, Yao M (2016) The impact of gender difference on operative time in laparoscopic partial nephrectomy for T1 renal tumor and the utility of retroperitoneal fat thickness as a predictor of operative time. BMC Cancer 16(1):944. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12885-016-2979-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-016-2979-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27955631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5154121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunseren KO, Cicek MC, Vuruskan H, Kordan Y, Yavascaoglu I (2019) Challenging risk factors for right and left laparoscopic adrenalectomy: a single centre experience with 272 cases. Int Braz J Urol 45(4):747&#x2013;753. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1677-5538.IBJU.2019.0131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1677-5538.IBJU.2019.0131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31136115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6837586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieder JM, Nisbet AA, Wuerstle MC, Tran VQ, Kwon EO, Chien GW (2010) Differences in left and right laparoscopic adrenalectomy. JSLS 14(3):369&#x2013;373. https://doi.org/10.4293/108680810X12924466007520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4293/108680810X12924466007520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21333190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3041033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cianci P, Fersini A, Tartaglia N, Ambrosi A, Neri V (2016) Are there differences between the right and left laparoscopic adrenalectomy? Our Exp Ann Ital Chir 87:242&#x2013;246 (PubMed PMID: 27345193)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragavan N, Selvaraj N, Raghavan D, Kamalakannan R, Govindaswamy TG, Balakrishnan AK, Jain N (2020) Robot assisted laparoscopic adrenalectomy: does size matter? Cureus 12(8):e9887. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.9887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.9887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7502421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>