<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41402461</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Blockchain-based secure MEC model for VANETs using hybrid networks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43912</StartPage><MedlinePgn>43912</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">43912</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-27682-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vehicular Ad-hoc Networks (VANETs) are a type of mobile ad-hoc network that enables vehicles to interact with one another and roadside infrastructure. Multi-Access Edge Computing (MEC) provides a promising solution by positioning storage and computation resources closer to the network edge. This helps to reduce the latency and improve performance. The combination of MEC and blockchain enhances data processing and security. This integration improves privacy safeguards, prevents fraud, and supports trusted communication within VANETs. Consequently, this proposed model aims to develop an innovative approach that leverages these technologies. The main objective of the implemented technique is to create a blockchain architecture powered by deep learning, which ensures the safety of VANETs. The network architecture consists of three layers: perception, edge computing, and services. The main goal of the initial layer is to protect the privacy of VANET data through blockchain activities. The perception layer processes data using edge computing and cloud services. The service layer ensures data protection by through the blockchain technology and storing information in a public cloud. The last layer focuses on addressing user demands for throughput and Quality of Service (QoS). The proposed framework is good for assessing the dependability of vehicle nodes stored on the blockchain. To accomplish node authentication, an Adaptive and Dilated Hybrid Network (ADHyNet) is used. In this approach, the Residual Long Short-Term Memory (Res-LSTM) with Gated Recurrent Unit (GRU) forms the ADHyNet, where the Random Number Updated Skill Optimization Algorithm (RNU-SOA) is used to optimize the hyperparameters. Finally, the encryption process is carried out using Homomorphic Encryption combined with Elliptic Curve Cryptography (HECC) to secure data. This process ensures that confidential user information is protected against unauthorized access. The functionality of the system is thoroughly assessed and simulated. The suggested technique outperforms well than other approaches in terms of data security in VANET.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goud</LastName><ForeName>G Vijay</ForeName><Initials>GV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Saveetha School of Engineering, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Thandalam, Chennai, Tamilnadu, 602105, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arunachalam</LastName><ForeName>Rajesh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Saveetha School of Engineering, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Thandalam, Chennai, Tamilnadu, 602105, India. rajesha.sse@saveetha.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shukla</LastName><ForeName>Surendra Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Amity school of Engineering and Technology, Amity University, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, 201303, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saranya</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Koneru Lakshmaiah Education Foundation, Vaddeswaram, Guntur, Andhra Pradesh, 522302, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venugopal</LastName><ForeName>Sumanth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Manipal Institute of Technology Bengaluru, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, India. sumanth.v@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palanisamy</LastName><ForeName>Preethi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research Impact &amp; Outcome, Chitkara University Institute of Engineering and Technology, Chitkara University, Rajpura, Punjab, 140401, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive and dilated hybrid network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Homomorphic with elliptic curve cryptography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of service</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Random number updated skill optimization algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Residual long short-term memory with gated recurrent unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Secured multi-access edge computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vehicular ad-hoc networks</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41402461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12708641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-27682-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-27682-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Poongodi, M. et al. A novel secured multi-access edge computing based vanet with neuro fuzzy systems based Blockchain framework. <i>Comput. Commun.</i><b>192</b>, 48&#x2013;56 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comcom.2022.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, L. et al. CoopEdge+, Enabling decentralized, secure and cooperative multi-access edge computing based on blockchain. <i>IEEE Trans. Parallel Distrib. Syst.</i><b>34</b>(3), 894&#x2013;908 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPDS.2022.3231296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, D., Richard Yu, F. &amp; Yang, R. Blockchain-based multi-access edge computing for future vehicular networks, a deep compressed neural network approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>23</b>(8), 12161&#x2013;12175 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2021.3110591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y. et al. Optimal computational power allocation in multi-access mobile edge computing for blockchain. <i>Sensors</i><b>18</b>(10), 3472 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s18103472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6211055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30326649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M., Fernando, N., Loke, SW., GhariNeiat, A., Pathirana, P.N., Blockchain-enabled device-enhanced multi-access edge computing in open adversarial environments, pp 2412&#x2013;02233 (2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din, N., Waheed, A., Zareei, M. &amp; Alanazi, F. An improved identity-based generalized signcryption scheme for secure multi-access edge computing empowered flying ad hoc networks. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 120704&#x2013;120714 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3108130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asheralieva, A. &amp; Niyato, D. Secure and efficient coded multi-access edge computing with generalized graph neural networks. <i>IEEE Trans. Mob. Comput.</i><b>22</b>(9), 5504&#x2013;5524 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMC.2022.3172117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaliq, Z., Hussein, A.R. Raft distributed system for multi-access edge computing sharing resources, pp. 2412&#x2013;16774 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatima, N., Saxena, P. &amp; Gupta, M. Integration of multi-access edge computing with unmanned aerial vehicles: Current techniques, open issues and research directions. <i>Phys. Commun.</i><b>52</b>, 101641 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phycom.2022.101641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, T., Wang, N., Pang, Q. &amp; Zhao, X. Security and privacy of 6G wireless communication using fog computing and multi-access edge computing. <i>Scalable Comput. Practice Exp.</i><b>25</b>(2), 770&#x2013;781 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12694/scpe.v25i2.2629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, M. et al. A secure batch authentication scheme for multi-access edge computing in 5G-enabled intelligent transportation system. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>10</b>, 96224&#x2013;96238 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3205001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tefera, G., She, K., Shelke, M. &amp; Ahmed, A. Decentralized adaptive resource-aware computation offloading and caching for multi-access edge computing networks. <i>Sustain. Comput. Inf. Syst.</i><b>30</b>, 100555 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Ioini, N., Barzegar, H. R. &amp; Pahl, C. Trust management for service migration in multi-access edge computing environments. <i>Computer Commun.</i><b>194</b>, 167&#x2013;179 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comcom.2022.07.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedjelmaci, H. &amp; Ansari, N. On cooperative federated defense to secure multi-access edge computing. <i>IEEE Consumer Electron. Magazine</i><b>13</b>, 24&#x2013;31 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MCE.2022.3167527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, F., Yuan, X., Ni, W., Jamalipour, A. A novel privacy-preserving incentive mechanism for multi-access edge computing. <i>IEEE Trans. Cogn. Commun. Network</i>. (2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, F., Yuan, X., Ni, W., Jamalipour, A. Privacy-preserving multi-agent deep reinforcement learning for effective resource auction in multi-access edge computing. <i>IEEE Trans. Cogn. Commun. Netw</i>. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, B., Gregory, M. A., Li, S. &amp; Dib, O. A. Implementing zero trust security with dual fuzzy methodology for trust-aware authentication and task offloading in multi-access edge computing. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>241</b>, 110197 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2024.110197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalidoss, L., Thouti, S., Arunachalam, R. &amp; Ramamurthy, P. An efficient model of enhanced optimization and dilated-GRU based secured multi-access edge computing with blockchain for VANET sector. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>260</b>, 125275 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.125275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. Privacy-aware laser wireless power transfer for aerial multi-access edge computing, a colonel blotto game approach. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>10</b>(7), 5923&#x2013;5939 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2022.3167052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asad, M., Shaukat, S., Javanmardi, E., Nakazato, J., Bao, N., &amp; Tsukada, M. Secure and efficient blockchain-based federated learning approach for VANETs. <i>IEEE Internet Things J</i>. (2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarah, A., Nencioni, G. &amp; Khan, M. M. I. Resource allocation in multi-access edge computing for 5G-and-beyond networks. <i>Computer Netw.</i><b>227</b>, 109720 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2023.109720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. A multi-access edge computing enabled framework for the construction of a knowledge-sharing intelligent machine tool swarm in Industry 4.0. <i>J. Manuf. Syst.</i><b>66</b>, 56&#x2013;70 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmsy.2022.11.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, B., Gregory, M. A. &amp; Li, S. Trust-aware task load balancing in multi-access edge computing based on blockchain and a zero trust security capability framework. <i>Trans. Emerg. Telecommun. Technol.</i><b>34</b>(12), e4845 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ett.4845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyamfi, E. &amp; Jurcut, A. A robust security task offloading in industrial IoT-enabled distributed multi-access edge computing. <i>Front. Signal Process.</i><b>2</b>, 788943 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frsip.2022.788943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Givi, H. &amp; Hubalovska, M. Skill optimization algorithm: a new human-based metaheuristic technique. <i>Comput. Mater. Contin.</i><b>74</b>(1), 179&#x2013;202 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talatahari, S., Azizi, M., Tolouei, M., Talatahari, B. &amp; Sareh, P. Crystal structure algorithm (CryStAl): a metaheuristic optimization method. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 71244&#x2013;71261 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3079161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacanin, N., Tuba, M. (2015) Fireworks algorithm applied to constrained portfolio optimization problem. <i>IEEE Congress Evolut. Ccomput</i>. pp. 1242&#x2013;1249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehghani, M., Hubalovsky, S. &amp; Trojovsky, P. Northern goshawk optimization: a new swarm-based algorithm for solving optimization problems. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 162059&#x2013;162080 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3133286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nechvatal, J. et al. Report on the development of the advanced encryption standard (AES). <i>J. Res. Nat. Inst. Stand. Technol.</i><b>106</b>(3), 511 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6028/jres.106.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4863838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27500035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laia, O. &amp; Zamzami, E. M. Analysis of combination algorithm data encryption standard (DES) and Blum-Blum-Shub (BBS). <i>J. Phys. Conf. Ser.</i><b>1898</b>(1), 012017 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/1898/1/012017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J., Lim, H. Privacy-preserving federated learning using homomorphic encryption. Appl. Sci. <b>12</b>(2) (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geragersian, P., Petrunin, I., Guo, W., Grech, R. An INS/GNSS fusion architecture in GNSS denied environment using gated recurrent unit. In AIAA SCITECH Forum, p. 1759 (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alotaibi, A. Identifying malicious software using deep residual long-short term memory. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>7</b>, 163128&#x2013;163137 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2951751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, J. &amp; Lim, H. Privacy-preserving federated learning using homomorphic encryption. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>12</b>(2), 734 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12020734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naskar, S., Brunetta, C., Zhang, T., Hancke, G., Gidlund, M. Authentication framework with enhanced privacy and batch verifiable message sharing in VANETs. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol, pp. 1&#x2013;6 (2025)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S., Kim, D. &amp; Lee, S. Enhancing V2X security through combined rule-based and DL-based local misbehavior detection in roadside units. <i>IEEE Open J. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>5</b>, 656&#x2013;668 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/OJITS.2024.3479716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, V., Ali, R. &amp; Sharma, P. K. IoV-6G+: A secure blockchain-based data collection and sharing framework for Internet of Vehicles in 6G-assisted environment. <i>Veh. Commun.</i><b>47</b>, 100783 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, V., Ali, R. &amp; Sharma, P. K. IoEPM+: a secured and lightweight 6G-enabled pollution monitoring authentication framework using IoT and blockchain technology. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>250</b>, 110554 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2024.110554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, N. &amp; Ali, R. A smart contract-based robotic surgery authentication system for healthcare using 6G-Tactile Internet. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>238</b>, 110133 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2023.110133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, N. &amp; Ali, R. Blockchain-enabled authentication framework for maritime transportation system empowered by 6G-IoT. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>244</b>, 110353 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2024.110353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, N. &amp; Ali, R. Biometric and smart contract-enabled secure data sharing in drone-assisted battlefield systems. <i>Comput. Electr. Eng.</i><b>124</b>, 110407 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2025.110407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>