<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41669155</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-1078</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical activity, resilience, and depressive symptoms in Chinese college students: gender differences in mediating pathways'.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1726761</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1726761</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1726761</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1726761</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aims to explore the relationship between physical activity and depression levels among college students, while examining the mediating role of resilience and the impact of gender differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Using measurement tools such as the Physical Activity Rating Scale (PARS-3), the Self-Rating Depression Scale (SDS), and the Adolescent Resilience Scale, a questionnaire survey was conducted among 2,000 college students in Chongqing, China. The data were processed and analyzed using SPSS 26.0, including difference analysis, correlation analysis, regression analysis, and Bootstrap analysis, and the structural equation model was established using AMOS 26.0 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">(1) From the perspective of gender differences, male college students exhibit a significantly higher level of physical activity than female students, while also demonstrating significantly lower levels of depression. (2) There is a significant correlation between physical activity, resilience, and depression levels of college students. (3) The level of physical activity exhibits a direct negative correlation with depression levels among college students, with resilience playing a partial mediating role between the two. (4) In the mediation models stratified by gender, physical activity demonstrates greater direct explanatory power for depression among male students, whereas female students exhibit a stronger mediated explanatory power.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Regular participation in physical activities is an important way to improve the mental health level of college students. As much as possible, college students should be encouraged and supported to participate in physical activities (such as organizing fun sports meetings, sports clubs), which holds positive direct or indirect implications for preventing or reducing the incidence of depression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Xu, Yang and Wei.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Junshuai</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School, Jose Rizal University, Mandaluyong, Philippines.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Southwest University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Xiudong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Physical Education, Chongqing University of Arts and Sciences, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550902</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-1078</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">college students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gender difference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resilience</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41669155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12883842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1726761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baron R. M., Kenny D. A. (1986). The moderator-mediator variable distinction in social psychological research: conceptual, strategic and statistical considerations. J. Person. Social Psychol. 51, 1173&#x2013;1182. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.51.6.1173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.51.6.1173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3806354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belcher B. R., Zink J., Azad A., Campbell E., Chakravartti S. P., Herting M. M., et al. (2021). The roles of physical activity, exercise, and fitness in promoting resilience during adolescence: effects on mental well-being and brain development. Biol. Psychiatry 6, 225&#x2013;237. doi: 10.1016/j.bpsc.2020.08.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpsc.2020.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7878276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33067166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campo-Arias A., Pinto-Vasquez H. L., Pedrozo-Pupo J. C. (2022). Confirmatory factor analysis of the brief Spanish Zung Self-rating Depression Scale in patients with chronic pulmonary obstructive disease. Perspect. Psychiatr. Care. 58, 889&#x2013;893. doi: 10.1111/ppc.12868</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ppc.12868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34056715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaliawala K. S., Vidourek R. A., King K. A. (2025). Exploring the impact of depression, stress, and sleep disturbances on academic success in international college students. J. Int. Stud. 15. doi: 10.32674/x8d6rf31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32674/x8d6rf31</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong B. L., Zhang H., Zhu L. Q., Song L. L., Chen C. (2013). Research on the mechanism of female students' physical exercise behavior. J. Sports Res. 27, 91&#x2013;98. doi: 10.15877/j.cnki.nsic.2013.06.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15877/j.cnki.nsic.2013.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H. Q. (2015). Peer victimization and children's problem behaviors: the moderating effect of self-esteem. Chin. J. Clin. Psychol. 23, 281&#x2013;284. doi: 10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2015.02.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2015.02.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan M. M., Lin Y. J., Xin Z. Q., Chen W. F. (2025). Peer attachment and adolescents internet addiction: chain mediating effect of coping style and resilience. Stud. Psychol. Behav. 23, 91&#x2013;98. doi: 10.12139/j.1672-0628.2025.01.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12139/j.1672-0628.2025.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X. L., Zhang K., Chen X. F. (2023). Report on the Mental Health Development of Chinese Citizens (2021&#x2013;2022). Beijing: Social Sciences Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao C., Liu Y., Yan Y. H., Zhang C. C. (2025). Analysis of the current situation and influencing factors of depression symptoms among college students in Shandong, Province. Chin. J. School Health 46, 1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2025151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2025151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Dia M. J., DiNapoli J. M., Garcia-Ona L., Jakubowski R., O'Flaherty D. (2013). Concept analysis: resilience. Arch. Psychiatr. Nurs. 27, 264&#x2013;270. doi: 10.1016/j.apnu.2013.07.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apnu.2013.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24238005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfield G. S., Henderson K., Buchholz A., Obeid N., Hien N., Flament M. F., et al. (2011). Physical activity and psychological adjustment in adolescents. J. Phys. Act. Health. 8, 157&#x2013;163. doi: 10.1123/jpah.8.2.157</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jpah.8.2.157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granizo I. A. R., Vargas J. M. A., Mata S. S. (2019). The role of resilience in the association between physical activity and academic aspects in school children. Sportis Sci. Tech. J. School Sport Phys. Educ. Psychomot. 5, 513&#x2013;531. doi: 10.17979/sportis.2019.5.3.5603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17979/sportis.2019.5.3.5603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenaway K. H., Haslam S. A., Cruwys T., Branscombe N. R., Ysseldyk R. (2015). From &#x201c;we&#x201d; to &#x201c;me&#x201d;: Group identification enhances perceived personal control with consequences for health and well-being. J. Pers. Soc. Psychol. 109, 53&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1037/pspi0000019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pspi0000019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25938701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo G. J., Ma H. (2022). Relationship between depressive emotion and personality of undergraduates: Analysis of coping style as a mediator or moderator. China J. Health Psychol. 30, 426&#x2013;431. doi: 10.13342/j.cnki.cjhp.2022.03.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13342/j.cnki.cjhp.2022.03.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrikse J., Chye Y., Thompson S., Rogasch N. C., Suo C., Coxon J. P., et al. (2022). Regular aerobic exercise is positively associated with hippocampal structure and function in young and middle-aged adults. Hippocampus 32, 137&#x2013;152. doi: 10.1002/hipo.23397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hipo.23397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34961996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzberg M. P., Dejoseph M. L., Luby J., Barch D. M. (2024). Threat experiences moderate the link between hippocampus volume and depression symptoms prospectively in adolescence. Dev. Cogn. Neurosci. 66:101359. doi: 10.1016/j.dcn.2024.101359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dcn.2024.101359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10925924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38447469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y. Q., Gan Y. Q. (2008). Development and psychometric validity of the resilience scale for Chinese adolescents. Acta Psychol. Sin. 40, 902&#x2013;912. doi: 10.3724/SP.J.1041.2008.00902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3724/SP.J.1041.2008.00902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H., Yan L., Yuan Y. R. (2025). The effect of national identity on depression among college students: the mediation of basic psychological needs satisfaction. Chin. J. Clin. Psychol. 33, 353&#x2013;357 + 361. doi: 10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2025.02.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2025.02.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y. F., Yi Z. Y., Yao Y. J., Hu Y. B., Li F. L., Ma H. Z., et al. (2023). Effects of college students' mindfulness on depression symptoms during the epidemic prevention and control period: the mediating effect of psychological resilience. Front. Psychiatry 13:991449. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2022.991449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.991449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36684002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiazhi S., Caixia C., Lamei G., Jian Z. (2025). The relationship between physical activity and depression, anxiety, and stress in college students: a mediating effect of diet. Front Nutr. 12:1611906. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2025.1611906</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2025.1611906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12537415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41127088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandola A., Lewis G., Osborn D. P., Stubbs B., Hayes J. F. (2020). Depression and objectively measured physical activity and sedentary behaviour throughout adolescence: a prospective cohort study. Lancet Psychiatry 7, 262&#x2013;271. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30034-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30034-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7033559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32059797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuehner C. (2017). Why is depression more common among women than among men? Lancet Psychia. 4, 146&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30263-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30263-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27856392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Jiang W., Han S. S., Ye Y. P., Li Y. X., Lou H., et al. (2024). Influence of moderate-to-high intensity physical activity on depression levels: a study based on a health survey of Chinese university students. BMC Public Health. 24:1023. doi: 10.1186/s12889-024-18433-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-18433-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11015539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38609890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Wang P., Li S., Liu Q., Yu F., Guo Z. H., et al. (2023). Canonical correlation analysis of depression and anxiety symptoms among college students and their relationship with physical activity. Sci. Rep. 13:11516. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-38682-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-38682-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10352328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37460562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T. T., Wu X. Y., Tao S. M., Yang Y. J., Xu H. L., Zou L. W., et al. (2020). Study on the relationship between physical activity and physical, mental health of college students. Chin. J. School Health 41, 867&#x2013;870. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2020.06.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2020.06.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W. Z., Zhao Z. Y., Chen D. J., Peng Y., Lu Z. X. (2022). Prevalence and associated factors of depression and anxiety symptoms among college students: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Child Psychol. Psychiatry 63, 1222&#x2013;1230. doi: 10.1111/jcpp.13606</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpp.13606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35297041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X. N., Yu H. S., Yang N. (2021). The mediating role of resilience in the effects of physical exercise on college students' negative emotions during the COVID-19 epidemic. Sci. Rep. 11:24510. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-04336-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-04336-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8720086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34972833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Guo K. (2023). Research on the relationship between physical activity, sleep quality, psychological resilience, and social adaptation among Chinese college students: a cross-sectional study. Front. Psychol. 14:1104897. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1104897</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2023.1104897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9950505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36844303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang D. Q. (1994). Stress level of college students and its relationship with physical activity. Chin. Mental Health J. 1, 5&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang X., Qiu H., Sit C. H. P. (2023). The mediating role of resilience in the association between MVPA and psychological ill-being in children with ADHD. Scand. J. Med. Sci. Sports 33, 485&#x2013;494. doi: 10.1111/sms.14282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36514869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M., Liu H. J., Qin Z. Z., Tao Y. N., Ye W., Liu R. Y., et al. (2024). Effects of physical activity on depression, anxiety, and stress in college students: the chain-based mediating role of psychological resilience and coping styles. Front. Psychol. 15, 1396795. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1396795</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2024.1396795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11191160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38911957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X. Y. (2018). Gender difference of physical exercise and its influence on mental health. Educ. Rev. 154&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z. H. (2020). Effects of physical exercise on negative emotion for university students-The mediating and moderating effects of self-efficacy and mental resilience. J. Phys. Educ. 27, 102&#x2013;108. doi: 10.16237/j.cnki.cn44-1404/g8.2020.05.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16237/j.cnki.cn44-1404/g8.2020.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y. Z., Li T., Wang Q. F., Liu L., andNi S. G. (2020). Effect of resilience and expression suppression on the relationship between social support and posttraumatic growth among front-line medical workers in the epidemic situation of COVID-19. Chin. J. Clin. Psychol. 28, 743&#x2013;746. doi: 10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2020.04.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2020.04.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marten A. S. (2025). Ordinary Magic: Resilience in Development. New York, NY: Guilford Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mccarty C. A., Mason W. A., Kosterman R., Hawkins J. D., Lengua L. J., McCauley E., et al. (2008). Adolescent school failure predicts later depression among girls. J. Adolesc. Health 43, 180&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1016/j.jadohealth.2008.01.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2008.01.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2430389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18639792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myntti W. W., Armstrong S. B. (2022). Bouncing back from COVID-19: The role of resilience in depression, substance use, and loneliness in college students amidst the pandemic. J. Am. Coll. Health. 72, 2872&#x2013;2881. doi: 10.1080/07448481.2022.2135377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2022.2135377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36328785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu G. F., Fan C. Y., Zhou Z. K., Tian Y., Lian S. L. (2015). The effect of adolescents' optimism on depression: the mediating role of resilience. Chin. J. Clin. Psychol. 23, 709&#x2013;711. doi: 10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2015.04.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2015.04.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira S. M. P., Geoffroy M. C., Power C. (2014). Depression and physical activity during 3 decades in adult life: bidirectional associations in a prospective cohort study. JAMA Psychiatry 71, 1373&#x2013;1380. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2014.1240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2014.1240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25321867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsakoff P. M., Mackenzie S. B., Lee J. Y., Podsakoff N. P. (2003). Common method biases in behavioral research: A critical review of the literature and recommended remedies. J. Appl. Psychol. 88, 879&#x2013;903. doi: 10.1037/0021-9010.88.5.879</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.88.5.879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14516251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reivich K., Gillham J. E., Chaplin T. M., Seligman M. E. P. (2013). From Helplessness to Optimism: The Role of Resilience in Treating and Preventing Depression in Youth. Handbook of Resilience in Children (pp. 201&#x2013;214: ). New York: Springer US. doi: 10.1007/978-1-4614-3661-4_12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4614-3661-4_12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro J. D., Huang X., Fox K. R., Franklin J. C. (2018). Depression and hopelessness as risk factors for suicide ideation, attempts and death: meta-analysis of longitudinal studies. Br. J. Psychiatry.212, 279&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1192/bjp.2018.27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.2018.27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29587888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuch F. B., Deslandes A. C., Stubbs B., Gosmann N. P., da Silva C. T. B., Fleck M. P. D., et al. (2016). Neurobiological effects of exercise on major depressive disorder: a systematic review. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 61, 1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2015.11.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2015.11.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26657969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuch F. B., Vancampfort D., Firth J., Rosenbaum S., Ward P. B., Silva E. S., et al. (2018). Physical activity and incident depression: a meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. Am. J. Psychiatry 175, 631&#x2013;648. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2018.17111194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2018.17111194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29690792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz D. (2020). Depression development: from lifestyle changes to motivational deficits. Behav. Brain Res. 395:112845. doi: 10.1016/j.bbr.2020.112845</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2020.112845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi K. Zhao Y. M. Zhang Z. Q. Song X. D. Chen Z. Y. Li H. H. (2024). Psychological screening and crisis intervention research among university students. Psychol. Expl. 44, 464&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorey S., Ng E. D., Wong C. H. J. (2022). Global prevalence of depression and elevated depression among adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br. J. Clin. Psychol. 61, 287&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1111/bjc.12333</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjc.12333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34569066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X. L., Yang M., Wang X. P. (2014). Effect of different sports on resilience of college students. Hebei Petrol. Univ. Technol. 16, 69&#x2013;72.doi: 10.13377/j.cnki.jcpc.2014.05.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13377/j.cnki.jcpc.2014.05.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M. Y., Piao M., Jia Z. N. (2024). The impact of alexithymia, anxiety, social pressure, and academic burnout on depression in Chinese university students: an analysis based on SEM. BMC Psychol. 12:757. doi: 10.1186/s40359-024-02262-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-024-02262-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11657414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39695783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q. F., Jiao L. Y., Zhang G. L. (2024). The effect of physical activity on social adjustment in adolescents: a serial mediation model and the gender differences. Psychol. Res. 17, 375&#x2013;382. doi: 10.19988/j.cnki.issn.2095-1159.2024.04.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19988/j.cnki.issn.2095-1159.2024.04.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taliaferro L. A., Rienzo B. A., Pigg R. M., Miller M. D., Dodd V. J. (2009). Associations between physical activity and reduced rates of hopelessness, depression, and suicidal behavior among college students. J. Am. Coll. Health. 57, 427&#x2013;436. doi: 10.3200/JACH.57.4.427-436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3200/JACH.57.4.427-436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Li Y., Liu H. X., Zhang T. R., Luo J. (2024). Relationship between different levels of internet use and depressive tendencies in Chinese college students: the chain mediating effect based on physical activity and social adaptability. BMC Psychol. 12:670. doi: 10.1186/s40359-024-02153-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-024-02153-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11571916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39551758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M. Y., Han F. F., Liu J., Huang K. L., Peng H. Y., Huang M. T., et al. (2020). A meta-analysis of detection rate of depression symptoms and related factors in college students. Chin. Mental Health J. 34, 1041&#x2013;1047. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1000-6729.2020.12.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1000-6729.2020.12.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X. R., Qiu L. H. (2023). Research progress on magnetic resonance brain structure imaging of gender differences in adolescent depression. J. Clin. Radiol. 42, 1689&#x2013;1692. doi: 10.13437/j.cnki.jcr.2023.10.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13437/j.cnki.jcr.2023.10.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf S., Seiffer B., Zeibig J. M., Welkerling J., Brokmeier L., Atrott B., et al. (2021). Is physical activity associated with less depression and anxiety during the COVID-19 pandemic? A rapid systematic review. Sports Med. 51, 1771&#x2013;1783. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01468-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01468-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8060908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33886101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang M. Q., Tan X. M., Sun J., Yang H. Y., Zhao X. P., Liu L., et al. (2020). Relationship of physical activity with anxiety and depression symptoms in Chinese college students during the COVID-19 outbreak. Front. Psychol. 11:582436. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2020.582436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.582436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33329238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao R., Wang Q. X. Z., Zheng Z. S. (2017). The relationship between college students' physical activity and depression: the impact of gender differences. Chin. J. Sports. Med. 36, 812&#x2013;816, 822. doi: 10.16038/j.1000-6710.2017.09.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16038/j.1000-6710.2017.09.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie H., Tao S., Zhang Y., Tao F. B., Wu X. Y. (2019). Impact of problematic mobile phone use and insufficient physical activity on depression symptoms: a college-based follow-up study. BMC Public Health 19, 1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1186/s12889-019-7873-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-019-7873-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6896767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31805915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Liu Z., Tian S., Ma Z., Jia C., Sun G., et al. (2021). Physical activity and resilience among college students: the mediating effects of basic psychological needs. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 18:3722. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18073722</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18073722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8038173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33918303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y. J., Huang C., Xu Y. P., Yang G. (2024). Relationship between physical activity levels and depression in college students: a cohort study. Chin. J. School Health 45, 406&#x2013;410. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2024075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2024075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J. W., Li W., Jin X., Yin F., Wang Z. J., Cao J. Q., et al. (2025). Network analysis of interrelationships among physical activity, sleep disturbances, depression, and anxiety in college students. BMC Psychiatry 25:904. doi: 10.1186/s12888-025-07376-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-025-07376-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12487090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41034803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L. (2023). Trends and prediction of the burden of depression among adolescents aged 10 to 24 years in China from 1990 to 2019. Chin. J. School Health 44, 1063&#x2013;1067. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2023.07.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2023.07.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X., Peng Z., Ma X., Meng Y. J., Li M. L., Zhang J., et al. (2017). Sex differences in the clinical characteristics and brain gray matter volume alterations in unmedicated patients with major depressive disorder. Sci. Rep. 7:2515. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-02828-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-02828-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5449404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28559571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X. F., Chu X. Y., Zhang L., Palizhati M., Hu P. (2025). Trait procrastination and depression in undergraduates: a moderated mediation model. Psychol. Explor. 45, 160&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Deng J. (2015). The moderating effect of psychological resilience on the relationship between life stress and suicidal ideation among poor college students. Theory Pract. Contemp. Educ. 7, 137&#x2013;140. doi: 10.13582/j.cnki.1674-5884.2015.02.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13582/j.cnki.1674-5884.2015.02.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye M. S., Jin L., Zhou Y. X., Chen C., Zhou M. J. (2018). Relationship between resilience and depression in emerging adulthood: the moderating effect of face. Chin. Gen. Pract. 21, 98&#x2013;103. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1007-9572.2018.01.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1007-9572.2018.01.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Dong B. L. (2017). Influence of gender role, sport friendship and autonomous motivation on adolescent exercise adherence. J. Tianjin Univ. Sport. 32, 355&#x2013;363. doi: 10.13297/j.cnki. issn1005-0000.2017.04.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13297/j.cnki.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Yen S. T. (2015). Physical activity, gender difference, and depressive symptoms. Health Serv. Res. 50, 1550&#x2013;1573. doi: 10.1111/1475-6773.12285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1475-6773.12285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4600361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25630931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Zhang S. Q., Zhao Y. G., Shang Y. X. (2024). Role of emotion regulation as a mediator between childhood abuse and depression in college students. Chin. J. Health Educ. 40, 441&#x2013;445. doi: 10.16168/j.cnki.issn.1002-9982.2024.05.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16168/j.cnki.issn.1002-9982.2024.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R. P., Wang Y. B. (2022). Relationship among peer victimization, resilience and depression tendency in rural primary and secondary school students in Pingdingshan city of Henan province. Med. Soc. 35, 100&#x2013;104 + 121. doi: 10.13723/j.yxysh.2022.09.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13723/j.yxysh.2022.09.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. H., Wang T., Kuang J., Herold F., Ludyga S., Li J. M., et al. (2022). The roles of exercise tolerance and resilience in the effect of physical activity on emotional states among college students. Int. J. Clin. Health Psychol. 22:100312. doi: 10.1016/j.ijchp.2022.100312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijchp.2022.100312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35712359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R. D., Yu J. H., Guo J. R., Wang X. Y. (2024). Correlation between physical exercise and parenting styles, and psychological resilience of college students. Chin. J. School Health 45, 1152&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2024240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2024240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Wang Y. Q., Wang J., Jiang M. M., Wang J., Jin Y. L., et al. (2021). Relationship between self-harm with depression and anxiety in college students. Chin. J. School Health 42, 92&#x2013;95. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2021.01.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2021.01.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J. F., Ma S., Xiong J. P., Song Y. J., Zou Z. Y. (2024). Association between physical activity and anxiety/depression symptoms among college students in Jiangxi Province. Chin. J. School Health 45:1722-1726. doi: 10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2024364</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16835/j.cnki.1000-9817.2024364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zung W. W. K. (1965). A self-rating depression scale. Arch. Gen. Psychiatry 12:63. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.1965.01720310065008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.1965.01720310065008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14221692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo L. J., Wang Y., Wang J. F., Yao Y. D., Yang G. (2025). Physical activity influences negative emotion among college students in china: the mediating and moderating role of psychological resilience. Healthcare 13:1170. doi: 10.3390/healthcare13101170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare13101170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12110846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40428006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>