<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41495307</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An intelligent life prediction approach employing machine learning models for the power transformers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4016</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4016</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4016</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-34033-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate assessment of transformer insulating paper is vital for reliable operation and optimal transformer management, with the Degree of Polymerization (DP) serving as a primary indicator of insulation health. Direct DP measurement is often impractical, prompting this study to explore machine learning models for predicting DP using 2-Furfuraldehyde (2-FAL), a cellulose degradation byproduct measurable in transformer oil. This approach classifies insulation into four categories&#x2014;Fresh (DP: 700&#x2013;1200), Lightly Aged (DP: 450&#x2013;700), Moderately Aged (DP: 250&#x2013;450), and Worstly Aged (DP&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;250)&#x2014;based on DP values, offering a streamlined alternative to conventional multi-gas diagnostic methods. Supervised machine learning algorithms were developed using IEEE C57.104-2019 standard data, employing regression (Linear Regression, Polynomial Regression, Random Forest Regressor) to predict continuous DP and classification (Logistic Regression, Support Vector Machine with RBF kernel, Random Forest Classifier) to categorize insulation condition. Model performance was evaluated using regression metrics (Mean Squared Error, Mean Absolute Error, R&#xb2; Score) and classification metrics (accuracy, precision, recall, F1-score). The Random Forest Regressor (R&#xb2;: 0.894) and Classifier (accuracy: 0.925) demonstrated superior performance, enabling precise, non-invasive DP estimation and condition assessment. These findings highlight the efficacy of 2-FAL-based machine learning models for transformer health monitoring, facilitating predictive maintenance and enhancing operational reliability.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nezami</LastName><ForeName>Md Manzar</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, GLA University, Mathura, 281406, India. manzar.nezami@gla.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Sultan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, College of Computer Engineering and Sciences, Prince Sattam Bin Abdulaziz University, Al kharj, 11942, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University Center for Research and Development (UCRD), Chandigarh University, Gharuan, Mohali, 140413, Punjab, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salamat</LastName><ForeName>Arshi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>F/o Engineering and Technology, Jamia Millia Islamia, New Delhi, 110025, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ansari</LastName><ForeName>Md Fahim</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Engineering Department, Graphic Era Deemed to be University, Dehradun, Uttarakhand, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsubait</LastName><ForeName>Tahani</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence, Umm Al-Qura University, Makkah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taha</LastName><ForeName>Ibrahim B M</ForeName><Initials>IBM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, College of Engineering, Taif University, Taif, 21944, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghatasheh</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Sciences, Middle East University, Amman, 11831, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed Abdelwahab</LastName><ForeName>Saad A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical, Faculty of Technology and Education, Suez University, P.O. Box 43221, Suez, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flah</LastName><ForeName>Aymen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Science Research Center, Applied Science Private University, Amman, 11931, Jordan. aymen.flah@vsb.cz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENET Centre, CEET, VSB- Technical University of Ostrava, Ostrava, Czech Republic. aymen.flah@vsb.cz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research Impact and Outcome, Chitkara University, Punjab University, Rajpura, 140401, Punjab, India. aymen.flah@vsb.cz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">2-FAL</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Condition monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power transformer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive maintenance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41495307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12855793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-34033-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-34033-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Badawi, M. et al. Reliable Estimation for health index of transformer oil based on novel combined predictive maintenance techniques. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>10</b>, 25954&#x2013;25972. 10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3156102 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2022.3156102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoneim, S. S. M., Mahmoud, K., Lehtonen, M. &amp; Darwish, M. M. F. Enhancing diagnostic accuracy of transformer faults using teaching-learning based optimization. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>9</b>, 30817&#x2013;30832 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3060288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emara, M. M., Peppas, G. D. &amp; Gonos, I. F. Two graphical shapes based on DGA for power transformer fault types discrimination. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>28</b> (3), 981&#x2013;987 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2021.009415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kachler, A. J. &amp; Hohlein, I. Aging of cellulose at transformer service temperatures. Part 1: influence of type of Oil and air on the degree of polymerization of pressboard, dissolved gases, and furanic compounds in Oi. <i>IEEE Elect. Insul. Magz</i>. <b>21</b> (2), 15&#x2013;21. 10.1109/MEI.2005.1412215 (2005). March-April.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MEI.2005.1412215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaman, H. S. et al. New insights on thermal ageing of electrical insulating oils as revealed from photoluminescence and absorption spectroscopy. <i>High. Voltage</i>. <b>9</b> (5), 1033 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/hve2.12482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, M. et al. A novel maintenance decision making model of power Transformers based on reliability and economy assessment. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>7</b>, 28778&#x2013;28790 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2897606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baird, P. J., Herman, H., Stevens, G. C. &amp; Jarman, P. N. Non-destructive measurement of the degradation of transformer insulating paper. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>13</b> (2), 309&#x2013;318 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2006.1624275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, X., Liu, J., Lai, B., Zhang, Y. &amp; Zhang, C. FDS measurement-based moisture Estimation model for transformer oil-paper insulation including the aging effect. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>70</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2021).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. et al. Moisture diagnosis of transformer oil-immersed insulation with intelligent technique and frequency-domain spectroscopy. <i>IEEE Trans. Industr Inf.</i><b>17</b>, 4624&#x2013;4634 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2020.3014224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghunem, R. A., Assaleh, K. &amp; El-Hag, A. H. Artificial neural networks with Stepwise regression for predicting transformer oil Furan content. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>19</b>, 414&#x2013;420 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2012.6180233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nezami, M. M., Wani, S. A., Khan, S. A., Khera, N. &amp; Sohail, S. A comb-type capacitive 2-FAL sensor for transformer oil with improved sensitivity. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>69</b>, 4524&#x2013;4532 (2020). </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2019.2942519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, D. W., Yang, L. J., Liao, R. J., Zhou, L. W. &amp; Lin, Y. D. Effect of moisture content on the production and partitioning of furfural in oil-paper insulation. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>25</b>, 2389&#x2013;2397 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2018.007238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teymouri, A. &amp; Vahidi, B. CO<sub>2</sub>/CO concentration ratio: A complementary method for determining the degree of polymerization of power transformer paper insulation. <i>IEEE Electr. Insul. Magz</i>. <b>33</b>, 24&#x2013;30 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MEI.2017.7804313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Liao, R., Cheng, L. &amp; Cheng, Z. Effects of winding vibration on the mechanical-thermal aging properties of insulating paper. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>8</b>, 67912&#x2013;67920 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2984257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandlik, M. &amp; Ramu, T. S. Moisture aided degradation of oil impregnated paper insulation in power Transformers. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>21</b> (1), 186&#x2013;193. 10.1109/TDEI.2013.004186 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2013.004186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leibfried, T. et al. Postmortem investigation of power transformers &#x2013; Profile of degree of polymerization and correlation with Furan concentration in the oil. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Deliv</i>. <b>28</b> (2), 886&#x2013;893. 10.1109/TPWRD.2013.2245152 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2013.2245152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S. et al. A new technique to estimate the degree of polymerization of insulation paper using multiple aging parameters of transformer oil. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>7</b>, 157471&#x2013;157479. 10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2949580 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2949580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, S., Baral, A., Mishra, D. &amp; Chakravorti, S. A novel method to predict severity of thermal aging and degree of polymerization for reliable diagnosis of dry-type insulation. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>29</b> (2), 631&#x2013;640. 10.1109/TDEI.2022.3157922 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2022.3157922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Siada, A. &amp; Islam, S. A new approach to identify power transformer criticality and asset management decision based on dissolved gas-in-oil analysis. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>19</b> (3), 1007&#x2013;1012. 10.1109/TDEI.2012.6215106 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2012.6215106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. C. &amp; Sun, H. C. Dissolved gas analysis of mineral oil for power transformer fault diagnosis using fuzzy logic. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>20</b> (3), 974&#x2013;981. 10.1109/TDEI.2013.6518967 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2013.6518967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoneim, S. S. M., Taha, I. B. M. &amp; Elkalashy, N. I. Integrated ANN-based proactive fault diagnostic scheme for power Transformers using dissolved gas analysis. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>33</b> (3), 1838&#x2013;1845. 10.1109/TDEI.2016.005301 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2016.005301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha, T. K. Review of modern diagnostic techniques for assessing insulation condition in aged Transformers. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>10</b> (5), 903&#x2013;917. 10.1109/TDEI.2003.1237337 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2003.1237337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., Zhang, H., Geng, C., Fan, X. &amp; Zhang, Y. Aging assessment model of transformer insulation based on furfural indicator under different oil/pressboard ratios and oil change. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>28</b> (3), 1061&#x2013;1069. 10.1109/TDEI.2021.009530 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2021.009530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M., Lee, G., Hettiwatte, S. N. &amp; Williams, K. Calculating a health index for power Transformers using a subsystem-based GRNN approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Deliv</i>. <b>33</b> (4), 1903&#x2013;1912. 10.1109/TPWRD.2017.2770166 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2017.2770166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Zhang, Y. &amp; Li, X. Quantitative measurements of DP in cellulose paper based on terahertz spectroscopy. <i>Polymers</i><b>15</b> (1), 247 10.3390/polym15010247 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15010247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9823725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36616596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Zhang, J., Wang, F., Huang, Z. &amp; Zhou, Q. A novel aging indicator of transformer paper insulation based on dispersion staining colors of cellulose fibers in oil. <i>IEEE Electr. Insul. Magz</i>. <b>34</b> (4), 8&#x2013;16. 10.1109/MEI.2018.8430039 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MEI.2018.8430039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senoussaoui, M. E. A., Brahami, M. &amp; Fofana, I. Transformer oil quality assessment using random forest with feature engineering. <i>Energies</i><b>14</b> (7), 1809. 10.3390/en14071809 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en14071809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rediansyah, D., Prasojo, R. A., Suwarno &amp; Abu-Siada, A. Artificial intelligent-based power transformer health index for handling data uncertainty. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>9</b>, 150637&#x2013;150648. 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3125379 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3125379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashkezari, A. D., Ma, H., Saha, T. K. &amp; Ekanayake, C. Application of fuzzy support vector machine for determining the health index of the insulation system of in-service power Transformers. <i>IEEE Trans. Dielectr. Electr. Insul.</i><b>20</b> (3), 965&#x2013;973. 10.1109/TDEI.2013.6518966 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDEI.2013.6518966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guide for the Interpretation of Gases Generated in Mineral. Oil-Immersed Transformers, Standard IEEE C57.104, <i>Inst. Elect. Electron. Eng</i>., Piscataway, NJ, USA, (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, S. et al. Concentration prediction of polymer insulation aging indicator-alcohols in oil based on genetic algorithm-optimized support vector machines. <i>Polymers</i><b>14</b>, 1449 10.3390/polym14071449 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14071449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9003247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35406322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundgaard, L. E., Hansen, W., Linhjell, D. &amp; Painter, T. J. Aging of oil-impregnated paper in power Transformers. <i>IEEE Trans. Power Deliv</i>. <b>19</b> (1), 230&#x2013;239. 10.1109/TPWRD.2003.820175 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2003.820175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>