<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41661498</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2150-5551</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nano-micro letters</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nanomicro Lett</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-Assembled Monolayers in Inverted Perovskite Solar Cells: A Rising Star with Challenges.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>241</StartPage><MedlinePgn>241</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">241</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40820-026-02089-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recently, self-assembled monolayers (SAMs) have been confirmed as a promising hole-selective contact and interfacial modifier for inverted perovskite solar cells (IPSCs), contributing to an inspiring record power conversion efficiency close to 27%, along with excellent stability. This review demonstrates the critical role of SAMs in enhancing the performance of IPSCs. First, the structure-property and structure-stability relationship of SAMs is systematically expounded by examining their electronic structure, spatial configuration, and the resulting intermolecular forces. Second, it concludes the underlying mechanisms how their unique properties promote the performance of IPSCs, including energy-level alignment, defect passivation, improved interface carrier extraction/transport, and the suppression of ion migration. Third, the applications of SAMs in IPSCs are systematically summarized, covering their roles as hole-selective contacts, interface modifiers, and as components in Co-SAMs strategies. Large-scalable fabrication methods are also summarized to promote industrial processing of IPSCs. Finally, the prevailing challenges and future research directions are outlined, proposing a roadmap for designing SAM-based IPSCs with superior longevity. By critically evaluating the pivotal role of SAMs, this review provides a strategic framework to guide future research and accelerate the development of self-assembled molecules in high-performance and stable photovoltaic devices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lele</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Flexible Optoelectronic Materials and Technology of the Ministry of Education, Jianghan University, Wuhan, 430056, Hubei, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Jiaqi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Flexible Optoelectronic Materials and Technology of the Ministry of Education, Jianghan University, Wuhan, 430056, Hubei, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Huimin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Flexible Optoelectronic Materials and Technology of the Ministry of Education, Jianghan University, Wuhan, 430056, Hubei, People's Republic of China. huiminxiang@jhun.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xunchang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Flexible Optoelectronic Materials and Technology of the Ministry of Education, Jianghan University, Wuhan, 430056, Hubei, People's Republic of China. wangxc@jhun.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Nanomicro Lett</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101727940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2150-5551</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inverted perovskite solar cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Large-scalable fabrication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-assembled monolayers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no interest conflict. They have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41661498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12886713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-026-02089-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40820-026-02089-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>W. Jiang, G. Qu, X. Huang, X. Chen, L. Chi et al., Toughened self-assembled monolayers for durable perovskite solar cells. Nature <b>646</b>(8083), 95&#x2013;101 (2025). 10.1038/s41586-025-09509-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-025-09509-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40963016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Magomedov, A. Al-Ashouri, E. Kasparavi&#x10d;ius, S. Strazdaite, G. Niaura et al., Self-assembled hole transporting monolayer for highly efficient perovskite solar cells. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>8</b>(32), 1801892 (2018). 10.1002/aenm.201801892</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.201801892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W.C. Bigelow, D.L. Pickett, W.A. Zisman, Oleophobic monolayers i. Films adsorbed from solution in non-polar liquids. J. Colloid Sci. <b>1</b>(6), 513&#x2013;538 (1946). 10.1016/0095-8522(46)90059-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0095-8522(46)90059-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gao, Z. Ou, C. Wang, L. Liu, D. Hu et al., Multifunctional buried molecule-bridge for high-performance inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. 38, e14273,(2025). 10.1002/adma.202514273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202514273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40960195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhang, S. Zhang, X. Ji, J. He, H. Guo et al., Formamidinium lead iodide-based inverted perovskite solar cells with efficiency over 25% enabled by an amphiphilic molecular hole-transporter. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>63</b>(16), e202401260 (2024). 10.1002/anie.202401260</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202401260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38372399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Al-Ashouri, E. K&#xf6;hnen, B. Li, A. Magomedov, H. Hempel et al., Monolithic perovskite/silicon tandem solar cell with &gt;29% efficiency by enhanced hole extraction. Science <b>370</b>(6522), 1300&#x2013;1309 (2020). 10.1126/science.abd4016
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abd4016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Wang, J. Zheng, W. Duan, J. Yang, M.A. Mahmud et al., Molecular engineering of hole-selective layer for high band gap perovskites for highly efficient and stable perovskite-silicon tandem solar cells. Joule <b>7</b>(11), 2583&#x2013;2594 (2023). 10.1016/j.joule.2023.09.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2023.09.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Al-Ashouri, A. Magomedov, M. Ro&#xdf;, M. Jo&#x161;t, M. Talaikis et al., Conformal monolayer contacts with lossless interfaces for perovskite single junction and monolithic tandem solar cells. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>12</b>(11), 3356&#x2013;3369 (2019). 10.1039/C9EE02268F</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9EE02268F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yang, G. Qu, Y. Qiao, S. Cai, J. Hu et al., Flexibility meets rigidity: a self-assembled monolayer materials strategy for perovskite solar cells. Nat. Commun. <b>16</b>(1), 6968 (2025). 10.1038/s41467-025-62388-4
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-62388-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12307864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40730816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C.C. Boyd, R.C. Shallcross, T. Moot, R. Kerner, L. Bertoluzzi et al., Overcoming redox reactions at perovskite-nickel oxide interfaces to boost voltages in perovskite solar cells. Joule <b>4</b>(8), 1759&#x2013;1775 (2020). 10.1016/j.joule.2020.06.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2020.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhou, X. Huang, J. Zhang, L. Zhang, H. Wu et al., Interfacial modification of NiO<sub>x</sub> for highly efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>14</b>(25), 2400616 (2024). 10.1002/aenm.202400616</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202400616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.A. Ok, B. Jo, S. Somasundaram, H.J. Woo, D.W. Lee et al., Management of transition dipoles in organic hole-transporting materials under solar irradiation for perovskite solar cells. Nat. Commun. <b>9</b>(1), 4537 (2018). 10.1038/s41467-018-06998-1
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-06998-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6208393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30382104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhao, T. Heumueller, J. Zhang, J. Luo, O. Kasian et al., A bilayer conducting polymer structure for planar perovskite solar cells with over 1,400 hours operational stability at elevated temperatures. Nat. Energy <b>7</b>(2), 144&#x2013;152 (2022). 10.1038/s41560-021-00953-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-021-00953-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F.H. Isikgor, S. Zhumagali, L.V.T. Merino, M. De Bastiani, I. McCulloch et al., Molecular engineering of contact interfaces for high-performance perovskite solar cells. Nat. Rev. Mater. <b>8</b>(2), 89&#x2013;108 (2023). 10.1038/s41578-022-00503-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41578-022-00503-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Li, S. Liu, Revolutionary SAMs: transforming inverted perovskite solar cells. J. Mater. Chem. A <b>12</b>(17), 9929&#x2013;9932 (2024). 10.1039/d4ta00962b</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ta00962b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Yu, D. Gao, Z. Li, X. Sun, B. Li et al., Green-solvent processable dopant-free hole transporting materials for inverted perovskite solar cells. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>62</b>(11), e202218752 (2023). 10.1002/anie.202218752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202218752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36648451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Zhao, Q. Liu, L. Yao, C. De&#x11f;er, J. Shen et al., Peri-fused polyaromatic molecular contacts for perovskite solar cells. Nature <b>632</b>(8024), 301&#x2013;306 (2024). 10.1038/s41586-024-07712-6
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-024-07712-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39048825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Liu, L. Bi, W. Jiang, Z. Zeng, S.-W. Tsang et al., Compact hole-selective self-assembled monolayers enabled by disassembling micelles in solution for efficient perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>35</b>(46), 2304415 (2023). 10.1002/adma.202304415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202304415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37487572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhang, F. Ye, X. Wang, R. Chen, H. Zhang et al., Minimizing buried interfacial defects for efficient inverted perovskite solar cells. Science <b>380</b>(6643), 404&#x2013;409 (2023). 10.1126/science.adg3755
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.adg3755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37104579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Du, J. Chen, B. Ouyang, A. Sun, C. Tian et al., Face-on oriented self-assembled molecules with enhanced &#x3c0;&#x2013;&#x3c0; stacking for highly efficient inverted perovskite solar cells on rough FTO substrates. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>18</b>(7), 3196&#x2013;3210 (2025). 10.1039/d4ee05849f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ee05849f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Lv, Z. Wang, G. Liu, Y. Gao, S. Li et al., Pre-anchored ionic bond mediators enabling controllable monolayer assembly for high-performance perovskite solar cells and modules. Adv. Mater. (2025). 10.1002/adma.202513600</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202513600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40937956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhang, Y. Yang, J. Zhao, H. Yang, Y. Lu et al., A self-assembling composite structural design for the conversion of hydroxyl-anchored bonds obtains high efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>37</b>(28), 2420155 (2025). 10.1002/adma.202420155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202420155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40348593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, X. Sun, X. Zheng, B. Li, D. Gao et al., Stabilized hole-selective layer for high-performance inverted p-i-n perovskite solar cells. Science <b>382</b>(6668), 284&#x2013;289 (2023). 10.1126/science.ade9637
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.ade9637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37856581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Jiang, F. Li, M. Li, F. Qi, F.R. Lin et al., &#x3c0;-expanded carbazoles as hole-selective self-assembled monolayers for high-performance perovskite solar cells. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>61</b>(51), e202213560 (2022). 10.1002/anie.202213560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202213560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36300589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ullah, K.H. Park, H.D. Nguyen, Y. Siddique, S.F.A. Shah et al., Novel phenothiazine-based self-assembled monolayer as a hole selective contact for highly efficient and stable p-i-n perovskite solar cells. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>12</b>(2), 2103175 (2022). 10.1002/aenm.202103175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202103175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, Q. Liao, J. Chen, W. Huang, X. Zhuang et al., Teaching an old anchoring group new tricks: enabling low-cost, eco-friendly hole-transporting materials for efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>142</b>(39), 16632&#x2013;16643 (2020). 10.1021/jacs.0c06373
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.0c06373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32852200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Li, C. Liu, H. Lin, X. Xu, S. Liu et al., Bonding strength regulates anchoring-based self-assembly monolayers for efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>31</b>(35), 2103847 (2021). 10.1002/adfm.202103847</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202103847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Li, Z. Zhang, H. Zhang, W. Yan, Y. Li et al., Fully aromatic self-assembled hole-selective layer toward efficient inverted wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells with ultraviolet resistance. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>63</b>(1), e202315281 (2024). 10.1002/anie.202315281</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202315281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37987092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C.E. Puerto Galvis, D.A. Gonz&#xe1;lez Ruiz, E. Mart&#xed;nez-Ferrero, E. Palomares, Challenges in the design and synthesis of self-assembling molecules as selective contacts in perovskite solar cells. Chem. Sci. <b>15</b>(5), 1534&#x2013;1556 (2024). 10.1039/d3sc04668k
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d3sc04668k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10829004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38303950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T.S. Bejitual, K. Ramji, A.J. Kessman, K.A. Sierros, D.R. Cairns, Corrosion of an amorphous indium tin oxide film on polyethylene terephthalate at low concentrations of acrylic acid. Mater. Chem. Phys. <b>132</b>(2&#x2013;3), 395&#x2013;401 (2012). 10.1016/j.matchemphys.2011.11.043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2011.11.043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Guo, C. Liu, H. Hu, S. Zhang, X. Ji et al., Neglected acidity pitfall: boric acid-anchoring hole-selective contact for perovskite solar cells. Natl. Sci. Rev. <b>10</b>(5), nwad057 (2023). 10.1093/nsr/nwad057
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nsr/nwad057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10237332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37274941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wang, L. Zhan, S. Zhang, H. Zhang, X. Ji et al., Enhancing interfacial contact of hole-collecting monolayer <i>via</i> coassembly with multiped triphenylamine for mechanically stable inverted perovskite solar cells. CCS Chem. (2025). 10.31635/ccschem.025.202506236</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31635/ccschem.025.202506236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Li, Y. Chen, Y. Li, Z. Zhang, J. Yang et al., Achieving 32% efficiency in perovskite/silicon tandem solar cells with bidentate-anchored superwetting self-assembled molecular layers. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>64</b>(23), e202502730 (2025). 10.1002/anie.202502730</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202502730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40171765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Gao, B. Li, X. Sun, Q. Liu, C. Zhang et al., High-efficiency perovskite solar cells enabled by suppressing intermolecular aggregation in hole-selective contacts. Nat. Photonics <b>19</b>(10), 1070&#x2013;1077 (2025). 10.1038/s41566-025-01725-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41566-025-01725-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhao, Y. Liu, Z. Ren, Y. Li, Y. Zhang et al., Enhanced interface adhesion with a polymeric hole transporter enabling high-performance air-processed perovskite solar cells. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>18</b>(3), 1366&#x2013;1374 (2025). 10.1039/d4ee04481a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ee04481a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhao, F. Wang, X. Hu, Y. Zhang, T. Liu et al., Ambient blade-coated perovskite solar cells with high reverse bias stability enabled by polymeric hole transporter design. Nat. Commun. <b>16</b>(1), 10355 (2025). 10.1038/s41467-025-65341-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-65341-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12644531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41285911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Liu, X. Liao, J. Wu, P. Ding, Z. Shao et al., Dimeric self-assembled molecules modulate phase homogeneity and anchoring stability for high-performance perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. e20189, (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202520189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202520189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Wang, T. Liu, Y. Liu, Y. Zhou, X. Dong et al., A polymeric hole transporter with dual-interfacial interactions enables 25%-efficiency blade-coated perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>36</b>(52), e2412059 (2024). 10.1002/adma.202412059
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202412059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39543432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M.A. Truong, T. Funasaki, L. Ueberricke, W. Nojo, R. Murdey et al., Tripodal triazatruxene derivative as a face-on oriented hole-collecting monolayer for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>145</b>(13), 7528&#x2013;7539 (2023). 10.1021/jacs.3c00805
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.3c00805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Sun, C. Tian, R. Zhuang, C. Chen, Y. Zheng et al., High open-circuit voltage (1.197 V) in large-area (1 cm<sup>2</sup>) inverted perovskite solar cell <i>via</i> interface planarization and highly polar self-assembled monolayer. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>14</b>(8), 2303941 (2024). 10.1002/aenm.202303941</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202303941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.N. Afraj, C.-H. Kuan, J.-S. Lin, J.-S. Ni, A. Velusamy et al., Quinoxaline-based X-shaped sensitizers as self-assembled monolayer for tin perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>33</b>(17), 2213939 (2023). 10.1002/adfm.202213939</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202213939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Zhang, M. Li, C. Dong, W. Ye, Y. Zhu et al., Role of NiO in wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells based on self-assembled monolayers. Chem. Eng. J. <b>494</b>, 153253 (2024). 10.1016/j.cej.2024.153253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.153253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Tang, Z. Shen, Y. Shen, G. Yan, Y. Wang et al., Reinforcing self-assembly of hole transport molecules for stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Science <b>383</b>(6688), 1236&#x2013;1240 (2024). 10.1126/science.adj9602
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.adj9602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38484063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y.-H. Lin, F. Vikram, X.-L. Yang, A.D. Cao et al., Bandgap-universal passivation enables stable perovskite solar cells with low photovoltage loss. Science <b>384</b>(6697), 767&#x2013;775 (2024). 10.1126/science.ado2302
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.ado2302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38753792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Meng, K. Mao, F. Cai, K. Zhang, S. Yuan et al., Inhibition of halide oxidation and deprotonation of organic cations with dimethylammonium formate for air-processed p&#x2013;i&#x2013;n perovskite solar cells. Nat. Energy <b>9</b>(5), 536&#x2013;547 (2024). 10.1038/s41560-024-01471-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-024-01471-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Luo, Q. Zhou, K. Wang, X. Wang, J. He et al., Engineering bonding sites enables uniform and robust self-assembled monolayer for stable perovskite solar cells. Nat. Mater. <b>24</b>(8), 1265&#x2013;1272 (2025). 10.1038/s41563-025-02275-x
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41563-025-02275-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40555860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Fu, N. Sun, H. Chen, Y. Li, Y. Li et al., Homogenizing SAM deposition <i>via</i> seeding&#x2013;OH groups for scalable fabrication of perovskite solar cells. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>18</b>(7), 3305&#x2013;3312 (2025). 10.1039/d5ee00350d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ee00350d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Yu, Z. Xiong, H. Zhou, Q. Zhang, Z. Wang et al., Homogenized NiO<sub>x</sub> nanoparticles for improved hole transport in inverted perovskite solar cells. Science <b>382</b>(6677), 1399&#x2013;1404 (2023). 10.1126/science.adj8858
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.adj8858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37995210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. He, G. Li, G. Huang, Z. Luo, B. Zhang et al., Improved anchoring of self-assembled monolayer on hydroxylated NiO<sub>x</sub> film surface for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(3), 2413104 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202413104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202413104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Levine, A. Al-Ashouri, A. Musiienko, H. Hempel, A. Magomedov et al., Charge transfer rates and electron trapping at buried interfaces of perovskite solar cells. Joule <b>5</b>(11), 2915&#x2013;2933 (2021). 10.1016/j.joule.2021.07.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2021.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Ben Amara, E.R. Dionne, S. Kassir, C. Pellerin, A. Badia, Molecular origin of the odd-even effect of macroscopic properties of n-alkanethiolate self-assembled monolayers: bulk or interface? J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>142</b>(30), 13051&#x2013;13061 (2020). 10.1021/jacs.0c04288
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.0c04288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32597648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H.B. Akkerman, S.C.B. Mannsfeld, A.P. Kaushik, E. Verploegen, L. Burnier et al., Effects of odd-even side chain length of alkyl-substituted diphenylbithiophenes on first monolayer thin film packing structure. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>135</b>(30), 11006&#x2013;11014 (2013). 10.1021/ja400015e
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja400015e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23822850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Ali, C. Rold&#xe1;n-Carmona, M. Sohail, M.K. Nazeeruddin, Applications of self-assembled monolayers for perovskite solar cells interface engineering to address efficiency and stability. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>10</b>(48), 2002989 (2020). 10.1002/aenm.202002989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202002989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhang, R. Wu, C. Mu, Y. Wang, L. Han et al., Conjugated self-assembled monolayer as stable hole-selective contact for inverted perovskite solar cells. ACS Mater. Lett. <b>4</b>(10), 1976&#x2013;1983 (2022). 10.1021/acsmaterialslett.2c00799</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsmaterialslett.2c00799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Liao, Y. Wang, Z. Zhang, K. Yang, Y. Shi et al., Self-assembled donor-acceptor hole contacts for inverted perovskite solar cells with an efficiency approaching 22%: the impact of anchoring groups. J. Energy Chem. <b>68</b>, 87&#x2013;95 (2022). 10.1016/j.jechem.2021.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jechem.2021.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Qu, S. Cai, Y. Qiao, D. Wang, S. Gong et al., Conjugated linker-boosted self-assembled monolayer molecule for inverted perovskite solar cells. Joule <b>8</b>(7), 2123&#x2013;2134 (2024). 10.1016/j.joule.2024.05.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2024.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhu, Y. Luo, R. He, C. Chen, Y. Wang et al., A donor&#x2013;acceptor-type hole-selective contact reducing non-radiative recombination losses in both subcells towards efficient all-perovskite tandems. Nat. Energy <b>8</b>(7), 714&#x2013;724 (2023). 10.1038/s41560-023-01274-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-023-01274-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhu, X. Huang, Y. Luo, W. Jiao, Y. Xu et al., Self-assembled hole-selective contact for efficient Sn-Pb perovskite solar cells and all-perovskite tandems. Nat. Commun. <b>16</b>(1), 240 (2025). 10.1038/s41467-024-55492-4
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-55492-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11696209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39747127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Han, Y. Zhang, Recent advances in carbazole-based self-assembled monolayer for solution-processed optoelectronic devices. Adv. Mater. <b>36</b>(33), e2405630 (2024). 10.1002/adma.202405630
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202405630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38940073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Qu, L. Zhang, Y. Qiao, S. Gong, Y. Ding et al., Self-assembled materials with an ordered hydrophilic bilayer for high performance inverted Perovskite solar cells. Nat. Commun. <b>16</b>(1), 86 (2025). 10.1038/s41467-024-55523-0
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-55523-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11696008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39747047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Dai, S. You, D. Chakraborty, S. Li, Y. Zhang et al., Connecting interfacial mechanical adhesion, efficiency, and operational stability in high performance inverted perovskite solar cells. ACS Energy Lett. <b>9</b>(4), 1880&#x2013;1887 (2024). 10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Peng, Y. Zhang, X. Zhou, J. Wu, D. Wang et al., A versatile energy-level-tunable hole-transport layer for multi-composition inverted perovskite solar cells. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>18</b>(2), 874&#x2013;883 (2025). 10.1039/d4ee03208j</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ee03208j</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Wr&#xf3;bel, T. &#x17b;aba, E. Sauter, M. Krawiec, J. Sobczuk et al., Thermally stable and highly conductive SAMs on Ag substrate: the impact of the anchoring group. Adv. Electron. Mater. <b>7</b>(2), 2000947 (2021). 10.1002/aelm.202000947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aelm.202000947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Aktas, R. Pudi, N. Phung, R. Wenisch, L. Gregori et al., Role of terminal group position in triphenylamine-based self-assembled hole-selective molecules in perovskite solar cells. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces <b>14</b>(15), 17461&#x2013;17469 (2022). 10.1021/acsami.2c01981
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c01981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Petrovi&#x107;, T. Maksudov, A. Panagiotopoulos, E. Serpetzoglou, I. Konidakis et al., Limitations of a polymer-based hole transporting layer for application in planar inverted perovskite solar cells. Nanoscale Adv. <b>1</b>(8), 3107&#x2013;3118 (2019). 10.1039/C9NA00246D
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9NA00246D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9417823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36133594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J.H. Park, O.J. Kwon, T.-H. Kim, J. Mun, Y.D. Park, Ultraviolet irradiation creates morphological order <i>via</i> conformational changes in polythiophene films. Org. Electron. <b>62</b>, 394&#x2013;399 (2018). 10.1016/j.orgel.2018.08.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orgel.2018.08.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Fei, A. Kuvayskaya, X. Shi, M. Wang, Z. Shi et al., Strong-bonding hole-transport layers reduce ultraviolet degradation of perovskite solar cells. Science <b>384</b>(6700), 1126&#x2013;1134 (2024). 10.1126/science.adi4531
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.adi4531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38843338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Mei, F. Yan, Recent advances in wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>37</b>(48), 2418622 (2025). 10.1002/adma.202418622
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202418622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12676096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40166849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Zhang, X. Wang, Y. Wu, X. Li, T. Hou et al., Self-assembled &#x3c0;-conjugated hole-selective molecules for UV-resistant high-efficiency perovskite solar cells. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>64</b>(34), e202508782 (2025). 10.1002/anie.202508782</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202508782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40541559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D.K. Schwartz, Mechanisms and kinetics of self-assembled monolayer formation. Annu. Rev. Phys. Chem. <b>52</b>, 107&#x2013;137 (2001). 10.1146/annurev.physchem.52.1.107
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.physchem.52.1.107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11326061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A.F. Raigoza, G. Kolettis, D.A. Villalba, S.A. Kandel, Restructuring of octanethiolate and dialkyldithiocarbamate monolayers in the formation of sequentially adsorbed mixed monolayers. J. Phys. Chem. C <b>115</b>(41), 20274&#x2013;20281 (2011). 10.1021/jp206983y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp206983y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Shi, S. Li, C. Min, J. Xie, R. Ma, Modification of energy levels by cetyltrimethylammonium bromide at the perovskite/carbon interface for highly efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. Org. Electron. <b>112</b>, 106689 (2023). 10.1016/j.orgel.2022.106689</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orgel.2022.106689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Xu, H. Lv, H. Jin, Y. Liu, Y. Ma et al., Crystalline facet-directed generation engineering of ultrathin platinum nanodendrites. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. <b>10</b>(3), 663&#x2013;671 (2019). 10.1021/acs.jpclett.8b03861
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.8b03861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30682888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Nagarajan, Molecular packing parameter and surfactant self-assembly: the neglected role of the surfactant tail. Langmuir <b>18</b>(1), 31&#x2013;38 (2002). 10.1021/la010831y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la010831y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Kulkarni, R. Sarkar, S. Akel, M. H&#xe4;ser, B. Klingebiel et al., A universal strategy of perovskite ink - substrate interaction to overcome the poor wettability of a self-assembled monolayer for reproducible perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>33</b>(47), 2305812 (2023). 10.1002/adfm.202305812</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202305812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Li, Q. Lian, T. Du, R. Ma, H. Liu et al., Co-adsorbed self-assembled monolayer enables high-performance perovskite and organic solar cells. Nat. Commun. <b>15</b>(1), 7605 (2024). 10.1038/s41467-024-51760-5
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-51760-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11366757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39218952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Liu, J. Li, W. Xiao, R. Chen, Z. Sun et al., Buried interface molecular hybrid for inverted perovskite solar cells. Nature <b>632</b>(8025), 536&#x2013;542 (2024). 10.1038/s41586-024-07723-3
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-024-07723-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38925147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Ma, S. Yang, C. Shao, Z. Nie, W. Zhang et al., Homogenizing self-assembled monolayers <i>via</i> covalent organic frameworks for inverted perovskite solar cells. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>65</b>, e19875 (2025). 10.1002/anie.202519875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202519875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41195867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Tan, H. Wang, S. Tang, Q. Cai, G. Ma et al., Asymmetric dimethyl-indenocarbazole phosphonic acid molecules with expanded &#x3c0;-conjugation for inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(41), 2501147 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202501147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202501147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, J. Li, R. Guo, X. Yin, R. Luo et al., Regulating phase homogeneity by self-assembled molecules for enhanced efficiency and stability of inverted perovskite solar cells. Nat. Photonics <b>18</b>(12), 1269&#x2013;1275 (2024). 10.1038/s41566-024-01531-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41566-024-01531-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wu, J. Wu, Z. Zhang, X. Guan, L. Wang et al., Tailored lattice-matched carbazole self-assembled molecule for efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>147</b>(9), 8004&#x2013;8011 (2025). 10.1021/jacs.5c00629
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5c00629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39966170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Zhao, B. Gothe, A. Groh, T. Schmaltz, J. Will et al., Oligothiophene phosphonic acids for self-assembled monolayer field-effect transistors. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces <b>13</b>(27), 32461&#x2013;32466 (2021). 10.1021/acsami.1c05764
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.1c05764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34213306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X.-M. Li, Y.-H. Wang, J.-W. Seng, J.-F. Zheng, R. Cao et al., Z-piezo pulse-modulated STM break junction: toward single-molecule rectifiers with dissimilar metal electrodes. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces <b>13</b>(7), 8656&#x2013;8663 (2021). 10.1021/acsami.0c21435
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.0c21435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33587592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.Y. Lee, Y. Choi, E. Ito, M. Hara, H. Lee et al., Growth, solvent effects, and thermal desorption behavior of octylthiocyanate self-assembled monolayers on Au(111). Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. <b>15</b>(10), 3609&#x2013;3617 (2013). 10.1039/c3cp44425b
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c3cp44425b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23381624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Mariotti, I.N. Rabehi, C. Zhang, X. Huo, J. Zhang et al., Unraveling the morphological and energetic properties of 2PACz self-assembled monolayers fabricated with upscaling deposition methods. Energy Environ. Mater. <b>8</b>(2), e12825 (2025). 10.1002/eem2.12825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eem2.12825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D.O. Hutchins, O. Acton, T. Weidner, N. Cernetic, J.E. Baio et al., Spin cast self-assembled monolayer field effect transistors. Org. Electron. <b>13</b>(3), 464&#x2013;468 (2012). 10.1016/j.orgel.2011.11.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orgel.2011.11.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Huang, T. Wang, W. Chen, Z. Wang, Z. Lin et al., Bottom-up regulation of perovskite growth and energetics <i>via</i> oligoether functionalized self-assembling molecules for high-performance solar cells. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>64</b>(36), e202507513 (2025). 10.1002/anie.202507513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202507513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40598821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L.V. Torres Merino, C.E. Petoukhoff, O. Matiash, A.S. Subbiah, C.V. Franco et al., Impact of the valence band energy alignment at the hole-collecting interface on the photostability of wide band-gap perovskite solar cells. Joule <b>8</b>(9), 2585&#x2013;2606 (2024). 10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Novak, A. Ebel, T. Meyer-Friedrichsen, A. Jedaa, B.F. Vieweg et al., Low-voltage p- and n-type organic self-assembled monolayer field effect transistors. Nano Lett. <b>11</b>(1), 156&#x2013;159 (2011). 10.1021/nl103200r
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nl103200r</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21133354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wang, X. Li, L. Gao, G. Liu, L. Yang et al., Thermal cross-linking hole-transport self-assembled monolayers for perovskite solar cells. ACS Energy Lett. <b>10</b>(5), 2250&#x2013;2258 (2025). 10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.5c00457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Wang, Z. Liu, J. Zou, S. Peng, D. Wang et al., <i>In situ</i> crosslinked self-assembled monolayer as processing stable hole selective contact in perovskite solar cells. Angew. Chem. <b>137</b>(52), e17058 (2025). 10.1002/ange.202517058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ange.202517058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41159682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Guo, H. Tang, L. Han, R. Qi, H. Yan et al., Self-assembled monolayer: revolutionizing p-i-n perovskite solar cells. ACS Energy Lett. <b>10</b>(10), 4882&#x2013;4910 (2025). 10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.5c02024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Zaera, Probing liquid/solid interfaces at the molecular level. Chem. Rev. <b>112</b>(5), 2920&#x2013;2986 (2012). 10.1021/cr2002068
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/cr2002068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22277079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, B. Yan, L. Chen, SERS tags: novel optical nanoprobes for bioanalysis. Chem. Rev. <b>113</b>(3), 1391&#x2013;1428 (2013). 10.1021/cr300120g
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/cr300120g</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23273312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Poonia, T. K&#xfc;ster, G.D. Bothun, Organic anion detection with functionalized SERS substrates <i>via</i> coupled electrokinetic preconcentration, analyte capture, and charge transfer. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces <b>14</b>(20), 23964&#x2013;23972 (2022). 10.1021/acsami.2c02934
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c02934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z.-F. Cai, T. K&#xe4;ser, N. Kumar, R. Zenobi, Visualizing on-surface decomposition chemistry at the nanoscale using tip-enhanced Raman spectroscopy. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. <b>13</b>(22), 4864&#x2013;4870 (2022). 10.1021/acs.jpclett.2c01112
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.2c01112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35617121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. de Boer, A. Hadipour, M.M. Mandoc, T. van Woudenbergh, P.W.M. Blom, Tuning of metal work functions with self-assembled monolayers. Adv. Mater. <b>17</b>(5), 621&#x2013;625 (2005). 10.1002/adma.200401216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.200401216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V.J.Y. Lim, A.J. Knight, R.D.J. Oliver, H.J. Snaith, M.B. Johnston et al., Impact of hole-transport layer and interface passivation on halide segregation in mixed-halide perovskites. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>32</b>(41), 2204825 (2022). 10.1002/adfm.202204825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202204825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A.J. Knight, L.M. Herz, Preventing phase segregation in mixed-halide perovskites: a perspective. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>13</b>(7), 2024&#x2013;2046 (2020). 10.1039/d0ee00788a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d0ee00788a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C.-H. Chen, G.-W. Liu, X. Chen, C. Deger, R.-J. Jin et al., Methylthio substituent in SAM constructing regulatory bridge with photovoltaic perovskites. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>64</b>(7), e202419375 (2025). 10.1002/anie.202419375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202419375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39618342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Liu, C. Luo, R. He, Z. Zhang, X. Lin et al., Advancing self-assembled molecules toward interface-optimized perovskite solar cells: from one to two. Adv. Mater. <b>37</b>(48), 2502032 (2025). 10.1002/adma.202502032
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202502032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12676094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40297925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wei, Q. Zhou, X. Niu, S. Liu, Z. Dong et al., Surpassing 90% Shockley&#x2013;Queisser VOC limit in 1.79 eV wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells using bromine-substituted self-assembled monolayers. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>18</b>(4), 1847&#x2013;1855 (2025). 10.1039/d4ee04029e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ee04029e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Huang, M. Tao, Y. Zhang, Z. Wang, Z. Sun et al., Asymmetric modification of carbazole based self-assembled monolayers by hybrid strategy for inverted perovskite solar cells. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>64</b>(4), e202416188 (2025). 10.1002/anie.202416188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202416188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39367792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zhang, L. Qiao, K. Meng, R. Long, G. Chen et al., Rationalization of passivation strategies toward high-performance perovskite solar cells. Chem. Soc. Rev. <b>52</b>(1), 163&#x2013;195 (2023). 10.1039/d2cs00217e
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d2cs00217e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhang, L. Pfeifer, S.M. Zakeeruddin, J. Chu, M. Gr&#xe4;tzel, Tailoring passivators for highly efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. Nat. Rev. Chem. <b>7</b>(9), 632&#x2013;652 (2023). 10.1038/s41570-023-00510-0
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41570-023-00510-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37464018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Ahn, K. Kwak, M.S. Jang, H. Yoon, B.Y. Lee et al., Trapped charge-driven degradation of perovskite solar cells. Nat. Commun. <b>7</b>, 13422 (2016). 10.1038/ncomms13422
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms13422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5110646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27830709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Azmi, D.S. Utomo, B. Vishal, S. Zhumagali, P. Dally et al., Double-side 2D/3D heterojunctions for inverted perovskite solar cells. Nature <b>628</b>(8006), 93&#x2013;98 (2024). 10.1038/s41586-024-07189-3
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-024-07189-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38382650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhou, F. Wang, X. Ai, Y. Liu, Y. Han et al., Dual interfacial modification with 1D perovskite for self-assembled monolayer based inverted perovskite solar cells. Nano Energy <b>128</b>, 109811 (2024). 10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhang, J. Yang, R. Dai, W. Sheng, Y. Su et al., Elimination of interfacial lattice mismatch and detrimental reaction by self-assembled layer dual-passivation for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>12</b>(18), 2103674 (2022). 10.1002/aenm.202103674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202103674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, Y. Feng, H. Yang, S. Li, K. Zhang et al., Covalent tridentate molecule anchoring enhances nickel oxide for efficient perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>37</b>(42), e07730 (2025). 10.1002/adma.202507730
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202507730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40767061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Guo, Y. Wan, M. Yang, J. Snaider, K. Zhu et al., Long-range hot-carrier transport in hybrid perovskites visualized by ultrafast microscopy. Science <b>356</b>(6333), 59&#x2013;62 (2017). 10.1126/science.aam7744
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aam7744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28386007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ugur, J.I. Khan, E. Aydin, M. Wang, M. Kirkus et al., Carrier extraction from perovskite to polymeric charge transport layers probed by ultrafast transient absorption spectroscopy. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. <b>10</b>(21), 6921&#x2013;6928 (2019). 10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b02502
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b02502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31634427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Dong, M. Wei, Y. Li, Y. Yang, W. Ma et al., Self-assembled bilayer for perovskite solar cells with improved tolerance against thermal stresses. Nat. Energy <b>10</b>(3), 342&#x2013;353 (2025). 10.1038/s41560-024-01689-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-024-01689-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Guo, X. Zhang, X. Zheng, L. Li, M. Li et al., Tailoring multifunctional self-assembled hole transporting molecules for highly efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>33</b>(10), 2211955 (2023). 10.1002/adfm.202211955</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202211955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Guo, H. Tan, B. Xu, Deciphering halide ion migration and performance loss in wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells: connection, mechanism, and solutions. Energy Environ. Sci. <b>18</b>(19), 8744&#x2013;8755 (2025). 10.1039/d5ee03136b</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ee03136b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Yantara, N. Mathews, Toolsets for assessing ionic migration in halide perovskites. Joule <b>8</b>(5), 1239&#x2013;1273 (2024). 10.1016/j.joule.2024.02.022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2024.02.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C.A. Aranda, A.O. Alvarez, V.S. Chivrony, C. Das, M. Rai et al., Overcoming ionic migration in perovskite solar cells through alkali metals. Joule <b>8</b>(1), 241&#x2013;254 (2024). 10.1016/j.joule.2023.11.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2023.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Singh, E. Siliavka, M. L&#xf6;ffler, Y. Vaynzof, Impact of buried interface texture on compositional stratification and ion migration in perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>34</b>(42), 2402655 (2024). 10.1002/adfm.202402655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202402655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Qu, H. Huang, J. Wang, P. Cui, Y. Li et al., Revealing and inhibiting the facet-related ion migration for efficient and stable perovskite solar cells. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>64</b>(4), e202415949 (2025). 10.1002/anie.202415949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202415949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39289891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. He, D. Ma, J. Zhang, Y. Yang, J. Ding et al., Universal ion migration suppression strategy based on supramolecular host&#x2013;guest interaction for high-performance perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>37</b>(33), 2505115 (2025). 10.1002/adma.202505115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202505115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40474427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Li, M. Wei, V. Carnevali, H. Zeng, M. Zeng et al., Buried-interface engineering enables efficient and 1960-hour ISOS-L-2I stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>36</b>(13), e2303869 (2024). 10.1002/adma.202303869
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202303869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37632843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yao, C. Cheng, C. Zhang, H. Hu, K. Wang et al., Organic hole-transport layers for efficient, stable, and scalable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>34</b>(44), 2203794 (2022). 10.1002/adma.202203794</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202203794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35771986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. He, J. Dai, J. Xiong, Q. Hu, Q. Yang et al., Overcoming the wetting issues of PTAA in inverted perovskite solar cells by cinnamyl alcohol modification. Mater. Today Commun. <b>47</b>, 113085 (2025). 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2025.113085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ullah, K.H. Park, Y. Lee, S. Park, A. Bin Faheem et al., Versatile hole selective molecules containing a series of heteroatoms as self-assembled monolayers for efficient p-i-n perovskite and organic solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>32</b>(49), 2208793 (2022). 10.1002/adfm.202208793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202208793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G.D. Kong, J. Jin, M. Thuo, H. Song, J.F. Joung et al., Elucidating the role of molecule-electrode interfacial defects in charge tunneling characteristics of large-area junctions. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>140</b>(38), 12303&#x2013;12307 (2018). 10.1021/jacs.8b08146
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.8b08146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30183277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H.J. Yoon, K.-C. Liao, M.R. Lockett, S.W. Kwok, M. Baghbanzadeh et al., Rectification in tunneling junctions: 2, 2&#x2032;-bipyridyl-terminated <i>n</i>-alkanethiolates. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>136</b>(49), 17155&#x2013;17162 (2014). 10.1021/ja509110a
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja509110a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25389953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Yuan, C. Ge, T. Zhang, G. Su, Q. Qiu et al., Conjugated bisphosphonic acid self-assembled monolayers for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>147</b>(28), 24662&#x2013;24671 (2025). 10.1021/jacs.5c05801
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5c05801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12272685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40588421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Cao, T. Wang, X. Pu, X. He, M. Xiao et al., Co-self-assembled monolayers modified NiO<sub>x</sub> for stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>36</b>(16), 2311970 (2024). 10.1002/adma.202311970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202311970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38198824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Warby, F. Zu, S. Zeiske, E. Gutierrez-Partida, L. Frohloff et al., Understanding performance limiting interfacial recombination in pin perovskite solar cells. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>12</b>(12), 2103567 (2022). 10.1002/aenm.202103567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202103567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Zhang, H. Zhang, H. Guo, F. Ye, S. Liu et al., Stable &#x3b1;-FAPbI<sub>3</sub> in inverted perovskite solar cells with efficiency exceeding 22% <i>via</i> a self-passivation strategy. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>32</b>(27), 2200174 (2022). 10.1002/adfm.202200174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202200174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Cacovich, G. Vidon, M. Degani, M. Legrand, L. Gouda et al., Imaging and quantifying non-radiative losses at 23% efficient inverted perovskite solar cells interfaces. Nat. Commun. <b>13</b>(1), 2868 (2022). 10.1038/s41467-022-30426-0
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-30426-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35606374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Chen, X. Lv, L. Duan, B. Farhadi, C. Yu et al., Reinforced anchor for scalable self-assembled monolayer to attain high-performance perovskite solar modules. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>15</b>(35), 2502000 (2025). 10.1002/aenm.202502000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202502000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Wang, Z. Liu, Y. Qiao, Z. Jiang, P. Zhu et al., Rigid molecules anchoring on NiO<sub>x</sub>&#xa0;enable &gt;26% efficiency perovskite solar cells. Joule <b>9</b>(3), 101815 (2025). 10.1016/j.joule.2024.101815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2024.101815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Chen, Q. Cao, X. Pu, Q. Zhao, X. He et al., Strong coupling of NiO<sub>x</sub> and self-assembled molecules <i>via</i> inserted reductant for high-performance inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Mater. <b>37</b>(43), e10553 (2025). 10.1002/adma.202510553
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202510553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40787970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C.A.F. Morales, Z. Pizzo, D.M. Sweeney, Z. Hu, G.P. Sharma et al., Multilayer formation, interfacial binding, and stability of self-assembled molecules in perovskite solar cells. J. Am. Chem. Soc. <b>147</b>(52), 48136&#x2013;48146 (2025). 10.1021/jacs.5c15955
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5c15955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41401250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Gao, D. Khan, I. Muhammad, Y. Zhang, C. Zhang et al., Self-assembled bi-monolayer for inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202519073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202519073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Sun, R. Xu, J. Dai, H. Tang, J. Wang et al., <i>In situ</i> coordinated HTL strategy for high-performance and scalable perovskite solar cells. Nat. Commun. <b>16</b>(1), 9110 (2025). 10.1038/s41467-025-64111-9
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-64111-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12521384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41087340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Liu, Z. Tan, J. Wang, S. Liu, T. Imran et al., Defect engineering and crystallization kinetics control <i>via</i> dual-functional mercaptoacetamide for high-performance, large-area perovskite solar modules. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>15</b>(40), e02193 (2025). 10.1002/aenm.202502193</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202502193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wang, X. Liu, J. Wang, C. Chen, J. Yu et al., Versatile self-assembled molecule enables high-efficiency wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells and organic solar cells. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>13</b>(23), 2300694 (2023). 10.1002/aenm.202300694</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202300694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhou, W. Wang, Y. Duan, R. Sun, Y. Li et al., Glycol monomethyl ether-substituted carbazolyl hole-transporting material for stable inverted perovskite solar cells with efficiency of 25.52%. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>63</b>(33), e202403068 (2024). 10.1002/anie.202403068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202403068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38687308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Chen, E. Luais, N. Darwish, S. Ciampi, P. Thordarson et al., Studies on the effect of solvents on self-assembled monolayers formed from organophosphonic acids on indium tin oxide. Langmuir <b>28</b>(25), 9487&#x2013;9495 (2012). 10.1021/la3010129
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la3010129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22621243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Dietrich, D. Zahn, Molecular mechanisms of solvent-controlled assembly of phosphonate monolayers on oxide surfaces. J. Phys. Chem. C <b>121</b>(33), 18012&#x2013;18020 (2017). 10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b05750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b05750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Deng, F. Qi, F. Li, S. Wu, F.R. Lin et al., Co-assembled monolayers as hole-selective contact for high-performance inverted perovskite solar cells with optimized recombination loss and long-term stability. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. <b>61</b>(30), e202203088 (2022). 10.1002/anie.202203088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202203088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35560775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Song, S. Ramakrishnan, Y. Zhang, Q. Yu, Mixed self-assembled monolayers for high-photovoltage tin perovskite solar cells. ACS Energy Lett. <b>9</b>(4), 1466&#x2013;1472 (2024). 10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, X. Wang, T. Wang, J. Li, H.Y. Chia et al., Determining the bonding&#x2013;degradation trade-off at heterointerfaces for increased efficiency and stability of perovskite solar cells. Nat. Energy <b>10</b>(2), 181&#x2013;190 (2025). 10.1038/s41560-024-01680-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-024-01680-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Chen, K. Sun, L.R. Franco, J. Wu, L. &#xd6;hrstr&#xf6;m et al., Effects of alkyl spacer length in carbazole-based self-assembled monolayer materials on molecular conformation and organic solar cell performance. Adv. Sci. <b>12</b>(4), 2410277 (2025). 10.1002/advs.202410277</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202410277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11775572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39629953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E.J. Cassella, E.L.K. Spooner, T. Thornber, M.E. O&#x2019;Kane, T.E. Catley et al., Gas-assisted spray coating of perovskite solar cells incorporating sprayed self-assembled monolayers. Adv. Sci. <b>9</b>(14), 2104848 (2022). 10.1002/advs.202104848</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202104848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Sch&#xf6;tz, C. Greve, A. Langen, H. Gorter, I. Dogan et al., Understanding differences in the crystallization kinetics between one-step slot-die coating and spin coating of MAPbI<sub>3</sub> using multimodal <i>in situ</i> optical spectroscopy. Adv. Opt. Mater. <b>9</b>(21), 2101161 (2021). 10.1002/adom.202101161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adom.202101161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Parvazian, A. Abdollah-zadeh, M. Dehghani, N. Taghavinia, Photovoltaic performance improvement in vacuum-assisted <i>Meniscus</i> printed triple-cation mixed-halide perovskite films by surfactant engineering. ACS Appl. Energy Mater. <b>2</b>(9), 6209&#x2013;6217 (2019). 10.1021/acsaem.9b00707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsaem.9b00707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Parvazian, R. Garcia-Rodriguez, D. Beynon, M. Davies, T. Watson, Slot-die coating of self-assembled monolayers: a scalable approach for perovskite solar cells. Mater. Today Energy <b>52</b>, 101955 (2025). 10.1016/j.mtener.2025.101955</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtener.2025.101955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Jang, G.D. Kong, H.J. Yoon, Electrically stable self-assembled monolayers achieved through repeated surface exchange of molecules. Acc. Mater. Res. <b>5</b>(10), 1251&#x2013;1262 (2024). 10.1021/accountsmr.4c00190</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/accountsmr.4c00190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhao, X. Luan, L. Han, Y. Wang, Post-assembled alkylphosphonic acids for efficient and stable inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>34</b>(46), 2405646 (2024). 10.1002/adfm.202405646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202405646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zheng, Z. Li, Y. Zhang, M. Chen, T. Liu et al., Co-deposition of hole-selective contact and absorber for improving the processability of perovskite solar cells. Nat. Energy <b>8</b>(5), 462&#x2013;472 (2023). 10.1038/s41560-023-01227-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-023-01227-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.M. Park, M. Wei, N. Lempesis, W. Yu, T. Hossain et al., Low-loss contacts on textured substrates for inverted perovskite solar cells. Nature <b>624</b>(7991), 289&#x2013;294 (2023). 10.1038/s41586-023-06745-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-023-06745-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37871614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Al-Ashouri, M. Mar&#x10d;inskas, E. Kasparavi&#x10d;ius, T. Malinauskas, A. Palmstrom et al., Wettability improvement of a carbazole-based hole-selective monolayer for reproducible perovskite solar cells. ACS Energy Lett. <b>8</b>(2), 898&#x2013;900 (2023). 10.1021/acsenergylett.2c02629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.2c02629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Liu, J. Dong, P. Wang, B. Shi, Y. Zhao et al., Suppressing the photoinduced halide segregation in wide-bandgap perovskite solar cells by strain relaxation. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>33</b>(41), 2303673 (2023). 10.1002/adfm.202303673</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202303673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, S. Akel, B. Klingebiel, T. Kirchartz, Hole transporting bilayers for efficient micrometer-thick perovskite solar cells. Adv. Energy Mater. <b>14</b>(5), 2302614 (2024). 10.1002/aenm.202302614</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202302614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Jiang, R. Tirawat, R.A. Kerner, E.A. Gaulding, Y. Xian et al., Towards linking lab and field lifetimes of perovskite solar cells. Nature <b>623</b>(7986), 313&#x2013;318 (2023). 10.1038/s41586-023-06610-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41586-023-06610-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37696288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, Y. Liu, Z. Zhao, T. Kong, W. Chen et al., Improving buried interface contact for inverted perovskite solar cells <i>via</i> dual modification strategy. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(12), 2417575 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202417575</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202417575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Cai, Q. Tan, J. He, S. Tang, Q. Sun et al., Enhancing electron transport for efficiency-recorded HTL-free inverted perovskite solar cells by molecular complementary passivation. Joule <b>9</b>(5), 101880 (2025). 10.1016/j.joule.2025.101880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2025.101880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wang, J. Yan, M. Dijkstra, E. Torun, M. Rana et al., Understanding the principles of co-deposition of mixed-SAMs in MAPbI<sub>3</sub>-based p-i-n structure perovskite solar cells. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces <b>17</b>(49), 67306&#x2013;67317 (2025). 10.1021/acsami.5c18266
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.5c18266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41325080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wang, H. Guo, Y. Wu, Advantages and challenges of self-assembled monolayer as a hole-selective contact for perovskite solar cells. Mater. Futures <b>2</b>(1), 012105 (2023). 10.1088/2752-5724/acbb5a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2752-5724/acbb5a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Xu, X. Ji, R. Chen, F. Ye, S. Liu et al., Improving contact and passivation of buried interface for high-efficiency and large-area inverted perovskite solar cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>32</b>(9), 2109968 (2022). 10.1002/adfm.202109968</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202109968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, S. Yang, S. Yan, X. Liu, G. Shi et al., Open-circuit voltage loss management for efficient inverted wide-bandgap perovskite photovoltaics. Adv. Funct. Mater. <b>35</b>(7), 2415331 (2025). 10.1002/adfm.202415331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202415331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhang, S. Mariotti, L.K. Ono, C. Ding, K. Mitrofanov et al., A hole injection monolayer enables cost-effective perovskite light-emitting diodes. J. Mater. Chem. C <b>11</b>(8), 2851&#x2013;2862 (2023). 10.1039/d2tc05491d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d2tc05491d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Li, K. Xie, G. Wang, J. Zheng, Y. Cao et al., An AIE-active ultrathin polymeric self-assembled monolayer sensor for trace volatile explosive detection. Macromol. Rapid Commun. <b>42</b>(23), 2170074 (2021). 10.1002/marc.202170074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/marc.202170074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34610177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>