<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41918661</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Evaluation of PRISM III, PIM 2, and PELOD Scores as Predictors of Outcome in Pediatric Intensive Care Unit Patients: An Experience From a Single Center in South Gujarat, India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104420</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104420</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104420</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104420</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">&#xa0;To assess and compare Pediatric Risk of Mortality III (PRISM III), Pediatric Index of Mortality 2 (PIM 2), and Pediatric Logistic Organ Dysfunction (PELOD) scores for predicting mortality in a pediatric intensive care unit (PICU) setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN AND SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional, hospital-based, analytical observational study conducted in an eight-bed PICU.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">PICU patients between the ages of 1 month and 17 years fulfilling the inclusion criteria were included in this study. PIM 2 score was calculated within the first hour of admission; PRISM III and PELOD scores were calculated at 24 hours. Outcomes of survival or non-survival were recorded.&#xa0;Scoring system performance was assessed using indices of discrimination and calibration. Predictive accuracy for mortality was evaluated with receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis, and calibration between predicted and observed mortality was examined using the Hosmer-Lemeshow goodness-of-fit test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Data from 138 patients were analyzed (M: F=0.8:1) with a mean age of 62.5 months and a median of 24 months. Respiratory ailments were the highest (46.4%),&#xa0;followed by central nervous system diseases (18.1%), and overall mortality was 20.3%. Area under the ROC curve was 0.984 for PRISM III, 0.836 for PIM 2, and 0.872 for PELOD.&#xa0;PRISM III was a better predictor of mortality risk, followed by PIM 2 and PELOD. The goodness-of-fit test showed good calibration for all three scores, but PRISM III had the better power compared to PIM 2 and PELOD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In our PICU setting, the PRISM III score was a better predictor of mortality risk, and the performance of PELOD was the least.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Sengupta et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sengupta</LastName><ForeName>Dorothy</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Surat Municipal Institute of Medical Education and Research (SMIMER), Surat, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatt</LastName><ForeName>Shreya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Surat Municipal Institute of Medical Education and Research (SMIMER), Surat, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Anand Hospital, Surat, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Swati</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Surat Municipal Institute of Medical Education and Research (SMIMER), Surat, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Poonam</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics, Surat Municipal Institute of Medical Education and Research (SMIMER), Surat, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mortality predictors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pelod</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">picu</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pim 2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prism iii</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee (IEC), SMIMER, Surat,Gujarat,India issued approval IEC/OUT/No 46, Dated 03/10/2018. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41918661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13033901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The use of severity scores in the intensive care unit. Le Gall JR. Intensive Care Med. 2005;31:1618&#x2013;1623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16244878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pediatric risk of mortality: an assessment of its performance in a sample of 26 Italian intensive care units. Bertolini G, Ripamonti D, Cattaneo A, Apolone G. Crit Care Med. 1998;26:1427&#x2013;1432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9710104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prognostic accuracy of Acute Physiology and Chronic Health Evaluation II scores in critically ill cancer patients. Chang L, Horng CF, Huang YC, Hsieh YY. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16391314/ Am J Crit Care. 2006;15:47&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16391314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cost, resource utilization, and severity of illness in intensive care. Klem SA, Pollack MM, Getson PR. J Pediatr. 1990;116:231&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2299492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severity of illness and organ dysfunction scoring in children. Lacroix J, Cotting J. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2005;6:0&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15857545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollack MM. Pediatric Critical Care. St. Louis: Mosby Year Book; 1992. Clinical scoring systems in pediatric intensive care; pp. 153&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PRISM III: an updated Pediatric Risk of Mortality score. Pollack MM, Patel KM, Ruttimann UE. Crit Care Med. 1996;24:743&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8706448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of severity scoring systems in a pediatric intensive care unit in India: a single-center prospective, observational cohort study. Patki VK, Raina S, Antin JV. J Pediatr Intensive Care. 2017;6:98&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6260256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31073431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severity scoring systems in the critically ill. Bouch DC, Thompson JP. Continuing Education in Anaesthesia Critical Care &amp; Pain. 2008;8:181&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severity scoring systems in paediatric intensive care units. Bhadoria P, Bhagwat AG. https://www.scribd.com/document/361420324/PRISM-Score Indian J Anaesth. 2008;52:663&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illness severity and organ dysfunction scoring in Pediatric Intensive Care Unit. Gulla KM, Sachdev A. Indian J Crit Care Med. 2016;20:27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4759990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26955214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of three prognostic scores (PRISM, PELOD and PIM 2) at pediatric intensive care unit under Pakistani circumstances. Qureshi AU, Ali AS, Ahmad TM. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18183720/ J Ayub Med Coll Abbottabad. 2007;19:49&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18183720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PIM2: a revised version of the Paediatric Index of Mortality. Slater A, Shann F, Pearson G. Intensive Care Med. 2003;29:278&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12541154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development of a pediatric multiple organ dysfunction score: use of two strategies. Leteurtre S, Martinot A, Duhamel A, et al. Med Decis Making. 1999;19:399&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10520678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validation of the paediatric logistic organ dysfunction (PELOD) score: prospective, observational, multicentre study. Leteurtre S, Martinot A, Duhamel A, et al. Lancet. 2003;362:192&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12885479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Performance of PRISM III, PELOD-2, and P-MODS scores in two pediatric intensive care units in China. Zhang L, Wu Y, Huang H, et al. Front Pediatr. 2021;9:626165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8113391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33996681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Internal validation and evaluation of the predictive performance of models based on the PRISM-3 (Pediatric Risk of Mortality) and PIM-3 (Pediatric Index of Mortality) scoring systems for predicting mortality in Pediatric Intensive Care Units (PICUs) Rahmatinejad Z, Rahmatinejad F, Sezavar M, Tohidinezhad F, Abu-Hanna A, Eslami S. BMC Pediatr. 2022;22:199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9004120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35413854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validation of the PELOD score for multiple organ dysfunction in children. Thukral A, Kohli U, Lodha R, Kabra SK, Kabra NK. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17921557/ Indian Pediatr. 2007;44:683&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17921557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing the areas under two or more correlated receiver operating characteristic curves: a nonparametric approach. DeLong ER, DeLong DM, Clarke-Pearson DL. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/3203132/ Biometrics. 1988;44:837&#x2013;845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3203132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of PRISM III and PIM II score in predicting mortality in paediatric intensive care unit: an observational study. Muthupandi V, Dianagrace R, Narayanan E, Sathya J. J Clin Diagn Res. 2022;16:8&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Performance of the pediatric logistic organ dysfunction (PELOD) and (PELOD-2) scores in a pediatric intensive care unit of a developing country. El-Nawawy A, Mohsen AA, Abdel-Malik M, Taman SO. Eur J Pediatr. 2017;176:849&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28492972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Application of the pediatric risk of mortality (PRISM) score and determination of mortality risk factors in a tertiary pediatric intensive care unit. Costa GA, Delgado AF, Ferraro A, Okay TS. Clinics (Sao Paulo) 2010;65:1087&#x2013;1092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2999700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21243277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of Pediatric Risk Of Mortality III, Pediatric Index of Mortality 2, and Pediatric Index of Mortality 3 in predicting mortality in a pediatric intensive care unit. Tyagi P, Tullu MS, Agrawal M. J Pediatr Intensive Care. 2018;7:201&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6506681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31073495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of death in the PICU at five U.S. teaching hospitals*. Burns JP, Sellers DE, Meyer EC, Lewis-Newby M, Truog RD. Crit Care Med. 2014;42:2101&#x2013;2108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4134743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validation of the Pediatric Index of Mortality 3 in a single pediatric intensive care unit in Korea. Lee OJ, Jung M, Kim M, Yang HK, Cho J. J Korean Med Sci. 2017;32:365&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5220006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28049251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validation of pediatric index of mortality 2 (PIM2) in a single pediatric intensive care unit in Japan. Imamura T, Nakagawa S, Goldman RD, Fujiwara T. Intensive Care Med. 2012;38:649&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22270470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daily estimation of the severity of multiple organ dysfunction syndrome in critically ill children. Leteurtre S, Duhamel A, Grandbastien B, et al. CMAJ. 2010;182:1181&#x2013;1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2917930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20547715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of pediatric scoring systems for mortality in septic patients and the impact of missing information on their predictive power: a retrospective analysis. Niederwanger C, Varga T, Hell T, et al. PeerJ. 2020;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33083117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating mortality risk adjustment among children receiving extracorporeal support for respiratory failure. Barbaro RP, Boonstra PS, Kuo KW, et al. ASAIO J. 2019;65:277&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29746311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Performance of Pediatric Risk of Mortality, Pediatric Index of Mortality and PIM2 in term Chinese neonates. Wang C, Xie G, Cheng B, et al. J Trop Pediatr. 2010;56:235&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Performance of Pediatric Risk of Mortality (PRISM), Pediatric Index of Mortality (PIM), and PIM2 in a pediatric intensive care unit in a developing country. Thukral A, Lodha R, Irshad M, Arora NK. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2006;7:356&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16738502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>