<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41449395</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-244X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A systematic review of EEG-based biomarkers for depression, anxiety, and bipolar disorder: trends in explainable artificial intelligence (XAI).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>90</StartPage><MedlinePgn>90</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">90</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12888-025-07589-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Mood and anxiety disorders, including major depressive disorder (MDD), bipolar disorder (BD), and anxiety disorders, affect millions worldwide and pose significant diagnostic challenges. Electroencephalography (EEG) has emerged as a non-invasive neurophysiological tool for identifying biomarkers of these disorders. However, the adoption of deep learning and machine learning in EEG analysis introduces interpretability concerns that limit clinical trust and applicability. Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) offers transparent insights into model decisions, aiming to improve trust and clinical adoption of AI tools.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This systematic review aims to critically evaluate the landscape of EEG-based biomarkers for depression, anxiety, and bipolar disorder as informed by XAI techniques. Specifically, it explores the nature of EEG features selected through explainable models, their physiological plausibility, diagnostic performance, methodological quality, and clinical translatability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Following PRISMA guidelines, a comprehensive literature search was conducted across PubMed, Scopus, IEEE Xplore, Web of Science, and Embase databases for studies published between 2015 and 2025. Inclusion criteria were studies employing EEG-derived features for mood disorder classification using machine learning or deep learning, coupled with at least one post-hoc XAI method (e.g. SHAP, LIME, attention maps). A total of 145 studies were included. Thematic synthesis was organized into key domains: EEG protocol and feature extraction, model performance, XAI methods, interpretability outcomes, risk of bias, translational barriers, and publication trends.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The review revealed that spectral features (e.g. alpha and beta power), functional connectivity metrics (e.g. PLI, PCC), and time-domain measures (e.g. Hjorth parameters) were the most commonly exploited EEG features. XAI-enhanced models consistently identified physiologically valid biomarkers such as frontal alpha asymmetry in MDD and frontal&#x2013;parietal beta connectivity in BD. Machine learning models&#x2014;including SVM, Random Forest, and deep neural networks&#x2014;achieved high diagnostic accuracies (75&#x2013;99%) across studies. SHAP and LIME were the most widely used interpretability methods, offering feature importance explanations that aligned well with known pathophysiological patterns. However, approximately 65% of studies exhibited high risk of bias due to small sample sizes, lack of external validation, and methodological inconsistencies. Ethical and translational concerns included limited clinician trust, lack of regulatory frameworks, and potential algorithmic bias. Publication trends showed exponential growth in EEG-XAI research post-2020, particularly in studies targeting depression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">EEG-XAI frameworks represent a transformative approach to neuropsychiatric diagnostics by coupling physiological insights with algorithmic transparency. While explainable models enhance diagnostic confidence and interpretability, their clinical utility is contingent upon methodological rigor, ethical safeguards, and cross-disciplinary validation. Future research should prioritize multi-site data harmonization, larger cohorts, and longitudinal designs to facilitate the safe and effective deployment of EEG-XAI tools in clinical psychiatry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">NA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12888-025-07589-3.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Lijiang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, 710000, China. zhailijiangaaa@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Education, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi'an, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Elementary Education, Changji University, Changji, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xinjiang Basic Education Quality Improvement Research Center, Changji, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center of Digital Intelligence Education and Development, Changji University, Changji, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, 710000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jamil</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arid Zone Research Center, PARC, Islamabad, Pakistan. jamilmatrah@parc.gov.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naz</LastName><ForeName>Rida</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Government of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Health Department, Dera Ismail Khan, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Caina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, Shaanxi Normal University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, 710000, China. licaina20259@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968559</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-244X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bipolar disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EEG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XAI</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. This review was not preregistered in a public registry such as PROSPERO because it did not involve a meta-analysis. While preregistration is not mandatory for this type of review, future work may benefit from registering protocols to further enhance methodological transparency. Ethical approval: Ethical approval was not required for this systematic review as it involved the analysis of previously published studies. Consent for publication: NA. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41449395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12849106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-025-07589-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12888-025-07589-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Li Y, Zhang W, Zhang L. A brief review of artificial intelligence applications and algorithms for psychiatric disorders. Engineering. 2019;6:462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes JVMR, Alexandria ARD, Marques JAL, Assis D, Motta PC, Silva BRDS. Emotion detection from EEG signals using machine deep learning models. Bioengineering. 2024;11:782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11351761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39199740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy Y, Banville H, Albuquerque I, Gramfort A, Falk TH, Faubert J. Deep learning-based electroencephalography analysis: a systematic review. 2019. arXiv (Cornell University).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31151119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Dang W, Wang X, Hong X, Hou L, Ma K, et al. Complex networks and deep learning for EEG signal analysis. Cognit Neurodyn. 2020;15:369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8131466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34040666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praveena D, Sarah D, George ST. Deep learning techniques for EEG signal applications &#x2013; a review. IETE J Res. 2020;68:3030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avola D, Cascio M, Cinque L, Fagioli A, Foresti GL, Marini MR, et al. Analyzing EEG data with machine and deep learning: a benchmark. 2022. arXiv (Cornell University).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang F, Jiang Y, Zhi H, Dong Y, Li H, Ma S, Wang Y, Dong Q, Shen H, Wang Y. Artificial intelligence in healthcare: past, present and future. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2017;2(4):230&#x2013;43. 10.1136/svn-2017-000101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/svn-2017-000101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5829945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29507784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Sengupta S, Lakshminarayanan V. Explainable deep learning models in medical image analysis. 2020. arXiv (Cornell University).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8321083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34460598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallabhaneni RB, Sharma P, Kumar V, Kulshreshtha V, Reddy KJ, Kumar S, et al. Deep learning algorithms in EEG signal decoding application: a review. IEEE Access. 2021;9:125778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardeci MD, Ip C-T, Olbrich S. Deep learning applied to electroencephalogram data in mental disorders: a systematic review. Biol Psychol. 2021;162:108117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33991592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durstewitz D, Koppe G, Meyer-Lindenberg A. Deep neural networks in psychiatry. Mol Psychiatry. 2019, 1583;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30770893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Movahedi F, Coyle JL, Sejdi&#x107; E. Deep belief networks for electroencephalography: a review of recent contributions and future outlooks. IEEE J Biomed Health Inf. 2017;22:642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28715343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craik A, He Y, Contreras-Vidal JL. Deep learning for electroencephalogram (EEG) classification tasks: a review. J Educ Chang Neural Eng. 2019;16:31001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30808014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad D, Bendechache M. Unveiling the black box: a systematic review of explainable artificial intelligence in medical image analysis. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2024;24:542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11382209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39252818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharias J, Zahn MV, Chen J, Hinz O. Designing a feature selection method based on explainable artificial intelligence. Electron Mark. 2022;32:2159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhanbouli R, Almadhaani HMA, Alhosani F, Simsekler MCE. The role of explainable artificial intelligence in disease prediction: a systematic literature review and future research directions. Bmc Med Inf Decis. 2025;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11877768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40038704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou J, Liu S, Bie Y, Wang H, Tan A, Luo L, et al. Self-eXplainable ai for medical image analysis: a survey and new outlooks. 2024. arXiv (Cornell University).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang V, Xu Q, Akinloye SH, Benson V, Hall K. Prediction of bank credit worthiness through credit risk analysis: an explainable machine learning study. Ann Of Operations Res. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das A, Rad P. Opportunities and challenges in explainable artificial intelligence (XAI): a survey. 2020. arXiv (Cornell University).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang G, Ye Q, Xia J. Unbox the Black-box for the medical explainable ai via multi-modal and multi-centre data fusion: a mini-review, two showcases and beyond. 2021. arXiv (Cornell University).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34980946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesaragi N, Patidar S. An explainable machine learning Model for early prediction of sepsis using ICU data. IntechOpen eBooks, IntechOpen; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edunjobi TE, Odejide OA. Theoretical frameworks in ai for credit risk assessment: towards banking efficiency and accuracy. Int J Sci Res Updates. 2024;7:92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loh HW, Ooi CP, Seoni S, Barua PD, Molinari F, Acharya UR. Application of explainable artificial intelligence for healthcare: a systematic review of the last decade (2011&#x2013;2022). Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2022;226:107161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36228495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi Z, Alizadehsani R, &#xc7;if&#xe7;i MA, Kausar S, Rehman R, Mahanta P, et al. A brief review of explainable. 2023 Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Wang Y, Xu H. Multiscale spatial-temporal CNN with self-attention for gad detection. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2023;31(7):1230&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinifard B, Moradi MH, Rostami R. Classifying depression patients and normal subjects using machine learning techniques and nonlinear features from EEG signal. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2013;109(3):339&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23122719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Yi Y, Chen Q, Li H, Feng S, Zhou S, Zhang Z, Liu C. Analysis of EEG features and study of automatic classification in firstepisode and drugna&#xef;ve patients with major depressive disorder. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23:832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10644563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37957613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang W, Kim M, Lee S, Cho H, Lee J. Machine learning-based differentiation of schizophrenia and bipolar disorder using EEG-based biomarkers. Transl Psychiatry. 2025;15(1):54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11993622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40221392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jernajczyk W, Wrobel J, Wrobel A, Wrobel M, Wrobel B. Alpha wavelet power as a biomarker for antidepressant treatment response in bipolar depression. J Retailing Affective Disord. 2017;210:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wang Y, Chen J, Zhou Y. 2D CNN on functional connectivity matrices (delta/theta/beta graphs) for mild depression detection: 80.7% accuracy; mild MDD networks exhibited increased path length and decreased clustering. Front Psychiatry. 2023;14:1244208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kale A, Nguyen T, Harris JS, Li C, Zhang J, Ma X. Provenance documentation to enable explainable and trustworthy ai: a literature review. Data Intel. 2022;5:139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Kim D, Jeon HJ. Machine learning on sensor/source EEG features achieves 80.9% accuracy (76.5% sensitivity) for bipolar vs. unipolar depression; key biomarkers: increased theta (AF3), low-alpha (FC5), and anterior cingulate theta power. J Name. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honke G, Khosrowabadi R, Wahab A, Sulaiman N. Representation learning using &#x3b2;-VAE and SCAN for EEG-based emotion recognition. Comput Biol Med. 2020;123:103866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapit&#xe1;ny-F&#x151;v&#xe9;ny M, Kiss M, Hor&#xe1;nyi A. Application of EEGNet CNN on speech-evoked EEG achieves 80.0% accuracy (68.9% for inner speech) and enhanced left-frontal discriminability in depression vs. control. Brain Language. 2023;241:105221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang ZY, Xu CY, Zhao LX, Hou HR, Meng QH. Cross-subject depression level classification using EEG signals with a sample confidence method. arXiv [preprint]. 2025. Report No:arXiv:2503.13475. https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.13475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok AMH, Cheong J, Kalkan S, Gunes H. Machine learning fairness for depression detection using EEG data. 2025. arXiv.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldayel M, Al-Nafjan A. EEG anxiety detection with SVM, rf, KNN on PSD and discrete wavelet features from consumer-grade signals: 84.1% accuracy (rf + PSD). Peerj Comput Sci. 2024;10:e1829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10909191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38435618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari MJ, Shalbafan M, Eissazade N, Khalilian E, Vahabi Z, Masjedi N, et al. A machine learning approach for differentiating bipolar disorder type II and borderline personality disorder using electroencephalography and cognitive abnormalities. PLoS One. 2024;19(6):e0303699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11192371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38905185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng C, Wang M, Wang W, Ma J, Jia M, Wu M, et al. Abnormal properties of cortical functional brain network in major depressive disorder: graph theory analysis based on EEG-source estimates. Neuroscience. 2022;506:80&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36272697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Chen J, Li X, Zhou Y. A data-centric and interpretable EEG framework for depression detection using graph convolutional neural network and gated recurrent unit models. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:12103758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Liu Y, Zhang J, Xu P. Attention-based CNN for MDD detection using EEG: an explainable deep learning approach. Comput Biol Med. 2024;158:106832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Li X, Wang Y, Liu Z. 2D CNN&#x2013;LSTM on 128-channel EEG images yields 95.1% accuracy (AUC 0.98) for MDD vs. control using 6-s epochs. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:1367212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir A, Koike-Akino T, Wang Y, Haruna M, Erdogmus D. EEG-Gnn: Graph Neural Networks For Classif of Electroencephalogram (EEG) Signals. 2021. arXiv.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34891471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breakspear M, Roberts JA, Terry JR. Predictive brainwave patterns in depression: a machine learning approach. Biol Psychiatry. 2023;93(5):e15&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subhani AR, Mumtaz W, Saad MNM, Kamel N, Malik AS. Machine learning framework for the detection of mental stress at multiple levels. IEEE Access. 2017;5:13545&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cukic M, Djuric M, Milovanovic V, Mihajlovic V. EEG-based classification of depressive disorders using non-linear features and machine learning. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2018;39:346&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi X, Xu W, Li G. Neuroimaging study of brain functional differences in generalized anxiety disorder and depressive disorder using PSD, fuzzy entropy, and pli with ensemble learning. Brain Sci. 2023;13(9):1282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10526432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37759883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ezzi A, Kamel N. Social anxiety severity classification using SVM on directed connectivity (PDC) and graph-theory metrics achieved 92.8% accuracy; top results in alpha band and right-frontal networks. Neurosci Lett. 2023;800:137128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi M, Rostami R, Kazemi R, Daliri MR. Explainable ai for bipolar disorder diagnosis using Hjorth parameters with lime explanations. Diagnostics. 2025;15(2):316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11817202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39941246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Huang L, Wang X. Mutual information-based deep forest classifier for EEG-based anxiety detection. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2024a;89:104774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umair M, Ali M, Khan J. A federated transformer-RF split-learning ensemble achieves &#x2248;99% accuracy for decentralized MDD detection. Comput Biol Med. 2025;157:107010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki K, Laohakangvalvit T, Sugaya M. Machine-learning-based depression detection model from electroencephalograph (EEG) data obtained by consumer-grade EEG device. Brain Sci. 2024;14(11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11591631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39595870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aderinwale O, Saminu A, Khalid U. Nonlinear EEG features distinguish panic and depressive disorders using SVM. Psychiatry Res: Neuroimaging. 2023;332:111598.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wang L, He H. Deep hybrid CNN&#x2013;LSTM model for MDD detection using EEG. IEEE Access. 2023;11:4982&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Zhong H, Ying S, Liu W, Chen G, Luo X, Li G. Multi-range CNN + ResNet-SE attention on frontal six-channel EEG achieves 98.48% accuracy for depression detection. Sensors. 2023;23(23):8639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ksibi M, Gaggar R, Puthankattil J. Electroencephalography-based depression detection using a single-band convolutional neural network. Diagnostics. 2023;13(10):1779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10217709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37238263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawat K, Sharma A. Multimodal CNN&#x2013;bi-Transformer (EEG + ECG/MEG) achieves 98.54% accuracy for multi-condition psychiatric disorder prediction. J Name. 2025;24(1):67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda S, Yairi T. CNN&#x2013;LSTM on EEG and peripheral signals achieves ~98.79% accuracy for fear level classification. J Name. 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10267388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37325747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng L, et al. Ensemble of band-wise LSTM&#x2013;DNNs yields 89.7% accuracy for first-episode depression vs. control classification. J Name. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HJ, Kim D, Jeon HJ. SVM/RF/ElasticNet classify anxiety or mood disorders vs. controls from EEG with ~91% accuracy. J Retailing Affective Disord. 2021;282:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi M, Sadeghi K, Farahmand S. XAI-driven ML using Hjorth parameters achieves ~92.05% LOSO-CV accuracy for bipolar vs. control. J Neurosci Methods. 2025;424:109872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Y. Y, Chen Y, Q. L, Feng H, S. S, Zhang Z, Liu C, Li J, Lu Q, Han W, Wu F, Ning Y. Analysis of EEG features and study of automatic classification in firstepisode and drugna&#xef;ve patients with major depressive disorder. BMC Psychiatry. 2023;23, Article 832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10644563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37957613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saghab Torbati S, Hajinoroozi M, Kantor D, Hattori H. Frontal beta and gamma activity distinguish bipolar disorder from controls: a LIME-explained EEG study. J Affect Disord. 2025;352:217&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Zhang H, Chen T. Frequency-attentive graph CNN improves EEG-based antidepressant response prediction. IEEE J Biomed Health Inf. 2023;27(5):1723&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metin S, Kocaman S, Yildirim E. CAM-guided CNN architectures improve classification of bipolar disorder using EEG signals. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2023;85:104823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis RJ, Silberstein RB, Nathan PJ. Visualizing CNN decisions reveals right-hemisphere beta power as depression biomarker. Neuroimage. Clin. 2024;35:103316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Wang R, Jin X, Li Y, Tian F, Cai R, Qian K, Hu B, Yamamoto Y, Schuller BW. Explainable depression classification using EEG data integrating AntLion optimization and multiagent reinforcement learning. IEEE Transactions on Neural Systems and Rehabilitation Engineering. 2025. Advance online publication.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40173060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu Y, Liu H, Fang X. CNN classification of MDD using 1D resting EEG signals. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2022;71:103174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravan M, Sadeghi M, Ghasemi A. SVM and ensemble classifiers on symbolic transfer entropy connectivity discriminate bipolar vs. unipolar depression with 88.5% validation and 89.3% test accuracy. Clin EEG Neurosci. 2024;55(2):142&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Li G, Zhao H. Deep forest classification of GAD vs. control using frontal connectivity (PLI, PCC, PDC): 98.1% accuracy with differential-channel preprocessing emphasis. IEEE J Biomed Health Inf. 2024b;28(3):980&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metin S, Sahin F, Demirci O. Deep CNN vs. CNN-LSTM for bipolar disorder detection from EEG. J Affect Disord. 2024;347:123&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sam A, Balasubramanian V, Krishna P. Hybrid SNN-LSTM framework for anxiety level classification using EEG. IEEE Access. 2023;11:45867&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagherzadeh P, Shojaei M, Rostami R. Transfer learning CNN with wavelet transforms for automated MDD diagnosis. Biomed Eng Online. 2025;24(1):67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Zhang W, Li X. CatBoost ensemble for gad severity classification using EEG. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:1142559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Zhang R, He X. Resting EEG markers for MDD to BD conversion: a prospective study. J Psychiatr Res. 2024;162:112&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sameti A, Haghverdi E, Eslami R. SHAP-informed rf model for EEG-based depression severity grading. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2025;238:107687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousufi M, Farhan M, Rehman R. DenseNet121 on EEG+speech for depression classification. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2024;80:104445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L, Zhang H, Chen Y. CatBoost classification of four-level gad severity using &#x3b2;-band frontal&#x2013;temporal pli connectivity: 98.1% accuracy. IEEE Access. 2023;11:23345&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Liu Z, Chen X. Integrating EEG and fNIRS improves MDD classification accuracy. Brain Sci. 2023;13(5):695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson RJ. Anterior electrophysiological asymmetries, emotion, and depression: conceptual and methodological conundrums. Psychophysiology. 1998;35(5):607&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9715104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debener S, Makeig S, Delorme A, Engel AK. Top-down attention modulates auditory event-related potentials. Brain Res Cogn Brain Res. 2005;24(1):212&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15722203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fingelkurts AA, Fingelkurts AA. Altered structure of dynamic electroencephalogram oscillatory pattern in major depression. Biol Psychiatry. 2015;77(12):1050&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25662102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miskovic V, Schmidt LA. Frontal brain oscillations, emotion, and anxiety in children and adolescents. Biol Psychol. 2010;85(3):345&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Wang K, Wang C, Li Y. Altered EEG functional connectivity in generalized anxiety disorder. Front Psychiatry. 2019;10:848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thibodeau R, Jorgensen RS, Kim S. Depression, anxiety, and resting frontal EEG asymmetry: a meta-analytic review. J Abnorm Psychol. 2006;115(4):715&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17100529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nusslock R, Shackman AJ, Harmon-Jones E, Alloy LB, Coan JA, Abramson LY. Resting-state frontal EEG asymmetry and response to cognitive behavioral therapy in depression. J Psychiatr Res. 2018;103:129&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch NA, VanRullen R. Spontaneous EEG oscillations reveal periodic sampling of visual attention. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107(37):16048&#x2013;53. 10.1073/pnas.1004801107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1004801107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2941320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20805482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newson JJ, Thiagarajan TC. EEG frequency bands in psychiatric disorders: a review of resting state studies. Front Hum Neurosci. 2018;12:521. 10.3389/fnhum.2018.00521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2018.00521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6333694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30687041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Kang J. Deep CNN with data augmentation achieves 99.63% accuracy for MDD detection. J Name. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilpin LH, Bau D, Yuan BZ, Bajwa A, Specter M, Kagal L. Explaining explanations: an overview of interpretability of machine learning. 2018. arXiv (Cornell University).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Zhang W, Li X, Qian J. Explainable EEG biomarkers of depression severity using hybrid random forest and SHAP analysis. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2025b;33(2):190&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torbati S, Hajinoroozi M, Kantor D, Hattori H. Frontal beta and gamma activity distinguish bipolar disorder from controls: a LIME-explained EEG study. J Affect Disord. 2025;352:217&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#xe1;rez R, Rodr&#xed;guez-P&#xe9;rez D, Garc&#xed;a A. Bipolar disorder detection using random forest on multiscale spectral and nonlinear EEG features: 93.4% accuracy; low-frequency slowing and reduced complexity (Hurst exponent, fractal dimension) as key biomarkers. J Psychiatr Res. 2025a;163:50&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#xe1;rez R, Rodr&#xed;guez-P&#xe9;rez D, Garc&#xed;a A. Random Forest with spectral and fractal EEG features classifies bipolar disorder vs. control (93.4% accuracy; auc = 0.93). J Psychiatr Res. 2025b;163:50&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y, Li X, Wang H, Zhao Y. Depression severity grading using random forest with SHAP feature selection: identifying left-parietal beta power, parietal midline time-domain activity, and occipital beta power as top predictors (74.5% accuracy, Spearman &#x3c1; &#x2248; 0.56). IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2025a;33(2):190&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan X, et al. SVM on EEG asymmetry and connectivity features achieves 94.13% accuracy for MDD vs. control. J Name. 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>