<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41647144</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1871-4080</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cognitive neurodynamics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cogn Neurodyn</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Design of intelligent neuro-supervised deep learning networks to analyze brain electrical activity rhythms of Parkinson's disease model.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>32</StartPage><MedlinePgn>32</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">32</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11571-025-10404-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Parkinson's disease (PD) is a multidimensional neurological condition designated by dopamine-sensitive neuron decline, which impairs generator and cognitive function. To study the dynamics of Parkinson's disease (PD), this paper presents a novel methodology that uses Intelligent Systems Neuro-Supervised Deep Learning Networks (INSDLNs). To describe the patterns of electrical activity in the brain metrics throughout various points in the central nervous system, we suggest a model based on mathematics governed by three distinct classes. To gain a deeper understanding of the fundamental processes underlying Parkinson's disease development, we aim to identify obscure trends within neurological data by leveraging intelligent neuro-supervised learning networks. This novel approach may lead to improved diagnostic and therapeutic approaches and holds promise for improving our understanding of the dynamics of Parkinson's disease (PD). By utilizing the features of an architecture containing multilayer recurrent layers, the suggested Intelligent Systems Neuro-Supervised Deep Learning Networks (INSDLNs) are designed. The input and target samples for INSDLNs were organizedand constructed from reference data that was formulated using the Adams method on a range of PI scenarios for modeling using a reliable numerical solver. To evaluate the impact on patterns of brain electrical activity, this method involved moving sensor positions.The differential equations are used for creating the dataset using Mathematica's ND solve function. The dataset for INSDLNs training was generated using the Adam stochastic solver. After that, this dataset is divided into three significant states: 80% is used for training, 10% is used for validation, and 15% is used for testing. The goal of these divisions is to effectively handle the difficulties presented by the dynamical model. The datasets, randomly divided into training, testing, and validation samples, were used to apply the INSDLNs created for the study. To ensure the model's stability and efficacy on various data sets, the procedure for segmentation was executed by optimizing a fitness function based on mean squared error. The proposed INSDLNs demonstrate accuracy, preciseness, and security through the achievement of minimal mean squared error (MSE), complete regression analysis (Rg. As), optimized error histograms (Err. Hg), auto-correlation of error (AC of Err), cross-correlation of input with error (CCIEr), and minimal absolute error (Ab. Er).When modeling the brain rhythms of Parkinson's disease, our INSDLNs outperformed LMBPA and BRM with very low error (MSE: 5.86E-12&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.1E-12), nearly zero absolute error, and strong regression accuracy (R2&#x2009;&#x2248;&#x2009;0.998).A lower mean square error (MSE) shows that the suggested approach operates effectively and that the forecasts generated by the model are more reliable. Reaching an almost zero absolute error (Ab. Er) provides more evidence for INSDLNs. These results highlight the higher accuracy and predictive power attained by applying INSDLNs and pursuing the best possible solutions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature B.V. 2026. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saqib</LastName><ForeName>Sana Ullah</ForeName><Initials>SU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Mathematics, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/05vn3ca78</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.260542.7</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0532 3749</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Hau</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, National Taiwan Normal University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/059dkdx38</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412090.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2158 7670</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raja</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Asif Zahoor</ForeName><Initials>MAZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Future Technology Research Center, National Yunlin University of Science and Technology, 123 University Road, Section 3, Douliou, 64002 Yunlin Taiwan, R.O.C.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04qkq2m54</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412127.3</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0532 0820</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nisar</LastName><ForeName>Kottakkaran Sooppy</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, College of Science and Humanities in Al-Kharj, Prince Sattam bin Abdulaziz University, 11942 Al-Kharj, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04jt46d36</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.449553.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0441 5588</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoaib</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Bachelor Program in Electrical and Communication Engineering, Yuan Ze University, Taoyuan, Taiwan.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01fv1ds98</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.413050.3</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1770 3669</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Yuan Ze University, Taoyuan, Taiwan.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01fv1ds98</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.413050.3</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1770 3669</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Cogn Neurodyn</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101306907</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1871-4080</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bioinformatics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intelligent computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuro-supervised deep learning networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease (PD)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2027</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41647144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12868464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11571-025-10404-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbas Z, Tayara H, Chong KT (2022) ENet-6&#xa0;mA: identification of 6&#xa0;mA modification sites in plant genomes using ElasticNet and neural networks. Int J Mol Sci 23(15):8314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23158314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35955447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afonso MM, Edla DR, Ramesh D (2025) Transformers-based deep learning for parkinson&#x2019;s disease detection using electroencephalography and Stockwell transform. Procedia Comput Sci 258:4094&#x2013;4104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2025.04.660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Khasawneh MA, Alzahrani A, Alarood A (2023) An artificial intelligence based effective diagnosis of Parkinson disease using EEG signal. Data analysis for neurodegenerative disorders. Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore, pp 239&#x2013;251</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anninou AP, Groumpos PP (2014) Modeling of parkinson&#x2019;s disease using fuzzy cognitive maps and non-linear hebbian learning. Int J Artif Intell Tools 23(05):1450010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0218213014500109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avola D, Bernardini A, Crocetti G, Ladogana A, Lezoche M, Mancini M, Pannone D, Ranaldi A (2025) Benchmarking of EEG analysis techniques for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease diagnosis: a comparison between traditional ML methods and foundation DL methods. arXiv:2507.13716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babichev S, Yasinska-Damri L, Liakh I (2023) A hybrid model of cancer diseases diagnosis based on gene expression data with joint use of data mining methods and machine learning techniques. Appl Sci 13(10):6022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13106022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakry SA, Mahmoud NM (2025) Automated early prediction of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease based on artificial intelligent techniques. Arab J Sci Eng. 10.1007/s13369-025-10358-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-025-10358-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakshi S, Chelliah V, Chen C, van der Graaf PH (2019) Mathematical biology models of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. CPT: Pharm Syst Pharmacol 8(2):77&#x2013;86</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6389348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30358157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaha HM, Hassan AES, Ahmed RA, Balaha MH (2025) Comprehensive multimodal approach for parkinson&#x2019;s disease classification using artificial intelligence: insights and model explainability. Soft Comput 29(3):1845&#x2013;1877</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00500-025-10463-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bdaqli M, Shoeibi A, Moridian P, Sadeghi D, Pouyani MF, Shalbaf A, Gorriz JM (2024) Diagnosis of Parkinson disease from EEG signals using a CNN-LSTM model and explainable AI. International work-conference on the interplay between natural and artificial computation. Springer, Cham, pp 128&#x2013;138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belozyorov VY, Zaytsev VG (2017) Mathematical modeling of parkinson&#x2019;s illness by chaotic dynamics methods. &#x412;&#x456;&#x441;&#x43d;&#x438;&#x43a; &#x414;&#x43d;&#x456;&#x43f;&#x440;&#x43e;&#x43f;&#x435;&#x442;&#x440;&#x43e;&#x432;&#x441;&#x44c;&#x43a;&#x43e;&#x433;&#x43e; &#x443;&#x43d;&#x456;&#x432;&#x435;&#x440;&#x441;&#x438;&#x442;&#x435;&#x442;&#x443; &#x421;&#x435;&#x440;&#x456;&#x44f;: &#x41c;&#x43e;&#x434;&#x435;&#x43b;&#x44e;&#x432;&#x430;&#x43d;&#x43d;&#x44f; 25(&#x2013; 9):21&#x2013;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15421/141702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borah M, Das D, Gayan A, Fenton F, Cherry E (2021) Control and anticontrol of chaos in fractional-order models of Diabetes, HIV, Dengue, Migraine, Parkinson&#x2019;s and Ebola virus diseases. Chaos Solitons Fractals 153:111419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chaos.2021.111419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9236268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35765659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunese L, Mercaldo F, Reginelli A, Santone A (2022) A neural network-based method for respiratory sound analysis and lung disease detection. Appl Sci 12(8):3877</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12083877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunterngchit C, Baniata LH, Albayati H, Baniata MH, Alharbi K, Alshammari FH, Kang S (2025) A hybrid convolutional&#x2013;transformer approach for accurate electroencephalography (EEG)-based parkinson&#x2019;s disease detection. Bioengineering 12(6):583</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering12060583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12189856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40564400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinaglia P, Cannataro M (2022) Forecasting COVID-19 epidemic trends by combining a neural network with Rt estimation. Entropy 24(7):929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/e24070929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35885152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danciu D (2015) A CNN-based approach for a class of non-standard hyperbolic partial differential equations modeling distributed parameters (nonlinear) control systems. Neurocomputing 164:56&#x2013;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucom.2014.12.092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Pup F, Brun R, Iotti F, Paccagnella E, Pezzato M, Bertozzo S, Zanola A, Tshimanga LF, M&#xfc;ller H, Atzori M (2025) TransformEEG: towards improving model generalizability in deep learning-based EEG Parkinson&#x2019;s disease detection. arXiv:2507.07622</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deuschl G, Beghi E, Fazekas F, Varga T, Christoforidi KA, Sipido E, Bassetti CL, Vos T, Feigin VL (2020) The burden of neurological diseases in europe: an analysis for the global burden of disease study 2017. Lancet Public Health 5(10):e551&#x2013;e567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(20)30190-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dipietro L, Eden U, Elkin-Frankston S, El-Hagrassy MM, Camsari DD, Ramos-Estebanez C, Fregni F, Wagner T (2024) Integrating big data, artificial intelligence, and motion analysis for emerging precision medicine applications in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Big Data 11(1):155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-024-01023-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11525280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39493349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorsey E, Sherer T, Okun MS, Bloem BR (2018) The emerging evidence of the Parkinson pandemic. J Parkinson&#x2019;s Dis 8(s1):S3&#x2013;S8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JPD-181474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6311367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30584159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin VL, Nichols E, Alam T, Bannick MS, Beghi E, Blake N, Culpepper WJ, Dorsey ER, Elbaz A, Ellenbogen RG, Fisher JL (2019) Global, regional, and national burden of neurological disorders, 1990&#x2013;2016: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2016. Lancet Neurol 18(5):459&#x2013;480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30499-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6459001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargantilla Becerra A, Guti&#xe9;rrez M, Lahoz Beltr&#xe1; R (2022) Computing within bacteria: programming of bacterial behavior by means of a plasmid encoding a perceptron neural network</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35063580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghassemi N, Shoeibi A, Rouhani M (2020) Deep neural network with generative adversarial networks pre-training for brain tumor classification based on MR images. Biomed Signal Process Control 57:101678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2019.101678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godoy Junior CA, Miele F, M&#xe4;kitie L, Fiorenzato E, Koivu M, Bakker LJ, Groot CUD, Redekop WK, van Deen WK (2024) Attitudes toward the adoption of remote patient monitoring and artificial intelligence in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease management: perspectives of patients and neurologists. Patient-Patient-Cent Outcomes Res 17(3):275&#x2013;285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40271-023-00669-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11039525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38182935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ven M (2024) Detection of Alzheimer&#x2019;s and Parkinson&#x2019;s diseases using deep learning-based various transformers models. Eng Proc 73(1):4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayete B, Wuest D, Laramie J, McDonagh P, Church B, Eberly S, Lang A, Marek K, Runge K, Shoulson I, Singleton A (2017) A Bayesian mathematical model of motor and cognitive outcomes in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. PLoS One 12(6):e0178982</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0178982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5467836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog B (2023) Fractional stochastic search algorithms: modelling complex systems via AI. Mathematics 11(9):2061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math11092061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang GM, Kim UH, Kim JG (2023) Vision transformers for the prediction of mild cognitive impairment to Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease progression using mid-sagittal sMRI. Front Aging Neurosci 15:1102869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2023.1102869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10133493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37122374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain SS, Shah PM, Dawood H, Degang X, Alshamayleh A, Khan MA, Ghazal TM (2025) A swin transformer and CNN fusion framework for accurate Parkinson disease classification in MRI. Sci Rep 15(1):15117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-93671-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12041535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40301455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari M, Sadeghi D, Shoeibi A, Alinejad-Rokny H, Beheshti A, Garc&#xed;a DL, Chen Z, Acharya UR, Gorriz JM (2024) Empowering precision medicine: AI-driven schizophrenia diagnosis via EEG signals: a comprehensive review from 2002&#x2013;2023. Appl Intell 54(1):35&#x2013;79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10489-023-05155-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalia LV, Lang AE (2015) Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet 386(9996):896&#x2013;912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(14)61393-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25904081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi-Sani I, Sharifi M, Abolpour N, Lotfi M, Atapour A, Takhshid MA, Sahebkar A (2025) Drug repositioning for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: an emphasis on artificial intelligence approaches. Ageing Res Rev. 10.1016/j.arr.2024.102651</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2024.102651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39755176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutlu H, Avci E, &#xd6;zyurt F (2020) White blood cells detection and classification based on regional convolutional neural networks. Med Hypotheses 135:109472</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mehy.2019.109472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31760248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Ao B, Wu X, Wen Q, Ul Haq E, Yin J (2024) Parkinson&#x2019;s disease detection and classification using EEG based on deep CNN-LSTM model. Biotechnol Genet Eng Rev 40(3):2577&#x2013;2596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02648725.2023.2200333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37039259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XY, Wang WL, Liu M, Chen MY, Pereira T, Doda DY, Ke YF, Wang SY, Wen D, Tong XG, Li WG (2025) Recent applications of EEG-based brain-computer-interface in the medical field. Mil Med Res 12(1):14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11931852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40128831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan A, Sharma N, Aparicio-Obregon S, Alyami H, Alharbi A, Anand D, Sharma M, Goyal N (2022) A novel stacking-based deterministic ensemble model for infectious disease prediction. Mathematics 10(10):1714</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10101714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmood T, Ali N, Chaudhary NI, Cheema KM, Milyani AH, Raja MAZ (2022) Novel adaptive Bayesian regularization networks for peristaltic motion of a third-grade fluid in a planar channel. Mathematics 10(3):358</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10030358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmood T, Ali N, Raja MAZ, Chaudhary NI, Cheema KM, Shu CM, Milyani AH (2023) Intelligent backpropagated predictive networks for dynamics of the power-law fluidic model with moving wedge and flat plate. Waves Random Complex Media. 10.1080/17455030.2023.2198025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17455030.2023.2198025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mwata-Velu TY, Avina-Cervantes JG, Cruz-Duarte JM, Rostro-Gonzalez H, Ruiz-Pinales J (2021) Imaginary finger movements decoding using empirical mode decomposition and a stacked BiLSTM architecture. Mathematics 9:3297</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math9243297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh K, Chung YC, Kim KW, Kim WS, Oh IS (2019) Classification and visualization of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease using volumetric convolutional neural network and transfer learning. Sci Rep 9(1):18150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-54548-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6890708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31796817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painuli D, Bhardwaj S, Kose U (2025) Efficient feature selection and hyperparameter tuning for improved speech signal-based Parkinson&#x2019;s disease diagnosis via machine learning techniques. Health Technol Assess Action. 10.18502/htaa.v9i1.17863</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/htaa.v9i1.17863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parakkal Unni M, Menon PP, Wilson MR, Tsaneva-Atanasova K (2020) Ankle push-off based mathematical model for freezing of gait in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 8:552635</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2020.552635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7658398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33195117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priyadharshini S, Ramkumar K, Vairavasundaram S, Narasimhan K, Venkatesh S, Amirtharajan R, Kotecha K (2024) A comprehensive framework for parkinson&#x2019;s disease diagnosis using explainable artificial intelligence empowered machine learning techniques. Alexandria Eng J 107:568&#x2013;582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2024.07.106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza WH, Shah AB, Wen Y, Shen Y, Lemus JDM, Schiess MC, Ellmore TM, Hu R, Fu X (2025) NeuroMoE: a transformer-based mixture-of-experts framework for multi-modal neurological disorder classification. arXiv:2506.14970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41336692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roethel A, Bili&#x144;ski P, Ishikawa T (2022) BioS2Net: holistic structural and sequential analysis of biomolecules using a deep neural network. Int J Mol Sci 23(6):2966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23062966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8954277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35328384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadiq MT, Yu X, Yuan Z, Zeming F, Rehman AU, Ullah I, Li G, Xiao G (2019) Motor imagery EEG signals decoding by multivariate empirical wavelet transform-based framework for robust brain&#x2013;computer interfaces. IEEE Access 7:171431&#x2013;171451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2956018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadiq MT, Yu X, Yuan Z, Aziz MZ (2020) Motor imagery BCI classification based on novel two-dimensional modelling in empirical wavelet transform. Electron Lett 56(25):1367&#x2013;1369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/el.2020.2509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadiq MT, Yu X, Yuan Z, Aziz MZ, ur Rehman N, Ding W, Xiao G (2022) Motor imagery BCI classification based on multivariate variational mode decomposition. IEEE Trans Emerg Top Comput Intell 6(5):1177&#x2013;1189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TETCI.2022.3147030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarbaz Y, Pourakbari H (2016) A review of presented mathematical models in parkinson&#x2019;s disease: black-and gray-box models. Med Biol Eng Comput 54:855&#x2013;868</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11517-015-1401-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26546075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoeibi A, Khodatars M, Alinejad-Rorky H, Heras J, Bagherzadeh S, Beheshti A, Gorriz JM (2024) Diagnosis of schizophrenia in eeg signals using ddtf effective connectivity and new pretrained cnn and transformer models. International work-conference on the interplay between natural and artificial computation. Springer, Cham, pp 150&#x2013;160</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shokrpour S, MoghadamFarid A, Bazzaz Abkenar S, Haghi Kashani M, Akbari M, Sarvizadeh M (2025) Machine learning for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a comprehensive review of datasets, algorithms, and challenges. NPJ Parkinsons Dis 11(1):187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41531-025-01025-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12217022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40595773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasu PN, SivaSai JG, Ijaz MF, Bhoi AK, Kim W, Kang JJ (2021) Classification of skin disease using deep learning neural networks with MobileNet V2 and LSTM. Sensors 21(8):2852</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21082852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8074091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoean R, Ionescu L, Stoean C, Boicea M, Atencia M, Joya G (2021) A deep learning-based surrogate for the Xrf approximation of elemental composition within archaeological artefacts before restoration. Procedia Comput Sci 192:2002&#x2013;2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2021.08.206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Zhang Z, Liu C, Yu Y, Pang S, Dui&#x107; N, Shafie-Khah M, Catalao JP (2019) Generative adversarial networks and convolutional neural networks-based weather classification model for day ahead short-term photovoltaic power forecasting. Energy Conv Manag 181:443&#x2013;462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2018.11.074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C, Mao Y (2021) Auxiliary model-based multi-innovation fractional stochastic gradient algorithm for Hammerstein output-error systems. Machines 9:247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/machines9110247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav S, Singh MK, Pal S (2023) Artificial intelligence model for Parkinson disease detection using machine learning algorithms. Biomedical Mater Devices 1(2):899&#x2013;911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44174-023-00068-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YD, Satapathy SC, Guttery DS, G&#xf3;rriz JM, Wang SH (2021) Improved breast cancer classification through combining graph convolutional network and convolutional neural network. Inf Process Manag 58(2):102439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ipm.2020.102439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao A, Liu Y, Yu X, Xing X, Zhou H (2025) Artificial intelligence-enabled detection and assessment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease using multimodal data: a survey. Inf Fus. 10.1016/j.inffus.2025.103175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2025.103175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>