<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600414</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Secure Hierarchical Asynchronous Federated Learning with Shuffle Model and Mask-DP.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">617</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26020617</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hierarchical asynchronous federated learning (HAFL) accommodates more real networking and ensures practical communications and efficient aggregations. However, existing HAFL schemes still face challenges in balancing privacy-preserving and robustness. Malicious training nodes may infer the privacy of other training nodes or poison the global model, thereby damaging the system's robustness. To address these issues, we propose a secure hierarchical asynchronous federated learning (SHAFL) framework. SHAFL organizes training nodes into multiple groups based on their respective gateways. Within each group, the training nodes prevent inference attacks from the gateways and committee nodes via a mask-DP exchange protocol and employ homomorphic encryption (HE) to prevent collusion attacks from other training nodes. Compared with conventional solutions, SHAFL uses noise that can be eliminated to reduce the impact of noise on the global model's performance, while employing a shuffle model and subsampling to enhance the local model's privacy-preserving level. At global model aggregation, SHAFL considers both model accuracy and communication delay, effectively reducing the impact of malicious and stale models on system performance. Theoretical analysis and experimental evaluations demonstrate that SHAFL outperforms state-of-the-art solutions in terms of convergence, security, robustness, and privacy-preserving capabilities.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yonghui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Hubei University of Technology, No. 28 Nanli Road, Hongshan District, Wuhan 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Provincial Engineering Research Center for Digital &amp; Intelligent Manufacturing Technologies and Applications, No. 28 Nanli Road, Hongshan District, Wuhan 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Provincial Key Laboratory of Green Intelligent Computing Power Network, No. 28 Nanli Road, Hongshan District, Wuhan 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ai</LastName><ForeName>Daxiang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Hubei University of Technology, No. 28 Nanli Road, Hongshan District, Wuhan 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Linglong</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Hubei University of Technology, No. 28 Nanli Road, Hongshan District, Wuhan 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>62002106</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>62002105</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>XJ2021000901</GrantID><Agency>Hubei University of Technology Green Industry Technology Leading Program Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">consensus mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">differential privacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">federated learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">secure aggregation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shuffle model</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12846026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26020617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26020617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Xu H., Liu J., Huang H., Qiao C., Zhao Y. Resource-efficient federated learning with hierarchical aggregation in edge computing; Proceedings of the IEEE INFOCOM 2021-IEEE Conference on Computer Communications; Vancouver, BC, Canada. 10&#x2013;13 May 2021; Piscataway, NJ, USA: IEEE; 2021. pp. 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Qu Y., Xiang Y., Gao L. Asynchronous federated learning on heterogeneous devices: A survey. Comput. Sci. Rev. 2023;50:100595. doi: 10.1016/j.cosrev.2023.100595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cosrev.2023.100595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang X., Sun A., Sun Y., Luo H., Guizani M. A Trust-Based Hierarchical Consensus Mechanism for Consortium Blockchain in Smart Grid. Tsinghua Sci. Technol. 2023;28:69&#x2013;81. doi: 10.26599/TST.2021.9010074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/TST.2021.9010074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Zheng Y., Huang H., Shu J., Jia X. Toward Robust Hierarchical Federated Learning in Internet of Vehicles. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 2023;24:5600&#x2013;5614. doi: 10.1109/TITS.2023.3243003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2023.3243003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Wu Y., Liang C., Chen Q., Zhang J. Distance-aware hierarchical federated learning in blockchain-enabled edge computing network. IEEE Internet Things J. 2023;10:19163&#x2013;19176. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2023.3279983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2023.3279983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H., Wang M., Shen J., Vijayakumar P., Moh S., Wu Q. Blockchain-Assisted Conditional Anonymous Authentication and Adaptive Tree-Based Group Key Agreement for VANETs. IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput. 2025:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2025.3628884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2025.3628884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Tian Z., Tang F., Pan H., She W., Liu W. Blockchain-empowered asynchronous federated reinforcement learning for IoT-based traffic trajectory prediction. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12:17095&#x2013;17109. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2025.3538887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3538887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y., Su Z., Wang Y., Zhou J., Mahmoud M. Privacy-Preserving Byzantine-Robust Federated Learning via Deep Reinforcement Learning in Vehicular Networks. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2025;74:9461&#x2013;9475. doi: 10.1109/TVT.2024.3524834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2024.3524834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X., Wei Y., Han Z. A Collaborative Sharding Consensus Mechanism for Blockchain-Based Federated Learning in IoT. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12:36422&#x2013;36435. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2025.3582818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3582818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M.S., Hongsong C. Hybrid transformer deep neural architectures for enhanced misinformation detection on social media. Expert Syst. Appl. 2025;300:130470. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2025.130470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2025.130470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H., Yang K., Jiao Y. Cellular Traffic Prediction via Byzantine-robust Asynchronous Federated Learning. IEEE Trans. Netw. Sci. Eng. 2025;12:2402&#x2013;2414. doi: 10.1109/TNSE.2025.3545912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSE.2025.3545912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Wu Y., Du W., Sun R., Xu G., Liu L., Wu C. Byzantine-Robust Hierarchical Aggregation for Cross-Device Federated Learning in Consumer IoT. IEEE Trans. Consum. Electron. 2024;71:6359&#x2013;6370. doi: 10.1109/TCE.2024.3450649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCE.2024.3450649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shokri R., Stronati M., Song C., Shmatikov V. Membership inference attacks against machine learning models; Proceedings of the 2017 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP); San Jose, CA, USA. 22&#x2013;26 May 2017; Piscataway, NJ, USA: IEEE; 2017. pp. 3&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredrikson M., Jha S., Ristenpart T. Model inversion attacks that exploit confidence information and basic countermeasures; Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security; Denver, CO, USA. 12&#x2013;16 October 2015; pp. 1322&#x2013;1333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun G., Cong Y., Dong J., Wang Q., Lyu L., Liu J. Data poisoning attacks on federated machine learning. IEEE Internet Things J. 2021;9:11365&#x2013;11375. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2021.3128646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2021.3128646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolpegin V., Truex S., Gursoy M.E., Liu L. Data poisoning attacks against federated learning systems; Proceedings of the Computer Security&#x2013;ESORICs 2020: 25th European Symposium on Research in Computer Security, ESORICs 2020; Guildford, UK. 14&#x2013;18 September 2020; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer; 2020. pp. 480&#x2013;501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Y., Gao L., Luan T.H., Xiang Y., Yu S., Li B., Zheng G. Decentralized privacy using blockchain-enabled federated learning in fog computing. IEEE Internet Things J. 2020;7:5171&#x2013;5183. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2020.2977383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2020.2977383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X., Miao Y., Li X., Choo K.K.R., Meng X., Deng R.H. Privacy-Preserving Asynchronous Federated Learning Framework in Distributed IoT. IEEE Internet Things J. 2023;10:13281&#x2013;13291. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2023.3262546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2023.3262546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian L., Lin F., Gan J., Jia R., Zheng Z., Li M. Pefl: Privacy-preserved and efficient federated learning with blockchain. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;12:3305&#x2013;3317. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2024.3479328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3479328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Chen B., Zhang J., Li W. ALGANs: Enhancing membership inference attacks in federated learning with GANs and active learning; Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE International Symposium on Product Compliance Engineering-Asia (ISPCE-ASIA); Guangzhou, China. 4&#x2013;6 November 2022; Piscataway, NJ, USA: IEEE; 2022. pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang M., Cao X., Jia J., Gong N. Local model poisoning attacks to Byzantine-Robust federated learning; Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security 20); Virtual. 12&#x2013;14 August 2020; pp. 1605&#x2013;1622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baruch G., Baruch M., Goldberg Y. A little is enough: Circumventing defenses for distributed learning; Proceedings of the NIPS&#x2019;19: 33rd International Conference on Neural Information; Vancouver, BC, Canada. 8&#x2013;14 December 2019; pp. 8635&#x2013;8645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5555/3454287.3455062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Xu D., Hu Y., Vijayakumar P., Zhu Y., Tolba A. Deep Fingerprinting Data Learning Based on Federated Differential Privacy for Resource-Constrained Intelligent IoT Systems. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;11:25744&#x2013;25756. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2024.3391662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3391662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K., Xu H., Hua K., Lin X., Li G., Jiang T., Li J. Joint Top-K Sparsification and Shuffle Model for Communication-Privacy-Accuracy Tradeoffs in Federated-Learning-Based IoV. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;11:19721&#x2013;19735. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2024.3370991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3370991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Zhou Y., Wu D., Hu M., Hui Wang J., Guizani M. FedDP-SA: Boosting Differentially Private Federated Learning via Local Data Set Splitting. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;11:31687&#x2013;31698. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2024.3421991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3421991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang R., Zhao T., Yu F.R., Li M., Zhang D., Zhao X. Blockchain-based federated learning with enhanced privacy and security using homomorphic encryption and reputation. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;11:21674&#x2013;21688. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2024.3379395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2024.3379395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Y., Liu Z., Li H., Choo K.K.R., Deng R.H. Privacy-Preserving Byzantine-Robust Federated Learning via Blockchain Systems. IEEE Trans. Inf. Forensics Secur. 2022;17:2848&#x2013;2861. doi: 10.1109/TIFS.2022.3196274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIFS.2022.3196274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijazi N.M., Aloqaily M., Guizani M., Ouni B., Karray F. Secure Federated Learning with Fully Homomorphic Encryption for IoT Communications. IEEE Internet Things J. 2024;11:4289&#x2013;4300. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2023.3302065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2023.3302065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng C., Liu B., Yu K., Goudos S.K., Wan S. Blockchain-empowered decentralized horizontal federated learning for 5G-enabled UAVs. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2021;18:3582&#x2013;3592. doi: 10.1109/TII.2021.3116132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2021.3116132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuda H., Kita K., Koizumi Y., Takemasa J., Hasegawa T. Model Fragmentation, Shuffle and Aggregation to Mitigate Model Inversion in Federated Learning; Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE International Symposium on Local and Metropolitan Area Networks (LANMAN); Boston, MA, USA. 12&#x2013;14 July 2021; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LANMAN52105.2021.9478813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen M., Wang J., Zhang J., Zhao Q., Peng B., Wu T., Zhu L., Xu K. Secure decentralized aggregation to prevent membership privacy leakage in edge-based federated learning. IEEE Trans. Netw. Sci. Eng. 2024;11:3105&#x2013;3119. doi: 10.1109/TNSE.2024.3360311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSE.2024.3360311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwork C., Roth A. The algorithmic foundations of differential privacy. Found. Trends&#xae; Theor. Comput. Sci. 2014;9:211&#x2013;407. doi: 10.1561/0400000042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1561/0400000042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T., Chen J.Q., Zhang Z., Su D., Cheng Y., Li Z., Li N., Jha S. Continuous release of data streams under both centralized and local differential privacy; Proceedings of the 2021 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security; Virtual. 15&#x2013;19 November 2021; pp. 1237&#x2013;1253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Gai K., Yu J., Zhu L., Wu H., Wei C., Yan Y., Zhang H., Choo K.K.R. Rafls: Rdp-based adaptive federated learning with shuffle model. IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput. 2024;22:1181&#x2013;1194. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2024.3429503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2024.3429503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X., Ni W., Ding M., Wei K., Li J., Poor H.V. Amplitude-varying perturbation for balancing privacy and utility in federated learning. IEEE Trans. Inf. Forensics Secur. 2023;18:1884&#x2013;1897. doi: 10.1109/TIFS.2023.3258255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIFS.2023.3258255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Ngai E., Voigt T. Byzantine-robust aggregation in federated learning empowered industrial iot. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2021;19:1165&#x2013;1175. doi: 10.1109/TII.2021.3128164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2021.3128164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Hu S., Beirami A., Smith V. Ditto: Fair and robust federated learning through personalization; Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning; Virtual. 18&#x2013;24 July 2021; pp. 6357&#x2013;6368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie C., Koyejo O., Gupta I. Fall of empires: Breaking byzantine-tolerant sgd by inner product manipulation; Proceedings of the Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence; Tel Aviv, Israel. 22&#x2013;25 July 2020; pp. 261&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Xu W., Chen T., Giannakis G.B., Ling Q. RSA: Byzantine-robust stochastic aggregation methods for distributed learning from heterogeneous datasets; Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence; Honolulu, HI, USA. 7 January&#x2013;1 February 2019; pp. 1544&#x2013;1551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimireddy S.P., He L., Jaggi M. Learning from history for byzantine robust optimization; Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning; Virtual. 18&#x2013;24 July 2021; pp. 5311&#x2013;5319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jere M.S., Farnan T., Koushanfar F. A taxonomy of attacks on federated learning. IEEE Secur. Priv. 2020;19:20&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1109/MSEC.2020.3039941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MSEC.2020.3039941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard P., El Mhamdi E.M., Guerraoui R., Stainer J. Machine learning with adversaries: Byzantine tolerant gradient descent; Proceedings of the NIPS&#x2019;17: Proceedings of the 31st International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems; Long Beach, CA, USA. 4&#x2013;9 December 2017; pp. 118&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5555/3294771.3294783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Su L., Xu J. Distributed statistical machine learning in adversarial settings: Byzantine gradient descent. Proc. ACM Meas. Anal. Comput. Syst. 2017;1:1&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1145/3154503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3154503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillutla K., Kakade S.M., Harchaoui Z. Robust aggregation for federated learning. IEEE Trans. Signal Process. 2022;70:1142&#x2013;1154. doi: 10.1109/TSP.2022.3153135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSP.2022.3153135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Ngai E.C.H., Voigt T. An experimental study of byzantine-robust aggregation schemes in federated learning. IEEE Trans. Big Data. 2023;10:975&#x2013;988. doi: 10.1109/TBDATA.2023.3237397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TBDATA.2023.3237397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattler F., M&#xfc;ller K.R., Wiegand T., Samek W. On the Byzantine Robustness of Clustered Federated Learning; Proceedings of the ICASSP 2020-2020 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP); Barcelona, Spain. 4&#x2013;8 May 2020; pp. 8861&#x2013;8865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICASSP40776.2020.9054676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Liu L., Zhang J., Liu J. Byzantine-robust federated learning through spatial-temporal analysis of local model updates; Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE 27th International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems (ICPADS); Beijing, China. 14&#x2013;16 December 2021; Piscataway, NJ, USA: IEEE; 2021. pp. 372&#x2013;379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin D., Chen Y., Kannan R., Bartlett P. Byzantine-robust distributed learning: Towards optimal statistical rates; Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning; Stockholm, Sweden. 10&#x2013;15 July 2018; pp. 5650&#x2013;5659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie C., Koyejo S., Gupta I. Asynchronous federated optimization. arXiv. 20191903.03934</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Y., Liu Z., Li X., Li M., Li H., Choo K.K.R., Deng R.H. Robust asynchronous federated learning with time-weighted and stale model aggregation. IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput. 2023;21:2361&#x2013;2375. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2023.3304788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2023.3304788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M., Boban M., Dressler F. Flexible training and uploading strategy for asynchronous federated learning in dynamic environments. IEEE Trans. Mob. Comput. 2024;23:12907&#x2013;12921. doi: 10.1109/TMC.2024.3418613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMC.2024.3418613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Yi W., Shin H., Nallanathan A. Adaptive semi-asynchronous federated learning over wireless networks. IEEE Trans. Commun. 2024;73:394&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1109/TCOMM.2024.3425635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCOMM.2024.3425635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei K., Li J., Ding M., Ma C., Yang H.H., Farokhi F., Jin S., Quek T.Q., Poor H.V. Federated learning with differential privacy: Algorithms and performance analysis. IEEE Trans. Inf. Forensics Secur. 2020;15:3454&#x2013;3469. doi: 10.1109/TIFS.2020.2988575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIFS.2020.2988575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang B., Li J., Wang H., Song H. Privacy-preserving federated learning for industrial edge computing via hybrid differential privacy and adaptive compression. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2021;19:1136&#x2013;1144. doi: 10.1109/TII.2021.3131175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2021.3131175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Wang H., Song T., Hua Y., Ma R., Jin X., Xue Z., Guan H. Siren+: Robust Federated Learning With Proactive Alarming and Differential Privacy. IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput. 2024;21:4843&#x2013;4860. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2024.3362534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2024.3362534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Weng J., Weng J., Zhong Y., Liu J.N., Deng C. Robust and Secure Federated Learning with Verifiable Differential Privacy. IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput. 2025;22:5713&#x2013;5729. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2025.3574745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2025.3574745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Ge J., Deng Y., Gao L., Zhang M., Li Y., Zhou W., Zheng X. BASS: A blockchain-based asynchronous SignSGD architecture for efficient and secure federated learning. IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput. 2024;21:5388&#x2013;5402. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2024.3374809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2024.3374809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balle B., Bell J., Gasc&#xf3;n A., Nissim K. The privacy blanket of the shuffle model; Proceedings of the Advances in Cryptology&#x2013;CRYPTO 2019: 39th Annual International Cryptology Conference; Santa Barbara, CA, USA. 18&#x2013;22 August 2019; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer; 2019. pp. 638&#x2013;667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girgis A., Data D., Diggavi S., Kairouz P., Suresh A.T. Shuffled model of differential privacy in federated learning; Proceedings of the International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics; Virtual. 13&#x2013;15 April 2021; pp. 2521&#x2013;2529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balle B., Barthe G., Gaboardi M. Privacy amplification by subsampling: Tight analyses via couplings and divergences; Proceedings of the NIPS&#x2019;18: Proceedings of the 32nd International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems; Montr&#xe9;al, Canada. 3&#x2013;8 December 2018; pp. 6280&#x2013;6290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5555/3327345.3327525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z., Xu C., Wang M., Kuang X., Zhuang Y., Yu S. A Multi-Shuffler Framework to Establish Mutual Confidence for Secure Federated Learning. IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput. 2023;20:4230&#x2013;4244. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2022.3215574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2022.3215574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahan H.B., Moore E., Ramage D., y Arcas B.A. Federated learning of deep networks using model averaging. arXiv. 20161602.05629</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Luo M., Ding W. Deep leakage from model in federated learning. arXiv. 2022 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2206.04887.2206.04887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2206.04887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin H., Mallya A., Vahdat A., Alvarez J.M., Kautz J., Molchanov P. See through gradients: Image batch recovery via gradinversion; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Nashville, TN, USA. 20&#x2013;25 June 2021; pp. 16337&#x2013;16346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J.C., Sharma A., Elkordy A.R., Ezzeldin Y.H., Avestimehr S., Bagchi S. Loki: Large-scale data reconstruction attack against federated learning through model manipulation; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (SP); San Francisco, CA, USA. 19&#x2013;23 May 2024; Piscataway, NJ, USA: IEEE; 2024. pp. 1287&#x2013;1305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu L., Yu H., Ma X., Chen C., Sun L., Zhao J., Yang Q., Yu P.S. Privacy and Robustness in Federated Learning: Attacks and Defenses. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 2022;35:8726&#x2013;8746. doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2022.3216981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2022.3216981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Luo X., Qian Y., Zhu Y., Chen K., Chen Q., Xin B., Yang W. Shuffle differential private data aggregation for random population. IEEE Trans. Parallel Distrib. Syst. 2023;34:1667&#x2013;1681. doi: 10.1109/TPDS.2023.3247541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPDS.2023.3247541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Z., Liu Y., Chang L. A robust and optional privacy data aggregation scheme for fog-enhanced IoT network. IEEE Syst. J. 2022;17:1110&#x2013;1120. doi: 10.1109/JSYST.2022.3177418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSYST.2022.3177418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paillier P. Proceedings of the International Conference on the Theory and Applications of Cryptographic Techniques. Springer; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 1999. Public-key cryptosystems based on composite degree residuosity classes; pp. 223&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Yan L., Ai D. An Robust Secure Blockchain-based Hierarchical Asynchronous Federated Learning Scheme for Internet of Things. IEEE Access. 2024;12:165280&#x2013;165297. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3493112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3493112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geyer R.C., Klein T., Nabi M. Differentially private federated learning: A client level perspective. arXiv. 20171712.07557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeCun Y., Bottou L., Bengio Y., Haffner P. Gradient-based learning applied to document recognition. Proc. IEEE. 1998;86:2278&#x2013;2324. doi: 10.1109/5.726791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/5.726791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizhevsky A., Hinton G. Learning Multiple Layers of Features from Tiny Images. 2009.  [(accessed on 9 January 2026)].  Available online:  https://www.cs.toronto.edu/~kriz/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta A., Batabyal T., Basu M., Acton S.T. An efficient convolutional neural network for coronary heart disease prediction. Expert Syst. Appl. 2020;159:113408. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2020.113408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2020.113408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Polato M., Brighente A., Conti M., Zhang L., Xu L. PriVeriFL: Privacy-preserving and aggregation-verifiable federated learning. IEEE Trans. Serv. Comput. 2024;18:998&#x2013;1011. doi: 10.1109/TSC.2024.3451183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSC.2024.3451183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>