<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41785686</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3573</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>305</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Talanta</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Talanta</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A severely overlapped-spectra decomposition approach for plasma emission spectroscopy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>129598</StartPage><MedlinePgn>129598</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.talanta.2026.129598</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0039-9140(26)00253-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ideal decomposition of severely overlapped spectra due to limited spectral resolution remains an unsolved puzzle for spectroscopic technologies. Although ultra-high-resolution spectrometers can resolve spectral overlap problems, they often entail high costs and significant signal loss, which naturally leads to relative high limit of detection (LOD). In this work, based on the assumption that the measured spectrum is the convolution of the much less overlapped real plasma emission profile and the spectrometer instrumental response, we propose a center-wavelength coupled with broadening-width-ratio constrained decomposition (CC-BCD) method for severely overlapped peaks from relatively low-resolution spectrometers. More specifically, the method incorporates the extra supporting information (the central wavelengths and the ratio of broadening width of the overlapped peaks obtained from ultra-high-resolution spectra) as hard constraints into the decomposition model, transforming the model from an otherwise underdetermined mathematical fit into a physically guided reconstruction and enabling accurate and stable resolution of severely overlapped peaks. The method was successfully applied for plasma emission technology such as laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy (LIBS) and spark-discharge optical emission spectroscopy (SD-OES). For uranium ores analysis using LIBS, the completely overlapped peaks (U II 385.957&#xa0;nm and Fe I 385.991&#xa0;nm) were fully resolved, reducing LOD to 7.3&#xa0;mg/kg, two orders of magnitude compared with that of using ultra-high-resolution spectrometer and the lowest record ever for ores. For brass sample detection using SD-OES, the severely overlapped peaks (Zn I 328.233&#xa0;nm and Cu I 328.272&#xa0;nm) were also resolved, reducing LOD for Zn from 0.39&#xa0;wt% to 0.11&#xa0;wt%. The proposed method enables relatively low-resolution spectrometers to achieve high resolution capabilities while retaining the high optical throughput, thereby providing a highly sensitive and low-cost approach for scenarios where the analysis heavily relies on severely overlapped lines, such as ultra-high-sensitivity analysis of uranium in complex matrices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Jianxun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Lab of Power Systems, International Joint Laboratory on Low Carbon Clean Energy Innovation, Department of Energy and Power Engineering, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Weiran</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Lab of Power Systems, International Joint Laboratory on Low Carbon Clean Energy Innovation, Department of Energy and Power Engineering, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Zongyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Lab of Power Systems, International Joint Laboratory on Low Carbon Clean Energy Innovation, Department of Energy and Power Engineering, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, China; Shanxi Research Institute for Clean Energy, Tsinghua University, Shanxi, 030032, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Xiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China National Uranium Corporation, Beijing, 100013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Zhi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Xuejing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Iron &amp; Steel Research Institute Group, Beijing, 100094, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Lab of Power Systems, International Joint Laboratory on Low Carbon Clean Energy Innovation, Department of Energy and Power Engineering, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, China; Shanxi Research Institute for Clean Energy, Tsinghua University, Shanxi, 030032, China; School of Energy and Electrical Engineering, Qinghai University, Key Laboratory of Intelligent Operation of New Energy Power System of Ministry of Education, Xining, 810016, China. Electronic address: zhewang@tsinghua.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Talanta</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2984816R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0039-9140</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Overlapped spectra decomposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plasma emission spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Uranium</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41785686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2026.129598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0039-9140(26)00253-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>