<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41775719</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cost-effective strategies can reduce water and energy requirements in China's wastewater treatment by 2035.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70159-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Wastewater treatment is a key component in ensuring future water resource security. However, this process itself faces major challenges in water and energy consumption. Reducing these inputs at low cost without compromising wastewater treatment effectiveness is crucial for sustainable development. Here, we assess the water and energy footprint of wastewater treatment in China, using estimated data from 10,124 urban wastewater treatment plants and 90 cases. We show that the water and energy footprints of wastewater treatment in China have nearly tripled from 2009 to 2022. By aligning treatment process selection through multi-objective trade-offs, reductions can be effectively achieved. By 2035, China's wastewater treatment water footprint and energy footprint could be reduced by 16.1% and 25.6%, respectively, with investments below 8% of total treatment costs, while the removal remains stable. Our findings offer a broadly applicable framework to guide sustainable wastewater management and support progress toward the Sustainable Development Goals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Siqi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center for Agricultural Water-Saving and Water Resources, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Edward R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5388-7774</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Geography, Faculty of Geosciences, Utrecht University, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Tuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center for Agricultural Water-Saving and Water Resources, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Weijie</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center for Agricultural Water-Saving and Water Resources, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yanhong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>En</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center for Agricultural Water-Saving and Water Resources, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environment and Civil Engineering, Dongguan University of Technology, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jiading</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiuzhi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9371-4648</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yellow River Research Institute, North China University of Water Resources and Electric Power, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasmu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaokaitijiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region Water Conservancy Management Station, Xinjiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center for Agricultural Water-Saving and Water Resources, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-7010-1842</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China. zhoubo89@cau.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center for Agricultural Water-Saving and Water Resources, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China. zhoubo89@cau.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yunkai</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4226-3805</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Efficient Utilization of Agricultural Water Resources, College of Water Resources and Civil Engineering, China Agricultural University, Beijing, China. yunkai@cau.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center for Agricultural Water-Saving and Water Resources, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China. yunkai@cau.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52339004</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52079139</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41775719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70159-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70159-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gozini, H., Zahraie, B. &amp; Ravar, Z. System dynamics modeling of water&#x2013;energy nexus for resource-saving policy assessment. Int. J. Environ. Res. 15, 349&#x2013;367 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai, J. et al. Water-energy nexus: A review of methods and tools for macro-assessment. Appl. Energy 210, 393&#x2013;408 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira, L. S. Water, agriculture and food: challenges and issues. Water Resour. Manag. 31, 2985&#x2013;2999 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fysikopoulos, A., Pastras, G., Alexopoulos, T. &amp; Chryssolouris, G. On a generalized approach to manufacturing energy efficiency. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 73, 1437&#x2013;1452 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora, M., Nair, S., Malano, H. &amp; George, B. A combined simulation-optimisation modelling framework for assessing the energy use of urban water systems. J. Environ. Manage. 274, 111166 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Z. J. &amp; Umble, A. K. Recover wastewater resources locally. Nature 529, 25&#x2013;25 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, E. R. et al. Current wastewater treatment targets are insufficient to protect surface water quality. Commun. Earth Environ. 3, 221 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, W.-J. et al. Spatiotemporal pattern of greenhouse gas emissions in China&#x2019;s wastewater sector and pathways towards carbon neutrality. Nat. Water 1, 166&#x2013;175 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magni, M., Jones, E. R., Bierkens, M. F. P. &amp; Van Vliet, M. T. H. Global energy consumption of water treatment technologies. Water Res 277, 123245 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove, W. J. &amp; Loucks, D. P. Water management: Current and future challenges and research directions. Water Resour. Res. 51, 4823&#x2013;4839 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OECD. Water quality and agriculture: meeting the policy challenge. OECD Studies on Water. OECD Publishing, Paris. (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan, J. et al. Potential pathogenic microorganisms in rural wastewater treatment process: Succession characteristics, concentration variation, source exploration, and risk assessment. Water Res 254, 121359 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, E. R., Bierkens, M. F. P. &amp; Van Vliet, M. T. H. Current and future global water scarcity intensifies when accounting for surface water quality. Nat. Clim. Change 14, 629&#x2013;635 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, L., Zhou, X., Due&#xf1;as-Osorio, L., Stadler, L. &amp; Li, Q. Hybrid wastewater treatment and reuse enhances urban water system resilience to disruptive incidents. Nat. Water 1, 1048&#x2013;1058 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahadir, M. Water and wastewater management: global problems and measures. springer (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen, T. A., Hoffmann, S., L&#xfc;thi, C., Truffer, B. &amp; Maurer, M. Emerging solutions to the water challenges of an urbanizing world. Science 352, 928&#x2013;933 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agbaitoro, G. A. &amp; Oyibo, K. I. Realizing the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals 7 and 13 in sub-Saharan Africa by 2030: synergizing energy and climate justice perspectives. J. World Energy Law Bus. 15, 223&#x2013;235 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fehri, R., Khlifi, S. &amp; Vanclooster, M. Disaggregating SDG-6 water stress indicator at different spatial and temporal scales in Tunisia. Sci. Total Environ. 694, 133766 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, C., Reid, M., Thwaites, J., Glover, R. &amp; Kestin, T. Assessing national progress and priorities for the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs): experience from Australia. Sustain. Sci. 15, 521&#x2013;538 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benetto, E., Nguyen, D., Lohmann, T., Schmitt, B. &amp; Schosseler, P. Life cycle assessment of ecological sanitation system for small-scale wastewater treatment. Sci. Total Environ. 407, 1506&#x2013;1516 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne, D. M., Lohman, H. A. C., Cook, S. M., Peters, G. M. &amp; Guest, J. S. Life cycle assessment (LCA) of urban water infrastructure: emerging approaches to balance objectives and inform comprehensive decision-making. Environ. Sci. Water Res. Technol. 3, 1002&#x2013;1014 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frischknecht, R., Stolz, P. &amp; Tsch&#xfc;mperlin, L. National environmental footprints and planetary boundaries: from methodology to policy implementation 59th LCA forum, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, Z&#xfc;rich, June 12, 2015. Int. J. Life Cycle Assess. 21, 601&#x2013;605 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corominas, L. et al. The application of life cycle assessment (LCA) to wastewater treatment: A best practice guide and critical review. Water Res 184, 116058 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beavis, P. &amp; Lundie, S. Integrated environmental assessment of tertiary and residuals treatment-LCA in the wastewater industry. Water Sci. Technol. 47, 109&#x2013;116 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Wastewater treatment technology selection under various influent conditions and effluent standards based on life cycle assessment. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 154, 104562 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loubet, P., Roux, P., Loiseau, E. &amp; Bellon-Maurel, V. Life cycle assessments of urban water systems: A comparative analysis of selected peer-reviewed literature. Water Res 67, 187&#x2013;202 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bringezu, S. et al. Environmental and socioeconomic footprints of the German bioeconomy. Nat. Sustain. 4, 775&#x2013;783 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bleischwitz, R. et al. Resource nexus perspectives towards the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals. Nat. Sustain. 1, 737&#x2013;743 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C., Qian, K. &amp; Li, Y. Diagnostic method for enhancing nitrogen and phosphorus removal in cyclic activated sludge technology (cast) process wastewater treatment plant. Water 14, 2253 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morera, S., Corominas, L., Rigola, M., Poch, M. &amp; Comas, J. Using a detailed inventory of a large wastewater treatment plant to estimate the relative importance of construction to the overall environmental impacts. Water Res 122, 614&#x2013;623 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, T. K. L. et al. Contribution of the construction phase to environmental impacts of the wastewater treatment plant. Sci. Total Environ. 743, 140658 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivero-Camacho, C. &amp; Marrero, M. Water Footprint of the Life Cycle of Buildings: Case Study in Andalusia, Spain. in Advances of Footprint Family for Sustainable Energy and Industrial Systems (ed. Ren, J.) 135&#x2013;165 (Springer International Publishing, Cham, 2022). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-76441-8_7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J.-L., Kong, L.-S., Wang, H. &amp; Zhang, X. A water-energy nexus review from the perspective of urban metabolism. Ecol. Model. 392, 128&#x2013;136 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner, S. W. D., Hejazi, M., Yonkofski, C., Kim, S. H. &amp; Kyle, P. Influence of groundwater extraction costs and resource depletion limits on simulated global nonrenewable water withdrawals over the twenty-first century. Earths Future 7, 123&#x2013;135 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, L. et al. Characteristic and correlation analysis of influent and energy consumption of wastewater treatment plants in Taihu Basin. Front. Environ. Sci. Eng. 13, 83 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penakalapati, G. et al. Exposure to animal feces and human health: a systematic review and proposed research priorities. Environ. Sci. Technol. 51, 11537&#x2013;11552 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tow, E. W. et al. Modeling the energy consumption of potable water reuse schemes. Water Res. X 13, 100126 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, P., Qin, C., Yu, L., Yang, L. &amp; Lu, L. A new policy of water resources and environmental regulation in China. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public. Health 20, 2556 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu, S., Chen, W., Zhang, W., Fan, Y. &amp; Jiao, W. Wastewater reclamation and reuse in China: Opportunities and challenges. J. Environ. Sci. 39, 86&#x2013;96 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, Y., Zhang, L. &amp; Adom, P. K. Economics of wastewater management in China&#x2019;s industry. Environ. Dev. Econ. 24, 457&#x2013;478 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D. et al. Impacts of water conservation, wastewater treatment, and reuse on water quantity and quality stress mitigation in China. J. Ind. Ecol. 29, 777&#x2013;793 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, Y., Lu, L., Shao, T., Shen, M. &amp; Jin, L. Decomposition analysis of factors affecting changes in industrial wastewater emission intensity in China: based on an SSBM-GMI approach. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public. Health15, 2779 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, W., Gao, S., Li, W. &amp; Luo, J. The impacts of technological progress and industrial structure distortion on water use intensity in China. Water Resour. Econ. 47, 100247 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, Y. et al. Quantification of the water, energy and carbon footprints of wastewater treatment plants in China considering a water&#x2013;energy nexus perspective. Ecol. Indic. 60, 402&#x2013;409 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, P., Kansal, A. &amp; Carliell-Marquet, C. Energy and carbon footprints of sewage treatment methods. J. Environ. Manage. 165, 22&#x2013;30 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morera, S., Corominas, L. L., Poch, M., Aldaya, M. M. &amp; Comas, J. Water footprint assessment in wastewater treatment plants. J. Clean. Prod. 112, 4741&#x2013;4748 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, S. M., Eckelman, M. J., Onnis-Hayden, A. &amp; Gu, A. Z. Life-cycle assessment of advanced nutrient removal technologies for wastewater treatment. Environ. Sci. Technol. 50, 3020&#x2013;3030 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, L. &amp; Chen, G. Q. Water footprint assessment for wastewater treatment: method, indicator, and application. Environ. Sci. Technol. 47, 7787&#x2013;7794 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turovskiy, I. S. &amp; Mathai, P. K. Wastewater Sludge Processing. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Hoboken (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey, P. A. Industrial Wastewater Treatment. PHI Learning, New Delhi (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honggui, G. The Multi&#x2014;game Research on Green Economic Development in China. China Popul. Resour. Environ. 22, 13&#x2013;18 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Assessing transboundary impacts of energy-driven water footprint on scarce water resources in China: catchments under stress and mitigation options. Environ. Sci. Technol. 57, 9639&#x2013;9652 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, E. R. et al. DynQual v1.0: a high-resolution global surface water quality model. Geosci. Model Dev. 16, 4481&#x2013;4500 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, Q. et al. Improving ecological protection redline from the perspective of water quality protection: A case study in the Tianmu Lake watershed. China. Ecol. Indic. 166, 112445 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. et al. Assessing progress towards sustainable development over space and time. Nature 577, 74&#x2013;78 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Vliet, M. T. H. et al. Global water scarcity including surface water quality and expansions of clean water technologies. Environ. Res. Lett. 16, 024020 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. &amp; Yang, W. Water sustainability for China and beyond. Science 337, 649&#x2013;650 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovink, H., Rahimzoda, S., Cullman, J. &amp; Imperiale, A. J. The UN 2023 Water Conference and pathways towards sustainability transformation for a water-secure world. Nat. Water 1, 212&#x2013;215 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, S. et al. Pollution control and cost analysis of wastewater treatment at industrial parks in Taihu and Haihe water basins, China. J. Clean. Prod. 172, 2435&#x2013;2442 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, S. et al. A Monte Carlo-based integrated model to optimize the cost and pollution reduction in wastewater treatment processes in a typical comprehensive industrial park in China. Sci. Total Environ. 647, 1&#x2013;10 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, M. et al. Pollution reduction and operating cost analysis of municipal wastewater treatment in China and implication for future wastewater management. J. Clean. Prod. 253, 120003 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guin&#xe9;e, J. B. et al. Life cycle assessment: past, present, and future. Environ. Sci. Technol. 45, 90&#x2013;96 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai, L., Liao, X., Yang, L. &amp; Yan, X. Assessing life cycle water use and pollution of coal-fired power generation in China using input-output analysis. Appl. Energy 231, 951&#x2013;958 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mardi, N. H., Ean, L. W., Malek, M. A., Chua, K. H. &amp; Ahmed, A. N. Operational blue water footprint and water deficit assessment of coal-fired power plants: case study in Malaysia. Environ. Sci. Eur. 35, 52 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cansino, J. M., S&#xe1;nchez-Braza, A. &amp; Rodr&#xed;guez-Ar&#xe9;valo, M. L. Driving forces of Spain&#x5f3;s CO<sub>2</sub> emissions: A LMDI decomposition approach. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 48, 749&#x2013;759 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang, B. W. The LMDI approach to decomposition analysis: a practical guide. Energy Policy 33, 867&#x2013;871 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, G., Sun, C., Ouyang, X. &amp; Zhang, C. A decomposition analysis of energy-related CO2 emissions in Chinese six high-energy intensive industries. J. Clean. Prod. 184, 1102&#x2013;1112 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. Provincial and gridded population projection for China under shared socioeconomic pathways from 2010 to 2100. Sci Data 7, 83 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>