<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41851128</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unlocking the reducing power of metal nitrides by mechanochemical hydrodefluorination of fluorinated compounds.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70813-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The carbon-fluorine (C-F) bond, present in both aromatic C(sp<sup>2</sup>)-F and aliphatic C(sp<sup>3</sup>)-F moieties, possesses an exceptionally high bond energy. This inherent stability renders C-F bond activation highly challenging. In this work, we address this challenge and reclaim valuable hydrocarbons from fluorinated compounds, including aryl fluorides, alkyl fluorides, and perfluoroalkyl substances, by developing a mechanochemical hydrodefluorination strategy. This approach exploits metal nitrides, particularly magnesium nitride, as reductants, contrasting with previous perception of metal nitrides as merely ammonia surrogates in organic reactions. Remarkably, this mechanochemical protocol achieves the degradation of even persistent polytetrafluoroethylene (Teflon&#xae;), a prototypical "forever chemical".</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jun-Shen</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, Anhui, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Li-Feng</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, Anhui, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, Anhui, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Guan-Wu</ForeName><Initials>GW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9287-532X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, Anhui, PR China. gwang@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Functional Molecular Solids, Ministry of Education, Anhui Laboratory of Molecule-Based Materials, and School of Chemistry and Materials Science, Anhui Normal University, Wuhu, Anhui, PR China. gwang@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu, PR China. gwang@ustc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>21372211</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22271271</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70813-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70813-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Fluorine in pharmaceutical industry: fluorine-containing drugs introduced to the market in the last decade (2001-2011). Chem. Rev. 114, 2432&#x2013;2506 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue, M., Sumii, Y. &amp; Shibata, N. Contribution of organofluorine compounds to pharmaceuticals. ACS Omega. 5, 10633&#x2013;10640 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeschke, P. The unique role of fluorine in the design of active ingredients for modern crop protection. ChemBioChem. 5, 570&#x2013;589 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara, T. &amp; O&#x2019;Hagan, D. Successful fluorine&#x2013;containing herbicide agrochemicals. J. Fluor. Chem. 167, 16&#x2013;29 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagliaro, M. &amp; Ciriminna, R. New fluorinated functional materials. J. Mater. Chem. 15, 4981&#x2013;4991 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joudan, S. &amp; Lundgren, R. Taking the &#x201c;F&#x201d; out of forever chemicals. Science 377, 816&#x2013;817 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung, S. C. E., Wanninayake, D., Chen, D., Nguyen, N. T. &amp; Li, Q. Physicochemical properties and interactions of perfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) &#x2013; challenges and opportunities in sensing and remediation. Sci. Total Environ. 905, 166764 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;ckl, J. L., Robertson, E. L. &amp; Lundberg, H. Electrosynthetic C&#x2013;F bond cleavage. Org. Biomol. Chem. 20, 6707&#x2013;6720 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy, S. &amp; Besset, T. New opportunities to access fluorinated molecules using organophotoredox catalysis via C(sp<sup>3</sup>)&#x2013;F bond cleavage. JACS Au 5, 466&#x2013;485 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer, C. E. et al. Electrochemical transformations of perfluoroalkyl acid (PFAA) precursors and PFAAs in groundwater impacted with aqueous film forming foams. Environ. Sci. Technol. 52, 10689&#x2013;10697 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, J. L. et al. Electrophotocatalysis for reductive defluorination of PTFE and PFASs. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e202422043 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, J., Gao, P. &amp; Deng, Y. Destruction of per&#x2013; and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) with advanced reduction processes (ARPs): a critical review. Environ. Sci. Technol. 54, 3752&#x2013;3766 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Chen, J. X., Qu, J. P. &amp; Kang, Y. B. Photocatalytic low&#x2013;temperature defluorination of PFASs. Nature. 635, 610&#x2013;617 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Photocatalytic C&#x2013;F bond activation in small molecules and polyfluoroalkyl substances. Nature. 637, 601&#x2013;607 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner, L. P. et al. Mechanochemical remediation of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid (PFOS) and perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) amended sand and aqueous film&#x2013;forming foam (AFFF) impacted soil by planetary ball milling. Sci. Total Environ. 765, 142722 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, N. et al. Solvent&#x2013;free nonthermal destruction of PFAS chemicals and PFAS in sediment by piezoelectric ball milling. Environ. Sci. Technol. Lett. 10, 198&#x2013;203 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battye, N. et al. Mechanochemical degradation of per&#x2013; and polyfuoroalkyl substances in soil using an industrial&#x2013;scale horizontal ball mill with comparisons of key operational metrics. Sci. Total Environ. 928, 172274 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L. et al. Phosphate&#x2013;enabled mechanochemical PFAS destruction for fluoride reuse. Nature 640, 100&#x2013;106 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattori, M., Saha, D., Bacho, M. Z. &amp; Shibata, N. Mechanochemical pathway for converting fluoropolymers to fluorochemicals. Nat. Chem. 17, 1480&#x2013;1487 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trang, B. et al. Low&#x2013;temperature mineralization of perfluorocarboxylic acids. Science 377, 839&#x2013;845 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monsky, R. J., Li, Y., Houk, K. N. &amp; Dichtel, W. R. Low&#x2013;temperature mineralization of fluorotelomers with diverse polar head groups. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 146, 17150&#x2013;17157 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl, T., Klare, H. F. T. &amp; Oestreich, M. Main&#x2013;group Lewis acids for C&#x2013;F bond activation. ACS Catal. 3, 1578&#x2013;1587 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt, D. B., Seath, C. P., Wang, H. &amp; Jui, N. T. Selective C&#x2013;F functionalization of unactivated trifluoromethylarenes. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 141, 13203&#x2013;13211 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Photochemical and electrochemical strategies in C&#x2013;F bond activation and functionalization. Org. Chem. Front. 9, 853&#x2013;873 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooker, L. V. &amp; Bandar, J. S. Synthetic advantages of defluorinative C&#x2013;F bond functionalization. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 62, e202308880 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S.-Y. et al. Selective defluoroalkylation and hydrodefluorination of trifluoromethyl groups photocatalyzed by dihydroacridine derivatives. J. Org. Chem. 88, 17284&#x2013;17296 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Y. et al. A general photocatalytic hydrodefluorination and defluoroalkylation of electronically-variable ArCF<sub>3</sub> by changing commercially-available arenethiolates. Green Chem. 26, 4518&#x2013;4527 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ningthoujam, R. S. &amp; Gajbhiye, N. S. Synthesis, electron transport properties of transition metal nitrides and applications. Prog. Mater. Sci. 70, 50&#x2013;154 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Z. et al. Transition metal nitrides for electrocatalytic application: progress and rational design. Nanomaterials. 12, 2660 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W. et al. Application of nitrides in energy storage field. J. Alloys Compd. 1022, 179847 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X., Xu, B., Chen, J. G. &amp; Yang, X. Recent progress in electrochemical nitrogen reduction on transition metal nitrides. ChemSusChem 16, e202201715 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batool, M., Hameed, A. &amp; Nadeem, M. A. Recent developments on iron and nickel-based transition metal nitrides for overall water splitting: a critical review. Coord. Chem. Rev. 480, 215029 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Z.-G. et al. Recent progress in the synthesis of transition metal nitride catalysts and their applications in electrocatalysis. Nanoscale 15, 11777&#x2013;11800 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, P. et al. Transition metal nitrides in lithium- and sodium-ion batteries: recent progress and perspectives. Adv. Mater. Interfaces 9, 2200606 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W. et al. Superionic conducting vacancy&#x2013;rich beta&#x2013;Li<sub>3</sub>N electrolyte for stable cycling of all&#x2013;solid&#x2013;state lithium metal batteries. Nat. Nanotechnol. 20, 265&#x2013;275 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. et al. Reactive magnesium nitride additive: a drop&#x2013;in solution for lithium/garnet wetting in all&#x2013;solid&#x2013;state batteries. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 62, e202305099 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridgwood, K., Veitch, G. &amp; Ley, S. Magnesium nitride as a convenient source of ammonia: preparation of dihydropyridines. Org. Lett. 10, 3627&#x2013;3629 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veitch, G., Bridgwood, K. &amp; Ley, S. Magnesium nitride as a convenient source of ammonia: preparation of primary amides. Org. Lett. 10, 3623&#x2013;3625 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Carpintero, J., Sanchez, J. D., Gonzalez, J. F. &amp; Menendez, J. C. Mechanochemical synthesis of primary amides. J. Org. Chem. 86, 14232&#x2013;14237 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghorbani-Choghamarani, A. et al. Nano aluminium nitride as a solid source of ammonia for the preparation of Hantzsch 1,4-dihydropyridines and bis-(1,4-dihydropyridines) in water via one pot multicomponent reaction. J. Braz. Chem. Soc. 22, 525&#x2013;531 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota, K., Pang, Y., Miura, A. &amp; Ito, H. Redox reactions of small organic molecules using ball milling and piezoelectric materials. Science 366, 1500&#x2013;1504 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, Y., Lee, J. W., Kubota, K. &amp; Ito, H. Solid&#x2013;state radical C&#x2013;H trifluoromethylation reactions using ball milling and piezoelectric materials. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 59, 22570&#x2013;22576 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doi, R., Yasuda, M., Kajita, N., Koh, K. &amp; Ogoshi, S. Nickel&#x2013;catalyzed exhaustive hydrodefluorination of perfluoroalkyl arenes. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 145, 11449&#x2013;11456 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, J. T. et al. Light&#x2013;driven hydrodefluorination of electron&#x2013;rich aryl fluorides by an anionic rhodium&#x2013;gallium photoredox catalyst. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 61, e202205575 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu, R. et al. Mechanical&#x2013;force&#x2013;induced non&#x2013;spontaneous dehalogenative deuteration of aromatic iodides enabled by using piezoelectric materials as a redox catalyst. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 63, e202400645 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>