<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41589930</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2313-7673</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biomimetics (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomimetics (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomimetic Approach to Designing Trust-Based Robot-to-Human Object Handover in a Collaborative Assembly Task.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">14</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/biomimetics11010014</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We presented a biomimetic approach to designing robot-to-human handover of objects in a collaborative assembly task. We developed a human-robot hybrid cell where a human and a robot collaborated with each other to perform the assembly operations of a product in a flexible manufacturing setup. Firstly, we investigated human psychology and biomechanics (kinetics and kinematics) for human-to-robot handover of an object in the human-robot collaborative set-up in three separate experimental conditions: (i) human possessed high trust in the robot, (ii) human possessed moderate trust in the robot, and (iii) human possessed low trust in the robot. The results showed that human psychology was significantly impacted by human trust in the robot, which also impacted the biomechanics of human-to-robot handover, i.e., human hand movement slowed down, the angle between human hand and robot arm increased (formed a braced handover configuration), and human grip forces increased if human trust in the robot decreased, and vice versa. Secondly, being inspired by those empirical results related to human psychology and biomechanics, we proposed a novel robot-to-human object handover mechanism (strategy). According to the novel handover mechanism, the robot varied its handover configurations and motions through kinematic redundancy with the aim of reducing potential impulse forces on the human body through the object during the handover when robot trust in the human was low. We implemented the proposed robot-to-human handover mechanism in the human-robot collaborative assembly task in the hybrid cell. The experimental evaluation results showed significant improvements in human-robot interaction (HRI) in terms of transparency, naturalness, engagement, cooperation, cognitive workload, and human trust in the robot, and in overall performance in terms of handover safety, handover success rate, and assembly efficiency. The results can help design and develop human-robot handover mechanisms for human-robot collaborative tasks in various applications such as industrial manufacturing and manipulation, medical surgery, warehouse, transport, logistics, construction, machine shops, goods delivery, etc.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahman</LastName><ForeName>S M Mizanoor</ForeName><Initials>SMM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5415-9912</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, The Pennsylvania State University, 120 Ridge View Drive, Dunmore, PA 18512, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Biomimetics (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101719189</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2313-7673</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">assembly task</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bio-inspired robot motion planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">handover biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human&#x2013;robot collaboration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human&#x2013;robot interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kinematic redundancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">object handover</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trust</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declares no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41589930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12838840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomimetics11010014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">biomimetics11010014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Burghart C., Yigit S., Kerpa O., Osswald D., Woern H. Intelligent Autonomous Systems. IOS Press; Amsterdam, The Netherlands: 2002. Concept for human-robot cooperation integrating artificial haptic perception; pp. 38&#x2013;45. Chapter 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding H., Heyn J., Matthias B., Staab H. Structured collaborative behavior of industrial robots in mixed human-robot environments; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering; Madison, WI, USA. 17&#x2013;21 August 2013; pp. 1101&#x2013;1106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X., Jiang Y., Chen C., Gong L., Ge M., Zhang T., Li X. A Complementary Framework for Human&#x2013;Robot Collaboration with a Mixed AR&#x2013;Haptic Interface. IEEE Trans. Control. Syst. Technol. 2024;32:112&#x2013;127. doi: 10.1109/TCST.2023.3301675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCST.2023.3301675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagenow M., Senft E., Radwin R., Gleicher M., Zinn M., Mutlu B. A System for Human-Robot Teaming through End-User Programming and Shared Autonomy; Proceedings of the 2024 19th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI); Boulder, CO, USA. 11&#x2013;14 March 2024; pp. 231&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shala E., Bajrami X., Zaev E., Babunski D. Efficient Kinematic Modeling, Simulation and Control of a 6-DOF Robotic Arm; Proceedings of the 2025 14th Mediterranean Conference on Embedded Computing (MECO); Budva, Montenegro. 10&#x2013;14 June 2025; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan H., Wang P., Yang Y., Li D., Wei W., Luo Y., Deng G. Reactive Human-to-Robot Dexterous Handovers for Anthropomorphic Hand. IEEE Trans. Robot. 2024;41:742&#x2013;761. doi: 10.1109/TRO.2024.3508194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2024.3508194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fryman J., Matthias B. Safety of industrial robots: From conventional to collaborative applications; Proceedings of the 7th German Conference on Robotics; Munich, Germany. 21&#x2013;22 May 2012; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segura P., Lobato-Calleros O., Soria-Arguello I., Hern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez E.G. Work Roles in Human&#x2013;Robot Collaborative Systems: Effects on Cognitive Ergonomics for the Manufacturing Industry. Appl. Sci. 2025;15:744. doi: 10.3390/app15020744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15020744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif S., Callari T.C., Khan F., Eimontaite I., Hubbard E.-M., Bahraini M.S., Webb P., Lohse N. Exploring tasks and challenges in human-robot collaborative systems: A review. Robot. Comput.-Integr. Manuf. 2026;97:103102. doi: 10.1016/j.rcim.2025.103102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rcim.2025.103102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othman U., Yang E. Human-Robot Collaborations in Smart Manufacturing Environments: Review and Outlook. Sensors. 2023;23:5663. doi: 10.3390/s23125663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23125663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10304173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37420834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baily M.N., Bosworth B.P. U.S. manufacturing: Understanding its past and its potential future. J. Econ. Perspect. 2015;28:3&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1257/jep.28.1.3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1257/jep.28.1.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fandi A., Harsanto B., Yunani A. Improvement of Assembly Manufacturing Process through Value Stream Mapping and Ranked Positional Weight: An Empirical Evidence from the Defense Industry. Processes. 2023;11:1334. doi: 10.3390/pr11051334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11051334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Keshavarzmanesh S., Feng H.-Y., Buchal R.O. Assembly process planning and its future in collaborative manufacturing: A review. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2008;41:132&#x2013;144. doi: 10.1007/s00170-008-1458-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-008-1458-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqahtani F.M., Noman M.A., Alabdulkarim S.A., Alharkan I., Alhaag M.H., Alessa F.M. A New Model for Determining Factors Affecting Human Errors in Manual Assembly Processes Using Fuzzy Delphi and DEMATEL Methods. Symmetry. 2023;15:1967. doi: 10.3390/sym15111967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym15111967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brovkina D., Riedel O. Assembly Process Model for Automated Assembly Line Design; Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE 3rd Eurasia Conference on IOT, Communication and Engineering (ECICE); Yunlin, Taiwan. 29&#x2013;31 October 2021; pp. 588&#x2013;594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheirabadi M., Ghorbani E., Keivanpour S. LLM-Powered Operator Advisor for Human-Robot Collaboration in Sustainable Assembly-Disassembly Cells; Proceedings of the 2025 IEEE 5th International Conference on Human-Machine Systems (ICHMS); Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates. 26&#x2013;28 May 2025; pp. 19&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transeth A.A., Stepanov A., Linnerud &#xc5;.S., Ening K., Gjerstad T. Competitive high variance, low volume manufacturing with robot manipulators; Proceedings of the 2020 3rd International Symposium on Small-Scale Intelligent Manufacturing Systems (SIMS); Gjovik, Norway. 10&#x2013;12 June 2020; pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rekik K., Silva G., Bashir A., M&#xfc;ller R. Multimodal Interaction for Human-Robot Collaboration in Assembly: An LLM-Enhanced Approach; Proceedings of the 2025 IEEE 21st International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE); Los Angeles, CA, USA. 17&#x2013;21 August 2025; pp. 1207&#x2013;1212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das A.R., Koskinopoulou M. Toward Sustainable Manufacturing: A Review on Innovations in Robotic Assembly and Disassembly. IEEE Access. 2025;13:100149&#x2013;100166. doi: 10.1109/access.2025.3576441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/access.2025.3576441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meshram S., Jaipuriar S., Sarkar A., Mondal A. An Efficient Iterative Beam Search for Human&#x2013;Robot Collaborative Assembly Line Balancing. IEEE Embed. Syst. Lett. 2025;17:313&#x2013;316. doi: 10.1109/LES.2025.3600560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LES.2025.3600560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel D., Phu N., Lu Y. Safe and Intuitive Human-Robot Collaborative Assembly with Potential Field-Based Dynamic Obstacle Avoidance and Gestured-Based Communication Interface; Proceedings of the 2025 IEEE 21st International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE); Los Angeles, CA, USA. 17&#x2013;21 August 2025; pp. 226&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoppi G., Forlini M., Palmieri G., Neto P. Recognition and Anticipation of Human Actions in a Human-Robot Collaborative Assembly Scenario; Proceedings of the 2025 34th IEEE International Conference on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO-MAN); Eindhoven, The Netherlands. 25&#x2013;29 August 2025; pp. 1229&#x2013;1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M. Communications in a Trust-Triggered Cyber-Physical-Human System for Human-Robot Collaborative Manufacturing; Proceedings of the 2025 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Technologies for Industrial Automation (ROBOTHIA); Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. 12 April 2025; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M., Wang Y. Mutual trust-based subtask allocation for human-robot collaboration in flexible lightweight assembly in manufacturing. Mechatronics. 2018;54:94&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1016/j.mechatronics.2018.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mechatronics.2018.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M. Performance Metrics for Human-Robot Collaboration: An Automotive Manufacturing Case; Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE International Workshop on Metrology for Automotive (MetroAutomotive); Bologna, Italy. 1&#x2013;2 July 2021; pp. 260&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kshirsagar A., Hoffman G. Empowering Robots for Object Handovers; Proceedings of the 2022 17th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI); Sapporo, Japan. 7&#x2013;10 March 2022; pp. 1164&#x2013;1166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera E., Lyons M., Parron J., Li R., Zhu M., Wang W. Learning-Finding-Giving: A Natural Vision-Speech-based Approach for Robots to Assist Humans in Human-Robot Collaborative Manufacturing Contexts; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE 4th International Conference on Human-Machine Systems (ICHMS); Toronto, ON, Canada. 15&#x2013;17 May 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corsini G., Jacquet M., Das H., Afifi A., Sidobre D., Franchi A. Nonlinear Model Predictive Control for Human-Robot Handover with Application to the Aerial Case; Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS); Kyoto, Japan. 23&#x2013;27 October 2022; pp. 7597&#x2013;7604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/IROS47612.2022.9981045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blengini C.L., Cheng P.D.C., Indri M. Safe robot affordance-based grasping and handover for Human-Robot assistive applications; Proceedings of the IECON 2024&#x2014;50th Annual Conference of the IEEE Industrial Electronics Society; Chicago, IL, USA. 3&#x2013;6 November 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal D., Yihun Y. Progress in Human-Robot Collaboration for Object Handover; Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE International Symposium on Measurement and Control in Robotics (ISMCR); Houston, TX, USA. 19&#x2013;21 September 2019; pp. C3-2-1&#x2013;C3-2-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castellani C., Turco E., Bo V., Malvezzi M., Prattichizzo D., Costante G., Pozzi M. Soft Human-Robot Handover Using a Vision-Based Pipeline. IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett. 2024;10:891&#x2013;898. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2024.3511415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2024.3511415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tulbure A., Zurbr&#xfc;gg R., Grigat T., Hutter M. LLM-Handover: Exploiting LLMs for Task-Oriented Robot-Human Handovers. IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett. 2025;10:12008&#x2013;12015. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2025.3615523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2025.3615523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaffir M.A.B.M., Wada T. Presentation of Robot-Intended Handover Position Using Vibrotactile Interface During Robot-to-Human Handover Task; Proceedings of the 2024 19th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI); Boulder, CO, USA. 11&#x2013;14 March 2024; pp. 492&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovur E., Quesada R.C., Demiris Y. Optimising Ergonomics for Robot-to-Human Object Handovers. IEEE Trans. Cogn. Dev. Syst. 2025 doi: 10.1109/TCDS.2025.3575625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCDS.2025.3575625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strabala K.W., Lee M.K., Dragan A.D., Forlizzi J.L., Srinivasa S.S., Cakmak M., Micelli V. Towards Seamless Human-Robot Handovers. J. Human-Robot Interact. 2013;2:112&#x2013;132. doi: 10.5898/JHRI.2.1.Strabala.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5898/JHRI.2.1.Strabala</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aleotti J., Micelli V., Caselli S. Comfortable robot to human object hand-over; Proceedings of the IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication; Paris, France. 9&#x2013;13 September 2012; pp. 771&#x2013;776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mainprice J., Gharbi M., Simeon T., Alami R. Sharing effort in planning human-robot handover tasks; Proceedings of the IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication; Paris, France. 9&#x2013;13 September 2012; pp. 764&#x2013;770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sisbot E., Alami R., Simeon T., Dautenhahn K., Walters M., Woods S. Navigation in the presence of humans; Proceedings of the 5th IEEE-RAS International Conference on Humanoid Robots; Tsukuba, Japan. 5&#x2013;7 December 2005; pp. 181&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agah A., Tanie K. Human interaction with a service robot: Mobile manipulator handing over an object to a human; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation; Albuquerque, NM, USA. 20&#x2013;25 April 1997; pp. 575&#x2013;580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diftler M., Ambrose R., Tyree K., Goza S., Huber E. A mobile autonomous humanoid assistant; Proceedings of the IEEE/RAS International Conference on Humanoid Robots; Santa Monica, CA, USA. 10&#x2013;12 November 2004; pp. 133&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan J., Duan F., Zhang Y., Watanabe K., Kato R., Arai T. Human-robot collaboration in cellular manufacturing: Design and development; Proceedings of the IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems; Louis, MO, USA. 11&#x2013;15 October 2009; pp. 29&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M., Sadrfaridpour B., Walker I.D., Wang Y. Cyber-Physical-Human Systems: Fundamentals and Applications. IEEE; Piscataway, NJ, USA: 2023. Trust-Triggered Robot&#x2013;Human Handovers Using Kinematic Redundancy for Collaborative Assembly in Flexible Manufacturing; pp. 299&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neranon P. Robot-to-Human Object Handover using a Behavioural Control Strategy; Proceedings of the 2018 IEEE 5th International Conference on Smart Instrumentation, Measurement and Application (ICSIMA); Songkhla, Thailand. 28&#x2013;30 November 2018; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker I.D., Mears L., Mizanoor R.S.M., Pak R., Remy S., Wang Y. Robot-human handovers based on trust; Proceedings of the IEEE Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Mathematics and Computers in Sciences and Industry&#x2014;MCSI 2015; Sliema, Malta. 17&#x2013;19 August 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megyeri A., Wiederhold N., Liu Y., Banerjee S., Banerjee N.K. Safety and Naturalness Perceptions of Robot-to-Human Handovers Performed by Data-Driven Robotic Mimicry of Human Givers; Proceedings of the 2025 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA); Atlanta, GA, USA. 19&#x2013;23 May 2025; pp. 1869&#x2013;1875.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M., Wang Y., Walker I.D., Mears L., Pak R., Remy S. Trust-based compliant robot-human handovers of payloads in collaborative assembly in flexible manufacturing; Proceedings of the 12th IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering; Fort Worth, TX, USA. 21&#x2013;25 August 2016; pp. 355&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billings D.R., Schaefer K.E., Chen J.Y.C., Hancock P.A. Human-robot interaction: Developing trust in robots; Proceedings of the ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction; Boston, MA, USA. 5&#x2013;8 March 2012; pp. 109&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G., Chen S., Zhou Z., Liu J. Modelling and analyzing trust conformity in e-commerce based on fuzzy logic. WSEAS Trans. Syst. 2015;14:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao L. Trusted access control based on FCE of user behavior in cloud environment. WSEAS Trans. Comput. 2015;14:629&#x2013;637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratna S.R., Ravi R. Trust based suspicious route categorization for wireless networks and its applications to physical layer attack. WSEAS Trans. Comput. 2015;14:502&#x2013;512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzahrani A., Ahmad M.I. Optimising Human Trust in Robots: A Reinforcement Learning Approach; Proceedings of the 2025 20th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI); Melbourne, Australia. 4&#x2013;6 March 2025; pp. 1202&#x2013;1206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esterwood C., Robert L.P. Repairing Trust in Robots? A Meta-analysis of HRI Trust Repair Studies with a No-Repair Condition; Proceedings of the 2025 20th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI); Melbourne, Australia. 4&#x2013;6 March 2025; pp. 410&#x2013;419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M. Cognitive Cyber-Physical System (C-CPS) for Human-Robot Collaborative Manufacturing; Proceedings of the 2019 14th Annual Conference System of Systems Engineering (SoSE); Anchorage, AK, USA. 19&#x2013;22 May 2019; pp. 125&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M. Trustworthy Power Assistance in Object Manipulation with a Power Assist Robotic System; Proceedings of the 2019 SoutheastCon; Huntsville, AL, USA. 11&#x2013;14 April 2019; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannum C., Li R., Wang W. Trust or Not? A Computational Robot-Trusting-Human Model for Human-Robot Collaborative Tasks; Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE International Conference on Big Data (Big Data); Atlanta, GA, USA. 10&#x2013;13 December 2020; pp. 5689&#x2013;5691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo-Sa H., Yang X.J., Robert L.P., Tilbury D.M. A Unified Bi-Directional Model for Natural and Artificial Trust in Human&#x2013;Robot Collaboration. IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett. 2021;6:5913&#x2013;5920. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2021.3088082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2021.3088082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman G., Breazeal C. Effects of anticipatory action on human-robot teamwork: Efficiency, fluency, and perception of team; Proceedings of the 2007 2nd ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI); Arlington, VA, USA. 9&#x2013;11 March 2007; pp. 1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M. Trust-Based Modular Cyber&#x2013;Physical&#x2013;Human Robotic System for Collaborative Manufacturing: Modulating Communications. Machines. 2025;13:731. doi: 10.3390/machines13080731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/machines13080731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basili P., Huber M., Brandt T., Hirche S., Glasauer S. Investigating human-human approach and hand-over. Hum. Centered Robot. Syst.-Cogn. Interact. Technol. 2009;6:151&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S., Ikeura R., Nobe M., Sawai H. Human operator&#x2019;s load force characteristics in lifting objects with a power assist robot in worst-cases conditions; Proceedings of the IEEE Workshop on Advanced Robotics and Its Social Impacts; Tokyo, Japan. 23&#x2013;25 November 2009; pp. 126&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Zhang T., Huang Y., Liu T., Wang C.C.L. Co-Optimization of Tool Orientations, Kinematic Redundancy, and Waypoint Timing for Robot-Assisted Manufacturing. IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng. 2025;22:12102&#x2013;12117. doi: 10.1109/TASE.2025.3542218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2025.3542218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukhorukov S., Lyamin M. Methodology for Implementing Some of Collaborative Functions on an Industrial Robot; Proceedings of the 2025 International Conference on Industrial Engineering, Applications and Manufacturing (ICIEAM); Sochi, Russia. 12&#x2013;16 May 2025; pp. 637&#x2013;642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou S., Tan R., Zhang Y., Zhou M., Lv C. Personalized Disassembly Sequence Planning for a Human&#x2013;Robot Hybrid Disassembly Cell. IEEE Trans. Ind. Inform. 2024;20:11372&#x2013;11383. doi: 10.1109/TII.2024.3403254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TII.2024.3403254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J.-J., Huang C.-N., Wang H.-W., Shieh P.-H., Hu J.-S. Safety-based human-robot collaboration in cellular manufacturing: A case study of power protector assembly; Proceedings of the 2013 International Conference on Advanced Robotics and Intelligent Systems; Tainan, Taiwan. 31 May&#x2013;2 June 2013; pp. 28&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.-M., Hu J., Posa M. Beyond Inverted Pendulums: Task-Optimal Simple Models of Legged Locomotion. IEEE Trans. Robot. 2024;40:2582&#x2013;2601. doi: 10.1109/TRO.2024.3386390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2024.3386390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper S., Ros R., Lemaignan S., Gebell&#xed; F., Ferrini L., Juri&#x10d;i&#x107; L. Demonstration of an Open-Source ROS 2 Framework and Simulator for Situated Interactive Social Robots; Proceedings of the 2025 20th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI); Melbourne, Australia. 4&#x2013;6 March 2025; pp. 1770&#x2013;1772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J., Moray N. Trust, control strategies and allocation of function in human-machine systems. Ergonomics. 1992;35:1243&#x2013;1270. doi: 10.1080/00140139208967392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140139208967392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1516577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff K.A., Bashir M. Trust in automation: Integrating empirical evidence on factors that influence trust. Hum. Factors. 2015;57:407&#x2013;434. doi: 10.1177/0018720814547570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0018720814547570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25875432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock P.A., Billings D.R., Schaefer K.E., Chen J., Visser E., Parasuraman R. Ameta-analysis of factors affecting trust in human-robot interactions. Hum. Factors. 2011;53:517&#x2013;527. doi: 10.1177/0018720811417254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0018720811417254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22046724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J., Moray N. Trust, self-confidence, and operators&#x2019; adaptation to automation. Int. J. Hum.-Comput. Stud. 1994;40:153&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1006/ijhc.1994.1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/ijhc.1994.1007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng X., Zhang H., Yue L., Song Z., Zhang L., Liu Y.-H. Adaptive Model Predictive Control with Data-driven Error Model for Quadrupedal Locomotion; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA); Yokohama, Japan. 13&#x2013;17 May 2024; pp. 5731&#x2013;5737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai S., Mackenzie C.L., Ivens C.J., Yamamoto T. Worst-case prediction strategy in force programming when visual information is obstructed. Percept. Mot. Ski. 2001;92:1099&#x2013;1108. doi: 10.2466/pms.2001.92.3c.1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2466/pms.2001.92.3c.1099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11565918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim W., Lorenzini M., Balatti P., Nguyen P.D., Pattacini U., Tikhanoff V., Peternel L., Fantacci C., Natale L., Metta G., et al. Adaptable workstations for human-robot collaboration: A reconfigurable framework for improving worker ergonomics and productivity. IEEE Robot. Autom. Mag. 2019;26:14&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1109/MRA.2018.2890460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MRA.2018.2890460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carifio J., Rocco J.P. Ten common misunderstandings, misconceptions, persistent myths and urban legends about Likert scales and Likert response formats and their antidotes. J. Soc. Sci. 2007;3:106&#x2013;116. doi: 10.3844/jssp.2007.106.116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3844/jssp.2007.106.116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M., Sadr B., Wang Y. Trust-based optimal subtask allocation and model predictive control for human-robot collaborative assembly in manufacturing; Proceedings of the ASME Dynamic Systems and Controls Conference; Columbus, OH, USA. 28&#x2013;30 October 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng M., Moon A., Gleeson B., Troniak D., Pan M., Blumer B., Meng M., Croft E. Human behavioural responses to robot head gaze during robot-to-human handovers; Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics; Bali, Indonesia. 5&#x2013;10 December 2014; pp. 362&#x2013;367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman G. Evaluating fluency in human&#x2013;robot collaboration. IEEE Trans. Hum.-Mach. Syst. 2019;49:209&#x2013;218. doi: 10.1109/THMS.2019.2904558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/THMS.2019.2904558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parastegari S., Noohi E., Abbasi B., &#x17d;efran M. Failure Recovery in Robot&#x2013;Human Object Handover. IEEE Trans. Robot. 2018;34:660&#x2013;673. doi: 10.1109/TRO.2018.2819198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2018.2819198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearce M., Mutlu B., Shah J., Radwin R. Optimizing makespan and ergonomics in integrating collaborative robots into manufacturing processes. IEEE Trans. Autom. Sci. Eng. 2018;15:1772&#x2013;1784. doi: 10.1109/TASE.2018.2789820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TASE.2018.2789820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khujamatov K., Reypnazarov E., Khasanov D., Akhmedov N. Networking and computing in internet of things and cyber-physical systems; Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE 14th International Conference on Application of Information and Communication Technologies (AICT); Tashkent, Uzbekistan. 7&#x2013;9 October 2020; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obaid M., Sandoval E.B., Z&#x142;otowski J., Moltchanova E., Basedow C.A., Bartneck C. Stop! That is close enough. How body postures influence human-robot proximity; Proceedings of the 2016 25th IEEE International Symposium on Robot and Human Interactive Communication (RO-MAN); New York, NY, USA. 26&#x2013;31 August 2016; pp. 354&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M. Dynamic affect-based motion planning of a humanoid robot for human-robot collaborative assembly in manufacturing. Electronics. 2024;13:1044. doi: 10.3390/electronics13061044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics13061044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai X., Vitrano G. Evaluating Mental Workload Measures in Human-robot Collaborative Assembly; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM); Bangkok, Thailand. 15&#x2013;18 December 2024; pp. 1059&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M., Liao Z., Jiang L., Wang Y. A regret-based autonomy allocation scheme for human-robot shared vision systems in collaborative assembly in manufacturing; Proceedings of the 2016 IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE); Fort Worth, TX, USA. 21&#x2013;25 August 2016; pp. 897&#x2013;902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M., Ikeura R. Cognition-based variable admittance control for active compliance in flexible manipulation of heavy objects with a power-assist robotic system. Robot. Biomim. 2018;5:7. doi: 10.1186/s40638-018-0090-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40638-018-0090-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6244568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30524934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman S.M.M. Assessment and Benchmark Metrics for Human-Robot Collaborative Object Manipulation Tasks; Proceedings of the 2025 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Technologies for Industrial Automation (ROBOTHIA); Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. 12 April 2025; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S., Vaishnav R., Goswami P. Evaluating Area Coverage Efficiency in Swarm Robotics: A Comparative Study of Different Approaches; Proceedings of the 2025 International Conference on Computer, Electrical &amp; Communication Engineering (ICCECE); Kolkata, India. 7&#x2013;8 February 2025; pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Du Q., Yang G., Chen C.-Y., Wang C., Fang Z. A Review of Compliant Control for Collaborative Robots; Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE 16th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA); Chengdu, China. 1&#x2013;4 August 2021; pp. 1103&#x2013;1108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y., Guo R., Lyu W., Zhang W. Gender effect in human-machine communication: A neurophysiological study. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2024;18:1376221. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2024.1376221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2024.1376221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11270542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39055534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zia A., Haleem M. Bridging research gaps in industry 5.0: Synergizing federated learning, collaborative robotics, and autonomous systems for enhanced operational efficiency and sustainability. IEEE Access. 2025;13:40456&#x2013;40479. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3541822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3541822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintero-Sanchez D.I., De La Garza-Inzunza E.E., Garc&#xed;a-Avila J., Ramirez-Cedillo E. Collaborative smart manufacturing with process operation diagrams: A case study from tec&#x2019;s smart factory; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM); Bangkok, Thailand. 15&#x2013;18 December 2024; pp. 1257&#x2013;1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma D., Zhang C., Zhou G., Xu Q., Li J., Zhao D. A systematic review on vision-based proactive human assembly intention recognition for human-centric smart manufacturing in industry 5.0. IEEE Internet Things J. 2025;12:32493&#x2013;32515. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2025.3570510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3570510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo V., Barbosa J., Mota G., Prieta F.D.L., Leitao P. Design of an ISO 23247 compliant digital twin for an automotive assembly line; Proceedings of the 2024 IEEE 7th International Conference on Industrial Cyber-Physical Systems (ICPS); St. Louis, MO, USA. 12&#x2013;15 May 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>