<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41396089</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-8473</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of perianesthesia nursing : official journal of the American Society of PeriAnesthesia Nurses</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Perianesth Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Operating Room Nurses' Attitudes Toward Patient Safety and Attitudes Toward Preventing Pressure Injuries: Descriptive and Regression Analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1089-9472(25)00425-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jopan.2025.08.008</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study was conducted to determine the relationship between patient safety attitudes of operating room nurses and their attitudes toward&#xa0;the prevention of pressure injuries.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study is a descriptive regression study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study data were collected from 102 nurses working in the operating room of a private hospital between September 2 and October 10, 2024. The sample size, which was known before the study, was determined by power analysis. Data were collected using a personal information form, a patient safety attitude scale, and a pressure ulcer prevention attitude scale. Descriptive statistics (frequencies, percentages, means, and standard deviations) were used to analyze the data. Mann-Whitney U test and Kruskal-Wallis test were used to compare groups. The correlational relationship between the patient safety attitude scale and the pressure injury prevention attitude scale was evaluated by Pearson correlation analysis. The predictors of all subdimensions of the nurses' attitudes toward pressure injury prevention scale were evaluated by stepwise multiple linear regression analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean age of the operating room nurses (56.9%) who participated in the study was between 20 and 30 years, 63.7% were female, 77.5% had a bachelor's degree, 39.2% had worked for less than 5 years, and 92.2% were scrub nurses. A high school education and less than 5 years of experience were found to be negative predictors of attitudes toward pressure injury prevention. Working conditions, job satisfaction, and teamwork subdimensions of the patient safety attitude scale were found to be significant predictors of attitudes toward pressure injury prevention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings of the study revealed that operating room nurses' attitudes toward patient safety and the prevention of pressure injuries were significantly related to variables&#xa0;such as educational level, professional experience, job satisfaction, teamwork, and safety climate.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The American Society of PeriAnesthesia Nurses. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cetinkaya</LastName><ForeName>Melis Merve</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fenerbah&#xe7;e University, Vocational School of Health Services, Operating Room Services Program, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylan</LastName><ForeName>Se&#xe7;il</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgical Nursing Department, Kumluca Faculty of Health Sciences, Akdeniz University, Kumluca, Antalya, Turkey. Electronic address: taylansecil@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eti Aslan</LastName><ForeName>Fatma</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bah&#xe7;e&#x15f;ehir University, Istanbul, Kumluca, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Perianesth Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9610507</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1089-9472</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nurse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">operating room</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pressure injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest None to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41396089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jopan.2025.08.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1089-9472(25)00425-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>