<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41481211</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-1403</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuromodulation : journal of the International Neuromodulation Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuromodulation</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Differential Gamma Responses to Transcutaneous Auricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation Revealed by Human Intracranial Recordings.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1094-7159(25)01185-7</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neurom.2025.11.013</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Vagus nerve stimulation (VNS), along with noninvasive transcutaneous auricular VNS (taVNS), has been the focus of considerable research across numerous indications. However, although invasive VNS literature has explored ways stimulation amplitude influences both physiologic and behavioral outcomes, there is a less robust understanding of taVNS parameter-specific effects on central nervous system activity. The focus of this study was to better understand neurophysiologic responses to multiple taVNS intensities to inform future taVNS work with therapeutic applications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We recorded stereotactic electroencephalography signals from ten patients (six male) with intractable epilepsy (N = 8 included for analysis, four male) while they underwent both active and sham taVNS. Both active and sham stimulation conditions were administered at 30-Hz frequency, 250-&#x3bc;s pulse width, 30-second train with 1-second intertrain interval, for a total duration of 1 minute. Active taVNS amplitudes included 0.5, 1.0, and 1.5 mA whereas sham taVNS was administered at 1.5 mA. High gamma power between 95 and 170 Hz was quantified as the primary indicator of local activity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">High gamma activity was amplitude-dependent, with different taVNS amplitudes producing distinct effects. Active taVNS at 1.0- and 1.5-mA amplitudes caused increased high gamma activity. Furthermore, the increases in high gamma in the orbitofrontal cortex and insula were maintained for significantly greater durations during 1.5-mA active taVNS than during sham. In addition, 0.5-mA stimulation led to moderate suppression of high gamma in certain regions, although further research is needed to investigate brain responses to subthreshold stimulation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">taVNS administered at 1.5-mA amplitude can elicit a sustained high gamma response throughout the course of stimulation in key brain areas implicated in the vagal afferent pathway. Our findings underscore the importance of parameter selection in taVNS protocols given different amplitudes can produce varied effects on brain activity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donovan</LastName><ForeName>Kara M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, USA; Division of Neurotechnology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Gansheng</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, USA; Division of Neurotechnology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Willie</LastName><ForeName>Jon T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Neurosurgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Psychiatry, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Neuroscience, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Neurology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brunner</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, USA; Division of Neurotechnology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Neurosurgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leuthardt</LastName><ForeName>Eric C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, USA; Division of Neurotechnology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Neurosurgery, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Neuroscience, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Department of Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, USA; Center for Innovation in Neuroscience and Technology, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA; Brain Laser Center, Washington University School of Medicine, St. Louis, MO, USA. Electronic address: leuthardte@wustl.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>U24 NS109103</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 NS108916</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 MH122258</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 NS126157</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 EB026439</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21 NS128307</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P41 EB018783</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neuromodulation</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804159</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1094-7159</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrophysiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromodulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stereotactic electroencephalography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">taVNS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vagus nerve</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest Eric C. Leuthardt reports stock ownership in Neurolutions, Face to Face Biometrics, Caeli Vascular, Acera, Sora Neuroscience, Inner Cosmos, Kinetrix, NeuroDev, Inflexion Vascular, Aurenar, Cordance Medical, Silent Surgical, and Petal Surgical; is a consultant for E15, Neurolutions, and Petal Surgical; and is the chief executive officer and cofounder of Aurenar. Washington University owns equity in Neurolutions. The remaining authors reported no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41481211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurom.2025.11.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1094-7159(25)01185-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>