<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41512248</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3708</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of plastic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Plast Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Out of the Laboratory and Into the Clinic: Out-of-Domain Validation of Machine Learning Models for Velopharyngeal Dysfunction Detection.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SAP.0000000000004633</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The diagnosis and management of velopharyngeal dysfunction (VPD) is a particularly challenging part of the cleft care timeline, particularly in resource-limited settings. Although machine learning (ML) models offer promising results as screening tools, their real-world clinical viability has yet to be reliably demonstrated. This study aims to systematically compare the capability of several ML models to detect VPD in nonstandardized conditions to simulate real-world clinical testing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eighty-two patients were enrolled under standardized acoustic conditions and partitioned into an in-domain 60-subject training set and a 22-subject test set. For the out-of-domain test set, audio samples were obtained from publicly available Internet sources. A total of 131 case samples (70 control, 61 case) were obtained from multiple publicly available sources. Recording scenarios were highly variable, nonstandardized and largely not described, thereby introducing extreme heterogeneity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">On the hold-out testing dataset, multiple deep learning models, particularly those using Whisper and HuBERT features, achieved near-perfect performance, with the Whisper/Support Vector Machine (SVM) pipeline reaching 100% accuracy and a 1.0 macro F1-score. The traditional MFCC baseline model also performed exceptionally well, achieving 99.2% accuracy and a 0.95 macro F1-score. Cross-domain generalization testing on the out-of-domain dataset demonstrated severe performance degradation. State-of-the-art deep learning models failed to generalize. The simpler baseline MFCC/SVM pipeline proved to be the most robust in real-world simulation, achieving an accuracy of 64.1% and a macro F1-score of 0.61.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results of this study demonstrate that pretrained ML models can achieve near-perfect VPD detection in highly standardized acoustic environments. However, models are highly susceptible to domain shift caused by variations in recording devices and acoustic environments. Out-of-domain testing results were mediocre but suggest that real-world clinical detection of VPD by ML models is feasible. These results shed light on the difficulties of real-world model generalization and emphasize that for clinically deployable diagnostic tools, cross-domain robustness is as important as, if not more important than, achieving maximal accuracy on a benchmark dataset. The development of a software-based screening tool has the power to improve VPD screening, particularly in low- and middle-income countries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Weixin</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Departments of Electrical Computer Engineering.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qu</LastName><ForeName>Bowen</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Computer Science, Vanderbilt University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stone</LastName><ForeName>Amy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery, Vanderbilt University Medical Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Powell</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery, Vanderbilt University Medical Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dufresne</LastName><ForeName>Shama</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Vanderbilt University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>Stephane</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galdyn</LastName><ForeName>Izabela</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Golinko</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Zhijun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pontell</LastName><ForeName>Matthew E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2329-9899</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Plast Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7805336</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-7043</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Data2Vec</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HuBERT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LMIC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MFCC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wav2Vec 2.0</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XGBoost</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">automated diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cleft palate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interpretable AI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">model bias</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">speech disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">velopharyngeal dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whisper</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest and sources of funding: The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article. This article was funded by the Cleft and Craniofacial Program at Monroe Carell Jr. Children's Hospital and the Department of Plastic Surgery at Vanderbilt University Medical Center.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41512248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SAP.0000000000004633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00000637-990000000-01020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hopper RA, Tse R, Smartt J, et al. Cleft palate repair and velopharyngeal dysfunction. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2014;133:852e&#x2013;864e.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradowska-Stolarz A, Mikulewicz M, Dus-Ilnicka I. Current concepts and challenges in the treatment of cleft lip and palate patients&#x2014;a comprehensive review. J Pers Med. 2022;12:2089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barr L, Thibeault SL, Muntz H, et al. Quality of life in children with velopharyngeal insufficiency. Arch Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2007;133:224&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhuskute A, Skirko JR, Roth C, et al. Association of velopharyngeal insufficiency with quality of life and patient-reported outcomes after speech surgery. JAMA Facial Plast Surg. 2017;19:406&#x2013;412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brydges HT, Laspro M, Verzella AN, et al. Contemporary prevalence of oral clefts in the US: geographic and socioeconomic considerations. J Clin Med. 2024;13:2570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters DH, Garg A, Bloom G, et al. Poverty and access to health care in developing countries. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2008;1136:161&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantoja T, Opiyo N, Lewin S, et al. Implementation strategies for health systems in low-income countries: an overview of systematic reviews. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;9:CD011086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alter N, Stone A, Powell M, et al. It's time to define the global burden of velopharyngeal insufficiency. Cleft Palate Craniofac J Published online January 31, 2025. doi:10.1177/10556656251316084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/10556656251316084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu HC, Zhang YL, Chiang HC. A CNN sound classification mechanism using data augmentation. Sensors (Basel). 2023;23:6972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon H, Chaudhari PK, Dhingra K, et al. Current applications of artificial intelligence in cleft care: a scoping review. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8:676490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baevski A, Zhou H, Mohamed A, et al. wav2vec 2.0: a framework for self-supervised learning of speech representations. Adv Neural Inform Process Syst. 2020;33:12449&#x2013;12460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alter N, Lucas C, Torres-Guzman R, et al. From support vector machines to neural networks: advancing automated velopharyngeal dysfunction detection in patients with cleft palate. Ann Plast Surg. 2025;95(3S Suppl 1):S55&#x2013;S59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas C, Torres-Guzman R, James AJ, et al. Machine learning for automatic detection of velopharyngeal dysfunction: a preliminary report. J Craniofac Surg. 2025;36:816&#x2013;819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu W, Bolte N, Tsai YHH, et al. Hubert: self-supervised speech representation learning by masked prediction of hiden units. IEEE/ACM Transact Audio Speech Lang Process. 2021;29:3451&#x2013;3460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baevski A, Hsu WN, Xu Q, et al. Data2vec: a general framework for self-supervised learning in speech, vision and language. Proc Machine Learn Res. 2022;1298&#x2013;1312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford A, Kim JW, Xu T, et al. Robust speech recognition via large-scale weak supervision. Proc Machine Learn Res. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roland T, Bock C, Tschoellitsch T, et al. Domain shifts in machine learning based Covid-19 diagnosis from blood tests. J Med Syst. 2022;46:23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva GFDS, Barcellos Filho FN, Wichmann RM, et al. Strategies for detecting and mitigating dataset shift in machine learning for health predictions: a systematic review. J Biomed Inform. 2025;170:104902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathad VC, Scherer N, Chapman K, et al. A deep learning algorithm for objective assessment of hypernasality in children with cleft palate. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 2021;68:2986&#x2013;2996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rah DK, Ko YL, Lee C, et al. A noninvasive estimation of hypernasality using a linear predictive model. Ann Biomed Eng. 2001;29:587&#x2013;594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirk MU, Dang C, Cho J, et al. Leveraging large language models for automated detection of velopharyngeal dysfunction in patients with cleft palate. Front Digit Health. 2025;7:1552746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Yang S, Tang M, et al. HypernasalityNet: deep recurrent neural network for automatic hypernasality detection. Int J Med Inform. 2019;129:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank T. ANSI update: maximum permissible ambient noise levels for audiometric test rooms. Am J Audiol. 2000;9:3&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. CDC's Developmental Milestones. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/actearly/milestones/index.html. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastern Ontario Health Unit. Let's talk: tips for building your child's speech and language skills. Available at: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K0aHjxzDb7I. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Cleft Palate Craniofacial Association. Resource center: speech samples, normal and hypernasal speech. Available at: https://acpacares.org/speech-samples/. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fauquier ENT. What is VPI (velopharyngeal insufficiency)? Available at: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WM5fVCdBPHs. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LEADERSproject. Cleft palate speech therapy using books for phrases and sentences. Available at: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1nHhqdCnwBI. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shriners Children's Chicago. New app may help kids with cleft palate speak easier. Available at: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5fubZitvY-Q. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bothell Pediatric and Hand Therapy. Case study: pediatric speech therapy for cleft palate. Available at: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=noUGRjClUg4. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The American Speech-Language-Hearing Association. Evaluation and treatment of resonance disorders and velopharyngeal insufficiency. Available at: https://fb.watch/nBEd3Y93AQ/. Accessed October 20, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly CJ, Karthikesalingam A, Suleyman M, et al. Key challenges for delivering clinical impact with artificial intelligence. BMC Med. 2019;17:195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen ES, Birk-Korch JB, Hansen RS, et al. Monitoring performance of clinical artificial intelligence in health care: a scoping review. JBI Evid Synth. 2024;22:2423&#x2013;2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill BG, Koback FL, Schilling PL. The risk of shortcutting in deep learning algorithms for medical imaging research. Sci Rep. 2024;14:29224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golabbakhsh M, Abnavi F, Kadkhodaei Elyaderani M, et al. Automatic identification of hypernasality in normal and cleft lip and palate patients with acoustic analysis of speech. J Acoust Soc Am. 2017;141:929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey AK, Prasanna SM, Dandapat S. Spectral analysis based objective assessment of hypernasality in cleft palate speech: a review. Circuits Syst Signal Process. 2025;44:4133&#x2013;4166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Yang S, Wang X, et al. Automatic hypernasality grade assessment in cleft palate speech based on the spectral envelope method. Biomed Tech (Berl). 2020;65:73&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang J, Li W, et al. Automatic detection system for velopharyngeal insufficiency based on acoustic signals from nasal and oral channels. Diagnostics (Basel). 2023;13:2714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tracey B, Volfson D, Glass J, et al. Towards interpretable speech biomarkers: exploring MFCCs. Sci Rep. 2023;13:22787.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>