<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41771892</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Persistent semiquinone radicals enable efficient near-infrared-driven H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> photosynthesis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70130-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Photosynthesis of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> under sunlight is a sustainable method; however, most developed photocatalysts utilize limited near-infrared light, which accounts for 52% of the solar spectrum. In typical near-infrared photocatalysts, excited electrons fall into low-energy sub-gap states, reducing the driving force for H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> generation. Here, a polydopamine-loaded porphyrin supramolecular photocatalyst efficiently utilizes near-infrared light for H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> production from H<sub>2</sub>O and O<sub>2</sub>, achieving an apparent quantum yield of 2.8% at 1020&#x2009;nm. This substantial near-infrared utilization significantly boosts activity under full-spectrum irradiation, with an H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> generation rate of 3.37&#x2009;mM/h and solar-to-chemical conversion efficiency of 2.2%. Persistent semiquinone radicals in polydopamine are demonstrated to enable ultrafast sub-gap electron transfer (ca. 79&#x2009;fs) from porphyrin to polydopamine and facilitate near-infrared-driven &#x2022;OOH radical generation, thereby accelerating H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> production. This study sheds light on the potential of near-infrared-responsive photocatalysts and offers insights into optimizing their performance for sustainable H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> synthesis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Dou</LastName><ForeName>Shuai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Material Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Joint Research Center for Photoresponsive Molecules and Materials, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yaning</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Material Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Joint Research Center for Photoresponsive Molecules and Materials, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Food Science and Technology, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6394-3231</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Material Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Joint Research Center for Photoresponsive Molecules and Materials, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lou</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8310-8150</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Material Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Joint Research Center for Photoresponsive Molecules and Materials, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jiawei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Material Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Joint Research Center for Photoresponsive Molecules and Materials, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Yuming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2999-1325</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Material Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Joint Research Center for Photoresponsive Molecules and Materials, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yongfa</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8528-509X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Chengsi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1624-4259</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical and Material Engineering, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China. cspan@jiangnan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Joint Research Center for Photoresponsive Molecules and Materials, Jiangnan University, Wuxi, Jiangsu, China. cspan@jiangnan.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22476071</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41771892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70130-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70130-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Choi, J. et al. Photocatalytic Hydrogen peroxide production through functionalized semiconductive metal-organic frameworks. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 146, 11319&#x2013;11327 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, H., Zeng, X. &amp; Zhang, X. Production of hydrogen peroxide by photocatalytic processes. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 59, 17356&#x2013;17376 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global hydrogen peroxide market forecast to experience a CAGR of 5.1% to 2030. Focus on Catalysts 2020, 3 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos-Martin, J., Blanco-Brieva, G. &amp; Fierro, J. Hydrogen peroxide synthesis: an outlook beyond the anthraquinone process. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 45, 6962&#x2013;6984 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng, Z. et al. Atomically dispersed antimony on carbon nitride for the artificial photosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide. Nat. Catal. 4, 374&#x2013;384 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou, M. et al. Molecularly engineered covalent organic frameworks for hydrogen peroxide photosynthesis. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 61, e202200413 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshikawa, A. et al. Near-infrared light-driven H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> generation via metalloporphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks and nanodisks. ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 7, 9084&#x2013;9088 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou, H. et al. Hydroxyl-bonded Co single atom site on boroncarbonitride surface realizes nonsacrificial H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> synthesis in the near-infrared region. Adv. Mater. 36, e2404851 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> generation from O<sub>2</sub> and H<sub>2</sub>O on a near-infrared absorbing porphyrin supramolecular photocatalyst. Nat. Energy 8, 361&#x2013;371 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, F. et al. Interfacial reaction-induced defect engineering: enhanced visible and near-infrared absorption of wide band gap metal oxides with abundant oxygen vacancies. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 12, 55417&#x2013;55425 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T. et al. Constructing oxygen-related defects in carbon nanodots with Janus optical properties: noninvasive NIR fluorescent imaging and effective photocatalytic therapy. Adv. Mater. 35, e2302705 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H. et al. Hydrogen radical mediated concerted electron&#x2212;proton transfer in 1D sulfone-based covalent organic framework for boosting photosynthesis of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e2025166572025 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraishi, Y. et al. Resorcinol-formaldehyde resins as metal-free semiconductor photocatalysts for solar-to-hydrogen peroxide energy conversion. Nat. Mater. 18, 985&#x2013;993 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao, P. &amp; Hayon, E. Experimental determination of the redox potential of the superoxide radical &#x2022;O<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x2212;</sup>. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 51, 468&#x2013;473 (1973).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petlicki, J. &amp; van de Ven, T. The equilibrium between the oxidation of hydrogen peroxide by oxygen and the dismutation of peroxyl or superoxide radicals in aqueous solutions in contact with oxygen. J. Chem. Soc. Faraday. Trans. 94, 2763&#x2013;2767 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9;s, C. et al. Superoxide anion chemistry&#x2014;its role at the core of the innate immunity. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 24, 1841 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Dopamine-melanin colloidal nanospheres: an efficient near-infrared photothermal therapeutic agent for in vivo cancer therapy. Adv. Mater. 25, 1353&#x2013;1359 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zangmeister, R., Morris, T. &amp; Tarlov, M. Characterization of polydopamine thin films deposited at short times by autoxidation of dopamine. Langmuir. 29, 8619&#x2013;8628 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Y. et al. Reduction of superoxide radical intermediate by polydopamine for efficient hydrogen peroxide photosynthesis. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 63, e202319216 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fei, B. et al. Coating carbon nanotubes by spontaneous oxidative polymerization of dopamine. Carbon 46, 1795&#x2013;1797 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panzella, L. et al. Atypical structural and pi-electron features of a melanin polymer that lead to superior free-radical-scavenging properties. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 52, 12684&#x2013;12687 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey, C. et al. Polydopamine as a visible-light photosensitiser for photoinitiated polymerisation. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 62, e202301678 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Y. &amp; Buettner, G. Thermodynamic and kinetic considerations for the reaction of semiquinone radicals to form superoxide and hydrogen peroxide. Free Radical Biol. Med. 49, 919&#x2013;962 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. et al. Hydrogen atom transfer from HOO&#x2022; to ortho-quinones explains the antioxidant activity of polydopamine. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 60, 15220&#x2013;15224 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Role of polydopamine&#x2019;s redox-activity on its pro-oxidant, radical-scavenging, and antimicrobial activities. Acta Biomater. 88, 181&#x2013;196 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, D. et al. Sustainable hydrogen peroxide production based on dopamine through Janus-like mechanism transition from chemical to photocatalytic reactions. J. Catal. 411, 235&#x2013;244 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaman, H., Baig, M. &amp; Kayan, A. Synthesis and characterization of tetrasubstituted porphyrin Tin(IV) complexes and their adsorption properties over tetracycline antibiotics. Reactions 6, 12 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurochkin, I. et al. Vibrational spectra of 5,10,15,20-Tetraphenylporphyrin (H<sub>2</sub>TPP) and Platinum(II) 5,10,15,20-Tetra(phenyl/pentafluorophenyl)porphyrins (PtTPP and PtTF5PP). Macroheterocycles 14, 334&#x2013;341 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takei, K., Takahashi, R. &amp; Noguchi, T. Correlation between the hydrogen-bond structures and the C&#x2550;O stretching frequencies of carboxylic acids as studied by density functional theory calculations: theoretical basis for interpretation of infrared bands of carboxylic groups in proteins. J. Phys. Chem. B. 112, 6725&#x2013;6731 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasilopoulou, M. et al. Porphyrin oriented self-assembled nanostructures for efficient exciton dissociation in high-performing organic photovoltaics. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2, 182&#x2013;192 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasha, M., Rawls, H. &amp; El-Bayoumi, M. The exciton model in molecular spectroscopy. Pure. Appl. Chem. 11, 371&#x2013;392 (1965).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, Z. et al. Artificial Photosynthesis of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> through reversible photoredox transformation between catechol and o-benzoquinone on polydopamine-coated CdS. ACS Catal. 12, 11436&#x2013;11443 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, J. et al. Supramolecular Zinc porphyrin photocatalyst with strong reduction ability and robust built-in electric field for highly efficient hydrogen production. Adv. Energy Mater. 11, 2101392 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, H. et al. Capacitance methodology for investigating defect states in energy gap of organic semiconductor. Org. Electron. 65, 275&#x2013;299 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian, Z. et al. Near infrared light induced plasmonic hot hole transfer at a nano-heterointerface. Nat. Commun. 9, 2314 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y. et al. Heavily doped carbon nitride nanocrystal promotes visible-near-infrared photosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide with near-unit photon utilization. ACS Nano. 18, 14583&#x2013;14594 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, Y. et al. Long-lived internal charge-separated state in two-dimensional metal-organic frameworks improving photocatalytic performance. ACS Energy Lett. 7, 2323&#x2013;2330 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Delocalized orbitals over metal clusters and organic linkers enable boosted charge transfer in metal-organic framework for overall CO<sub>2</sub> photoreduction. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 63, e202411508 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff, C. et al. All-in-one visible-light-driven water splitting by combining nanoparticulate and molecular co-catalysts on CdS nanorods. Nat. Energy 3, 862&#x2013;869 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao, T. &amp; Tang, J. Characterization of charge carrier behavior in photocatalysis using transient absorption spectroscopy. J. Chem. Phys. 152, 194201 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, H. et al. Efficient photothermal persulfate activation for rapid removal of antibiotics by heat-promoted Co<sup>3+</sup> to Co<sup>2+</sup> conversion on Bi<sub>12</sub>CoO<sub>20</sub> photocatalyst. J. Catal. 428, 115172 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. Visible-light-driven non-oxidative dehydrogenation of alkanes at ambient conditions. Nat. Energy 7, 1042&#x2013;1051 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, L. et al. H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> self-supplied CuFeO<sub>x</sub> nanosystem as fenton-like reaction agents for endogenous/exogenous responsive synergetic antibacterial therapy. Chem. Eng. J. 492, 152265 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, Y., Liu, J. &amp; Han, X. Important contributions of in-situ produced H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> during photocatalytic sterilization of air by self-doped Bi<sub>2.15</sub>WO<sub>6</sub>. Sep. Purif. Technol. 363, 132052 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, price, Sigma-Aldrich, https://www.sigmaaldrich.com/US/en/product/sial/18304, (accessed Jan 06, 2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai, K. et al. Sp<sup>2</sup> C-dominant N-doped carbon sub-micrometer spheres with a tunable size: a versatile platform for highly efficient oxygen-reduction catalysts. Adv. Mater. 25, 998&#x2013;1003 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou, S. et al. Boosting photocatalytic oxygen reduction to hydrogen peroxide via chemisorbed oxygen activation on polydopamine-coated zinc oxide. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 691, 137370 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, C. &amp; Zhu, Y. New type of BiPO<sub>4</sub> oxy-acid salt photocatalyst with high photocatalytic activity on degradation of dye. Environ. Sci. Technol. 44, 5570&#x2013;5574 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, C. et al. Efficient and stable H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> production from H<sub>2</sub>O and O<sub>2</sub> on BiPO<sub>4</sub> photocatalyst. Appl. Catal. B Environ. 316, 121675 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers, R. Spectrophotometric determination of hydrogen peroxide using potassium titanium(IV) oxalate. Analyst 105, 950&#x2013;954 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Facile synthesis of biocompatible cysteine-coated CuS nanoparticles with high photothermal conversion efficiency for cancer therapy. Dalton. Trans. 43, 11709&#x2013;11715 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barros, M. C. F. et al. Diffusion of levodopa in aqueous solutions of hydrochloric acid at 25&#x2009;&#xb0;C. Chem. Thermodyn. 72, 44&#x2013;47 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke, C. &amp; Chang, P. Correlation of diffusion coefficients in dilute solutions. AIChE Journal 1, 264 (1955).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hines, A. &amp; Maddo, R. Mass Transfer: Fundamentals and Applications (Prentice-Hall, 1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnny, L. Development of a model to determine mass transfer coefficient and oxygen solubility in bioreactors. Heliyon. 3, e00248 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan, M. et al. The influence of gas&#x2013;liquid interfacial transport theory on numerical modelling of plasma activation of water. Plasma. Chem. Plasma. Process. 41, 1363 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riet, K. Review of measuring methods and results in nonviscous gas-liquid mass transfer in stirred Vessels. Ind. Eng. Chem. Process Des. Dev. 18, 3 (1979).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delley, B. From molecules to solids with the DMol3 approach. J. Chem. Phys. 113, 7756&#x2013;7764 (2000).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>