<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41656289</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1752-1505</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Conflict and health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Confl Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pathways to self-reliance: a pilot trial of an integrated livelihoods and psychosocial program for displaced women in Colombia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">24</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13031-026-00764-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Forcibly displaced women face intersecting economic and psychosocial risks, yet few rigorously evaluated programs address both simultaneously. This pilot aimed to examine the preliminary feasibility and effects of the Entrepreneurship School with a Gender Lens (ESGL), an 8-9-month hybrid program combining business training, seed capital, and mental health and psychosocial support, could promote self-reliance among forcibly displaced women who have experienced or are at risk of gender-based violence (GBV).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This pilot randomized controlled trial (RCT) was conducted with 253 Venezuelan and Colombian women living in Colombia. Eligible participants scored between 2 and 4.25 on the Self-Reliance Index (SRI) and were randomly assigned in a 2:1 ratio to the intervention (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;175) or control (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;78) group. The intervention included seven group workshops, one individual counselling session, and post-training business plan presentations for seed capital. Outcomes measured at baseline in March 2024 and at 8-9-month follow-up in December 2024 included overall and domain-specific self-reliance (SRI), depressive symptoms measured with the Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9), and resilience measured with the Brief Resilient Coping Scale (BRCS). Analyses used intent-to-treat (ITT) and instrumental variable (IV) regression models controlling for baseline scores and key covariates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">211 out of 253 participants completed both assessments (146 intervention, 65 control). At baseline in March 2024, mean SRI was 3.27 (SD 0.54) in the intervention group and 3.25 (SD 0.52) in the control group. At endline in December 2024, assignment to the intervention was associated with statistically significant positive changes in overall self-reliance (B&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.195, CI 0.026-0.364; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and in the domains of food security, employment, and debt. Effects were stronger among participants who completed the program and received seed capital. No statistically significant effects were observed for depressive symptoms or resilience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ESGL shows preliminary promise in maintaining or improving economic self-reliance among forcibly displaced women in urban Colombia. A fully powered RCT is needed to confirm these initial findings and examine potential mental health effects. Future research should also assess longer-term impacts and optimize delivery in urban humanitarian contexts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stark</LastName><ForeName>Lindsay</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8775-9735</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health at Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA. lindsaystark@wustl.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roa</LastName><ForeName>Arturo Harker</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidad de los Andes, Bogota, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castellar</LastName><ForeName>Diany</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HIAS, Bogota, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monar</LastName><ForeName>Adriana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Corus International, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venegas</LastName><ForeName>Marcela</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HIAS, Bogota, Colombia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leeson</LastName><ForeName>Kellie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Women's Refugee Commission, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebrekidan</LastName><ForeName>Feven</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health at Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meerdink</LastName><ForeName>Ned</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Refugee Self-Reliance Initiative, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seff</LastName><ForeName>Ilana</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health at Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Confl Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101286573</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1752-1505</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic empowerment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Forcibly displaced women</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gender-based violence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Humanitarian settings</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Latin America</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-reliance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Urban displacement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study protocol was reviewed and approved by the Universidad de Los Andes&#x2019; Institutional Review Board (IRB00007443). Participation in this study was entirely voluntary. Data collectors explained the purpose of the study, potential risks and benefits of participation, confidentiality, and other safeguarding procedures, and provided ample time for potential participants to ask any questions. Informed written consent was obtained from all participants who agreed to join the study. All data were anonymized and stored securely to ensure participant confidentiality. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41656289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12983543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13031-026-00764-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13031-026-00764-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>UNHCR. Refugee Data Finder. UNHCR Refugee Statistics. 2025. https://www.unhcr.org/refugee-statistics/insights/explainers/forcibly-displaced-pocs.html. Accessed 15 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlson F, van Ommeren M, Flaxman A, Cornett J, Whiteford H, Saxena S. New WHO prevalence estimates of mental disorders in conflict settings: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet. 2019;394:240&#x2013;8. 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30934-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30934-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klugman J, Ortiz E. Key Development Challenges Around Internal Displacement. World Bank Publications - Books; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Hamad A, Yasin YM, Metersky K. Predictors, barriers, and facilitators to refugee women&#x2019;s employment and economic inclusion: a mixed methods systematic review. PLoS One. 2024;19:e0305463. 10.1371/journal.pone.0305463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0305463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11253926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39018302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buecher B, Aniyamuzaala JR. Women, work &amp; war: Syrian women and the struggle to survive five years of conflict. CARE International; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody C, Hoop T, Vojtkova M, Warnock R, Dunbar M, Murthy P, et al. Economic self-help group programs for improving women&#x2019;s empowerment: a systematic review. Campbell Syst Rev. 2015;11:1&#x2013;182. 10.4073/csr.2015.19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4073/csr.2015.19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinen M, Hoop TD, AIR, Balarin M, Group for the Analysis of Development (GRADE), Alc&#xe1;zar L, et al. Vocational and business training to improve women&#x2019;s labour market outcomes in low- and middle-income countries: a systematic review. 2018th edition. Int Init Impact Evalua (3ie). 2017. 10.23846/SR71094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbar SA, Zaza HI. Evaluating a vocational training programme for women refugees at the Zaatari camp in Jordan: women empowerment: a journey and not an output. Int J Adolesc Youth. 2016;21:304&#x2013;19. 10.1080/02673843.2015.1077716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02673843.2015.1077716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skran C, Easton-Calabria E. Old concepts making new history: refugee self-reliance, livelihoods and the &#x2018;Refugee entrepreneur.&#x2019; J Refug Stud. 2020;33:1&#x2013;21. 10.1093/jrs/fez061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jrs/fez061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Refugee Self-Reliance Initiative, Global Refugee Youth Network and University of Oxford. Refugee Self-Reliance and the Global Compact on Refugees: Unpacking Barriers and Opportunities for Success. Refugee Self-Reliance Initiative, Global Refugee Youth Network and University of Oxford. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeson KC, Slaughter A, Buscher D. Better Lives Now: A Conceptual Framework for Understanding and Measuring Refugee Self-Reliance. Refugee Self-Reliance Initiative. 2022. https://www.refugeeselfreliance.org/resource-database1/2022/the-case-for-measuring-self-reliance. Accessed 15 Sept 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussam R, Kelley EM, Lane G, Zahra F. The psychosocial value of employment: evidence from a refugee camp. Am Econ Rev. 2022;112:3694&#x2013;724. 10.1257/aer.20211616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1257/aer.20211616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seff I, Roa AH, Atwebembere R, Cottle J, Meerdink N, Monar A, et al. Understanding linkages between self-reliance and mental health among forcibly displaced women in Colombia. SSM - Mental Health. 2025;7:100383. 10.1016/j.ssmmh.2024.100383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssmmh.2024.100383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slaughter AG. Fostering refugee self-reliance: a case study of an agency&#x2019;s approach in Nairobi. J Refug Stud. 2020;33:107&#x2013;24. 10.1093/jrs/fez060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jrs/fez060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annan J, Falb K, Kpebo D, Hossain M, Gupta J. Reducing PTSD symptoms through a gender norms and economic empowerment intervention to reduce intimate partner violence: a randomized controlled pilot study in C&#xf4;te D&#x2019;Ivoire. Glob Ment Health (Camb). 2017;4:e22. 10.1017/gmh.2017.19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/gmh.2017.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5719471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29230318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs A, Corboz J, Chirwa E, Mann C, Karim F, Shafiq M, et al. The impacts of combined social and economic empowerment training on intimate partner violence, depression, gender norms and livelihoods among women: an individually randomised controlled trial and qualitative study in Afghanistan. BMJ Glob Health. 2020;5:e001946. 10.1136/bmjgh-2019-001946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2019-001946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7076232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32201622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNHCR. Colombia. Global Focus. 2024. https://reporting.unhcr.org/operational/operations/colombia. Accessed 15 Apr 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNHCR. Colombia emergency. UNHCR US. 2025. https://www.unhcr.org/us/emergencies/colombia-emergency. Accessed 25 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabir R, Klugman J. Unlocking Refugee Women&#x2019;s Potential. Int Rescue Com. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pineros-Leano M, Agarwal-Harding P, Ruscitti B, V&#xe9;lez-Grau C, Costas-Rodr&#xed;guez B, P&#xe9;rez-Flores N, et al. Mental health of female Venezuelan migrant caregivers in Colombia: a multi-study, mixed-methods analysis. Cambridge Prisms: Global Mental Health. 2025;12:e103. 10.1017/gmh.2025.10056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/gmh.2025.10056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12455508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40994840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair VG, Wallston KA. The development and psychometric evaluation of the brief resilient coping scale. Assess. 2004;11:94&#x2013;101. 10.1177/1073191103258144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1073191103258144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14994958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trejos Herrera AM, Alarc&#xf3;n Y, Baham&#xf3;n Mu&#xf1;et&#xf3;n MJ, Vinnacia Alpi S, Gonz&#xe1;lez Guti&#xe9;rrez O, Llin&#xe1;s Solano H, et al. Validaci&#xf3;n de las propiedades psicom&#xe9;tricas de la escala breve de estrategias resilientes en adultos colombianos. Interdisciplinaria Revista de Psicolog&#xed;a y Ciencias Afines. 2023;40:479&#x2013;96. 10.16888/interd.2023.40.2.28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16888/interd.2023.40.2.28</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Suaza A, Mondrag&#xf3;n-Mayo A, Sarango-Iturralde A. Occupational downgrading of Venezuelan migrants in Colombia: Do work permits Improve occupational mobility? Documentos de Trabajo. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CALP Network. The Impact of Business Cash Grants on Venezuelan Migrants&#x2019; Livelihoods in Peru. The CALP Network. 2025. https://www.calpnetwork.org/publication/the-impact-of-business-cash-grants-on-venezuelan-migrants-livelihoods-in-peru/. Accessed 15 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahrens A, Beerli A, Hangartner D, Kurer S, Siegenthaler M. The Labor Market Effects of Restricting Refugees&#x2019; Employment Opportunities. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardila Vargas LK, D&#xe1;valos ME, Garc&#xed;a-Suaza AF. Barriers to the Integration of Venezuelan Migrants and Refugees in Colombia: Policy Lessons from the Migration Pulse Survey. World Bank&#x2013;UNHCR Joint Data Center Forced Displace. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNHCR. A data-driven look at how promoting employment fosters refugee mental health. 2024. https://www.unhcr.org/blogs/a-data-driven-look-at-how-promoting-employment-fosters-refugee-mental-health/. Accessed 15 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunselman AR. A brief overview of pilot studies and their sample size justification. Fertil Steril. 2024;121:899&#x2013;901. 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2024.01.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2024.01.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11128343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38331310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass J, Murray S, Cole G, Bolton P, Poulton C, Robinette K, et al. Economic, social and mental health impacts of an economic intervention for female sexual violence survivors in Eastern Democratic Republic of Congo. Glob Ment Health. 2016;3:e19. 10.1017/gmh.2016.13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/gmh.2016.13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5314746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green EP, Blattman C, Jamison J, Annan J. Does poverty alleviation decrease depression symptoms in post-conflict settings? A cluster-randomized trial of microenterprise assistance in Northern Uganda. Glob Ment Health. 2016;3:e7. 10.1017/gmh.2015.28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/gmh.2015.28</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5314750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalra N, Habumugisha L, Shankar A. Impacts of an abbreviated personal agency training with refugee women and their male partners on economic empowerment, gender-based violence, and mental health: a randomized controlled trial in Rwanda. BMC Public Health. 2024;24:1306. 10.1186/s12889-024-18780-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-18780-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11092213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38745312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>