<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41351161</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors associated with disaster nursing competence among emergency department nurses: the roles of disaster preparedness, self-efficacy, and communication ability.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-025-04198-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Disasters are increasing owing to climate change and urban overcrowding, and emergency department nurses play a pivotal role in disaster response. Understanding the factors associated with disaster nursing competence is essential to enhance preparedness and response capacity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional survey was conducted with emergency department nurses from one regional medical centre and three local emergency medical centres in South Korea between 15 July and 10 August 2023. Validated instruments were used to assess disaster experience, disaster preparedness, self-efficacy, communication ability, and disaster nursing competence. Data were analysed using correlation and hierarchical regression analyses. In Model 1, general characteristics (e.g. age, marital status, emergency department experience, job position) were entered; in Model 2, additional variables (disaster experience, disaster preparedness, self-efficacy, and communication ability) were added.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean disaster nursing competence score was 50.65 out of 75. In Model 1, age, marital status, and emergency department experience were significantly associated with disaster nursing competence (adjusted R&#xb2; = 0.30). After adding disaster preparedness, self-efficacy, and communication ability, the explanatory power increased to 62%, representing a 32% improvement (&#x394; adjusted R&#xb2; = 0.32). In the final model, disaster preparedness (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.42, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), self-efficacy (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.15, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.016), and communication ability (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.15, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.025) remained significantly associated with disaster nursing competence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Given that disaster preparedness showed the strongest association, institutional investment in systematic, continuous, and practice-based disaster education and drills should be considered a central strategy for strengthening emergency department nurses' competence and overall emergency response capacity. In addition, given the demonstrated contributions of self-efficacy and communication ability, institutions should incorporate structured programmes and interprofessional exercises that enhance nurses' confidence and communication skills.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noh</LastName><ForeName>Gyu Bong</ForeName><Initials>GB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ajou University Hospital, Suwon, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Ajou University, Suwon, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bae</LastName><ForeName>Sun Hyoung</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Research Institute of Nursing Science, Ajou University, Suwon, South Korea. shyoung@ajou.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical competence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disaster nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disaster planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emergency nurses</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-efficacy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board of Ajou University Hospital (Approval No: AJOUIRB-SBR-SUR-2022-033). All procedures were conducted per the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants before data collection. Consent for publication: The participants provided consent for anonymised data to be used for publication. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41351161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12798075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-04198-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-025-04198-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. Climate change 2021: the physical science basis. Contribution of working group I to the sixth assessment report of the IPCC. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Council of Nurses. ICN framework of disaster nursing competencies. Geneva: ICN; 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27646611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Council of Nurses. Core competencies in disaster nursing: version 2.0. Geneva: ICN; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Thobaity A. Overcoming challenges in nursing disaster preparedness and response: an umbrella review. BMC Nurs. 2024;23(1):562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-024-02226-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11323674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39143575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams LM, Melius J. Prepared to respond? Exploring personal disaster preparedness and nursing staff response to disasters. Disaster Med Public Health Prep. 2021;15(5):557&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/dmp.2020.47</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32375915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy JP, Kurland L, R&#xe5;destad M, Magnusson S, Ringqvist T, R&#xfc;ter A. Emergency department registered nurses overestimate their disaster competency: a cross-sectional study. Int Emerg Nurs. 2021;58:101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ienj.2021.101019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34333331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrague LJ, Hammad K. Disaster preparedness among nurses in disaster-prone countries: a systematic review. Australas Emerg Care. 2024;27(2):88&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.auec.2023.09.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37778913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh JY. Nurse&#x2019;s perception and core competencies on disaster nursing [Master&#x2019;s thesis]. Seoul: Yonsei University; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sook Jung K, Ha Ji H. Trends of nursing research on disasters for nursing students in korea: a systematic review. J Korean Public Health Nurs. 2022;36(1):90&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park YM, Hwang WJ. Development and effect of a simulation-based disaster nursing education program for nursing students using standardized patients. J Nurs Res. 2024;32(1):e314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/jnr.0000000000000596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38265077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benner P. From novice to expert: excellence and power in clinical nursing practice. Menlo Park: Addison-Wesley; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy: the exercise of control. New York: Worth; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huh SS, Kang HY. Effects of an educational program on disaster nursing competency. Public Health Nurs. 2019;36(1):28&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/phn.12557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30397963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S, Choi H, Kim M. Factors influencing nurses&#x2019; disaster preparedness and experience in regional hospitals. Korean J Adult Nurs. 2022;34(5):487&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Yang L, Cao X, Ren Y, Han X, Zang S, et al. Assessment of disaster preparedness and related impact factors among emergency nurses in tertiary hospitals: a descriptive cross-sectional study from Henan Province, China. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1093959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2023.1093959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10192630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37213610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hur GH. Development of a scale for interpersonal communication competence. Korean J Journalism Commun Stud. 2003;47(6):380&#x2013;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nejadshafiee M, Bahaadinbeigy K, Kazemi M, Nekoei-Moghadam M. Telenursing in incidents and disasters: a systematic review. J Emerg Nurs. 2020;46(5):611&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jen.2020.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32360295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiessling A, Amiri C, Arhammar J, Lundb&#xe4;ck M, Wallingstam C, Wikner J, et al. Interprofessional simulation-based team training and self-efficacy in emergency medicine situations. J Interprof Care. 2022;36(6):873&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820.2022.2038103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35341425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Kim SO. Effects on triage competency based on nursing task performance and self-efficacy of nurses in regional emergency medical institutions. Korean J Adult Nurs. 2022;34(3):304&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7475/kjan.2022.34.3.304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chegini Z, Arab-Zozani M, Kakemam E, Lotfi M, Nobakht A, Aziz Karkan H. Disaster preparedness and core competencies among emergency nurses: a cross-sectional study. Nurs Open. 2022;9(2):1294&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.1172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8859035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34985209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam J, Park H. Association of disaster perception, attitudes, and communication skills with disaster nursing competence among nurse officers. J Korean Acad Fundam Nurs. 2022;29(2):202&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7739/jkafn.2022.29.2.202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park YJ, Lee EJ. A study on ego-resilience, disaster experience, and core competencies among emergency room nurses. J Korean Clin Nurs Res. 2015;21(1):67&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrague LJ, Kamanyire JK, Achora S, Wesonga R, Malik A, Al Shaqsi S. Predictors of disaster response self-efficacy among nurses in Oman. Int J Disaster Risk Reduct. 2021;61:102300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijdrr.2021.102300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;ahin NE, Karaca T. Disaster response self-efficacy and preparedness levels of Turkish nurses: a cross-sectional study. BMC Emerg Med. 2025;25(1):158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12873-025-01299-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12366231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40830827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkin &#xd6;, Kiyan SG. How does integrating &#x2018;disaster nursing&#x2019; into nursing curricula impact nursing students&#x2019; disaster literacy and preparedness? BMC Nurs. 2025;24(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-024-02478-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11697737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39754162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement. PLoS Med. 2007;4(10):e296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.0040296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2020495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17941714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh J, Oh EG, Kim SS, Jang YS, Chung HS, Lee O. Needs assessment for training in disaster preparedness for hospital nurses: a modified Delphi study. Nurs Adm Q. 2018;42(4):373&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NAQ.0000000000000309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30180084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Gully SM, Eden D. Validation of a new general self-efficacy scale. Organ Res Methods. 2001;4(1):62&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/109442810141004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh I. General self-efficacy: concept, measurement issues, and HRM implications. Korean J Ind Organ Psychol. 2002;15(3):49&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin RB, Martin MM, Bruning SS, Power DE. Interpersonal communication competence: Scale development and test of a self-efficacy model. In: Annual Conference of the Speech Communication Association; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J, Cohen P, West SG, Aiken LS. Applied multiple regression/correlation analysis for the behavioral sciences. Mahwah: Erlbaum; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallant J. SPSS survival manual. New York: Routledge; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu D, Li Y, Chen Q, Ke J, Fan Y, Sheng X, et al. Status and influencing factors of clinical nurses&#x2019; disaster nursing competency: a multicenter cross-sectional study. BMC Nurs. 2025;24(1):376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-03026-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11971766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40188344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiao CC, Huang CY, Lai FC, Chen TL, Cheng SF. Development and evaluation of an immersive cinematic escape room for disaster preparedness and self-efficacy among nurses. Clin Simul Nurs. 2024;91:101541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecns.2024.101541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molin I, Fornander L, Berggren P. An analysis of trauma team communication using the verbal response mode taxonomy. Surgery. 2021;170(6):1849&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surg.2021.05.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CW, Lin CW, Huang CY, Hsu CW, Sung HY, Cheng SF. Effectiveness of a virtual reality chemical disaster training program in emergency nurses: a quasi-experimental study. Nurse Educ Today. 2022;119:105613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2022.105613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36327790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>