<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41832534</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-799X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic surgery and research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Surg Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Web-based education enhances self-care agency, self-efficacy, and quality of life in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13018-026-06779-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Total knee arthroplasty plays a pivotal role in restoring patients' quality of life; however, challenges related to postoperative adaptation and self-care remain significant. Integrating technology into patient education through web-based and mobile application-supported interventions has emerged as an innovative approach to strengthen recovery and enhance patient outcomes. This study aimed to evaluate the impact of a web-based education (WBE) program on self-care power, self-efficacy, and quality of life in patients undergoing total knee arthroplasty.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This prospective, two-group clinical trial was conducted between January and October 2024 at the Orthopedics and Traumatology Clinic of a city hospital. A total of 67 patients were assigned to either the WBE group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;33) or the control group (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;34). The control group received standard unstructured discharge education, whereas the WBE group received the same education plus a one-month web-based education program using a mobile application starting on the 15th day post-discharge. Data were collected via the Self-Care Agency Scale (SCAS), the Self-Efficacy Scale (SES), and the Short Form-36 Health Survey (SF-36) at 15 days and one-month post-discharge.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">No significant baseline differences were observed between the WBE and control groups (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). After the intervention, the WBE group showed significantly greater improvements in self-care agency, self-efficacy, and quality of life compared with the control group (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Mixed-design ANOVA demonstrated significant group&#xd7;time interaction effects for all outcomes, with large effects for self-care agency (&#x3b7;p&#xb2;=0.703-0.827) and moderate to large effects for self-efficacy (&#x3b7;p&#xb2; = 0.435-0.719) and SF-36 quality-of-life subdimensions (&#x3b7;p&#xb2;=0.451-0.713).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Web-designed education via mobile applications was shown to be effective in improving the self-care power and self-efficacy and increasing the quality of life of patients undergoing TKA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study was registered in the ClinicalTrials.gov database as (NCT06306027) Protocol Registration and Results System.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bozta&#x15f;</LastName><ForeName>Esra Nur</ForeName><Initials>EN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6266-2833</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Health Sciences University Konya City Hospital, Konya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sayar</LastName><ForeName>Serap</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4195-0320</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, KTO Karatay University Health Sciences Faculty, Konya, Turkey. oranserap@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sayar</LastName><ForeName>Ferhat</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0084-2414</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Traumatology, Health Sicences University, Konya City Hospital, Konya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06306027</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Surg Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101265112</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1749-799X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Internet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mobile application</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient education as topic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-efficacy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: The study was approved KTO Karatay University Drug and Non-Medical Device Research Ethics Committee (approval number 2023/024, approval date June 22, 2023). Participation was voluntary, and written informed consent was obtained from all participants. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41832534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-026-06779-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13018-026-06779-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Milliren CE, Lindsay B, Biernat L, Smith TA, Weaver B. Can digital engagement improve outcomes for total joint replacements? Digit Health 2022;8(1):16. https://doi.org/10.1177/20552076221095322</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OECD, Hip, Replacement K. Health at a Glance 2023: OECD Indicators. OECD Publishing, Paris 118&#x2013;20. https://www.oecd.org/en/publications/health-at-a-glance-2023_7a7afb35-en.html ; 2023 [Retrieved May 19, 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar&#x131;s A, Ozturkmen Y. Complications after total knee arthroplasty. J TOTB&#x130;D. 2021;20:589&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.14292/totbid.dergisi.2021.91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricciardi BF, Oi KK, Daines SB, Lee YY, Joseph AD, Westrich GH. Patient and perioperative variables affecting 30-day readmission for surgical complications after hip and knee arthroplasties: a matched cohort study. J Arthroplast. 2017;32(4):1074&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arth.2016.10.019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu VJ, Ross BJ, Sanchez FL, Billings CR, Sherman WF. Complications following total hip arthroplasty: a nationwide database study comparing elective vs hip fracture cases. J Arthroplast. 2020;35(8):2144&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arth.2020.03.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayar S, Sayar F. Postdischarge learning needs of patients who had undergone orthopedic surgery. Gevher Nesibe J Med Health Sci. 2023;8:797&#x2013;807. https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8404201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;y&#xfc;kyilmaz F, Ozdemir NG. A new life with total hip and knee replacement: key concepts in patient education. Inonu Univ J Health Serv Vocat School. 2018;6(2):86&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdi A, Svantesson M, Wretenberg P, H&#xe4;lleberg-Nyman M. Patients&#x2019; experiences of discontentment one year after total knee arthroplasty-a qualitative study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2020;14(1):29. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891-020-3041-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya C, Bilik O. Why should consultancy be offered to the patients scheduled for total knee artroplasty? J Nurs Sci. 2020;3(1):25&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi M, Hiyama Y, Kamitani T, Kubo M, Kawasaki T, Wada O, et al. Comparison of recovery of mobility and self-efficacy after total knee arthroplasty based on two different protocols: a prospective cohort study. Mod Rheumatol. 2020;30(1):197&#x2013;203. https://doi.org/10.1080/14397595.2018.1553228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canovas F, Dagneaux L. Quality of life after total knee arthroplasty. Orthop Traumatol: Surg Res. 2018;104(1):41&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.otsr.2017.04.017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinci M, Kapucu S. Total hip or knee prosthesis in older women with osteoarthritis determination of pain, functional status and daily livin&#x11f; activities. Osmangazi J Med. 2020;42(4):434&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.20515/otd.554098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akyuz E, Unlu H, Ugurlu Z, Ozhan Elbas N. Psychosocial problems and changes in quality of life experienced by patients who underwent orthopedic surgery. Health Soc J. 2021;31(3):79&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askari A, Mohammadpour M, Jabalameli M, Naeimipoor N, Goodarzy B, Jafari B. et. al. Predictors of health-related quality of life after total knee arthroplasty: a case-control study. Sci Rep. 2024;19(1):14176. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-65042-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva RR, Santos AA, de Sampaio Carvalho J&#xfa;nior J, Matos MA. Quality of life after total knee arthroplasty: systematic review. Rev Bras Ortop. 2014;19(5):520&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rboe.2014.09.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cetinkaya Eren O, Buker N, Tonak HA, Urguden M. The effect of video-assisted discharge education after total hip replacement surgery: a randomized controlled study. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):3067. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-07146-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdogan EG, Orsal O. Asthma management effectiveness of web-based education. J Nursology. 2022;25(1):54&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.54614/JANHS.2022.936868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avci A, Gun M. The effect of web-based education on the management of cardiovascular diseases. J Adnan Menderes Univ Health Sci Fac. 2021;5(2):389&#x2013;403. https://doi.org/10.46237/amusbfd.799106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eck CF, Toor A, Banffy MB, Gambardella RA. Web-based education prior to outpatient orthopedic surgery enhances early patient satisfaction scores: a prospective randomized controlled study. Orthop J Sports Med. 2018;6(1):2325967117751418. https://doi.org/10.1177/2325967117751418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildiz E, Karagozoglu S. The effects of a web-based interactive nurse support program based on the health promotion model on healthy living behaviors and self-efficacy in patients who regained weight after bariatric surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Obes Surg. 2023;33(10):3212&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-023-06795-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang E, Gillespie BM, Tobiano G, Chaboyer W. Development of a web-based discharge education intervention to improve the postdischarge recovery of general surgical patients. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2022;54(2):143&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1111/jnu.12717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langarizadeh M, Moghbeli F, Ahmadi S, Langarizadeh MH, Sayadi M, Sarpourian F, et al. Design and evaluation of an educational mobile program for liver transplant patients. BMC Health Serv Res. 2023;23(1):974. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12913-023-09989-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson MM, Rantala A, Miettunen J, Puhto AP, Pikkarainen M. The effects and safety of telerehabilitation in patients with lower-limb joint replacement: a systematic review and narrative synthesis. J Telemed Telecare. 2022;28(2):96&#x2013;114. https://doi.org/10.1177/1357633X20917868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozden F, Sari Z. The effect of mobile application-based rehabilitation in patients with total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archger.2023.105058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekkers T, Melles M, Groeneveld BS, de Ridder H. Web-based patient education in orthopedics: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2018;20(4):e143. https://doi.org/10.2196/jmir.9013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkurt B, Utkan A. Surgical site problems and superficial infection after primary total knee arthroplasty. J TOTB&#x130;D. 2019. https://doi.org/10.14292/totbid.dergisi.2019.15. 18:128&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rainey JP, Blackburn BE, Campbell KJ, Anderson LA, Gililland JM. Patient engagement Platforms: how technology is impacting perioperative communication and engagement in total hip and knee arthroplasty. Arthroplasty Today. 2024;27:101349. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.artd.2024.101349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahcivan NO. A Turkish language equivalence of the exercise of self-care agency scale. West J Nurs Res. 2004;26(7):813&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/10.1177/0193945904267599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gozum S, Aksayan S. The reliability and validity of Turkish form of the self-efficacy scale. Atat&#xfc;rk Univ School Nurs J. 1999;2(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE, Sherbourne CD. The MOS 36-item short-form health survey (SF-36): I. Conceptual framework and item SelectionMed. Care. 1992;30(6):473&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocyigit H. Reliability and validity of the Turkish version of the Short Form-36 (SF-36). J Med Treat. 1999;12(2):102&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadioglu B, Akman B, Gulcin S, Ozkurt G. Pain control and rehabilitation after total knee arthroplasty. J TOTB&#x130;D. 2021;20:581&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.14292/totbid.dergisi.2021.90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miettinen HJ, M&#xe4;kirinne-Kallio N, Kr&#xf6;ger H, Miettinen SS. Health-related quality of life after hip and knee arthroplasty operations. Scand J Surg. 2021;110(3):427&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1177/1457496920952232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzel K, Azboy &#x130;. Prevention, diagnosis and treatment methods of infections after total knee arthroplasty. J TOTB&#x130;D. 2021;20:603&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.14292/totbid.dergisi.2021.93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polit DF, Beck CT. The content validity index: are you sure you know what&#x2019;s being reported? Critique and recommendations. Res Nurs Health. 2006;29(5):489&#x2013;97. https://doi.org/10.1002/nur.20147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmers T, Janssen L, Van der Weegen W, Das D, Marijnissen WJ, Hannink G, et al. The effect of an app for day-to-day post-operative care education on patients with total knee replacement: randomized controlled trial. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2019;7(10):e15323. https://doi.org/10.2196/15323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umapathy H, Bennell K, Dickson C, Dobson F, Fransen M, Jones G, et al. The web-based osteoarthritis management resource my joint pain improves quality of care: a quasiexperimental study. J Med Internet Res. 2015;17(7):e167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Gu Z, Ning R, Yin H. Study on the effect of internet plus continuous nursing on functional recovery and medication compliance of patients with knee joint replacement. J Orthop Surg Res. 2023;18(1):424. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13018-023-03907-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de la Gonz&#xe1;lez &#xc1;, Garc&#xed;a P&#xe9;rez de Sevilla G, Dom&#xed;ngez Balmaseda D, Mart&#xed;n Vera D, Montero Mart&#xed;nez M, Del Blanco Muniz JA. Relationship between self-efficacy and headache &#x131;mpact, anxiety, and physical activity levels in patients with chronic tension&#x2010;type headache: an observational study. Behav Neurol. 2022;2022(1):8387249. https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/8387249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Akker-Scheek I, Stevens M, Groothoff JW, Bulstra SK, Zijlstra W. Preoperative or postoperative self-efficacy: which is a better predictor of outcome after total hip or knee arthroplasty? Patient Educ Couns. 2007;66(1):92&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2006.10.012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter SN, Johnson AH, Brennan JC, Dolle SS, Turcotte JJ, King PJ. The efficacy of telemedicine versus in-person education for high-risk patients undergoing unilateral total joint arthroplasty. J Arthroplast. 2023;38(7):1230&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arth.2023.01.015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HN, Luo P, Liu S, Liu Y, Zhang X, Li J. Effectiveness of internet-based telehealth programs in patients with hip or knee osteoarthritis: systematic review and Meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2024;30:26: e55576. https://doi.org/10.2196/55576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R, Cheng L, Zheng Q, Lv Y, Wang YM, Ni M, et al. A smartphone application-based remote rehabilitation system for posttotal knee arthroplasty rehabilitation: a randomized controlled trial. J Arthroplast. 2024;39(3):575&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arth.2023.08.019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Lee RL, Hunter S, Zhu A, Chan SW. Patient engagement in a mobile app&#x2013;based rehabilitation program for total hip or knee arthroplasty: secondary data analysis of a randomized controlled trial. JMIR mHealth uHealth. 2024;12(1):e57635. https://doi.org/10.2196/57635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biricik B, Ugra&#x15f; GA, Unal R, Donmez SC, Tasdelen B, et al. The effect of video-assisted education on knee function and quality of life after total knee replacement: a randomized controlled trial. J Nursology. 2024;27(3):171&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.17049/jnursology.1418019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turhan Damar H, Bilik O. Effects of video-based education program on pain, physical funct&#x131;on, and qual&#x131;ty of life in patients with total knee replacement. J Inonu Univ Health Serv Vocat School. 2022. https://doi.org/10.33715/inonusaglik.1026363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichler S, Salzwedel A, Rabe S, Mueller S, Mayer F, Wochatz M, et al. The effectiveness of telerehabilitation as a supplement to rehabilitation in patients after total knee or hip replacement: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Rehabilit Assist Technol. 2019;6(2):e14236. https://doi.org/10.2196/14236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement ND, Weir D, Deehan D. Meaningful values in the short form health survey-36 after total knee arthroplasty: an alternative to the EuroQol five-dimension index as a measure for health-related quality of life. Bone Joint Res. 2022;11(7):477&#x2013;83. https://doi.org/10.1302/2046-3758.117.BJR-2021-0493.R1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keurentjes JC, Fiocco M, Nelissen RG. Willingness to undergo surgery again validated clinically important differences in health-related quality of life after total hip replacement or total knee replacement surgery. J Clin Epidemiol. 2014;67(1):114&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.04.010.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>