<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41829620</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Survey on Reconnaissance Autonomous Robotic Systems for Disaster Management.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1659</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26051659</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Systems that operate in dangerous environments are becoming essential in case of emergencies. This survey reviews the latest ground reconnaissance robots using computer vision (CV), machine learning (ML), MCU-based control, LoRa communication, DC motors, and dual-power systems. The analysis includes hardware and algorithms, and their performance in the field and lab. There has been clear progress in navigation, sensor fusion, and situational awareness. The main challenges which remain include the use of energy and standardization of benchmarks. This survey focuses exclusively on Unmanned Ground Vehicles (UGVs) for disaster reconnaissance, examining recent advances in hardware, software, and autonomy. The survey highlights the improvements in navigation, sensor fusion, and intelligence, and identifies remaining challenges such as energy limitations, robustness in harsh conditions, and the lack of standardized benchmarks. The analysis synthesizes findings from over 190 recent studies (2020-2025) in ground-based disaster robotics, providing a comprehensive overview of current capabilities and research gaps. It encapsulates all issues with their remedy for future disaster-response systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinha</LastName><ForeName>Sahaj</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AI and Big Data, Endicott College, Woosong University, Daejeon 34606, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sinjae</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer and Software Major, School of IT Convergence, Woosong University, Daejeon 34606, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Saurabh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1118-9569</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AI and Big Data, Endicott College, Woosong University, Daejeon 34606, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025-RISE-06-009</GrantID><Agency>Regional Innovation System &amp; Education (RISE)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arduino control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LoRa communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UGV</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomous robotics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">computer vision</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disaster management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ground reconnaissance systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41829620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12986560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26051659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26051659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Girma A., Bahadori N., Sarkar M., Tadewos T.G., Behnia M.R., Mahmoud M.N., Karimoddini A., Homaifar A. IoT-enabled autonomous system collaboration for disaster-area management. IEEE/CAA J. Autom. Sin. 2020;7:1249&#x2013;1262. doi: 10.1109/JAS.2020.1003291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JAS.2020.1003291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy R.R., Kravitz J., Stover S.L., Shoureshi R. Mobile robots in mine rescue and recovery. IEEE Robot. Autom. Mag. 2009;16:91&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1109/MRA.2009.932521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MRA.2009.932521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyanov Y., Petrov O., Georgieva T. 2025 34th Annual Conference of the European Association for Education in Electrical and Information Engineering (EAEEIE) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2025. A review of ground-based robotic systems for search and rescue; pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebastin J.S., Sivaraman, Kuberaganapathi V.K. A Comprehensive Review on Robotics in Disaster Response and Recovery. Integr. AI Sustain. Disaster Manag. Build. Resil. Prev. Catastr. 2026;2026:369&#x2013;392. doi: 10.1002/9781394271603.ch15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781394271603.ch15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z.-Q., Zheng P., Xu S.-T., Wu X. Object detection with deep learning: A review. IEEE Trans. Neural Netw. Learn. Syst. 2019;30:3212&#x2013;3232. doi: 10.1109/TNNLS.2018.2876865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNNLS.2018.2876865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30703038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amanatiadis A.A., Chatzichristofis S.A., Charalampous K., Doitsidis L., Kosmatopoulos E.B., Tsalides P., Gasteratos A., Roumeliotis S.I. A multi-objective exploration strategy for mobile robots under operational constraints. IEEE Access. 2013;1:691&#x2013;702. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2013.2283031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2013.2283031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghamry K.A., Kamel M.A., Zhang Y. 2016 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2016. Cooperative forest monitoring and fire detection using a team of UAVs-UGVs; pp. 1206&#x2013;1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanan M.G., Salgaonkar A. Probabilistic approach to robot motion planning in dynamic environments. SN Comput. Sci. 2020;1:181. doi: 10.1007/s42979-020-00185-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42979-020-00185-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., Shrestha S. Integrating HCI Principles in AI: A Review of Human-Centered Artificial Intelligence Applications and Challenges. J. Future Artif. Intell. Technol. 2024;1:309&#x2013;317. doi: 10.62411/faith.3048-3719-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62411/faith.3048-3719-47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casper J., Murphy R. Human-robot interactions during the robot-assisted urban search and rescue response at the world trade center. IEEE Trans. Syst. Man Cybern. Part B (Cybern.) 2003;33:367&#x2013;385. doi: 10.1109/TSMCB.2003.811794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSMCB.2003.811794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18238185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu S.-A., Yu C., Gao F., Wu Y., Wang Y. Flightbench: Benchmarking learning-based methods for ego-vision-based quadrotors navigation. IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett. 2025;10:6888&#x2013;6895. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2025.3573167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2025.3573167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonin-Font F., Ortiz A., Oliver G. Visual navigation for mobile robots: A survey. J. Intell. Robot. Syst. 2008;53:263&#x2013;296. doi: 10.1007/s10846-008-9235-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10846-008-9235-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Shen Y., Zhou W., Zou Y., Zhou C., He S. 2024 5th International Conference on Mechatronics Technology and Intelligent Manufacturing (ICMTIM) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2024. Adaptive speed planning for unmanned vehicle based on deep reinforcement learning; pp. 642&#x2013;645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez I., Flores J., Salazar S., Lozano R. Robust and Precise Navigation and Obstacle Avoidance for Unmanned Ground Vehicle. Sensors. 2025;25:4334. doi: 10.3390/s25144334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25144334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12299314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40732461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redmon J., Farhadi A. Yolov3: An incremental improvement. arXiv. 2018 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767.1804.02767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.1804.02767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M., Seo K.-H., Suh J.-H. Research trends on disaster response robots. J. Korean Soc. Precis. Eng. 2019;36:331&#x2013;337. doi: 10.7736/KSPE.2019.36.4.331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7736/KSPE.2019.36.4.331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegwart R., Nourbakhsh I.R., Scaramuzza D. Introduction to Autonomous Mobile Robots. MIT Press; Cambridge, MA, USA: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micire M.J. Evolution and field performance of a rescue robot. J. Field Robot. 2008;25:17&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1002/rob.20218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rob.20218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacoff A., Messina E., Evans J.  Proceedings 2001 Performance Metrics for Intelligent Systems (PerMIS) Workshop, Mexico City, Mexico, 4 September 2001. National Institute of Standards and Technology; Gaithersburg, MD, USA: 2001.  [(accessed on 21 February 2026)]. Experiences in Deploying Test Arenas for Autonomous Mobile Robots. Available online:  https://tsapps.nist.gov/publication/get_pdf.cfm?pub_id=821638.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Birchfield S.T. Qualitative vision-based path following. IEEE Trans. Robot. 2009;25:749&#x2013;754. doi: 10.1109/TRO.2009.2017140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2009.2017140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satishkumar D., Sivaraja M., editors. Internet of Things and AI for Natural Disaster Management and Prediction. IGI Global; Hershey, PA, USA: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., Chen C., Sagoe-Crentsil K., Zhang J., Duan W. Intelligent robotic systems for structural health monitoring: Applications and future trends. Autom. Constr. 2022;139:104273. doi: 10.1016/j.autcon.2022.104273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autcon.2022.104273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xfc;ger J., Lien T., Verl A. Cooperation of human and machines in assembly lines. CIRP Ann. 2009;58:628&#x2013;646. doi: 10.1016/j.cirp.2009.09.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cirp.2009.09.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadena C., Carlone L., Carrillo H., Latif Y., Scaramuzza D., Neira J., Reid I., Leonard J.J. Past, present, and future of simultaneous localization and mapping: Toward the robust-perception age. IEEE Trans. Robot. 2017;32:1309&#x2013;1332. doi: 10.1109/TRO.2016.2624754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2016.2624754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z., Shen H., Han X., Jin H., Ye K., Shimada K. LV-DOT: LiDAR-visual dynamic obstacle detection and tracking for autonomous robot navigation. arXiv. 20252502.20607</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee S., Zunjani F.H., Nandi G.C. Real-time object detection and recognition on low-compute humanoid robots using deep learning. arXiv. 20202002.03735</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heshmat M., Saoud L.S., Abujabal M., Sultan A., Elmezain M., Seneviratne L., Hussain I. Underwater SLAM Meets Deep Learning: Challenges, Multi-Sensor Integration, and Future Directions. Sensors. 2025;25:3258. doi: 10.3390/s25113258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25113258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12157327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40968800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan T., Englot B. 2018 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2018. Lego-loam: Lightweight and ground-optimized lidar odometry and mapping on variable terrain; pp. 4758&#x2013;4765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geiger A., Lenz P., Urtasun R. 2012 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition. IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2012. Are we ready for autonomous driving? The kitti vision benchmark suite; pp. 3354&#x2013;3361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stachniss C. Photogrammetrie und Fernerkundung: Handbuch der Geod&#xe4;sie, herausgegeben von Willi Freeden und Reiner Rummel. Springer; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 2017. Simultaneous Localization and Mapping; pp. 293&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Xu Q., Li Z., Xu C., Li K. Cooperative Safety Intelligence in V2X-Enabled Transportation: A Survey. arXiv. 20252512.00490</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuru K. Planning the future of smart cities with swarms of fully autonomous unmanned aerial vehicles using a novel framework. IEEE Access. 2021;9:6571&#x2013;6595. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3049094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3049094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kofod-Petersen A. How to Do a Structured Literature Review in Computer Science. Oct, 2012.  [(accessed on 15 December 2025)].  Version 0.1. Available online:  https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Anders-Kofod-Petersen/publication/265158913_How_to_do_a_Structured_Literature_Review_in_computer_science/links/599a00350f7e9b3edb17cda2/How-to-do-a-Structured-Literature-Review-in-computer-science.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golroudbari A.A., Sabour M.H. Recent advancements in deep learning applications and methods for autonomous navigation: A comprehensive review. arXiv. 2023 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2302.11089.2302.11089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2302.11089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corke P.I., Jachimczyk W., Pillat R. Robotics, Vision and Control: Fundamental Algorithms in MATLAB. Volume 73 Springer; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr J., Dutta A. Multi-agent deep reinforcement learning for multi-robot applications: A survey. Sensors. 2023;23:3625. doi: 10.3390/s23073625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23073625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10098527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37050685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaker R.K. Robotics in disaster management: AI-driven rescue, aerial mapping, and emerging IoT applications for effective response. Int. J. Innov. Res. Eng. Multidiscip. Phys. Sci. 2024;12:231435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao P. Ph.D. Dissertation. University of California; San Diego, CA, USA: 2024. Design, Deployment, Navigation, and Control of Mobile Robots for Perception and Sensor Data Collection.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo W., Ebel H., Eberhard P. An LSTM-based approach to precise landing of a UAV on a moving platform. Int. J. Mech. Syst. Dyn. 2022;2:99&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1002/msd2.12036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/msd2.12036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negi P., Pathani A., Bhatt B.C., Swami S., Singh R., Gehlot A., Thakur A.K., Gupta L.R., Priyadarshi N., Twala B., et al. Integration of industry 4.0 technologies in fire and safety management. Fire. 2024;7:335. doi: 10.3390/fire7100335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fire7100335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A., Kim S.J. Real-Time Map Generation by VLP-16 LiDAR sensor in GPS denied environment. Penins. Int. J. Innov. Sustain. 2025;3:628626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#xe9;pez-Ponce D.F., Montalvo W., Guam&#xe1;n-Gavilanes X.A., Echeverr&#xed;a-Cadena M.D. Route Optimization for UGVs: A Systematic Analysis of Applications, Algorithms and Challenges. Appl. Sci. 2025;15:6477. doi: 10.3390/app15126477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15126477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalakrishnan A., Ramya G., Preethiya T., Paranthaman R.N., Ashwini S., Dhwarithaa R. Advancements in Multi-Agent Large Language Model Systems for Next-Generation AI. IGI Global Scientific Publishing; Hershey, PA, USA: 2026. Advancements in Multi-Agent Large Language Model Systems for Next-Generation AI: Multi-Agent LLMs in Healthcare and Diagnostics; pp. 33&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saputra R.P., Alattar A., Rijanto E., Taqriban R.B., Septevani A.A., Rakicevic N., Kormushev P. Rescue Robots for Casualty Extraction: A Comprehensive Review. IEEE Access. 2025;13:209164&#x2013;209196. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3637567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3637567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahia H.S., Mohammed A.S. Path planning optimization in unmanned aerial vehicles using meta-heuristic algorithms: A systematic review. Environ. Monit. Assess. 2023;195:30. doi: 10.1007/s10661-022-10590-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-022-10590-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36282405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dritsas E., Trigka M. Machine Learning in Information and Communications Technology: A Survey. Information. 2024;16:8. doi: 10.3390/info16010008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info16010008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siami M., Barszcz T., Zimroz R. Advanced Image Analytics for Mobile Robot-Based Condition Monitoring in Hazardous Environments: A Comprehensive Thermal Defect Processing Framework. Sensors. 2024;24:3421. doi: 10.3390/s24113421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24113421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11174847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38894210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edlinger R. Ph.D. Dissertation. Bayerische Julius-Maximilians-Universitaet; Wuerzburg, Germany: 2025. Robust Mobility and Manipulation for Flexible and Modular Robot Assistants.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeown C. Designing for situation awareness: An approach to user-centered design. Ergonomics. 2013;56:727&#x2013;728. doi: 10.1080/00140139.2013.793052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140139.2013.793052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Commey D., Mai B., Hounsinou S.G., Crosby G.V. Securing Blockchain-Based IoT Systems: A Review. IEEE Access; New York, NY, USA: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaka S. Taxonomic Robot Identifiers: Toward General Classification and Oversight for Autonomous Systems. IEEE Access. 2025;13:101801&#x2013;101816. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3578870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3578870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon M.L., Khan M.N., Shaikh A.A. Industry 5.0: Human-robot interaction, smart manufacturing, and ai/ml integration&#x2014;A comprehensive review for next-generation manufacturing systems. Spectr. Eng. Sci. 2025;3:1889&#x2013;1928.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafique T., Gantassi R., Soliman A.-H., Amjad A., Hui Z.-Q., Choi Y. A review of Energy Hole mitigating techniques in multi-hop many to one communication and its significance in IoT oriented Smart City infrastructure. IEEE Access. 2023;11:121340&#x2013;121367. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3327311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3327311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamrani A., Rayhan M., Mackenson T., McDaniel D., Lagos L. Smart quadruped robotics: A systematic review of design, control, sensing and perception. Adv. Robot. 2025;39:3&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1080/01691864.2024.2411684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01691864.2024.2411684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravichandran Z., Cladera F., Hughes J., Murali V., Hsieh M.A., Pappas G.J., Taylor C.J., Kumar V. Deploying Foundation Model-Enabled Air and Ground Robots in the Field: Challenges and Opportunities. arXiv. 2025 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2505.09477.2505.09477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2505.09477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahavandi S., Alizadehsani R., Nahavandi D., Mohamed S., Mohajer N., Rokonuzzaman M., Hossain I. A comprehensive review on autonomous navigation. ACM Comput. Surv. 2025;57:1&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1145/3727642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3727642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan R., Ji B., Gao Y., Tao H. A review of LiDAR simultaneous localization and mapping techniques for multi-robot. Robotica. 2025;43:3200&#x2013;3240. doi: 10.1017/S0263574725102178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0263574725102178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabrielli S., Riva G., Cattaneo L., Corno M., Savaresi S.M. 2025 European Control Conference (ECC) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2025. A fast LiDAR registration algorithm for autonomous racing: Track constrained Generalized Iterative Closest Point (tc-GICP) pp. 1755&#x2013;1760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu H., Zhang K., Tan A.H., Ruan M., Agia C.G., Nejat G. A sim-to-real pipeline for deep reinforcement learning for autonomous robot navigation in cluttered rough terrain. IEEE Robot. Autom. Lett. 2021;6:6569&#x2013;6576. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2021.3093551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LRA.2021.3093551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizk Y., Awad M., Tunstel E.W. Cooperative heterogeneous multi-robot systems: A survey. ACM Comput. Surv. (CSUR) 2019;52:29. doi: 10.1145/3303848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3303848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Mei L., Liu R., Jiang W., Yin Z., Deng X., He T. Multi-modal fusion sensing: A comprehensive review of millimeter-wave radar and its integration with other modalities. IEEE Commun. Surv. Tutor. 2024;27:322&#x2013;352. doi: 10.1109/COMST.2024.3398004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/COMST.2024.3398004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei H., Lou B., Zhang Z., Liang B., Wang F.-Y., Lv C. Autonomous navigation for eVTOL: Review and future perspectives. IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh. 2024;9:4145&#x2013;4171. doi: 10.1109/TIV.2024.3352613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIV.2024.3352613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya &#xd6;. Data-Driven Methodology for Emergency Rescue Station Placement: Geographic Information Systems based Multi Criteria Decision Making Approach. Recep Tayyip Erdogan Univ. J. Sci. Eng. 2025;6:659&#x2013;684. doi: 10.53501/rteufemud.1611414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53501/rteufemud.1611414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M.L., Zhang Z. The YOLO framework: A comprehensive review of evolution, applications, and benchmarks in object detection. Computers. 2024;13:336. doi: 10.3390/computers13120336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/computers13120336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zheng S., Yang Z., Guo J., Yang Z., Hong J. A global and local agent-based curriculum reinforcement learning approach for multi-end-effector robotic arm manipulation. Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell. 2026;163:113121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S., Wang C., Yang Z., Yuan H., Sun A., Xie H., Zhang L., Fang Y. 2020 5th International Conference on Universal Village (UV) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2020. Evaluation of smart humanity systems and novel UV-oriented solution for integration, resilience, inclusiveness and sustainability; pp. 1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza A., Flores E. Pruning and Quantization of Deep Learning Models for Arduino-Compatible MCUs. Microprocess. Microsyst. 2024;106:105022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chellapandi V.P., Yuan L., Brinton C.G., &#x17b;ak S.H., Wang Z. Federated learning for connected and automated vehicles: A survey of existing approaches and challenges. IEEE Trans. Intell. Veh. 2023;9:119&#x2013;137. doi: 10.1109/TIV.2023.3332675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIV.2023.3332675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joice A., Tufaique T., Tazeen H., Igathinathane C., Zhang Z., Whippo C., Hendrickson J., Archer D. Applications of Raspberry Pi for Precision Agriculture&#x2014;A Systematic Review. Agriculture. 2025;15:227. doi: 10.3390/agriculture15030227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture15030227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Q., Shi Y., Li M. A review of computer vision-based crack detection methods in civil infrastructure: Progress and challenges. Remote Sens. 2024;16:2910. doi: 10.3390/rs16162910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16162910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi W., Chen C., Li K., Xiong Y., Cao X., Zhou Z. LangLoc: Language-Driven Localization via Formatted Spatial Description Generation. IEEE Trans. Image Process. 2025;34:1737&#x2013;1752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40067730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M.M.S., Yadav H., Soman D., Kumar A. 2020 14th International Conference on Innovations in Information Technology (IIT) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2020. Acoustic Localization for Autonomous Unmanned Systems; pp. 69&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesti T., Boddana S., Yaman B. Ultra-sonic sensor based object detection for autonomous vehicles; Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition; Vancouver, BC, Canada. 18&#x2013;22 June 2023; pp. 210&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong A.W.-L., Goh S.L., Hasan M.K., Fattah S. Multi-hop and mesh for LoRa networks: Recent advancements, issues, and recommended applications. ACM Comput. Surv. 2024;56:1&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1145/3638241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3638241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stateczny A., Gierlowski K., Hoeft M. Wireless local area network technologies as communication solutions for unmanned surface vehicles. Sensors. 2022;22:655. doi: 10.3390/s22020655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22020655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8779497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35062622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigley M., Conley K., Gerkey B., Faust J., Foote T., Leibs J., Wheeler R., Ng A.Y. ROS: An open-source Robot Operating System. ICRA Workshop Open Source Softw. 2025;3:e12010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Yu C., Xu X., Gao Y., Yang X., Tang W., Yu S., Chen Y., Gao F., Jian Z., et al. Multi-Robot System for Cooperative Exploration in Unknown Environments: A Survey. arXiv. 2025 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2503.07278.2503.07278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2503.07278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng Y., Nie W., Liu Z., Zhang H., Zhou H., Liu Z., Liu H. Biomimetic Robotics and Intelligence: A Survey. SmartBot. 2025;1:e12010. doi: 10.1002/smb2.12010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smb2.12010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gul O.M. Energy-Aware 3D Path Planning by Autonomous Ground Vehicle in Wireless Sensor Networks. World Electr. Veh. J. 2024;15:383. doi: 10.3390/wevj15090383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/wevj15090383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Zhang R., Sun J. Developing real-time IoT-based public safety alert and emergency response systems. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:29056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12334619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40781521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abruzzo B., Cappelleri D.J., Mordohai P. Comparing Complementary Kalman Filters Against SLAM for Collaborative Localization of Heterogeneous Multirobot Teams. J. Auton. Veh. Syst. 2022;2:021001. doi: 10.1115/1.4054817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4054817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan T.B. Human&#x2013;robot interaction: Status and challenges. Hum. Factors. 2016;58:525&#x2013;532. doi: 10.1177/0018720816644364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0018720816644364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hachemi L., Guiatni M., Nemra A. Fault diagnosis and reconfiguration for mobile robot localization based on multi-sensors data fusion. Unmanned Syst. 2022;10:69&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1142/S2301385022500042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S2301385022500042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M.-F.R., Nugroho A. 2020 International Conference on Sustainable Energy Engineering and Application (ICSEEA) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2020. Energy management system for sustainable operation of robot in disaster response; pp. 22&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekinci S., Izci D., Yilmaz M. Efficient speed control for DC motors using novel gazelle simplex optimizer. IEEE Access. 2023;11:105830&#x2013;105842. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3319596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3319596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chariev M., Ashyrmuhammedov U. Gear Systems in Robots: Torque, Speed, and Efficiency.  [(accessed on 15 December 2025)];Obrazovanie i Nauka v XXI Veke. 2025 61 Available online:  https://mpcareer-google.ru/index.php/journal/article/view/1646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Rozas S., Alejo D., Carpio J.J., Caballero F., Merino L. Long-Duration Inspection of GNSS-Denied Environments with a Tethered UAV-UGV Marsupial System. Drones. 2025;9:765. doi: 10.3390/drones9110765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones9110765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., You Y., Zhang X., Fang H., Wang J., Huang X. Origami Inspired Soft Robotic Arm: A Modular Platform for Manipulation. 2025.  [(accessed on 15 December 2025)].  Available online:  https://softroboticsforspace.eu/images/paper-submissions/Fang-ICRA2025-Soft-Robotics-for-Space-Applications.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan R., Malik F.M., Raza A., Mazhar N. Comprehensive study of skid-steer wheeled mobile robots: Development and challenges. Ind. Robot: Int. J. Robot. Res. Appl. 2021;48:142&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1108/IR-04-2020-0082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IR-04-2020-0082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu S., Ota K., Dong M. Energy-efficient artificial intelligence of things with intelligent edge. IEEE Internet Things J. 2022;9:7525&#x2013;7532. doi: 10.1109/JIOT.2022.3143722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2022.3143722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serebrennyi V., Boshliakov A., Ovsiankin G. MATEC Web of Conferences. Volume 161. EDP Sciences; Les Ulis, France: 2018. Active stabilization in robotic vision systems; p. 03019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam R. Parallel Computing Architectures for Robotic Applications: A Comprehensive Review. arXiv. 2024 doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2407.01011.2407.01011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2407.01011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banbury C., Zhou C., Fedorov I., Matas R., Thakker U., Gope D., Reddi V.J., Mattina M., Whatmough P. Micronets: Neural network architectures for deploying tinyml applications on commodity microcontrollers. Proc. Mach. Learn. Syst. 2021;3:517&#x2013;532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondal S., Ramasamy S., Humann J.D., Dotterweich J.M., Reddinger J.-P.F., Childers M.A., Bhounsule P. 2024 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2024. A robust uav-ugv collaborative framework for persistent surveillance in disaster management applications; pp. 1239&#x2013;1246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Guo J., Chen K., Lu J. An in-depth examination of SLAM methods: Challenges, advancements, and applications in complex scenes for autonomous driving. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 2025;26:11066&#x2013;11087. doi: 10.1109/TITS.2025.3545479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2025.3545479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messina E., Jacoff A. Unmanned Systems Technology VIII. Volume 6230. SPIE; Berlin, Germany: 2006. Performance standards for urban search and rescue robots; pp. 639&#x2013;650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerolimos N., Alevizos V., Edralin S., Xu C., Priniotakis G., Papakostas G.A., Yue Z. Autonomous Decision-Making Enhancing Natural Disaster Management through Open World Machine Learning: A Systematic Review. Hum.-Centric Intell. Syst. 2025;5:269&#x2013;284. doi: 10.1007/s44230-025-00098-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44230-025-00098-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matuszek C., Williams T., DePalma N., Mead R., Wen R., Schneiders E., Kennington C., Bezabih A. Reporting Guidelines for Large Language Models in Human-Robot Interaction. ACM Trans. Hum.-Robot Interact. 2026;15:1&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1145/3777552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3777552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nohel J., Stodola P., Zezula J., Flasar Z., Hrdinka J. International Conference on Modelling and Simulation for Autonomous Systems. Springer Nature; Cham, Switzerland: 2023. Challenges associated with the deployment of autonomous reconnaissance systems on future battlefields; pp. 176&#x2013;197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vimos V., Sacoto E., Morales D.X. 2016 IEEE International Conference on Automatica (ICA-ACCA) IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2016. Conceptual architecture definition: Implementation of a network sensor using Arduino devices and multiplatform applications through OPC UA; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatzopoulos A., Tzerachoglou A., Priniotakis G., Papoutsidakis M., Drosos C., Symeonaki E. Using stem to educate engineers about sustainability: A case study in mechatronics teaching and building a mobile robot using upcycled and recycled materials. Sustainability. 2023;15:15187. doi: 10.3390/su152115187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su152115187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuru K., Khan W. A framework for the synergistic integration of fully autonomous ground vehicles with smart city. IEEE Access. 2020;9:923&#x2013;948. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3046999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3046999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mankins J.C.  Technology Readiness Levels: A White Paper. Advanced Concepts Office, Office of Space Access and Technology, National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); Washington, DC, USA: 1995.  [(accessed on 15 December 2025)].  Edited 22 December 2004. Available online:  http://www.artemisinnovation.com/images/TRL_White_Paper_2004-Edited.pdf.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>