<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41455042</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Force and Power Testing During Anterior Cruciate Ligament Reconstruction Rehabilitation: A World-Wide Survey of Current Practices.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02374-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">During rehabilitation, the importance of restoring strength and power in a stage-based framework highlights the paramount role of testing and monitoring. Despite theoretical understanding of an optimal recovery pathway, it is unclear and inconsistent as to how practitioners implement force and power assessment following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction (ACLR).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We aimed to examine current worldwide practices with evaluating patients post-ACLR, identify the relative utilisation of different devices and methodologies across the rehabilitation process, and to explore the interactions between the implemented devices and respondents' self-perceived testing quality (evaluated by participants via a Likert scale).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data were collected via an international online survey composed of 100 items, organised across 12 sections, exploring the demographics of respondents and implemented testing devices to assess individuals after ACLR and their perceived testing quality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 1154 practitioners from 78 different countries completed the survey. According to the pre-defined eight categories, 157 different combinations were recorded among practitioners. Respondents tended to use multiple devices (95.8%), with a mean of 3.6&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.4. Patient assessments were most often repeated longitudinally throughout the recovery process post-ACLR (96.4%). Specific devices were used as part of "criteria-based" testing by 46.4% of respondents, "criteria- and time-based" testing by 30.8% and solely "time-based" testing by 21.9%. A significant but weak direct correlation was observed between the number of implemented devices and self-perceived testing quality (&#x3c1;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.32, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), with force plates, an isokinetic dynamometer, Nordic hamstrings device and a hand-held dynamometer significantly associated with increased self-perceived testing quality (R<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.21, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A high degree of variability in test device implementation existed among practitioners. According to the eight pre-defined device categories, over 150 different device combinations were recorded among respondents. Device use was different throughout the stages of rehabilitation and testing was primarily performed as criteria to advance patients throughout the recovery process. While acknowledging that these findings may be influenced by self-serving bias, they suggest that practitioners involved in force and power testing post-ACLR may benefit from implementing a wide range of devices, including more quantitative and objective instruments such as force plates and the isokinetic dynamometer, as these appeared to be related to higher levels of self-perceived testing quality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Compagnin</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-2345-4945</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education and Research Department, Isokinetic Medical Group, FIFA Medical Centre of Excellence, Bologna, Italy. a.compagnin@isokinetic.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Isokinetic Medical Group, FIFA Medical Centre of Excellence, London, UK. a.compagnin@isokinetic.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Technology and Health Science, St Mary's University, Twickenham, London, UK. a.compagnin@isokinetic.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Della Villa</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9379-6666</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education and Research Department, Isokinetic Medical Group, FIFA Medical Centre of Excellence, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>La Rosa</LastName><ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6327-8769</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education and Research Department, Isokinetic Medical Group, FIFA Medical Centre of Excellence, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patterson</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4667-9939</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Technology and Health Science, St Mary's University, Twickenham, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Read</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1508-8602</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sports Institute, Middlesex University Dubai, Dubai, UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Surgery and Interventional Science, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise, University of Gloucestershire, Gloucester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herrington</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4732-1955</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Society, University of Salford, Salford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Paolo</LastName><ForeName>Stefano</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1761-7352</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education and Research Department, Isokinetic Medical Group, FIFA Medical Centre of Excellence, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedic and Traumatology II Clinic, IRCCS Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Senorski</LastName><ForeName>Eric Hamrin</ForeName><Initials>EH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9340-0147</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Physiotherapy, Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Myer</LastName><ForeName>Gregory D</ForeName><Initials>GD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory Sports Performance And Research Center (SPARC), Flowery Branch, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wallace H. Coulter Department of Biomedical Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology &amp; Emory University, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Micheli Center for Sports Injury Prevention, Waltham, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davison</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Football Research Group, Link&#xf6;ping, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hughes</LastName><ForeName>Mick</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>North Queensland Physiotherapy Centre, Townsville, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buckthorpe</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4925-4031</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Education and Research Department, Isokinetic Medical Group, FIFA Medical Centre of Excellence, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Isokinetic Medical Group, FIFA Medical Centre of Excellence, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, Technology and Health Science, St Mary's University, Twickenham, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: Alessandro Compagnin, Francesco Della Villa, Giovanni La Rosa, Stephen Patterson, Paul Read, Lee Herrington, Stefano Di Paolo, Eric Hamrin Senorski, Gregory D. Myer, Mike Davison, Mick Hughes and Matthew Buckthorpe have no conflicts of interest that are directly relevant to the content of this article. Ethics Approval: Ethics approval was obtained from the STHS Ethics Committee of St Mary&#x2019;s University, Twickenham, London, UK (SMU_ETHICS_2023-24_366). Consent to Participate: Participants were informed about the nature of the study, the research team, the data management process and additional information via the participants information sheet, a downloadable document included in the first page of the survey. Key information was also summarised in the survey&#x2019;s opening page, where participants were encouraged to download and carefully read the information sheet before participating. Collecting a written consent would have required participants to disclose personal identifiers information such as their name, compromising in this way the anonymity of the survey. Therefore, consent was implied through the voluntary completion and submission of the survey rather than being collected in written form. Consent for Publication: Not applicable. Availability of Data and Material: The dataset collected and analysed during the study are not publicly available. However, because of the anonymous nature of the survey, the data are completely anonymised and can be made available by the corresponding author in the case of a reasonable request. Code Availability: Not applicable. Authors&#x2019; Contributions: AC, SP and MB contributed to the study conception and design. Material preparation was addressed by AC and MB, with a revision by all the other authors. The whole team was involved in the distribution of the survey. AC, MB and SdP supported the analysis and interpretation of results. The first draft of the manuscript was written by AC and MB, and all authors commented on previous versions of the manuscript. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41455042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02374-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02374-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Taylor NF, Feller JA, Webster KE. Fifty-five per cent return to competitive sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis including aspects of physical functioning and contextual factors. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(21):1543&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2013-093398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies GJ, McCarty E, Provencher M, Manske RC. ACL return to sport guidelines and criteria. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2017;10(3):307&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5577421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12178-017-9420-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filbay SR, Ackerman IN, Dhupelia S, Arden NK, Crossley KM. Quality of life in symptomatic individuals after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction, with and without radiographic knee osteoarthritis. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2018;48(5):398&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29669490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2018.7830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzat AM, Brussoni M, M&#xe2;sse LC, Emery CA. Effect of anterior cruciate ligament rupture on physical activity, sports participation, patient-reported health outcomes, and physical function in young female athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(6):1460&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33830821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465211002530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caumeil B, Laboute E, Verhaeghe E, P&#xe9;rez S, D&#xe9;camps G. Reinjury anxiety and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a cluster analysis and prospective study among 162 athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52(5):1189&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38520139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465241234887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culvenor AG, Patterson BE, Guermazi A, et al. Accelerated return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction and early knee osteoarthritis features at 1 year: an exploratory study. PM&amp;R. 2018;10(4):349&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmrj.2017.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Webster KE, Taylor NF, Feller JA. Return to the preinjury level of competitive sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: two-thirds of patients have not returned by 12 months after surgery. Am J Sports Med. 2011;39(3):538&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546510384798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wald&#xe9;n M, H&#xe4;gglund M, Magnusson H, Ekstrand J. Acl injuries in men&#x2019;s professional football: a 15-year prospective study on time trends and return-to-play rates reveals only 65% of players still play at the top level 3 years after acl rupture. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(12):744&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27034129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J, Krutsch W, Spreco A, et al. Time before return to play for the most common injuries in professional football: a 16-year follow-up of the uefa elite club injury study. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(7):421&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31182429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-100666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grindem H, Snyder-Mackler L, Moksnes H, Engebretsen L, Risberg MA. Simple decision rules can reduce reinjury risk by 84% after acl reconstruction: the Delaware-Oslo ACL cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):804&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27162233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins AJ, Grandhi RK, Schneider DK, et al. Risk of secondary injury in younger athletes after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(7):1861&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26772611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5501245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515621554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Merchan EC, Valentino LA. Return to sport activities and risk of reinjury following primary anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arch Bone Jt Surg. 2022;10(8):648&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36258743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9569141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Melick N, van Cingel RE, Brooijmans F, et al. Evidence-based clinical practice update: practice guidelines for anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation based on a systematic review and multidisciplinary consensus. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1506&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27539507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diermeier TA, Rothrauff BB, Engebretsen L, et al. Treatment after ACL injury: Panther symposium ACL treatment consensus group. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(1):14&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-102200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Gokeler A, Herrington L, et al. Optimising the early-stage rehabilitation process post-ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2024;54(1):49&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37787846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01934-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Della Villa F. Optimising the &#x2018;mid-stage&#x2019; training and testing process after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2020;50(4):657&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31782065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01222-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M. Optimising the late-stage rehabilitation and return-to-sport training and testing process after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2019;49(7):1043&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31004279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01102-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardern CL, Glasgow P, Schneiders A, et al. 2016 consensus statement on return to sport from the First World Congress in Sports Physical Therapy, Bern. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(14):853&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-096278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Frizziero A, Roi GS. Update on functional recovery process for the injured athlete: return to sport continuum redefined. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(5):265&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30269097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrosimone B, Lepley AS, Harkey MS, et al. Quadriceps strength predicts self-reported function post-ACL reconstruction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(9):1671&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27054675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angelozzi M, Madama M, Corsica C, et al. Rate of force development as an adjunctive outcome measure for return-to-sport decisions after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(9):772&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.3780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Morris N, Lane M, et al. Monitoring the return to sport transition after ACL injury: an alpine ski racing case study. Front Sports Act Living. 2020;2:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7739580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2020.00012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyritsis P, Bahr R, Landreau P, Miladi R, Witvrouw E. Likelihood of ACL graft rupture: not meeting six clinical discharge criteria before return to sport is associated with a four times greater risk of rupture. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(15):946&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27215935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronstr&#xf6;m A, H&#xe4;ger CK, Thorborg K, Ageberg E. Factors associated with sports function and psychological readiness to return to sports at 12 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a cross-sectional study. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51(12):3112&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37681565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10543957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465231192983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri-Smith RM, Lepley LK. Quadriceps strength asymmetry after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction alters knee joint biomechanics and functional performance at time of return to activity. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43(7):1662&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25883169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4758854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546515578252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;iestad BE, Juhl CB, Eitzen I, Thorlund JB. Knee extensor muscle weakness is a risk factor for development of knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2015;23(2):171&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25450853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2014.10.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owoeye OBA, Rauvola RS, Brownson RC. Dissemination and implementation research in sports and exercise medicine and sports physical therapy: translating evidence to practice and policy. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2020;6(1):e000974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33304607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7704287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2020-000974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg EM, Greenberg ET, Albaugh J, Storey E, Ganley TJ. Rehabilitation practice patterns following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a survey of physical therapists. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2018;48(10):801&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29787697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2018.8264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maestroni L, Read P, Turner A, Korakakis V, Papadopoulos K. Strength, rate of force development, power and reactive strength in adult male athletic populations post anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction&#x2014;a systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;47:91&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33232907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2020.11.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Read P, Mc Auliffe S, Wilson MG, Myer GD. Better reporting standards are needed to enhance the quality of hop testing in the setting of ACL return to sport decisions: a narrative review. Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(1):23&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32522734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chechik O, Amar E, Khashan M, et al. An international survey on anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction practices. Int Orthop. 2013;37(2):201&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22782378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-012-1611-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold MP, Calcei JG, Vogel N, et al. Acl study group survey reveals the evolution of anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction graft choice over the past three decades. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29(11):3871&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33486558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-021-06443-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korakakis V, Kotsifaki A, Korakaki A, Karanasios S, Whiteley R. Current perspectives and clinical practice of physiotherapists on assessment, rehabilitation, and return to sport criteria after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction: an online survey of 538 physiotherapists. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;52:103&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34479178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingenen B, Billiet B, De Baets L, et al. Rehabilitation strategies of Flemish physical therapists before and after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: an online survey. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;49:68&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33621760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayer TA, van Melick N, Riera J, et al. Is it time to develop specific return to running criteria for ACL rehabilitation? An international survey of physiotherapists criteria for return to running following ACL injury. Phys Ther Sport. 2024;67:19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38457997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2024.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulver M, Hilfiker R, Bizzini M, et al. Clinical practice and barriers among swiss physiotherapists treating patients with anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a survey of pre-operative rehabilitation to return to sport. Phys Ther Sport. 2024;65:38&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38006798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2023.10.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tondelli E, Feroldi A, Garc&#xed;a F, Meza F, Dingenen B. Rehabilitation and return-to-sport after anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction: exploring physical therapists&#x2019; approaches in argentina. Phys Ther Sport. 2024;67:131&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38703448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2024.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert JR, Webster KE, Edwards PK, et al. Current perspectives of australian therapists on rehabilitation and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a&#xa0;survey. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;35:139&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30557764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fausett WA, Reid DA, Larmer PJ. Current perspectives of new zealand physiotherapists on rehabilitation and return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a survey. Phys Ther Sport. 2022;53:166&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34711502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.10.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassi A, Vascellari A, Combi A, et al. Return to sport after acl reconstruction: a survey between the Italian society of knee, arthroscopy, sport, cartilage and orthopaedic technologies (sigascot) members. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2016;26(5):509&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26972570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00590-016-1756-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aquino CF, Ocarino JM, Cardoso VA, et al. Current clinical practice and return-to-sport criteria after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a survey of Brazilian physical therapists. Braz J Phys Ther. 2021;25(3):242&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjpt.2020.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S, Cheema SG, Tarakemeh A, et al. Return to sport after primary anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction: a survey of the American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine. Kans J Med. 2023;16(1):105&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37124097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10136672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17161/kjm.vol16.18617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turocy PS. Survey research in athletic training: the scientific method of development and implementation. J Athl Train. 2002;37(4 Suppl):S174&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadaba MP, Ramakrishnan HK, Wootten ME, et al. Repeatability of kinematic, kinetic, and electromyographic data in normal adult gait. J Orthop Res. 1989;7(6):849&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2795325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.1100070611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan Y, Witvrouw E. When is it safe to return to sport after ACL reconstruction? Reviewing the criteria. Sports Health Multidiscip Approach. 2019;11(4):301&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738119846502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies WT, Myer GD, Read PJ. Is it time we better understood the tests we are using for return to sport decision making following acl reconstruction? A critical review of the hop tests. Sports Med. 2020;50(3):485&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31745732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-019-01221-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gen&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu C, Ulup&#x131;nar S, &#xd6;zbay S, et al. Validity and reliability of &#x201c;my jump app&#x201d; to assess vertical jump performance: a meta-analytic review. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):20137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37978338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10656545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-46935-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton RT, Shultz SJ, Schmitz RJ, Perrin DH. Triple-hop distance as a valid predictor of lower limb strength and power. J Athl Train. 2008;43(2):144&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18345338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2267326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-43.2.144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt LC, Paterno MV, Hewett TE. The impact of quadriceps femoris strength asymmetry on functional performance at return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2012;42(9):750&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22813542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4157226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2012.4194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toole AR, Ithurburn MP, Rauh MJ, et al. Young athletes cleared for sports participation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: how many actually meet recommended return-to-sport criterion cutoffs? J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47(11):825&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28990491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.7227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert JR, Du Preez L, Furzer B, Edwards P, Joss B. Which hop tests can best identify functional limb asymmetry in patients 9-12 months after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction employing a hamstrings tendon autograft? Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;16(2):393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33842035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8016443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.21140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Korakakis V, Graham-Smith P, Sideris V, Whiteley R. Vertical and horizontal hop performance: contributions of the hip, knee, and ankle. Sports Health Multidiscip Approach. 2021;13(2):128&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738120976363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Van Rossom S, Whiteley R, et al. Single leg vertical jump performance identifies knee function deficits at return to sport after acl reconstruction in male athletes. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(9):490&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35135826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-104692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Whiteley R, Van Rossom S, et al. Single leg hop for distance symmetry masks lower limb biomechanics: time to discuss hop distance as decision criterion for return to sport after acl reconstruction? Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(5):249&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33687928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2020-103677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Sideris V, King E, Bahr R, Whiteley R. Performance and symmetry measures during vertical jump testing at return to sport after acl reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(20):1304&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37263763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinacore JA, Evans AM, Lynch BN, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of handheld dynamometry and 1-repetition-maximum tests for identifying meaningful quadriceps strength asymmetries. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2017;47(2):97&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28142362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2017.6651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale D, MacDougall D. Specificity in strength training: a review for the coach and athlete. Can J Appl Sport Sci. 1981;6(2):87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7016357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen EM, McCartney CN, Sweeney RS, Palimenio MR, Grindstaff TL. Hand-held dynamometer positioning impacts discomfort during quadriceps strength testing: a validity and reliability study. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2015;10(1):62&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25709864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4325289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris R, Morrison S, Price A, et al. Inline dynamometry provides reliable measurements of quadriceps strength in healthy and ACL-reconstructed individuals and is a valid substitute for isometric electromechanical dynamometry following acl reconstruction. Knee. 2024;46:136&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38142660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2023.12.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mentiplay BF, Perraton LG, Bower KJ, et al. Assessment of lower limb muscle strength and power using hand-held and fixed dynamometry: a reliability and validity study. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(10):e0140822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26509265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4624940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0140822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorborg K, Bandholm T, Schick M, Jensen J, H&#xf6;lmich P. Hip strength assessment using handheld dynamometry is subject to intertester bias when testers are of different sex and strength. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2013;23(4):487&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22092308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2011.01405.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Araujo Ribeiro Alvares JB, Rodrigues R, de Azevedo Franke R, et al. Inter-machine reliability of the biodex and cybex isokinetic dynamometers for knee flexor/extensor isometric, concentric and eccentric tests. Phys Ther Sport. 2015;16(1):59&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24913915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2014.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk KE, Arrigo CA, Davies GJ. Isokinetic testing: why it is more important today than ever. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19(4):374&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38576833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10987309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.95038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingenen B, Gokeler A. Optimization of the return-to-sport paradigm after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a critical step back to move forward. Sports Med. 2017;47(8):1487&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0674-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki R, Korakakis V, King E, et al. Aspetar clinical practice guideline on rehabilitation after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(9):500&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2022-106158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright RW, Haas AK, Anderson J, et al. Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction rehabilitation: MOON guidelines. Sports Health. 2015;7(3):239&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4482298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1941738113517855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Undheim MB, Cosgrave C, King E, et al. Isokinetic muscle strength and readiness to return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: is there an association? A systematic review and a protocol recommendation. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(20):1305&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26105017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2014-093962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Horst N, Denderen RV. Isokinetic hamstring and quadriceps strength interpretation guideline for football (soccer) players with ACL reconstruction: a Delphi consensus study in the Netherlands. Sci Med Football. 2022;6(4):434&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2021.2024592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croisier JL, Ganteaume S, Binet J, Genty M, Ferret JM. Strength imbalances and prevention of hamstring injury in professional soccer players: a prospective study. Am J Sports Med. 2008;36(8):1469&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18448578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0363546508316764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Villa F, Buckthorpe M, Grassi A, et al. Systematic video analysis of acl injuries in professional male football (soccer): injury mechanisms, situational patterns and biomechanics study on 134 consecutive cases. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(23):1423&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2019-101247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucarno S, Zago M, Buckthorpe M, et al. Systematic video analysis of anterior cruciate ligament injuries in professional female soccer players. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49(7):1794&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33989090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465211008169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Pirli Capitani L, Olivares-Jabalera J, Olmo J, Della Villa F. Systematic video analysis of acl injuries in professional spanish male football (soccer): Injury mechanisms, situational patterns, biomechanics and neurocognitive errors: a study on 115 consecutive cases. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2024;10(3):e002149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39351123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11440205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2024-002149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper DJ, Jordan AR, Kiely J. Relationships between eccentric and concentric knee strength capacities and maximal linear deceleration ability in male academy soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2021;35(2):465&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29995690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picinini F, Della Villa F, Tallent J, et al. High return to competition rate after on-field rehabilitation in competitive male soccer players after acl reconstruction: GPS tracking in 100 consecutive cases. Orthop J Sports Med. 2025;13(3):23259671251320093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40052178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11881939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671251320093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, L&#xe9;am A, Four&#xe9; A, Wong DP, Hautier CA. Relationship between explosive strength capacity of the knee muscles and deceleration performance in female professional soccer players. Front Physiol. 2021;12:723041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8542697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.723041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical Research Council: Nerve Injuries Research Committee. Aids to the investigation of peripheral nerve injuries. London: Her Majesty&#x2019;s Stationery Office; 1942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill S, Jaszczak SLT, Steffensen AKS, Debrabant B. Using 4+ to grade near-normal muscle strength does not improve agreement. Chiropr Man Therap. 2017;25:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29051814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5633899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12998-017-0159-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Aagaard P, Herzog W. Lower limb asymmetry in mechanical muscle function: a comparison between ski racers with and without ACL reconstruction. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(3):e301&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25212216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Aagaard P, Herzog W. Asymmetry and thigh muscle coactivity in fatigued anterior cruciate ligament-reconstructed elite skiers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(1):11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27532454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan MJ, Morris N, Nimphius S, Aagaard P, Herzog W. Attenuated lower limb stretch-shorten-cycle capacity in ACL injured vs. non-injured female alpine ski racers: not just a matter of between-limb asymmetry. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:853701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9008592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.853701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotsifaki A, Van Rossom S, Whiteley R, et al. Symmetry in triple hop distance hides asymmetries in knee function after acl reconstruction in athletes at return to sports. Am J Sports Med. 2022;50(2):441&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34889652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465211063192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M. Recommendations for movement re-training after ACL reconstruction. Sports Med. 2021;51(8):1601&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33840081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01454-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien M, Bourne M, Heerey J, Timmins RG, Pizzari T. A novel device to assess hip strength: concurrent validity and normative values in male athletes. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;35:63&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30471548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2018.11.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desmyttere G, Gaudet S, Begon M. Test-retest reliability of a hip strength assessment system in varsity soccer players. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;37:138&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30959443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.03.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor C, McIntyre M, Delahunt E, Thorborg K. Reliability and validity of common hip adduction strength measures: the forceframe strength testing system versus the sphygmomanometer. Phys Ther Sport. 2023;59:162&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36566587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arp K, Frydendal T, Kjeldsen T, et al. Validity, agreement and reliability of the forceframe dynamometer in patients with anterior cruciate ligament injury. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2024;19(9):1068&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39229449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11368445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.122486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Danelon F, La Rosa G, et al. Recommendations for hamstring function recovery after acl reconstruction. Sports Med. 2021;51(4):607&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01400-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;gberg J, Bergentoft E, Piussi R, et al. Persistent knee flexor strength deficits identified through the nordbord eccentric test not seen with &#x201c;gold standard&#x201d; isokinetic concentric testing during the first year after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction with a hamstring tendon autograft. Phys Ther Sport. 2022;55:119&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35339867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2022.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesinger HP, Gressenbauer C, K&#xf6;sters A, Scharinger M, M&#xfc;ller E. Device and method matter: a critical evaluation of eccentric hamstring muscle strength assessments. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(2):217&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31593621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahr R, Clarsen B, Ekstrand J. Why we should focus on the burden of injuries and illnesses, not just their incidence. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(16):1018&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29021247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand J, Bengtsson H, Wald&#xe9;n M, et al. Hamstring injury rates have increased during recent seasons and now constitute 24% of all injuries in men&#x2019;s professional football: the UEFA Elite Club Injury Study study from 2001/02 to 2021/22. Br J Sports Med. 2022;57(5):292&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36588400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2021-105407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckthorpe M, Tamisari A, Villa FD. A ten task-based progression in rehabilitation after acl reconstruction: from post-surgery to return to play: a clinical commentary. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15(4):611&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33354394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7735691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20200611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgi CR, Peters S, Ardern CL, et al. Which criteria are used to clear patients to return to sport after primary ACL reconstruction? A scoping review. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53(18):1154&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2018-099982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rambaud AJM, Ardern CL, Thoreux P, Regnaux JP, Edouard P. Criteria for return to running after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a scoping review. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(22):1437&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unverzagt C, Andreyo E, Tompkins J. Acl return to sport testing: it&#x2019;s time to step up our game. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;16(4):1169&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8329322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/001c.25463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;gberg J, Piussi R, Simonson R, et al. Is absolute or relative knee flexor strength related to patient-reported outcomes in patients treated with acl reconstruction with a hamstring tendon autograft? An analysis of eccentric nordic hamstring strength and seated concentric isokinetic strength. Knee. 2023;41:161&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36702050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.knee.2023.01.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brink M, Kuyvenhoven J, Toering T, Jordet G, Frencken W. What do football coaches want from sport science? Kinesiology. 2018;50:90&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minnig MC, Hawkinson L, Root HJ, et al. Barriers and facilitators to the adoption and implementation of evidence-based injury prevention training programmes: a narrative review. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2022;8(3):e001374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36187085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9516217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjsem-2022-001374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaabi S, Varughese B, Singh R. Public and private healthcare system in terms of both quality and cost: a review. J Clin Diagn Res. 2022. https://doi.org/10.7860/JCDR/2022/55387.16742 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7860/JCDR/2022/55387.16742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldron K, Brown M, Calderon A, Feldman M. Anterior cruciate ligament rehabilitation and return to sport: how fast is too fast? Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(1):e175&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8811519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmr.2021.10.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>