<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41741288</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of surgical education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Surg Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How do Trainers Think They Should Train? A Qualitative Study Investigating the Training Practices That General Surgical Consultants Value.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103895</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103895</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jsurg.2026.103895</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1931-7204(26)00028-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The role of the surgical trainer is critical in the development and training of surgeons of the future. Despite this, the majority of research in this area focuses on the views of the trainees. There is very little, or in some cases no research, into which practices make good surgical training, or what good modern surgical training looks like according to the trainers. This research looked to fill this gap.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A constructivist exploratory approach was used. Semi structured interviews were conducted. Interviews continued until it was felt that sufficient information power had been achieved. Reflective thematic analysis was then applied using Braun and Clarke's 6 step technique.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ninety-minute interviews were conducted over Microsoft teams, over a 3-month period General Surgery Consultants who self-identified as trainers from Yorkshire and Humber School of Surgery were recruited on a voluntary basis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Four main themes were identified, "Trainees are responsible for their own training," "The best training happens in positive relationships," "Learning to operate is the easy bit" and "Trainers are not empowered to train."</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Participants emphasized trainee responsibility for proactive learning whilst simultaneously describing structural constraints limiting their capacity to deliver desired training. This tension may reflect broader contradictions in how training responsibilities are understood within current systems. Participants identified resource limitations, particularly time and access to training funding, as barriers beyond their control. However, perceptions that training produces "reasonable" consultants may reduce urgency for systemic change. Findings suggest that meaningful improvement in surgical training may require both institutional changes-such as formal recognition and resourcing of training activities-and collective advocacy by trainers themselves to address structural barriers. Given this study's single-region focus, further research across multiple regions and specialties would strengthen understanding of whether these perspectives reflect wider patterns in UK surgical training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clarke</LastName><ForeName>Rory William</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yorkshire and Humber School of Surgery, Yorkshire, United Kingdom; University of Leeds, School of Medicine, Leeds, United Kingdom. Electronic address: rory.clarke2@nhs.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Surg Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101303204</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1878-7452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">general surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trainer professionalization</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41741288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsurg.2026.103895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1931-7204(26)00028-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>