<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41927661</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analytical solution of driven time-dependent mesoscopic circuits.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-45828-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>When a time-dependent harmonic system is further driven by an external source, it presents significant challenges to obtaining analytical solutions for the system. This paper applies the Lewis-Riesenfeld invariant method to a mesoscopic time-dependent dissipative inductor-capacitor (RLC) circuit with an external source. By constructing quantum invariant Hermitian operators and introducing auxiliary equations that can describe the effects of external sources and resistance, we analytically solve the Schr&#xf6;dinger equation of the system. Taking an alternating current (AC) voltage source as an example, we derive the generalized coherent states of a mesoscopic time-dependent RLC circuit with an external source, calculate the quantum fluctuations of charge and current, and obtain their corresponding uncertainty relations. The results indicate that the time-dependent inductance and resistance disrupt the minimum uncertainty relation of the Glauble coherent states in driven time-dependent mesoscopic RLC circuits. This research contributes to the establishment of a quantum theory for mesoscopic circuits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Jinying</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Physics, North China Electric Power University, Baoding, 071003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Yazhuo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Physics, North China Electric Power University, Baoding, 071003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ronghai</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electric Power Research Institute of Yunnan Power Grid Co. Ltd., Kunming, 650011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Fangcheng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electric Power Research Institute of Yunnan Power Grid Co. Ltd., Kunming, 650011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiyuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Physics, North China Electric Power University, Baoding, 071003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Zhanyuan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Physics, North China Electric Power University, Baoding, 071003, China. yanzhanyuan@ncepu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hebei Key Laboratory of Physics and Energy Technology, North China Electric Power University, Baoding, 071003, China. yanzhanyuan@ncepu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023GJJG427</GrantID><Agency>Research and Practice Project on Higher Education Reform in Hebei Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YNKJXM20220050</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Projects of China Southern Power Grid</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41927661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-45828-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-45828-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Buot, F. A. Mesoscopic physics and nanoelectronics: Nanoscience and nanotechnology. Phys. Rep. 234, 73&#x2013;174. https://doi.org/10.1016/0370-1573(93)90097-W (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blais, A., Grimsmo, A. L., Girvin, S. M. &amp; Wallraff, A. Circuit quantum electrodynamics. Rev. Mod. Phys. 93, 025005. https://doi.org/10.1103/RevModPhys.93.025005 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yurke, B. &amp; Denker, J. S. Quantum network theory. Phys. Rev. A 29, 1419&#x2013;1437. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.29.1419 (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kockum, A. F., Miranowicz, A., Liberato, S. D., Savasta, S. &amp; Nori, F. Ultrastrong coupling between light and matter. Nat. Rev. Phys. 1, 19&#x2013;40. https://doi.org/10.1038/s42254-018-0006-2 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boit&#xe9;, A. L. Theoretical methods for ultrastrong light-matter interactions. Adv. Quantum Technol. 3, 1900140. https://doi.org/10.1002/qute.201900140 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forati, E., Langley, B. W., Nersisyan, A. &amp; Molavi, R. On the electromagnetic couplings in superconducting qubit circuits. arXiv:2405.11426 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louisell, W. H. Quantum Statistical Properties of Radiation 3 edn. (John Wiley, 1973).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. Q. &amp; Chen, B. Quantum theory for mesoscopic electric circuits. Phys. Rev. B 53, 4027&#x2013;4032. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.53.4027 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flores, J. C. Mesoscopic circuits with charge discreteness: quantum transmission lines. Phys. Rev. B 64, 235309&#x2013;235313. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.64.235309 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aunola, M. The discretised harmonic oscillation: Mathieu function and a new class of generalized Hermite polynomials. J. Math. Phys. 44, 1913&#x2013;1928. https://doi.org/10.1063/1.1561156 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, Y. H., Luo, H. M. &amp; Guo, Q. The time evolution of charge and current in mesoscopic lc circuit with charge discreteness. Phys. Lett. A 349, 104&#x2013;108 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, J. Y., Zhao, W. R., Wang, W. L. &amp; Yan, Z. Y. Improved quantization method of coupled circuits in charge discrete space. Mathematics 12, 3753. https://doi.org/10.3390/math12233753 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, Z. Y., Xu, S. L. &amp; Ma, J. Y. Path integral solutions of rlc mesoscopic circuit with source. Mod. Phys. Lett. B 26, 1250058&#x2013;1250065. https://doi.org/10.1142/S0217984912500583 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, H. Y. &amp; Liang, X. T. Quantum fluctuation in thermal vacuum state for mesoscopic lc electric circuit. Chin. Phys. Lett. 17, 174&#x2013;176. https://doi.org/10.1088/0256-307X/17/3/007 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa, I. A. &amp; Pinheiro, A. P. Quantum description of a mesoscopic rlc circuit. Prog. Theor. Phys. 125, 1133&#x2013;1141. https://doi.org/10.1143/PTP.125.1133 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa, I. A. Quantum description of a time-dependent mesoscopic rlc circuit. Physica Scripta T151, 014042&#x2013;014044. https://doi.org/10.1088/0031-8949/2012/T151/014042 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. X. &amp; Yan, Z. Y. Quantum effect in the mesoscopic rlc circuits with a source. Commun. Theor. Phys. 44, 1091&#x2013;1094. https://doi.org/10.1088/6102/44/6/1091 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla, M. S. Time-dependent harmonic oscillator with variable mass under the action of a driving force. Phys. Rev. A 34, 4598&#x2013;4605. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.34.4598 (1986).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, S.-W., Huang, B.-W. &amp; Gu, Z.-Y. Ermakov invariant and the general solution for a damped harmonic oscillator with a force quadratic in velocity. J. Phys. A Math. Gen. 34, 5613. https://doi.org/10.1088/0305-4470/34/27/311 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas, F. On the damped pinney equation from noether symmetry principles. Symmetry https://doi.org/10.3390/sym16101310 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, B. W. &amp; Wang, W. Driven and possibly frequecy modulated linear harmonic oscillator. J. Capital Normal Univ. (Nat. Sci. Ed.) 21, 21&#x2013;24 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, H. R. &amp; Leach, P. G. L. A direct approach to finding exact invariants for one-dimensional time-dependent classical hamiltonians. J. Math. Phys. 23, 2371&#x2013;2374. https://doi.org/10.1063/1.525329 (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dantas, C. M. A., Pedrosa, I. A. &amp; Baseia, B. Harmonic oscillator with time-dependent mass and frequency and a perturbative potential. Phys. Rev. A 45, 1320&#x2013;1324. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.45.1320 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrosa, I. A., Serra, G. P. &amp; Guedes, I. Wave functions of a time-dependent harmonic oscillator with and without a singular perturbation. Phys. Rev. A 56, 4300&#x2013;4303. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.56.4300 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, J. R. Quantum states with continuous spectrum for the time-dependent harmonic oscillator with a singular perturbation. Mod. Phys. Lett. B 21, 585&#x2013;593. https://doi.org/10.1142/S0217984907012992 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. S., Liu, T. K. &amp; Zhan, M. S. Coulomb blockade and quantum fluctuations of mesoscopic inductance coupling circuit. Phys. Lett. A 276, 155&#x2013;161. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0375-9601(00)00661-7 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. X., Yan, Z. Y. &amp; Song, Y. H. Quantum effects of mesoscopic inductance and capacity coupling circuits. Commun. Theor. Phys. 45, 1126&#x2013;1130. https://doi.org/10.1088/0253-6102/45/6/032 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borletto, F., Giacomelli, L. &amp; Ciuti, C. Circuit quantum electrodynamics of direct and dual shapiro steps with finite-size-transmission-line resonators. Phys. Rev. Appl. 22, 054061. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.22.054061 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shou, Z., Chung-In, U. &amp; Kyu-Hwang, Y. Zero-point energy in a mesoscopic nonlinear inductance-capacitance circuit. Chin. Phys. Lett. 19, 985. https://doi.org/10.1088/0256-307X/19/7/332 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, Z. Y., Zhang, X. H. &amp; Ma, J. Y. Quantum effect in a diode included nonlinear inductance-capacitance mesoscopic circuit. Commun. Theor. Phys. 52, 534&#x2013;538. https://doi.org/10.1088/0253-6102/52/3/29 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, Z. Y., Zhang, X. H. &amp; Han, Y. H. Quantum effect in mesoscopic open electron resonator. Commun. Theor. Phys. 50, 521&#x2013;524. https://doi.org/10.1088/0253-6102/50/2/49 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. S. &amp; Su, C. Y. Quantum effect in a diode included nonlinear inductance-capacitance mesoscopic circuit. Int. J. Theor. Phys. 37(3), 1213&#x2013;1216 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis, H. R. &amp; Riesenfeld, W. B. An exact quantum theory of the time-dependent harmonic oscillator and of a charged particle in a time-dependent electromagnetic field. J. Math. Phys. 10, 1458&#x2013;1473. https://doi.org/10.1063/1.1664991 (1969).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, Y.-H. et al. Nonadiabatic geometric quantum computation with cat-state qubits via invariant-based reverse engineering. Phys. Rev. Res. 4, 013233. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.013233 (2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>