<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41748777</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of AI on Japanese language education: a hybrid model for student behavior detection.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11140</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40262-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The increasing complexity of classroom environments necessitates nigh-on-sophisticated methods for the detection and analysis of student behavior, especially in Japanese language education, where engagement and attention are crucial for effective learning. This study presents a new model to integrate the AlexNet deep Neural Network combined with an Extreme Learning Machine (ELM) for enhanced feature extraction and classification accuracy in the detection of student behavior under wireless network settings. Up until now, optimizer parameters of the ELM need to be adjusted to enhance the convergence of the learning model, therefore, an Advanced Electric Fish Optimization (AEFO) algorithm is introduced with frequency adjustment and multi-modal exploration capabilities for improved search ability. The model was tested on a real-life classroom dataset consisting of 282 images and videos, 1,456 test samples, and it was compared to state-of-the-art methods, namely CNN, ANN, and others optimized by metaheuristic. The experimental result shows that the proposed AlexNet/ELM/AEFO framework achieves a classification accuracy of 96.5%, precision of 94.8%, and recall of 98.2%, which surpassed existing methods in the detection of behaviors like writing, listening, raising hands, sleeping, and answering questions. The robustness of the proposed model and its high discriminating power has further been substantiated through confusion matrix and ROC/AUC analysis. This study shows promise in positioning the proposed system as a reliable and automated method for real-time monitoring of student engagement with the ability for data-driven pedagogical intervention, thus expediting the AI framework in intelligent classroom environments.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yuquan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Jiujiang University, Jiujiang, 332005, Jiangxi, China. liyuquan00@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zou</LastName><ForeName>Hongyu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Jiujiang University, Jiujiang, 332005, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Jiujiang University, Jiujiang, 332005, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Dechao</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Jiujiang University, Jiujiang, 332005, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Jiujiang University, Jiujiang, 332005, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Jiujiang University, Jiujiang, 332005, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Advanced electric fish optimization algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AlexNet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Classroom behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Convolutional neural network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Detection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ELM Net</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Feature extraction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41748777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40262-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40262-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13046975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kindaichi, H. <i>Japanese Language: Learn the Fascinating History and Evolution of the Language Along With Many Useful Japanese Grammar Points</i> (Tuttle Publishing, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norboyevich, M. A. Evolution and origins of the Japanese language. <i>World Bull. Soc. Sci.</i><b>30</b>, 20&#x2013;22 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogura, F. The evolution of Japanese learners in Japan: Crossing Japan, the West and South East Asia, ed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshfar, F., Dolati, M. &amp; Sulaimany, S. Graph clustering techniques for community detection in social networks. In <i>Community Structure Analysis from Social Networks</i> 81&#x2013;100 (Chapman and Hall/CRC, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshfar, F., Dolati, M. &amp; Sulaimany, S. Semi-supervised and deep learning approaches to social network community analysis. In <i>Community Structure Analysis from Social Networks</i> 101&#x2013;120 (Chapman and Hall/CRC, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Shloul, T. et al. Role of activity-based learning and ChatGPT on students&#x2019; performance in education. <i>Comput. Educ. Artif. Intell.</i><b>6</b>, 100219 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.caeai.2024.100219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, T.-H. The current situation of AI foreign language education and its influence on college Japanese teaching. In <i>Cross-Cultural Design. Applications in Health, Learning, Communication, and Creativity: 12th International Conference, CCD 2020, Held as Part of the 22nd HCI International Conference, HCII 2020, Copenhagen, Denmark, July 19&#x2013;24, 2020, Proceedings, Part II 22</i>, 315&#x2013;324 (Springer, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazhar, T., Shahzad, T., Ahmad, W. &amp; Hamam, H. Use of brain-computer interface in educational paradigm. <i>J. Comput. Soc. Sci.</i><b>8</b>(3), 64 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42001-025-00394-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, S. F. A., Mazhar, T., Shahzad, T., Ghadi, Y. Y. &amp; Hamam, H. Integrating educational theories with virtual reality: Enhancing engineering education and VR laboratories. <i>Soc. Sci. Humanit. Open</i><b>10</b>, 101207 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazhar, T., Shahzad, T., Waheed, W., Waheed, A. &amp; Hamam, H. Predictive analytics in education-enhancing student achievement through machine learning. <i>Soc. Sci. Humanit. Open</i><b>12</b>, 101824 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jodoin, J. J. Promoting language education for sustainable development: A program effects case study in Japanese higher education. <i>Int. J. Sustain. High. Educ.</i><b>21</b>(4), 779&#x2013;798 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJSHE-09-2019-0258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marfina, V. E. Prospects of integration of virtual assistants in the process of teaching speaking to the beginner learners of the Japanese language. <i>RUDN J. Informatization Educ.</i><b>20</b>(3), 305&#x2013;315 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22363/2312-8631-2023-20-3-305-315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikitenko, V., Voronkova, V., Oleksenko, R., Andriukaitiene, R. &amp; Holovii, L. Education as a factor of cognitive society development in the conditions of digital transformation. <i>Rev. Univ. Zulia</i><b>13</b>(38), 680&#x2013;695 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshad, A., Afzal, M. &amp; Hussain, M. S. Sudden switch to post-COVID-19 online classes and cognitive transformation of ESL learners: Critical analysis of discourse of fear. <i>Res. J. Soc. Sci. Econ. Rev.</i><b>1</b>(3), 188&#x2013;199 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan, X. The application of cognitive linguistics theory in Japanese language teaching in the age of artificial intelligence. <i>Appl. Math. Nonlinear Sci</i>. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. The cognitive transformation of Japanese language education by artificial intelligence technology in the wireless network environment. <i>Comput. Intell. Neurosci.</i><b>2022</b>(1), 7886369 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9283021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35845870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamb, R. Successful use of a novel artificial neural network to computationally model cognitive processes in high school students learning science. <i>Comput. Rev. J.</i><b>3</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohnke, L., Moorhouse, B. L. &amp; Zou, D. ChatGPT for language teaching and learning. <i>RELC J.</i><b>54</b>(2), 537&#x2013;550 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00336882231162868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radianti, J., Majchrzak, T. A., Fromm, J. &amp; Wohlgenannt, I. A systematic review of immersive virtual reality applications for higher education: Design elements, lessons learned, and research agenda. <i>Comput. Educ.</i><b>147</b>, 103778 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compedu.2019.103778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonassen, D. H. &amp; Rohrer-Murphy, L. Activity theory as a framework for designing constructivist learning environments. <i>Educ. Technol. Res. Dev.</i><b>47</b>(1), 61&#x2013;79 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02299477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell, P. <i>Acquiring a Conception of Mind: A Review of Psychological Research and Theory</i> (Psychology Press, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmad Ramadhan, L. &amp; Anne Mudya, Y. A comparative study of Z-score and min-max normalization for rainfall classification in Pekanbaru. <i>J. Data Sci.</i><b>2024</b>(04), 1&#x2013;8 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, A. et al. Comparative analysis of median filter and its variants for removal of impulse noise from gray scale images. <i>J. King Saud Univ.</i><b>34</b>(3), 505&#x2013;519 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksuci.2020.03.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., Wang, Y. &amp; Razmjooy, N. Lung cancer diagnosis in CT images based on Alexnet optimized by modified Bowerbird optimization algorithm. <i>Biomed. Signal Process. Control</i><b>77</b>, 103791 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2022.103791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, S., Wang, S.-H. &amp; Zhang, Y.-D. Detection of abnormal brain in MRI via improved AlexNet and ELM optimized by chaotic bat algorithm. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>33</b>(17), 10799&#x2013;10811 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-020-05082-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navid Razmjooy, F. R. S. &amp; Ghadimi, N. A hybrid neural network &#x2013; World cup optimization algorithm for melanoma detection. <i>Open Med.</i><b>13</b>, 9&#x2013;16 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/med-2018-0002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5850997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29577090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, D., Wang, Y., Liu, H., Jermsittiparsert, K. &amp; Razmjooy, N. System identification of PEM fuel cells using an improved Elman neural network and a new hybrid optimization algorithm. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>5</b>, 1365&#x2013;1374 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2019.09.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Lu, S., Wang, S.-H. &amp; Zhang, Y.-D. A review on extreme learning machine. <i>Multimed. Tools Appl.</i><b>81</b>(29), 41611&#x2013;41660 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11042-021-11007-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz, S. &amp; Sen, S. Electric fish optimization: A new heuristic algorithm inspired by electrolocation. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>32</b>(15), 11543&#x2013;11578 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-019-04641-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, A. W., Hadi, A. A. &amp; Mohamed, A. K. Gaining-sharing knowledge based algorithm for solving optimization problems: A novel nature-inspired algorithm. <i>Int. J. Mach. Learn. Cybern.</i><b>11</b>(7), 1501&#x2013;1529 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13042-019-01053-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noel, M. M., Muthiah-Nakarajan, V., Amali, G. B. &amp; Trivedi, A. S. A new biologically inspired global optimization algorithm based on firebug reproductive swarming behaviour. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>183</b>, 115408 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2021.115408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abualigah, L., Abd Elaziz, M., Sumari, P., Geem, Z. W. &amp; Gandomi, A. H. Reptile search algorithm (RSA): A nature-inspired meta-heuristic optimizer. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>191</b>, 116158 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2021.116158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razmjooy, N., Khalilpour, M. &amp; Ramezani, M. A new meta-heuristic optimization algorithm inspired by FIFA world cup competitions: Theory and its application in PID designing for AVR system. <i>J. Control Autom. Electr. Syst.</i><b>27</b>(4), 419&#x2013;440 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40313-016-0242-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coufal, P., Hub&#xe1;lovsk&#xfd;, &#x160;, Hub&#xe1;lovsk&#xe1;, M. &amp; Balogh, Z. Snow leopard optimization algorithm: A new nature-based optimization algorithm for solving optimization problems. <i>Mathematics</i><b>9</b>(21), 2832 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math9212832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>