<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41486153</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Artificial intelligence based resuscitation simulation: a pilot study of a novel approach to team leadership training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>183</StartPage><MedlinePgn>183</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">183</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12909-025-08539-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Team leadership training is essential alongside with technical training for effective resuscitation management. Addressing this gap, we developed a novel simulation system leveraging Large Language Models (LLMs) to create Artificial Intelligence (AI) agents simulating team members in Advanced Cardiovascular Life Support (ACLS) scenarios. This pilot study aimed to to develop a novel LLM-based ACLS simulation training platform and evaluate its performance in simulated resuscitation scenarios on established protocols.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">Using the Claude 3.5 Sonnet API, we designed a simulation system with four AI agents assigned specific roles as healthcare staff within an ACLS team. Each agent strictly followed the 2020 American Heart Association (AHA) ACLS guidelines while interacting with an ACLS certified emergency medicine specialist user. The ten patient scenario transcripts were evaluated with three blinded emergency medicine specialists whether all the recommended steps are completed. Inter-rater reliability was assessed using Kendall&#x2019;s W and Krippendorff&#x2019;s Alpha statistics to evaluate agreement both within raters and the model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">AI agents consistently adhered to the AHA 2020 ACLS algorithm across scenarios, with a high inter-rater reliability (Kendall&#x2019;s W&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.75). Krippendorff&#x2019;s Alpha values for agreement ranged from substantial (0.84) to almost perfect (0.99), indicating robust compliance with guidelines and effective simulation of resuscitation responses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study highlights the potential of LLM-powered simulations as an adjunct to traditional resuscitation training. The system effectively supported team leadership training by providing consistent and guideline-compliant responses. While the results are promising, further research with larger participant samples is necessary to evaluate the long-term educational impact and scalability of such systems.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12909-025-08539-z.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanbakan</LastName><ForeName>Altu&#x11f;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Ufuk University, K&#x131;z&#x131;l&#x131;rmak, Ufuk &#xdc;nv. Cd No:1, 06510, Ankara, Turkey. altug.kanbakan@ufuk.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berikol</LastName><ForeName>G&#xf6;ksu Bozdereli</ForeName><Initials>GB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, At&#x131;l&#x131;m University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x130;lhan</LastName><ForeName>Bu&#x11f;ra</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, K&#x131;r&#x131;kkale University, K&#x131;r&#x131;kkale, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alt&#x131;nta&#x15f;</LastName><ForeName>Emel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Ufuk University, K&#x131;z&#x131;l&#x131;rmak, Ufuk &#xdc;nv. Cd No:1, 06510, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Do&#x11f;anay</LastName><ForeName>Fatih</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, FL, 32224, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088679</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6920</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACLS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Emergency medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resuscitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study protocol was reviewed by the Ufuk University Health Sciences Scientific Research Assessment and Ethics Committee (Ankara, Turkey). It was determined that formal ethical approval and informed consent were not required (Waiver granted), as the study consisted entirely of computer-based simulations and did not involve human subjects or the collection of identifiable personal data, in accordance with the principles of Non-Interventional Clinical Research (Decision Date: 05.12.2025, Decision No: 25.11.21.09/04). However, to ensure adherence to high ethical standards, written informed consent to participate was obtained from the participant involved in the pilot evaluation prior to the study. The study was conducted in accordance with the ethical standards laid down in the 1964 Declaration of Helsinki and its later amendments. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41486153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12870186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-025-08539-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12909-025-08539-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yeung JHY, Ong GJ, Davies RP, Gao F, Perkins GD. Factors affecting team leadership skills and their relationship with quality of cardiopulmonary resuscitation. Crit Care Med. 2012;40(9):2617&#x2013;21. 10.1097/CCM.0b013e3182588a9f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0b013e3182588a9f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22732290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kello JE, Allen JA. The burned out physician: managing the stress and reducing the errors. 1st ed. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2022. 10.1017/9781009052795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amatya Y, Shrestha S. Evaluating the impact of ACLS scenario-based resuscitation simulation for emergency team. Med J Shree Birendra Hosp. 2021;20:12&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/mjsbh.v20i1.31431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zern SC, Marshall WJ, Shewokis PA, Vest MT. Use of simulation as a needs assessment to develop a focused team leader training curriculum for resuscitation teams. Adv Simul. 2020;5:6. 10.1186/s41077-020-00126-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-020-00126-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32514384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toft LEB, Bottinor W, Cobourn A, et al. A simulation-enhanced, spaced learning, interprofessional code blue curriculum improves ACLS algorithm adherence and trainee resuscitation skill confidence. J Interprof Care. 2023;37(5):623&#x2013;8. 10.1080/13561820.2022.2122183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13561820.2022.2122183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36373206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer A, Selladurai RI, Pfeifle AL, et al. Effective teamwork and healthcare delivery outcomes. In: Selladurai R, Hobson C, editors. Advances in healthcare information systems and administration. Hershey, PA: IGI Global; 2020. pp. 77&#x2013;99. 10.4018/978-1-7998-2348-5.ch005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenman ED, Shandro JR, Ilgen JS, Harper AL, Fernandez R. Simulation-based healthcare leadership training: a systematic review. Simul Healthc. 2013;8(6):356&#x2013;72. 10.1097/SIH.0b013e31829e59dc.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SIH.0b013e31829e59dc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford K, Menchine M, Burner E, Arora S, Inaba K, Demetriades D, Yersin B, Lin S. Leadership and team behaviours are the critical factors in the management of simulated resuscitations by medical students. Resuscitation. 2016;99:62&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2015.11.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resuscitation.2015.11.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapierre V, Fernandez R, Auerbach M, Bhanji F, Cheng A, Grant V, et al. Leadership in pediatric resuscitation: a review and future directions. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2020;36(5):e262&#x2013;8. 10.1097/PEC.0000000000002001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PEC.0000000000002001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin SA, Doezema D, Sklar DP. Human simulation in emergency medicine training: a systematic review. Acad Emerg Med. 2019;26(8):1002&#x2013;14. 10.1111/acem.13791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acem.13791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez R, Rosenman ED, Olenick J, et al. Simulation-based team leadership training improves team leadership during actual trauma resuscitations: a randomized controlled trial. Crit Care Med. 2020;48(1):73&#x2013;82. 10.1097/CCM.0000000000004049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000004049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31725441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez Castelao E, Boos M, Ringer C, Eich C, Russo SG. Effect of CRM team leader training on team performance and leadership behavior in simulated cardiac arrest scenarios: a prospective, randomized, controlled study. BMC Med Educ. 2015;15:116. 10.1186/s12909-015-0414-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-015-0414-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4526177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26205962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao C, Lan X, Li N, Yuan Y, Ding J, Zhou Z, et al. Large Language models empowered agent-based modeling and simulation: a survey and perspectives. Humanit Soc Sci Commun. 2024;11:1259. 10.1057/s41599-024-02521-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/s41599-024-02521-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saiedian H. Leveraging large language models in education: enhancing learning and teaching. In: 2023 ASEE Midwest Section Conference Proceedings. Lincoln, NE: University of Nebraska-Lincoln; 2024. p. 46353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zeng C, Zhong J, Zhang R, Zhang M, Zou L, et al. Leveraging large Language model as simulated patients for clinical education. ArXiv Preprint. arXiv:2404.13066. 10.48550/arXiv.2404.13066.&#xa0;Published April 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprigler A, Drobek A, Weinstock K, Tapsoba W, Childress G, Dao A, et al. Synergistic simulations: multi-agent problem solving with large language models. ArXiv Preprint. arXiv:2409.13753. 10.48550/arXiv.2409.13753. Published September 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semeraro F, Fija&#x10d;ko N, Gamberini L, Bignami EG, Greif R. The gap between promise and reality: evaluating new ai&#x2019;s role in CPR education. Resuscitation. 2025;208:110540. 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2025.110540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resuscitation.2025.110540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39952381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DK, Choi H, Jheon S, Jo YH, Im CW, Il SY. Development of an extended reality simulator for basic life support training. IEEE J Transl Eng Health Med. 2022;10:1&#x2013;7. 10.1109/JTEHM.2022.3179342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JTEHM.2022.3179342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9342859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35937462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallam M. ChatGPT utility in healthcare education, research, and practice: systematic review on the promising perspectives and valid concerns. Healthc (Basel). 2023;11(6):887. 10.3390/healthcare11060887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11060887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10048148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36981544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadario R, Longoni C, Morewedge CK. Understanding, explaining, and utilizing medical artificial intelligence. Nat Hum Behav. 2021;5:1636&#x2013;42. 10.1038/s41562-021-01146-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41562-021-01146-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34183800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorey S, Ang E, Yap J, Ng ED, Lau ST, Chui CK. A virtual counseling application using artificial intelligence for communication skills training in nursing education: development study. J Med Internet Res. 2019;21(10):e14658. 10.2196/14658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6913997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31663857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorey S, Ang ENK, Ng ED, Yap J, Lau LST, Chui CK, et al. Evaluation of a theory-based virtual counseling application in nursing education. CIN Comput Inf Nurs. 2023;41(7):385&#x2013;93. 10.1097/CIN.0000000000000987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CIN.0000000000000987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36728150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KS, Zary N. Applications and challenges of implementing artificial intelligence in medical education: integrative review. JMIR Med Educ. 2019;5(1):e13930. 10.2196/13930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/13930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6598417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31199295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greif R, Lockey AS, Conaghan P, et al. European resuscitation Council guidelines for resuscitation 2015. Resuscitation. 2015;95:288&#x2013;301. 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2015.07.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resuscitation.2015.07.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greif R, Lockey A, Breckwoldt J, et al. European resuscitation Council guidelines 2021: education for resuscitation. Resuscitation. 2021;161:388&#x2013;407. 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2021.02.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resuscitation.2021.02.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33773831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins GD, Gr&#xe4;sner JT, Semeraro F, et al. European resuscitation Council guidelines 2021: executive summary. Resuscitation. 2021;161:1&#x2013;60. 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2021.02.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resuscitation.2021.02.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33773824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greif R, Bhanji F, Bigham BL, et al. Education, implementation, and teams. Resuscitation. 2020;156:A188&#x2013;239. 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2020.02.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resuscitation.2020.02.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33098918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini M, Heydari A, Reihani H, Kareshki H. Elements of teamwork in resuscitation: an integrative review. Bull Emerg Trauma. 2022;10(2):47&#x2013;55. 10.30476/beat.2021.91963.1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30476/beat.2021.91963.1291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9373058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35991377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farquharson B, Cortegiani A, Lauridsen KG, Yeung J, Greif R, Nabecker S. Teaching team competencies within resuscitation training: a systematic review. Resusc Plus. 2024;19:100687. 10.1016/j.resplu.2024.100687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resplu.2024.100687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11239706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39006135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebig S, Kues S, Klebl F, Br&#xfc;nnler T, Rockmann F, Sch&#xf6;lmerich J, et al. Cardiac arrest. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2009;106(6):105&#x2013;11. 10.3238/arztebl.2009.0065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.2009.0065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2695287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19562012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Heart Association. Advanced cardiovascular life support provider manual. International english ed. Dallas, TX: American Heart Association; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham C, Govender R, Tehami S, Chavez S, Adepoju OE, Liaw W. ChatGPT&#x2019;s performance in cardiac arrest and bradycardia simulations using the American heart association&#x2019;s advanced cardiovascular life support guidelines: exploratory study. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e55037. 10.2196/55037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/55037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11074885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38648098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherr R, Halaseh FF, Spina A, Andalib S, Rivera R. ChatGPT interactive medical simulations for early clinical education: case study. JMIR Med Educ. 2023;9:e49877. 10.2196/49877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/49877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10674152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37948112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck S, Kuhner M, Haar M, Daubmann A, Semmann M, Kluge S. Evaluating the accuracy and reliability of AI chatbots in disseminating the content of current resuscitation guidelines: a comparative analysis between the ERC 2021 guidelines and both ChatGPT 3.5 and 4. Scand J Trauma Resusc Emerg Med. 2024;32:95. 10.1186/s13049-024-01234-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13049-024-01234-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11425874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39327587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chelli M, Descamps J, Lavou&#xe9; V, Trojani C, et al. Hallucination rates and reference accuracy of ChatGPT and bard for systematic reviews: comparative analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e53164. 10.2196/53164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/53164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11153973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38776130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinc MT, Bardak AE, Bahar F, Noronha C. Comparative analysis of large Language models in clinical diagnosis: performance evaluation across common and complex medical cases. JAMIA Open. 2025;8(3):ooaf055. 10.1093/jamiaopen/ooaf055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamiaopen/ooaf055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12161448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40510808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthropic. Claude 3.5 Sonnet model card. 2025. Available from: https://www.anthropic.com/index/claude-3-5-model-card.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>