<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41720880</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fault detection and diagnosis in photovoltaic systems using artificial intelligence and time-frequency analysis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10056</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39386-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This research introduces a novel artificial intelligence (AI) framework for fault detection and diagnosis (FDD) in photovoltaic (PV) systems that combines Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) with time&#x2013;frequency analysis via the Wigner&#x2013;Ville Distribution (WVD). The proposed method transforms raw numerical measurements&#x2014;including solar irradiance, temperature, voltage, current, and power&#x2014;into compact 6&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;12 time&#x2013;frequency image representations, enabling effective spatial feature extraction by CNNs that are well suited to image-like data. The framework is benchmarked under both noiseless and noisy conditions on a comprehensive 17&#x2011;class dataset comprising one healthy condition (C0) and sixteen fault types (F1&#x2013;F16), including progressive short&#x2011;circuit faults within a single string, pure partial&#x2011;shading faults, and combined inter&#x2011;string short&#x2011;circuit and asymmetric partial&#x2011;shading patterns along PV strings. To contextualize performance, the CNN&#x2013;WVD model is compared not only with classical Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) and Deep Neural Networks (DNNs) but also with Gradient Boosting Machines (GBM), Random Forests (RF), Support Vector Machines (SVM), and k&#x2011;Nearest Neighbors (kNN), all trained on the same WVD&#x2011;transformed data. In noiseless conditions, ANN and DNN achieve 99.51% and 99.49% accuracy, respectively, while the CNN attains 97.09%; RF, SVM, GBM, and kNN reach 93.47%, 88.62%, 84.01%, and 75.69% accuracy. Under noisy conditions that emulate real PV environments, the CNN is the most robust model with 90.27% accuracy, outperforming ANN (82.20%), RF (82.80%), SVM (83.85%), GBM (73.85%), DNN (76.27%), and kNN (72.80%). Key contributions include: (i) the use of WVD to obtain highly informative time&#x2013;frequency representations of PV electrical signals, (ii) a structured data&#x2011;organization strategy that maps multivariate PV measurements into fixed&#x2011;size WVD images, and (iii) a CNN architecture that preserves high discrimination capability across closely related fault severities and locations, even in the presence of noise achieving 90.8% accuracy under realistic sensor noise ([Formula: see text] baseline uncertainty: [Formula: see text] irradiance, [Formula: see text] temperature, [Formula: see text] voltage, [Formula: see text] current, [Formula: see text] power) and maintaining 71.5% accuracy at [Formula: see text] noise, representing extreme aging sensor conditions. With a competitive degradation of only 8.91 percentage points&#x2014;lower than the neural-network baselines (ANN: 16.27%, DNN: 15.00%) and the tree ensemble RF (11.34%)&#x2014;the CNN&#x2009;+&#x2009;WVD framework demonstrates superior noise robustness for long-term deployment in real-world PV installations. By bridging advanced time&#x2013;frequency analysis with deep learning and systematically comparing against a broad set of machine&#x2011;learning baselines, the proposed framework enables fully automated, fine&#x2011;grained PV fault classification without manual feature engineering, thereby enhancing monitoring reliability, reducing downtime, and supporting predictive maintenance in large&#x2011;scale PV deployments.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seghiour</LastName><ForeName>Abdellatif</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electric Power and Energy Systems Research Laboratory, Ecole Sup&#xe9;rieure en G&#xe9;nie Electrique Et Energ&#xe9;tique d'Oran, 31000, Oran, Algeria. seghiour_abdellatif@esgee-oran.dz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bendjeddou</LastName><ForeName>Yacine</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electric Power and Energy Systems Research Laboratory, Ecole Sup&#xe9;rieure en G&#xe9;nie Electrique Et Energ&#xe9;tique d'Oran, 31000, Oran, Algeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mostefaoui</LastName><ForeName>Imene Meriem</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electric Power and Energy Systems Research Laboratory, Ecole Sup&#xe9;rieure en G&#xe9;nie Electrique Et Energ&#xe9;tique d'Oran, 31000, Oran, Algeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chouder</LastName><ForeName>Aissa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Engineering Laboratory (LGE), University of M'sila, BP 166, 28000, M'Sila, Algeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alharbi</LastName><ForeName>Hisham</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, College of Engineering, Taif University, 21944, Taif, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Humayd</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah S Bin</ForeName><Initials>ASB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Umm Al-Qura University, 21421, Makkah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wondimeneh</LastName><ForeName>Abebe Wondiferaw</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Faculty of Technology, Debre Markos University, P. BOX 269, Debre Markos, Ethiopia. abebe_wondiferaw@dmu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babqi</LastName><ForeName>Abdulrahman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, College of Engineering, Taif University, 21944, Taif, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Convolutional neural networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fault detection and diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photovoltaic systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renewable energy monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wigner-ville distribution</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41720880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13022248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39386-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39386-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sizkouhi, A. M., Aghaei, M. &amp; Esmailifar, S. M. A deep convolutional encoder-decoder architecture for autonomous fault detection of PV plants using multi-copters. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>223</b>, 217&#x2013;228 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2021.05.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, X. et al. Efficient fault diagnosis approach for solar photovoltaic array using a convolutional neural network in combination of generative adversarial network under small dataset. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>253</b>, 360&#x2013;374 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2022.12.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latoui, A. &amp; Daachi, M. E. H. Real-time monitoring of partial shading in large PV plants using Convolutional Neural Network. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>253</b>, 428&#x2013;438 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2023.02.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousif, H. &amp; Al-Milaji, Z. Fault detection from PV images using hybrid deep learning model. <i>Sol. Energy</i><b>267</b>, 112207 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2023.112207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Gao, W., Hong, C. &amp; Tu, Y. A novel series arc fault detection method for photovoltaic system based on multi-input neural network. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>140</b>, 108018 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2022.108018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, X. et al. Fault diagnosis model for photovoltaic array using a dual-channels convolutional neural network with a feature selection structure. <i>Energy Convers. Manag.</i><b>248</b>, 114777 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2021.114777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez, I. S., M&#xe1;rquez, F. P. G. &amp; Chaparro, J. P. Convolutional neural networks and Internet of Things for fault detection by aerial monitoring of photovoltaic solar plants. <i>Measurement</i>10.1016/J.MEASUREMENT.2024.114861 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.MEASUREMENT.2024.114861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu, J., Sun, Q., Qian, Z., Wei, L. &amp; Zareipour, H. Fault diagnosis for PV arrays considering dust impact based on transformed graphical features of characteristic curves and convolutional neural network with CBAM modules. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>355</b>, 122252 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2023.122252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, Y. Y. &amp; Pula, R. A. Detection and classification of faults in photovoltaic arrays using a 3D convolutional neural network. <i>Energy</i><b>246</b>, 123391 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2022.123391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellil, N., Aissat, A. &amp; Mellit, A. Fault diagnosis of photovoltaic modules using deep neural networks and infrared images under Algerian climatic conditions. <i>Energy</i><b>263</b>, 125902 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2022.125902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, Z., Liu, J., Shao, Z., Ma, Q. &amp; Liu, W. Machine learning innovations in renewable energy systems with integrated NRBO-TXAD for enhanced wind speed forecasting accuracy. <i>Electronics</i><b>14</b>, 2329 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14122329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Q., Fan, C. &amp; Guo, D. Forecasting future power via machine learning models for predicting energy consumption. <i>S&#x101;dhan&#x101;</i><b>50</b>(3), 225 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12046-025-02833-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., Hou, Z. &amp; Yin, T. Short-term power load forecast using OOA optimized bidirectional long short-term memory network with spectral attention for the frequency domain. <i>Energy Rep.</i><b>12</b>, 4891&#x2013;4908 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2024.10.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, Z., Wang, B., Liu, J., He, Y. &amp; Yao, Y. Physics-inspired time-frequency feature extraction and lightweight neural network for power quality disturbance classification. <i>Front. Phys.</i><b>13</b>, 1616367 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphy.2025.1616367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, Z., Liu, J. &amp; Yu, S. Enhanced analog circuit fault diagnosis via continuous wavelet transform and dual-stream convolutional fusion. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>(1), 19828 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-02596-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12141528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40473707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seghiour, A., Abbas, H. A., Chouder, A. &amp; Rabhi, A. Deep learning method based on autoencoder neural network applied to faults detection and diagnosis of photovoltaic system. <i>Simul. Model Pract. Theory</i><b>123</b>, 102704 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.simpat.2022.102704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garoudja, E., Chouder, A., Kara, K. &amp; Silvestre, S. An enhanced machine learning based approach for failures detection and diagnosis of PV systems. <i>Energy Convers. Manag.</i><b>151</b>, 496&#x2013;513 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2017.09.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chouder, A., Silvestre, S., Taghezouit, B. &amp; Karatepe, E. Monitoring, modelling and simulation of PV systems using LabVIEW. <i>Sol. Energy</i>10.1016/j.solener.2012.09.016 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2012.09.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmamoune, H., Abdellatif, S., Lakhdar, M., Aissa, C. &amp; Said, B. <i>An Improved Grey Wolf Optimizer for Parameter Extraction of Photovoltaic Cells</i>. https://www.icaens.com/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik, A., Haque, A., Kurukuru, V. S. B., Khan, M. A. &amp; Blaabjerg, F. Overview of fault detection approaches for grid connected photovoltaic inverters. <i>e-Prime &#x2013; Adv. Electr. Eng., Electron. Energy</i><b>2</b>, 100035 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prime.2022.100035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saifi, I. A., Amir, M., Haque, A. &amp; Iqbal, A. Investigation of condition monitoring system for grid connected photovoltaic (GCPV) system with power electronics converters using machine learning techniques. <i>e-Prime &#x2013; Adv. Electr. Eng., Electron. Energy</i><b>9</b>, 100722 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prime.2024.100722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seghiour, A., Seghier, T., Zegnini, B. &amp; Georgoulas, G. Multi-Class Classification Approach for the Diagnosis of Broken Rotor Bars Based on Air-Gap Magnetic Flux Density Spectrum. <i>Electrotehnica, Electronica</i>. <i>Automatica (EEA)</i><b>65</b>, 31&#x2013;39 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Fadili, Y. &amp; Boumhidi, I. New design of an intelligent electromagnetic torque controller based on neural network and fractional calculus: Variable-speed wind energy systems application. <i>e-Prime &#x2013; Adv. Electr. Eng., Electron. Energy</i><b>10</b>, 100829 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prime.2024.100829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh, S. N., Sugumaran, V., Subramanian, B., Josephin, J. S. F. &amp; Varuvel, E. G. A comparative study on bayes classifier for detecting photovoltaic module visual faults using deep learning features. <i>Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess.</i><b>64</b>, 103713 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, Y. Y. &amp; Pula, R. A. Diagnosis of photovoltaic faults using digital twin and PSO-optimized shifted window transformer. <i>Appl. Soft Comput.</i><b>150</b>, 111092 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2023.111092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri, A. F., Kichou, S., Oudira, H., Chouder, A. &amp; Silvestre, S. Fault Detection and Diagnosis of a Photovoltaic System Based on Deep Learning Using the Combination of a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) and Bidirectional Gated Recurrent Unit (Bi-GRU). <i>Sustain. (Switzerland)</i><b>16</b>, 1012 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, S. D., Wu, C. C. &amp; Sian, H. W. A novel fault diagnosis method for PV arrays using convolutional extension neural network with symmetrized dot pattern analysis. <i>IET Sci., Meas. Technol.</i><b>18</b>, 49&#x2013;64 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/smt2.12166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M. H., Hung, C. C., Lu, S. D., Lin, Z. H. &amp; Kuo, C. C. Fault Diagnosis for PV Modules Based on AlexNet and Symmetrized Dot Pattern. <i>Energies (Basel)</i><b>16</b>, 7563 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en16227563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chouder, A. &amp; Silvestre, S. Automatic supervision and fault detection of PV systems based on power losses analysis. <i>Energy Convers. Manag.</i><b>51</b>, 1929&#x2013;1937 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2010.02.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>