<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41844637</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Built-in electric field engineering in Co<sub>2</sub>N<sub>0.67</sub>/CoP heterostructures for glycerol electrooxidation-assisted hydrogen production.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70731-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Glycerol electrooxidation emerges as an electrochemically cogent paradigm to supplant the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction in water electrolysis. However, most non-precious catalysts still suffer from large electrolytic voltage and poor stability when operating at industrially relevant current densities. Here, we develop a heterostructure catalyst by immobilizing abundant cobalt phosphide (CoP) nanoparticles on conductive cobalt nitride (Co<sub>2</sub>N<sub>0.67</sub>) support, which results in the construction of a strong built-in electric field at the heterointerface. The optimal catalyst demonstrates effective bifunctional catalytic performance, yielding an industrial-level current density of 500&#x2009;mA&#x2009;cm<sup>-2</sup> at low potentials of -141 mV and 1.44&#x2009;V for hydrogen evolution and glycerol oxidation, respectively. When integrated into a flow cell system, this catalyst maintains good stability for 260&#x2009;hours at 1&#x2009;A&#x2009;cm<sup>-2</sup> (1.67&#x2009;V) while preserving &gt; 85% Faradaic efficiency for formate production. Both theoretical and experimental analyses substantiate that the built-in electric field drives directional electron transfer from CoP to Co<sub>2</sub>N<sub>0.67</sub>, forming an electron-deficient region at the CoP interface that enriches OH* species, and an electron-rich region at the Co<sub>2</sub>N<sub>0.67</sub> interface, facilitating hydrogen adsorption, thereby expediting the glycerol and H* co-adsorption process. Multiple in-situ spectroscopic characterizations verify the existence of a combined direct/indirect oxidation mechanism for glycerol electrooxidation. This discovery sets the stage for low-voltage hydrogen production by hybrid water splitting using the excess electrical power whenever and wherever available.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Dimensional Quantum Structures and Quantum Control of Ministry of Education, National &amp; Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for New Petro-chemical Materials and Fine Utilization of Resources, Hunan Research Center of the Basic Discipline for Quantum Effects and Quantum Technologies, Hunan Normal University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Dimensional Quantum Structures and Quantum Control of Ministry of Education, National &amp; Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for New Petro-chemical Materials and Fine Utilization of Resources, Hunan Research Center of the Basic Discipline for Quantum Effects and Quantum Technologies, Hunan Normal University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Haiqing</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0263-3026</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Dimensional Quantum Structures and Quantum Control of Ministry of Education, National &amp; Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for New Petro-chemical Materials and Fine Utilization of Resources, Hunan Research Center of the Basic Discipline for Quantum Effects and Quantum Technologies, Hunan Normal University, Changsha, China. hqzhou@hunnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-1005-7479</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Provincial Key Laboratory of Advanced Catalysis and Energy Materials, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Anqing Normal University, Anqing, P. R. China. zyan@hainanu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Jingying</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instrumental Analysis and Research Center, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Wenqi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Dimensional Quantum Structures and Quantum Control of Ministry of Education, National &amp; Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for New Petro-chemical Materials and Fine Utilization of Resources, Hunan Research Center of the Basic Discipline for Quantum Effects and Quantum Technologies, Hunan Normal University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Jiayi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Dimensional Quantum Structures and Quantum Control of Ministry of Education, National &amp; Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for New Petro-chemical Materials and Fine Utilization of Resources, Hunan Research Center of the Basic Discipline for Quantum Effects and Quantum Technologies, Hunan Normal University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Ligang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9879-0773</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Materials Science and Engineering, Kunming University of Science and Technology, Kunming, China. ligang.feng@kust.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-7956-771X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Low-Dimensional Quantum Structures and Quantum Control of Ministry of Education, National &amp; Local Joint Engineering Laboratory for New Petro-chemical Materials and Fine Utilization of Resources, Hunan Research Center of the Basic Discipline for Quantum Effects and Quantum Technologies, Hunan Normal University, Changsha, China. fyu@hunnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Interdisciplinary Studies, Hunan Normal University, Changsha, China. fyu@hunnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22572048</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41844637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70731-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70731-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Quan, L. et al. Bifunctional electrocatalysts for overall and hybrid water splitting. Chem. Rev. 124, 3694&#x2013;3812 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, B. &amp; Sun, Y. Innovative strategies for electrocatalytic water splitting. Acc. Chem. Res. 51, 1571&#x2013;1580 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, W. et al. Ultrastable supported oxygen evolution electrocatalyst formed by ripening-induced embedding. Science 387, 791&#x2013;796 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, K. et al. Polyoxometalated metal-organic framework superstructure for stable water oxidation. Science 388, 430&#x2013;436 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Y. et al. Coupled amorphous NiFeP/cystalline Ni<sub>3</sub>S<sub>2</sub> nanosheets enables accelerated reaction kinetics for high current density seawater electrolysis. App. Catal. B Environ. 352, 124028 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, H. et al. Pioneering built-in interfacial electric field for enhanced anion exchange membrane water electrolysis. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e202414647 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Z. W. et al. Unusual Sabatier principle on high entropy alloy catalysts for hydrogen evolution reactions. Nat. Commun. 15, 359 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Synergizing hydrogen spillover and deprotonation by the internal polarization field in a MoS<sub>2</sub>/NiPS<sub>3</sub> vertical heterostructure for boosted water electrolysis. Adv. Mater. 34, 2203615 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T., Cao, X. &amp; Jiao, L. Progress in hydrogen production coupled with electrochemical oxidation of small molecules. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 61, e202213328 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H. et al. In situ reconstruction of helical iron borophosphate precatalyst toward durable industrial alkaline water electrolysis and selective oxidation of alcohols. Adv. Funct. Mater. 33, 2303702 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, W. K. et al. Activating lattice oxygen in layered lithium oxides through cation vacancies for enhanced urea electrolysis. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 61, e202206050 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, L. S. et al. How to change the reaction chemistry on nonprecious metal oxide nanostructure materials for electrocatalytic oxidation of biomass-derived glycerol to renewable chemicals. Adv. Mater. 35, 2203285 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J. et al. Vertically-interlaced NiFeP/MXene electrocatalyst with tunable electronic structure for high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction. Sci. Bull. 66, 1063&#x2013;1072 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Visualizing dynamic competitive reconstruction of trimetallic hybrid catalysts for stable hybrid water electrolysis at large current density. Energy Environ. Sci. 18, 7695&#x2013;7707 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Z. et al. Promoting biomass electrooxidation via modulating proton and oxygen anion deintercalation in hydroxide. Nat. Commun. 13, 3777 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz, M. K., Bender, M. T. &amp; Choi, K. S. Predictive control of selective secondary alcohol oxidation of glycerol on NiOOH. Nat. Commun. 13, 5848 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, X. et al. Electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol to formic acid by CuCo<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub> spinel oxide nanostructure catalysts. ACS Catal. 10, 6741&#x2013;6752 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Q. et al. Integrative catalytic pairs for efficient multi-intermediate catalysis. Nat. Nanotechnol. 19, 1442&#x2013;1451 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q. et al. Active hydroxyl-mediated preferential cleavage of carbon-carbon bonds in electrocatalytic glycerol oxidation. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e202420942 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. et al. Cobalt-based Co<sub>3</sub>Mo<sub>3</sub>N/Co<sub>4</sub>N/Co metallic heterostructure as a highly active electrocatalyst for alkaline overall water splitting. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 63, e202319239 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z. et al. Electric field redistribution triggered surface adsorption and mass transfer to boost electrocatalytic glycerol upgrading coupled with hydrogen evolution. Adv. Energy Mater. 14, 2400851 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Facilitating OH* generation on atomic Pd-Cu dual sites towards efficient glycerol electrooxidation to formate. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e202425006 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsabban, M. M. et al. Unusual activity of rationally designed cobalt phosphide/oxide heterostructure composite for hydrogen production in alkaline medium. ACS Nano 16, 3906&#x2013;3916 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai, L. et al. Modulating built-in electric field via variable oxygen affinity for robust hydrogen evolution reaction in neutral media. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 61, e202116057 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D. et al. Collaborative multi-interface engineering and dynamic iron exchange boost robust bifunctional water electrolysis at 2 A cm<sup>&#x2212;2</sup>. Energy Environ. Sci. 18, 1320&#x2013;1330 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. et al. Heterojunction catalyst in electrocatalytic water splitting. Coord. Chem. Rev. 439, 213953 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, G., Rui, K., Dou, S. X. &amp; Sun, W. Heterostructures for electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction: a review. Adv. Funct. Mater. 28, 1803291 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, Y. et al. Ultrafine homologous Ni<sub>2</sub>P-Co<sub>2</sub>P heterostructures via space-confined topological transformation for superior urea electrolysis. Adv. Funct. Mater. 33, 2303300 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Radio frequency plasma-engraved vacancy engineering towards robust hydrogen-evolving catalysts with large-current stable catalytic activity for over 1000 h. Sci. China Mater. 68, 1129&#x2013;1137 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. et al. Mott&#x2013;Schottky barrier enabling high-performance hydrazine-assisted hydrogen generation at ampere-level current densities. Adv. Funct. Mater. 35, 2401011 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, X. et al. Mott&#x2013;Schottky construction boosted plasmon thermal and electronic effects on the Ag/CoV-LDH nanohybrids for highly-efficient water oxidation. Adv. Mater. 36, 2313057 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. et al. Constructing built-in electric field in heterogeneous nanowire arrays for efficient overall water electrolysis. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 62, e202302795 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, S. et al. Doping Mo triggers charge distribution optimization and P vacancy of Ni<sub>2</sub>P@Ni<sub>12</sub>P<sub>5</sub> heterojunction for industrial electrocatalytic production of adipic acid and H<sub>2</sub>. Adv. Mater. 37, 2502523 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Mo-Ni-based heterojunction with fine-customized d-band centers for hydrogen production coupled with benzylamine electrooxidation in low alkaline medium. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 62, e202306640 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Diluting the resistance of built-in electric fields in oxygen vacancy-enriched Ru/NiMoO<sub>4</sub><sub>&#x2212;x</sub> for enhanced hydrogen spillover in alkaline seawater splitting. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 63, e202316319 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, W. et al. Dynamic restructuring of asymmetric built-in electric field catalysts facilitates the efficient water splitting. Adv. Funct. Mater. 35, 2422734 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Manipulation on active electronic states of metastable phase &#x3b2;-NiMoO<sub>4</sub> for large current density hydrogen evolution. Nat. Commun. 12, 5960 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, F. et al. Electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution of ultrathin Co-Mo<sub>5</sub>N<sub>6</sub> heterojunction with interfacial electron redistribution. Adv. Energy Mater. 10, 2002176 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi, N. et al. Polyhedral coordination determined Co&#x2013;O activity for electrochemical oxidation of biomass alcohols. Adv. Energy Mater. 13, 2301572 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Valence engineering via manganese-doping on cobalt nitride nanoarrays for efficient electrochemically paired glycerol valorization and H<sub>2</sub> production. Adv. Funct. Mater. 34, 2316718 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, L. et al. High entropy alloy electrocatalytic electrode toward alkaline glycerol valorization coupling with acidic hydrogen production. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 144, 7224&#x2013;7235 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, X. et al. Hydrogen evolution linked to selective oxidation of glycerol over CoMoO<sub>4</sub>&#x2014;A theoretically predicted catalyst. Adv. Energy Mater. 12, 2103750 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Efficient electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol via promoted OH* generation over single-atom-bismuth-doped spinel Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>. ACS Catal 12, 12432&#x2013;12443 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, Q. et al. Electrochemical biomass upgrading coupled with hydrogen production under industrial-level current density. Adv. Mater. 35, 2300935 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, B. et al. Seeded synthesis of hollow PdSn intermetallic nanomaterials for highly efficient electrocatalytic glycerol oxidation. Adv. Mater. 35, 2302233 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. Y. et al. Re and Ru co-doped transition metal alloy as a bifunctional catalyst for electrooxidation of glycerol to formate coupled with H<sub>2</sub> production. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e202501766 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, Z. et al. Pt<sub>1</sub> enhanced C&#x2013;H activation synergistic with Pt<sub>n</sub> catalysis for glycerol cascade oxidation to glyceric acid. Nat. Commun. 13, 5467 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, H. Z. et al. Ambient &#x3b3;-rays-mediated noble-metal deposition on defect-rich manganese oxide for glycerol-assisted H<sub>2</sub> evolution at industrial-level current density. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 62, e202314569 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, W. S. et al. Controlled electrocatalytic glycerol upgrading to glyceraldehyde in near neutral media by cobalt oxide lattice sctivation. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 64, e202505059 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, W. et al. Controllable electron distribution reconstruction of spinel NiCo<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub> boosting glycerol oxidation at elevated current density. Adv. Funct. Mater. 34, 2306995 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y. et al. Integrated catalytic sites for highly efficient electrochemical oxidation of the aldehyde and hydroxyl groups in 5-hydroxymethylfurfural. ACS Catal 12, 4242&#x2013;4251 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wygant, B. R., Kawashima, K. &amp; Mullins, C. B. Catalyst or precatalyst? The effect of oxidation on transition metal carbide, pnictide, and chalcogenide oxygen evolution catalysts. ACS Energy Lett 3, 2956&#x2013;2966 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, Y. et al. ZIF-8@ZIF-67-derived nitrogen-doped porous carbon confined CoP polyhedron targeting superior potassium-ion storage. Small 16, 1906566 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elshahawy, A. M. et al. Sulfur-doped cobalt phosphide nanotube arrays for highly stable hybrid supercapacitor. Nano Energy 39, 162&#x2013;171 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, P. et al. Understanding the synergistic effects and structural evolution of Co(OH)<sub>2</sub> and Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> toward boosting electrochemical charge storage. Adv. Funct. Mater. 32, 2108644 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, J. et al. Enhanced stability and narrowed d-band gap of Ce-doped Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> for rechargeable aqueous Zn-air battery. Adv. Funct. Mater. 33, 2212021 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing, C. et al. Electrocatalyst with dynamic formation of the dual-active site from the dual pathway observed by in situ Raman spectroscopy. ACS Catal. 12, 10276&#x2013;10284 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. et al. CoSe<sub>2</sub>@NiSe-CoSe<sub>2</sub> heterojunction for enhanced electrocatalytic 5-hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation coupled with hydrogen evolution. Adv. Funct. Mater. 35, 2421447 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X. et al. Interface engineering of Mo-doped Ni<sub>2</sub>P/Fe<sub>x</sub>P-V multiheterostructure for efficient dual-pH hydrogen evolution and overall water splitting. Adv. Funct. Mater. 34, 2400397 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. A fundamental viewpoint on the hydrogen spillover phenomenon of electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution. Nat. Commun. 12, 3502 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, Y. Y. et al. Mott&#x2013;Schottky heterojunction modulating iron-vanadium oxide for high-performance aqueous zinc battery cathodes. Nano Lett. 25, 1002&#x2013;1009 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudarev, S. L. et al. Electron-energy-loss spectra and the structural stability of nickel oxide: an LSDA+U study. Phys. Rev. B. 57, 1505&#x2013;1509 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, R. et al. Tracking the role of defect types in Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> structural evolution and active motifs during oxygen evolution reaction. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 145, 2271&#x2013;2281 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henkelman, G., Uberuaga, B. P. &amp; J&#xf3;nsson, H. A climbing image nudged elastic band method for finding saddle points and minimum energy paths. J. Chem. Phys. 113, 9901&#x2013;9904 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahn, A. Fermi level, work function and vacuum level. Mater. Horiz. 3, 7&#x2013;10 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, L. et al. Work function: fundamentals, measurement, calculation, engineering, and applications. Phys. Rev. Appl. 19, 037001 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>