<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41857768</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2059-0628</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in simulation (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Simul (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Education that Empowers: A critical realist evaluation of a novel incivility-focused immersive simulation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s41077-026-00413-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">When we experience incivility, or rudeness, our performance suffers, negatively impacting patient safety. Immersive simulation-based education (SBE) has been under-explored as an educational strategy that may empower individuals to challenge incivility. Psychological empowerment was conceptualised by Spreitzer as four cognitive domains (meaning, competence, self-determination, and impact) that influence motivation and an active orientation towards work. We aimed to explore the mechanisms underlying the influence of incivility-based immersive SBE on the experiences of medical registrars when facing workplace incivility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We situated this study within a critical realist paradigm, a philosophical stance which aims to provide explanatory power to understanding the mechanisms that drive social reality. We conducted semi-structured interviews with 11 medical registrars at least four months after an incivility-based immersive simulation scenario. Interviews focused on participants&#x2019; experiences and reflections of workplace incivility, and the potential impact of their simulation experience. Data were analysed using template analysis, utilising Spreitzer&#x2019;s theory of psychological empowerment as the guiding framework.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Incivility-based SBE stimulated powerful reflection relating to the cognitive domains of psychological empowerment. <i>Meaning</i> encompassed a sense that civility was important, with mechanisms of awareness and advocacy across boundaries. <i>Competence</i> referred to having the skills to manage incivility, with mechanisms of mindful response, self-regulation and perspective taking. <i>Self-determination</i> related to having autonomy when experiencing incivility, with mechanisms of identity formation and risk assessment. <i>Impact</i> was re-conceptualised as <i>transfer</i>, referring to the socio-structural mediators of transfer to practice, with mechanisms of socio-political support, participatory culture, and systems.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">We highlight the potential role of immersive SBE as a powerful tool to explore workplace incivility. SBE may influence behavioural change through provoking reflection related to psychological empowerment. We explore SBE as an influencer of the nuanced risk assessment that occurs when individuals face incivility. This framework of psychological empowerment has utility in designing effective SBE focused on relational aspects of work.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s41077-026-00413-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ralston</LastName><ForeName>Katherine</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Directorate, NHS Lothian, Little France Crescent, Old Dalkeith Road, Edinburgh, EH16 4SA, UK. Katherine.ralston@nhs.scot.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rae</LastName><ForeName>Valerie</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Directorate, NHS Lothian, Little France Crescent, Old Dalkeith Road, Edinburgh, EH16 4SA, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mellanby</LastName><ForeName>Ed</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Directorate, NHS Lothian, Little France Crescent, Old Dalkeith Road, Edinburgh, EH16 4SA, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hislop</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Education, Edinburgh Medical School, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tallentire</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Directorate, NHS Lothian, Little France Crescent, Old Dalkeith Road, Edinburgh, EH16 4SA, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NHS Education for Scotland, Edinburgh, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Simul (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101700425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2059-0628</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">civility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">empowerment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study received ethical approval from NHS Education for Scotland (NES/Res/46/22/Med). Participants gave informed written consent for data collection and the publication of anonymised results. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: Victoria Tallentire is an Associate Editor for Advances in Simulation.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41857768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13001293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-026-00413-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s41077-026-00413-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Guppy JH, Widlund H, Munro R, et al. Incivility in healthcare: the impact of poor communication. BMJ Lead. 2023;883&#x2013;7. 10.1136/leader-2022-000717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37419661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villafranca A, Fast I, Jacobsohn E. Disruptive behavior in the operating room: prevalence, consequences, prevention, and management. Curr Opin Anesthesiology. 2018;31(3):366&#x2013;74. 10.1097/ACO.0000000000000592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACO.0000000000000592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29668524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mammen BN, Lam L, Hills D. Newly qualified graduate nurses&#x2019; experiences of workplace incivility in healthcare settings: an integrative review. Nurse Educ Pract. 2023;69:103611. 10.1016/j.nepr.2023.103611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nepr.2023.103611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37002995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westbrook J, Sunderland N, Li L, et al. The prevalence and impact of unprofessional behaviour among hospital workers: a survey in seven Australian hospitals. Med J Aust. 2021;214(1):31&#x2013;7. 10.5694/mja2.50849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/mja2.50849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33174226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riskin A, Erez A, Foulk TA, et al. The impact of rudeness on medical team performance: A randomized trial. Pediatrics. 2015;136(3):487&#x2013;95. 10.1542/peds.2015-1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26260718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porath CL, Erez A. Does rudeness really matter? The effects of rudeness on task performance and helpfulness. Acad Manag J. 2007;50(5):1181&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen JM, Aschenbrenner A, Merkel R, et al. A Mixed-Methods systematic review of interventions to address incivility in nursing. J Nurs Educ. 2020;59(6):319&#x2013;26. 10.3928/01484834-20200520-04.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/01484834-20200520-04</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purdy E, Borchert L, El-Bitar A, et al. Taking simulation out of its safe container&#x2014;exploring the bidirectional impacts of psychological safety and simulation in an emergency department. Adv Simul. 2022;7(1):5. 10.1186/s41077-022-00201-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-022-00201-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazil V, Purdy E, Alexander C, et al. Improving the relational aspects of trauma care through translational simulation. Adv Simul. 2019;4(1):10. 10.1186/s41077-019-0100-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-019-0100-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6528296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31139436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson LM, Pearson CM. Tit for tat? The spiraling effect of incivility in the workplace. Acad Manage Rev. 1999;24(3):452&#x2013;71. 10.5465/amr.1999.2202131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amr.1999.2202131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Civility Saves Lives. [23/04/2025]. Available from: https://www.civilitysaveslives.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan PA, Oeppen RS. The role of human factors in improving patient safety. Trends Urol Men&#x2019;s Health. 2022;13(3):30&#x2013;3. 10.1002/tre.858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tre.858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller S, Yule S, Zagarese V, et al. Predictors and triggers of incivility within healthcare teams: a systematic review of the literature. BMJ Open. 2020;10(6). 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-035471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32513884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel K, Kimberly B, Robert I, et al. Exposure to incivility hinders clinical performance in a simulated operative crisis. BMJ Qual Saf. 2019;28(9):750. 10.1136/bmjqs-2019-009598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2019-009598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31152113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amick AE, Schrepel C, Bann M, et al. From battles to burnout: investigating the role of interphysician conflict in physician burnout. Acad Med. 2023;98(9):1076&#x2013;82. 10.1097/ACM.0000000000005226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0000000000005226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37043749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Ambra AM, Andrews DR. Incivility, retention and new graduate nurses: an integrated review of the literature. J Nurs Adm Manag. 2014;22(6):735&#x2013;42. 10.1111/jonm.12060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jonm.12060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23927565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS England. Civility and Respect [23/04/2025]. Available from: https://www.england.nhs.uk/supporting-our-nhs-people/health-and-wellbeing-programmes/civility-and-respect/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Council GM, West M, Coia D. Caring for Doctors. Caring for Patients. 2019 [23/04/2025]. Available from: https://www.gmc-uk.org/-/media/documents/caring-for-doctors-caring-for-patients_pdf-80706341.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osatuke K, Leiter M, Belton L, et al. Civility, respect and engagement at the workplace (CREW): A National organization development program at the department of veterans affairs. J Manage Policies Practices. 2013;1(2):25&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupras DM, Edson RS. The Vanderbilt method for resolving unprofessional behavior. Ann Intern Med. 2008;149(10):775&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-149-10-200811180-00029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19017609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver N, Edgar S, Mellanby E, et al. The Scottish simulation &#x2018;KSDP&#x2019; design framework: a sense-making and ordered approach for Building aligned simulation programmes. Adv Simul. 2024;9(1):52. 10.1186/s41077-024-00321-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-024-00321-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11673891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39731140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark CM, Kardong-Edgren S, Willhaus J. Pilot study using cognitive Rehearsal, Simulation, and biomarker data to address workplace incivility. J Contin Educ Nurs. 2023;54(2):79&#x2013;. 10.3928/00220124-20230113-07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/00220124-20230113-07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36720094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose KA, Jenkins SD, Astroth K, et al. Lessons learned: Raising awareness of civility and incivility using Semi-Virtual reality simulation. J Nurs Educ. 2020;59(8):461&#x2013;4. 10.3928/01484834-20200723-08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/01484834-20200723-08</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32757011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kile D, Eaton M, deValpine M, et al. The effectiveness of education and cognitive rehearsal in managing nurse-to-nurse incivility: A pilot study. J Nurs Adm Manag. 2019;27(3):543&#x2013;52. 10.1111/jonm.12709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jonm.12709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30171666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stagg SJ, Sheridan DJ, Jones RA, et al. Workplace bullying: the effectiveness of a workplace program. Workplace Health Saf. 2013;61(8):333&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23875566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrner J, Sommers K, Zappa M, et al. Decreasing workplace incivility. Nurs Manag. 2016;47(1):22&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.NUMA.0000475622.91398.c3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikstaitis T, Simko LC. Incivility among intensive care nurses: the effects of an educational intervention. Dimens Crit Care Nurs. 2014;33(5):293&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DCC.0000000000000061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25140748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgar S, Forrest K, McKimm J. Essential simulation in clinical education / edited by Kirsty Forrest, Judy McKimm, Simon Edgar. Chichester, West Sussex: John Wiley and Sons; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison EW. Employee voice and silence. Annu Rev Organ Psychol Organ Behav. 2014;1(1):173&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-orgpsych-031413-091328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly Guris RJ, Duarte SS, Miller CR, et al. Training novice anaesthesiology trainees to speak up for patient safety. Br J Anaesth. 2019;122(6):767&#x2013;75. 10.1016/j.bja.2019.01.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2019.01.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30916005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arriaga AF, Szyld D, Pian-Smith MCM. Real-Time debriefing after critical events. Anesthesiol Clin. 2020;38(4):801&#x2013;20. 10.1016/j.anclin.2020.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anclin.2020.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7552980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33127029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman Z, Perelman V, McLuckie D et al. Challenging authority during an Emergency&#x2014;the effect of a teaching intervention. Crit Care Med. 2017;45(8).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28471813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dongen D, Guldenmund F, Grossmann I, et al. Classification of influencing factors of speaking-up behaviour in hospitals: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2024;24(1):1657. 10.1186/s12913-024-12138-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-024-12138-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11681692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39732664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vauk S, Seelandt JC, Huber K, et al. Exposure to incivility does not hinder speaking up: a randomised controlled high-fidelity simulation-based study. Br J Anaesth. 2022;129(5):776&#x2013;87. 10.1016/j.bja.2022.07.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bja.2022.07.050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreitzer GM. Psychological empowerment in the workplace: Dimensions, measurement, and validation. Acad Manag J. 1995;38(5):1442&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/256865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreitzer GM. Toward the integration of two perspectives: A review of social-structural and psychological empowerment at work. The handbook of organizational behavior C Cooper et J barling. dir Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanta LL, Eliason ARM. Application of an empowerment model to improve civility in nursing education. Nurse Educ Pract. 2014;14(1):82&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.nepr.2013.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nepr.2013.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23838091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanter RM. Men and women of the corporation. New York: Basic books; 1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreitzer GM. Social structural characteristics of psychological empowerment. Acad Manag J. 1996;39(2):483&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/256789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar R. A realist theory of science. Routledge; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellaway RH, Kehoe A, Illing J. Critical realism and realist inquiry in medical education. Acad Med. 2020;95(7):984&#x2013;8. 10.1097/acm.0000000000003232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/acm.0000000000003232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxwell JA. A realist approach for qualitative research. Thousand Oaks: SAGE; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong G, Greenhalgh T, Westhorp G, et al. Realist methods in medical education research: what are they and what can they contribute? Med Educ. 2012;46(1):89&#x2013;96. 10.1111/j.1365-2923.2011.04045.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2923.2011.04045.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22150200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerins J, Ralston K, Stirling SA, et al. Training as imagined? A critical realist analysis of scotland&#x2019;s internal medicine simulation programme. Adv Simul (Lond). 2024;9(1):27. 10.1186/s41077-024-00299-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-024-00299-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11210083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38926742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher AJ. Applying critical realism in qualitative research: methodology Meets method. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2017;20(2):181&#x2013;94. 10.1080/13645579.2016.1144401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13645579.2016.1144401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collier A. Critical realism: an introduction to Roy Bhaskar&#x2019;s philosophy. Verso Books;&#xa0;1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver N, Shippey B, Edgar S, et al. The Scottish centre debrief model. Int J Healthc Simul. 2023;1. 10.54531/lvxq6860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King N, Brooks JM. Template analysis for business and management students. London: SAGE Publications Ltd; 2017.3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston K, Smith SE, Kerins J, et al. Safety on the ground: using critical incident technique to explore the factors influencing medical registrars&#x2019; provision of safe care. BMJ Open Qual. 2024;13(1):e002641. 10.1136/bmjoq-2023-002641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjoq-2023-002641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10900368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38413094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerins J, Smith SE, Tallentire VR. Ego massaging that helps: a framework analysis study of internal medicine trainees&#x2019; interprofessional collaboration approaches. Med Educ Online. 2023;28(1):2243694. 10.1080/10872981.2023.2243694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10872981.2023.2243694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10402837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37535844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thom O&#x2019;Neill, Merriman A, Robinson S. Beyond bystanding: a novel simulation methodology addressing interprofessional microaggressions. Journal of Healthcare Simulation. 2025(SRSIS 1). 10.54531/hgsr6094</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picketts L, Warren MD, Bohnert C. Diversity and inclusion in simulation: addressing ethical and psychological safety concerns when working with simulated participants. BMJ Simul Technol Enhanc Learn. 2021;7(6):590&#x2013;9. 10.1136/bmjstel-2020-000853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjstel-2020-000853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8936749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35520976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauer PA, Thompson CE, Verzella MM. Empowering nursing students to address incivility. Clin Simul Nurs. 2018;21. 10.1016/j.ecns.2018.06.004. :40&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brazil V, McLean D, Lowe B, et al. A relational approach to improving interprofessional teamwork in post-partum haemorrhage (PPH). BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):1108. 10.1186/s12913-022-08463-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-08463-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9438096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36050714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brydges R, Nemoy L, Ng S, et al. Getting everyone to the table: exploring everyday and everynight work to consider &#x2018;latent social threats&#x2019; through interprofessional tabletop simulation. Adv Simul. 2021;6(1):39. 10.1186/s41077-021-00191-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41077-021-00191-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34732264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rixon A, Skinner C, Wilson S. What factors help and hinder efforts to address incivility in Australasian emergency departments? A modified Delphi study of FACEM perspectives. Emerg Med Australasia. 2023;35(3):420&#x2013;6. 10.1111/1742-6723.14132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1742-6723.14132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36436511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips T, Smith P. Emotional and behavioural responses to everyday incivility:challenging the fear/avoidance paradigm. J Sociol. 2004;40(4):378&#x2013;99. 10.1177/1440783304048382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1440783304048382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortina LM, Sandy Hershcovis M, Clancy KBH. The embodiment of insult: A theory of biobehavioral response to workplace incivility. J Manag. 2021;48(3):738&#x2013;63. 10.1177/0149206321989798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0149206321989798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8918878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35299898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watters C, Reedy G, Ross A, et al. Does interprofessional simulation increase self-efficacy: a comparative study. BMJ Open. 2015;5(1):e005472. 10.1136/bmjopen-2014-005472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2014-005472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4298099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25586366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin AE, Lee CS. Effectiveness of simulation for improvement in self-efficacy among novice nurses: a meta-analysis. J Nurs Educ. 2014;53(11):607&#x2013;14. 10.3928/01484834-20141023-03.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/01484834-20141023-03</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25350902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kameg K, Howard VM, Clochesy J, et al. The impact of high fidelity human simulation on self-efficacy of communication skills. Issues Ment Health Nurs. 2010;31(5):315&#x2013;23. 10.3109/01612840903420331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/01612840903420331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20394477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung C-C, Kao H-F, Liu H-C, et al. Effects of simulation-based learning on nursing students&#x2019; perceived competence, self-efficacy, and learning satisfaction: A repeat measurement method. Nurse Educ Today. 2020;97:104725. 10.1016/j.nedt.2020.104725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2020.104725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33373813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malterud K, Siersma VD, Guassora AD. Sample size in qualitative interview studies:guided by information power. Qual Health Res. 2016;26(13):1753&#x2013;60. 10.1177/1049732315617444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732315617444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26613970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>