<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41535420</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Lightweight Sequential AI Framework for Real Time Intrusion Detection in Dynamic Vehicular Networks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5217</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5217</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5217</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-36103-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vehicular Ad-Hoc Networks (VANETs) is a type&#x2019;s of Mobile Ad Hoc Networks (MANETs) designed to facilitate wireless communication among vehicles as well as between vehicles and fixed roadside infrastructure. These networks play a vital role in the development of Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITS), aiming to optimize traffic flow, and provide infotainment services to drivers and passengers. Due to high node mobility, frequent topology changes, and decentralized communication architectures of VANET, making real-time and reliable data exchange a complex challenge. Moreover, open and dynamic nature of VANETs is also susceptible to wide range of security threats. Ensuring secure and efficient communication within VANETs faced more challenging s. To address these challenges, a novel <b>Seq</b>uential <b>AI-</b>Powered Lightweight Intrusion Detection System (Seq-AIIDS) is proposed. The main aim of Seq-AIIDS is to enhance the accuracy of intrusion detection with minimal time consumption. The proposed Seq-AIIDS comprises of four major steps namely data acquisition, scrubbing feature selection and classification. Initially, the system performs data acquisition by gathering relevant samples from a dataset. Following this, Rosenthal correlation function is employed for feature selection, identifying the more necessary features for accurate intrusion detection. With these refined features, the system proceeds to the classification phase, where a liquid neural network model is utilized to differentiate between normal and malicious network behavior. The architecture adopts a sequential AI-driven framework capable of detecting and responding to cyber attacks in Real-time detection high-mobility vehicular networks. Fine-tuning the layers in the liquid neural network is an essential step using the multipoint spiral search optimization algorithm thereby minimizing both training and validation errors and increasing the accuracy of the intrusion detection. To evaluate system performance, various metrics are considered, including detection accuracy, precision, recall, F1-score, specificity, and intrusion detection latency relative to the of input data samples. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed Seq-AIIDS outperforms traditional methods, offering superior accuracy and lower computational latency, making it highly effective for security improvement in Dynamic and Decentralized VANETs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeyaram</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Engineering (AI&amp;ML), Easwari Engineering College, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India. jeyaram.g@eec.srmrmp.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vidhya</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Artificial Intelligence and Data Science, Easwari Engineering College, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhanaraj</LastName><ForeName>Rajesh Kumar</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis Institute of Computer Studies and Research (SICSR), Symbiosis International (Deemed University), Pune, India. rajesh.dhanaraj@sicsr.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alabdultif</LastName><ForeName>Abdulatif</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science, College of Computer, Qassim University, Buraydah, 52571, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep Learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intrusion detection system (IDS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liquid Neural Network model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multipoint spiral search optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rosenthal correlation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sequential AI</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41535420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12881473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-36103-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-36103-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>SuhailaZeinElabideen Omer, F. H. &amp; Ahmad, A. S. F. A. Binary classification of Low-Rate DoS attacks using long Short-Term memory Feed-Forward (LSTM-FF) Intrusion Detection System (IDS), Engineering Science and Technology, an International Journal, Elsevier, 66, 1&#x2013;16. 10.1016/j.jestch.2025.102049 (2025). [LSTM].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FatemehEbrahimi, R. &amp; Javidan <i>Reza Akbari &amp;YasinHosseini, Intrusion Detection in the Internet of Things Using Convolutional Neural Networks: an Explainable AI approach, Cybersecurity</i> 8, 1&#x2013;22 (Springer, 2025). 10.1186/s42400-025-00369-2[CNN].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KanikaGuptaa, P. N. C. &amp; Himanshi A GNN-based novel approach to detect malicious traffic inintrusion detection system. <i>Procedia Comput. Sci. Elsevier</i>. <b>258</b>, 3184&#x2013;3193. 10.1016/j.procs.2025.04.576 (2025). [GNN].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.procs.2025.04.576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christy, C., Nirmala, A., Mary Odilya, A., Isabella Amali, A. &amp; Teena &amp; Machine learning based multi-stage intrusion detection system and feature selection ensemble security in cloud assisted vehicular ad hoc networks. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 1&#x2013;15. 10.1038/s41598-025-96303-0 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-96303-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12297508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40715607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waqar Khan, J., Ahmad, N., Alasbali, AlanoudAl Mazroa, M. S., Alshehri, M. S. &amp; Khan A novel transformer-based explainable AI approach using SHAP for intrusion detection in vehicular ad hoc networks. <i>Comput. Networks Elsevier</i>. <b>270</b>, 1&#x2013;18. 10.1016/j.comnet.2025.111575 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2025.111575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muawia, A. et al. Connected vehicles security: A lightweight machine learning model to detect VANET attacks. <i>World Electr. Veh. J.</i><b>16, 6</b>,, 1&#x2013;29. 10.3390/wevj16060324 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/wevj16060324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopi, R. &amp; ThiruppathyKesavan, V. Md. JakirHossen&amp; nor HidayatiBinti Abdul Aziz, Bi directional sparse attention recurrent autoencoder based intrusion detection for VANET security with tuna swarm optimization. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 1&#x2013;18. 10.1038/s41598-025-02729-x (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-02729-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12106616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40419606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafiq Ahmed, M. H. &amp; Anisi, A. I. D. A. S. AI-Enhanced intrusion detection and authentication for autonomous vehicles. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>26, 8</b>,, 12548&#x2013;12557. 10.1109/TITS.2025.3562919 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2025.3562919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miriam &amp; ZambudioMart&#xed;nez Rafael Marin-PerezandAntonio Fernando Skarmeta Gomez, development of an In-Vehicle intrusion detection model integrating federated learning and LSTM networks. <i>Information</i><b>16</b> (4). 10.3390/info16040292 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Tao &amp; Xiyang, Z. Spatial-Temporal cooperative In-Vehicle network intrusion detection method based on federated learning. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>13</b>, 97194&#x2013;97207. 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3575849 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3575849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Li, J. C. Y. W. S. &amp; Dai, L. K. ConvGRU: A Lightweight Intrusion Detection System for Vehicle Networks Based on Shallow CNN and GRU, IEEE Access, 13, 73297&#x2013;73318.10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3563908 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Han LiangJie Li,Yuanyuan Song, FEXGBIDS: Federated XGBoost-Based Intrusion Detection System for In-Vehicle Network, IEEE Access, 13, 89399&#x2013;89410.10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3569356 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, W. E. S. A. T. A. AI-Driven Ensemble Classifier for Jamming Attack Detection in VANETs to Enhance Security in Smart Cities, IEEE Access, 13, 50687&#x2013;50713. 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3552544 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EasaAlalwany,ImadMahgoub, B., Alsharif &amp; Alfahaid, A. An intelligent Ensemble-Based detection of. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>15</b> (12), 1&#x2013;22. 10.3390/app15126869 (2025). Vehicle Network Intrusion.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15126869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, S., Senouci, S. M., Brik, B. &amp; AbdelwahabBoualouache A privacy-preserving Self-Supervised Learning-based intrusion detection system for 5G-V2X networks. <i>Ad Hoc Networks Elsevier</i>. <b>166</b>, 1&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.adhoc.2024.103674 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.adhoc.2024.103674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usha, G. &amp; Karthikeyan, H. Kumar Gautam&amp; Nikhil Pachauri, DDoS attack detection in intelligent transport systems using adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system. <i>Sci. Rep. 15</i>. 1&#x2013;16. 10.1038/s41598-025-06719-x (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12218899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40594577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad Wazid,Jaskaran Singh,Charvi, Pandey, R., Simon Sherratt, A. K., Das &amp; DebasisGiri Explainable deep Learning-Enabled malware attack detection for IoT-Enabled intelligent transportation systems. <i>IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst.</i><b>(26</b> (5), 7231&#x2013;7244. 10.1109/TITS.2025.3525505 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2025.3525505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julia &amp; Boone TolunaySeyfi,FatemehAfghah, A joint Reconstruction-Triplet loss autoencoder approach toward unseen attack detection in IoV networks. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>12</b> (16), 33258&#x2013;33270. 10.1109/JIOT.2025.3576219 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3576219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TanerGuven&amp;ZiyaCihanTaysi Creating a realistic sybil attack dataset for inter-vehicle communication, Peer-to-Peer Networking and Applications, Springer, 18, 1&#x2013;18. 10.1007/s12083-025-02058-w (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ThiruppathyKesavanVenkatasamy, M. JakirHossen, GopiRamasamy&amp; nor HidayatiBinti Abdul Aziz, intrusion detection system for V2X communication in VANET networks using machine learning-based cryptographic protocols. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 1&#x2013;18. 10.1038/s41598-024-82313-x (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-82313-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11685416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39738363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayaz Hassan, Z. S. et al. A hybrid approach for intrusion detection in vehicular networks using feature selection and dimensionality reduction with optimized deep learning. <i>PLoS ONE</i>. <b>20</b> (2), 1&#x2013;18. 10.1371/journal.pone.0312752 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0312752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11801628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39913503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghunath, M., Kawale, D. R. V., Patil, D. L. V., Patil, D. S. A. &amp; Mahajan FuzzyRankingforEnhancedSecurity:OptimizingFeature selection in VANET intrusion detection. <i>Adv. Nonlinear Variational Inequalities</i>. <b>27</b> (3), 728&#x2013;738. 10.52783/anvi.v27.1439 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52783/anvi.v27.1439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EslamAbdelkreem, S. H., Ashraf &amp; Tammam Feature engineering impact on position falsification attacks detection in vehicular ad-hoc network, International Journal of Information Security, (Springer, 2024). 23, 1939&#x2013;1961. 10.1007/s10207-024-00830-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, S. W. Y. W. B. Z. J. &amp; Dai, Y. S. Y. Intrusion detection system for vehicular networks based on MobileNetV3. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>12</b>, 106285&#x2013;106302. 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3437416 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3437416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari, P. K., Prakash, S. &amp; Aggarwal, M. AnimeshTripathi,Tiansheng Yang,Rajkumar Singh Rathore, A Secure and Robust Machine Learning Model for Intrusion Detection in Internet of Vehicles, IEEE Access, 13, 20678&#x2013;20690. 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3532716 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amandeep Verma, R., Saha, G., Kumar, M., Conti, T. H. &amp; Kim, P. R. E. V. I. R. Fortifying vehicular networks against denial of service attacks. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>12</b>, 48301&#x2013;48320. 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3382992 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3382992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuvva Anjali, R., Goyal &amp; Balaji, G. N. X-GEVON- a novel explainable intelligent network to detect the multiple attacks in vanet systems, Discover Computing, (Springer, 2025). 28, 1&#x2013;31. 10.1007/s10791-025-09696-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, K. Z. J. Y. Y. S. L., Ou, W. &amp; Han, W. Intrusion detection model for internet of vehicles using GRIPCA and OWELM. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>12</b>, 28911&#x2013;28925. 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3368392 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3368392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na, I. S. Federal deep learning approach of intrusion detection system for In-Vehicle communication network security. <i>IEEE Access.</i><b>13</b>, 2215&#x2013;2228. 10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3521661 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2024.3521661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsaid, S. A., EsraaShehab, A. M. &amp; Mattar Ahmad Taher Azar &amp; Ibrahim A. Hameed, Hybrid intrusion detection models based on GWO optimized deep learning, Discover Applied Sciences, Springer, 6, 1&#x2013;34. (2024). 10.1007/s42452-024-06209-1</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>