<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41680074</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-203X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International psychogeriatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int Psychogeriatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of EEG features between patients with and without reduced <sup>123</sup>I-MIBG myocardial scintigraphy uptake: A 6-year retrospective study of 230 patients with suspected dementia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100197</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100197</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.inpsyc.2026.100197</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1041-6102(26)00015-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Dementia with Lewy bodies (DLB) remains a diagnostic challenge due to its clinical overlap with other dementia-related diseases. Although <sup>123</sup>I-metaiodobenzylguanidine (MIBG) myocardial scintigraphy provides high specificity for DLB and is one of the indicative biomarkers, its application is constrained by substantial cost and limited accessibility. Electroencephalography (EEG), by contrast, is inexpensive and widely available, but currently serves only as a supportive biomarker. The aim of this study is to investigate the association between these biomarkers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective study included 230 patients who underwent both examinations for DLB evaluation. After removing 66 patients according to the exclusion criteria, the remaining 164 patients were categorized into a reduced uptake group (n&#x202f;=&#x202f;68) and a non-reduced uptake group (n&#x202f;=&#x202f;96) based on a heart-to-mediastinum (H/M) ratio. We performed quantitative EEG analysis to calculate the relative power. Group differences in relative power at each electrode were assessed using Welch's t-tests with the Benjamini-Hochberg procedure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The groups showed no significant differences in age, sex, or cognitive scores. Compared to the non-reduced uptake group, the reduced uptake group exhibited a significant increase (adjusted p&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.05) in the relative power of delta and theta waves, with the most prominent changes in the posterior regions. Conversely, it showed a widespread and significant decrease (adjusted p&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.05) in the relative power of beta and gamma waves.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrated that patients with reduced <sup>123</sup>I-MIBG uptake exhibited posterior-dominant slowing and reduced fast-wave activity in EEG, suggesting that EEG may offer additional neurophysiological insights into DLB.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Omori</LastName><ForeName>Hisaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: omori@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hata</LastName><ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: mhata@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shigenobu</LastName><ForeName>Kazue</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Behavioral Neurology and Neuropsychiatry, The University of Osaka United Graduate School of Child Development, Osaka, Japan; Department of Psychiatry, Asakayama General Hospital, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: kamae@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Shun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan; Clinical Research and Education Center, Asakayama General Hospital, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: s.takahashi@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyazaki</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan; Kosaka Hospital, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: miyazaki@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eto</LastName><ForeName>Mitsuhiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan; Department of Psychiatry, Asakayama General Hospital, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: eto@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Yuta</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan; Minoh Neuropsychiatric Sanatorium, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: nakagawa@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirashima</LastName><ForeName>Atsuya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: hirashima@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muto</LastName><ForeName>Kanae</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan; Department of Psychiatry, Asakayama General Hospital, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: kmuto@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shinosaki</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research and Education Center, Asakayama General Hospital, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: sinosaki@wakayama-med.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikeda</LastName><ForeName>Manabu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The University of Osaka Graduate School of Medicine, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: mikeda@psy.med.osaka-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int Psychogeriatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9007918</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1041-6102</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dementia with Lewy bodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">&#xb9;&#x202f;&#xb2;&#xb3;I-metaiodobenzylguanidine (MIBG) myocardial scintigraphy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41680074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inpsyc.2026.100197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1041-6102(26)00015-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>