<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41900646</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring Thermally Conductive and Form-Stable Phase Change Composites: A Review of Recent Advances and Thermal Energy Applications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1156</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19061156</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The global population explosion and accelerated industrialization have led to an increasing shortage of fossil fuels and environmental contamination, underscoring the urgent need to develop innovative energy storage technologies to improve energy utilization efficiency. As pivotal components in thermal energy storage (TES) systems, phase change materials (PCMs) enable spatiotemporal matching between thermal energy supply and demand through latent heat absorption and release during phase transitions. Organic PCMs are considered ideal candidates for thermal energy storage due to their high energy storage density, stable phase transition temperature, low supercooling, and negligible phase separation. However, inherent drawbacks such as low thermal conductivity, liquid leakage, limited light absorption, and lack of functionality have hindered their widespread application in advanced thermal management systems. Herein, we systematically summarize cutting-edge functionalization strategies for PCMs, progressing from conventional methods like thermal conductive particle blending and microencapsulation to the emerging design of 3D porous thermally conductive skeletons, including metal foams, boron nitride aerogels, carbon-based aerogels, and MXene aerogels. These frameworks not only enhance thermal transport via continuous conductive pathways and impart shape stability through capillary encapsulation but also, when integrated with photo-thermal, electro-thermal, and magneto-thermal conversion properties, enable broad applications in solar photo-thermal/photo-thermo-electric conversion, thermal management of electronics and batteries, building efficiency, and wearable thermal regulation. The review further addresses current challenges and future directions, highlighting scalable 3D framework fabrication, the shift to active thermal management, and innovative applications beyond conventional domains. By establishing a microstructure-property-application correlation, this work provides valuable insights for developing next-generation high-performance multifunctional phase change composites.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Energy and Chemical Engineering, Tianjin Ren'ai College, Tianjin 301636, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carbon Neutrality Interdisciplinary Science Centre, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Nankai University, Tianjin 300350, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Boyang</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-2506-2097</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Carbon Neutrality Interdisciplinary Science Centre, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Nankai University, Tianjin 300350, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shan</LastName><ForeName>Huiting</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, National University of Singapore, Singapore 117585, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joint School of National University of Singapore and Tianjin University, International Campus of Tianjin University, Binhai New City, Fuzhou 350207, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hangzhou Huadian Huayuan Environment Engineering Co., Ltd., Hangzhou 310030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025M780086</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024YFD2401300</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023KJ262</GrantID><Agency>Tianjin Research Innovation Project for Postgraduate Students</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>5419-202019385A</GrantID><Agency>State Grid Corporation of China's Research Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy storage and conversion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phase change composites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermal conductivity enhancement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermal management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Xiao Yang was employed by the company Hangzhou Huadian Huayuan Environment Engineering Co., Ltd. The funder sponsor was not involved in the study design, collection, analysis, interpretation of data, the writing of this article or the decision to submit it for publication. The remaining authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41900646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13027809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19061156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19061156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liu W., Dong Y., Li M., Liu H., Wang X. Weather-adaptive janus aerogel integrated with phase change materials enables dual-mode thermal regulation via radiative cooling and solar heating. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025;36:e13665. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202513665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202513665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan K., Cong L., Yu Z., Ye X. Artificial intelligence empowering geothermal energy development: A full-lifecycle review from exploration to operation. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2026;226:116468. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2025.116468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.116468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riaz A., Ullah Z., Hashmi S.H. A temporal exploration of resilience of renewable energy consumption to the energy-related uncertainty shocks in the us. J. Clean. Prod. 2025;493:144946. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.144946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Chen M., Cao X.E., Liu X., Wei P., Xu Q., Yao H., Ci E., Zhang Q., Lv S., et al. 24-h bidirectional thermal energy harvesting: From light to darkness. Adv. Mater. 2025;38:e16756. doi: 10.1002/adma.202516756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202516756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41178141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou M., Chen H., Li S., Zhang X., Chen J., Jiang Z., Wang C., Lai N.C., Ding Y. A tri-mode photothermal, phase-change, and radiative-cooling film for all-day thermoelectric generation. Adv. Mater. 2025;37:2505601. doi: 10.1002/adma.202505601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202505601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40622341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Li Z.R., Feng B., Hu S.S., Wu Y.F., Lai Y.Y., Liu G.B., Yang S., Yu T.C., Ong W.L., et al. Energy density recovery by enhanced hydrogen bonding for high-performance composite phase change materials. Adv. Mater. 2025;38:e20608. doi: 10.1002/adma.202520608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202520608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41441776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan M., Liu C., Tang R., Zhu X., Li Z., Zhou J. Supramolecular phase change materials for spatiotemporally thermal energy utilization. Adv. Sci. 2025;13:e12924. doi: 10.1002/advs.202512924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202512924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12866706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41387377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demirk&#x131;ran &#x130;.G., Niedermeier K., &#xc7;etkin E. Hollowed and perforated fins in latent heat storage units for high-temperature hybrid thermal energy storage applications. Energy Convers. Manag. 2025;340:119998. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2025.119998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2025.119998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulakhnif K., El Majd A., Azhar A., Haily E.M., Ait Ousaleh H., Faik A., Sair S., El Bouari A. Advanced porous geomaterial frameworks for high-performance latent heat storage. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2026;226:116483. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2025.116483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.116483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atinafu D.G., Yun B.Y., Yang S., Yuk H., Wi S., Kim S. Structurally advanced hybrid support composite phase change materials: Architectural synergy. Energy Storage Mater. 2021;42:164&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/j.ensm.2021.07.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2021.07.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Zhang Y., Zhang S., Tang B. Advanced phase change materials from natural perspectives: Structural design and functional applications. Adv. Sci. 2023;10:2207652. doi: 10.1002/advs.202207652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202207652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10401154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37226721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao F., Yuan W., Chen H., Fu H., Li Z., Xiao J., Feng Y. Advances in organic porous polymeric-supported photothermal phase change materials. Carbon. Energy. 2025;7:e719. doi: 10.1002/cey2.719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cey2.719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baniasadi H., Fathi Z., Abidnejad R., Silva P.E.S., Bordoloi S., Vapaavuori J., Niskanen J., Lizundia E., Kontturi E., Lipponen J. Biochar-infused cellulose foams with peg-based phase change materials for enhanced thermal energy storage and photothermal performance. Carbohydr. Polym. 2025;367:123999. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2025.123999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2025.123999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40817486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korti A.I.N. Advances in characterization methods and thermal performance enhancement of phase change materials (pcms): A critical review. J. Storage Mater. 2026;144:119833. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.119833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.119833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Hu J., Xie P., Yu Y., Zhang Z. Medium-temperature promising candidate thermal management materials: Interfacial passivation via TTA ligands enhances thermal cyclability of copper foam/Bi-in phase change materials. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;522:167526. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.167526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.167526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J., Hong M., Lee D., Choi Y., Lee J., Lee J., Jiong S., Chen X., Seo B., Choi W. Mechanically robust phase-change multiscale-architected metastructures integrating asymmetric MXene/T-CNF aerogel for thermal energy storage and electromagnetic interference shielding. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025;36:e14180. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202514180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202514180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasiri M., Hadim H. Thermal management of li-ion batteries using phase change materials: Recent advances and future challenges. J. Storage Mater. 2025;111:115440. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.115440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.115440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P., Diao X., Chen X. Intelligent phase change materials for long-duration thermal energy storage. Matter. 2024;7:2716&#x2013;2718. doi: 10.1016/j.matt.2024.05.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matt.2024.05.048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Zuo Y., Ma Y., Li P., Zhao D., Wu Y. A formable wood-based phase change materials with enhanced mechanical properties and thermal efficiency for smart building. Adv. Sci. 2025;13:e19262. doi: 10.1002/advs.202519262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202519262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12884778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41287600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khdair A.I., Kalbasi R., Dara R.N., Afrand M. Phase change materials in buildings: A comprehensive review of applications, climate strategies, and 3E performance. J. Storage Mater. 2025;132:117675. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.117675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.117675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., Yang R., Pan H., Zheng N., Huang X. Biomass-based shape-stabilized phase change materials for thermal energy storage and multiple energy conversion. Nano Energy. 2025;133:110440. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa Pereira S.C., Jannat M., Filho E.M., Ahmed T., Cardoso E.M., Sun D. Bio-based organic shape-stabilised phase change materials using agricultural waste-derived matrices: A review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2026;226:116436. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2025.116436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.116436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B., Guo H., Li T., Cao X., Cao M., Qi W., Cui Y., Li B. Engineering tiramisu-like phase change nanocomposite for superior thermal energy management and electromagnetic interference shielding. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2025;206:113&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmst.2024.04.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Du R., Li T. Progress and perspective on thermal conductivity enhancement of phase change materials. Sci. Bull. 2024;69:3176&#x2013;3179. doi: 10.1016/j.scib.2024.08.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scib.2024.08.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39227270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M., Xuan Y., Liu X., Jing Y., Li T. Flexible, recyclable, and highly conductive self-healing polymer-based phase change films for thermal management. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025;35:2506229. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202506229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202506229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P., Wu D., Xiong T., Cao X., Tan Z., Lin W., Gao M., Gencel O., Shahsavar A., Sari A., et al. Enhanced thermal properties of composite phase change material by polydopamine-driven Cu nanoparticles. Energy Mater. Adv. 2025;6:0183. doi: 10.34133/energymatadv.0183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34133/energymatadv.0183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Hu B., Shan H., Li Z., Qi W., Li B. Magnetically assembled flexible phase change composites with vertically aligned structures for thermal management and electromagnetic interference shielding. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;495:153361. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.153361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.153361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B., Guo H., Li T., Li J., Cao M., Qi W., Li X., Li B. Millefeuille-like phase change composite with multi-level oriented architecture for efficient thermal management and electromagnetic interference shielding. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;483:149240. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.149240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.149240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Tian Y., Tong J., Zheng N., Wang G., Huang X. State-of-the-art progress in composite phase change materials for photo-thermal conversion and their multifunctional applications. EnergyChem. 2026;8:100180. doi: 10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enchem.2025.100180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C., Hu L., Seidu R.K., Xu J., Jiang S.-X. Development of phase change materials directly encapsulated within gold shell microcapsules for flexible intelligent textile with energy storage and photo-thermal conversion ability. Nano Energy. 2025;143:111295. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.111295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Mao K., Sun H., Hu Q., Gong H., Colombo P., Feng Y., Guo X. Integrated design of multifunctional paraffin-impregnated porous ceramic metastructures for electromagnetic wave absorption and thermal management. J. Adv. Ceram. 2025;14:9221155. doi: 10.26599/JAC.2025.9221155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/JAC.2025.9221155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Z., Huang H., Li B., Zhao R., Wang Q., Liu H., Xue H., Zhou W., Li G. Engineering exosome membrane disguised thermal responsive system for targeted drug delivery and controlled release across the blood-brain barrier. Mater. Today Bio. 2025;32:101656. doi: 10.1016/j.mtbio.2025.101656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtbio.2025.101656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11953974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40160247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazaz O., Karimi N., Paul M.C. Micro-/nano-encapsulated phase change materials: Revolutionising heat transfer fluids for solar energy applications. Energy Convers. Manag. 2025;342:120113. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang C., Wang X., Hao Y., Zhang Y., Jiang L., Tang B., Song Y. A comprehensive review of form-stable phase change materials in cold chain logistics: Encapsulation strategies, thermal conductivity enhancement, and applications. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2025;13:24387&#x2013;24415. doi: 10.1039/D5TA01227A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5TA01227A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng H., Zhou Y., Xu P., Zhang M., Sun L. Kaolinite-based form-stable phase change materials for thermal energy storage. J. Storage Mater. 2024;87:111349. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2024.111349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.111349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman I.U., Khan H., Khan N., Manca O., Buonomo B., Nardini S. A review on assessment of thermal conductivity enhancement strategies for phase change materials. Int. Commun. Heat Mass Transf. 2025;169:109644. doi: 10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2025.109644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2025.109644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdellatif H.E., Belaadi A., Arshad A., Bourchak M. Modeling and performance analysis of phase change materials in advanced thermal energy storage systems: A comprehensive review. J. Storage Mater. 2025;121:116517. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.116517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.116517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Mo S., Zhou Z., Du Y., Jia L., Chen Y. Nanoparticle-enhanced phase change materials for thermal energy storage: A critical review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2025;223:116040. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2025.116040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.116040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahmer A., Turner T., Al-Dahidi S., Alrbai M. A comprehensive review of optimizing phase change materials in thermal energy storage: The role of nanoparticles, fin configurations, and data-driven approaches. J. Storage Mater. 2025;131:117464. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.117464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.117464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mani D., Saranprabhu M.K., Rajan K.S. Intensification of thermal energy storage using copper-pentaerythritol nanocomposites for renewable energy utilization. Renew. Energy. 2021;163:625&#x2013;634. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2020.08.119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2020.08.119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M., Qian R., Yang Y., Lu X., Huang L., Zou D. Modification of phase change materials for electric-thermal, photo-thermal, and magnetic-thermal conversions: A comprehensive review. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;34:2400038. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202400038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202400038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan K., Shi J., Aftab W., Qin M., Usman A., Zhou F., Lv Y., Gao S., Zou R. Engineering the thermal conductivity of functional phase-change materials for heat energy conversion, storage, and utilization. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2019;30:1904228. doi: 10.1002/adfm.201904228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.201904228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan M., Manjunath V., Mehdi S.M.Z., Soni S.K., Dewangan S.K., Lee H., Awasthi A., Sharma V.K., Sharma A., Song E., et al. Phonon-photon synergy in phase change materials through nano-engineered carbon materials for multifunctional applications. Energy Storage Mater. 2025;76:104142. doi: 10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S.C., Al-Kayiem H.H. Evaluation of copper nanoparticles&#x2013;paraffin wax compositions for solar thermal energy storage. Sol. Energy. 2016;132:267&#x2013;278. doi: 10.1016/j.solener.2016.03.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2016.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X., Wang C., Wang Y., Zhu Y. Experimental study of thermo-physical properties and application of paraffin-carbon nanotubes composite phase change materials. Int. J. Heat Mass Transf. 2019;140:671&#x2013;677. doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2019.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2019.06.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Li Y., Zheng D., Mikul&#x10d;i&#x107; H., Vujanovi&#x107; M., Sund&#xe9;n B. Preparation and thermophysical property analysis of nanocomposite phase change materials for energy storage. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2021;151:111541. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2021.111541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2021.111541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L.-W., Fang X., Wang X., Zeng Y., Xiao Y.-Q., Yu Z.-T., Xu X., Hu Y.-C., Cen K.-F. Effects of various carbon nanofillers on the thermal conductivity and energy storage properties of paraffin-based nanocomposite phase change materials. Appl. Energy. 2013;110:163&#x2013;172. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.04.043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.04.043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Tang L.S., Bai L., Bao R.Y., Liu Z.Y., Xie B.H., Yang M.B., Yang W. High-performance composite phase change materials for energy conversion based on macroscopically three-dimensional structural materials. Mater. Horiz. 2019;6:250&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1039/C8MH01219A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C8MH01219A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B., Guo H., Liu J., Cao M., Li M., Cui Y., Li B. Vertically oriented boron nitride/silicon carbide scaffold for thermal-conductive and electrical-insulating phase change composites. Compos. Part A-Appl. S. 2023;168:107460. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2023.107460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2023.107460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Yu H., Gao Y., Wang L., Wang G. The marriage of two-dimensional materials and phase change materials for energy storage, conversion and applications. EnergyChem. 2022;4:111541. doi: 10.1016/j.enchem.2022.100071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enchem.2022.100071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera-Rivera D., Neira-Vi&#xf1;as M., Freixa-Arum&#xed; N., Formosa J., Giro-Paloma J. Microcapsules with thermal, mechanical, and chemical stability from polystyrene waste to contain phase change materials. J. Storage Mater. 2026;143:119744. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.119744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.119744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan Y.-J., Lee H.-T., Chu W.-S., Patakamuri G., Hsu S.M., Ahn S.-H. Physically microencapsulated phase change materials for wide range of applicable temperatures. J. Storage Mater. 2025;115:115951. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.115951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.115951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan K., Chen Q., Qin M., Gao S., Wang Q., Gao S., Xiong F., Lv Y., Zou R. Micro/nano encapsulated phase change materials: Preparation, principle, and emerging advances in medical field. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;34:2314487. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202314487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202314487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X., Qian R., Xu X., Liu M., Liu Y., Zou D. Modifications of microencapsulated phase change materials: Supercooling suppression, thermal conductivity enhancement and stability improvement. Nano Energy. 2024;124:109520. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Tian D., Zheng Z., Wang X., Qian Z. Mxene-decorated magnetic phase-change microcapsules for solar-driven continuous seawater desalination with easy salt accumulation elimination. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;458:141395. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.141395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.141395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaffari F., Shekaari H., Beladi N. Enhanced thermal energy storage: Microencapsulation and thermophysical analysis of ethanolamine-based ionic liquids as phase change materials in poly(acrylate) shells. J. Storage Mater. 2025;138:118521. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.118521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.118521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan B., Li M., Lu H., Pi M., Mu J., Cui W., Ran R. Composite aerogel incorporating low temperature phase change microcapsules for enhanced thermal insulation. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;481:148540. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.148540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.148540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Jiao W., Jin H., Yuan Z., He X. Microsphere structure composite phase change material with anti-leakage, self-sensing, and photothermal conversion properties for thermal energy harvesting and multi-functional sensor. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022;33:2209345. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202209345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202209345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Zheng Z., Liu H., Wang X. Highly efficient, antibacterial, and salt-resistant strategy based on carbon black/chitosan-decorated phase-change microcapsules for solar-powered seawater desalination. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2023;15:16640&#x2013;16653. doi: 10.1021/acsami.2c21298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c21298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Z., Zhang G., Xiao Y., Ding Y., Li Y., She X., Zhang X., Zhao D. High-directional thermally conductive stearic acid/expanded graphite&#x2014;Graphene films for efficient photothermal energy storage. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;484:149203. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.149203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.149203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Zeng J., Guo Y., Chen H., Bi T., Lin Q. Three-dimensional hierarchical porous carbon surface-decorated graphitic carbon foam/stearic acid composite as high-performance shape-stabilized phase change material with desirable photothermal conversion efficiency. Appl. Energy. 2023;352:121995. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2023.121995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2023.121995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu B., Guo H., Li J., Li T., Cao M., Qi W., Wu Z., Li Y., Li B. Dual-encapsulated phase change composites with hierarchical MXene-graphene monoliths in graphene foam for high-efficiency thermal management and electromagnetic interference shielding. Compos. Part B-Eng. 2023;266:110998. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2023.110998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2023.110998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Mao Y., Li K., Liu Y., Xu Z., Pang K., Cai S., Fan L., Gao C. High power and energy density graphene phase change composite materials for efficient thermal management of Li-ion batteries. Energy Storage Mater. 2025;75:104003. doi: 10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Zhang X., Sang H., Tang K., Tang Y., Chen L., Li T. A low-thermal-resistance and oriented assembly strategy enabling ultrahigh thermal conductivity phase change composites for efficient thermal management. Small. 2025;21:e07948. doi: 10.1002/smll.202507948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202507948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40965011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Liu W., Du R., Wang S., Han H., Jing Y., Wu S., Wang R., Li T. Carbon-based phase change composites with directional high thermal conductivity for interface thermal management. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;496:154305. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.154305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.154305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Y., Zhu B., Li L., Wang Y., Li M., Zhang Z., Zhou Y., Yang R., Xu K., Cai T., et al. Dual-functional carbon material possessing light absorption and heat conduction &amp; energy storage. Adv. Compos. Hybrid Mater. 2025;8:313. doi: 10.1007/s42114-025-01371-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42114-025-01371-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin D., Yu C., Guo J., Li G., Jiang X., Yao Y., Zhang X. Polyethylene glycol modified polysiloxane and silver decorated expanded graphite composites with high thermal conductivity, emi shielding, and leakage-free performance. Compos. Part B-Eng. 2025;291:112041. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2024.112041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2024.112041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y., Zhao Z., Zeng X., Teng J., Huang J., Min Y. High-performance polyimide/polypyrrole-CNTs@PEG composites for integrated thermal management and enhanced electromagnetic wave absorption. Adv. Compos. Hybrid. Mater. 2025;8:104. doi: 10.1007/s42114-024-01202-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42114-024-01202-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Yang B., Li Y., Yang X., Sund&#xe9;n B. Research progress on synergistic enhanced heat transfer of metal foams in phase change energy storage process. Int. J. Heat Mass Transf. 2026;255:127736. doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2025.127736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2025.127736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Song Z., Xie Y., Wang J., Yang X. Numerical analysis of topological optimization and metal foam structure of phase change energy storage process for buildings. Energy Build. 2025;346:116166. doi: 10.1016/j.enbuild.2025.116166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enbuild.2025.116166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baccega E., Vallese L., Bottarelli M. Enhancement of thermal conductivity of paraffin pcm with metal foams. Int. J. Thermophys. 2025;46:35. doi: 10.1007/s10765-024-03500-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10765-024-03500-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Zou M., Xiao S., Chen W., Xie Y., Luo W., Luo L., Hu X., Jiang X., He Y., et al. Nano-silver@polydopamine carbonized melamine foam supported polyethylene glycol phase change materials: With simultaneous improved photo-thermal conversion ability. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2024;269:112762. doi: 10.1016/j.solmat.2024.112762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2024.112762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Wang T., Hu Z., Cai Z. Facile synthesis and thermal performance of cety palmitate/nickel foam composite phase change materials for thermal energy storage. J. Storage Mater. 2020;28:101179. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2019.101179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2019.101179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang M., Li J., Tian L., Huang P., Li X., Yu J., Zhang S., Miao W., Peng J. Thermal conductivity enhancement of polyethylene glycol/nf composite as stabilized phase change materials for thermal energy storage. J. Storage Mater. 2024;99:113313. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2024.113313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.113313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., An L., Wang Y., Lee A., Schuman Y., Ural A., Fleischer A.S., Feng G. Thermal enhancement and shape stabilization of a phase-change energy-storage material via copper nanowire aerogel. Chem. Eng. J. 2019;373:857&#x2013;869. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2019.05.104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2019.05.104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo Y.-J., Yan T., Wu S.-F., Kuai Z.-H., Pan W.-G. Preparation and thermal properties of palmitic acid/copper foam phase change materials. Energy. 2024;293:130629. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2024.130629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2024.130629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo P., Sheng N., Zhu R., Zhu C., Rao Z. Improved anisotropic thermal transfer property of form-stable phase change material supported by 3D bionic porous copper. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2023;11:3324&#x2013;3333. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.2c06396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.2c06396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong X., Chen Y., Yang R., Wang Y., Zhang Z., Li M., Chen H., Li L., Gong P., Zhang J., et al. Large-scale production of boron nitride nanosheets for flexible thermal interface materials with highly thermally conductive and low dielectric constant. Compos. Part B-Eng. 2024;271:111164. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2023.111164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2023.111164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui S., Zhang H., Xu G., Zhang J., Xu F., Sun L., Lin X., Ma L., Peng H., Li B., et al. Hierarchically porous and flexible BN/Co-MOF aerogel encapsulated paraffin for efficient dual-thermal insulation. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2025;13:5882&#x2013;5897. doi: 10.1039/D4TA07235A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4TA07235A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Wang H., Lei T., He Y., Zhu F., Liu Y., Li R., Wu T., Xiao H. Design of boron nitride/nanocellulose aerogel-stabilized phase change materials for efficient thermal energy capture and storage. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;295:139572. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.139572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.139572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39778824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Lei T., Zhu F., Wang M., Yu Z., Liu Y., Deng C., Liu C., Xiao H. Lignosulfonate-decorated boron nitride/cellulose nanofibril porous foam: Multifunctional phase change composites for leakage-free thermal energy storage and photothermal conversion. Biomacromolecules. 2025;26:5873&#x2013;5887. doi: 10.1021/acs.biomac.5c00757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.biomac.5c00757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40747840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong H., Gu L., Niu C., Zhang J., Ge X., Xing R., Pan G. Shape-stable phase change materials based on carboxymethyl chitosan/boron nitride nanosheets high-strength aerogel. Diam. Relat. Mater. 2024;145:111126. doi: 10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Zheng X., Cao Y., Algadi H., He M., Qiu H., Ren J., Huang J., Min Y., Guo Z. Dual-functional polyimide-based phase change composite aerogels with latent heat storage and radiative cooling capabilities for energy-efficient buildings. Sci. China Mater. 2025;68:4448&#x2013;4459. doi: 10.1007/s40843-025-3565-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40843-025-3565-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., Lin R., Cao Z. Leakage-proof nacre-like boron nitride nanosheet/phase change microcapsule composites with enhanced thermal conduction and thermal energy storage for advanced thermal management systems. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2025;13:23126&#x2013;23141. doi: 10.1039/D5TA02963E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5TA02963E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu S., Zhang J., Hu X., Sun J., Gu X., Wang H., Fei B., Zhang S. Constructing functionalized eco-friendly boron nitride and diatomaceous earth based phase change composite backsheets for thermal management and fire safety of solar modules. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2025;13:28353&#x2013;28367. doi: 10.1039/D5TA02193F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5TA02193F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng R., Liu S., He T., Zu C., Yin D., Bai Y., Yue C., Peng T. Bio-inspired carbon-stitched 3D boron nitride skeleton with enhanced thermal conductivity and waterproof performance for polyethylene glycol-based composite phase change materials. Renew. Energy. 2026;258:124984. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2025.124984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2025.124984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao H., Li S.-Z., Yang J., Liu Z.-Y., Bai L., Yang W. Thermally conductive magnetic composite phase change materials for anisotropic photo/magnetic-to-thermal energy conversion. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2023;15:55723&#x2013;55733. doi: 10.1021/acsami.3c12302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.3c12302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37992260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Li G., Xu L., Liao J., Zhang X. Nanoporous boron nitride aerogel film and its smart composite with phase change materials. ACS Nano. 2020;14:16590&#x2013;16599. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.0c05931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.0c05931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D., Lei C., Wu K., Fu Q. A multidirectionally thermoconductive phase change material enables high and durable electricity via real-environment solar-thermal-electric conversion. ACS Nano. 2020;14:15738&#x2013;15747. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.0c06680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.0c06680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L.S., Zhou Y.C., Zhou L., Yang J., Bai L., Bao R.Y., Liu Z.Y., Yang M.B., Yang W. Double-layered and shape-stabilized phase change materials with enhanced thermal conduction and reversible thermochromism for solar thermoelectric power generation. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;430:132773. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2021.132773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.132773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J., Tan R., Huang C., Chen J., Huang M., Zhang Q. Self-assembled cellulose nanofibers/graphene aerogel-supported phase change composites with a three-dimensional network structure for enhanced solar-thermal energy conversion and storage. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2025;700:138343. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40644970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Sha Q., Yan X., Ma C., Ma C., Li W., Zhang X., Han N. Cyclized polyacrylonitrile@carbon nanotubes reinforced graphene aerogel phase change composites for efficient solar-thermal-electric energy conversion. Carbon. 2025;242:120446. doi: 10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhardwaj S., Singh S., Dev K., Maji P.K. Structurally stable cellulose nanofiber-based phase change aerogels for thermal management and acoustic insulation. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2025;13:32842&#x2013;32856. doi: 10.1039/D5TA05021A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5TA05021A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J., Liu G., Li G., Liu F., Xu Y., Qin H., Zhuoga D.Q. Poly(vinyl alcohol)/carbon nanotube hybrid aerogel-based composite phase change materials for thermal energy and flame-retardant. Colloids Surf. A. 2025;727:138337. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.138337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.138337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Tang A., Jin Y., Cai T., Chen K., Shao S. Construction of electrostatically self-assembled pomelo peel/carbon nanotube aerogel and the modulation of thermal performance in composite phase change material. Biomass Bioenergy. 2026;206:108614. doi: 10.1016/j.biombioe.2025.108614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biombioe.2025.108614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji D., Alasiri A., Zhang Y., Zheng X. High thermal anisotropy in aligned carbon fiber/chitosan aerogel composites for ultra-efficient solar thermal energy harvesting. Int. J. Heat Mass Transf. 2026;256:128030. doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2025.128030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2025.128030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan B., Shi Z., Wen H., Hu X., Liu Z., Zhao X., Yan X., Wang W., Huang X., Qu J., et al. Flexible OBC/PW/EG phase change composites with high thermal conductivity via phase-change-induced in situ exfoliation. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;522:168144. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.168144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.168144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Feng Y., Qin M., Chen K., An Y., Liu P., Jiang Y., Shen Z., Chen X. Co-anchored hollow carbonized kapok fiber encapsulated phase change materials for upgrading photothermal utilization. Small. 2025;21:2500479. doi: 10.1002/smll.202500479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202500479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40166806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Liu P., Li P., Feng Y., Gao Y., Diao X., Chen X., Wang G. Neural network-inspired hybrid aerogel boosting solar thermal storage and microwave absorption. Nano Res. Energy. 2024;3:9120120. doi: 10.26599/NRE.2024.9120120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/NRE.2024.9120120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng J., Liu X., Lin F., Duan S., Zeng K., Bai Y., Wu X., Huang Z., Min X. Aligned channel gelatin@nanographite aerogel supported form-stable phase change materials for solar-thermal energy conversion and storage. Carbon. 2023;201:756&#x2013;764. doi: 10.1016/j.carbon.2022.09.064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2022.09.064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao H., Chen W., Liu Y., Wang Q. A phase change material encapsulated in a mechanically strong graphene aerogel with high thermal conductivity and excellent shape stability. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2020;189:108010. doi: 10.1016/j.compscitech.2020.108010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2020.108010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Zhao X., Li Y., Yang Z., Zuo X., Tang A., Yang H. Nanoclay hybridized graphene aerogels encapsulating phase change material for efficient solar-driven desalination and electricity generation. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;34:2408693. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202408693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202408693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J., Zhou B., Liu C., He C., Feng Y., Liu C. Carbonization welding graphene architecture for thermally conductive phase change composites with solar/electric-to-heat conversion ability. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;475:146087. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.146087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.146087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su H., Lin P., Li D., Chen Y. Reduced graphene oxide/cellulose sodium aerogel-supported eutectic phase change material gel demonstrating superior energy conversion and storage capacity toward high-performance personal thermal management. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2024;16:3334&#x2013;3347. doi: 10.1021/acsami.3c15470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.3c15470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38193700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Li L., Qin Y., Wei X., Kong X., Zhang Z., Xiong S., Do H., Greer J.C., Pan Z., et al. Crystallization induced realignment of carbon fibers in a phase change material to achieve exceptional thermal transportation properties. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2022;10:593&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1039/D1TA09056A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1TA09056A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Li T., Tong Z., Chao J., Zhai T., Xu J., Yan T., Wu M., Xu Z., Bao H., et al. High-performance thermally conductive phase change composites by large-size oriented graphite sheets for scalable thermal energy harvesting. Adv. Mater. 2019;31:1905099. doi: 10.1002/adma.201905099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201905099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31621971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Ge J., Yang X., Yang Q., Feng Y., Feng W. Phase-change gradient composites for variable thermal management. Compos. Commun. 2024;48:101948. doi: 10.1016/j.coco.2024.101948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coco.2024.101948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., An C., Guo Y., Zong Y., Jiang N., Zheng Q., Yu Z.-Z. Highly aligned graphene aerogels for multifunctional composites. Nano-Micro Lett. 2024;16:118. doi: 10.1007/s40820-024-01357-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-024-01357-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10869679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38361077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin L., Cao W., Wang P., Song N., Ding P. Interconnected mxene/graphene network constructed by soft template for multi-performance improvement of polymer composites. Nano-Micro Lett. 2022;14:133. doi: 10.1007/s40820-022-00877-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-022-00877-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9198158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35699778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi G., Yang J., Bao R., Xia D., Cao M., Yang W., Yang M., Wei D. Hierarchical graphene foam-based phase change materials with enhanced thermal conductivity and shape stability for efficient solar-to-thermal energy conversion and storage. Nano Res. 2016;10:802&#x2013;813. doi: 10.1007/s12274-016-1333-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12274-016-1333-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z., Jia S., Niu Y., Lv X., Fu H., Zhang Y., Liu D., Wang B., Li Q. Bean-pod-inspired 3D-printed phase change microlattices for solar-thermal energy harvesting and storage. Small. 2021;17:2101093. doi: 10.1002/smll.202101093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202101093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34145751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H.-Y., Shu C., Min P., Li C., Deng W., Yang J., Li X., Yu Z.-Z. Constructing anisotropic conical graphene aerogels with concentric annular structures for highly thermally conductive phase change composites towards efficient solar&#x2013;thermal&#x2013;electric energy conversion. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2022;10:22488&#x2013;22499. doi: 10.1039/D2TA06457J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2TA06457J</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W., Lai J., Xie K., Liu D., Wu K., Fu Q. D-mannitol/graphene phase-change composites with structured conformation and thermal pathways allow durable solar-thermal-electric conversion and electricity output. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2022;14:38981&#x2013;38989. doi: 10.1021/acsami.2c11843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c11843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35989565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H.Y., Shu C., Wang X., Min P., Li C., Gao F.L., Li X., Yu Z.Z. Bioinspired intelligent solar-responsive thermally conductive pyramidal phase change composites with radially oriented layered structures toward efficient solar&#x2013;thermal&#x2013;electric energy conversion. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023;33:2302527. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202302527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202302527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Wang S., Zhao J., Wang S., Wang S., Peng Y., Huang Q., Liu C. Preparation of mxene-based aerogel-derived phase change materials for mitigating thermal runaway risk in batteries. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;511:162039. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.162039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.162039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K., Meng F., Zhang X., Yan H., Liu H., Shi Q. Flexible mxene-functionalized composite phase change film with dual-mode of solar-thermal conversion and infrared stealth. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;509:161279. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.161279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.161279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Z., Zhang F., Feng W. Percolating mxene networks and ldh thermal bridges in 3D hierarchical polyimide aerogels for rapid thermal charging, leakage-resistant solar&#x2013;thermal phase-change storage. Small. 2025;22:e13143. doi: 10.1002/smll.202513143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202513143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41427460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y., Weng M., Mahmoud M.H.H., Elnaggar A.Y., Zhang L., El Azab I.H., Chen Y., Huang M., Huang J., Sheng X. Flame-retardant and leakage-proof phase change composites based on mxene/polyimide aerogels toward solar thermal energy harvesting. Adv. Compos. Hybrid Mater. 2022;5:1253&#x2013;1267. doi: 10.1007/s42114-022-00504-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42114-022-00504-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y., Zeng Z., Huang D., Chen Y., Zhang L., Sheng X. Multifunctional phase change composites based on biomass/MXene-derived hybrid scaffolds for excellent electromagnetic interference shielding and superior solar/electro-thermal energy storage. Nano Res. 2022;15:8524&#x2013;8535. doi: 10.1007/s12274-022-4626-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12274-022-4626-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C., Hao Y., Wu H., Chen M., Quan B., Liu S., Hu X., Liu S., Ji Q., Lu X., et al. Self-assembly of binderless MXene aerogel for multiple-scenario and responsive phase change composites with ultrahigh thermal energy storage density and exceptional electromagnetic interference shielding. Nano-Micro Lett. 2023;16:57. doi: 10.1007/s40820-023-01288-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-023-01288-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10728427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38110610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Meng Y., Zhang J., Xie Y., Guo H., He M., Shi X., Mei Y., Sheng X., Xie D. Leakage proof, flame-retardant, and electromagnetic shield wood morphology genetic composite phase change materials for solar thermal energy harvesting. Nano-Micro Lett. 2024;16:196. doi: 10.1007/s40820-024-01414-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-024-01414-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11099002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38753068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X., Ma Y., Tian Z., Sun H., Zhu Z., Li J., Liang W., Li A. Shape-stable MXene/sodium alginate/carbon nanotubes hybrid phase change material composites for efficient solar energy conversion and storage. Compos. Sci. Technol. 2022;230:109794. doi: 10.1016/j.compscitech.2022.109794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2022.109794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X., Liu J., Zhang L., Zhao W., Cao Y., Liu X. Dual-mode MXene-based phase-change composite towards enhanced photothermal utilization and excellent infrared stealth. Small. 2024;20:2405694. doi: 10.1002/smll.202405694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202405694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39246246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Zhu X., Dai J., Yang K., Wang S., Liu X. Integration of sustainable polymers with phase change materials. Prog. Mater. Sci. 2025;151:101447. doi: 10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2025.101447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani McCord M.R., Zimmerman J.B., Rojas O.J. Harnessing multifunctional electrospun nanofibers containing phase change materials for energy-efficient thermal management: A review on recent trends. Nano Energy. 2024;131:110212. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalidasan B., Pandey A.K. Next generation phase change materials: State-of-the-art towards sustainable future. Prog. Mater. Sci. 2025;148:101380. doi: 10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao T., Zhao J., Geng L., Wang Z., Qiao W., Liu C. Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication: One-step forming for thermosensitive solid&#x2013;solid phase change thermal energy harvesting, storage, and utilization. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;477:147068. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.147068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.147068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian T., Li J., Min X., Deng Y., Guan W., Ning L. Diatomite: A promising natural candidate as carrier material for low, middle and high temperature phase change material. Energy Convers. Manag. 2015;98:34&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2015.03.071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2015.03.071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Chen Z., Hu Z., Yu S., Zhou J., Xiang H., Zhu M. Soft-hard complex microsphere strategy to construct high-temperature form-stable phase change material for melt-spun temperature-regulating fibers. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;476:146833. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.146833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.146833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Kang Q., Liu Y., Zhu Y., Jiang P., Mai Y.W., Huang X. Flexible, highly thermally conductive and electrically insulating phase change materials for advanced thermal management of 5g base stations and thermoelectric generators. Nano-Micro Lett. 2023;15:31. doi: 10.1007/s40820-022-01003-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-022-01003-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9829950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36624322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., Ai B., Quan B., Shi Z., Liu Z., Sheng M., Ding Y., Yan H., Xiao Y., Lu G., et al. Synergistically networked 1D/2D/3D phase change composites with ultra-fast contactless thermal energy conversion and enhanced electromagnetic interference shielding performance. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;504:158915. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.158915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.158915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Su X., Liao M., Yu J., Yang J. Tunable graphene frameworks enable advanced phase change composites with both ultrahigh thermal conductivity and latent heat. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025;36:e18070. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202518070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202518070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadim H.B., Godin A., Veillere A., Duquesne M., Haillot D. Review of thermal management of electronics and phase change materials. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2025;208:115039. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2024.115039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2024.115039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Wang S., Li T. Progress and prospective of thermal interface materials for thermal management. IET Smart Energy Syst. 2025;1:42&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1049/ses2.70004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/ses2.70004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Chen W., Ma X., Feng Y., Geng X., Gong Q., Guan D., Liu Y., Ma B. Directional construction of thermal superhighways with composite phase change materials for chip thermal management application. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025:e22766. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202522766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202522766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang W.-J., Wang R.-Q., Zhu T.-Y., Feng M., Sun D.-X., Yang J.-H., Qi X.-D., Wang Y. Tree-ring structured phase change materials with high through-plane thermal conductivity and flexibility for advanced thermal management. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;479:147622. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.147622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.147622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han G., Cheng H., Cheng Y., Zhou B., Liu C., Feng Y. Scalable sol&#x2013;gel permeation assembly of phase change layered film toward thermal management and light-thermal driving applications. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;34:2401295. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202401295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202401295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samykano M. Advancing battery thermal management: Future directions and challenges in nano-enhanced phase change materials-based systems. Prog. Mater. Sci. 2025;148:101388. doi: 10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2024.101388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Cao F., Zhang Y., Zhang S., Tang B. Enhancing thermal protection in lithium batteries with power bank-inspired multi-network aerogel and thermally induced flexible composite phase change material. Nano-Micro Lett. 2025;17:166. doi: 10.1007/s40820-024-01593-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-024-01593-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11865416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40009293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao W., Quan R., Ju J., Hu M., Cao H., Xu Q., Xiong Y., Zhao Y., Ding Y., Ling X. Calcium chloride hexahydrate based composite phase change/thermochemical material for wide-temperature range passive battery thermal management. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;508:160800. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.160800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.160800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Piao J., Xu D., Meng Y., Zhang L., Han X., Yang X., Jin L., Bi S. Thermally triggered tunable-thermal-conductivity phase-change composites for lithium-ion battery thermal management and runaway mitigation. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;524:169799. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.169799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.169799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Kang Q., Wei H., Bao H., Jiang P., Mai Y.W., Huang X. Spider web-inspired graphene skeleton-based high thermal conductivity phase change nanocomposites for battery thermal management. Nano-Micro Lett. 2021;13:180. doi: 10.1007/s40820-021-00702-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-021-00702-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8374024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34406526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo C., He L., Yao Y., Lin W., Zhang Y., Zhang Q., Wu K., Fu Q. Bifunctional liquid metals allow electrical insulating phase change materials to dual-mode thermal manage the li-ion batteries. Nano-Micro Lett. 2022;14:202. doi: 10.1007/s40820-022-00947-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-022-00947-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9551009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu M., Li T., Wang P., Wu S., Wang R., Lin J. Dual-encapsulated highly conductive and liquid-free phase change composites enabled by polyurethane/graphite nanoplatelets hybrid networks for efficient energy storage and thermal management. Small. 2021;18:2105647. doi: 10.1002/smll.202105647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202105647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34936192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu D., Han L., Zhou W., Li P., Huang Y., Yang Z., Jia X. Flexible phase change composite based on loading paraffin into cross-linked CNT/SBS network for thermal management and thermal storage. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;437:135056. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.135056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.135056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang A., Xiong Y., Zhao Y., Wu Y., Xu Q., Ding Y. A review of passive building thermal management with phase-change materials. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2025;211:115334. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2025.115334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.115334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad A., Memon S.A., Dang H., Sari A., Gencel O. Breaking new ground: A first-of-its-kind critical analysis of review articles on phase change materials for building applications. Appl. Energy. 2025;392:125984. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.125984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.125984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y., Jiang Z., Wang X., Dong B. Empowering phase change material thermodynamics via physics-consistent neural network-enabled advanced building control. Appl. Energy. 2026;404:127143. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.127143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2025.127143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Z.Y., Zhao B.C., Wang R.Z. Passive day and night heating for zero energy buildings with solar-based adsorption thermal battery. Cell Rep. Phys. Sci. 2021;2:100578. doi: 10.1016/j.xcrp.2021.100578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrp.2021.100578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X., Feng J. Facilely prepare passive thermal management materials by foaming phase change materials to achieve long-duration thermal insulation performance. Compos. Part B-Eng. 2022;245:110203. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.110203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.110203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Wang F., Duvigneau J., Wang Y., Wang B., Feng X., Mao Z., Vancso G.J., Sui X. Highly stable and nonflammable hydrated salt-paraffin shape-memory gels for sustainable building technology. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2021;9:15442&#x2013;15450. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.1c04586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.1c04586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao F., Li Z., Zhang Y., Wang X., Zhu L., Zhang S., Tang B. Silica-based aerogels encapsulate organic/inorganic composite phase change materials for building thermal management. J. Storage Mater. 2024;97:112858. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2024.112858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.112858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Shan X., Hu P., Zhang C., Yuan D., Hu X., Wang J. Bioinspired multilayer structures for energy-free passive heating and thermal regulation in cold environments. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2022;14:46569&#x2013;46580. doi: 10.1021/acsami.2c12610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.2c12610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36206445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Chen X. Wearable thermotherapy devices made with phase change modules. Device. 2024;2:100282. doi: 10.1016/j.device.2024.100282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.device.2024.100282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan H., Kou Y., Zhang S., Liu H., Yin N., Xu Y., Shi Q. Flexible erythritol-based spatiotemporal phase change films with multiple energy responses for wearable thermal management. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;522:167630. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.167630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.167630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Luo L., Mao Z., Wang B., Feng X., Sui X. Electrothermal phase change composite with flexibility over a wide temperature range for wearable thermotherapy. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2024;16:4089&#x2013;4098. doi: 10.1021/acsami.3c17269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.3c17269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38268145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Zhou F., Shi X., Sun K., Kou Y., Das P., Li Y., Zhang X., Mateti S., Chen Y., et al. A thermoregulatory flexible phase change nonwoven for all-season high-efficiency wearable thermal management. Nano-Micro Lett. 2023;15:29. doi: 10.1007/s40820-022-00991-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-022-00991-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9813330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36598606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., He Y., Tian M., Qu L., Fan T., Miao J. Core&#x2013;sheath heterogeneous interlocked conductive fiber enables smart textile for personalized healthcare and thermal management. Small. 2023;20:2308404. doi: 10.1002/smll.202308404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202308404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38148325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Sun K., Liu H., Chen J., Yan X., Kou Y., Shi Q. Flexible insulating phase change composite film with improved thermal conductivity for wearable thermal management. Nano Energy. 2024;121:109256. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Sheng X., Fang Y., Hu X., Gong S., Sheng M., Lu X., Qu J. Wearable janus-type film with integrated all-season active/passive thermal management, thermal camouflage, and ultra-high electromagnetic shielding efficiency tunable by origami process. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023;33:2212776. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202212776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202212776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong S., Sheng X., Li X., Sheng M., Wu H., Lu X., Qu J. A multifunctional flexible composite film with excellent multi-source driven thermal management, electromagnetic interference shielding, and fire safety performance, inspired by a &#x201c;brick&#x2013;mortar&#x201d; sandwich structure. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022;32:2200570. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202200570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202200570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao H., Ma H., Cui J., Ge X., Tan J., Xu J. Hierarchical hollow p-doped ZIF-8/MXene aerogel composites for phase change materials integrating shape stability, thermal energy storage, solar-thermal conversion and flame retardancy. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;526:171306. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.171306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.171306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Zhang S., Gao Z., Liu Z., Zhao Z., Rao Z. Multifunctional flexible phase change materials: From material design to thermal energy storage in renewable scenarios. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2025;222:115965. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2025.115965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2025.115965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Z.-C., Liu Y.-L., Huang Z.-J., Wang Q., Sun D.-X., Yang J.-H., Qi X.-D., Wang Y. Hierarchical carbon foams with tunable mof nanostructure for improving solar-thermal conversion performance of phase change materials. Carbon. 2025;237:120161. doi: 10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2025.120161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo T., Lu J., Kong L., Li Y., Ni Q., Lin B., Fu L., Huang B., Xu C. Inspired by the &#x201c;interlocking&#x201d; structure in human skin: A universal and efficient interfacial strategy enabling flexible phase change materials with a wide scope of customizable functionalities. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025;36:e12674. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202512674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202512674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue R., Wang K., Zhao Z., Li W., Ding D., Liang H., Wang H., Shan X., Huang Y., Liu X., et al. Composite phase change materials with efficient solar-thermal energy conversion, storage and superior shape stability by interfacial enhancement. Energy Convers. Manag. 2025;334:119863. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2025.119863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2025.119863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said Z., Pandey A.K., Tiwari A.K., Kalidasan B., Jamil F., Thakur A.K., Tyagi V.V., Sar&#x131; A., Ali H.M. Nano-enhanced phase change materials: Fundamentals and applications. Prog. Energy Combust. Sci. 2024;104:101162. doi: 10.1016/j.pecs.2024.101162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pecs.2024.101162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Tang Y., Wang J., Li Y., Li D., Zuo X., Yang H. Visible light locking in mineral-based composite phase change materials enabling high photothermal conversion and storage. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2023;15:49132&#x2013;49145. doi: 10.1021/acsami.3c10348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.3c10348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37831549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Tang J., Chen J., Zhang Y., Chen X., Ding M., Zhou W., Xu X., Liu H., Xue G. Accelerating the solar-thermal energy storage via inner-light supplying with optical waveguide. Nat. Commun. 2023;14:3456. doi: 10.1038/s41467-023-39190-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-39190-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10261122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37308484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Wu M., Wu S., Xiang S., Xu J., Chao J., Yan T., Deng T., Wang R. Highly conductive phase change composites enabled by vertically-aligned reticulated graphite nanoplatelets for high-temperature solar photo/electro-thermal energy conversion, harvesting and storage. Nano Energy. 2021;89:106338. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.106338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.106338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhiani A.R., Cornelis Metselaar H.S., Ang B.C., Mehrali M., Mehrali M. MXene/rGO grafted sponge with an integrated hydrophobic structure towards light-driven phase change composites. Compos. Part B-Eng. 2023;264:110885. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2023.110885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2023.110885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Z., Cheng P., Liu P., Gao Y., Chen X., Wang G. Tightened 1D/3D carbon heterostructure infiltrating phase change materials for solar&#x2013;thermoelectric energy harvesting: Faster and better. Carbon Energy. 2023;5:281. doi: 10.1002/cey2.281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cey2.281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Zhang J., Liu J., Tan Z., Cao Y., Li X., Rao Z. Highly efficient thermalenergy storage using a hybrid hypercrosslinked polymer. Angwandte Chem. Int. Ed. 2021;60:13978&#x2013;13987. doi: 10.1002/anie.202103186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202103186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33797119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Chen Y., Dai W., Zhang Z., Kong X., Li M., Li L., Gong P., Chen H., Ruan X., et al. Anisotropic black phosphorene structural modulation for thermal storage and solar-thermal conversion. Small. 2023;19:2303933. doi: 10.1002/smll.202303933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202303933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37574266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K., Li Y., Feng Y., Li X., Li Z., Liu S., Ge C., Chen X. In situ vertical alignment of MoS2 on Co/C dodecahedron boosting phase change materials for solar-thermoelectric generation. J. Energy Chem. 2025;107:548&#x2013;557. doi: 10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jechem.2025.03.070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y., Huang X., Zhao X., Hu X., Lu G., Shi Q., Ren J., Qu J., Lu X. Renewable cellulose-reinforced flexible Ti3C2Tx-based phase change composites for electromagnetic shielding and thermal management. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;525:170655. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.170655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.170655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai B., Liu Z., Hu X., Quan B., Sui M., Zhu C., Xiao Y., Zhang M., Liu L., Yan X., et al. Sandwich-structured hdpe-based medium-temperature phase change composites with mxene interlayers for photo-thermal-electrical applications. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;512:162367. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2025.162367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2025.162367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Wu K., Fu Q. A structured phase change material with controllable thermoconductive highways enables unparalleled electricity via solar-thermal-electric conversion. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2021;32:2109255. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202109255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202109255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X., Guo Q., Tao Z., Liang Y., Liu Z. Modified phase change materials used for thermal management of a novel solar thermoelectric generator. Energy Convers. Manag. 2020;208:112459. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2019.112459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2019.112459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu C., Zhao H.-Y., Lu X.-H., Min P., Zhang Y., Wang Q., Li X., Yu Z.-Z. High-quality anisotropic graphene aerogels and their thermally conductive phase change composites for efficient solar&#x2013;thermal&#x2013;electrical energy conversion. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2023;11:11991&#x2013;12003. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c02154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c02154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Li M., Qin Y., Chen Y., Dai W., Zhang Z., Kong X., Gong P., Wang Y., Yang R., et al. Eicosane-based thermo-conductive phase change composite for efficient capture solar energy and using in real-environment as power source. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;462:142273. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.142273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.142273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H., Dong M., Wang Q., Zhang J., Feng Q., Wei Q., Cai Y. A multifunctional carbon-base phase change composite inspired by &#x201c;fruit growth&#x201d;. Carbon. 2023;205:499&#x2013;509. doi: 10.1016/j.carbon.2023.01.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2023.01.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu C., Zhao H.-Y., Zhao S., Deng W., Min P., Lu X.-H., Li X., Yu Z.-Z. Highly thermally conductive phase change composites with anisotropic graphene/cellulose nanofiber hybrid aerogels for efficient temperature regulation and solar-thermal-electric energy conversion applications. Compos. Part B-Eng. 2023;248:110367. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.110367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.110367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D., Zhang S., Liang Q., Song J., Guan M., Zhang T., Chen S., Wang H. One-step synthesis of multifunctional bacterial cellulose film-based phase change materials with cross-linked network structure for solar&#x2013;thermal energy conversion, storage, and utilization. Small. 2023;20:2307259. doi: 10.1002/smll.202307259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202307259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37948421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y.-C., Yang J., Bai L., Bao R.-Y., Yang M.-B., Yang W. Super-flexible phase change materials with a dual-supporting effect for solar thermoelectric conversion in the ocean environment. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2022;11:341&#x2013;351. doi: 10.1039/D2TA07885F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2TA07885F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Lu Q., Jiao W., Yuan X., Ren S., Sun H., He X. Shape memory multidimensional microsphere network for thermal energy storage and intelligent sensing. Compos. Part B-Eng. 2026;311:113288. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2025.113288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2025.113288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K., Ye Z., Meng F., Sheng N., Zhu C., Liu C., Hou F. Multi-responsive phase change aerogel for solar/electro-thermal energy conversion and management. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2026;297:114135. doi: 10.1016/j.solmat.2025.114135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2025.114135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng S., Zhang Z., Zhao Z., Ning Y., Yu C., Liu K., Jiang L. Photo/electro-thermal superhydrophobic wood with phase change materials for highly efficient anti-/deicing. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025;35:2424897. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202424897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202424897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Zou R., Lin Z., Gui X., Chen R., Lin J., Shang Y., Cao A. Tailoring carbon nanotube density for modulating electro-to-heat conversion in phase change composites. Nano Lett. 2013;13:4028&#x2013;4035. doi: 10.1021/nl401097d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nl401097d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23899195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan K., Feng Y., Qiu L. Thermal and photo/electro-thermal conversion characteristics of high energy storage density expanded graphite/polyethylene glycol shaped composite phase change materials. Sol. Energy. 2024;272:112477. doi: 10.1016/j.solener.2024.112477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2024.112477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Liu H., Qi H. High efficiency electro- and photo-thermal conversion cellulose nanofiber-based phase change materials for thermal management. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2023;629:478&#x2013;486. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2022.08.132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2022.08.132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36088693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Zheng Z., Xu L., Xie H., Fei Z., Dyson P.J., Yan N. Light- and electro-driven phase change materials derived from activated porous biochar nanosheets and encapsulated polyethylene glycol. Colloids Surf. A. 2024;690:133783. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li A., Dong C., Dong W., Yuan F., Gao H., Chen X., Chen X.B., Wang G. Network structural cnts penetrate porous carbon support for phase-change materials with enhanced electro-thermal performance. Adv. Electron. Mater. 2020;6:1901428. doi: 10.1002/aelm.201901428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aelm.201901428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Zhang C., Wang J., Wang Y., Yu F. Carbon hybrid aerogel-based phase change material with reinforced energy storage and electro-thermal conversion performance for battery thermal management. J. Storage Mater. 2022;52:104905. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2022.104905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2022.104905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin F., Liu X., Leng G., Bai Y., Feng J., Guo Z., Wang Z., Huang Z., Mi R., Min X., et al. Grid structure phase change composites with effective solar/electro-thermal conversion for multi-functional thermal application. Carbon. 2023;201:1001&#x2013;1010. doi: 10.1016/j.carbon.2022.09.077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2022.09.077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiaojun T., Yingqi C., Wenlong X., Fangfang L., Meiyun Z., Shunxi S., Bin Y., Jingyi N., Chunmei L. Aramid nanofiber-based multifunctional phase change film for photo/electro-thermal energy conversion, harvesting and storage. Small. 2026;22:e10359. doi: 10.1002/smll.202510359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202510359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41546503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y., Li Y., Lin J., Liu P., Chen X., Wang G. Magnetically-responsive phase change thermal storage materials: Mechanisms, advances, and beyond. J. Energy Chem. 2025;101:485&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1016/j.jechem.2024.09.055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jechem.2024.09.055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao Y., Wu B., Wang G., Li Y., Pan C., Long Y., Cheng Q., Yang H., Fan G. Zinc/iron/cobalt modified functionalized biochar composites for multi-source energy conversion and building temperature management. J. Storage Mater. 2026;141:119243. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2025.119243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.119243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Yan Y., Wu Y., Liu C., Huang J., Hu Y., Li Y., Yang Z. Phase-change-integrated magnetic porous carbon for synergistic magnetothermal and photothermal interfacial evaporation. Energy Convers. Manag. 2026;349:120813. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Liu X., Tie J., Ding J., Wang P., Jiang Z., Tie S., Wang C. Photo- and magneto-responsive highly CNTs@Fe3O4 glauber&#x2019;s salt based phase change composites for energy conversion and storage. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2025;286:113598. doi: 10.1016/j.solmat.2025.113598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2025.113598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H., Fang M., Long F., Jing H., Wang B., Fan X., Guo J., Cheng Y., Sun A. 4D printing of programmable liquid&#x2013;vapor phase change composites for multi-responsive flexible actuators. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2025;13:18473&#x2013;18483. doi: 10.1039/D5TA01299F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5TA01299F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Tang B., Ju B., Gao Z., Xiu J., Zhang S. Fe3O4-functionalized graphene nanosheet embedded phase change material composites: Efficient magnetic- and sunlight-driven energy conversion and storage. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2017;5:958&#x2013;968. doi: 10.1039/C6TA07144A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6TA07144A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Fan X., Qiu J., Umair M.M., Ju B., Zhang S., Tang B. Extracorporeal magnetic thermotherapy materials for self-controlled temperature through phase transition. Chem. Eng. J. 2019;358:1279&#x2013;1286. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2018.10.118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2018.10.118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y., Tang Z., Chen X., Yan J., Jiang Y., Xu J., Tao Z., Wang L., Liu Z., Wang G. Magnetically accelerated thermal energy storage within Fe3O4-anchored mxene-based phase change materials. Aggregate. 2022;4:e248. doi: 10.1002/agt2.248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/agt2.248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao Z., Yang M., Wu L., Yan J., Yang F., Lin J., Wang J., Wang G. Phase change material based on polypyrrole/Fe3O4- functionalized hollow kapok fiber aerogel matrix for solar /magnetic- thermal energy conversion and storage. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;423:130180. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2021.130180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.130180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao W., Yang H., Cao G., Sun X., Wang X., Wang C. Carbonized wood flour matrix with functional phase change material composite for magnetocaloric-assisted photothermal conversion and storage. Energy. 2020;202:117636. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2020.117636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.117636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Xu J., Li Y., Gao Y., Wang G. Integrating multiple energy storage in 1d&#x2013;2d bridged array carbon-based phase change materials. SusMat. 2023;3:510&#x2013;521. doi: 10.1002/sus2.147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sus2.147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Jiang Y., Chen X., Tang Z., Gao Y., Huang M., Wan Y., Cheng P., Wang G. Photo- and magneto-responsive highly graphitized carbon based phase change composites for energy conversion and storage. Mater. Today Nano. 2022;19:100234. doi: 10.1016/j.mtnano.2022.100234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtnano.2022.100234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>