<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41935473</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-2831</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Radiography (London, England : 1995)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Radiography (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Adaptation and Validation of an Ergonomic Assessment of Radiographers-Questionnaire (EAR-Q&#xa9;) for assessing Work-Related Musculoskeletal Disorders among Radiographers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103404</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103404</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.radi.2026.103404</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1078-8174(26)00080-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Work-related musculoskeletal disorders (WRMSDs) are multifactorial conditions that require assessment across multiple domains to understand their underlying causes. Although global research highlights the significant burden of WRMSDs among Radiographers, existing studies have not comprehensively captured all relevant contributing factors. This study aimed to adapt and preliminarily validate an existing copyrighted tool- Ergonomic assessment of Radiographers-questionnaire (EAR-Q&#xa9;) by expanding its scope.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">With permission from the original developers, the existing tool was extended by adding items based on literature review and workplace observation. The adapted tool underwent two rounds of expert content validation, achieving an improved content validity index (CVI) from 0.43 to 0.85. A pilot study was conducted with 40 Radiographers to test feasibility, reliability and preliminary factor structure.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Reliability analyses indicated good internal consistency for the overall scale (&#x3b1; = 0.827) and for the musculoskeletal pain subscale (&#x3b1; = 0.872). Principal component analysis support coherent structures for the musculoskeletal pain and work-related sections, while highlighting areas for refinement within the sociodemographic and work environment section. Confirmatory factor analysis did not reach acceptable fit, emphasizing sample size limitation and the need for item revision.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The adapted questionnaire demonstrates feasibility and preliminary measurement strengths. Pilot findings provide guidance for targeted refinements and emphasize the need for full validation in a larger, adequately powered sample.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATION TO PRACTICE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Use of the adapted EAR-Q&#xa9; can support the systematic identification of WRMSD risk factors among Radiographers; these findings can then be used to guide targeted ergonomic interventions, workplace modifications, and health monitoring initiatives aimed at reducing WRMSD prevalence and severity, enhancing occupational well-being, and informing policies for a safer, healthier work environment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nayak</LastName><ForeName>U U</ForeName><Initials>UU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Anatomy, Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India. Electronic address: ullas.nayak@learner.manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohapatra</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Comprehensive Rehab&#x131;l&#x131;tat&#x131;on, Department of Physiotherapy, Manipal College of Health Professions, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India. Electronic address: sidhi.mohapatra@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>George</LastName><ForeName>B M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Anatomy, Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India. Electronic address: bincy.george@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vennila</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistics, Manipal College of Health Professions, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India. Electronic address: vennila.j@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maiya</LastName><ForeName>G A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Podiatry &amp; Diabetic Foot Care and Research, Department of Physiotherapy, Manipal College of Health Professions, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India. Electronic address: arun.maiya@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohandas Rao</LastName><ForeName>K G</ForeName><Initials>KG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Anatomy, Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India. Electronic address: mohandas.rao@manipal.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Radiography (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9604102</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-8174</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Occupational health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radiology technologist</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Structural equation modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">principal component analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">questionnaire adaptation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41935473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radi.2026.103404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1078-8174(26)00080-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>