<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41487361</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-462X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in plant science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Plant Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pheno-morphological and biochemical characterization of root nodules and associated root nodulating bacteria from <i>Pongamia pinnata</i> (L.) Pierre in the arid regions of India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1717750</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1717750</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1717750</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpls.2025.1717750</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED"><i>Pongamia pinnata</i> (L.) Pierre is a resilient leguminous tree valued for its biofuel potential and ability to flourish in marginal soils due to symbiotic nitrogen fixation by root-nodulating bacteria (RNB). Understanding the phenomorphological, soil, and biochemical characteristics of its associated RNB is essential for enhancing productivity in arid regions. This study aimed to characterize RNB isolates associated with <i>P. pinnata</i> and assess how soil properties and nodule biochemistry influence plant growth in the arid ecosystems of western Rajasthan.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty RNB isolates (PP-01 to PP-20) were collected from <i>P. pinnata</i> nodules across arid sites. Rhizospheric soil samples were analysed for physico-chemical parameters, including pH, EC, organic carbon, and nutrient contents. Nodules were examined for morphology and nitrogen-fixing activity. Biochemical profiling of isolates included phenolics, tannins, FRAP, and total antioxidant capacity. Seedling growth responses to individual isolates were evaluated under controlled conditions. Statistical analyses included multiple regression, stepwise regression, PCA, and hierarchical cluster analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Soils were alkaline (pH 8.2-9.1) with moderate EC (1.18-1.89 dS m<sup>-</sup>&#xb9;) and heterogeneous nutrient availability. Nodules exhibited diverse morphology with active nitrogen fixation. Seedling growth differed significantly among isolates, with PP-18, PP-19, and PP-20 showing the highest performance. Biochemical traits varied widely; isolates PP-08, PP-09, PP-14, and PP-20 demonstrated superior antioxidant activity. Multiple regression identified nitrogen, potassium, pH, organic carbon, tannin, and antioxidant content as positive contributors to growth, while phosphorus, phenol, and EC were negative predictors (R&#xb2; = 0.85). Stepwise regression indicated nitrogen, pH, organic carbon, and tannin as the most influential variables (R&#xb2; = 0.61). PCA explained 98.8% of the total variance and distinctly separated isolates based on biochemical and growth characteristics. Cluster analysis grouped the twenty sites into three clusters corresponding to soil fertility gradients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study demonstrates that both soil nutrient status and nodule biochemical composition jointly regulate <i>P. pinnata</i> growth under arid conditions. High-performing isolates, particularly PP-18, PP-19, and PP-20, possess favourable physiological and biochemical attributes supportive of plant growth. The strong discriminatory power of PCA and clustering highlights the ecological differentiation among isolates across fertility gradients. These results underscore the potential of selecting site-specific, elite RNB strains to enhance <i>P. pinnata</i> productivity, soil fertility, and sustainable agroforestry in arid landscapes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Vyas, Singh, Choudhary, Bhoi, Dey and Saraswat.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vyas</LastName><ForeName>Vipula</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Forest Protection Division, Indian Council of Forestry Research and Education (ICFRE)-Arid Forest Research Institute, Jodhpur, Rajasthan, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Sangeeta</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Forest Protection Division, Indian Council of Forestry Research and Education (ICFRE)-Arid Forest Research Institute, Jodhpur, Rajasthan, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choudhary</LastName><ForeName>Sunil</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, Shri Baldev Ram Mirdha Government College, Nagaur, Rajasthan,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhoi</LastName><ForeName>Tanmaya Kumar</ForeName><Initials>TK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Forest Protection Division, Indian Council of Forestry Research and Education (ICFRE)-Arid Forest Research Institute, Jodhpur, Rajasthan, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dey</LastName><ForeName>Prithwiraj</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agricultural and Food Engineering Department, Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur, West Bengal,&#xa0;India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saraswat</LastName><ForeName>Anuj</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, United Arab Emirates University, Al Ain,&#xa0;United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Plant Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101568200</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-462X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pongamia pinnata</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antioxidant activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nitrogen fixation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nodule morphology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">root nodulating bacteria</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41487361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12756030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2025.1717750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdelaal K., AlKahtani M., Attia K., Hafez Y., Kir&#xe1;ly L., K&#xfc;nstler A. (2021). The role of plant growth-promoting bacteria in alleviating the adverse effects of drought on plants. Biology 10, 520. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/biology10060520, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology10060520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8230635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34207963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abera T., Semu E., Debele T., Wegary D., Kim H. (2015). Determination soil rhizobium populations, intrinsic antibiotic resistance, nodulation and seed yield of faba bean and soybean in Western Ethiopia. World J. Agric. Sci. 11, 311&#x2013;324. doi:&#xa0; 10.5829/idosi.wjas.2015.11.5.1869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5829/idosi.wjas.2015.11.5.1869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar C. H., Pires D., Cortaga C., Peja R., Jr., Cruz M. A., Langres J., et al. (2025). Harnessing legume productivity in tropical farming systems by addressing challenges posed by legume diseases. Nitrogen 6, 65. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/nitrogen6030065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nitrogen6030065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agustiani R. D., Rahmani N., Ekowati N. (2023). Isolation and characterization of rhizospheric bacteria associated with canna plant: for production of maltooligosaccharide amylase (Jakarta, Indonesia: Asadel Publisher; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameer S., Ibrahim H., Kulsoom F. N. U., Ameer G., Sher M. (2024). Real-time detection and measurements of nitrogen, phosphorous &amp; potassium from soil samples: a comprehensive review. J. Soils Sediments 24, 2565&#x2013;2583. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s11368-024-03827-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11368-024-03827-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim E. L., Nascimento J. E., Monteiro J. M., Peixoto Sobrinho T. J., Ara&#xfa;jo T. A., Albuquerque U. P. (2008). A simple and accurate procedure for the determination of tannin and flavonoid levels and some applications in ethnobotany and ethnopharmacology. Funct. Ecosyst. Commun. 2, 88&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benzie I. F., Strain J. J. (1999). Ferric reducing/antioxidant power assay: direct measure of total antioxidant activity of biological fluids and modified version for simultaneous measurement of total antioxidant power and ascorbic acid concentration. Methods enzymology 299, 15&#x2013;27. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/S0076-6879(99)99005-5, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0076-6879(99)99005-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhati K. T., Kumar S., Haileslassie A., Whitbread A. M. (2017). Assessment of agricultural technologies for Dryland systems in South Asia: a case study of Western Rajasthan, India. 68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhoi T. K., Samal I., Saraswat A., Hombegowda H. C., Samal S. K., Dash A. K., et al. (2024). &#x201c; Biochar as a soil amendment: Effects on microbial communities and soil health,&#x201d; in Biochar production for green economy (London, United Kingdom: Academic Press; ), 137&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhusal A., Muriana P. M. (2021). Isolation and characterization of nitrate reducing bacteria for conversion of vegetable-derived nitrate to &#x2018;natural nitrite&#x2019;. Appl. Microbiol. 1, 11&#x2013;23. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/applmicrobiol1010002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/applmicrobiol1010002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappuccino J. G., Sherman N. (2007). Microbiology, A laboratory manual. 7th ed (California, USA: The Benjamin/Cummings Publishing Co.).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Cappuccino J. G., Sherman N. (2008). <i>Microbiology: a laboratory manual</i> (Vol. 9) (San Francisco, CA, USA: 
Pearson/Benjamin Cummings; ).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chimdi A., Negasa D., Chala G. (2022). Effects of rhizobium inoculation and P fertilizer levels on selected soil properties, yield, and yield components of faba bean (Vicia faba L.): The case of Abuna Gindeberat, west Shewa Zone, Ethiopia. Appl. Environ. Soil Sci. 2022, 3635989. doi:&#xa0; 10.1155/2022/3635989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/3635989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Chiranjeevi N. (2020). <i>Investigations into antagonistic basis of root endophytic bacteria in the control of chickpea dry root rot pathogen (Rhizoctonia bataticola (Taub.) Butler)</i>. Guntur, Andhra Pradesh, India: 
ACHARYA NG RANGA AGRICULTURAL UNIVERSITY.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degani E., Prasad M. V. R., Paradkar A., Pena R., Soltangheisi A., Ullah I., et al. (2022). A critical review of Pongamia pinnata multiple applications: from land remediation and carbon sequestration to socioeconomic benefits. J. Environ. Manage. 324, 116297. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.116297, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.116297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36174475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhaliwal S. S., Sharma V., Shukla A. K., Kaur J., Gupta R. K., Verma V., et al. (2023). Interactive effect of land use systems on depth-wise soil properties and micronutrients minerals in North-Western, India. Current science 116 (1), 112&#x2013;116. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13591, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9970903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36865444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enagbonma B. J., Fadiji A. E., Ayangbenro A. S., Babalola O. O. (2023). Communication between plants and rhizosphere microbiome: exploring the root microbiome for sustainable agriculture. Microorganisms 11, 2003. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/microorganisms11082003, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms11082003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10458600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37630562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Fernandes J&#xfa;nior P. I., Lima A. A. D., Passos S. R., Gava C. A. T., Oliveira P. J. D., Rumjanek N. G., et al. (2012). 
Phenotypic diversity and amylolytic activity of fast growing rhizobia from pigeonpea [<i>Cajanus cajan</i> (L.) Millsp. Braz. J. Microbiol.
43, 1604&#x2013;1612. doi:&#xa0; 10.1590/S1517-83822012000400045, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1517-83822012000400045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3769046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24031992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebreegziabher B. W., Dubale A. A., Adaramola M. S., Morken J. (2025). Advancing anaerobic digestion of biodiesel byproducts: A comprehensive review. Bioenergy Res. 18, 15. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s12155-025-10820-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12155-025-10820-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giordano M., Petropoulos S. A., Rouphael Y. (2021). The fate of nitrogen from soil to plants: Influence of agricultural practices in modern agriculture. Agriculture 11, 944. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/agriculture11100944</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture11100944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon S. A., Weber R. P. (1951). Colorimetric estimation of indoleacetic acid. Plant Physiol. 26, 192&#x2013;195. doi:&#xa0; 10.1104/pp.26.1.192, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.26.1.192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC437633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16654351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal R. K., Habtewold J. Z. (2023). Evaluation of legume&#x2013;rhizobial symbiotic interactions beyond nitrogen fixation that help the host survival and diversification in hostile environments. Microorganisms 11, 1454. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/microorganisms11061454, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms11061454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10302611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37374957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal R. K., Schmidt M. A., Hynes M. F. (2021). Molecular biology in the improvement of biological nitrogen fixation by rhizobia and extending the scope to cereals. Microorganisms 9, 125. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/microorganisms9010125, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms9010125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7825764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33430332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal K., Singh N., Jindal S., Kaur R., Goyal A., Awasthi R. (2022). Kjeldahl method. Advanced techniques analytical Chem. 1, 105. doi:&#xa0; 10.2174/97898150502331220101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/97898150502331220101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham P. H. (2008). Ecology of the root-nodule bacteria of legumes. In Dilworth M. J., James E. K., Sprent J. I., Newton W. E. (Eds.), Nitrogen-fixing leguminous symbioses (pp. 23&#x2013;58). Springer Netherlands. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/978-1-4020-3548-2_2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4020-3548-2_2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan M. (2018). Effect of rhizobium inoculation with phosphorus and nitrogen fertilizer on physico-chemical properties of the groundnut soil. Environ. Ecosystem Sci. 2, 04&#x2013;06. doi:&#xa0; 10.26480/ees.01.2018.04.06</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26480/ees.01.2018.04.06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isokar S., Potdukhe S., Ingle R., Pudake S. P. (2024). Characterization of Mesorhizobium ciceri isolates from chickpea root nodules: A biochemical approach. Int. J. Advanced Biochem. Res. 8, 753&#x2013;759. doi:&#xa0; 10.33545/26174693.2024.v8.i4i.1042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33545/26174693.2024.v8.i4i.1042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasana R. C., Salwan R., Dhar H., Dutt S., Gulati A. (2008). A rapid and easy method for the detection of microbial cellulases on agar plates using Gram&#x2019;s Iodine. Curr. Microbiol. 57, 503&#x2013;507. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s00284-008-9276-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00284-008-9276-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18810533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashyap A. S., Tetorya M., Kesharwani A. K., Singh D. (2019). MOLECULAR AND PHYSIOLOGICAL CHARACTERIZATION OF PLANT GROWTH PROMOTING RHIZOBACTERIA: METHODS AND PROTOCOLS. Pharmacognosy Nutr. 79, 79&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandelwal M., Vyas P. S. (2024). Cultural and biochemical characteristics of rhizobium present in nodule of pongamia pinnata (l.) pierre. Indian J. Advanced Bot. (IJAB) 4, 32&#x2013;36. doi:&#xa0; 10.54105/ijab.B1036.04021024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54105/ijab.B1036.04021024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khare N., Khare P., Singh S. (2025). &#x201c; Molecular and physiological concepts: Macronutrients in crop plant growth and development,&#x201d; in Agricultural crop improvement (Boca Raton, FL, USA: CRC Press; ), 148&#x2013;164).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnasamy R., Natesh R., Obbineni J. M. (2024). Efficient ROS scavenging improves the growth and yield in black gram (Vigna mungo (L.) Hepper) after seed priming and treatment using biosynthesized silver nanoparticles with Pongamia pinnata (L.) Pierre leaf extract. J. Plant Growth Regul. 43, 2422&#x2013;2438. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s00344-024-11276-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00344-024-11276-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnasamy R., Obbineni J. M. (2025). Phytopriming of Vigna mungo (L.) Hepper (Blackgram) Seeds using Aqueous Extracts of Moringa oleifera Lam, Gliricidia sepium (Jacq.) Walp and Pongamia pinnata (L.) Pierre Improves Seedling Emergence, Growth and Yield. Indian J. Agric. Res. 59, 2422&#x2013;2438. doi:&#xa0; 10.18805/ijare.a-6334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18805/ijare.a-6334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M., Mitra S., Mazumdar S. P., Verma B. C., Pramanick B. (2025). System productivity, soil carbon and nitrogen sequestration of intensive rice-based cropping systems can be improved through legume crop inclusion with appropriate fertilizer application and crop residues incorporation in the eastern Indo-Gangatic plain. Plant Soil 507, 25&#x2013;46. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s11104-023-06415-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11104-023-06415-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N., Pathak L., Shah K. (2025). Exploring the contribution of non-edible plants in phytoremediation and biofuel production in India. Environ. Sustainability, 1&#x2013;14. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s42398-025-00343-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42398-025-00343-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundu A., Kundu C. K., Dey P., Rana S., Majumder J., Bera A., et al. (2024). Management of soil cover and tillage regimes in upland rice-sweet corn systems for better system performance, energy use and carbon footprints. Heliyon 10, e26524. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26524, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e26524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10900818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38420378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B., Zhang D., Pan X. (2022). Nodules of wild legumes as unique natural hotspots of antibiotic resistance genes. Sci. Total Environ. 839, 156036. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.156036, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.156036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35597353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marriboina S., Sekhar K. M., Subramanyam R., Reddy A. R. (2022). Physiological, biochemical, and root proteome networks revealed new insights into salt tolerance mechanisms in Pongamia pinnata (L.) Pierre. Front. Plant Sci. 12, 771992. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fpls.2021.771992, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2021.771992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35140728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Maya R. (2022). <i>Studies on biochemical and molecular characterization of isolated nodule-associated bacteria from Mimosa pudica L. and their plant growth promoting activities on Vigna radiata L.(Wilczek)</i>. [Master&#x2019;s/MPhil/Ph.D. thesis, University of Calicut]. Malappuram, Kerala, India Chiranjeevi: 
Department of Botany, University of Calicut.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehata D. K., Kattel I., Sapkota P., Ghimire N. P., Mehta R. K. (2023). Biofertilizers: A sustainable strategy for organic farming that would increase crop production and soil health. Plant Physiol. Soil Chem. 3, 49&#x2013;53. doi:&#xa0; 10.26480/ppsc.02.2023.49.53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26480/ppsc.02.2023.49.53</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza-Su&#xe1;rez M., Andersen S. U., Poole P. S., S&#xe1;nchez-Ca&#xf1;izares C. (2021). Competition, nodule occupancy, and persistence of inoculant strains: key factors in the rhizobium-legume symbioses. Front. Plant Sci. 12, 690567. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fpls.2021.690567, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2021.690567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8416774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir M. I., Nagabhushanam B., Quadriya H. U. M. E. R. A., Kumar B. K., Hameeda B. (2020). Morphological, biochemical and intrinsic antibiotic resistance of rhizobia isolated from root and stem nodules of various leguminous plants. Plant Cell Biotechnol. Mol. Biol. 21, 126&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moharana P. C., Jena R. K., Kumar N., Singh R. S., Rao S. S. (2021). Assessment of soil organic and inorganic carbon stock at different soil depths after conversion of desert into arable land in the hot arid regions of India. Carbon Manage. 12, 153&#x2013;165. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/17583004.2021.1893128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17583004.2021.1893128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrunalini K., Behera B., Chandana P., Patnaik G. P., Modi R. U., Saraswat A., et al. (2022). &#x201c; Legumes to reduce ecological footprints for climate-smart cropping systems,&#x201d; in Advances in legumes for sustainable intensification (London, United Kingdom: Academic Press; ), 403&#x2013;420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee R., Sen S. (2021). Role of biological nitrogen fixation (BNF) in sustainable agriculture: A Review. Int. J. Adv. Life Sci. Res. 4, 01&#x2013;07. doi:&#xa0; 10.31632/ijalsr.2021.v04i03.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31632/ijalsr.2021.v04i03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulla A. A., Shah A. P. (2025). Production and engine performance analysis of biodiesel from Pongamia pinnata using PTSA and CaO nanocatalysts. Biomass Bioenergy 195, 107714. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.biombioe.2025.107714</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biombioe.2025.107714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nag P., Shriti S., Das S. (2020). Microbiological strategies for enhancing biological nitrogen fixation in nonlegumes. J. Appl. Microbiol. 129, 186&#x2013;198. doi:&#xa0; 10.1111/jam.14557, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jam.14557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31858682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naorem A., Jayaraman S., Dang Y. P., Dalal R. C., Sinha N. K., Rao C. S., et al. (2023). Soil constraints in an arid environment&#x2014;Challenges, prospects, and implications. Agronomy 13, 220. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/agronomy13010220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy13010220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nautiyal C. S. (1999). An efficient microbiological growth medium for screening phosphate solubilizing microorganisms. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 170, pp.265&#x2013;pp.270. doi:&#xa0; 10.1111/j.1574-6968.1999.tb13383.x, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6968.1999.tb13383.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9919677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemenzo P. (2016). Nodulation and symbiotic nitrogen fixation in the biofuel legume tree Pongamia pinnata. Atlas J. Biol. 2016, 274&#x2013;291. doi:&#xa0; 10.5147/ajb.2016.0141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5147/ajb.2016.0141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nohwar N., Khandare R. V., Desai N. S. (2019). Isolation and characterization of salinity tolerant nitrogen fixing bacteria from Sesbania sesban (L) root nodules. Biocatalysis Agric. Biotechnol. 21, 101325. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.bcab.2019.101325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcab.2019.101325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ort&#xed;z J., Sanhueza C., Romero-Munar A., Hidalgo-Castellanos J., Castro C., Bascu&#xf1;&#xe1;n-Godoy L., et al. (2020). 
<i>In vivo</i> metabolic regulation of alternative oxidase under nutrient deficiency&#x2014;interaction with arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi and rhizobium bacteria. Int. J. Mol. Sci.
21, 4201. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/ijms21124201, PMID: 

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms21124201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32545597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S., Shin Y., Kim J. M., Kim M. S., Jung S. (2024). Rhizobial oxidized 3-hydroxylbutanoyl glycan-based gelatin hydrogels with enhanced physiochemical properties for pH-responsive drug delivery. Int. J. Biol. Macromolecules 264, 130538. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.130538, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.130538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38432278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil J. R., Mhatre K. J., Yadav K., Yadav L. S., Srivastava S., Nikalje G. C. (2024). Flavonoids in plant-environment interactions and stress responses. Discover Plants 1, 68. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s44372-024-00063-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44372-024-00063-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paudyal S. P., Kunwar B., Paudel N., Das B. D. (2021). Isolation and characterization of rhizobia from the root nodule of some cultivated legume crops. Eur. J. Biol. Res. 11, 294&#x2013;306. doi:&#xa0; 10.5281/zenodo.4906255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5281/zenodo.4906255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto P., Pineda M., Aguilar M. (1999). Spectrophotometric quantitation of antioxidant capacity through the formation of a phosphomolybdenum complex: specific application to the determination vitamin E. Anal. Biochem. 269, 337&#x2013;341. doi:&#xa0; 10.1006/abio-.1999.4019, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/abio-.1999.4019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10222007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajarajan K., Sakshi S., Taria S., Prathima P. T., Radhakrishna A., Anuragi H., et al. (2022). Whole plant response of Pongamia pinnata to drought stress tolerance revealed by morpho-physiological, biochemical and transcriptome analysis. Mol. Biol. Rep. 49, 9453&#x2013;9463. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s11033-022-07808-0, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11033-022-07808-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36057878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramanjaneyulu A. V., Chaitanya T., Raghu Rami Reddy P., Rajashekhar M., Handa A. K., Arunachalam A., et al. (2025). Monograph on &#x201c;Pongamia&#x201d;(Pongamia pinnata) Vol. 500 (Rajendranagar, Hyderabad, India: Professor Jayashankar Telangana Agricultural University (PJTAU), Rajendranagar, Hyderabad; ), 1&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronald M. A., James W. S. (2006) in 2nd ed (Boca Raton, Florida, United States: CRC Press; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo G. R., Swamy S. L., Mishra A., Thakur T. K. (2021). Effect of seed source, light, and nitrogen levels on biomass and nutrient allocation pattern in seedlings of Pongamia pinnata. Environ. Sci. pollut. Res. 28, 15005&#x2013;15020. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/s11356-020-11734-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-11734-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33221992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saritha M., Kumar S., Naorem A. K., Meena O. P., Meena K. K., Singh D. (2025). &#x201c; Fostering the future of drylands: balancing productivity and resilience through nature-based solutions,&#x201d; in Land restoration through ecosystem-based approach: contexts from drylands of the global south ( Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore: ), 129&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., Saraswat A., Khardia N., Chawla R., Ram S., Kumar R., et al. (2024). &#x201c; Soil-based implication approach for environmental nexus,&#x201d; in Environmental nexus for resource management (Boca Raton, FL, USA: CRC Press; ), 67&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., Singh Y. V., Saraswat A., Meena R., Khardia N. (2021). Soil quality assessment of different villages of Sanganer block in Jaipur district of Rajasthan (India). Environment &amp; Ecology. 39 (4A), 1106&#x2013;1113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen T., Jin R., Yan J., Cheng X., Zeng L., Chen Q., et al. (2023). Study on diversity, nitrogen-fixing capacity, and heavy metal tolerance of culturable Pongamia pinnata rhizobia in the vanadium-titanium magnetite tailings. Front. Microbiol. 14, 1078333. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fmicb.2023.1078333, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1078333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10315665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37405163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi P., Zhang J., Li X., Zhou L., Luo H., Wang L., et al. (2022). Multiple metabolic phenotypes as screening criteria are correlated with the plant growth-promoting ability of rhizobacterial isolates. Front. Microbiol. 12, 747982. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fmicb.2021.747982, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.747982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shihab M. A., Alkurtany E. S. (2023). &#x201c; Isolation and diagnosis of the root nodule bacteria associated with mung bean plant in gypsiferous soil and testing the promotional criterion of isolates,&#x201d; in IOP Conference Series: Earth and Environmental Science, Vol. 1259. 012019 (Bristol, United Kingdom: IOP Publishing; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoaib M., Hussain S., Cheng X., Cui Y., Liu H., Chen Q., et al. (2021). Synergistic anti-oxidative effects of Pongamia pinnata against nickel mediated by Rhizobium pisi and Ochrobacterium pseudogrignonense. Ecotoxicology Environ. Saf. 217, 112244. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.ecoenv.2021.112244, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2021.112244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33933891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui A. R., Shahzad S. M., Ashraf M., Yasmeen T., Kausar R., Albasher G., et al. (2021). Development and characterization of efficient k-solubilizing rhizobacteria and mesorhizobial inoculants for chickpea. Sustainability 13 (18), 10240. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/su131810240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su131810240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S., Bhoi T. K., Vyas V. (2023). &#x201c; Interceding microbial biofertilizers in agroforestry system for enhancing productivity,&#x201d; in Plant growth promoting microorganisms of arid region ( Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore: ), 161&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh G., Nagora P. R., Haksar P., Kulshrestha S., Rani A. (2025). Assessing soil quality and biomass productivity under wastewater irrigation in the Indian arid region. Environ. Qual. Manage. 34, e70051. doi:&#xa0; 10.1002/tqem.70051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tqem.70051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A., Pant K. S., Prakash P. (2020). Effect of multipurpose tree species on soil Physico-chemical properties and available nutrients in subtropical region of Himachal Pradesh. J. Pharmacognosy Phytochem. 9, 935&#x2013;938. doi:&#xa0; 10.22271/phyto.2020.v9.i6n.13066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22271/phyto.2020.v9.i6n.13066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S., Samal I., Vyas V., Bhoi T. K., Sharma K., Mahanta D. K., et al. (2025). &#x201c; Phytomicrobiome-produced chemosignals: role and implication in plant protection,&#x201d; in Detection, diagnosis and management of air-borne diseases in agricultural crops ( Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore: ), 267&#x2013;291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh G., Sharma S. (2025). &#x201c; Desert ecology and functional aspects of desert ecosystems,&#x201d; in Textbook of forest science ( Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore: ), 227&#x2013;251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S., Shukla P., Rajan N. (2021). Traditional utilization &amp; Pharmacological properties of medicinal plants (Karanja). Traditional Utilization Pharmacol. Properties Medicinal Plants 89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singleton V. L., Rossi J. A. (1965). Colorimetry of total phenolics with phosphomolybdic-phosphotungstic acid reagents. Am. J. Enology Viticulture 16, 144&#x2013;158. doi:&#xa0; 10.5344/ajev.1965.16.3.144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5344/ajev.1965.16.3.144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somasegaran P., Hoben H. J. (1994). Handbook for Rhizobia: Methods in legume&#x2013;Rhizobium technology ( Springer Verlag; ).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soumare A., Diedhiou A. G., Thuita M., Hafidi M., Ouhdouch Y., Gopalakrishnan S., et al. (2020). Exploiting biological nitrogen fixation: a route towards a sustainable agriculture. Plants 9, 1011. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/plants9081011, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants9081011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7464700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32796519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talha Bin Yousaf M., Farrakh Nawaz M., Yasin G., Ahmad I., Gul S., Ijaz M., et al. (2022). Effect of organic amendments in soil on physiological and biochemical attributes of Vachellia nilotica and Dalbergia sissoo under saline stress. Plants 11, 228. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/plants11020228, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants11020228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8781470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur P., Kumar P., Sharma C. L., Sharma U., Sharma N., Ladon T. (2025). Ameliorating potential effects of natural biological formulations and biostimulants on plant health and quality attributes in coriander-fenugreek intercropped strawberry (Fragaria&#xd7; ananassa Duch.). BMC Plant Biol. 25, 164. doi:&#xa0; 10.1186/s12870-025-06184-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-025-06184-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11804047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39920644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilgam J., Sreeshma N., Priyadarshini P., Bhavyasree R. K., Choudhury S., Bharati A., et al. (2022). &#x201c; Rhizosphere engineering for systemic resistance/tolerance to biotic and abiotic stress,&#x201d; in Re-visiting the rhizosphere eco-system for agricultural sustainability ( Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore: ), 271&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsegaye Z., Gizaw B., Tefera G., Feleke A., Chaniyalew S., Alemu T., et al. (2019). Isolation and biochemical characterization of Plant Growth Promoting (PGP) bacteria colonizing the rhizosphere of Tef crop during the seedling stage. J. Plant Sci. Phytopathol. 3, 013&#x2013;027. doi:&#xa0; 10.29328/journal.jpsp.1001027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29328/journal.jpsp.1001027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah R., Abbas Z., Bilal M., Habib F., Iqbal J., Bashir F., et al. (2022). Method development and validation for the determination of potassium (K2O) in fertilizer samples by flame photometry technique. J. King Saud University-Science 34, 102070. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jksus.2022.102070</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksus.2022.102070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valiullin L. R., Gibadullin A. R., Egorov V. I., Mukhammadiev R. S., Mukhammadiev R. S., Sakhnov V. V., et al. (2024). Ensuring tree protection, growth and sustainability by microbial isolates. Sustainability 16, 7837. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/su16177837</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16177837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vashistha H., Kumar P., Kumar S. (2024). PGP attributes of non-rhizobial bacterial endophytes from root nodules of wild leguminous plant Tephrosia purpurea (L) Pers. Environ. Conserv. J. 25, 942&#x2013;955. doi:&#xa0; 10.36953/ECJ.27592833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36953/ECJ.27592833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villar I., Rubio M. C., Calvo-Begueria L., P&#xe9;rez-Rontom&#xe9; C., Larrainzar E., Wilson M. T., et al. (2021). Three classes of hemoglobins are required for optimal vegetative and reproductive growth of Lotus japonicus: genetic and biochemical characterization of LjGlb2-1. J. Exp. Bot. 72, 7778&#x2013;7791. doi:&#xa0; 10.1093/jxb/erab376, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/erab376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8664582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34387337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vyas V., Bhoi T. K., Samal I., Singh S., Mahanta D. K. (2024). Revitalizing degraded soils with agroforestry interventions: opportunities, challenges, and future direction. Agroforestry to Combat Global Challenges: Curr. Prospects Future Challenges, 529&#x2013;549. doi:&#xa0; 10.1007/978-981-99-7282-1_25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-7282-1_25</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiegel J. (1981). Distinction between the Gram reaction and the Gram type of bacteria. Int. J. Systematic Evolutionary Microbiol. 31, 88&#x2013;88. doi:&#xa0; 10.1099/00207713-31-1-88</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/00207713-31-1-88</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeremko L., Czopek K., Staniak M., Marenych M., Hanhur V. (2025). Role of environmental factors in legume-rhizobium symbiosis: A review. Biomolecules 15, 118. doi:&#xa0; 10.3390/biom15010118, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom15010118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11764364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39858512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Shen T., Kang X., Cui Y., Chen Q., Shoaib M., et al. (2021). Long-term phytoremediation using the symbiotic Pongamia pinnata reshaped soil micro-ecological environment. Sci. Total Environ. 774, 145112. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.145112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.145112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>