<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41335297</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2198-4018</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Brain informatics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Brain Inform</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Brain-inspired signal processing for detecting stress during mental arithmetic tasks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>34</StartPage><MedlinePgn>34</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">34</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40708-025-00281-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brain-Computer Interfaces provide promising alternatives for detecting stress and enhancing emotional resilience. This study introduces a lightweight, subject-independent method for detecting stress during arithmetic tasks, designed for low computational cost and real-time use. Stress detection is performed through ElectroEncephaloGraphy (EEG) signal analysis using a simplified processing pipeline. The method begins with preprocessing the EEG recordings to eliminate artifacts and focus on relevant frequency bands (&#x3b1;, &#x3b2;, and &#x3b3;). Features are extracted by calculating band power and its deviation from a baseline. A statistical thresholding mechanism classifies stress and no-stress epochs without the need for subject-specific calibration. The approach was validated on a publicly available dataset of 36 subjects and achieved an average accuracy of 88.89%. The method effectively identifies stress-related brainwave patterns while maintaining efficiency, making it suitable for embedded and wearable devices. Unlike many existing systems, it does not require subject-specific training, enhancing its applicability in real-world environments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belwafi</LastName><ForeName>Kais</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, College of Computing and informatics, University of Sharjah, Sharjah, United Arab Emirates. kbelwafi@sharjah.ac.ae.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alsuwaidi</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering, College of Computing and informatics, University of Sharjah, Sharjah, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mejri</LastName><ForeName>Sami</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pedagogical Enhancement - CTL, Khalifa University of Science and Technology, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Djemal</LastName><ForeName>Ridha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, ATMS Lab, National School of Engineering, University of Sfax, Sfax, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Brain Inform</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101673751</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-4026</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain-computer interface</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EEG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Signal processing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stress detection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interest: The authors declare no Conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41335297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12686278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40708-025-00281-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40708-025-00281-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Immanuel S, Teferra MN, Baumert M, Bidargaddi N (2023) Heart rate variability for evaluating psychological stress changes in healthy adults: a scoping review. Neuropsy 82(4):187&#x2013;202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10614455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37290411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeroh OE, Powers LS, Roveda JM (2018) Determination of stress in humans using data fusion of off-the-shelf wearable sensors data for electrocardiogram and galvanic skin response. J Biomed Sci. 10.4172/2254-609x.100090</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2254-609x.100090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satapathy C, Gokhale H, Syed AZ, Nersisson R (2024) Galvanic skin response based stress level detection using supervised machine learning approach. In: AIP Conference Proceedings, vol. 2966. AIP Publishing</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Shaun MA, Chaurasia BK (2024) Identification of psychological stress from speech signal using deep learning algorithm. e-Prime - Adv Electr Eng Electron Energy 9:100707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prime.2024.100707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saadon JR, Yang F, Burgert R, Mohammad S, Gammel T, Sepe M, Rafailovich M, Mikell CB, Polak P, Mofakham S (2023) Real-time emotion detection by quantitative facial motion analysis. PLoS ONE 18(3):0282730</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0282730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10004542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36897921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jyothirmy S, Ahamed SF, A RR, Geethika G, Sai SB, Saiteja B (2023) Stress monitoring in humans using biomedical signal analysis. In: 2023 Second International Conference on Electrical, Electronics, Information and Communication Technologies (ICEEICT), pp. 1&#x2013;7. 10.1109/ICEEICT56924.2023.10156948</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Gamper H, Tashev I, Dong S, Ma S, Remaley J, Holbery JD, Yoon SH (2020) Stress monitoring using multimodal bio-sensing headset. In: Extended Abstracts of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. CHI EA &#x2019;20, pp. 1&#x2013;7. Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA. 10.1145/3334480.3382891</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanei S, Chambers JA (2007) EEG Signal Processing. Wiley, Chichester, UK</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouallegue G, Djemal R, Belwafi K (2021) Artificial EEG signal generated by a network of neurons with one and two dendrites. Results Phys 20:103699. 10.1016/j.rinp.2020.103699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rinp.2020.103699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gannouni S, Aledaily A, Belwafi K, Aboalsamh H (2022) Electroencephalography based emotion detection using ensemble classification and asymmetric brain activity. J Affect Disord 319:416&#x2013;427. 10.1016/j.jad.2022.09.054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2022.09.054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36162677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De&#xa0;Vries S, Smits R, Tataj M, Ronckers M, Van Der&#xa0;Pol M, Van&#xa0;Oost F, Adam E, Smaling H, Meinders E (2022) Accurate stress detection from novel real-time electrodermal activity signals and multi-task learning models. In: Cognitive Computing and Internet of Things. AHFE 2022. AHFE International, New York, USA. 10.54941/ahfe1001845</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashivan P, Rish I, Yeasin M, Codella N (2015) Learning Representations from EEG with Deep Recurrent-Convolutional Neural Networks. arXiv. 10.48550/ARXIV.1511.06448 . arxiv:1511.06448</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam MK, Rastegarnia A, Yang Z (2016) Methods for artifact detection and removal from scalp EEG: a review. Neurophys Clin/Clin Neurophy 46(4&#x2013;5):287&#x2013;305. 10.1016/j.neucli.2016.07.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neucli.2016.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27751622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Z, Zhao M, Wang Y, Yang J, Zhang J (2017) Recognition of emotions using multimodal physiological signals and an ensemble deep learning model. Comput Methods Programs Biomed 140:93&#x2013;110. 10.1016/j.cmpb.2016.12.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2016.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28254094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premchand B, Liang L, Phua KS, Zhang Z, Wang C, Guo L, Ang J, Koh J, Yong X, Ang KK (2024) Wearable EEG -based brain&#x2013;computer interface for stress monitoring. NeuroSci 5(4):407&#x2013;428. 10.3390/neurosci5040031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/neurosci5040031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11503304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39484299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casson AJ (2019) Wearable EEG and beyond. Biomed Eng Lett 9(1):53&#x2013;71. 10.1007/s13534-018-00093-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13534-018-00093-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6431319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30956880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juez JY, Moumane H, Nassar M, Molina-Salcedo I, Enrique Segura-Quijano F, Valderrama M, Le Van Quyen M (2024) Ear-EEG devices for the assessment of brain activity: a review. IEEE Sens J 24(20):31606&#x2013;31623. 10.1109/JSEN.2024.3415668</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2024.3415668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonacci A, Dellabate A, Dieni A, Bachi L, Sansone F, Conte R, Billeci L (2020) Can machine learning predict stress reduction based on wearable sensors&#x2019; data following relaxation at workplace? a pilot study. Process 8(4):448. 10.3390/pr8040448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr8040448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha S, Baumert M (2020) Intra- and inter-subject variability in EEG -based sensorimotor brain computer interface: a review. Front Comput Neurosci 13:87. 10.3389/fncom.2019.00087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncom.2019.00087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6985367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32038208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Carabarin L, Castellanos-Alvarado EA, Castro-Garcia P, Garcia-Ramirez MA (2021) Machine learning for personalised stress detection: Inter-individual variability of EEG -ECG markers for acute-stress response. Comput Methods Programs Biomed 209:106314. 10.1016/j.cmpb.2021.106314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2021.106314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34433128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Xu Y, Hua J, Yi W, Yin H, Hu R, Wang S (2021) A review on signal processing approaches to reduce calibration time in EEG -based brain-computer interface. Front Neurosci 15:733546. 10.3389/fnins.2021.733546</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2021.733546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8417074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang S, Li L, Zu W, Feng W, Hang W (2024) Adaptive deep feature representation learning for cross-subject EEG decoding. BMC Bioinform 25(1):393. 10.1186/s12859-024-06024-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12859-024-06024-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11686875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39741250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brophy E, Redmond P, Fleury A, De Vos M, Boylan G, Ward T (2022) Denoising EEG signals for real-world BCI applications using gans. Front Neuroergonomics 2:805573. 10.3389/fnrgo.2021.805573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnrgo.2021.805573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10790876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38235245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobade P, Vani M (2020) Stress detection with machine learning and deep learning using multimodal physiological data. In: 2020 Second International Conference on Inventive Research in Computing Applications (ICIRCA), pp. 51&#x2013;57. 10.1109/ICIRCA48905.2020.9183244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahithi R, Siddarth JJ, Monisha HM, Ashok Kumar R 2024) A survey of EEG-based stress detection using machine learning and deep learning techniques. In: 2024 1st International Conference on Communications and Computer Science (InCCCS), pp. 1&#x2013;6 10.1109/InCCCS60947.2024.10593592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakare S, Kuge S, Sugandhi S, Warad S, Panguddi V (2024) Detection of mental stress using EEG signals - alpha, beta, theta, and gamma bands. In: 2024 5th International Conference for Emerging Technology (INCET), pp. 1&#x2013;9. 10.1109/INCET61516.2024.10592994</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AR, Singh G, Saluja N (2024). Stress detection using EEG signals a review on current strategies and future aspects. 10.1109/icemps60684.2024.10559253</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez J, Mart&#xed;nez R, Innocenti B, L&#xf3;pez B (2024) Contribution of EEG biosignals for stress detection. 10.36227/techrxiv.171709835.51370876/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhake D, Angal Y (2023) A comparative analysis of EEG-based stress detection utilizing machine learning and deep learning classifiers with a critical literature review. Int. J. Recent Innovat. Trends Comput. Commun. 10.17762/ijritcc.v11i8s.7175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim S, AlSharabi K, Djemal R, Alsuwailem A (2016) An adaptive learning approach for eeg-based computer aided diagnosis of epilepsy. In: 2016 International Seminar on Intelligent Technology and Its Applications (ISITIA), pp. 55&#x2013;60. 10.1109/ISITIA.2016.7828633</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Zhang S, Chen W-L, Truong D, Jung T-P (2025) From theory to application: Fine-tuning large EEG model with real-world stress data. arXiv preprint arXiv:2505.23042. [Online]. Available: https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.23042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mynoddin M, Dev T, Chakma R (2025) Brain2vec: a deep learning framework for EEG-based stress detection using CNN-LSTM-attention. arXiv preprint arXiv:2506.11179. [Online]. Available: https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.11179</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinidis I, Avdimiotis S, Sapounidis T (2025) Evaluation of academic stress employing network and time series analysis on EEG data. Information 16(2):86. 10.3390/info16020086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info16020086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C-Y, Hsu C, Wu YC, Wang S, Tsui D, Jung T-P (2024) Online Mental Stress Detection Using Frontal-channel EEG Recordings in a Classroom Scenario. arXiv. 10.48550/ARXIV.2405.11394. https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.11394</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak K, Haneef F (2023) EEG based stress analysis through feature extraction. Int J Recent innov trends comput commun 11:140&#x2013;144. 10.17762/ijritcc.v11i8.7931</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17762/ijritcc.v11i8.7931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolpagni M, Pardini S, Dianti M, Gabrielli S (2024) Personalized stress detection using biosignals from wearables: A scoping review. Sensors 24(10):3221. 10.3390/s24103221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24103221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11126007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38794074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamaluddin R, Mazlan M, Adom A, Abdull Sukor AS (2024) Review of analysis of EEG signals for stress detection. AIP Conf Proceed 10(1063/5):0181590. 10.1063/5.0181590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0181590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zyma I, Tukaev S, Seleznov I, Kiyono K, Popov A, Chernykh M, Shpenkov O (2019) Electroencephalograms during mental arithmetic task performance. Data 4(1):14. 10.3390/data4010014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/data4010014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bali A, Gupta S, Singh N, Jaggi AS (2013) Implicating the role of plasma membrane localized calcium channels and exchangers in stress-induced deleterious effects. Eur J Pharmacol 714(1&#x2013;3):229&#x2013;238. 10.1016/j.ejphar.2013.06.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2013.06.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23796956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paithane AN, Alagirisamy M (2022) Electroencephalogram signal analysis using wavelet transform and support vector machine for human stress recognition. Biomed Pharmacol J 15(3):1349&#x2013;1360. 10.13005/bpj/2471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13005/bpj/2471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gannouni S, Aledaily A, Belwafi K, Aboalsamh H (2021) Emotion detection using electroencephalography signals and a zero-time windowing-based epoch estimation and relevant electrode identification. Scientific Reports 11(1):7071. 10.1038/s41598-021-86345-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-86345-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D, Lawhern VJ, Gordon S, Lance BJ, Lin CT (2017) Driver drowsiness estimation from EEG signals using online weighted adaptation regularization for regression. IEEE Trans Hum Mach Syst 47(5):819&#x2013;829. 10.1109/THMS.2017.2705307</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/THMS.2017.2705307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciaraffa N, Di Flumeri G, Germano D, Giorgi A, Di Florio A, Borghini G, Vozzi A, Ronca V, Varga R, Gasteren M, Babiloni F, Aric&#xf2; P (2022) Validation of a light EEG-based measure for real-time stress monitoring during realistic driving. Brain Sci 12(3):304. 10.3390/brainsci12030304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci12030304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8946850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35326261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pomer-Escher AG, Souza MDP, Filho TFB (2014) Methodology for analysis of stress level based on asymmetry patterns of alpha rhythms in EEG signals. In: 5th ISSNIP-IEEE Biosignals and Biorobotics Conference (2014): Biosignals and Robotics for Better and Safer Living (BRC), pp. 1&#x2013;5. 10.1109/BRC.2014.6880963</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walther D, Viehweg J, Haueisen J, M&#xe4;der P (2023) A systematic comparison of deep learning methods for EEG time series analysis. Front Neuroinf. 17:1067095. 10.3389/fninf.2023.1067095</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fninf.2023.1067095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9995756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36911074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy B, Malviya L, Kumar R, Mal S, Kumar A, Bhowmik T, Hu JW (2023) Hybrid deep learning approach for stress detection using decomposed EEG signals. Diagnostics 13(11):1936. 10.3390/diagnostics13111936</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics13111936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10252840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37296788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saranya K, Jayanthy S (2022) An efficient ap-ANN-based multimethod fusion model to detect stress through EEG signal analysis. Comput intell Neurosci 2022:1&#x2013;18. 10.1155/2022/7672297</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/7672297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9763020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36544857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan MJ, Kim J-M (2019) A hybrid feature pool-based emotional stress state detection algorithm using EEG signals. Brain Sci 9(12):376. 10.3390/brainsci9120376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci9120376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6956373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31847238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mhaouch A, Fradi M, Gtifa W, Abdelali AB, Machhout M (2024) Deep learning based recurrent neural network model for stress detection in EEG signals. Rev d&#x2019;Intell Artif 38(3):979&#x2013;985. 10.18280/ria.380323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18280/ria.380323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C-Y, Chen R-C, Tai S-K (2018) Emotion stress detection using EEG signal and deep learning technologies. In: 2018 IEEE International Conference on Applied System Invention (ICASI). IEEE, Chiba, Japan. 10.1109/icasi.2018.8394414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C-Y, Hsu C, Wu YC, Wang S, Tsui D, Jung T-P (2024) Online Mental Stress Detection Using Frontal-channel EEG Recordings in a Classroom Scenario. arXiv. 10.48550/ARXIV.2405.11394. https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.11394</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chikhi S, Lefebvre A, D&#x2019;Hondt F, Delorme A, Wascher E (2022) EEG power spectral measures of cognitive workload: a meta-analysis. Psychophys 59(12):805573&#x2013;14009. 10.1111/psyp.14009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/psyp.14009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimesch W (1999) EEG alpha and theta oscillations reflect cognitive and memory performance: a review and analysis. Brain Res Rev 29(2&#x2013;3):169&#x2013;195. 10.1016/s0165-0173(98)00056-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0165-0173(98)00056-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10209231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe4;rtner M, Grimm S, Bajbouj M (2015) Frontal midline theta oscillations during mental arithmetic: effects of stress. Front Behav Neurosci 9:96. 10.3389/fnbeh.2015.00096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2015.00096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4403551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25941479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields GS, Sazma MA, McCullough AM, Yonelinas AP (2017) The effects of acute stress on episodic memory: a meta-analysis and integrative review. Psychol Bull 143(6):636&#x2013;675. 10.1037/bul0000100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/bul0000100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5436944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28368148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupien SJ, Maheu F, Tu M, Fiocco A, Schramek TE (2007) The effects of stress and stress hormones on human cognition: implications for the field of brain and cognition. Brain Cogn 65(3):209&#x2013;237. 10.1016/j.bandc.2007.02.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bandc.2007.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17466428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavanagh JF, Frank MJ (2014) Frontal theta as a mechanism for cognitive control. Trends Cogn Sci 18(8):414&#x2013;421. 10.1016/j.tics.2014.04.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tics.2014.04.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4112145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24835663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>