<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41927815</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of accurate load forecasting on electricity market stability in Japan using classical time-series and deep-learning methods.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-46859-2</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rabie</LastName><ForeName>Dalia</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Graduate School of Engineering Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, 816-8580, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moradi</LastName><ForeName>Mehran</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Graduate School of Engineering Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, 816-8580, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering and Physics, Karlstad University, Karlstad, 651 88, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xuan</LastName><ForeName>Wang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Graduate School of Engineering Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, 816-8580, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farzaneh</LastName><ForeName>Hooman</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Graduate School of Engineering Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, 816-8580, Japan. farzaneh.hooman.961@m.kyushu-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Transdisciplinary Research and Education Center for Green Technologies, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan. farzaneh.hooman.961@m.kyushu-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan. farzaneh.hooman.961@m.kyushu-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hidden Markov model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Japan electric power exchange</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long short-term memory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARIMA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Short-term load forecasting</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41927815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-46859-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-46859-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Casla, I. M., Khodadadi, A. &amp; S&#xf6;der, L. Optimal day ahead planning and bidding strategy of battery storage unit participating in nordic frequency markets. IEEE Access. 10, 76870&#x2013;76883 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, A. &amp; Gupta, S. Evaluation of electrical load demand forecasting using various machine learning algorithms. Front. Energy Res. 12, 1408119 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suliman, M. S. &amp; Farzaneh, H. Synthesizing the market clearing mechanism based on the national power grid using hybrid of deep learning and econometric models: evidence from the Japan Electric Power Exchange (JEPX) market. J. Clean. Prod. 411, 137353 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Lin, C., Zhang, Y., Liu, J. &amp; Yu, D. Day-ahead load forecast based on Conv2D-GRU_SC aimed to adapt to steep changes in load. Energy 302, 131814 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debusschere, V. &amp; Bacha, S. One week hourly electricity load forecasting using Neuro-Fuzzy and Seasonal ARIMA models. IFAC Proc. 45, 97&#x2013;102 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson, M. Modeling electricity load curves with hidden Markov models for demand-side management status estimation. Int. Trans. Electr. Energy Syst. 27 (3), e2265 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MAa, T. Renewable energy generation effects on the electricity market: an empirical study on Japan&#x2019;s Electricity Spot Market (Hunan Normal University, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x67ef;&#x5b9c;&#x5747; &amp; &#x30b3;&#x30a4;&#x30b8;&#x30e5;&#x30f3; Japan residential electricity consumption in response to climate change (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misiurek, K., Olkuski, T. &amp; Zy&#x15b;k, J. Review of methods and models for forecasting electricity consumption. Energies 18, 4032 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shaikh, H., Rahman, M. A. &amp; Zubair, A. Short-term electric demand forecasting for power systems using similar months approach based SARIMA. In IEEE International Conference on Power, Electrical, and Electronics and Industrial Applications (PEEIACON) 122&#x2013;126 (IEEE, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andoh, P. Y. A., Sekyere, C. K. K., Mensah, L. D. &amp; Dzebre, D. E. K. Forecasting electricity demand In Ghana with the Sarima model. J. Appl. Eng. Technol. Sci. (JAETS) 3, 1&#x2013;9 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kien, D. T., Huong, P. D. &amp; Minh, N. D. Application of sarima model in load forecasting in Hanoi city. Int. J. Energy Econ. Policy. 13 (3), 164&#x2013;170 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aks&#xf6;z, A., Oyucu, S., Bi&#xe7;er, E. &amp; Bay&#x131;nd&#x131;r, R. Analysis of SARIMA models for forecasting electricity demand. In 12th International Conference on Smart Grid (icSmartGrid) 767&#x2013;771 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez, J. J., Zapirain, I., Camblong, H., Barroso, N. &amp; Curea, O. Real implementation and testing of short-term building load forecasting: a comparison of SVR and NARX. Energies 18, 1775 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anh, N. T. N. et al. Online SARIMA applied for short-term electricity load forecasting. Appl. Intell. 54 (1), 1003&#x2013;1019 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan, A., Das, S., Su, W. &amp; Bui, V. H. Bayesian neural network-based approach for probabilistic prediction of building energy demands (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Wang, J., Wang, R. &amp; Hou, G. Forecasting next-day electricity prices with Hidden Markov Models. In 5th IEEE Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications 1736&#x2013;1740 (IEEE, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlwein, C., Benth, F. E. &amp; Mamon, R. HMM filtering and parameter estimation of an electricity spot price model. Energy Econ. 32 (5), 1034&#x2013;1043 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah, I., Ahmad, R. &amp; Kim, D. A prediction mechanism of energy consumption in residential buildings using hidden markov model. Energies 11, 358 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khetarpal, P., Nagpal, N., Kumar, M., Lakshmi, D. &amp; Kassarwani, N. Short-term electricity load forecasting using modified hidden Markov model. In International Conference on Renewable Power 61&#x2013;74 (Springer, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, S. &amp; Bao, T. Short-term electricity load forecasting based on NeuralProphet and CNN-LSTM. IEEE Access. 12, 76870&#x2013;76879 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, W. et al. Short-term residential load forecasting based on LSTM recurrent neural network. IEEE Trans. Smart Grid. 10 (1), 841&#x2013;851 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miah, M. S. U. et al. REDf: a deep learning model for short-term load forecasting to facilitate renewable integration and attaining the SDGs 7, 9, and 13. PeerJ Comput. Sci. 11, e2819 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahranjani, Y. K., Beiraghi, M. &amp; Ghanizadeh, R. Short time load forecasting for Urmia city using the novel CNN-LTSM deep learning structure. Electr. Eng. 107 (1), 1253&#x2013;1264 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, B. J. &amp; Nam, I. W. A review of hybrid LSTM models in smart cities. Processes 13, 2298 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochreiter, S. The vanishing gradient problem during learning recurrent neural nets and problem solutions. Int. J. Uncertain. Fuzziness Knowl.-Based Syst. 6 (02), 107&#x2013;116 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, H. et al. Multi-source data fusion-based grid-level load forecasting. Applied Sciences 15, 4820 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x131;rat, O., Cicek, A. &amp; Yerlikaya, T. A new artificial intelligence-based system for optimal electricity arbitrage of a second-life battery station in day-ahead markets. Appl. Sci. 14 (21), 10032 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x131;rat, O. &amp; &#xc7;i&#xe7;ek, A. Artificial intelligence based optimal operation of green hydrogen refueling. In 2024 32nd Telecommunications Forum (TELFOR) 1&#x2013;4 (IEEE, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, N. N. &amp; Duc, H. N. Virtual power plant&#x2019;s optimal scheduling strategy in day-ahead and balancing markets considering reserve provision model of energy storage system. Appl. Sci. 14, 2175 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Azab, H. A. I., Swief, R., El-Amary, N. H. &amp; Temraz, H. Seasonal forecasting of the hourly electricity demand applying machine and deep learning algorithms impact analysis of different factors. Sci. Rep. 15 (1), 9252 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, K. &amp; Yamada, Y. A comprehensive analysis of imbalance signal prediction in the Japanese electricity market using machine learning techniques. Energies 18, 2680 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muzaffar, S. &amp; Afshari, A. Short-term load forecasts using LSTM networks. Energy Procedia. 158, 2922&#x2013;2927 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IEA. Japan Electricity Security Policy [Online]. Available: https://www.iea.org/articles/japan-electricity-security-policy</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiruta, Y., Ishizaki, N. N., Ashina, S. &amp; Takahashi, K. Regional and temporal variations in the impacts of future climate change on Japanese electricity demand: simultaneous interactions among multiple factors considered. Energy Convers. Manage. X. 14, 100172 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otsuka, A. Regional energy demand in Japan: dynamic shift-share analysis. Energy Sustain. Soc. 6 (1), 10 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advisory, S. Everything you need to know about the Japanese Electricity Grid (Shulman, 2025). https://shulman-advisory.com/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-japanese-electricity-grid/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyuhoshi Japan Travel &amp; Culture Guide. https://www.kyuhoshi.com/map-of-japan/ (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distribution, K. E. P. T. Kyushu Electric Power Transmission and Distribution ed (Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry&#x2019;s Agency for Natural Resources and Energy&#x2019;s, 2025). https://www.kyuden.co.jp/td_area_jukyu/jukyu.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distribution, K. E. P. T. Kansai electric power transmission and distribution. https://www.kansai-td.co.jp/denkiyoho/area-performance/past.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distribution, H. E. P. T. Hokuriku electric power transmission and distribution. https://www.rikuden.co.jp/nw_jyukyudata/area_jisseki.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distribution, H. E. P. T. Hokkaido electric power transmission and distribution. https://www.hepco.co.jp/network/con_service/public_document/supply_demand_results/index.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Network, C. E. P. Chugoku electric power network. https://www.energia.co.jp/nw/service/retailer/data/area/index.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distribution, S. E. P. T. Shikoku electric power transmission and distribution. https://www.yonden.co.jp/nw/denkiyoho/download.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grid, T. P. Tokyo electric power company Power Grid. https://www.tepco.co.jp/forecast/html/area_data-j.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grid, C. E. P. Chubu electric power grid. https://powergrid.chuden.co.jp/denkiyoho/ (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Network, T. E. P. Tohoku electric power network. https://setsuden.nw.tohoku-epco.co.jp/download.html (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasvarian Jahromi, K., Gharavian, D. &amp; Mahdiani, H. R. Wind power prediction based on wind speed forecast using hidden Markov model. J. Forecast. 42 (1), 101&#x2013;123 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingma, D. P. &amp; Ba, J. Adam: a method for stochastic optimization. arXiv preprint arXiv:1412.6980 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow, I., Bengio, Y., Courville, A. &amp; Bengio, Y. Deep learning (MIT press, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyndman, R. J. &amp; Athanasopoulos, G. Forecasting: Principles and Practice (OTexts, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariko, P. C. &amp; O&#x2019;Neil, B. N. E. F. Power market outlook: East Meets West as Japan Prices Cool. https://about.bnef.com/insights/commodities/power-market-outlook-east-meets-west-as-japan-prices-cool/ (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>