<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41464052</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2076-328X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Behavioral sciences (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Behav Sci (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Positive Effects of Employee AI Dependence on Voice Behavior-Based on Power Dependence Theory.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1709</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/bs15121709</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid integration of artificial intelligence (AI) into organizational workflows is re-shaping traditional patterns of interaction between leaders and employees. Grounded in power dependence theory, this study investigates how employees' voluntary dependence on AI influences leader-subordinate power relations and, consequently, influences employees' voice behavior. We propose that employees' dependence on AI can increase their perceived power when interacting with leaders, which subsequently enhances their willingness to offer constructive suggestions or question established practices. Furthermore, we propose that the extent to which leadership tasks can be substituted by AI plays a moderating role in this process. Coaching leadership, characterized by its emphasis on guiding task performance and developing employee skills, may be particularly sensitive to such substitution. Using two experimental studies and two survey investigations, we provide evidence that employees' AI dependence is positively associated with voice behavior through heightened perceptions of personal power, and that this relationship is strengthened under high levels of coaching leadership. These findings advance leadership theory by explicating how AI adoption alters foundational power structures in the workplace and by identifying a novel, power-based pathway linking AI use to proactive employee behaviors. The study contributes to emerging discussions on effective leadership in technologically augmented organizations and offers empirical insights into how leaders can adapt their roles and behaviors in the new era of AI-driven work.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jialin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0756-9107</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Business School, University of International Business and Economics, Beijing 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Mingpeng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Business School, University of International Business and Economics, Beijing 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Northwest Normal University, Lanzhou 730070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Guangdi</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Business Administration, Shanxi University of Finance and Economics, Taiyuan 030006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xinyue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Party School of State Grid Corporation of China (Senior Management Training Center of State Grid Corporation of China), Beijing 100192, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>72072032</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>71602032</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Behav Sci (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101576826</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2076-328X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-era leadership</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coaching leadership</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">employee voice behavior</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">power dependence theory</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Xinyue Li was employed by the company Party School of State Grid Corporation of China (Senior Management Training Center of State Grid Corporation of China). The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41464052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12729973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs15121709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">bs15121709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Halim A. A. Interaction effects of power equalization and subordinate personality on job satisfaction and performance. Human Relations. 1979;32(6):489&#x2013;502. doi: 10.1177/001872677903200604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/001872677903200604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ackerman P. L., Kanfer R. Work in the 21st century: New directions for aging and adult development. American Psychologist. 2020;75(4):486&#x2013;498. doi: 10.1037/amp0000615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/amp0000615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32378944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal A., Gans J. S., Goldfarb A. What to expect from artificial intelligence? MIT Sloan Management Review. 2017;58:23&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldrich H., Herker D. Boundary spanning roles and organization structure. Academy of Management Review. 1977;2(2):217&#x2013;230. doi: 10.2307/257905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/257905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M., Raza B., Ali W., Imtaiz N. Linking managerial coaching with employees&#x2019; innovative work behaviors through affective supervisory commitment: Evidence from Pakistan. International Review of Management and Marketing. 2020;10(4):11&#x2013;16. doi: 10.32479/irmm.9715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32479/irmm.9715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson C., Galinsky A. D. Power, optimism, and risk-taking. European Journal of Social Psychology. 2006;36(4):511&#x2013;536. doi: 10.1002/ejsp.324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejsp.324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson C., John O. P., Keltner D. The personal sense of power. Journal of Personality. 2012;80(2):313&#x2013;344. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-6494.2011.00734.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-6494.2011.00734.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21446947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social cognitive theory: An agentic perspective. Asian Journal of Social Psychology. 1999;2(1):21&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1111/1467-839X.00024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1467-839X.00024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11148297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borde P. S., Arora R., Kakoty S. Linkages of organizational commitment and leadership styles: A systematic review. European Journal of Training and Development. 2024;48(1/2):41&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1108/EJTD-09-2021-0151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/EJTD-09-2021-0151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boussioux L., Lane J. N., Zhang M., Jacimovic V., Lakhani K. R. The crowdless future? Generative AI and creative problem-solving. Organization Science. 2024;35(5):1589&#x2013;1607. doi: 10.1287/orsc.2023.18430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1287/orsc.2023.18430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brislin R. W. Handbook of cross-cultural psychology: Methodology. Allyn and Bacon; 1980. Translation and content analysis of oral and written materials; pp. 389&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brougham D., Haar J. Smart technology, artificial intelligence, robotics, and algorithms (STARA): Employees&#x2019; perceptions of our future workplace. Journal of Management &amp; Organization. 2018;24(2):239&#x2013;257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brynjolfsson E., McAfee A. Will humans go the way of horses. Foreign Affairs. 2015;94:8&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brynjolfsson E., Mitchell T. What can machine learning do? Workforce implications. Science. 2017;358(6370):1530&#x2013;1534. doi: 10.1126/science.aap8062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aap8062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29269459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bugental D. B., Lewis J. C. The paradoxical misuse of power by those who see themselves as powerless: How does it happen? Journal of Social Issues. 1999;55:51&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1111/0022-4537.00104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/0022-4537.00104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamberlin M., Newton D. W., Lepine J. A. A meta-analysis of voice and its promotive and prohibitive forms: Identification of key associations, distinctions, and future research directions. Personnel Psychology. 2017;70(1):11&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1111/peps.12185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/peps.12185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu C. Y. C., Balkundi P., Weinberg F. J. When managers become leaders: The role of manager network centralities, social power, and followers&#x2019; perception of leadership. The Leadership Quarterly. 2017;28(2):334&#x2013;348. doi: 10.1016/j.leaqua.2016.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.leaqua.2016.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chughtai A. A., Buckley F. Work engagement: Antecedents, the mediating role of learning goal orientation and job performance. Career Development International. 2011;16(7):684&#x2013;705. doi: 10.1108/13620431111187290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/13620431111187290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport T. H., Kirby J. Just how smart are smart machines? MIT Sloan Management Review. 2016;57:21&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Detert J. R., Burris E. R. Leadership behavior and employee voice: Is the door really open? Academy of Management Journal. 2007;50(4):869&#x2013;884. doi: 10.5465/amj.2007.26279183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amj.2007.26279183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Einhorn C. S. When working with ai, act like a decision-maker&#x2014;Not a tool-user. Harvard Business Review. Dec 1, 2025.  [(accessed on 1 December 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.hbrtaiwan.com/article/24572/when-working-with-ai-act-like-a-decision-maker-not-a-tool-user.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldor L., Vigoda-Gadot E. The nature of employee engagement: Rethinking the employee&#x2013;organization relationship. The International Journal of Human Resource Management. 2017;28(3):526&#x2013;552. doi: 10.1080/09585192.2016.1180312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09585192.2016.1180312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellinger A. D., Ellinger A. E., Keller S. B. Supervisory coaching behavior, employee satisfaction, and warehouse employee performance: A dyadic perspective in the distribution industry. Human Resource Development Quarterly. 2003;14(4):435&#x2013;458. doi: 10.1002/hrdq.1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hrdq.1078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elloy D. F. The influence of superleader behaviors on organization commitment, job satisfaction and organization self-esteem in a self-managed work team. Leadership &amp; Organization Development Journal. 2005;26(2):120&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ely K., Boyce L. A., Nelson J. K., Zaccaro S. J., Hernez-Broome G., Whyman W. Evaluating leadership coaching: A review and integrated framework. The Leadership Quarterly. 2010;21(4):585&#x2013;599. doi: 10.1016/j.leaqua.2010.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.leaqua.2010.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerson R. M. Power&#x2013;dependence relations. American Sociological Review. 1962;27:31&#x2013;41. doi: 10.2307/2089716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2089716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farh J. L., Hackett R. D., Liang J. Individual-level cultural values as moderators of perceived organizational support&#x2013;employee outcome relationships in China: Comparing the effects of power distance and traditionality. Academy of Management Journal. 2007;50(3):715&#x2013;729. doi: 10.5465/amj.2007.25530866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amj.2007.25530866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmer S. M., Aguinis H. Accounting for subordinate perceptions of supervisor power: An identity-dependence model. Journal of Applied Psychology. 2005;90(6):1069&#x2013;1083. doi: 10.1037/0021-9010.90.6.1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.90.6.1069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16316266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F., Erdfelder E., Buchner A., Lang A. G. Statistical power analyses using G* Power 3.1: Tests for correlation and regression analyses. Behavior Research Methods. 2009;41(4):1149&#x2013;1160. doi: 10.3758/BRM.41.4.1149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BRM.41.4.1149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19897823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glikson E., Woolley A. W. Human trust in artificial intelligence: Review of empirical research. Academy of Management Annals. 2020;14(2):627&#x2013;660. doi: 10.5465/annals.2018.0057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/annals.2018.0057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyory J. T., Soria Zurita N. F., Martin J., Balon C., McComb C., Kotovsky K., Cagan J. Human versus artificial intelligence: A data-driven approach to real-time process management during complex engineering design. Journal of Mechanical Design. 2022;144(2):021405. doi: 10.1115/1.4052488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4052488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai S., Long T., Honora A., Japutra A., Guo T. The dark side of employee-generative AI collaboration in the workplace: An investigation on work alienation and employee expediency. International Journal of Information Management. 2025;83:102905. doi: 10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2025.102905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2025.102905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes A. F. Partial, conditional, and moderated moderated mediation: Quantification, inference, and interpretation. Communication Monographs. 2018;85(1):4&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1080/03637751.2017.1352100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03637751.2017.1352100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henley J. Albania puts AI-created &#x2018;minister&#x2019; in charge of public procurement. The Guardian. Sep 11, 2025.  [(accessed on 11 October 2025)].  Available online:  https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/11/albania-diella-ai-minister-public-procurement.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofstede G. Culture&#x2019;s consequences: Comparing values, behaviors, institutions, and organizations across nations. 2nd ed. Sage Publications; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain S., Fernando M., Akter S. The influence of artificial intelligence-driven capabilities on responsible leadership: A future research agenda. Journal of Management &amp; Organization. 2025;31(5):2360&#x2013;2384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;ddinghaus M., Sondern D., Hertel G. The automation of leadership functions: Would people trust decision algorithms? Computers in Human Behavior. 2021;116:106635. doi: 10.1016/j.chb.2020.106635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2020.106635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu L. T., Bentler P. M. Cutoff criteria for fit indexes in covariance structure analysis: Conventional criteria versus new alternatives. Structural Equation Modeling: A Multidisciplinary Journal. 1999;6(1):1&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1080/10705519909540118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10705519909540118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui C., Lee C., Rousseau D. M. Psychological contract and organizational citizenship behavior in China: Investigating generalizability and instrumentality. Journal of Applied Psychology. 2004;89:311&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1037/0021-9010.89.2.311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.89.2.311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15065977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter S. T., Cushenbery L. D., Jayne B. Why dual leaders will drive innovation: Resolving the exploration and exploitation dilemma with a conservation of resources solution. Journal of Organizational Behavior. 2017;38(8):1183&#x2013;1195. doi: 10.1002/job.2195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/job.2195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarrahi M. H. Artificial intelligence and the future of work: Human-AI symbiosis in organizational decision making. Business Horizons. 2018;61(4):577&#x2013;586. doi: 10.1016/j.bushor.2018.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bushor.2018.03.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia N., Luo X., Fang Z., Liao C. When and how artificial intelligence augments employee creativity. Academy of Management Journal. 2024;67(1):5&#x2013;32. doi: 10.5465/amj.2022.0426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amj.2022.0426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju D., Huang M., Liu D., Qin X., Hu Q., Chen C. Supervisory consequences of abusive supervision: An investigation of sense of power, managerial self-efficacy, and task-oriented leadership behavior. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes. 2019;154:80&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1016/j.obhdp.2019.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.obhdp.2019.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellogg K. C., Valentine M. A., Christin A. Algorithms at work: The new contested terrain of control. The Academy of Management Annals. 2020;14(1):366&#x2013;410. doi: 10.5465/annals.2018.0174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/annals.2018.0174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keltner D., Gruenfeld D. H., Anderson C. Power, approach, and inhibition. Psychological Review. 2003;110:265&#x2013;284. doi: 10.1037/0033-295X.110.2.265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-295X.110.2.265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12747524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr S., Jermier J. M. Substitutes for leadership: Their meaning and measurement. Organizational Behavior and Human Performance. 1978;22(3):375&#x2013;403. doi: 10.1016/0030-5073(78)90023-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0030-5073(78)90023-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolbj&#xf8;rnsrud V., Amico R., Thomas R. J. Partnering with AI: How organizations can win over skeptical managers. Strategy and Leadership. 2017;45:37&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1108/SL-12-2016-0085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/SL-12-2016-0085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krackhardt D. Assessing the political landscape: Structure, cognition, and power in organizations. Administrative Science Quarterly. 1993;35:342&#x2013;369. doi: 10.2307/2393394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2393394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladyshewsky R. K., Taplin R. Employee perceptions of managerial coaching and work engagement using the measurement model of coaching skills and the utrecht work engagement scale. International Journal of Evidence Based Coaching and Mentoring. 2017;15(2):25&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebel R. D. Overcoming the fear factor: How perceptions of supervisor openness lead employees to speak up when fearing external threat. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes. 2016;135:10&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.obhdp.2016.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.obhdp.2016.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M. K. Understanding perception of algorithmic decisions: Fairness, trust, and emotion in response to algorithmic management. Big Data &amp; Society. 2018;5:1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1177/2053951718756684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2053951718756684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang J., Farh C. I., Farh J. L. Psychological antecedents of promotive and prohibitive voice: A two-wave examination. Academy of Management Journal. 2012;55(1):71&#x2013;92. doi: 10.5465/amj.2010.0176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amj.2010.0176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y., Huang Z., Su L. Too time-crunched to seek variety: The influence of parenting motivation on consumer variety seeking. Journal of Marketing Research. 2023;60(4):812&#x2013;833. doi: 10.1177/00222437221136491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00222437221136491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin X., Chen Z. X., Tse H. H., Wei W., Ma C. Why and when employees like to speak up more under humble leaders? The roles of personal sense of power and power distance. Journal of Business Ethics. 2019;158(4):937&#x2013;950. doi: 10.1007/s10551-017-3704-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10551-017-3704-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>London M., Sherman G. D. Becoming a leader: Emergence of leadership style and identity. Human Resource Development Review. 2021;20(3):322&#x2013;344. doi: 10.1177/15344843211009632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15344843211009632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo S., Wang J., Xie Z., Tong D. Y. K. When and why are employees willing to engage in voice behavior: A power cognition perspective. Current Psychology. 2024;43(5):4211&#x2013;4222. doi: 10.1007/s12144-023-04638-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-023-04638-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10111083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37359604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik A., Budhwar P., Patel C., Srikanth N. R. Artificial intelligence and international HRM. Routledge; 2023. May the bots be with you! Delivering HR cost-effectiveness and individualised employee experiences in an MNE; pp. 83&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maner J. K., Mead N. L. The essential tension between leadership and power: When leaders sacrifice group goals for the sake of self-interest. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology. 2010;99(3):482&#x2013;497. doi: 10.1037/a0018559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0018559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20649369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manley A., Williams S. We&#x2019;re not run on numbers, we&#x2019;re people, we&#x2019;re emotional people&#x2019;: Exploring the experiences and lived consequences of emerging technologies, organizational surveillance and control among elite professionals. Organization. 2019;29(4):692&#x2013;713. doi: 10.1177/1350508419890078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1350508419890078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann J. The humanoid-robot CEO of a drinks company says it doesn&#x2019;t have weekends and is &#x2018;always on 24/7&#x2019;. Business Insider. Sep 17, 2023.  [(accessed on 20 November 2024)].  Available online:  https://www.businessinsider.com/humanoid-ai-robot-ceo-says-she-doesnt-have-weekends-2023-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;kel&#xe4; L., Kangas H., Korkiakangas E., Laitinen J. Coaching leadership as a link between individual-and team-level strength use at work. Cogent Business &amp; Management. 2024;11(1):2293469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meade A. W., Craig S. B. Identifying careless responses in survey data. Psychological Methods. 2012;17(3):437&#x2013;455. doi: 10.1037/a0028085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0028085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22506584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molm L. D. Coercive power in social exchange. Cambridge University Press; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molm L. D., Takahashi N., Peterson G. Risk and trust in social exchange: An experimental test of a classical proposition. American Journal of Sociology. 2000;105(5):1396&#x2013;1427. doi: 10.1086/210434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/210434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monod E., Lissillour R., K&#xf6;ster A., Jiayin Q. Does AI control or support? Power shifts after AI system implementation in customer relationship management. Journal of Decision Systems. 2023;32(3):542&#x2013;565. doi: 10.1080/12460125.2022.2066051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/12460125.2022.2066051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison E. W. Employee voice behavior: Integration and directions for future research. Academy of Management Annals. 2011;5(1):373&#x2013;412. doi: 10.5465/19416520.2011.574506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/19416520.2011.574506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison E. W. Employee voice and silence: Taking stock a decade later. Annual Review of Organizational Psychology and Organizational Behavior. 2023;10:79&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1146/annurev-orgpsych-120920-054654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-orgpsych-120920-054654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison E. W., Milliken F. J. Organizational silence: A barrier to change and development in a pluralistic world. Academy of Management Review. 2000;25:706&#x2013;725. doi: 10.2307/259200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/259200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison E. W., Rothman N. B. Silence and the dynamics of power. Voice and Silence in Organizations. 2009;6(5):111&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muth&#xe9;n B., Muth&#xe9;n B. O. Statistical analysis with latent variables. No. 6 Vol. 123. Wiley; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller V. C., Bostrom N. Future progress in artificial intelligence: A survey of expert opinion. Fundamental Issues of Artificial Intelligence. 2016;376:555&#x2013;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman D. T., Fast N. J., Harmon D. J. When eliminating bias isn&#x2019;t fair: Algorithmic reductionism and procedural justice in human resource decisions. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes. 2020;160:149&#x2013;167. doi: 10.1016/j.obhdp.2020.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.obhdp.2020.03.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng T. W. H., Feldman D. C. Employee voice behavior: A meta-analytic test of the conservation of resources framework. Journal of Organizational Behavior. 2012;33(2):216&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1002/job.754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/job.754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omoteso K. The application of artificial intelligence in auditing: Looking back to the future. Expert Systems with Applications. 2012;39(9):8490&#x2013;8495. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2012.01.098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2012.01.098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker S. K., Grote G. Automation, algorithms, and beyond: Why work design matters more than ever in a digital world. Applied Psychology. 2022;71(4):1171&#x2013;1204. doi: 10.1111/apps.12241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apps.12241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peer E., Brandimarte L., Samat S., Acquisti A. Beyond the Turk: Alternative platforms for crowdsourcing behavioral research. Journal of Experimental Social Psychology. 2017;70:153&#x2013;163. doi: 10.1016/j.jesp.2017.01.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesp.2017.01.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson C., Schumacker R. E. Interaction effects: Centering, variance inflation factor, and interpretation issues. Multiple Linear Regression Viewpoints. 2009;35(1):6&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousseau D. M., Fried Y. Location, location, location: Contextualizing organizational research. Journal of Organizational Behavior. 2001;22(1):1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1002/job.78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/job.78</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schildt H. Big data and organizational design&#x2014;The brave new world of algorithmic management and computer augmented transparency. Innovation. 2017;19:23&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1080/14479338.2016.1252043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14479338.2016.1252043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J., Johnson R. E., Liu Y., Wang M. Linking subordinate political skill to supervisor dependence and reward recommendations: A moderated mediation model. Journal of Applied Psychology. 2013;98(2):374&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1037/a0031129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0031129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23276117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu Q., Tu Q., Wang K. The impact of computer self-efficacy and technology dependence on computer-related technostress: A social cognitive theory perspective. International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction. 2011;27(10):923&#x2013;939. doi: 10.1080/10447318.2011.555313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10447318.2011.555313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SimanTov-Nachlieli I., Bamberger P. Pay communication, justice, and affect: The asymmetric effects of process and outcome pay transparency on counterproductive workplace behavior. Journal of Applied Psychology. 2021;106(2):230&#x2013;249. doi: 10.1037/apl0000502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/apl0000502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32271031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spekman R. E. Influence and information: An exploratory investigation of the boundary role person&#x2019;s basis of power. Academy of Management Journal. 1979;22(1):104&#x2013;117. doi: 10.2307/255482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/255482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreitzer G. M. Psychological empowerment in the workplace: Dimensions, measurement, and validation. Academy of Management Journal. 1995;38(5):1442&#x2013;1465. doi: 10.2307/256865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/256865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturm R. E., Antonakis J. Interpersonal power: A review, critique, and research agenda. Journal of Management. 2015;41(1):136&#x2013;163. doi: 10.1177/0149206314555769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0149206314555769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiyi Yan T., Tangirala S., Vadera A. K., Ekkirala S. How employees learn to speak up from their leaders: Gender congruity effects in the development of voice self-efficacy. Journal of Applied Psychology. 2022;107(4):650&#x2013;667. doi: 10.1037/apl0000892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/apl0000892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang P. M., Koopman J., McClean S. T., Zhang J. H., Li C. H., De Cremer D., Lu Y., Ng C. T. S. When conscientious employees meet intelligent machines: An integrative approach inspired by complementarity theory and role theory. Academy of Management Journal. 2022;65(3):1019&#x2013;1054. doi: 10.5465/amj.2020.1516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amj.2020.1516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang P. M., Koopman J., Yam K. C., De Cremer D., Zhang J. H., Reynders P. The self-regulatory consequences of dependence on intelligent machines at work: Evidence from field and experimental studies. Human Resource Management. 2023;62(5):721&#x2013;744. doi: 10.1002/hrm.22154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hrm.22154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topol E. J. High-performance medicine: The convergence of human and artificial intelligence. Nature Medicine. 2019;25(1):44&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1038/s41591-018-0300-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-018-0300-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tost L. P., Gino F., Larrick R. P. Power, competitiveness, and advice taking: Why the powerful don&#x2019;t listen. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes. 2012;117(1):53&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1016/j.obhdp.2011.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.obhdp.2011.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai C. Y., Marshall J. D., Choudhury A., Serban A., Hou Y. T.-Y., Jung M. F., Dionne S. D., Yammarino F. J. Human-robot collaboration: A multilevel and integrated leadership framework. The Leadership Quarterly. 2022;33(1):101&#x2013;594. doi: 10.1016/j.leaqua.2021.101594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.leaqua.2021.101594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dyne L., LePine J. A. Helping and voice extra-role behaviors: Evidence of construct and predictive validity. Academy of Management Journal. 1998;41(1):108&#x2013;119. doi: 10.2307/256902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/256902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hootegem A., Niesen W., De Witte H. Does job insecurity hinder innovative work behaviour? A threat rigidity perspective. Creativity and Innovation Management. 2019;28(1):19&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1111/caim.12271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/caim.12271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh T. Expert and non-expert opinion about technological unemployment. International Journal of Automation and Computing. 2018;15(5):637&#x2013;642. doi: 10.1007/s11633-018-1127-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11633-018-1127-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward A. K., Ravlin E. C., Klaas B. S., Ployhart R. E., Buchan N. R. When do high-context communicators speak up? Exploring contextual communication orientation and employee voice. Journal of Applied Psychology. 2016;101(10):1498. doi: 10.1037/apl0000144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/apl0000144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27504663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wee E. X., Liao H., Liu D., Liu J. Moving from abuse to reconciliation: A power-dependence perspective on when and how a follower can break the spiral of abuse. Academy of Management Journal. 2017;60(6):2352&#x2013;2380. doi: 10.5465/amj.2015.0866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amj.2015.0866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesche J. S., Sonderegger A. When computers take the lead: The automation of leadership. Computers in Human Behavior. 2019;101:197&#x2013;209. doi: 10.1016/j.chb.2019.07.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2019.07.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson H. J., Daugherty P. R. Collaborative intelligence: Humans and AI are joining forces. Harvard Business Review. 2018;96:114&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M., Yu Z., Tu Y. I will get a reward, too: When disclosing the referrer reward increases referring. Journal of Marketing Research. 2023;60(2):355&#x2013;370. doi: 10.1177/00222437221117113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00222437221117113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan C., Wang Y., Huang W., Zhu Y. Can coaching leadership encourage subordinates to speak up? Dual perspective of cognition-affection. Leadership &amp; Organization Development Journal. 2019;40(4):485&#x2013;498. doi: 10.1108/lodj-01-2018-0009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/lodj-01-2018-0009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagenczyk T. J., Restubog S. L. D., Kiewitz C., Kiazad K., Tang R. L. Psychological contracts as a mediator between Machiavellianism and employee citizenship and deviant behaviors. Journal of Management. 2014;40(4):1098&#x2013;1122. doi: 10.1177/0149206311415420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0149206311415420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>