<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41853456</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnostic Utility of Mast Cell Density and Neutrophilic Infiltration for Differentiating Aseptic Loosening From Periprosthetic Joint Infection: A Retrospective Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103612</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103612</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103612</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103612</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Accurate differentiation between periprosthetic joint infection (PJI) and aseptic loosening (AL) is essential for appropriate surgical planning and optimal postoperative outcomes. Although neutrophil infiltration remains the standard histological marker for diagnosing PJI, it has recognized limitations. Mast cells, which play a role in chronic inflammatory responses, may serve as a complementary biomarker. This study evaluated the combined diagnostic utility of Giemsa-stained mast cell density and neutrophil counts in periprosthetic tissue to distinguish PJI from AL. Methods This single-center retrospective cohort study included patients who underwent revision arthroplasty between January 2022 and September 2025. PJI was defined according to the 2018 International Consensus Meeting criteria, whereas AL was diagnosed based on negative microbiological cultures and radiographic evidence of loosening. Periprosthetic tissue samples were stained with H&amp;E for neutrophil assessment and Giemsa stain for mast cell identification. Two blinded observers quantified cells across 10 high-power fields (HPFs; 0.237 mm&#xb2; per field). Results A total of 146 revision cases were analyzed, including 48 PJI and 98 AL cases. Median neutrophil counts were significantly higher in the PJI group than in the AL group (26.5 vs. 1.0 cells/HPF; p &lt; 0.001). Conversely, median mast cell density was significantly higher in AL (11.0 vs. 3.5 cells/HPF; p &lt; 0.001). A neutrophil threshold of &#x2265;5 cells/HPF demonstrated 93.8% sensitivity and 91.8% specificity for diagnosing PJI (area under the curve (AUC) = 0.97). A mast cell cutoff of &#x2265;7 cells/HPF showed 86.7% sensitivity and 85.4% specificity for diagnosing AL (AUC = 0.91). The combined sequential algorithm achieved an overall diagnostic accuracy of 93.2%. Conclusions Giemsa-stained mast cell density is a novel, cost-effective histological marker elevated in AL. When combined with neutrophil counts, it improves diagnostic accuracy and may serve as a practical adjunct in the routine pathological evaluation of revision arthroplasty specimens.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Pathan et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pathan</LastName><ForeName>Rameez Ahmedkhan R</ForeName><Initials>RAR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Shri Balaji Institute of Medical Science, Raipur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Hindu Rao Hospital and North Delhi Municipal Corporation (NDMC) Medical College, Delhi, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, SPARSH Hospital, Bengaluru, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Mangaluru, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wankhade</LastName><ForeName>Akanksha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology, Shri Balaji Institute of Medical Science, Raipur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panda</LastName><ForeName>Sujata R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology, Shri Balaji Institute of Medical Science, Raipur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrawal</LastName><ForeName>Sandesh Subhash</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spine Surgery, Shree Narayana Hospital, Raipur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Sri Devaraj Urs Academy of Higher Education and Research, Kolar, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Shri Balaji Institute of Medical Science, Raipur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spine Surgery, Stavya Spine Hospital and Research Institute, Ahmedabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Shahzad</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, Shri Balaji Institute of Medical Science, Raipur, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aseptic loosening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">giemsa stain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">histology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mast cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neutrophils</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">periprosthetic tissue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prosthetic joint infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Institutional Ethics Committee, Shri Balaji Institute of Medical Science issued approval SBIMS/IEC/Certi./150/2025. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41853456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12991901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Prosthetic joint infection. Tande AJ, Patel R. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2014;27:302&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3993098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24696437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosthetic joint-associated infections treated with DAIR (debridement, antibiotics, irrigation, and retention) Kuiper JW, Vos SJ, Saouti R, et al. Acta Orthop. 2013;84:380&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3768038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23848215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of biomarkers in the diagnosis of periprosthetic joint infection. Shahi A, Parvizi J. EFORT Open Rev. 2016;1:275&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5367543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28461959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Routine diagnostic tests for periprosthetic joint infection demonstrate a high false-negative rate and are influenced by the infecting organism. Kheir MM, Tan TL, Shohat N, Foltz C, Parvizi J. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2018;100:2057&#x2013;2065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30516629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis of periprosthetic joint infection following hip and knee arthroplasty. Parvizi J, Fassihi SC, Enayatollahi MA. Orthop Clin North Am. 2016;47:505&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27241375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Periprosthetic osteolysis: mechanisms, prevention and treatment. Goodman SB, Gallo J. J Clin Med. 2019;8:2091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6947309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31805704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recent advances in our understanding of mast cell activation - or should it be mast cell mediator disorders? Theoharides TC, Tsilioni I, Ren H. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2019;15:639&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30884251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staphylococcus aureus evasion of host immunity in the setting of prosthetic joint infection: biofilm and beyond. Ricciardi BF, Muthukrishnan G, Masters E, Ninomiya M, Lee CC, Schwarz EM. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2018;11:389&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29987645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The 2018 definition of periprosthetic hip and knee infection: an evidence-based and validated criteria. Parvizi J, Tan TL, Goswami K, Higuera C, Della Valle C, Chen AF, Shohat N. J Arthroplasty. 2018;33:1309&#x2013;1314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29551303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic pain after total knee arthroplasty. Wylde V, Beswick A, Bruce J, Blom A, Howells N, Gooberman-Hill R. EFORT Open Rev. 2018;3:461&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6134884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30237904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of mast cells in bone metabolism and bone disorders. Ragipoglu D, Dudeck A, Haffner-Luntzer M, Voss M, Kroner J, Ignatius A, Fischer V. Front Immunol. 2020;11:163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7025484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32117297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mast cells - a role in periodontal diseases? Steinsvoll S, Helgeland K, Schenck K. J Clin Periodontol. 2004;31:413&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeletal infections: microbial pathogenesis, immunity and clinical management. Masters EA, Ricciardi BF, Bentley KL, Moriarty TF, Schwarz EM, Muthukrishnan G. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2022;20:385&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8852989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35169289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Profiling the immune response to periprosthetic joint infection and non-infectious arthroplasty failure. Fisher CR, Patel R. Antibiotics (Basel) 2023;12:296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9951934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36830206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The local inflammatory environment and microorganisms in "aseptic" loosening of hip prostheses. Hoenders CS, Harmsen MC, van Luyn MJ. J Biomed Mater Res B Appl Biomater. 2008;86:291&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18098200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usefulness of histological analysis for predicting the presence of microorganisms at the time of reimplantation after hip resection arthroplasty for the treatment of infection. Bori G, Soriano A, Garc&#xed;a S, Mallofr&#xe9; C, Riba J, Mensa J. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2007;89:1232&#x2013;1237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17545426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnosis and management of prosthetic joint infection. Peel TN, Buising KL, Choong PF. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2012;25:670&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22964949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alpha defensin lateral flow test for diagnosis of periprosthetic joint infection: not a screening but a confirmatory test. Renz N, Yermak K, Perka C, Trampuz A. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2018;100:742&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29715222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An enhanced understanding of culture-negative periprosthetic joint infection with next-generation sequencing: a multicenter study. Goswami K, Clarkson S, Phillips CD, et al. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2022;104:1523&#x2013;1529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35726882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The alpha-defensin immunoassay and leukocyte esterase colorimetric strip test for the diagnosis of periprosthetic infection: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Wyatt MC, Beswick AD, Kunutsor SK, Wilson MJ, Whitehouse MR, Blom AW. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2016;98:992&#x2013;1000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4901182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27307359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>