<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41607837</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ENGAGE: Analyzing the value of virtual reality in a patient-centric immersive learning program in myasthenia gravis for healthcare professionals.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1655351</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1655351</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1655351</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2025.1655351</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Myasthenia gravis (MG) is a chronic autoimmune neuromuscular disease characterized by muscle weakness that can significantly impact patients' lives. Recent patient-led research highlighted a disconnect between healthcare professionals (HCPs) and patients, emphasizing the need for effective and empathetic patient-HCP dialogue and shared decision-making (SDM). The power of virtual reality (VR) to increase empathy and provide impactful learning experiences has been established. This outcome evaluation assessed the ability of VR to improve HCPs' knowledge, attitudes and empathy in MG, aiming to strengthen patient-HCP communication and facilitate SDM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The ENGAGE educational pilot program comprised a needs assessment, a VR-based intervention and an outcome evaluation. Content for the VR intervention was developed using a patient-centric approach integrating patient and HCP voices. The VR module simulated "a day in the life of Julia," a virtual patient with MG, allowing HCPs to experience MG symptoms and their impact on a patient's life. The experience was implemented in hospital-based workshops. The outcome evaluation included surveys assessing Moore's Levels 2-4, the Theoretical Domains Framework (TDF), and SDM, and was supplemented by semi-structured interviews. Quantitative and qualitative data were analyzed using SPSS Statistics and thematic analysis, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Eighty-seven HCPs completed the VR experience across 12 workshops. Sixty HCPs participated in the outcome evaluation survey, and 10 participated in interviews. HCPs reported high satisfaction with the immersive learning, citing its relevance and ease of use. Based on survey responses, HCPs' most important learnings were a "better understanding of the impact of MG on patients' lives" (<i>n/N</i>&#x202f;=&#x202f;46/60) and "developing empathy for how a patient with MG might feel" (<i>n/N</i>&#x202f;=&#x202f;37/60). HCPs expressed commitment to changing their practice. Quantitative analysis revealed significant improvements in most TDF domains and SDM post-intervention, with the TDF domain "beliefs about capabilities" emerging as the strongest predictor of SDM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our study found that the immersive VR intervention effectively increased HCP empathy, knowledge and attitudes in MG care. The program's patient-centric design ensured content relevance. These findings suggest that VR-based learning is a valuable tool for medical education and the improvement of SDM, particularly in rare diseases like MG.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Weisshardt, Reyes Acosta, Chauhan, Haralampiev, Mu&#x161;ura Gabor, Rodriguez, Foss, Pinto, Hewamadduma, Vissing, Silvestri, Lehnerer, De Backer, Monin, Barry and Vlaev.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weisshardt</LastName><ForeName>Ina</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LLH Concepts GbR, Haimhausen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reyes Acosta</LastName><ForeName>Cornelia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LLH Concepts GbR, Haimhausen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chauhan</LastName><ForeName>Trishna</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The University of Liverpool, Liverpool, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haralampiev</LastName><ForeName>Kaloyan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sofia University, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu&#x161;ura Gabor</LastName><ForeName>Andrijana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Behavioral and Experimental Economics Lab, Zagreb School of Economics and Management, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodriguez</LastName><ForeName>Alexis</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MG Georgia, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foss</LastName><ForeName>Allison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Myasthenia Gravis Association (MGA), Kansas City, MO, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pinto</LastName><ForeName>Ashwin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Neuroscience, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hewamadduma</LastName><ForeName>Channa</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Neuromuscular Unit, Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vissing</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Rigshospitalet, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silvestri</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jacobs School of Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, University at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lehnerer</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Experimental Neurology, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Backer</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCB, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monin</LastName><ForeName>Natasha</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCB, Malvern, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barry</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCB, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vlaev</LastName><ForeName>Ivo</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Behavioral and Implementation Science Interventions (BISI), Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myasthenia gravis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immersive learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient&#x2013;healthcare professional communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shared decision-making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virtual reality</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Ina Weisshardt has received consulting fees from Heel, ILAE, ISHH, Janssen and UCB. Cornelia Reyes Acosta was a Consultant for LLH Concepts GbR. Since manuscript development, she further holds a position in the Digital Health &amp; Applied Tech Assessment research division at the Florence Nightingale Faculty of Nursing, Midwifery and Palliative Care, King's College London, London, UK. Trishna Chauhan was employed at the University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK. Since manuscript development, she holds a position at the University of Lancashire, Lancashire, UK. Andrijana Mu&#x161;ura Gabor was a Consultant for LLH Concepts GbR. Allison Foss is part of the argenx Leadership Council. Ashwin Pinto has received funding for consultancy on scientific or educational advisory boards for argenx, Terumo BCT and UCB. Channa Hewamadduma is Principal Investigator/NCI in clinical trials in various neuromuscular disorders sponsored by Alexion Pharmaceuticals, argenx, Avidity, Cartesian, Dyne, Janssen Pharmaceuticals (now Johnson &amp; Johnson), Novartis, PepGen, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals and UCB. He has received funding for consultancy on scientific or educational advisory boards for argenx, Biogen, Lupin, Roche and UCB, and has received an investigator-led research grant from UCB. His study activities were supported by a Sheffield NIHR BRC UK centre grant. He is a trustee of the myasthenia gravis patient organisation Myaware. John Vissing has been a Consultant on advisory boards for Amicus Therapeutics, Biogen, Edgewise Therapeutics, Fulcrum Therapeutics, Genethon, Horizon Therapeutics (now Amgen), Lupin, ML Biopharma, Novartis, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Roche, Sanofi Genzyme (now Sanofi), Sarepta Therapeutics and UCB. He has received research and travel support and/or speaker honoraria from Alexion Pharmaceuticals, argenx, Biogen, Edgewise Therapeutics, Fulcrum Therapeutics, Lupin, Sanofi Genzyme (now Sanofi) and UCB. He is a Principal Investigator in clinical trials for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, argenx, Atamyo Therapeutics, Genethon, Horizon Therapeutics (now Amgen), Janssen Pharmaceuticals (now Johnson &amp; Johnson Innovative Medicine), ML Biopharma, Novartis, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Roche, Sanofi Genzyme (now Sanofi) and UCB. Nicholas J. Silvestri is a Consultant/Adviser for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Amgen, Annexon Biosciences, argenx, Immunovant, Janssen Pharmaceuticals (now Johnson &amp; Johnson Innovative Medicine) and UCB; he is a Speaker for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, argenx, Takeda Pharmaceuticals and UCB. Sophie Lehnerer has received speaker or consultancy honoraria or financial research support (paid to her institution) from Alexion, argenx, Biogen, Hormosan, HUMA, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Merck, Roche and UCB. Marc De Backer, Natasha Monin and Sophie Barry are employees and shareholders of UCB. Ivo Vlaev has received consulting fees, research or institutional support and educational grants from AtomicPR, Barclays Bank, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ernst &amp; Young, Kindred Agency, MC&amp;T, McDonald&#x2019;s, Ogilvy, Pfizer, Prime Global Medical Communications, Swiss Re Ltd. and UCB. He has received speaker fees from Teva UK Limited. During the initial study period, he was employed by Warwick Business School, University of Warwick, Coventry, UK. Since manuscript development, he holds a position at Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, Singapore. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41607837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12836303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2025.1655351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gilhus NE, Skeie GO, Romi F, Lazaridis K, Zisimopoulou P, Tzartos S. Myasthenia gravis &#x2013; autoantibody characteristics and their implications for therapy. Nat Rev Neurol. (2016) 12:259&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2016.44,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2016.44</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27103470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iorio R. Myasthenia gravis: the changing treatment landscape in the era of molecular therapies. Nat Rev Neurol. (2024) 20:84&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1038/s41582-023-00916-w,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41582-023-00916-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38191918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guptill JT, Sanders DB, Evoli A. Anti-MuSK antibody myasthenia gravis: clinical findings and response to treatment in two large cohorts. Muscle Nerve. (2011) 44:36&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1002/mus.22006,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.22006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21674519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehnerer S, Jacobi J, Schilling R, Grittner U, Marbin D, Gerischer L, et al. Burden of disease in myasthenia gravis: taking the patient's perspective. J Neurol. (2022) 269:3050&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1007/s00415-021-10891-1,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-021-10891-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34800167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law N, Davio K, Blunck M, Lobban D, Seddik K. The lived experience of myasthenia gravis: a patient-led analysis. Neurol Ther. (2021) 10:1103&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1007/s40120-021-00285-w,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-021-00285-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8540870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas A, Kuper A, Chin-Yee B, Park M. What is "shared" in shared decision-making? Philosophical perspectives, epistemic justice, and implications for health professions education. J Eval Clin Pract. (2020) 26:409&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1111/jep.13370,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.13370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32032468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elwyn G, Frosch D, Thomson R, Joseph-Williams N, Lloyd A, Kinnersley P, et al. Shared decision making: a model for clinical practice. J Gen Intern Med. (2012) 27:1361&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1007/s11606-012-2077-6,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-012-2077-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22618581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams EM, Shaker M, Oppenheimer J, Davis RS, Bukstein DA, Greenhawt M. The challenges and opportunities for shared decision making highlighted by COVID-19. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. (2020) 8:2474&#x2013;2480.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.jaip.2020.07.003,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaip.2020.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7358768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32679348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadet LB, Chainay H. Memory of virtual experiences: role of immersion, emotion and sense of presence. Int J Hum Comput Stud. (2020) 144:102506. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhcs.2020.102506</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhcs.2020.102506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halton C, Cartwright T. Walking in a patient's shoes: an evaluation study of immersive learning using a digital training intervention. Front Psychol. (2018) 9:2124. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02124,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6240611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30483174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhiman DB. The power of immersive media: enhancing empathy through virtual reality experiences. Preprintsorg. (2023). doi: 10.22541/essoar.168565392.25062595/v1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22541/essoar.168565392.25062595/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formosa NJ, Morrison BW, Hill G, Stone D. Testing the efficacy of a virtual reality-based simulation in enhancing users&#x2019; knowledge, attitudes, and empathy relating to psychosis. Aust J Psychol. (2018) 70:57&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1111/ajpy.12167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajpy.12167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resnick LB. Mathematics and science learning: a new conception. Science. (1983) 220:477&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1126/science.220.4596.477,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.220.4596.477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17816206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause F. Shared decision making bei seltenen erkrankungen. Ethik Med. (2019) 31:131&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1007/s00481-019-00522-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00481-019-00522-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyes Acosta C, Vlaev I, Rodriguez A, Foss A, Pinto A, Hewamadduma C, et al. What patients don&#x2019;t say and physicians don&#x2019;t ask: a needs assessment in myasthenia gravis integrating patient and healthcare professional perspectives. Neurol Ther. (2025) 14:1419&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1007/s40120-025-00751-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-025-00751-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12255620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40372604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babac A, von Friedrichs V, Litzkendorf S, Zeidler J, Damm K, Graf von der Schulenburg JM. Integrating patient perspectives in medical decision-making: a qualitative interview study examining potentials within the rare disease information exchange process in practice. BMC Medical Inform Decis Mak. (2019) 19:188. doi: 10.1186/s12911-019-0911-z,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-019-0911-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6751820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31533712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins L, Francis J, Islam R, O'Connor D, Patey A, Ivers N, et al. A guide to using the Theoretical Domains Framework of behaviour change to investigate implementation problems. Implement Sci. (2017) 12:77. doi: 10.1186/s13012-017-0605-9,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-017-0605-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5480145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28637486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DE, Jr, Green JS, Gallis HA. Achieving desired results and improved outcomes: integrating planning and assessment throughout learning activities. J Contin Educ Heal Prof. (2009) 29:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19288562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DE, Jr, Chappell K, Sherman L, Vinayaga-Pavan M. A conceptual framework for planning and assessing learning in continuing education activities designed for clinicians in one profession and/or clinical teams. Med Teach. (2018) 40:904&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1080/0142159X.2018.1483578</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0142159X.2018.1483578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30058424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leo A, Bayes S, Bloxsome D, Butt J. Exploring the usability of the COM-B model and Theoretical Domains Framework (TDF) to define the helpers of and hindrances to evidence-based practice in midwifery. Implement Sci Commun. (2021) 2:7. doi: 10.1186/s43058-020-00100-x,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43058-020-00100-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7805209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33436092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, van Stralen MM, West R. The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. Implement Sci. (2011) 6:42. doi: 10.1186/1748-5908-6-42,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21513547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Thematic analysis. In: Cooper H, Camic PM, Long DL, Panter AT, Rindskopf D, Sher KJ, editors. APA handbook of research methods in psychology (vol 2): research designs: quantitative, qualitative, neuropsychological, and biological. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association; (2012). 57&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekker M, van der Ent K, Geelen S. Learning through lived experience: an educational tool to improve health professionals' insight into the perspectives of patients [version 1]. MedEdPublish. (2021) 10:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peck TC, Seinfeld S, Aglioti SM, Slater M. Putting yourself in the skin of a black avatar reduces implicit racial bias. Conscious Cogn. (2013) 22:779&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1016/j.concog.2013.04.016,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.concog.2013.04.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23727712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardman DI, Howick J. The friendly relationship between therapeutic empathy and person-centered care. Eur J Pers Cent Healthc. (2019) 7:351&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebinga VY, Driever EM, Stiggelbout AM, Brand PLP. Shared decision making, patient-centered communication and patient satisfaction &#x2013; a cross-sectional analysis. Patient Educ Couns. (2022) 105:2145&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2022.03.012,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2022.03.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35337712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonelli MR, Sullivan MD. Person-centred shared decision making. J Eval Clin Pract. (2019) 25:1057&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1111/jep.13260,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.13260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31407417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Atkins L, West R. The Behaviour Change Wheel: a guide to designing interventions. London: Silverback Publishing; (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe9;gar&#xe9; F, Adekpedjou R, Stacey D, Turcotte S, Kryworuchko J, Graham ID, et al. Interventions for increasing the use of shared decision making by healthcare professionals. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. (2018) 2018:CD006732. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD006732.pub4,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006732.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6513543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30025154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy mechanism in human agency. Am Psychol. (1982) 37:122&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1037/0003-066X.37.2.122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0003-066X.37.2.122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy: the exercise of control. New York, NY: W. H. Freeman and Company; (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A, Locke EA. Negative self-efficacy and goal effects revisited. J Appl Psychol. (2003) 88:87&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1037/0021-9010.88.1.87,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.88.1.87</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12675397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crosby LE, Real FJ, Cruse B, Davis D, Klein M, McTate E, et al. An immersive virtual reality curriculum for pediatric providers on shared decision making for hydroxyurea. Blood. (2019) 134:3402. doi: 10.1182/blood-2019-128661,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2019-128661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8943226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35319512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisshardt I, Vlaev I, Chauhan T, Hofst&#xe4;dter-Thalmann E. Learnings from the forced transition of an industry supported educational programme for young experts in urology and oncology from face-to-face to digital during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Eur CME. (2022) 11:2085011. doi: 10.1080/21614083.2022.2085011,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21614083.2022.2085011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9196841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35711723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y-K, Wu Y-K, Liu T-H. The effectiveness of a virtual reality teaching module on advance care planning and advance decision for medical professionals. BMC Med Educ. (2024) 24:112. doi: 10.1186/s12909-023-04990-y,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-023-04990-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10845462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38317136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy: toward a unifying theory of behavioral change. Psychol Rev. (1977) 84:191&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1037/0033-295X.84.2.191,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-295X.84.2.191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">847061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>