<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41836997</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2210-2612</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>138</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of surgery case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Surg Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>First successful radiofrequency ablation for papillary thyroid microcarcinoma in Indonesia: a case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>514</StartPage><EndPage>520</EndPage><MedlinePgn>514-520</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RC9.0000000000000159</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Papillary thyroid microcarcinoma (PTMC) is the most common subtype of thyroid cancer, generally associated with a favorable prognosis. Radiofrequency ablation (RFA) is emerging as a minimally invasive alternative to surgery, particularly for patients unsuitable for active surveillance and surgery. This report presents the first documented case of RFA for PTMC in Indonesia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE REPORT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A 40-year-old woman presented with a palpable thyroid nodule on the right side of her neck. Thyroid ultrasound and thyroid core needle biopsy confirmed PTMC. The patient underwent RFA using a 5-mm probe tip and 50-Watt power, employing the "moving shot" technique. The procedure was successful, with no reported complications. Follow-up assessments showed a significant reduction in tumor volume of 95.38%, from 0.264&#xa0;ml to 0.012&#xa0;ml, with no signs of progression at 12&#xa0;months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">RFA provides a minimally invasive alternative to active surveillance with advantages, giving patient definitive treatment. Compare to surgery, this treatment have advantage such as shorter procedure time, lower procedural costs, reduced blood loss, and preservation of thyroid function, leading to faster recovery. However, wider adoption in Indonesia remains limited by the need for trained operators and access to advanced ultrasonography equipment. Strengthening workforce training, improving infrastructure, and generating long-term outcome data are essential for broader implementation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This case highlights RFA as a safe and effective treatment for PTMC, particularly for patients who do not wish to undergo active surveillance management for low risk thyroid cancer. Further studies are necessary to assess its long-term efficacy and feasibility.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yarso</LastName><ForeName>Kristanto Yuli</ForeName><Initials>KY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4514-4676</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Oncology Division, Sebelas Maret University, Moewardi General Hospital, Surakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilyas</LastName><ForeName>Muhana Fawwazy</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0176-9773</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Sebelas Maret University, Surakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adli</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad Rifki</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Sebelas Maret University, Moewardi General Hospital, Surakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wahyudi</LastName><ForeName>Akmal Zhahir</ForeName><Initials>AZ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-9933-8530</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Sebelas Maret University, Surakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Surg Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101529872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2210-2612</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indonesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">active surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">minimally invasive</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">papillary thyroid microcarcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiofrequency ablation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasound-guided ablation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Sponsorships or competing interests that may be relevant to content are disclosed at the end of this article. The authors declare that there are no conflicts of interest regarding the publication of this case report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41836997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12981851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RC9.0000000000000159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJSCASEREPORTS-D-25-01614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pellegriti G, Frasca F, Regalbuto C, et al. Worldwide Increasing Incidence of Thyroid Cancer: Update on Epidemiology and Risk Factors. J Cancer Epidemiol 2013;2013:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3664492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23737785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dideban S, Abdollahi A, Meysamie A, et al. Thyroid Papillary Microcarcinoma: Etiology, Clinical Manifestations,Diagnosis, Follow-up, Histopathology and Prognosis. Iran J Pathol 2016;11:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4749190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26870138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigneri R, Malandrino P, Vigneri P. The changing epidemiology of thyroid cancer. Curr Opin Oncol 2015;27:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25310641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim H, Devesa SS, Sosa JA, et al. Trends in Thyroid Cancer Incidence and Mortality in the United States, 1974-2013. JAMA 2017;317:1338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8216772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28362912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Luo Y, Zhang Y, et al. Efficacy and Safety of Ultrasound-Guided Radiofrequency Ablation for Treating Low-Risk Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma: A Prospective Study. Thyroid 2016;26:1581&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan Y, Luo Y, Zhang M, et al. Quality of Life in Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma Patients Undergoing Radiofrequency Ablation or Surgery: A Comparative Study. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2020;11:249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7242647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32499754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Zhang M, Song Q, et al. Ultrasound-Guided Radiofrequency Ablation Versus Thyroid Lobectomy for Low-Risk Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma: A Propensity-Matched Cohort Study of 884 Patients. Thyroid 2021;31:1662&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34269611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerwan A, Al-Jabir A, Mathew G, et al. Revised Surgical Case Report (SCARE) Guideline: An Update for the Age of Artificial Intelligence. Prem J Sci 2025;10:100079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi Z, Siyu L, Lijun F, et al. Efficacy, safety, and controversy of ultrasound-guided radiofrequency ablation in the treatment of T1N0M0 papillary thyroid carcinoma. Front Oncol 2022;12:1068210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36605434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Zhang M, Song Q, et al. The Efficacy and Safety of Radiofrequency Ablation for Bilateral Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021;12:663636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8227434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34177804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim HK, Cho SJ, Baek JH, et al. US-Guided Radiofrequency Ablation for Low-Risk Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma: Efficacy and Safety in a Large Population. Korean J Radiol 2019;20:1653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6923213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31854153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia C, Solis-Pazmino P, Lincango EP, et al. Radiofrequency ablation for thyroid nodules in Ecuador: a cross-sectional study. Thyroid Res 2024;17:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38167215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringel MD, Sosa JA, Baloch Z, et al. 2025 American Thyroid Association Management Guidelines for Adult Patients with Differentiated Thyroid Cancer. Thyroid&#xae; 2025;35:841&#x2013;985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40844370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filetti S, Durante C, Hartl D, et al. Thyroid cancer: ESMO Clinical Practice Guidelines for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol 2019;30:1856&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31549998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanokwongnuwat W, Larbcharoensub N, Sriphrapradang C, et al. Risk-stratified papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: post-operative management and treatment outcome in a single center. Endocrine 2022;77:134&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9242919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35476179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito Y, and Miyauchi A. Active Surveillance May Be the Best Initial Management for Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma. J Endocr Soc 2023;7:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10243838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37287648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Qurayshi Z, Nilubol N, Tufano RP, et al. Wolf in Sheep&#x2019;s Clothing: Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma in the US. J Am Coll Surg 2020;230:484&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8916219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant CS. Recurrence of papillary thyroid cancer after optimized surgery. Gland Surg 2015;4:52&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4321046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conroy PC, Wilhelm A, Calthorpe L, et al. Endocrine surgeons are performing more thyroid lobectomies for low-risk differentiated thyroid cancer since the 2015 ATA guidelines. Surgery 2022;172:1392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36002375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartl DM, Guerlain J, Breuskin I, et al. Thyroid Lobectomy for Low to Intermediate Risk Differentiated Thyroid Cancer. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12:3282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7694652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33171949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Gui Z, Xu C, et al. Comparison of total thyroidectomy and lobectomy for intermediate-risk papillary thyroid carcinoma with lateral lymph node metastasis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Surg 2025;111:6343&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12430778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40557546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padur AA, Kumar N, Guru A, et al. Safety and Effectiveness of Total Thyroidectomy and Its Comparison with Subtotal Thyroidectomy and Other Thyroid Surgeries: A Systematic Review. J Thyroid Res 2016;2016:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4783568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27006857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Dijk SPJ, Coerts HI, Gunput STG, et al. Assessment of Radiofrequency Ablation for Papillary Microcarcinoma of the Thyroid. JAMA Otolaryngol Neck Surg 2022;148:317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8832309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs D, Breen CT, Pucar D, et al. Changes in Population-Level and Institutional-Level Prescribing Habits of Radioiodine Therapy for Papillary Thyroid Cancer. Thyroid 2021;31:272&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoon KJ, Baek JH, Sung JY, et al. Radiofrequency ablation of low-risk small papillary thyroidcarcinoma: preliminary results for patients ineligible for surgery. Int J Hyperth 2017;33:212&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27590679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho SJ, Baek SM, Lim HK, et al. Long-Term Follow-Up Results of Ultrasound-Guided Radiofrequency Ablation for Low-Risk Papillary Thyroid Microcarcinoma: More Than 5-Year Follow-Up for 84 Tumors. Thyroid 2020;30:1745&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32375570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>