<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41834000</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recycling fossil infrastructure for cleaner energy transitions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-026-70777-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The climate crisis mandates building renewable energy infrastructure faster, increasing the demand for primary materials with large environmental footprints. Sourcing these materials from urban mines can mitigate such impacts, but the potential of recycling depends on waste availability. Here, we use life cycle assessment and monetization of impacts to explore the environmental implications of recycling fossil infrastructure that may become obsolete during the transition. We find that among many materials in fossil infrastructure, recycling steel and copper is particularly appealing, as their stocks (1.34 gigatons and 10.03 megatons) align with the projected energy transition demands (145% and 32% of median demand between 2020-2050, respectively). Recycling steel and copper in fossil infrastructure could save up to 1.95 gigatons CO<sub>2,eq</sub> and 11.69 trillion US Dollars in externality costs until 2050, while remaining competitive considering current production methods. Using recycled steel and copper would also reduce the carbon footprint of energy transition technologies-for example, wind and photovoltaic power-by one third.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlesier</LastName><ForeName>Hauke</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-5692-2818</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Technology and Society Laboratory, Empa-Swiss Federal Laboratories for Materials Science and Technology, St. Gallen, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Chemical and Bioengineering, Department of Chemistry and Applied Biosciences, ETH Z&#xfc;rich, Z&#xfc;rich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guill&#xe9;n-Gos&#xe1;lbez</LastName><ForeName>Gonzalo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6074-8473</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Chemical and Bioengineering, Department of Chemistry and Applied Biosciences, ETH Z&#xfc;rich, Z&#xfc;rich, Switzerland. gonzalo.guillen.gosalbez@chem.ethz.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desing</LastName><ForeName>Harald</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4363-9563</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Technology and Society Laboratory, Empa-Swiss Federal Laboratories for Materials Science and Technology, St. Gallen, Switzerland. harald.desing@empa.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22.00166</GrantID><Agency>Federal Department of Economic Affairs, Education and Research, Switzerland | Staatssekretariat f&#xfc;r Bildung, Forschung und Innovation (State Secretariat for Education, Research and Innovation)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22.00166</GrantID><Agency>Federal Department of Economic Affairs, Education and Research, Switzerland | Staatssekretariat f&#xfc;r Bildung, Forschung und Innovation (State Secretariat for Education, Research and Innovation)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41834000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-026-70777-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-026-70777-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>International Renewable Energy Agency. Global Energy Transformation: A Roadmap to 2050 (International Renewable Energy Agency, Abu Dhabi, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Renewable Energy Agency. World Energy Transitions Outlook: 1.5 &#xb0;C Pathway (International Renewable Energy Agency, Abu Dhabi, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aramendia, E., Brockway, P. E., Taylor, P. G. &amp; Norman, J. Global energy consumption of the mineral mining industry: Exploring the historical perspective and future pathways to 2060. Glob. Environ. Change 83, 102745 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Environment Programme. Global Resources Outlook 2024: Bend the Trend &#x2013; Pathways to a liveable planet as resource use spikes. https://wedocs.unep.org/20.500.11822/44901 (International Resource Panel, Nairobi, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aska, B., Franks, D. M., Stringer, M. &amp; Sonter, L. J. Biodiversity conservation threatened by global mining wastes. Nat. Sustain. 7, 23&#x2013;30 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe8;bre, &#xc9;. et al. The social and environmental complexities of extracting energy transition metals. Nat. Commun. 11, 4823 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen, J. R. et al. Energy transition minerals and their intersection with land-connected peoples. Nat. Sustain. 6, 203&#x2013;211 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen, J. M., Allwood, J. M. &amp; Bambach, M. D. Mapping the global flow of steel: from steelmaking to end-use goods. Environ. Sci. Technol. 46, 13048&#x2013;13055 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oda, J., Akimoto, K. &amp; Tomoda, T. Long-term global availability of steel scrap. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 81, 81&#x2013;91 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watari, T., Hata, S., Nakajima, K. &amp; Nansai, K. Limited quantity and quality of steel supply in a zero-emission future. Nat. Sustain. 6, 336&#x2013;343 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency. The Role of Critical Minerals in Clean Energy Transitions (International Energy Agency, Paris, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koolen, D. &amp; Vidovic, D. Greenhouse Gas Intensities of the EU Steel Industry and Its Trading Partners. https://doi.org/10.2760/170198 (Publications Office of the European Union, Luxembourg, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broadbent, C. Steel&#x2019;s recyclability: demonstrating the benefits of recycling steel to achieve a circular economy. Int. J. Life Cycle Assess. 21, 1658&#x2013;1665 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciacci, L. et al. Exploring future copper demand, recycling and associated greenhouse gas emissions in the EU-28. Glob. Environ. Change 63, 102093 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M. L. The Environmental Footprint of Semi-Fabricated Aluminum Products in North America. A Life Cycle Assessment Report (The Aluminum Association, Arlington VA, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu, X., Ma, W. &amp; Li, H. Geothermal energy production utilizing abandoned oil and gas wells. Renew. Energy 41, 80&#x2013;85 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caulk, R. A. &amp; Tomac, I. Reuse of abandoned oil and gas wells for geothermal energy production. Renew. Energy 112, 388&#x2013;397 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nian, Y.-L. &amp; Cheng, W.-L. Insights into geothermal utilization of abandoned oil and gas wells. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 87, 44&#x2013;60 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurnia, J. C. et al. Geothermal energy extraction using abandoned oil and gas wells: Techno-economic and policy review. Int. J. Energy Res. 46, 28&#x2013;60 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, J., van Dyk, S. &amp; Saddler, J. Repurposing oil refineries to stand-alone units that refine lipids/oleochemicals to produce low-carbon intensive, drop-in biofuels. J. Clean. Prod. 376, 134335 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayanti, S. E.-P. Repurposing pipelines for hydrogen: legal and policy considerations. Energy Rep. 8, 815&#x2013;820 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tassi, F. &amp; Kittner, N. Repurposing coal plants&#x2014;regional economic impacts from low carbon generation. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 199, 114467 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza, A., Gholami, R., Rezaee, R., Rasouli, V. &amp; Rabiei, M. Significant aspects of carbon capture and storage&#x2014;a review. Petroleum 5, 335&#x2013;340 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency. World Energy Outlook 2021 (International Energy Agency, Paris, France, 2021)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson, M. Z. et al. Impacts of green new deal energy plans on grid stability, costs, jobs, health, and climate in 143 countries. One Earth 1, 449&#x2013;463 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanov, D. et al. Radical transformation pathway towards sustainable electricity via evolutionary steps. Nat. Commun. 10, 1077 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breyer, C. et al. On the history and future of 100% renewable energy systems research. IEEE Access 10, 78176&#x2013;78218 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Boulzec, H. et al. Dynamic modeling of global fossil fuel infrastructure and materials needs: overcoming a lack of available data. Appl. Energy 326, 119871 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deetman, S., de Boer, H. S., Van Engelenburg, M., van der Voet, E. &amp; van Vuuren, D. P. Projected material requirements for the global electricity infrastructure&#x2013;generation, transmission and storage. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 164, 105200 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. Future demand for electricity generation materials under different climate mitigation scenarios. Joule 7, 309&#x2013;332 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habert, G. et al. Environmental impacts and decarbonization strategies in the cement and concrete industries. Nat. Rev. Earth Environ. 1, 559&#x2013;573 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X., Peoples, J., Yao, P. &amp; Ruan, X. Ultrawhite BaSO<sub>4</sub> paints and films for remarkable daytime subambient radiative cooling. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 13, 21733&#x2013;21739 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency. Global Critical Minerals Outlook 2025 (International Energy Agency, Paris, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, X. et al. Factors research on the influence of leaching rate of nickel and cobalt from waste superalloys with sulfuric acid. Int. J. Nonferrous Metall. 2, 63&#x2013;67 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leszczy&#x144;ska-Sejda, K. et al. Hydrometallurgical technology for producing rhenium(VII) and cobalt(II) from waste. Crystals 14, 783 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Energy Monitor. Global Steel Plant Tracker, April 2024 Release. https://globalenergymonitor.org/projects/global-steel-plant-tracker/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Steel Association. World Steel in Figures 2024. https://worldsteel.org/wp-content/uploads/World-Steel-in-Figures-2024.pdf (World Steel Association, Brussels, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumstark, L. et al. REMIND2.1: transformation and innovation dynamics of the energy-economic system within climate and sustainability limits. Geosci. Model Dev. 14, 6571&#x2013;6603 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacchi, R. et al. Prospective environmental impact assement (premise): a streamlined approach to producing databases for prospective life cycle assessment using integrated assessment models. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 160, 112311 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Climate Action Tracker. 2100 Warming Projections: Emissions and Expected Warming Based on Pledges and Current Policies (November 2024). Climate Analytics and NewClimate Institute. https://climateactiontracker.org/global/temperatures/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Carbon Project. The Global Carbon Project&#x2019;s fossil CO<sub>2</sub> emissions dataset. Zenodo https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.13981696 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg. Luxembourg&#x2019;s territory &#x2013; Luxembourg. Government of the Grand Duchy of Luxembourg. https://luxembourg.public.lu/en/society-and-culture/territoire-et-climat/territoire.html (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Environmental Protection Agency. Air pollutant emissions trends data: National Tier 1 caps trends. Environmental Protection Agency. https://www.epa.gov/air-emissions-inventories/air-pollutant-emissions-trends-data (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y., Yan, B., Fabritius, T. &amp; Shu, Q. Immobilization of chromium in stainless steel slag using low zinc electric arc furnace dusts. Metall. Mater. Trans. B 51, 763&#x2013;775 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strandkvist, I. et al. Minimizing chromium leaching from low-alloy electric arc furnace (EAF) slag by adjusting the basicity and cooling rate to control brownmillerite formation. Appl. Sci. 10, 35 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Pyrometallurgical recovery of zinc and valuable metals from electric arc furnace dust&#x2013;a review. J. Clean. Prod. 298, 126788 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. et al. Valuable recovery technology and resource utilization of chromium-containing metallurgical dust and slag: a review. Metals 13, 1768 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TransitionZero. Global Steel Cost Tracker. TransitionZero. https://www.transitionzero.org/products/global-steel-cost-tracker (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desing, H. &amp; Blum, N. On circularity, complexity and (elements of) hope. Circ. Econ. 1, 1&#x2013;5 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaulin, N. &amp; Le Billon, P. Climate change and fossil fuel production cuts: assessing global supply-side constraints and policy implications. Clim. Policy 20, 888&#x2013;901 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond Fossil Fuels. Europe&#x2019;s Coal Exit: Overview of National Coal Phase Out Commitments. https://beyondfossilfuels.org/europes-coal-exit/ (2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ember. The UK&#x2019;s journey to a coal power phase-out. https://ember-energy.org/latest-insights/the-uks-journey-to-a-coal-power-phase-out/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond Oil &amp; Gas Alliance. Beyond Oil &amp; Gas Alliance. https://beyondoilandgasalliance.org (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Vallejo, D. F., Galan-Martin, A., Guillen-Gosalbez, G. &amp; Chachuat, B. Data envelopment analysis approach to targeting in sustainable chemical process design: application to liquid fuels. AIChE J. 65, e16480 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolz, B., Held, M., Georges, G. &amp; Boulouchos, K. Techno-economic analysis of renewable fuels for ships carrying bulk cargo in Europe. Nat. Energy 7, 203&#x2013;212 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency. Indicative production costs for crude steel via electrolytic hydrogen-based DRI in selected regions compared to current references. https://www.iea.org/data-and-statistics/charts/indicative-production-costs-for-crude-steel-via-electrolytic-hydrogen-based-dri-in-selected-regions-compared-to-current-references (International Energy Agency, Paris, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lura, P. et al. Mining the atmosphere: a concrete solution to global warming. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 212, 107968 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennon, A., Lunardi, M., Hallam, B. &amp; Dias, P. R. The aluminium demand risk of terawatt photovoltaics for net zero emissions by 2050. Nat. Sustain. 5, 357&#x2013;363 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Geological Survey. Mineral Commodity Summaries 2024: Aluminum. https://pubs.usgs.gov/periodicals/mcs2024/mcs2024-aluminum.pdf (U.S. Geological Survey, Reston, VA, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change. Paris Agreement. https://unfccc.int/process-and-meetings/the-paris-agreement/the-paris-agreement (UNFCCC, Bonn, Germany, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powering Past Coal Alliance. k Powering Past Coal Alliance. https://www.canada.ca/en/environment-climate-change/corporate/international-affairs/partnerships-organizations/powering-past-coal-alliance.html (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang, G., Rosendahl, K. E. &amp; B&#xf6;hringer, C. Balancing cost and justice concerns in the energy transition: comparing coal phase-out policies in Germany and the UK. Clim. Policy 22, 1000&#x2013;1015 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, D. et al. Targeted emission reductions from global super-polluting power plant units. Nat. Sustain. 1, 59&#x2013;68 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Energy Monitor. Global Oil and Gas Plant Tracker, February 2024 release. https://globalenergymonitor.org/projects/global-oil-gas-plant-tracker/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Energy Monitor. Global Coal Plant Tracker, January 2024 release. https://globalenergymonitor.org/projects/global-coal-plant-tracker/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazard. Lazard&#x2019;s Levelized Cost of Energy Analysis&#x2014;Version 17.0. https://www.lazard.com/media/xemfey0k/lazards-lcoeplus-june-2024-_vf.pdf (Lazard, New York, NY, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Renewable Energy Agency. Renewable Power Generation Costs in 2023 https://www.irena.org/-/media/Files/IRENA/Agency/Publication/2024/Sep/IRENA_Renewable_power_generation_costs_in_2023.pdf. (International Renewable Energy Agency, Abu Dhabi, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kost, C., M&#xfc;ller, P., Sep&#xfa;lveda Schweiger, J., Fluri, V. &amp; Thomsen, J. Levelized Cost of Electricity Renewable Energy Technologies. https://www.ise.fraunhofer.de/content/dam/ise/en/documents/publications/studies/EN2024_ISE_Study_Levelized_Cost_of_Electricity_Renewable_Energy_Technologies.pdf (Fraunhofer Institute for Solar Energy Systems, Freiburg, Germany, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statista. Oil &amp; gas giants cash in tens of billions. https://www.statista.com/chart/27887/big-oil-sees-profits-increase/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Energy Monitor. Global Oil and Gas Extraction Tracker, March 2024 release. https://globalenergymonitor.org/projects/global-oil-gas-extraction-tracker/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond Fossil Fuels. European countries delay coal phase-outs and gamble on fossil gas amidst push for decarbonised power. https://beyondfossilfuels.org/2023/12/07/european-countries-delay-coal-phase-outs-and-gamble-on-fossil-gas-amidst-push-for-decarbonised-power/ (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desing, H., Gerber, A., Hischier, R., W&#xe4;ger, P. &amp; Widmer, R. The 3-machines energy transition model: Exploring the energy frontiers for restoring a habitable climate. Earth&#x2019;s Futur. 10, e2022EF002875 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desing, H. et al. Mobilizing materials to enable a fast energy transition: a conceptual framework. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 200, 107314 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda, A. et al. A cost-efficiency and health benefit approach to improve urban air quality. Sci. Total Environ. 569, 342&#x2013;351 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernet, G. et al. The ecoinvent database version 3 (part i): overview and methodology. Int. J. Life Cycle Assess. 21, 1218&#x2013;1230 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Energy Monitor. Global Coal Mine Tracker, July 2022 release. https://globalenergymonitor.org/projects/global-coal-mine-tracker/ (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Energy Monitor. Global Gas Infrastructure Tracker, December 2022 release. https://globalenergymonitor.org/projects/global-gas-infrastructure-tracker (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Energy Monitor. Global Oil Infrastructure Tracker, June 2022 release. https://globalenergymonitor.org/projects/global-oil-infrastructure-tracker/ (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, G., Guo, W., Fu, E., Yang, C. &amp; Li, J. Dynamic optimization of open-pit coal mine production scheduling based on ARIMA and fuzzy structured element. Front. Earth Sci. 10, 1040464 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swalec, C. &amp; Shearer, C. Pedal to the Metal &#x2019;21: No Time to Delay Decarbonizing the Global Steel Sector. https://globalenergymonitor.org/report/pedal-to-the-metal-no-time-for-delay-in-decarbonizing-global-steel-sector/ (Global Energy Monitor, Covina, CA, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Copper Study Group. World Copper Factbook 2024. https://icsg.org/copper-factbook/ (International Copper Study Group, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huijbregts, M. et al. Recipe2016: a harmonised life cycle impact assessment method at midpoint and endpoint level. Int. J. Life Cycle Assess. 22, 138&#x2013;147 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masson-Delmotte, V. et al. (eds.). Climate Change 2021: The Physical Science Basis. Contribution of Working Group I to the Sixth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-working-group-i/ (Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas, E., Guo, M. &amp; Guill&#xe9;n-Gos&#xe1;lbez, G. Low-carbon diets can reduce global ecological and health costs. Nat. Food 4, 394&#x2013;406 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brander, L. Guidance Manual on Value Transfer Methods for Ecosystem Services. https://www.unep.org/resources/report/guidance-manual-value-transfer-methods-ecosystem-services (United Nations Environment Programme, Nairobi, Kenya, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algunaibet, I. M., Pozo, C., Galan-Martin, A. &amp; Guillen-Gosalbez, G. Quantifying the cost of leaving the Paris agreement via the integration of life cycle assessment, energy systems modeling and monetization. Appl. Energy 242, 588&#x2013;601 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viscusi, W. K. The role of publication selection bias in estimates of the value of a statistical life. Am. J. Health Econ. 1, 27&#x2013;52 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen, J. B. &amp; Hanley, N. Are there income effects on global willingness to pay for biodiversity conservation? Environ. Resour. Econ. 43, 137&#x2013;160 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byers, E. et al. AR6 Scenarios Database. https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5886911 (2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>