<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41896324</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative behavior of steam turbine model for dynamical power system analyses by means of multiple fractional and artificial neural network techniques.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10882</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-45449-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Steam turbine is pivotal in industrial and power generation because it has become an essential technology for optimization of energy that efficiently converts thermal energy from steam into mechanical energy. This manuscript proposes a predictive modelling of steam turbine by invoking artificial neural network analysis and develops dynamic mathematical model for steam turbine via multiple fractional techniques. A novel mathematical model for steam turbine is developed by means modern fractional differentials and artificial neural network subject to steady-state condition for high efficiency and long operation. For seeking the transfer function, mathematical techniques of Laplace and Sumudu transforms, rectified linear function, mean squared error have been invoked to have estimation for ratio of output to input as a dynamic response. At last, the comparison of best validation performance versus epoch, absolute error versus pressure, training dynamics versus epoch, error histogram versus targets and actual scale versus predicted scale in terms of fit have been deeply discussed for the efficiency of steam turbine.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abro</LastName><ForeName>Kashif Ali</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Sciences and Related Studies, Mehran University of Engineering and Technology, Jamshoro, Pakistan. kashif.abro@faculty.muet.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Souayeh</LastName><ForeName>Basma</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, College of Science, King Faisal University, PO Box 400, Al-Ahsa, 31982, Saudi Arabia. bsouayeh@kfu.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flah</LastName><ForeName>Aymen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Science Research Center, Applied Science Private University, Amman, 11931, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENET Centre, CEET, VSB-Technical University of Ostrava, Ostrava, 708 00, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering, University of Business and Technology, Jeddah, 21448, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Analytic investigation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiple fractional and classical steam turbine model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neural network techniques</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimization and controllability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Statistical analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41896324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13039493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-45449-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-45449-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chaibakhsh, A. &amp; Ghaffari, A. Steam turbine model. <i>Simul. Model. Pract. Theory</i>. <b>16</b>, 1145&#x2013;1162 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.simpat.2008.05.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, P., Lin, G. &amp; Yiping, D. A new non-linear model of steam turbine unit for dynamic analysis of power system. <i>2010 International Conference on Power System Technology</i> 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/POWERCON.2010.5666735 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K., Chiasson, J., Bodson, M. &amp; Tolbert, L. M. A nonlinear least-squares approach for identification of the induction motor parameters. <i>IEEE Trans. Autom. Control</i>. <b>50</b>(10), 1622&#x2013;1628. 10.1109/TAC.2005.856661 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAC.2005.856661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharhremani, E., Karrari, M. &amp; Malik, O. Synchronous generator third-order model parameter estimation using online experimental data. <i>IET generation transmission distribution</i>. <b>2</b>, 708&#x2013;719 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-gtd:20080175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmer, G. Modelling and simulation of steam turbine processes: individual models for individual tasks. <i>Math. Comput. Model. Dyn. Syst.</i><b>14</b>(6), 469&#x2013;493. 10.1080/13873950802384001 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13873950802384001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szapajko, G. &amp; Rusinowski, H. Theoretical-empirical model of the steam-water cycle of the power unit. <i>Acta Montanist. Slovaca Ro&#x10d;nik</i>. <b>15</b>(1), 24&#x2013;27 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, X., Zhang, B., Chen, Y. &amp; Songping, M. Modeling and optimization of a utility system containing multiple extractions steam turbines. <i>Energy</i><b>36</b>(5), 3501&#x2013;3512 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2011.03.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laskowski, R. M. A mathematical model of a steam condenser in off-design operation. <i>J. Power Technol.</i><b>92</b>, 101&#x2013;108 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson, C. A., Meybodi, M. A. &amp; Behnia, M. Optimisation and selection of a steam turbine for a large scale industrial CHP (combined heat and power) system under Australia&#x2019;s carbon price. <i>Energy</i><b>61</b>(C), 291&#x2013;307 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2013.08.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztof, B. Mathematical model for digital simulation of steam turbine set dynamics and on-line turbine load distribution. <i>Trans. Inst. Fluid-Flow Mach.</i><b>126</b>, 65&#x2013;82 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genovski, I. &amp; Hristov, K. Optimal heat load distribution between cogeneration steam turbine installations in combined heat and power (CHP) plant. <i>J. MacroTrends Technol. Innov.</i><b>1</b>, 30&#x2013;46 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatarinova, N. V., Efros, Y. &amp; Sushchikh, V. M. Results of a calculation based on mathematical models of variable operating modes of cogeneration steam turbine plants in real operating conditions. <i>Perspektivy nauki</i>. <b>3</b>(54), 95&#x2013;100 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plis, M. &amp; Rusinowski, H. Mathematical modelling of single pressure heat recovery steam generator. <i>Proc. 16th Int. Carpathian Control Conf.</i><b>315-320</b>, Szilv&#x2013;sv (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murmanskii, B. E., Aronson, K. E. &amp; Brodov, Y. M. Estimation of the residual life of steam-turbine condensers based on statistical models. <i>Therm. Eng.</i><b>62</b>, 785&#x2013;789. 10.1134/S0040601515110051 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S0040601515110051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shempelev, A. G., Sushchikh, V. M. &amp; Iglin, P. V. On the results of comparing the calculated and standard characteristics of condensers of steam turbine units in a wide range of their steam loads. <i>Energetik</i><b>10</b>, 60&#x2013;64 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inkyu, C., Joohee, W., Byoungchul, K. &amp; Gihun, S. Application of dynamic model for steam turbine and its parameter estimation in a fossil fired power plant. <i>KEPCO J. Electr. Power Energy</i>. <b>2</b>(3). 10.18770/KEPCO.2016.02.03.409 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusinowski, H. &amp; Plis, M. Mathematical model of a steam turbine for the thermal diagnostics system, 17th International Carpathian Control Conference (ICCC), High Tatras, Slovakia, 630&#x2013;634, (2016). 10.1109/CarpathianCC.2016.7501172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Q., Luo, X., Zhang, B., Chen, Y. &amp; Songping, M. Mathematical modeling, validation, and operation optimization of an industrial complex steam turbine network-methodology and application. <i>Energy</i><b>97</b>(C), 191&#x2013;213 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2015.12.112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murmansky, B. E., Aronson, K. E. &amp; Brodov, Y. M. An expert system for diagnostics and estimation of steam turbine components condition. <i>J. Phys. : Conf. Ser.</i><b>891</b>, 012279. 10.1088/1742-6596/891/1/012279 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/891/1/012279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalili, R. &amp; Karrari, M. Modeling and identification of an industrial gas turbine using classical and non-classical approaches, Electrical Engineering (ICEE), Iranian Conference on, 2017. IEEE, 667&#x2013;672. (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munirah, W. M., Tahir, A. &amp; Azmirul, A. Identifying the uncertain model parameter of a steam turbine system. <i>Pertanika J. Sci. Technol.</i><b>25</b>(2), 545&#x2013;560 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramtin, K., Hadi, R., Abolfazl, K., Behrooz, Z. &amp; Mehdi Ki, Shahab, K. Mathematical modelling and parameter estimation of an industrial steam turbine-generator based on operational data. <i>IFAC Papers On-line</i>. <b>51</b>(2), 214&#x2013;219 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ifacol.2018.03.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamad, W. M., Ahmad, T., Karim, A. &amp; Ashaari, A. Fuzzy arithmetical modeling of a steam turbine and a boiler system. <i>Math. Modelling Anal.</i><b>23</b>(1), 101&#x2013;116. 10.3846/mma.2018.007 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3846/mma.2018.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah, H. M., Mustafa, G., Chaudri, K. S. &amp; Abid, M. and Modeling of an extraction steam turbine and speed control system design. <i>Nucleus</i> (2021). https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:275960849</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shavdinova, M. Mathematical model of a steam turbine condenser. <i>Therm. Eng.</i><b>69</b>(9), 674&#x2013;682 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S0040601522090051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kravets, T. &amp; Riabokon, H. Development of a mathematical model for obtaining energy characteristics of the turbine unit with the K-325-23.5 steam turbine. <i>Energy Eng. Control Syst.</i><b>8</b>(2), 81&#x2013;89. 10.23939/jeecs2022.02.081 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23939/jeecs2022.02.081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mircea Dulau, D. &amp; Bica Mathematical modelling and simulation of the behaviour of the steam turbine. <i>Procedia Technol.</i><b>12</b>, 723&#x2013;729. 10.1016/j.protcy.2013.12.555 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.protcy.2013.12.555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlubny, I. <i>Fractional Differential Equations</i> (Academic, 1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim Mahariq, K. A., Abro, A. &amp; Siyal Energy transfer and thermal transport for unsteady fractional viscous fluid under Fourier and statistical analysis. <i>Propuls. Power Res.</i>10.1016/j.jppr.2025.02.005 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jppr.2025.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caputo, M. &amp; Fabrizio, M. A. New definition of fractional derivative without singular kernel. <i>Prog Fract. Diff Appl.</i><b>1</b>, 73&#x2013;85 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abro, K. A., Memon, I. Q., Mohamed, K. S. &amp; Aldwoah, K. Neurobiological transition of magnetized and demagnetized dynamism for fractional Hindmarsh&#x2013;Rose neuron model via fractal numerical simulations. <i>J. Comput. Electron.</i><b>24</b>, 33. 10.1007/s10825-024-02243-9 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10825-024-02243-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atangana, A. &amp; Baleanu, D. New fractional derivative with non-local and non-singular kernel: theory and application to heat transfer model. <i>Therm. Sci.</i><b>20</b>, 763&#x2013;769 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2298/TSCI160111018A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abro, K. A. &amp; Mahariq, I. Fractal performance under magnetization procedures of fractional memristive Wilson neuron dynamical model. <i>Int. J. Numer. Model. Electron. Networks Devices Fields</i>. <b>38</b>, e70016. 10.1002/jnm.70016 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jnm.70016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambreen, S. &amp; Kashif, A. A. A fractal model for thermal analysis of Newtonian fluid to forecast thermal behavior. <i>J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. (2024) DOI</i> :10.1007/s10973-024-13519-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. J., Abdel-Aty, M. &amp; Cattani, C. A new general fractional order derivative with Rabotnov fractional exponential kernel applied to model the anomalous heat. <i>Therm. Sci.</i><b>23</b>(3A), 1677&#x2013;1681 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2298/TSCI180320239Y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amarah Akhund, K. A. &amp; Abro Fractal modeling of non-integer Newtonian fluid through comparison of Sumudu and Laplace transforms. <i>Int. J. Geom. Methods Mod. Phys.</i>10.1142/S0219887824503286 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0219887824503286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf, W. M. &amp; Dua, V. Data Information integrated Neural Network (DINN) algorithm for modelling and interpretation performance analysis for energy systems. <i>Energy AI</i>. <b>16</b>, 100363 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyai.2024.100363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansar, T. &amp; Ashraf, W. M. Comparison of Kolmogorov&#x2013;Arnold Networks and Multi-Layer Perceptron for modelling and optimisation analysis of energy systems. <i>Energy AI</i>. <b>20</b>, 100473 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyai.2025.100473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishfaq, K., Sana, M. &amp; Ashraf, W. Artificial intelligence&#x2013;built analysis framework for the manufacturing sector: performance optimization of wire electric discharge machining system. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol.</i><b>128</b>(11), 5025&#x2013;5039 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-023-12191-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>