<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41824747</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1660-2862</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuro-degenerative diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurodegener Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Facial Emotion Recognition Deficits and EEG Alterations in Mild Behavioral Impairment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>21</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-21</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000551440</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Mild Behavioral Impairment (MBI) is a late-life neurobehavioral syndrome associated with increased risk of incident cognitive decline and dementia. Facial emotion recognition (FER), a core component of social cognition, is impaired across neurodegenerative disorders, yet its association with MBI remains underexplored. We examined cognitive/socio-emotional profiles and resting-state electroencephalogram (EEG) in individuals with MBI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 120 older adults with subjective cognitive decline (SCD) or mild cognitive impairment (MCI) were classified into MBI (n = 57) and non-MBI (n = 63) using the MBI-Checklist. Participants underwent comprehensive clinical and neuropsychological evaluation and neuropsychological assessments including Mini-Mental State Examination (MMSE), and the Korean Facial Affect Battery (K-FAB subtests 1-5). Resting-state EEG was analyzed using an automated platform to derive sensor-level spectral power and source-level connectivity measures. Group comparisons used appropriate tests; K-FAB analyses were adjusted for age, education, MMSE, and Geriatric Depression Scale (GDS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The MBI group showed greater functional impairment (higher CDR-SOB, p = 0.019) and higher depressive symptom severity (GDS, p = 0.004), with a trend toward fewer years of education (p = 0.090). Neuropsychological domain scores were broadly comparable, although the MBI group showed a trend toward lower frontal executive composite performance after covariate adjustment (p = 0.076). On K-FAB, the MBI group demonstrated significantly poorer affect selection performance (FAB4; adjusted p = 0.031), with additional trend-level differences in affect naming (FAB3; adjusted p = 0.084) and in negative emotion recognition (fear and sadness). Resting-state EEG findings indicated elevated Beta1-3 and Gamma absolute power in the MBI group across multiple scalp regions (p &lt; 0.05), as well as frequency-specific source connectivity differences, including widespread Delta-band hyperconnectivity, relatively stronger Alpha1 connectivity in the non-MBI group, and increased Beta1 connectivity within fronto-parietal and fronto-temporal circuits in the MBI group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this clinic-based SCD/MCI cohort, MBI was associated with greater functional impairment and depressive symptom burden, selective FER deficits-particularly in affect selection-and distinct resting-state EEG spectral and connectivity patterns. These findings suggest that socio-emotional measures and EEG markers may provide complementary information for characterizing neurobehavioral alterations associated with MBI, although interpretations should remain cautious given the cross-sectional design and methodological constraints of automated EEG analyses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). Published by S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shim</LastName><ForeName>YongSoo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Eun-Ye</ForeName><Initials>EY</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Neurodegener Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101189034</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1660-2854</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41824747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000551440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000551440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>