<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41588392</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medical education</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med Educ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Determinants of effective feedback on educational performance of faculty members based on their own experiences: a content analysis study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>304</StartPage><MedlinePgn>304</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">304</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12909-026-08601-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Providing faculty members with feedback, as the last stage of the evaluation of their educational performance is of particular importance. Offering helpful information about strengths and weaknesses, opportunities and threats of their performance, feedback provision empowers both faculty members and education officials to improve the existing situation. The present study aimed to identify the determinants of effective feedback on educational performance of faculty members based on their own experiences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This study employed conventional qualitative content analysis, with data gathered through semi-structured interviews featuring open-ended questions. The research focused on 16 faculty members from Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, who were purposefully selected to ensure maximum diversity. The data was analyzed using the Graneheim and Lundman content analysis method, and the quality of the results was confirmed by following Guba and Lincoln&#x2019;s criteria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The results of this study yielded 10 categories and 2 themes including barriers to and facilitators of effective feedback. Categories related to the theme of barriers to effective feedback included Imbalance of the power of feedback giver and feedback receiver, unstructured feedback, Feedback without the appropriate content, Recipient-related barriers to accepting feedback, and, Conflict and differences between feedback giver and feedback receiver. Categories related to the theme of effective feedback facilitators were ethical feedback, Communication-based feedback, Personality traits of the feedback giver, Psychological readiness of the feedback receiver, and Structured nature of the feedback.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Effective feedback is a vital component of instructional strategies that support individual skill development and learning. The findings of this study may inform feedback providers about potential obstacles and highlight facilitators that could enhance feedback practices. These insights contribute to scientific understanding by emphasizing context-specific determinants of effective feedback in academic settings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12909-026-08601-4.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karimijavan</LastName><ForeName>Gelavizh</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Education, Faculty of Medicine, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Speech Therapy, Rehabilitation Faculty, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mahasti</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Research Center, Health Management and Safety Promotion Research Institute, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranjbar</LastName><ForeName>Fatemeh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research center of psychiatry and behavioral sciences, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghaffarifar</LastName><ForeName>Saeideh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Research Center, Health Management and Safety Promotion Research Institute, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran. ghaffarifars@tbzmed.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karimi</LastName><ForeName>Salah Eddin</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Social Determinants of Health Research Center, Health Management and Safety Promotion Research Institute, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran. Salahkarimi2009@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Policy and Management, Tabriz Health Services Management Research Center, School of Management &amp; Medical Informatics, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran. Salahkarimi2009@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med Educ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088679</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6920</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Barriers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Effective feedback</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Facilitators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Feedback</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethics approval and consent to participate The aim of the study was explained to all potential participants, and only those who verbally agreed to participate were recruited. Written consent was obtained from all participants willing to take part. Participants were informed about the study objectives, procedures, voluntary participation, and their right to withdraw at any time. The study was approved by the Research Ethics Committee of Tabriz University of Medical Sciences (Approval Code: IR.TBZMED.REC.1401.779). Consent for publication: All participants provided consent for the publication of anonymized and aggregated data, including demographic information such as age, sex, and department. No identifying information is included in the manuscript. Competing interests: Apart from Saeideh Ghaffarifar, an editorial board member of BMC Medical Education, the authors want to disclose 598 that they do not have any conflicting interests to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41588392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12918631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-026-08601-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12909-026-08601-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hattie J, Timperley H. The power of feedback. Rev Educ Res. 2007;77(1):81&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/003465430298487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein RM. Assessment in medical education. N Engl J Med. 2007;356(4):387&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra054784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17251535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamali D, Illing J. How can positive and negative trainer feedback in the operating theatre impact a surgical trainee&#x2019;s confidence and well-being: a qualitative study in the North of England. BMJ Open. 2018;8(2):e017935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2017-017935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5829657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29440141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabbir A, Raja H, Qadri AA, Qadri MHA. Faculty feedback program evaluation in CIMS Multan, Pakistan. Cureus 2020, 12(6).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32676249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zolaly MA. Are we giving proper feedback to medical students? Experience from a Saudi medical college. J Taibah Univ Med Sci. 2019;14(2):110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6695070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31435400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipsch-Wijnen I, Dirkx K. A case study of the use of the Hattie and Timperley feedback model on written feedback in thesis examination in higher education. Cogent Education. 2022;9(1):2082089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisniewski B, Zierer K, Hattie J. The power of feedback revisited: A meta-analysis of educational feedback research. Front Psychol. 2020;10:487662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.03087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32038429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamshidian S, Haghani F, Yamani N, Sabri MR. Provision of feedback to medical teachers on their educational performance: perspectives of internal medicine teachers. Adv Med Educ Pract 2019:85&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6396651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30881169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer JC. State of the science in health professional education: effective feedback. Med Educ. 2010;44(1):101&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2923.2009.03546.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20078761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spooner M, Reinhardt C, Strawbridge J, Larkin J, Liew SC, Jafar MH, Pawlikowska T. How cultural factors affect medical students&#x2019; interactions with clinical practice feedback: a qualitative study of ethnically diverse students at three transcontinental campuses. Med Educ Online. 2025;30(1):2567075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10872981.2025.2567075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12576907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41162831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poursaberi N, Rostampour K, Teymoori R. Identifying barriers to effective feedback in higher education classrooms. Assess Pract Educational Sci. 2023;1(1):41&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daher-Nashif S, Kane T. A culturally competent approach to teaching humanities in an international medical school: potential frameworks and lessons learned. MedEdPublish. 2022;12:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9370088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36168538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghahrani N, Siamian H, Balaghafari A, Aligolbandi K, Vahedi M. The opinion of students and faculty members about the effect of the faculty performance evaluation. Materia socio-medica. 2015;27(4):267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4610664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26543421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy ST, Zegarek MH, Fromme HB, Ryan MS, Schumann S-A, Harris IB. Barriers and facilitators to effective feedback: a qualitative analysis of data from multispecialty resident focus groups. J Graduate Med Educ. 2015;7(2):214&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4300/JGME-D-14-00461.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26221437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bing-You R, Ramesh S, Hayes V, Varaklis K, Ward D, Blanco M. Trainees&#x2019; perceptions of feedback: validity evidence for two FEEDME (feedback in medical education) instruments. Teach Learn Med. 2018;30(2):162&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10401334.2017.1392863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29240456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelgrim EA, Kramer AW, Mokkink HG, Van Der Vleuten CP. The process of feedback in workplace-based assessment: organisation, delivery, continuity. Med Educ. 2012;46(6):604&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2923.2012.04266.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22626052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsini C, Rodrigues V, Tricio J, Rosel M. Common models and approaches for the clinical educator to plan effective feedback encounters. J Educational Evaluation Health Professions 2022, 19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9842479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36537186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelenski AB, Tischendorf JS, Kessler M, Saunders S, MacDonald MM, Vogelman B, Zakowski L. Beyond read more: an intervention to improve faculty written feedback to learners. J Graduate Med Educ. 2019;11(4):468&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4300/JGME-D-19-00058.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6699542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31440343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EJ, Lee KR. Effects of an examiner&#x2019;s positive and negative feedback on self-assessment of skill performance, emotional response, and self-efficacy in korea: a quasi-experimental study. BMC Med Educ. 2019;19(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-019-1595-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCutcheon S, Duchemin A-M. Overcoming barriers to effective feedback: a solution-focused faculty development approach. Int J Med Educ. 2020;11:230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5116/ijme.5f7c.3157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33099519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speziale HS, Streubert HJ, Carpenter DR. Qualitative research in nursing: advancing the humanistic imperative. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forman J, Damschroder L. Qualitative content analysis. Empirical methods for bioethics: A primer. edn.: Emerald Group Publishing Limited; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holley RP. Applications of social research methods to questions in information and library science. Portal: Libr Acad. 2009;9(4):517&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/pla.0.0081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch R. Qualitative research: analysis types and software. Routledge; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln YS, Guba EG. But is it rigorous? Trustworthiness and authenticity in naturalistic evaluation. New Dir Program Evaluation. 1986;1986(30):73&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ev.1427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamali D, Illing J. How can positive and negative trainer feedback in the operating theatre impact a surgical trainee&#x2019;s confidence and well-being: a qualitative study in the North of England. BMJ Open 2018, 8(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5829657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29440141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cestone CM, Levine RE, Lane DR. Peer assessment and evaluation in team-based learning. New Dir Teach Learn. 2008;2008(116):69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tl.334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaelsen LK, Schultheiss EE. Making feedback helpful. Organizational Behav Teach Rev. 1989;13(1):109&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/105256298801300114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jug R, Jiang XS, Bean SM. Giving and receiving effective feedback a review Article and how-to guide. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2019;143(2):244&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5858/arpa.2018-0058-RA</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30102068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veloski J, Boex JR, Grasberger MJ, Evans A, Wolfson DB. Systematic review of the literature on assessment, feedback and physicians&#x2019; clinical performance: BEME guide 7. Med Teach. 2006;28(2):117&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01421590600622665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16707292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Audia PG, Locke EA. Benefiting from negative feedback. Hum Resource Manage Rev. 2003;13(4):631&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrmr.2003.11.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natesan S, Jordan J, Sheng A, Carmelli G, Barbas B, King A, Gore K, Estes M, Gottlieb M. Feedback in medical education: an Evidence-based guide to best practices from the Council of residency directors in emergency medicine. Western J Emerg Med. 2023;24(3):479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5811/WESTJEM.56544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37278777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie KC, Sjaus A, Munro A, George RB. An interpretive phenomenological analysis of formative feedback in anesthesia training: the residents&#x2019; perspective. BMC Med Educ. 2020;20(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12909-020-02402-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7720595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33287808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckingham M, Goodall A. Why feedback rarely does what it&#x2019;s meant to [Internet]. Harvard Business Rev 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesketh E, Laidlaw J. Developing the teaching instinct. Med Teach. 2002;24(3):239&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01421590220134051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12098408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson ST, Couldry R, Phillips H, Buck B. Preceptor development: providing effective feedback. Hosp Pharm. 2013;48(1):26&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1310/hpj4801-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3839441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24421419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crommelinck M, Anseel F. Understanding and encouraging feedback-seeking behaviour: a literature review. Med Educ. 2013;47(3):232&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/medu.12075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23398009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluger AN, DeNisi A. The effects of feedback interventions on performance: a historical review, a meta-analysis, and a preliminary feedback intervention theory. Psychol Bull. 1996;119(2):254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.119.2.254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdoch-Eaton D, Sargeant J. Maturational differences in undergraduate medical students&#x2019; perceptions about feedback. Med Educ. 2012;46(7):711&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2923.2012.04291.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22691150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho KK, Marjadi B, Langendyk V, Hu W. The self-regulated learning of medical students in the clinical environment&#x2013;a scoping review. BMC Med Educ. 2017;17:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5504849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28693468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruppen LD. Humility and respect: core values in medical education. Med Educ. 2014;48(1):53&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/medu.12269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24330117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eva KW, Armson H, Holmboe E, Lockyer J, Loney E, Mann K, Sargeant J. Factors influencing responsiveness to feedback: on the interplay between fear, confidence, and reasoning processes. Adv Health Sci Educ. 2012;17:15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10459-011-9290-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3274671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21468778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bing-You RG, Bertsch T, Thompson JA. Coaching medical students in receiving effective feedback. Teach Learn Med. 1998;10(4):228&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15328015TLM1004_6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerchenfeldt S, Eng M. A survey of health sciences faculty practices and attitudes regarding the peer feedback component of team-based learning. Med Sci Educ. 2019;29:1211&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40670-019-00816-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8368767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34457605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>