<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41840328</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2198-6576</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rheumatology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rheumatol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and Safety of Obexelimab to Treat IgG4-Related Disease: Protocol for a Global, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40744-026-00835-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">IgG4-related disease (IgG4-RD) is a chronic, multiorgan fibroinflammatory condition characterized by recurring flares that can lead to progressive organ damage and failure, impaired quality of life, and death. Glucocorticoids (GCs) remain the primary therapy despite their significant toxicity. Obexelimab is a humanized, bifunctional, monoclonal antibody designed to inhibit B cells by co-engaging CD19 and Fc&#x3b3;RIIb (CD32b), mimicking natural inhibitory signaling triggered by antigen-antibody complexes. Following promising phase 2 results that demonstrated clinical improvement in 93% of patients with IgG4-RD, the phase 3 INDIGO trial was initiated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">INDIGO is a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of obexelimab in patients with IgG4-RD. The trial has enrolled adult patients&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;18&#xa0;years old with active IgG4-RD meeting the 2019 ACR/EULAR classification criteria (score&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;20). Following standardized GC induction, patients are randomized 1:1 to weekly subcutaneous obexelimab 250&#xa0;mg or placebo for 52&#xa0;weeks. An independent adjudication committee (AC) ensures consistent application of IgG4-RD classification and organ-specific flare criteria developed for the trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PLANNED OUTCOMES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The primary endpoint is time to first IgG4-RD flare requiring initiation of rescue therapy as determined by both the investigator and AC. Key secondary endpoints are time to first investigator-determined flare requiring rescue therapy, number of investigator- and AC-determined flares requiring rescue therapy, proportion of patients achieving complete remission, and cumulative dose of GC rescue therapy for active IgG4-RD through Week 52.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The INDIGO trial achieved its global enrollment goal with 194 patients, making it the largest phase 3 trial in IgG4-RD to date and providing 90% power to detect a clinically meaningful reduction in flare risk. This trial will provide critical evidence on B-cell inhibition as a treatment strategy for IgG4-RD and assess obexelimab as a potential steroid-sparing option to address significant unmet needs of this patient population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">NCT05662241.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Culver</LastName><ForeName>Emma L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Gastroenterology and Liver Unit, John Radcliffe Hospital, and Nuffield Department of Medicine, University of Oxford, Headley Way, Headington, Oxford, OX3 9DU, UK. emma.culver@ndm.ox.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baker</LastName><ForeName>Matthew C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Immunology and Rheumatology, Department of Medicine, Stanford University, Palo Alto, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Della-Torre</LastName><ForeName>Emanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe0; Vita-Salute San Raffaele, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unit of Immunology, Rheumatology, Allergy and Rare Diseases (UnIRAR), IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wen</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology and Clinical Immunology, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, 100730, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Dermatologic and Immunologic Diseases, State Key Laboratory of Complex Severe and Rare Diseases, The Ministry of Education Key Laboratory, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perugino</LastName><ForeName>Cory A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Allergy, and Immunology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wells</LastName><ForeName>Audrey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zenas BioPharma, Waltham, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamuye</LastName><ForeName>Admasu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zenas BioPharma, Waltham, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quinn</LastName><ForeName>Shauna M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zenas BioPharma, Waltham, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poma</LastName><ForeName>Allen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zenas BioPharma, Waltham, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greene</LastName><ForeName>Thomas J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zenas BioPharma, Waltham, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stone</LastName><ForeName>John H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Allergy, and Immunology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05662241</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rheumatol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101674543</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-6576</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">B-cell inhibition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IgG4-related disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obexelimab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subcutaneous administration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trial design</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: Emma L. Culver has participated in advisory boards and consulting for Amgen, Zenas BioPharma, Sanofi, Acepodia, Ipsen, Mirum, GSK, Dr Falk Pharma, and Gilead, and receives research support from the NIHR Oxford Biomedical Research Centre. Matthew C. Baker has received fees from Amgen, Sanofi, Zenas BioPharma, argenx, Eli Lilly, Gilead, and Neurocrine. Emanuel Della-Torre has participated in advisory boards and consulting for Amgen, Zenas BioPharma, Sanofi, and Acepodia. Wen Zhang has participated in advisory boards and consulting for Amgen, Zenas BioPharma, Sanofi, and Acepodia. Cory A. Perugino has received consulting fees from Amgen, Sanofi, and Acepodia. Audrey Wells, Admasu Mamuye, Shauna M. Quinn, Allen Poma, and Thomas J. Greene are employees of Zenas BioPharma, Inc. and may hold stock or stock options in the company. John H. Stone has received grants from the National Institutes of Health (UM1 AI144295) and Q32Bio, serves as Chair of a Data and Safety Monitoring Board for Merck, and has received consulting fees from Amgen, Zenas, Sanofi, AcepodiaBio, Novartis, HingeBio, ZipBio, and Argenx. Ethical Approval: The INDIGO study protocol has been approved by relevant health authorities and institutional review boards and was activated at 114 sites in Argentina, Canada, China, France, Germany, Hong Kong, Hungary, Italy, Japan, Mexico, Netherlands, Poland, South Korea, Spain, Sweden, Taiwan, Turkey, United Kingdom, and United States. The trial is conducted in accordance with consensus ethical principles derived from the Declaration of Helsinki and applicable International Council for Harmonisation&#x2013;Good Clinical Practice (ICH GCP) guidelines. All patients provide written informed consent prior to any study procedures.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41840328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40744-026-00835-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40744-026-00835-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kamisawa T, Zen Y, Pillai S, Stone JH. IgG4-related disease. Lancet. 2015;385(9976):1460&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25481618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(14)60720-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Stone JH. Management of IgG4-related disease. Lancet Rheumatol. 2019;1(1):e55&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38229361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(19)30017-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Katz G, Hernandez-Barco YG, Baker MC. Current and future advances in practice: IgG4-related disease. Rheumatol Adv Pract. 2024;8(2):rkae020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38601138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11003820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rap/rkae020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Naden RP, Chari S, Choi H, Della-Torre E, Dicaire JF, et al. The 2019 American College of Rheumatology/European League Against Rheumatism classification criteria for IgG4-related disease. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2020;72(1):7&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31793250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.41120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Deshpande V, Mattoo H, Mahajan VS, Kulikova M, Pillai S, et al. IgG4-related disease: clinical and laboratory features in one hundred twenty-five patients. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2015;67(9):2466&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25988916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4621270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perugino CA, Stone JH. IgG4-related disease: an update on pathophysiology and implications for clinical care. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2020;16(12):702&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32939060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41584-020-0500-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanzillotta M, Mancuso G, Della-Torre E. Advances in the diagnosis and management of IgG4 related disease. BMJ. 2020;369:m1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m1067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro FAG, Pereira IA, de Souza AWS, Giardini HAM, Cordeiro RA. IgG4-related disease-rare but you should not forget it. Adv Rheumatol. 2024;64(1):35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38702764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42358-024-00374-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Miles G, Smolkina E, Petruski-Ivleva N, Madziva D, Cook C, et al. Incidence, prevalence and mortality of IgG4-related disease in the USA: a claims-based analysis of commercially insured adults. Ann Rheum Dis. 2023;82(7):957&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37137671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard-2023-223950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanzillotta M, Fernandez-Codina A, Culver E, Ebbo M, Martinez-Valle F, Schleinitz N, et al. Emerging therapy options for IgG4-related disease. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2021;17(5):471&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33689549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1744666X.2021.1902310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rispens T, Huijbers MG. The unique properties of IgG4 and its roles in health and disease. Nat Rev Immunol. 2023;23(11):763&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37095254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10123589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41577-023-00871-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso G. A comprehensive review of IgG4 related disease unraveling the role of B and T lymphocytes in the pathogenesis of the disease. J ISSN. 2024;2766:2276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattoo H, Mahajan VS, Della-Torre E, Sekigami Y, Carruthers M, Wallace ZS, et al. De novo oligoclonal expansions of circulating plasmablasts in active and relapsing IgG4-related disease. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2014;134(3):679&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24815737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4149918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2014.03.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Mattoo H, Carruthers M, Mahajan VS, Della Torre E, Lee H, et al. Plasmablasts as a biomarker for IgG4-related disease, independent of serum IgG4 concentrations. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74(1):190&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24817416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2014-205233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Miles G, Smolkina E, Petruski-Ivleva N, Madziva D, Cook C, et al., editors. The epidemiology, clinical outcomes, and healthcare resource utilization of IgG4-related disease among commercially insured people in the United States. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology; 2022. ACR Convergence 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culver EL, Sadler R, Bateman AC, Makuch M, Cargill T, Ferry B, et al. Increases in IgE, eosinophils, and mast cells can be used in diagnosis and to predict relapse of IgG4-related disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;15(9):1444-1452 e1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28223204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5592233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2017.02.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Miles G, Smolkina E, Petruski-Ivleva N, Madziva D, Guzzo K, et al. The clinical outcomes and healthcare resource utilization in IgG4-related disease: a claims-based analysis of commercially insured adults in the United States. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2024;63(9):2457&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38637947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11371374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keae230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosroshahi A, Wallace ZS, Crowe JL, Akamizu T, Azumi A, Carruthers MN, et al. International consensus guidance statement on the management and treatment of IgG4-related disease. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2015;67(7):1688&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25809420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Ahmet A, Ward L, Krishnamoorthy P, Mandelcorn ED, Leigh R, et al. A practical guide to the monitoring and management of the complications of systemic corticosteroid therapy. Allergy Asthma Clin Immunol. 2013;9(1):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23947590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3765115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1710-1492-9-30</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka Y, Stone JH. Perspectives on current and emerging therapies for immunoglobulin G4-related disease. Mod Rheumatol. 2023;33(2):229&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36408992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/mr/roac141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiyama M, Alshehri W, Saito K, Takeuchi T, Kaneko Y. Pharmacological management of IgG4-related disease: from traditional to mechanism-based targeted therapies. Drugs Aging. 2025;42(2):111&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39755996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40266-024-01172-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebbo M, Grados A, Samson M, Groh M, Loundou A, Rigolet A, et al. Long-term efficacy and safety of rituximab in IgG4-related disease: data from a French nationwide study of thirty-three patients. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(9):e0183844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28915275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5600376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0183844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers MN, Topazian MD, Khosroshahi A, Witzig TE, Wallace ZS, Hart PA, et al. Rituximab for IgG4-related disease: a prospective, open-label trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74(6):1171&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25667206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2014-206605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campochiaro C, Della-Torre E, Lanzillotta M, Bozzolo E, Baldissera E, Milani R, et al. Long-term efficacy of maintenance therapy with rituximab for IgG4-related disease. Eur J Intern Med. 2020;74:92&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31901297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2019.12.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold F, Huzly D, Tanriver Y, Welte T. Response to SARS-CoV-2 vaccines in patients receiving B-cell modulating antibodies for renal autoimmune disease. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36104663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9472190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-022-07722-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedognetti D, Zoppoli G, Massucco C, Zanardi E, Zupo S, Bruzzone A, et al. Impaired response to influenza vaccine associated with persistent memory B cell depletion in non-Hodgkin&#x2019;s lymphoma patients treated with rituximab-containing regimens. J Immunol. 2011;186(10):6044&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21498665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3530046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.1004095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornek B, Leutmezer F, Rommer PS, Koblischke M, Schneider L, Haslacher H, et al. B cell depletion and SARS-CoV-2 vaccine responses in neuroimmunologic patients. Ann Neurol. 2022;91(3):342&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35067959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9011809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone JH, Khosroshahi A, Zhang W, Della Torre E, Okazaki K, Tanaka Y, et al. Inebilizumab for treatment of IgG4-related disease. N Engl J Med. 2025;392(12):1168&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39541094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2409712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikse J, Jonsdottir K, Kvaloy JT, Wildhagen K, Omdal R. Tolerability and safety of long-term rituximab treatment in systemic inflammatory and autoimmune diseases. Rheumatol Int. 2019;39(6):1083&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30923955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-019-04272-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varley CD, Winthrop KL. Long-term safety of rituximab (risks of viral and opportunistic infections). Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2021;23(9):74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34269903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8284038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11926-021-01037-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gron KL, Glintborg B, Norgaard M, Mehnert F, Ostergaard M, Dreyer L, et al. Overall infection risk in rheumatoid arthritis during treatment with abatacept, rituximab and tocilizumab; an observational cohort study. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2020;59(8):1949&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31764977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kez530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu SY, Vostiar I, Karki S, Moore GL, Lazar GA, Pong E, et al. Inhibition of B cell receptor-mediated activation of primary human B cells by coengagement of CD19 and FcgammaRIIb with Fc-engineered antibodies. Mol Immunol. 2008;45(15):3926&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18691763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molimm.2008.06.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Gao M, Matijevic M, Quinn S, Yamashita M, Arora S, et al. Pharmacokinetics, receptor occupancy, and pharmacodynamics of obexelimab following intravenous administration in adult healthy volunteers and in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Clin Pharmacol Drug Dev. 2025;14(9):656&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40512061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpdd.1557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton HM, Chu SY, Ortiz EC, Pong E, Cemerski S, Leung IW, et al. Antibody-mediated coengagement of FcgammaRIIb and B cell receptor complex suppresses humoral immunity in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Immunol. 2011;186(7):4223&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21357255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.1003412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abeles I, Palma C, Meednu N, Payne AS, Looney RJ, Anolik JH. B cell-directed therapy in autoimmunity. Annu Rev Immunol. 2024;42(1):103&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38011889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-immunol-083122-044829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perugino CA, Wallace ZS, Zack DJ, Quinn SM, Poma A, Fernandes AD, et al. Evaluation of the safety, efficacy, and mechanism of action of obexelimab for the treatment of patients with IgG4-related disease: an open-label, single-arm, single centre, phase 2 pilot trial. Lancet Rheumatol. 2023;5(8):e442&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38251576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(23)00157-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Kirk R, Matijevic M, Gao M, Poma A, Quinn S, et al. Pharmacokinetics, pharmacodynamics, bioavailability, and immunogenicity of obexelimab following subcutaneous administration in healthy Japanese and non-Japanese volunteers. Adv Ther. 2025;42(2):813&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39636565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-024-03067-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu SY, Pong E, Bonzon C, Yu N, Jacob CO, Chalmers SA, et al. Inhibition of B cell activation following in vivo co-engagement of B cell antigen receptor and Fcgamma receptor IIb in non-autoimmune-prone and SLE-prone mice. J Transl Autoimmun. 2021;4:100075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33409482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtauto.2020.100075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szili D, Cserhalmi M, Banko Z, Nagy G, Szymkowski DE, Sarmay G. Suppression of innate and adaptive B cell activation pathways by antibody coengagement of FcgammaRIIb and CD19. MAbs. 2014;6(4):991&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24828435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4171032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/mabs.28841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrill JT, Guthridge J, Smith M, June J, Koumpouras F, Machua W, et al. Obexelimab in systemic lupus erythematosus with exploration of response based on gene pathway co-expression patterns: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Arthritis Rheum. 2023;75(12):2185&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.42652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone JH, McDowell PJ, Jayne DRW, Merkel PA, Robson J, Patel NJ, et al. The glucocorticoid toxicity index: measuring change in glucocorticoid toxicity over time. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2022;55:152010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35486995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2022.152010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers MN, Stone JH, Deshpande V, Khosroshahi A. Development of an IgG4-RD Responder Index. Int J Rheumatol. 2012;2012:259408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22611406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3348627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/259408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, Khosroshahi A, Carruthers MD, Perugino CA, Choi H, Campochiaro C, et al. An international multispecialty validation study of the IgG4-related disease Responder Index. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2018;70(11):1671&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29457382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6098740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.23543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ZS, McMahon GA, Hang B, Fu X, Harkness T, Donelan K, et al. Assessment of patient-reported symptoms and distress in IgG4-related disease (IgG4-RD): development, clinical validation, and content validation of the IgG4-RD Symptom Severity Index. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2023;63:152253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37619485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11004491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2023.152253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittner B, Richter W, Schmidt J. Subcutaneous administration of biotherapeutics: an overview of current challenges and opportunities. BioDrugs. 2018;32(5):425&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6182494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40259-018-0295-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bittner B, Schmidt J. Clinical development of subcutaneous dosing alternatives to established intravenous formulations for monoclonal antibodies&#x2014;pharmacokinetic-based bridging approach. In: Bittner B, Schmidt J, editors. Formulation and device lifecycle management of biotherapeutics. New York: Academic Press; 2022. p. 47&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-823741-0.00002-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller C, Adler M. Switching from an IV to an SC formulation&#x2014;considerations for formulation development and formulation bridging. In: Warne NW, Mahler H-C, editors. Challenges in protein product development. AAPS advances in the pharmaceutical sciences series. Cham: Springer; 2018. p. 579&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efe O, Sauvage G, Jeyabalan A, Al Jurdi A, Seethapathy HS, Cosgrove K, et al. Persistent B cell depletion after rituximab for autoimmune and glomerular diseases: a case series. Kidney Int Rep. 2025;10(5):1441&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40485690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12142800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ekir.2025.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starvaggi Cucuzza C, Longinetti E, Ruffin N, Evertsson B, Kockum I, Jagodic M, et al. Sustained low relapse rate with highly variable B-cell repopulation dynamics with extended rituximab dosing intervals in multiple sclerosis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2023;10(1):e200056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36411076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000200056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>