<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41600099</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2223-7747</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Plants (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Plants (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Simulation and Parameter Optimization of Inserting-Extracting-Transporting Process of a Seedling Picking End Effector Using Two Fingers and Four Needles Based on EDEM-MFBD.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">291</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/plants15020291</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This paper aims to address the problem of the low success rate of seedling picking and throwing, and the high damage rate of pot seedling, caused by the unclear interaction and parameter mismatch between the seedling picking end effector and the pot seedling during the seedling picking and throwing process of automatic transplanters. An EDEM-RecurDyn coupled simulation was conducted, through which the disturbance of substrate particles in the bowl body during the inserting, extracting, and transporting processes by the seedling picking end effector was visualized and analyzed. The force and motion responses of the particles during their interaction with the seedling picking end effector were explored, and the working parameters of the seedling picking end effector were optimized. A seedling picking end effector using two fingers and four needles is taken as the research object, a kinematic mathematical model of the seedling picking end effector is established, and the dimensional parameters of each component of the end effector are determined. Physical characteristic tests are conducted on Shanghai bok choy pot seedlings to obtain relevant parameters. A discrete element model of the pot seedling is established in EDEM 2022 software, and a virtual prototype model of the seedling picking end effector is established in Recurdyn 2024 software. Through EDEM-Recurdyn coupled simulation, the force and movement of the substrate particles in the bowl body during the inserting, extracting, and transporting processes of the seedling picking end effector under different operating parameters were explored, providing a theoretical basis for optimizing the working parameters of the end effector. The inserting and extracting velocity, transporting velocity, and inserting depth of the seedling picking end effector were used as experimental factors, and the success rate of seedling picking and throwing, and the loss rate of substrate, were used as evaluation indicators; single-factor tests and three-factor, three-level Box-Behnken bench tests were conducted. Variance analysis, response surface methodology, and multi-objective optimization were performed using Design-Expert 13 software to obtain the optimal parameter combination: when the inserting and extracting velocity was 228 mm/s, the transporting velocity was 264 mm/s, the inserting depth was 37 mm, the success rate of seedling picking and throwing was 97.48%, and the loss rate of substrate was 2.12%. A verification experiment was conducted on the bench, and the success rate of seedling picking and throwing was 97.35%, and the loss rate of substrate was 2.34%, which was largely consistent with the optimized results, thereby confirming the rationality of the established model and optimized parameters. Field trial showed the success rate of seedling picking and throwing was 97.04%, and the loss rate of substrate was 2.41%. The error between the success rate of seedling picking and throwing and the optimized result was 0.45%, indicating that the seedling picking end effector has strong anti-interference ability, and verifying the feasibility and practicality of the established model and optimized parameters.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Jiawei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Provincial Key Laboratory of Hi-Tech Research for Intelligent Agricultural Equipment, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang 212013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Jianping</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Provincial Key Laboratory of Hi-Tech Research for Intelligent Agricultural Equipment, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang 212013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Provincial Key Laboratory of Hi-Tech Research for Intelligent Agricultural Equipment, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang 212013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Mengjiao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Provincial Key Laboratory of Hi-Tech Research for Intelligent Agricultural Equipment, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang 212013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Jinhao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Provincial Key Laboratory of Hi-Tech Research for Intelligent Agricultural Equipment, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang 212013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Pengcheng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Provincial Key Laboratory of Hi-Tech Research for Intelligent Agricultural Equipment, Jiangsu University, Zhenjiang 212013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZYYD2024QY03</GrantID><Agency>2024 Central Government Guiding Local Science and Technology Development Fund Project (ZYYD2024QY03)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NJ2024-04</GrantID><Agency>Jiangsu Province Modern Agricultural Machinery Equipment and Technology Demonstration and Promotion Project, Research and Application of Key Technologies and Equipment for High-Efficiency Automatic Transplanting of Open-Field Cabbage (NJ2024-04)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 52505263</GrantID><Agency>Project supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No. 52505263)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. BK20240882</GrantID><Agency>the Natural Science Foundation of Jiangsu Province (Grants No. BK20240882).</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Plants (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596181</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2223-7747</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Box&#x2013;Behnken test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EDEM-MFBD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">automatic transplanter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">parameter optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seedling picki/ng end effector</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41600099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12844707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants15020291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">plants15020291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jin X., Liu J., Chen Z., Xu Z., Ji J. Precision control system of rice potting and transplanting machine based on GA-Fuzzy PID controller. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2024;220:108912. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2024.108912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2024.108912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G., Wang S., Zhang A., Xiao Y., Li L., Yin Y., Li H., Wen C., Yan B. Optimized design and experiment of a self-covering furrow opener for an automatic sweet potato seedling transplanting machine. Sustainability. 2023;15:13091. doi: 10.3390/su151713091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151713091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miah M.S., Rahman M.M., Hoque M.A., Ibrahim S.M., Sultan M., Shamshiri R.R., Ucgul M., Hasan M., Barna T.N. Design and evaluation of a power tiller vegetable seedling transplanter with dibbler and furrow type. Heliyon. 2023;9:e17827. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e17827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10392037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37533994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M., Shan Y., Xue X., Yin D. Theoretical analysis and development of a mechanism with punching device for transplanting potted vegetable seedlings. Int. J. Agric. Biol. Eng. 2020;13:85&#x2013;92. doi: 10.25165/j.ijabe.20201304.5404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25165/j.ijabe.20201304.5404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Periasamy V., Gounder D.V.M., Ramasamy K. Factors influencing the performance of mechanical end effector during automatic transplanting of tomato seedlings. J. Appl. Nat. Sci. 2022;14:227&#x2013;231. doi: 10.31018/jans.v14iSI.3613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31018/jans.v14iSI.3613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X., Zhou M., Chen X., Yang J. Processing method of gearbox with non-circular gear train and its application in rice potted seedling transplanting mechanism. Agriculture. 2022;12:1676. doi: 10.3390/agriculture12101676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture12101676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L., Mo M., Ma H., Kumi F., Mao H. Design and test of a lateral-approaching and horizontal-pushing transplanting manipulator for greenhouse seedlings. Appl. Eng. Agric. 2023;39:325&#x2013;338. doi: 10.13031/aea.15420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13031/aea.15420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A., Khar S. Design and development of a vegetable plug seedling transplanting mechanism for a semi-automatic transplanter. Sci. Hortic. 2024;326:112773. doi: 10.1016/j.scienta.2023.112773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2023.112773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadatkar A., Mathur S. Design and development of an automatic vegetable transplanter using a novel rotating finger device with push-type mechanism for plug seedlings. Int. J. Veg. Sci. 2022;28:121&#x2013;131. doi: 10.1080/19315260.2020.1848962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19315260.2020.1848962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L., Mo M., Gao Y., Ma H., Xiang D., Ma G., Mao H. Effects of new compounds into substrates on seedling qualities for efficient transplanting. Agronomy. 2022;12:983. doi: 10.3390/agronomy12050983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy12050983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J., Wang Z., Zhou M., Wu L., Zhang Y. Optimized design and experiment of the three-arm transplanting mechanism for rice potted seedlings. Int. J. Agric. Biol. Eng. 2021;14:56&#x2013;62. doi: 10.25165/j.ijabe.20211405.6844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25165/j.ijabe.20211405.6844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao S., Liu J., Jin Y., Bai Z., Liu J., Zhou X. Design and testing of an intelligent multi-functional seedling transplanting system. Agronomy. 2022;12:2683. doi: 10.3390/agronomy12112683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy12112683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y., Liu J., Xu Z., Yuan S., Li P., Wang J. Development status and trend of agricultural robot technology. Int. J. Agric. Biol. Eng. 2021;14:1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.25165/j.ijabe.20211404.6821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25165/j.ijabe.20211404.6821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaohong Y., Lei W., Liang S., Xiong Z., Bingliang Y. Advancement of mechanized transplanting technology and equipments for field crops. Nongye Jixie Xuebao/Trans. Chin. Soc. Agric. Mach. 2022;53:1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M., Wei Z., Wang Z., Sun H., Wang G., Yin J. Design and experimental investigation of a transplanting mechanism for super rice pot seedlings. Agriculture. 2023;13:1920. doi: 10.3390/agriculture13101920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture13101920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M.N., Iqbal M.Z., Ali M., Chowdhury M., Kabir M.S.N., Park T., Kim Y.-J., Chung S.-O. Kinematic analysis of a clamp-type picking device for an automatic pepper transplanter. Agriculture. 2020;10:627. doi: 10.3390/agriculture10120627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture10120627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi W.C., Kim D.C., Ryu I.H., Kim K.U. Development of a seedling pick&#x2013;up device for vegetable transplanters. Trans. ASAE. 2002;45:13&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N., Zhang G., Fu J., Liu W., Chen L., Tang N. Design and experiment of the seedling pick-up device with ejecting pot-clamping stem combination. Trans. Chin. Soc. Agr. Eng. (Trans. CSAE) 2024;40:50&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji D., Hu X., Zhe X.-R., Bai X.-H., Gong Y.-J., Tian S.-B. Design and Experiment of Double Row Transplanting Manipulator Linkage High Speed Transplanting Device. Trans. Chin. Soc. Agric. Mach. 2022;53:126&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Liu L., Ning Y., Kong D., Liu Y., Wu H. Design and experiment of end effector of seedling taking by jacking and clampling of vegetable transplanter. Trans. Chin. Soc. Agric. Mach. 2023;54:115&#x2013;124,134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X., Yun Z., Jin X., Li P., Gao K. Design and experiment of automatic adjustable transplanting end-effector based on double-cam. Agriculture. 2023;13:987. doi: 10.3390/agriculture13050987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture13050987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yongjie C., Yongzhe W., Xinting D., Gongpei C., Zhi H., Minghui W. Design and Experiment of Adjustable Spacing End-effector Based on Cylindrical Cam. Nongye Jixie Xuebao/Trans. Chin. Soc. Agric. Mach. 2022;53:104&#x2013;114+122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianping H., Jie P., Fan C., Rencai Y., Mengjiao Y., Jing L. Simulation Optimization and Experiment of Finger-clamping Seedling Picking Claw Based on EDEM-RecurDyn. Nongye Jixie Xuebao/Trans. Chin. Soc. Agric. Mach. 2022;53:75&#x2013;85+301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Q., Zuo Z., Zheng Q., Fu Y., Zhang S., Mao H. Optimization and Experimental Study of a Soil Loosening and Root Lifting Device for Shanghai Green (Brassica rapa subsp. chinensis) Harvesting Based on an EDEM-RecurDyn Simulation. Agriculture. 2025;15:1865. doi: 10.3390/agriculture15171865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture15171865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Sun W., Yang X., Zhao M., Simionescu P.A. Analytical Design and Test of Licorice Harvester Based on DEM&#x2013;MBD Coupling. Agronomy. 2024;14:2651. doi: 10.3390/agronomy14112651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14112651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue R., Yao M., Zhang T., Shi J., Zhou J., Hu J. Design and experiment of dual-row seedling pick-up device for high-speed automatic transplanting machine. Agriculture. 2024;14:942. doi: 10.3390/agriculture14060942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14060942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai F., Wang F., Guo W., Shi R., Xin S., Liu X., Zhao W. Simulation and test on the operation process of an intermittent film-picking component on full-film mulched double ditches. Int. J. Agric. Biol. Eng. 2024;17:99&#x2013;108. doi: 10.25165/j.ijabe.20241701.8348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25165/j.ijabe.20241701.8348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X., Zhao G., Li M., Li S., Zhou L., Liang J., Xie X., Hou B. Optimization of transplanting mechanism working parameters based on a coupled machine-soil-pot seedling model. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2025;238:110786. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2025.110786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2025.110786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma F., Wang L., Wang C., Wang Q., Lu C. Study on Impact Soil Movement Experiments on Wheat Seeds Based on EDEM. Agriculture. 2025;15:400. doi: 10.3390/agriculture15040400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture15040400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Sun X., Li H., Fu J., Zeng X., Xu Y., Wang Y., Liu H., L&#xfc; Z. Design and parameter optimization of a finger clip plate garlic seed-metering device based on EDEM. Agronomy. 2022;12:1543. doi: 10.3390/agronomy12071543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy12071543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Li H., Cao W., Yu S., Li S. Optimization and experiment of working parameters of automatic seedling picking device for tomato seedlings transplanting. Trans. Chin. Soc. Agric. Eng. 2020;36:46&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X., Zong W., Wei X. DEM-MBD coupling-based analysis and experiment on loss reduction mechanisms of rapeseed pickup header in hilly and mountainous areas. Comput. Electron. Agric. 2025;238:110817. doi: 10.1016/j.compag.2025.110817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compag.2025.110817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B., Ni X., Cai W., Li K. The Simulation and Parameter Optimization of the Hole-Forming Process of a Duckbilled Hole-Forming Device. Agriculture. 2024;14:843. doi: 10.3390/agriculture14060843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture14060843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng G., Qi B., Zhang W., Shao W., Zhang L., Wang Y., Ding Y. Engineering discrete element method-based design and optimization of the key components of a spoon-wheel spinach seed-metering device. Agronomy. 2024;14:2096. doi: 10.3390/agronomy14092096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14092096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>