<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41646331</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2693-5015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research square</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Sq</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Multifractal-Guided Machine Learning Framework for Late Post-Traumatic Seizure Prediction Following Hemorrhagic Traumatic Brain Injury.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">rs.3.rs-8613721</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.21203/rs.3.rs-8613721/v1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Traumatic brain injury can lead to post-traumatic epilepsy, yet early, reliable biomarkers to predict its emergence remain elusive. By investigating the multifractal characteristics of electroencephalogramrecordings from the first available day post-injury, we develop for the first time a machine learning framework that distinguishes between traumatic brain injury patients who develop late post-traumatic seizures and those who do not. Statistical analysis demonstrates statistically significant differences in multifractal properties of EEG signals between patients who develop late post-traumatic seizures and patients who do not. We show that random forest classifier trained on multi-fractal properties of EEG achieve a high predictive accuracy (95%) and area under the curve (98%) for predicting late PTS. The predictive power of multifractal features was robust to sample length and electrode selection. Our findings indicate that multifractal properties of EEG offers a promising, objective approach to early risk stratification for post-traumatic epilepsy in neurocritical care settings.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riabukhina</LastName><ForeName>Daria</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ming Hsieh Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA 90031, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kriukova</LastName><ForeName>Kseniia</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vespa</LastName><ForeName>Paul M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain Research Institute, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blanco</LastName><ForeName>Manuel B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain Research Institute, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogdan</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ming Hsieh Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA 90031, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duncan</LastName><ForeName>Dominique</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 19104, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pereira</LastName><ForeName>Emily A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX 79409, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Res Sq</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101768035</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2693-5015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there are no competing interests. Additional Declarations: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41646331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12869568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-8613721/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">rs.3.rs-8613721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sosin D. M., Sniezek J. E. &amp; Thurman D. J. Incidence of mild and moderate brain injury in the United States, 1991. Brain Inj. 10, 47&#x2013;54 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8680392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas A. I., Marmarou A., Murray G. D., Teasdale S. G. M. &amp; Steyerberg E. W. Prognosis and clinical trial design in traumatic brain injury: the IMPACT study. J. Neurotrauma 24, 232&#x2013;238 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17375987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas A. I., Stocchetti N. &amp; Bullock R. Moderate and severe traumatic brain injury in adults. The Lancet Neurol. 7, 728&#x2013;741 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18635021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas A. I. et al. Traumatic brain injury: progress and challenges in prevention, clinical care, and research. The Lancet Neurol. 21, 1004&#x2013;1060 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10427240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36183712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewan M. C. et al. Estimating the global incidence of traumatic brain injury. J. Neurosurg. 130, 1080&#x2013;1097 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29701556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar A. M. et al. Epilepsy after penetrating head injury. I. clinical correlates: a report of the Vietnam Head Injury Study. Neurology 35, 1406&#x2013;1406 (1985).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3929158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annegers J. F. &amp; Coan S. P. The risks of epilepsy after traumatic brain injury. Seizure 9, 453&#x2013;457 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11034867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pease M. et al. Risk factors and incidence of epilepsy after severe traumatic brain injury. Annals neurology 92, 663&#x2013;669 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennett B. Epilepsy after non-missile head injuries. Scott. Med. J. 18, 8&#x2013;13 (1973).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4197932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennett B. Early traumatic epilepsy: incidence and significance after nonmissile injuries. Arch. Neurol. 30, 394&#x2013;398 (1974).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4207011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haltiner A. M., Temkin N. R. &amp; Dikmen S. S. Risk of seizure recurrence after the first late posttraumatic seizure. Arch. Phys. Medicine Rehabil. 78, 835&#x2013;840 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verellen R. M. &amp; Cavazos J. E. Post-traumatic epilepsy: an overview. Therapy 7, 527&#x2013;531 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3992621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24761136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher R. S. et al. ILAE official report: a practical clinical definition of epilepsy. Epilepsia 55, 475&#x2013;482 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24730690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pease M. et al. Insights into epileptogenesis from post-traumatic epilepsy. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 20, 298&#x2013;312 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12257072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38570704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annegers J. F., Hauser W. A., Coan S. P. &amp; Rocca W. A. A population-based study of seizures after traumatic brain injuries. New Engl. J. Medicine 338, 20&#x2013;24 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymont V. et al. Correlates of posttraumatic epilepsy 35 years following combat brain injury. Neurology 75, 224&#x2013;229 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2906177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20644150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke J. et al. Association of posttraumatic epilepsy with 1-year outcomes after traumatic brain injury. JAMA Netw. Open 4, e2140191&#x2013;e2140191 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8717106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34964854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kryukova K. et al. Early predictive biomarkers of posttraumatic epilepsy. Zhurnal Voprosy Neirokhirurgii Imeni NN Burdenko 85, 110&#x2013;115 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pease M. et al. Predicting posttraumatic epilepsy using admission electroencephalography after severe traumatic brain injury. Epilepsia 64, 1842&#x2013;1852 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11293840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37073101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyrzowski J., Ka&#x142;as M., Mazurkiewicz-Be&#x142;dzi&#x144;ska M. &amp; Siemi&#x144;ski M. EEG biomarkers for the prediction of posttraumatic epilepsy-a systematic review of an emerging field. Seizure: Eur. J. Epilepsy 119, 71&#x2013;77 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruckhaus A. A. et al. Exploring multimodal biomarker candidates of post-traumatic epilepsy following moderate to severe traumatic brain injury: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Epilepsia 66, 6&#x2013;32 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39530841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gans F., Schumann A. Y., Kantelhardt J. W., Penzel T. &amp; Fietze I. Cross-modulated amplitudes and frequencies characterize interacting components in complex systems. Phys. Rev. Lett. 102, 098701 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19392568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed E. A., Ramos G., Bogdan P. &amp; Pequito S. The role of long-term power-law memory in controlling large-scale dynamical networks. Sci. Reports 13, 19502 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdan P. Taming the unknown unknowns in complex systems: challenges and opportunities for modeling, analysis and control of complex (biological) collectives. Front. Physiol. 10, 1452 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6903773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau Z. J., Pham T., Chen S. A. &amp; Makowski D. Brain entropy, fractal dimensions and predictability: A review of complexity measures for EEG in healthy and neuropsychiatric populations. Eur. J. Neurosci. 56, 5047&#x2013;5069 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9826422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35985344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorick T. &amp; Mandelkern M. A. Multifractal detrended fluctuation analysis of human EEG: preliminary investigation and comparison with the wavelet transform modulus maxima technique. PLoS ONE 8, e68360 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3700954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23844189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krapf D. et al. Spectral content of a single non-brownian trajectory. Phys. Rev. X 9, 011019 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercier M. et al. The value of linear and non-linear quantitative EEG analysis in paediatric epilepsy surgery: a machine learning approach. Sci. Reports 14, 10887 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardstone R. et al. Detrended fluctuation analysis: a scale-free view on neuronal oscillations. Front. Physiol. 3, 450 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3510427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23226132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shlesinger M. F., Zaslavsky G. M. &amp; Klafter J. Strange kinetics. Nature 363, 31&#x2013;37 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stam C. J. Nonlinear dynamical analysis of EEG and MEG: review of an emerging field. Clin. Neurophysiol. 116, 2266&#x2013;2301 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16115797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X. &amp; Chen Y. Remarks on fractional order control systems. In 2012 American Control Conference (ACC), 5169&#x2013;5173 (IEEE, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed E. A., Chatterjee S., Ramos G., Bogdan P. &amp; Pequito S. Fractional cyber-neural systems &#x2014; a brief survey. Annu. Rev. Control. 54, 386&#x2013;408 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fran&#xe7;a L. G. S. et al. Fractal and multifractal properties of electrographic recordings of human brain activity: toward its use as a signal feature for machine learning in clinical applications. Front. Physiol. 9, 1767 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6295567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Kriukova K., Engel J. &amp; Bragin A. Seizure development in the acute intrahippocampal epileptic focus. Sci. Reports 8, 1423 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stam C. J. &amp; de Bruin E. A. Scale-free dynamics of global functional connectivity in the human brain. Hum. Brain Mapp. 22, 97&#x2013;109 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6871799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15108297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraiman D. &amp; Chialvo D. R. What kind of noise is brain noise: anomalous scaling behavior of the resting brain activity fluctuations. Front. Physiol. 3, 307 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3429078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22934058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandelbrot B. B. The Fractal Geometry of Nature (Freeman, New York, 1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley H. E. Scaling, universality, and renormalization: Three pillars of modern critical phenomena. Rev. Mod. Phys. 71, S358&#x2013;S366 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihlen E. A. F. Introduction to multifractal detrended fluctuation analysis in MATLAB. Front. Physiol. 3, 141 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3366552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22675302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta S., Ghosh D., Samanta S. &amp; Dey S. Multifractal parameters as an indication of different physiological and pathological states of the human brain. Phys. A: Stat. Mech. its Appl. 396, 155&#x2013;163 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantelhardt J. W. et al. Multifractal detrended fluctuation analysis of nonstationary time series. Phys. A: Stat. Mech. its Appl. 316, 87&#x2013;114 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikdar D., Roy R. &amp; Mahadevappa M. Epilepsy and seizure characterisation by multifractal analysis of EEG subbands. Biomed. Signal Process. Control. 41, 264&#x2013;270 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vespa P. M. et al. The epilepsy bioinformatics study for anti-epileptogenic therapy (EpiBioS4Rx) clinical biomarker: Study design and protocol. Neurobiol. Dis. 123, 110&#x2013;114 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6344322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oostenveld R., Fries P., Maris E. &amp; Schoffelen J.-M. Fieldtrip: Open source software for advanced analysis of MEG, EEG, and invasive electrophysiological data. Comput. Intell. Neurosci. 2011, 1&#x2013;9 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3151498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21837235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorme A. &amp; Makeig S. EEGLAB: an open source toolbox for analysis of single-trial EEG dynamics including independent component analysis. J. Neurosci. Methods 134, 9&#x2013;21 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosanne D. A. &amp; Vourvopoulos A. EEG amplitude modulation analysis across mental tasks: Towards improved active bcis. MDPI Sensors 23, 9352 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahmiri S. Generalized Hurst exponent estimates differentiate EEG signals of healthy and epileptic patients. Phys. A: Stat. Mech. its Appl. 490, 378&#x2013;385 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Ashourvan A., Ramos G., Bogdan P. &amp; Pereira E. A. Stabilizing fractional dynamical networks suppresses epileptic seizures. arXiv preprint arXiv:2511.20950 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Li J., Xia Y., Feng P. &amp; Feng F. Variation trends of fractal dimension in epileptic EEG signals. MDPI Algorithms 14, 316 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee S., Pratiher S. &amp; Bose R. Multifractal detrended fluctuation analysis based novel feature extraction technique for automated detection of focal and non-focal electroencephalogram signals. IET Sci. Meas. &amp; Technol. 11, 1014&#x2013;1021 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas C.-G., Abry P., Wendt H. &amp; Didier G. Epileptic seizure prediction from eigen-wavelet multivariate self-similarity analysis of multi-channel EEG signals. In 2023 31st European Signal Processing Conference, 970&#x2013;974 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T. et al. Multi-dimensional feature extraction of EEG signal and its application in stroke classification. Sci. Reports 15 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorick T., Gaines K. D., Berenji G. R., Mandelkern M. A. &amp; Smith J. Information transfer and multifractal analysis of EEG in mild blast-induced TBI. Comput. Math. Methods Medicine 2021, 1&#x2013;8 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tubi M. A. et al. Early seizures and temporal lobe trauma predict post-traumatic epilepsy: A longitudinal study. Neurobiol. Dis. 123, 115&#x2013;121 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6274611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29859872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laing J. et al. Risk factors and prognosis of early posttraumatic seizures in moderate to severe traumatic brain injury. JAMA Neurol. 79, 334&#x2013;341 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8861899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35188950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorshkov O. &amp; Ombao H. Assessment of fractal synchronization during an epileptic seizure. MDPI Entropy 26, 666 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fordington S. &amp; Manford M. A review of seizures and epilepsy following traumatic brain injury. J. Neurol. 267, 3105&#x2013;3111 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7501105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32444981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu T., Liu X., Sun L., Wu J. &amp; Wang Q. Clinical characteristics of post-traumatic epilepsy and the factors affecting the latency of PTE. BMC Neurol. 21, 301 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8340486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34348691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bragin A. et al. Pathologic electrographic changes after experimental traumatic brain injury. Epilepsia 57, 735&#x2013;745 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5081251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27012461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L. et al. Spatial and temporal profile of high-frequency oscillations in posttraumatic epileptogenesis. Neurobiol. Dis. 161, 105544 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9075674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34742877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. A. et al. Epileptiform activity in traumatic brain injury predicts post-traumatic epilepsy. Annals Neurol. 83, 858&#x2013;862 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englander J. et al. Analyzing risk factors for late posttraumatic seizures: A prospective, multicenter investigation. Arch. Phys. Medicine Rehabil. 84, 365&#x2013;373 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal A., Timothy J., Pandit L. &amp; Manju M. Post-traumatic epilepsy: An overview. Clin. Neurol. Neurosurg. 108, 433&#x2013;439 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16225987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta P. K. et al. Subtypes of post-traumatic epilepsy: Clinical, electrophysiological, and imaging features. J. Neurotrauma 31, 1439&#x2013;1443 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4132580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24693960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olejarczyk E., Gotman J. &amp; Frauscher B. Region-specific complexity of the intracranial EEG in the sleeping human brain. Sci. Reports 12, 451 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zappasodi F., Marzetti L., Olejarczyk E., Tecchio F. &amp; Pizzella V. Age-related changes in electroencephalographic signal complexity. PLoS ONE 10, e0141995 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26536036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S., Kumar A., Gombar S., Trikha A. &amp; Anand S. Fractal dimension of electroencephalogram for assessment of hypnosis state of patient during anaesthesia. Int. J. Biomed. Eng. Technol. 10, 30&#x2013;37 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schartner M. et al. Complexity of multi-dimensional spontaneous EEG decreases during propofol induced general anaesthesia. PLoS ONE 10, e0133532 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4529106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26252378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>