<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41403198</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1738-3684</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychiatry investigation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychiatry Investig</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predicting Treatment Response in Female Adolescents With Non-Suicidal Self-Injury Using Neurophysiological Biomarkers and Machine Learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>63</StartPage><EndPage>70</EndPage><MedlinePgn>63-70</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.30773/pi.2025.0256</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study investigated whether quantitative electroencephalography (qEEG) features, combined with clinical data, could predict treatment outcomes in female adolescents with non-suicidal self-injury (NSSI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We analyzed clinical and EEG data from 104 female adolescent inpatients with repetitive NSSI. Resting-state EEG was recorded, and various brain activity patterns across frequency bands were extracted. Clinical outcomes were assessed using pre- and postadmission scores on the Health of the Nation Outcome Scales (HoNOS), Clinical Global Impression-Severity (CGI-S), World Health Organization Disability Assessment Schedule (WHODAS), and Global Assessment of Functioning (GAF). Machine learning models were trained to predict outcomes using EEG and medication data. Model performance was evaluated using cross-validation, and feature importance was interpreted using SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All predictive models demonstrated excellent predictive performance (R2&#x2265;0.96, mean squared error [MSE] as low as 0.02). The HoNOS model showed the highest performance (R2=0.99, MSE=0.32), followed by the WHODAS (R2=0.98, MSE=1.32), GAF (R2=0.97, MSE=0.76), and CGI-S (R2=0.96, MSE=0.02) models. Key qEEG predictors included relative low-beta power at Pz, absolute theta power at Fp1, and the delta-to-beta ratio at Cz. Pre-admission clinical severity, particularly CGI-S and HoNOS, also significantly contributed to prediction accuracy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that qEEG features, combined with machine learning, can effectively predict treatment response in adolescents with NSSI, supporting their use as neurophysiological biomarkers for individualized care.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Seng Yoon</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Daegu Catholic University School of Medicine, Daegu, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jun Won</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Daegu Catholic University School of Medicine, Daegu, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Daegu Catholic University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Psychiatry Investig</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101242994</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1738-3684</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-suicidal self-injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quantitative electroencephalography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment prediction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>Conflicts of Interest</b>
. The authors have no potential conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41403198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12835630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30773/pi.2025.0256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pi.2025.0256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nock MK, Favazza AR. In: Understanding nonsuicidal self-injury: origins, assessment, and treatment. Nock MK, editor. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association; 2009. Nonsuicidal self-injury: definition and classification; pp. 9&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YJ, Li X, Ng CH, Xu DW, Hu S, Yuan TF. Risk factors for non-suicidal self-injury (NSSI) in adolescents: a meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2022;46:101350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35330803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriano A, Cella S, Cotrufo P. Nonsuicidal self-injury: a systematic review. Front Psychol. 2017;8:1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5682335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29167651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor PJ, Jomar K, Dhingra K, Forrester R, Shahmalak U, Dickson JM. A meta-analysis of the prevalence of different functions of non-suicidal self-injury. J Affect Disord. 2018;227:759&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29689691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HO. The effect of adolescent health behavior on the prevalence of allergic diseases based on the 15th (2019) Korea Youth Risk Behavior Web-Based Survey. J Korean Soc Sch Health. 2020;33:125&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammerman BA, Lengel GJ, Washburn JJ. Consideration of clinician and researcher opinions on the parameters of nonsuicidal self-injury disorder diagnostic criteria. Psychiatry Res. 2021;296:113642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brager-Larsen A, Zeiner P, Mehlum L. DSM-5 non-suicidal self-injury disorder in a clinical sample of adolescents with recurrent self-harm behavior. Arch Suicide Res. 2024;28:523&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37506259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan H, Yue W. Risk factors, theoretical models, and biological mechanisms of nonsuicidal self-injury: a brief review. Interdiscip Nurs Res. 2023;2:112&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10461723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37645376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SY, Park YM, Park EJ. Non-suicidal self-injury and quantified electroencephalogram in adolescents and young adults with depression. Clin Psychopharmacol Neurosci. 2024;22:151&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38247421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iznak AF, Iznak EV, Damyanovich EV, Oleichik IV. Differences of EEG frequency and spatial parameters in depressive female adolescents with suicidal attempts and non-suicidal self-injuries. Clin EEG Neurosci. 2021;52:406&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Wen Y, Liang X, Xu Y, Qiao D, Yang C, et al. Prefrontal cortex neural activity predicts reduction of non-suicidal self-injury in adolescents with major depressive disorder: an event related potential study. Front Neurosci. 2022;16:972870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9671107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36408379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparrow-Downes VM, Trincao-Batra S, Cloutier P, Helleman AR, Salamatmanesh M, Gardner W, et al. Peripheral and neural correlates of self-harm in children and adolescents: a scoping review. BMC Psychiatry. 2022;22:318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9066835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35509053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pion-Tonachini L, Kreutz-Delgado K, Makeig S. ICLabel: an automated electroencephalographic independent component classifier, dataset, and website. Neuroimage. 2019;198:181&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6592775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gramfort A, Luessi M, Larson E, Engemann DA, Strohmeier D, Brodbeck C, et al. MEG and EEG data analysis with MNE-Python. Front Neurosci. 2013;7:267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3872725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24431986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MX. Assessing transient cross-frequency coupling in EEG data. J Neurosci Methods. 2008;168:494&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18061683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combrisson E, Nest T, Brovelli A, Ince RAA, Soto JLP, Guillot A, et al. Tensorpac: an open-source Python toolbox for tensor-based phase-amplitude coupling measurement in electrophysiological brain signals. PLoS Comput Biol. 2020;16:e1008302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33119593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James M, Painter J, Buckingham B, Stewart MW. A review and update of the Health of the Nation Outcome Scales (HoNOS) BJPsych Bull. 2018;42:63&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29502543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang CY, Voort JLV, Yuruk D, Mills JA, Emslie GJ, Kennard BD, et al. A characterization of the Clinical Global Impression Scale thresholds in the treatment of adolescent depression across multiple rating scales. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2022;32:278&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9353998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35704877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;st&#xfc;n TB. Measuring health and disability: manual for WHO disability assessment schedule WHODAS 2.0. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aas IH. Guidelines for rating Global Assessment of Functioning (GAF) Ann Gen Psychiatry. 2011;10:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3036670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21251305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Guestrin C. XGBoost: a scalable tree boosting system. Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining; 2016 Aug 13&#x2013;17; San Francisco, CA, USA. New York: ACM; 2016. pp. 785&#x2013;794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM, Lee SI. A unified approach to interpreting model predictions. In: Guyon I, Luxburg UV, Bengio S, Wallach H, Fergus R, Vishwanathan S, et al., editors. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 30 (NeurIPS 2017); 2017 Dec 4&#x2013;9; Long Beach, CA. Curran Associates, Inc.; 2017. pp. 4765&#x2013;4774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knyazev GG. Motivation, emotion, and their inhibitory control mirrored in brain oscillations. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2007;31:377&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi Y, Huang Y, Wei Y, Wei X, Zou Z, Pan L, et al. Absence of differences in resting-state EEG spectral power and cognitive impairments between first-episode, drug-na&#xef;ve MDD patients with and without suicidal ideation. J Psychiatr Res. 2025;191:95&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40976159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Str&#xfc;ber D, Herrmann CS. Modulation of gamma oscillations as a possible therapeutic tool for neuropsychiatric diseases: a review and perspective. Int J Psychophysiol. 2020;152:15&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Q, Xiao M, Ai M, Chen J, Wang W, Hu L, et al. Disruption of neural activity and functional connectivity in adolescents with major depressive disorder who engage in non-suicidal self-injury: a resting-state fMRI study. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:571532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8203805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott CH, Zisk A, Bounoua N, Diamond GS, Kobak R. Predicting patterns of treatment response and outcome for adolescents who are suicidal and depressed. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2019;58:897&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30877051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhiala P, Marttunen M, Gergov V, Torppa M, Ranta K. Predictors of outcome after a time-limited psychosocial intervention for adolescent depression. Front Psychol. 2022;13:955261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9667940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36405121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moloney F, Amini J, Sinyor M, Schaffer A, Lanct&#xf4;t K, Mitchell RHB. Research review: sex differences in the clinical correlates of nonsuicidal self-injury in adolescents - a systematic review. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2025;66:1263&#x2013;1273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12267678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39825677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lurigio AJ, Nesi D, Meyers SM. Nonsuicidal self injury among young adults and adolescents: historical, cultural and clinical understandings. Soc Work Ment Health. 2024;22:122&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>