<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41345209</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reliability-oriented framework for UAV-based inspection missions in modern power and energy systems.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>958</StartPage><MedlinePgn>958</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">958</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-30410-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ensuring mission reliability is vital for the autonomous deployment of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) in modern power and energy systems, particularly under spatial and operational constraints. This study presents a data-driven classification method that assesses the reliability of UAV-based inspection missions by identifying whether individual mission locations are suitable, at risk, or infeasible based on spatial and operational parameters. Leveraging the Cumulative UAV Routing Problem (CUAVRP) benchmark, four representative mission scenarios were analyzed, each characterized by unique UAV fleet sizes, sensor ranges, and endurance limits. Synthetic stress nodes were introduced to emulate edge-case conditions encountered in infrastructure inspection tasks. Each node was classified based on three categorical targets: Mission Feasibility, Coverage Reliability, and Deployment Suitability. A gradient boosting classification model was trained on spatial and operational features to determine node status. Evaluation across all scenarios yielded consistently high performance, with the cuavrp_d9_k6_r800 scenario achieving 97.05% accuracy, 96.33% precision, 97.72% recall, and 97.02% F1-score. Furthermore, incorporating physical-layer degradation factors such as signal attenuation, multipath fading, and interference is expected to enhance the realism of future reliability assessments and improve classification robustness. The proposed classification framework supports intelligent mission planning, enhances operational resilience, and facilitates automated UAV deployment strategies in critical inspection environments within the power and energy sector.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Haddad</LastName><ForeName>Luttfi A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical Engineering, University of Technology- Iraq, Baghdad, Iraq. Luttfi.a.alhaddad@uotechnology.edu.iq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalid</LastName><ForeName>Wissam</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical Engineering, University of Technology- Iraq, Baghdad, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tariq</LastName><ForeName>Sarmad Ziyad</ForeName><Initials>SZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical Engineering, University of Technology- Iraq, Baghdad, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mrah</LastName><ForeName>Muhannad M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical Engineering, University of Technology- Iraq, Baghdad, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flah</LastName><ForeName>Aymen</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering, University of Business and Technology (UBT) Jeddah, 21448, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. aymen.flah@vsb.cz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Applied Science Research Center, Applied Science Private University, Amman, 11931, Jordan. aymen.flah@vsb.cz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENET Centre, CEET, VSB-Technical University of Ostrava, Ostrava, Czech Republic. aymen.flah@vsb.cz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tazay</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Electrical Engineering Department, College of Engineering, Al-Baha University, Al Baha, Saudi Arabia. afareed@bu.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaber</LastName><ForeName>Alaa Abdulhady</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanical Engineering, University of Technology- Iraq, Baghdad, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CUAVRP dataset</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Catboost</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Communication reliability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mission planning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UAV</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41345209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12783628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-30410-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-30410-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ishiwatari, M. Leveraging drones for effective disaster management: A comprehensive analysis of the 2024 Noto Peninsula earthquake case in Japan. <i>Progress Disaster Sci.</i><b>23</b>, 100348 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pdisas.2024.100348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Kasm, O., Raymer, M. &amp; Diabat, A. A drone-assisted last-mile delivery framework for shipment prioritization in post-disaster and high demand periods. <i>Appl. Math. Model.</i><b>146</b>, 116175 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apm.2025.116175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafa, S. A. et al. A YOLO-based deep learning model for Real-Time face mask detection via drone surveillance in public spaces. <i>Inf. Sci.</i><b>676</b>, 120865 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ins.2024.120865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollet, F., Budinger, M., Delbecq, S., Moschetta, J.-M. &amp; Liscou&#xeb;t, J. Quantifying and mitigating uncertainties in design optimization including off-the-shelf components: Application to an electric multirotor UAV. <i>Aerosp. Sci. Technol.</i><b>136</b>, 108179 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ast.2023.108179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, A., Liang, X., Zhang, J., Hou, Y. &amp; Wang, N. Distributed time-varying optimization with coupled constraints: Application in UAV swarm predefined-time cooperative consensus. <i>Aerosp. Sci. Technol.</i><b>147</b>, 109034 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ast.2024.109034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karbach, N., Bobrowski, N. &amp; Hoffmann, T. Observing volcanoes with drones: Studies of volcanic plume chemistry with ultralight sensor systems. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>12</b>, 17890 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-21935-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9596470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36284218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, W. &amp; Yang, Z. Strengthening the connection and monitoring of dead zones: Implementing drone-based monitoring images using 6G IoT and deep learning. <i>Wirel Pers. Commun.</i>10.1007/s11277-024-11228-7 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11277-024-11228-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazurally, A. &amp; Chuttur, Y. M. Data Acquisition Framework for Drone-Based Research: The Case of Erosion Monitoring in Mauritius. In <i>Intelligent Computing and Automation</i> (eds Bhateja, V. et al.) 11&#x2013;23 (Singapore, Springer Nature Singapore, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar, P. &amp; Chowdhury, S. IoT and Drone-Based Field Monitoring and Surveillance System. In <i>Artificial Intelligence Techniques in Smart Agriculture</i> (eds Chouhan, S. S. et al.) 253&#x2013;266 (Singapore, Springer Nature Singapore, 2024). 10.1007/978-981-97-5878-4_15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y., Li, Y., Cheng, J., Li, C. &amp; Hu, S. Two-stage hierarchical 4D low-risk trajectory planning for urban air logistics. <i>Drones</i><b>9</b>, 267 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones9040267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pamula, G. &amp; Ramachandran, A. Thermal management for unmanned aerial vehicle payloads: Mechanisms, systems, and applications. <i>Drones</i><b>9</b>, 350 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones9050350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassolillo, S. R. et al. Bridging ACO-based drone logistics and computing continuum for enhanced smart city applications. <i>Drones</i><b>9</b>, 368 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones9050368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazir, M. F., Atif, S. &amp; Hussain, E. An integrated geographic information system (GIS) and analytical hierarchy process (AHP)-based approach for drone-optimized large-scale flood imaging. <i>Drone Syst. Appl.</i><b>13</b>, 1&#x2013;18 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/dsa-2024-0039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemzadeh, F. &amp; Kumbasar, T. Swarm of drones for surveillance monitoring of a grounded target: An event-triggered approach. <i>Drone Syst. Appl.</i><b>12</b>, 1&#x2013;16 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/dsa-2023-0107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharrad, H., Yasar, A.U.-H. &amp; Ectors, W. Simulating collaborative and autonomous persistent surveillance by drones for search and rescue operations. <i>Transp. Res. Procedia</i><b>84</b>, 209&#x2013;218 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trpro.2025.03.065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahar, F. S., Sultan, M. T. H., Nowakowski, M. &amp; &#x141;ukaszewicz, A. UGV-UAV integration advancements for coordinated missions: A review. <i>J. Intell. Robot. Syst.</i><b>111</b>, 69 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10846-025-02273-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booysen, R. et al. Detection of REEs with lightweight UAV-based hyperspectral imaging. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>10</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-74422-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7562707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, H., Biocca, F., Lee, T., Park, K. &amp; Rhee, J. Effects of human connection through social drones and perceived safety. <i>Adv. Human Comput. Interact.</i><b>2018</b>, 9280581 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/9280581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z., Mineshita, H. &amp; Lim, H. Development of a voice information presentation guidance system (VIPGS) using coanda-drone-V2. <i>IEEJ Trans. Electr. Electron. Eng.</i><b>20</b>, 862&#x2013;875 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tee.24248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C., Niu, H., Shen, G. &amp; Li, Y. Self-healing hydrogel-based triboelectric nanogenerator in smart glove system for integrated drone safety protection and motion control. <i>Adv. Funct. Mater.</i><b>35</b>, 2419809 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202419809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, W., Yang, H. &amp; Xiong, Z. Resource allocation for UAV-assisted anti-jamming semantic D2D networks: A graph reinforcement learning approach. <i>Comput. Netw.</i><b>269</b>, 111463 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.comnet.2025.111463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaggero, G. B., Marchese, M., Moheddine, A. &amp; Patrone, F. A possible smart metering system evolution for rural and remote areas employing unmanned aerial vehicles and internet of things in smart grids. <i>Sensors</i><b>21</b>, 1627 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21051627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7956395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33652571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. et al. Energy consumption and efficiency degradation predictive analysis in unmanned aerial vehicle batteries using deep neural networks. <i>Adv. Sci. Technol. Res. J.</i><b>19</b>, 21&#x2013;30 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12913/22998624/201346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. et al. Protocol for UAV fault diagnosis using signal processing and machine learning. <i>STAR Protoc.</i><b>5</b>, 103351 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xpro.2024.103351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11480223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39356637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaber, A. A. &amp; Al-Haddad, L. A. Integration of discrete wavelet and fast fourier transforms for quadcopter fault diagnosis. <i>Exp. Tech.</i>10.1007/s40799-024-00702-3 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40799-024-00702-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. et al. Quadcopter unmanned aerial vehicle structural design using an integrated approach of topology optimization and additive manufacturing. <i>Designs</i><b>8</b>, 58 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/designs8030058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adaika, Z. et al. Fault detection and diagnosis methodologies for unmanned aerial vehicles: State-of-the-art. <i>J. Intell. Robot. Syst.</i><b>111</b>, 63 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10846-025-02267-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Khafaji, A. J. D. &amp; Al-Haddad, L. A. Parametric aerodynamic characterization of tail geometry variations in fixed-wing UAVs. <i>Aerosp. Syst.</i>10.1007/s42401-025-00406-5 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42401-025-00406-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein, R. M. et al. Hybrid integral sliding mode and fuzzy logic control for omnidirectional robots: Modified elephant herding optimization for trajectory tracking. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 35666 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-19449-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12518826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41083499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadi, A. S. &amp; Al-Haddad, L. A. Towards fault diagnosis interpretability: Gradient boosting framework for vibration-based detection of experimental gear failures. <i>J. Dyn. Monit. Diagn.</i><b>4</b>, 160&#x2013;169 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamandi, S. J., Al-Haddad, L. A., Shaaban, S. M. &amp; Flah, A. Child behavior recognition in social robot interaction using stacked deep neural networks and biomechanical signals. <i>Sci Rep</i><b>15</b>, 35995 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-19728-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12528455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41093966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibraheem, L. et al. Enhancing energy yield in horizontal axis wind turbines via optimized tip speed ratio and intelligent power regulation techniques. <i>Terra Joule J.</i><b>1</b>, 6 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsalman, A. et al. Potential of renewable energy resource in middle east-challenges and solutions, case study of Basra (Iraq). <i>Terra Joule J.</i><b>1</b>, 1 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousaf, M. Z., Khalid, S., Tahir, M. F., Tzes, A. &amp; Raza, A. A novel dc fault protection scheme based on intelligent network for meshed dc grids. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>154</b>, 109423 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2023.109423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousaf, M. Z., Tahir, M. F., Raza, A., Khan, M. A. &amp; Badshah, F. Intelligent sensors for DC fault location scheme based on optimized intelligent architecture for HVdc systems. <i>Sensors</i><b>22</b>, 9936 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22249936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9780844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36560301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousaf, M. Z., Liu, H., Raza, A. &amp; Mustafa, A. Deep learning-based robust DC fault protection scheme for meshed HVDC grids. <i>CSEE J. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>9</b>, 2423&#x2013;2434 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, S., Sami, A., Thasin, A. &amp; Saad, R. M. A. AI-enabled ant-routing protocol to secure communication in flying networks. <i>Appl. Comput. Intell. Soft Comput.</i><b>2022</b>, 3330168 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arishi, A., Krishnan, K. &amp; Arishi, M. Machine learning approach for truck-drones based last-mile delivery in the era of industry 4.0. <i>Eng. Appl. Artif. Intell.</i><b>116</b>, 105439 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engappai.2022.105439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong, J., Jia, X. &amp; Yang, Z. Towards routing in low-altitude drone networks: A physical sensing-aided intelligent forwarding mechanism with deep learning. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i>10.1109/JIOT.2025.3560142 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2025.3560142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najim, A. H., Abbas, A. H., Al-sharhanee, K. &amp; Hariz, H. M. Reinforcement Learning-based Topology-Aware Routing Protocol with Priority Scheduling for Internet of Drones in Agriculture Application. <i>International J. Intell. Eng. Syst.</i><b>16</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behjati, M., Zulkifley, M. A., Alobaidy, H. A. H., Nordin, R. &amp; Abdullah, N. F. Reliable aerial mobile communications with RSRP &amp; RSRQ prediction models for the internet of drones: A machine learning approach. <i>Sensors</i><b>22</b>, 5522 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22155522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9331756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35898026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerber, C., Royer, M. &amp; Larrieu, N. Machine learning and software defined network to secure communications in a swarm of drones. <i>J. Inf. Secur. Appl.</i><b>61</b>, 102940 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan, L. et al. Machine learning-based field data analysis and modeling for drone communications. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>7</b>, 79127&#x2013;79135 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2922544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klaine, P. V., Nadas, J. P. B., Souza, R. D. &amp; Imran, M. A. Distributed drone base station positioning for emergency cellular networks using reinforcement learning. <i>Cognit. Comput.</i><b>10</b>, 790&#x2013;804 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12559-018-9559-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6182572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil, H. et al. A UAV-swarm-communication model using a machine-learning approach for search-and-rescue applications. <i>Drones</i><b>6</b>, 372 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/drones6120372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Learning to routing in UAV swarm network: A multi-agent reinforcement learning approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol.</i><b>72</b>, 6611&#x2013;6624 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TVT.2022.3232815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyriakakis, N. A., Stamadianos, T., Marinaki, M. &amp; Marinakis, Y. Dataset for the cumulative unmanned aerial vehicle routing problem. <i>Data Brief</i><b>48</b>, 109296 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dib.2023.109296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10294095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37383775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alawee, W. H. et al. Forecasting sustainable water production in convex tubular solar stills using gradient boosting analysis. <i>Desalin. Water Treat.</i><b>318</b>, 100344 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dwt.2024.100344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shijer, S. S., Jassim, A. H., Al-Haddad, L. A. &amp; Abbas, T. T. Evaluating electrical power yield of photovoltaic solar cells with k-nearest neighbors: A machine learning statistical analysis approach. <i>e-Prime Adv. Electr. Eng. Electron. Energy</i><b>9</b>, 100674 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prime.2024.100674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. et al. Enhancing building sustainability through aerodynamic shading devices: an integrated design methodology using finite element analysis and optimized neural networks. <i>Asian J. Civ. Eng.</i>10.1007/s42107-024-01047-3 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42107-024-01047-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. et al. UAV propeller fault diagnosis using deep learning of non-traditional &#x3c7;2-selected Taguchi method-tested Lempel-Ziv complexity and Teager-Kaiser energy features. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 18599 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-69462-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11316750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39127843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. &amp; Jaber, A. Applications of machine learning techniques for fault diagnosis of UAVs. <i>CEUR Workshop Proc.</i><b>3360</b>, 19&#x2013;25 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadi Fadhil, T., Al-Karkhi, M. I. &amp; Al-Haddad, L. A. Legal and communication challenges in smart grid cybersecurity classification of network resilience under cyber attacks using machine learning. <i>J. Commun.</i><b>20</b>, 221&#x2013;228 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12720/jcm.20.2.221-228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, Z. H., Mekid, S., Al-Haddad, L. A. &amp; Jaber, A. A. AI Enabled Manufacturing: A Deep Learning Approach to Network Fault Detection. In <i>Proc. of 2025 4th International Conference on Computing and Information Technology, ICCIT 2025</i> 245&#x2013;250 (2025). 10.1109/ICCIT63348.2025.10989388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunyan, S. T. et al. Intelligent thermal condition monitoring for predictive maintenance of gas turbines using machine learning. <i>Machines</i><b>13</b>, 401 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/machines13050401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdul-Zahra, A. S., Ghane, E., Kamali, A. &amp; Farhan Ogaili, A. A. Power forecasting in continuous extrusion of pure titanium using Na&#xef;ve Bayes algorithm. <i>Terra Joule J.</i><b>1</b>, 2 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. et al. Advancing sustainability in buildings using an integrated aerodynamic fa&#xe7;ade: Potential of artificial intelligence. <i>Terra Joule J.</i><b>1</b>, 1 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Karkhi, M. I., Rzadkowski, G., Ibraheem, L. &amp; Aqib, M. Anomaly detection in electrical systems using machine learning and statistical analysis. <i>Terra Joule J.</i><b>1</b>, 3 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A., Fattah, M. Y., Al-Soudani, W. H. S., Al-Haddad, S. A. &amp; Jaber, A. A. Enhanced load-settlement curve forecasts for open-ended pipe piles incorporating soil plug constraints using shallow and deep neural networks. <i>China Ocean Eng.</i><b>39</b>, 562&#x2013;572 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13344-025-0041-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shams, O. A., Al-Baity, H. B. M. &amp; Al-Haddad, L. A. Experimental investigation and laser control in Ti10Mo6Cu powder bed fusion: optimizing process parameters with machine learning. <i>Discov. Mater.</i><b>5</b>, 125 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43939-025-00322-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, V. N., Jenssen, R. &amp; Roverso, D. Automatic autonomous vision-based power line inspection: A review of current status and the potential role of deep learning. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>99</b>, 107&#x2013;120 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2017.12.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, J. et al. A fault detection method for transmission line components based on synthetic dataset and improved YOLOv5. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>157</b>, 109852 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2024.109852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza, B. J., Stefenon, S. F., Singh, G. &amp; Freire, R. Z. Hybrid-YOLO for classification of insulators defects in transmission lines based on UAV. <i>Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst.</i><b>148</b>, 108982 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2023.108982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulaiman, M. H., Mustaffa, Z., Samsudin, A. S., Mohamed, A. I. &amp; Saari, M. M. Electric vehicle battery state of charge estimation using metaheuristic-optimized CatBoost algorithms. <i>Franklin Open</i><b>11</b>, 100293 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fraope.2025.100293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, W., Hou, P., Liang, X., Gao, F. &amp; Liu, Q. An interpretable rockburst prediction model based on SSA-CatBoost. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>164</b>, 106820 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2025.106820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Wang, T., Qiu, J. &amp; Feng, J. Mission planning on autonomous avoidance for spacecraft confronting orbital debris. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i><b>61</b>, 4115&#x2013;4126 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2024.3496415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Qiu, J., Wang, T. &amp; Li, M. Onboard mission planning for autonomous avoidance of spacecraft subject to various orbital threats: An SMT-based approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i><b>61</b>, 4866&#x2013;4878 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2024.3508665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Qiu, J., Wang, T. &amp; Li, M. Autonomous avoidance mission planning for spacecrafts confronting orbital threats with flexible durations and resource demands. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i>10.1109/TAES.2025.3602944 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2025.3602944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X., Qiu, J., Zhou, Y., Wang, T. &amp; Li, M. Temporal mission planning of autonomous avoidance for spacecraft confronting orbital threats: An interval-based heuristic approach. <i>IEEE Trans. Aerosp. Electron. Syst.</i>10.1109/TAES.2025.3610569 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TAES.2025.3610569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Haddad, L. A. et al. Multiaxial vibration data for blade fault diagnosis in multirotor unmanned aerial vehicles. <i>Sci. Data</i><b>12</b>, 1383 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-025-05692-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12331888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40774972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>