<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41828096</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on Applicability of Energy-Saving Conductors in Alpine Regions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">828</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19050828</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The development of energy-efficient conductors capable of operating reliably in harsh, cold climates is crucial for sustainable power infrastructure. High-mountain and cold regions are key research scenarios for energy-saving conductors, enabling the natural enhancement of conductor heat dissipation in low-temperature environments and improving the current carrying capacity and energy efficiency. These regions are rich in renewable energy and urgently need efficient transmission channels. However, the extremely complex working conditions create strict requirements for the thermal-mechanical coupling performance of conductors, and existing research has paid insufficient attention to this. This study evaluates the thermal and mechanical performance of three advanced energy-saving conductors (JLHA3-275, JL1/G1A-240/30, JL/LHA1-135/140) in comparison with a conventional conductor (JL/G1A-240/30) under cold-region operating conditions. A finite element analysis model, validated against theoretical calculations under combined meteorological factors, was employed to simulate radial temperature fields and stress distribution. The results demonstrate that the JLHA3 conductor exhibits superior heat dissipation and minimal resistive losses, maintaining a radial temperature of -23.35 &#xb0;C under a 700 A load, approximately 1.6 &#xb0;C lower than the conventional type. Its temperature further decreases significantly with increased wind speeds. Thermally, JLHA3 shows high stability across a broad temperature range (-28.85 &#xb0;C to 29.03 &#xb0;C). Mechanically, it displays uniform stress distribution and a notable decrease in stress from 79.53 MPa to 39.46 MPa with rising temperatures, indicating excellent flexibility and thermal adaptability. These findings confirm that the JLHA3 conductor offers an optimal combination of thermal performance, structural reliability, and energy efficiency for high-altitude, cold-region power transmission applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>E</LastName><ForeName>Wenqi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Northeast Electric Power University, Jilin 132012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Haodong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huizhou Boluo Power Supply Bureau of Guangdong Power Grid Co., Ltd., Huizhou 516100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Cong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1426-3939</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Northeast Electric Power University, Jilin 132012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>JJKH20230140KJ</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project of the Jilin Provincial Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cold environment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy-saving conductors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">finite element model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transmission efficiency</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Haodong Liu was employed by the Huizhou Boluo Power Supply Bureau of Guangdong Power Grid Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41828096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12985838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19050828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19050828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xie D., Wang C., Li J., Xie S. The application status and development trends of overhead transmission line conductors. J. Chongqing Univ. 2025;48:50&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bend&#xed;k J., Cenk&#xfd; M., Eleschova &#x17d;., Bel&#xe1;&#x148; A., Cintula B. Influence of Different Weather Conditions on the Maximum Load Current of Overhead Power Lines; Proceedings of the 2018 19th International Scientific Conference on Electric Power Engineering (EPE); Brno, Czech Republic. 16&#x2013;18 May 2018; pp. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad A., Jin Y., Zhu C., Javed I., Akram M.W. Investigating Tension in Overhead High Voltage Power Transmission Line Using Finite Element Method. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 2020;114:105418. doi: 10.1016/j.ijepes.2019.105418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2019.105418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Yang M., Han X. Optimal Power Flow Considering Transient Thermal Behavior of Overhead Transmission Lines. Int. J. Electr. Power Energy Syst. 2020;114:105396. doi: 10.1016/j.ijepes.2019.105396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijepes.2019.105396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chawasak R., Sermsak U. Power System State and Transmission Line Conductor Temperature Estimation. IEEE Trans. Power Syst. 2017;32:1818&#x2013;1827. doi: 10.1109/TPWRS.2016.2601072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRS.2016.2601072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X., Zhu S., Qin S., Zhan X., Zhu L. Analysis of Temperature Rise Characteristics and Current Carrying Capacity of Overhead Conductor; Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE Conference on Electrical Insulation and Dielectric Phenomena (CEIDP); Denver, CO, USA. 30 October&#x2013;2 November 2022; pp. 123&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C., Zheng L., Tian C., Yang W. Numerical Calculation on Conductor Temperature Field of 66 kV Overhead Transmission Lines. Jilin Electr. Power. 2007;35:5&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1009-5306.2007.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1009-5306.2007.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z., Zhu C. Numerical Study on Flow Field and Temperature Field of Overhead High Voltage Line Based on Fluid Solid Coupling Analysis. J. Electr. Power. 2020;35:302&#x2013;312. doi: 10.13357/j.dlxb.2020.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13357/j.dlxb.2020.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Be&#x148;a &#x13d;., G&#xe1;ll V., Kan&#xe1;lik M., Kolcun M., Margitov&#xe1; A., M&#xe9;sz&#xe1;ros A., Urbansk&#xfd; J. Calculation of the Overhead Transmission Line Conductor Temperature in Real Operating Conditions. Electr. Eng. 2021;103:769&#x2013;780. doi: 10.1007/s00202-020-01107-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00202-020-01107-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frigerio M., Buehlmann P.B., Buchheim J., Holdsworth S.R., Dinser S., Franck C.M., Papailiou K., Mazza E. Analysis of the Tensile Response of a Stranded Conductor Using a 3D Finite Element Model. Int. J. Mech. Sci. 2016;106:176&#x2013;183. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2015.12.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2015.12.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alawar A., Bosze E.J., Nutt S.R. A Composite Core Conductor for Low Sag at High Temperatures. IEEE Trans. Power Deliv. 2005;20:2193&#x2013;2199. doi: 10.1109/TPWRD.2005.848736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TPWRD.2005.848736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Jia S., Wu P., Du D., He Q. Calculation and Analysis of Ampacity and Stress of Overhead Transmission Line. AIP Adv. 2022;12:105209. doi: 10.1063/5.0110688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0110688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Z., Jiang Y. Calculation of Electric Field and Temperature of Overhead Transmission Lines with Covered Conductors; Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE 8th International Conference on Computer Science and Network Technology (ICCSNT); Dalian, China. 20&#x2013;22 November 2020; pp. 50&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Liao C., Dai Y., Du B., Li Q., Dai M. Displacement and Stress Analysis of 10 kV Iced Overhead Lines Based on Finite Element Method; Proceedings of the 2022 IEEE International Conference on High Voltage Engineering and Applications (ICHVE); Chongqing, China. 25&#x2013;29 September 2022; pp. 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nechitaev R., Khalyasmaa A. A New Approach to Evaluating Energy Efficiency and Energy Saving for Overhead Power Transmission Lines; Proceedings of the 2021 XVIII International Scientific Technical Conference Alternating Current Electric Drives (ACED); Ekaterinburg, Russia. 10&#x2013;13 May 2021; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Liu H., Jiang D., Xie Y., Wei X., Jin Y. The Comparison of Conductor Stress Calculation Methods for Overhead Line under Extreme Weather Conditions; Proceedings of the 2013 IEEE PES Asia-Pacific Power and Energy Engineering Conference (APPEEC); Hong Kong, China. 8&#x2013;11 December 2013; pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard for Round Wire Concentric Lay Overhead Electrical Stranded Conductors. Standards Press of China; Beijing, China: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E W., Liu H., Zeng C., Wang D., Li Y., Lin Y. Finite element study on temperature stress of medium strength aluminum alloy wire in high cold area. J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 2024;2918:012010. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/2918/1/012010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/2918/1/012010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>