<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41688232</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-8952</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>184</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical neurophysiology : official journal of the International Federation of Clinical Neurophysiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical utility and prospective of TMS-EEG: Updated review from an international expert group.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2111487</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2111487</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.clinph.2025.2111487</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1388-2457(25)01339-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) is a non-invasive technique to stimulate the brain, while electroencephalography (EEG) is a non-invasive technique to record its electrical activity. Their combined use (TMS-EEG) has been established only relatively recently, after successful development of TMS-compatible EEG amplifiers. TMS-EEG offers the unparalleled opportunity to directly perturb the brain with TMS and simultaneously record its response with EEG. This allows inferences on causal input-output relationships, therefore going critically beyond purely observational techniques, such as resting-state EEG or functional MRI, in the study of brain dynamics. This consensus review updates the work of Tremblay and coworkers [Clin Neurophysiol 2019; 130: 802-844]. Since then, substantial advances have been made in understanding contamination of TMS-EEG signals by physiological and non-physiological artifacts, as well as in developing strategies to avoid or control them. In parallel, new insights have emerged regarding the physiological mechanisms underlying TMS-EEG responses and their diagnostic and prognostic utility in a broad range of psychiatric and neurological disorders. As such, TMS-EEG is rapidly shaping a dynamic new field in clinical neurophysiology and neuroscience. This review provides a critical and comprehensive synthesis of current knowledge, including practical guidance for implementing TMS-EEG in the clinical setting.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziemann</LastName><ForeName>Ulf</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology &amp; Stroke, University of T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany; Hertie Institute for Clinical Brain Research, University of T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany. Electronic address: ulf.ziemann@uni-tuebingen.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Disorders of Consciousness Rehabilitation, Affiliated Rehabilitation Hospital, Jiangxi Medical College, Nanchang University, Nanchang, Jiangxi, China; Rehabilitation Medicine Clinical Research Center of Jiangxi Province, Jiangxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baumer</LastName><ForeName>Fiona M</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA; Wu Tsai Neurosciences Institute, Stanford University, Stanford, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beck</LastName><ForeName>Mikkel M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Centre for Functional and Diagnostic Imaging and Research, Copenhagen University Hospital-Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belardinelli</LastName><ForeName>Paolo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hertie Institute for Clinical Brain Research, University of T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany; CiMeC, Center for Mind/Brain Sciences, University of Trento, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belvisi</LastName><ForeName>Daniele</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neurosciences, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy; IRCCS Neuromed, Pozzilli, IS, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bender</LastName><ForeName>Stephan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry, Medical Faculty and University Hospital, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergmann</LastName><ForeName>Til Ole</ForeName><Initials>TO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroimaging Center (NIC), Focus Program Translational Neuroscience (FTN), Johannes Gutenberg University Medical Center, Mainz, Germany; Leibniz Institute for Resilience Research (LIR), Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bortoletto</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Mind Laboratory, IMT School for Advanced Studies Lucca, Lucca, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casarotto</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, University of Milan, Milan, Italy; IRCCS Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi ONLUS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casula</LastName><ForeName>Elias</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of System Medicine, University of Tor Vergata, Rome, Italy; Experimental Neuropsychophysiology Laboratory, IRCCS Santa Lucia Foundation, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaves</LastName><ForeName>Arthur R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Royal's Institute of Mental Health Research, Ottawa, Canada; Interdisciplinary School of Health Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Andrade</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Ciampi</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Neuroplasticity and Pain, Department of Health Sciences and Technology, Faculty of Medicine, Aalborg University, Aalborg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conte</LastName><ForeName>Antonella</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neurosciences, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy; IRCCS Neuromed, Pozzilli, IS, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daskalakis</LastName><ForeName>Zafiris J</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of California San Diego, La Jolla, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farzan</LastName><ForeName>Faranak</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>eBrain Lab, School of Mechatronic Systems Engineering, Simon Fraser University, Surrey, British Columbia, Canada; University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada; Centre for Addiction and Mental Health, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrarelli</LastName><ForeName>Fabio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fitzgerald</LastName><ForeName>Paul B</ForeName><Initials>PB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine and Psychology, The Australian National University, Canberra, Australia; Monarch Research Institute, Monarch Mental Health Group, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gordon</LastName><ForeName>Pedro C</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology &amp; Stroke, University of T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany; Hertie Institute for Clinical Brain Research, University of T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grefkes</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Goethe University, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harquel</LastName><ForeName>Sylvain</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Univ. Grenoble Alpes, Univ. Savoie Mont Blanc, CNRS, LPNC, Grenoble, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hernandez-Pavon</LastName><ForeName>Julio C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological Sciences, Kansas State University, Manhattan, KS, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Aron T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Deakin University, Melbourne Burwood Campus, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoy</LastName><ForeName>Kate E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Bionics Institute, Fitzroy, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hummel</LastName><ForeName>Friedhelm C</ForeName><Initials>FC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Defitech Chair of Clinical Neuroengineering, Neuro-X Institute (INX), &#xc9;cole Polytechnique F&#xe9;d&#xe9;rale de Lausanne (EPFL), Geneva, Switzerland; Defitech Chair of Clinical Neuroengineering, INX, EPFL Valais, Clinique Romande de R&#xe9;adaptation, Sion, Switzerland; Clinical Neuroscience, University of Geneva Medical School, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Julkunen</LastName><ForeName>Petro</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Technical Physics, University of Eastern Finland, Kuopio, Finland; Department of Clinical Neurophysiology, Kuopio University Hospital, Kuopio, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kallioniemi</LastName><ForeName>Elisa</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, New Jersey Institute of Technology, Newark, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keller</LastName><ForeName>Corey J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wu Tsai Neurosciences Institute, Stanford University, Stanford, USA; Department of Psychiatry &amp; Behavioral Sciences, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, USA; Veterans Affairs Palo Alto Healthcare System, and the Sierra Pacific Mental Illness, Research, Education, and Clinical Center (MIRECC), Palo Alto, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimiskidis</LastName><ForeName>Vasilios K</ForeName><Initials>VK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Department of Neurology, AHEPA University Hospital, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Thessaloniki, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirkovski</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Deakin University, Melbourne Burwood Campus, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koch</LastName><ForeName>Giacomo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical and Behavioural Neurology, Santa Lucia Foundation IRCCS, Rome, Italy; Department of Neuroscience and Rehabilitation, University of Ferrara, and Center for Translational Neurophysiology of Speech and Communication (CTNSC), Italian Institute of Technology (IIT), Ferrara, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leodori</LastName><ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Neurosciences, Sapienza University of Rome, Rome, Italy; IRCCS Neuromed, Pozzilli, IS, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lioumis</LastName><ForeName>Pantelis</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Biomedical Engineering, Aalto University, Espoo, Finland; BioMag Laboratory, HUS Medical Imaging Center, University of Helsinki, Aalto University and Helsinki University Hospital, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4;</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurophysiology, Diagnostic Imaging Center, Kuopio University Hospital, Kuopio, Finland; Institute of Clinical Medicine, Clinical Neurophysiology, University of Eastern Finland, Kuopio, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maidan</LastName><ForeName>Inbal</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Early Markers of Neurodegeneration (LEMON), Neurological Institute, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel; Gray Faculty of Medical and Health Sciences , Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel; Sagol School of Neuroscience, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Massimini</LastName><ForeName>Marcello</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, University of Milan, Milan, Italy; IRCCS Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi ONLUS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mengel</LastName><ForeName>Annerose</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology &amp; Stroke, University of T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany; Hertie Institute for Clinical Brain Research, University of T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Metsomaa</LastName><ForeName>Johanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Biomedical Engineering, Aalto University, Espoo, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miniussi</LastName><ForeName>Carlo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CiMeC, Center for Mind/Brain Sciences, University of Trento, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mutanen</LastName><ForeName>Tuomas P</ForeName><Initials>TP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Biomedical Engineering, Aalto University, Espoo, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noda</LastName><ForeName>Yoshihiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropsychiatry, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan; Shinjuku-Yoyogi Mental Lab Clinic, Tokyo, Japan; Department of Psychiatry, International University of Health and Welfare, Mita Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozdemir</LastName><ForeName>Recep A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Berenson-Allen Center for Noninvasive Brain Stimulation, Department of Neurology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA; Department of Neurology, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raffin</LastName><ForeName>Estelle</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Univ. Grenoble Alpes, Univ. Savoie Mont Blanc, CNRS, LPNC, Grenoble, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocchi</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Sciences and Public Health, University of Cagliari, Cagliari, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rogasch</LastName><ForeName>Nigel C</ForeName><Initials>NC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychological Sciences and Turner Institute for Brain and Mental Health, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia; School of Biomedicine, University of Adelaide, Adelaide, Australia; Hopwood Centre for Neurobiology, Lifelong Health Theme, South Australian Health and Medical Research Institute (SAHMRI), Adelaide, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosanova</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santarnecchi</LastName><ForeName>Emiliano</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Berenson-Allen Center for Noninvasive Brain Stimulation, Department of Neurology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA; Precision Neuroscience &amp; Neuromodulation Program, Gordon Center for Medical Imaging, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarasso</LastName><ForeName>Simone</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schabrun</LastName><ForeName>Siobhan M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Gray Centre for Mobility and Activity, Parkwood Institute, St Joseph's Healthcare, London, Ontario, Canada; School of Physical Therapy, University of Western Ontario, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shafi</LastName><ForeName>Mouhsin M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Berenson-Allen Center for Noninvasive Brain Stimulation, Department of Neurology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA; Department of Neurology, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siebner</LastName><ForeName>Hartwig R</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Centre for Functional and Diagnostic Imaging and Research, Copenhagen University Hospital-Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Denmark; Department of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health and Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark; Department of Neurology, Copenhagen University Hospital Bispebjerg, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tolner</LastName><ForeName>Else A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Genetics, Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, the Netherlands; Department of Neurology, Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomasevic</LastName><ForeName>Leo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Centre for Functional and Diagnostic Imaging and Research, Copenhagen University Hospital-Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Denmark; Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany; Department of Human Sciences, Institute of Psychology, University of the Bundeswehr Munich, Neubiberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tremblay</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Royal's Institute of Mental Health Research, Ottawa, Canada; The University of Ottawa Brain and Mind Research Institute, Ottawa, Canada; D&#xe9;partement de psycho&#xe9;ducation et de psychologie, Universit&#xe9; du Qu&#xe9;bec en Outaouais, Gatineau, Canada; Department of Neuroscience, Carleton University, Ottawa, Canada; Department of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tscherpel</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Goethe University, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veniero</LastName><ForeName>Domenica</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, University of Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Versace</LastName><ForeName>Viviana</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurorehabilitation, Hospital of Vipiteno (SABES-ASDAA), Vipiteno-Sterzing, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Voineskos</LastName><ForeName>Daphne</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Temerty Centre for Therapeutic Brain Intervention, Centre for Addiction and Mental Health, Toronto, Canada; Department of Psychiatry, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada; Poul Hansen Family Centre for Depression, University Health Network, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vucic</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Nerve Research Centre, The University of Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zangen</LastName><ForeName>Abraham</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Life Science and the School of Brain Sciences and Cognition, Ben-Gurion University, Beer Sheba, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zrenner</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Temerty Centre for Therapeutic Brain Intervention, Centre for Addiction and Mental Health, Toronto, Canada; Department of Psychiatry, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada; Institute for Biomedical Engineering, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada; Institute of Medical Science, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilmoniemi</LastName><ForeName>Risto J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience and Biomedical Engineering, Aalto University, Espoo, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883319</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1388-2457</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050781" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cortical excitability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Effective connectivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TMS-EEG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial magnetic stimulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: SC: Advisor and shareholder of Intrinsic Powers, a spin-off of the University of Milan. DCdA: Investigator-initiated research supported by Pfizer, Allergan, Mundipharma, Abbot, Medtronic. ZJD: Brainsway: Scientific Advisory Board; Brainsway and MagVenture: research support. PBF: Reimbursement for educational activities from Otsuka Australia Pharmaceutical Pty Ltd and equipment for research from Brainsway Ltd. Founder of TMS Clinics Australia. PJ: Consulting for Nexstim Plc (Helsinki, Finland). EK: Consulting fees from Nexstim Inc. CJK: Equity holder in Alto Neuroscience, Inc. and Flow Neuroscience, Inc. GK: Scientific co-founder and advisor of Sinaptica Therapeutics Inc. received payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from: Epitech, Roche, Novo Nordisk. PL: Consultant for TMS-EEG to Sinaptica Ltd. and Nexstim Ltd. MM: Cofounder and shareholder of the spin-off Intrinsic Powers. TPM: Employed by Nexstim Plc. NCR: Received grant research funding from the Australian Research Council (ARC), and the Medical Research Future Fund (MRFF); contract research funding from the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation (CSIRO), and CMAX Clinical Research PTY LTD; consultancy fees from OVID Therapeutics Inc. MR: Shareholder and advisor of Intrinsic Powers Inc., Spin-off of the University of Milan. SS: Advisor of Intrinsic Powers, Inc., a spin-off of the University of Milan. HRS: Received honoraria as speaker and consultant from Lundbeck AS, Denmark, and as editor (Neuroimage Clinical) from Elsevier Publishers, Amsterdam, The Netherlands. Received royalties as book editor from Springer Publishers, Stuttgart, Germany, Oxford University Press, Oxford, UK, and from Gyldendal Publishers, Copenhagen, Denmark. AZ: Has invented TMS coils and systems, which are produced by BrainsWay LTD, and has financial interest in BrainsWay LTD. CZ: Minority equity ownership in sync2brain GmbH (Germany), a manufacturer of a real-time EEG analysis device for personalized TMS applications. RJI: Co-founder and minority owner of the company Cortisys. All other authors have declared to have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41688232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12991018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2025.2111487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1388-2457(25)01339-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Afra J., Mascia A., Gerard P., Maertens de Noordhout A., Schoenen J. Interictal cortical excitability in migraine: a study using transcranial magnetic stimulation of motor and visual cortices. Ann. Neurol. 1998;44(2):209&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9708543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn S., Fr&#xf6;hlich F. Pinging the brain with transcranial magnetic stimulation reveals cortical reactivity in time and space. Brain Stimul. 2021;14(2):304&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33516859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Chalabi A., Calvo A., Chio A., Colville S., Ellis C.M., Hardiman O., et al. Analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis as a multistep process: a population-based modelling study. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(11):1108&#x2013;1113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4197338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25300936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman N., Krzywinski M. The curse(s) of dimensionality. Nat. Methods. 2018;15(6):399&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29855577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alyagon U., Shahar H., Hadar A., Barnea-Ygael N., Lazarovits A., Shalev H., et al. Alleviation of ADHD symptoms by non-invasive right prefrontal stimulation is correlated with EEG activity. NeuroImage Clin. 2020;26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7021642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32062566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>APA. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (5th edition., text revision); 2022. Available from: https://ezproxy.deakin.edu.au/login?url=https://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=edspsy&amp;AN=edspsy.10.1176.appi.books.9780890425787&amp;site=eds-live&amp;scope=site.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arieli A., Sterkin A., Grinvald A., Aertsen A. Dynamics of ongoing activity: explanation of the large variability in evoked cortical responses. Science. 1996;273(5283):1868&#x2013;1871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8791593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artemenko A.R., Kurenkov A.L., Filatova E.G., Nikitin S.S., Kaube H., Katsarava Z. Effects of topiramate on migraine frequency and cortical excitability in patients with frequent migraine. Cephalalgia. 2008;28(3):203&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18254890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atluri S., Frehlich M., Mei Y., Garcia Dominguez L., Rogasch N.C., Wong W., et al. TMSEEG: A MATLAB-based graphical user interface for processing electrophysiological signals during transcranial magnetic stimulation. Front. Neural Circuits. 2016;10:78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5054290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27774054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attal N., Poindessous-Jazat F., De Chauvigny E., Quesada C., Mhalla A., Ayache S.S., et al. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for neuropathic pain: a randomized multicentre sham-controlled trial. Brain. 2021;144(11):3328&#x2013;3339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34196698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atti I., Belardinelli P., Ilmoniemi R.J., Metsomaa J. Measuring the accuracy of ICA-based artifact removal from TMS-evoked potentials. Brain Stimul. 2024;17(1):10&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11636693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38072355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avnit A., Zibman S., Alyagon U., Zangen A. Abnormal functional asymmetry and its behavioural correlates in adults with ADHD: A TMS-EEG study. PLoS One. 2023;18(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10212190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagattini C., Mutanen T.P., Fracassi C., Manenti R., Cotelli M., Ilmoniemi R.J., et al. Predicting Alzheimer's disease severity by means of TMS-EEG coregistration. Neurobiol. Aging. 2019;80:38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31077959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y., Belardinelli P., Thoennes C., Blum C., Baur D., Laichinger K., et al. Cortical reactivity to transcranial magnetic stimulation predicts risk of post-stroke delirium. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;148:97&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36526534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y., Gong A., Wang Q., Guo Y., Zhang Y., Feng Z. Breakdown of oscillatory effective networks in disorders of consciousness. CNS Neurosci. Ther. 2023;30(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10916448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37718541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y., Yang L., Meng X., Huang Y., Wang Q., Gong A., et al. Breakdown of effective information flow in disorders of consciousness: Insights from TMS-EEG. Brain Stimul. 2024;17:533&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38641169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Z., Zhang J.J., Fong K.N.K. Intracortical and intercortical networks in patients after stroke: a concurrent TMS-EEG study. J. Neuroeng. Rehabil. 2023;20(1):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10398934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37533093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Z., Zhu F., Lou X., Zhang J.J., Jin M., Qin W., et al. Considerable effects of lateralization and aging in intracortical excitation and inhibition. Front. Neurosci. 2023;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38033537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey N.W., Biabani M., Hill A.T., Miljevic A., Rogasch N.C., McQueen B., et al. Introducing RELAX: An automated pre-processing pipeline for cleaning EEG data - Part 1: Algorithm and application to oscillations. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;149:178&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36822997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey N.W., Hill A.T., Biabani M., Murphy O.W., Rogasch N.C., McQueen B., et al. RELAX part 2: A fully automated EEG data cleaning algorithm that is applicable to Event-Related-Potentials. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;149:202&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36822996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey N.W., Hoy K.E., Sullivan C.M., Allman B., Rogasch N.C., Daskalakis Z.J., et al. Concurrent transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalography measures are associated with antidepressant response from rTMS treatment for depression. J. Aff. Disorders Rep.rts. 2023;14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker A.M.E., Maffitt N.J., Del Vecchio A., McKeating K.M., Baker M.R., Baker S.N., et al. Neural dysregulation in post-COVID fatigue. Brain Commun. 2023;5(3) fcad122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10257363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37304792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker A.T., Shields K. Transcranial Magnetic stimulation: basic principles and clinical applications in migraine. Headache. 2017;57(3):517&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28028801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartos M., Vida I., Jonas P. Synaptic mechanisms of synchronized gamma oscillations in inhibitory interneuron networks. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2007;8(1):45&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17180162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barzan H., Ichim A.M., Moca V.V., Muresan R.C. Time-frequency representations of brain oscillations: which one is better? Front. Neuroinf. 2022;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9050353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35492077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashir S., Edwards D., Pascual-Leone A. Neuronavigation increases the physiologic and behavioral effects of low-frequency rTMS of primary motor cortex in healthy subjects. Brain Topogr. 2011;24(1):54&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3589808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21076861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashir S., Vernet M., Yoo W.K., Mizrahi I., Theoret H., Pascual-Leone A. Changes in cortical plasticity after mild traumatic brain injury. Restor. Neurol. Neurosci. 2012;30(4):277&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3951777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22596356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer P.R., Helling R.M., Perenboom M.J.L., Lopes da Silva F.H., Tolner E.A., Ferrari M.D., et al. Phase clustering in transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked EEG responses in genetic generalized epilepsy and migraine. Epilepsy &amp; Behav. : E&amp;B. 2019;93:102&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30875639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumer F.M., Pfeifer K., Fogarty A., Pena-Solorzano D., Rolle C.E., Wallace J.L., et al. Cortical excitability, synaptic plasticity, and cognition in benign epilepsy with centrotemporal spikes: a pilot TMS-EMG-EEG study. J. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2020;37(2):170&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9014862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaulieu L.D., Flamand V.H., Masse-Alarie H., Schneider C. Reliability and minimal detectable change of transcranial magnetic stimulation outcomes in healthy adults: a systematic review. Brain Stimul. 2017;10(2):196&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28031148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck M.M., Christiansen L., Madsen M.A.J., Jadidi A.F., Vinding M.C., Thielscher A., et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation of primary motor cortex elicits an immediate transcranial evoked potential. Brain Stimul. 2024;17(4):802&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38909748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck M.M., Heyl M., Mejer L., Vinding M.C., Christiansen L., Tomasevic L., et al. Methodological choices matter: a systematic comparison of TMS-EEG studies targeting the primary motor cortex. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2024;45(15)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11512442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39460649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belardinelli P., Biabani M., Blumberger D.M., Bortoletto M., Casarotto S., David O., et al. Reproducibility in TMS-EEG studies: A call for data sharing, standard procedures and effective experimental control. Brain Stimul. 2019;12(3):787&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30738777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belardinelli P., K&#xf6;nig F., Liang C., Premoli I., Desideri D., M&#xfc;ller-Dahlhaus F., et al. TMS-EEG signatures of glutamatergic neurotransmission in human cortex. Sci. Rep. 2021;11(1):8159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8047018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33854132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender S., Basseler K., Sebastian I., Resch F., Kammer T., Oelkers-Ax R., et al. Electroencephalographic response to transcranial magnetic stimulation in children: Evidence for giant inhibitory potentials. Ann. Neurol. 2005;58(1):58&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15984026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benecke R., Meyer B.U., Schonle P., Conrad B. Transcranial magnetic stimulation of the human brain: responses in muscles supplied by cranial nerves. Experim. Brain Res. Exp. Hirnforschung. 1988;71(3):623&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3416974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg P., Scherg M. Dipole models of eye movements and blinks. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1991;79(1):36&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1713550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann T.O. Brain state-dependent brain stimulation. Front. Psychol. 2018;9:2108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6221926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30443236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann T.O., M&#xf6;lle M., Schmidt M.A., Lindner C., Marshall L., Born J., et al. EEG-GUIDED TRANSCRANIAL MAGNETIC STIMULATION REVEALS RAPID SHIFTS IN MOTOR CORTICAL EXCITABILITY DURING THE HUMAN SLEEP SLOW OSCILLAtion. J. Neurosci. 2012;32(1):243&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6621327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann T.O., Tomasevic L., Siebner H.R. In: The Oxford Handbook of Transcranial Stimulation. 2nd ed: Wassermann E.M., Peterchev A.V., Ziemann U., Lisanby S.H., Siebner H.R., Walsh V., editors. Oxford University Press; 2021. Transcranial brain stimulation and EEG/MEG.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berman B.D., Horovitz S.G., Morel B., Hallett M. Neural correlates of blink suppression and the buildup of a natural bodily urge. Neuroimage. 2012;59(2):1441&#x2013;1450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3230735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21906689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertazzoli G., Dognini E., Fried P.J., Miniussi C., Julkunen P., Bortoletto M. Bridging the gap to clinical use: A systematic review on TMS-EEG test-retest reliability. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2025;171:133&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39914155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertazzoli G., Esposito R., Mutanen T.P., Ferrari C., Ilmoniemi R.J., Miniussi C., et al. The impact of artifact removal approaches on TMS-EEG signal. Neuroimage. 2021;239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34144161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betzel R.F., Byrge L., He Y., Go&#xf1;i J., Zuo X.N., Sporns O. Changes in structural and functional connectivity among resting-state networks across the human lifespan. Neuroimage. 2014;102(Pt 2):345&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25109530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biabani M., Fornito A., Coxon J.P., Fulcher B.D., Rogasch N.C. The correspondence between EMG and EEG measures of changes in cortical excitability following transcranial magnetic stimulation. J. Physiol. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33599980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biabani M., Fornito A., Goldsworthy M., Thompson S., Graetz L., Semmler J.G., et al. Characterising the contribution of auditory and somatosensory inputs to TMS-evoked potentials following stimulation of prefrontal, premotor, and parietal cortex. Imaging Neurosci. 2024;2:1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12290563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40800374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biabani M., Fornito A., Mutanen T.P., Morrow J., Rogasch N.C. Characterizing and minimizing the contribution of sensory inputs to TMS-evoked potentials. Brain Stimul. 2019;12(6):1537&#x2013;1552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31377097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biermann L., Wunram H.L., Pokorny L., Breitinger E., Gro&#xdf;heinrich N., Jarczok T.A., et al. Changes in the TMS-evoked potential N100 in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex as a function of depression severity in adolescents. J. Neural Transm. (Vienna) 2022;129(11):1339&#x2013;1352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9550695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36029418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigdely-Shamlo N., Mullen T., Kothe C., Su K.M., Robbins K.A. The PREP pipeline: standardized preprocessing for large-scale EEG analysis. Front. Neuroinf. 2015;9:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4471356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26150785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biondi A., Rocchi L., Santoro V., Rossini P.G., Beatch G.N., Richardson M.P., et al. Spontaneous and TMS-related EEG changes as new biomarkers to measure anti-epileptic drug effects. Sci. Rep. 2022;12(1):1919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8817040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliss T.V., Lomo T. Long-lasting potentiation of synaptic transmission in the dentate area of the anaesthetized rabbit following stimulation of the perforant path. J. Physiol. (Lond.) 1973;232(2):331&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1350458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4727084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodart O., Gosseries O., Wannez S., Thibaut A., Annen J., Boly M., et al. Measures of metabolism and complexity in the brain of patients with disorders of consciousness. NeuroImage Clinical. 2017;14:354&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5318348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28239544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodien Y.G., Allanson J., Cardone P., Bonhomme A., Carmona J., Chatelle C., et al. Cognitive motor dissociation in disorders of consciousness. N. Engl. J. Med. 2024;391(7):598&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7617195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39141852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohotin V., Fumal A., Vandenheede M., Bohotin C., Schoenen J. Excitability of visual V1-V2 and motor cortices to single transcranial magnetic stimuli in migraine: a reappraisal using a figure-of-eight coil. Cephalalgia. 2003;23(4):264&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12716343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonato C., Miniussi C., Rossini P.M. Transcranial magnetic stimulation and cortical evoked potentials: a TMS/EEG co-registration study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2006;117(8):1699&#x2013;1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16797232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borich M.R., Wheaton L.A., Brodie S.M., Lakhani B., Boyd L.A. Evaluating interhemispheric cortical responses to transcranial magnetic stimulation in chronic stroke: A TMS-EEG investigation. Neurosci. Lett. 2016;618:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4904777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26940237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortoletto M., Bonzano L., Zazio A., Ferrari C., Pedull&#xe0; L., Gasparotti R., et al. Asymmetric transcallosal conduction delay leads to finer bimanual coordination. Brain Stimul. 2021;14(2):379&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33578035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortoletto M., Veniero D., Julkunen P., Hernandez-Pavon J.C., Mutanen T.P., Zazio A., et al. T4TE: Team for TMS-EEG to improve reproducibility through an open collaborative initiative. Brain Stimul. 2023;16(1):20&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36528272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortoletto M., Veniero D., Thut G., Miniussi C. The contribution of TMS-EEG coregistration in the exploration of the human cortical connectome. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2015;49C:114&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25541459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botvinik-Nezer R., Holzmeister F., Camerer C.F., Dreber A., Huber J., Johannesson M., et al. Variability in the analysis of a single neuroimaging dataset by many teams. Nature. 2020;582(7810):84&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32483374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bracco M., Mutanen T.P., Veniero D., Thut G., Robertson E.M. Distinct frequencies balance segregation with interaction between different memory types within a prefrontal circuit. Curr. Biol. 2023;33(12) 2548-56.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37269827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancaccio A., Tabarelli D., Baur D., Roesch J., Mahmoud W., Ziemann U., et al. Motor cortex excitability states in chronic stroke patients probed by EEG-TMS. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2025;175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40409176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brancaccio A., Tabarelli D., Zazio A., Bertazzoli G., Metsomaa J., Ziemann U., et al. Towards the definition of a standard in TMS-EEG data preprocessing. Neuroimage. 2024;301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39341472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigo F., Storti M., Tezzon F., Manganotti P., Nardone R. Primary visual cortex excitability in migraine: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Neurol. Sci. 2013;34(6):819&#x2013;830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23263736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito, D.V.C., Esteves, F., Rajado AT, Silva N, Consortium As, Ara&#xfa;jo I, et al. Assessing cognitive decline in the aging brain: lessons from rodent and human studies. NPJ Aging 2023;9(1):23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37857723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruckmann S., Hauk D., Roessner V., Resch F., Freitag C.M., Kammer T., et al. Cortical inhibition in attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: new insights from the electroencephalographic response to transcranial magnetic stimulation. Brain. 2012;135(Pt 7):2215&#x2013;2230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22492560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno M.A., Vanhaudenhuyse A., Thibaut A., Moonen G., Laureys S. From unresponsive wakefulness to minimally conscious PLUS and functional locked-in syndromes: recent advances in our understanding of disorders of consciousness. J. Neurol. 2011;258(7):1373&#x2013;1384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21674197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner R.L., Andrews-Hanna J.R., Schacter D.L. The brain's default network: anatomy, function, and relevance to disease. Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 2008;1124:1&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18400922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burbank D.P.W. Reducing skin potential motion artefact by skin abrasion. Med. Biol. Eng. Compu. 1978;16(1):31&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">305999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzsaki G., Anastassiou C.A., Koch C. The origin of extracellular fields and currents&#x2013;EEG, ECoG, LFP and spikes. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2012;13(6):407&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4907333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22595786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calma A.D., van den Bos M., Pavey N., Santos Silva C., Menon P., Vucic S. Physiological biomarkers of upper motor neuron dysfunction in ALS. Brain Sci. 2024;14(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11352893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39199454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canali P., Casarotto S., Rosanova M., Sferrazza-Papa G., Casali A.G., Gosseries O., et al. Abnormal brain oscillations persist after recovery from bipolar depression. Eur. Psychiatry. 2017;41:10&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28049075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canali P., Sarasso S., Rosanova M., Casarotto S., Sferrazza-Papa G., Gosseries O., et al. Shared reduction of oscillatory natural frequencies in bipolar disorder, major depressive disorder and schizophrenia. J. Affect. Disord. 2015;184:111&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26074020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canali P., Sferrazza Papa G., Casali A.G., Schiena G., Fecchio M., Pigorini A., et al. Changes of cortical excitability as markers of antidepressant response in bipolar depression: Preliminary data obtained by combining transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) and electroencephalography (EEG) Bipolar Disord. 2014;16(8):809&#x2013;819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25219396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao K.X., Ma M.L., Wang C.Z., Iqbal J., Si J.J., Xue Y.X., et al. TMS-EEG: An emerging tool to study the neurophysiologic biomarkers of psychiatric disorders. Neuropharmacology. 2021;197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33894219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardin J.A., Carl&#xe9;n M., Meletis K., Knoblich U., Zhang F., Deisseroth K., et al. Driving fast-spiking cells induces gamma rhythm and controls sensory responses. Nature. 2009;459(7247):663&#x2013;667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3655711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19396156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carf&#xec; A., Bernabei R., Landi F. Persistent Symptoms in Patients After Acute COVID-19. J. Am. Med. Assoc. 2020;324(6):603&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carl&#xe9;n M. What constitutes the prefrontal cortex? Science. 2017;358(6362):478&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29074767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney P.W., Jackson G.D. Insights into the mechanisms of absence seizure generation provided by EEG with functional MRI. Front. Neurol. 2014;5:162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4150362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25225491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrera E., Tononi G. Diaschisis: past, present, future. Brain. 2014;137(Pt 9):2408&#x2013;2422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24871646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casali A.G., Casarotto S., Rosanova M., Mariotti M., Massimini M. General indices to characterize the electrical response of the cerebral cortex to TMS. Neuroimage. 2010;49(2):1459&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19770048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casali A.G., Gosseries O., Rosanova M., Boly M., Sarasso S., Casali K.R., et al. A theoretically based index of consciousness independent of sensory processing and behavior. Sci. Transl. Med. 2013;5(198) 198ra05.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23946194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casarotto S., Canali P., Rosanova M., Pigorini A., Fecchio M., Mariotti M., et al. Assessing the effects of electroconvulsive therapy on cortical excitability by means of transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalography. Brain Topogr. 2013;26(2):326&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3587686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casarotto S., Comanducci A., Rosanova M., Sarasso S., Fecchio M., Napolitani M., et al. Stratification of unresponsive patients by an independently validated index of brain complexity. Ann. Neurol. 2016;80(5):718&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5132045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27717082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casarotto S., Fecchio M., Rosanova M., Varone G., D'Ambrosio S., Sarasso S., et al. The rt-TEP tool: real-time visualization of TMS-Evoked Potentials to maximize cortical activation and minimize artifacts. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35074394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casarotto S., Hassan G., Rosanova M., Sarasso S., Derchi C.C., Trimarchi P.D., et al. Dissociations between spontaneous electroencephalographic features and the perturbational complexity index in the minimally conscious state. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2024;59(5):934&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38440949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casarotto S., M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4; S., Herukka S.K., Pigorini A., Napolitani M., Gosseries O., et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked EEG/cortical potentials in physiological and pathological aging. Neuroreport. 2011;22(12):592&#x2013;597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21753711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casarotto S., Romero Lauro L.J., Bellina V., Casali A.G., Rosanova M., Pigorini A., et al. EEG responses to TMS are sensitive to changes in the perturbation parameters and repeatable over time. PLoS One. 2010;5(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2858649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20421968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casarotto S., Turco F., Comanducci A., Perretti A., Marotta G., Pezzoli G., et al. Excitability of the supplementary motor area in Parkinson's disease depends on subcortical damage. Brain Stimul. 2019;12(1):152&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30416036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey B.J., Tottenham N., Liston C., Durston S. Imaging the developing brain: what have we learned about cognitive development? Trends Cogn. Sci. 2005;9(3):104&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15737818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Bertoldo A., Tarantino V., Maiella M., Koch G., Rothwell J.C., et al. TMS-evoked long-lasting artefacts: A new adaptive algorithm for EEG signal correction. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2017;128(9):1563&#x2013;1574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28709122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Borghi I., Maiella M., Pellicciari M.C., Bonn&#xec; S., Mencarelli L., et al. Regional precuneus cortical hyperexcitability in Alzheimer's disease patients. Ann. Neurol. 2023;93(2):371&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10092632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36134540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Esposito R., Dezi S., Ortelli P., Sebastianelli L., Ferrazzoli D., et al. Reduced TMS-evoked EEG oscillatory activity in cortical motor regions in patients with post-COVID fatigue. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2024;165:26&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38943790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Leodori G., Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J., Benussi A., Rawji V., Tremblay S., et al. The effect of coil orientation on the stimulation of the pre-supplementary motor area: a combined TMS and EEG study. Brain Sci. 2022;12(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9599651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36291292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Maiella M., Pellicciari M.C., Porrazzini F., D'Acunto A., Rocchi L., et al. Novel TMS-EEG indexes to investigate interhemispheric dynamics in humans. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2020;131(1):70&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31756594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Mayer I.M.S., Desikan M., Tabrizi S.J., Rothwell J.C., Orth M. Motor cortex synchronization influences the rhythm of motor performance in premanifest huntington's disease. Mov. Disord. 2018;33(3):440&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29356133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Pellicciari M.C., Bonn&#xec; S., Borghi I., Maiella M., Assogna M., et al. Decreased frontal gamma activity in Alzheimer's disease patients. Ann. Neurol. 2022;92:464&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9543336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35713198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Rocchi L., Hannah R., Rothwell J.C. Effects of pulse width, waveform and current direction in the cortex: a combined cTMS-EEG study. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(5):1063&#x2013;1070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29709505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casula E.P., Stampanoni Bassi M., Pellicciari M.C., Ponzo V., Veniero D., Peppe A., et al. Subthalamic stimulation and levodopa modulate cortical reactivity in Parkinson's patients. Parkinsonism Relat. Disord. 2017;34:31&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27771287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caulfield K.A., Fleischmann H.H., Cox C.E., Wolf J.P., George M.S., McTeague L.M. Neuronavigation maximizes accuracy and precision in TMS positioning: Evidence from 11,230 distance, angle, and electric field modeling measurements. Brain Stimul. 2022;15(5):1192&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10026380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36031059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caulfield, K.A., Savoca, M.T., Lopez JW, Summers PM, Li X, Fecchio M, et al. Assessing the Intra- and Inter-Subject Reliability of the Perturbational Complexity Index (PCI) of Consciousness for Three Brain Regions Using TMS-EEG. bioRxiv 2020:2020.01.08.898775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesp&#xf3;n J., Pellicciari M.C., Casula E.P., Miniussi C. Age-related changes in cortical excitability linked to decreased attentional and inhibitory control. Neuroscience. 2022;495:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35605905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chard D.T., Alahmadi A.A.S., Audoin B., Charalambous T., Enzinger C., Hulst H.E., et al. Mind the gap: from neurons to networks to outcomes in multiple sclerosis. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2021;17(3):173&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33437067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri A., Behan P.O. Fatigue in neurological disorders. Lancet. 2004;363(9413):978&#x2013;988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15043967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.C.B., Lin H.Y., Wang L.J., Hung K.C., Brunoni A.R., Chou P.H., et al. A network meta-analysis of non-invasive brain stimulation interventions for autism spectrum disorder: Evidence from randomized controlled trials. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2024;164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38981573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chio A., Mazzini L., D'Alfonso S., Corrado L., Canosa A., Moglia C., et al. The multistep hypothesis of ALS revisited: The role of genetic mutations. Neurology. 2018;91(7):e635&#x2013;e642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30045958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury, N.S., Chiang, A.K.I., Millard SK, Skippen P, Chang WJ, Seminowicz DA, et al. Combined transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalography reveals alterations in cortical excitability during pain. eLife 2023;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10651174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37966464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury N.S., Millard S.K., de Martino E., Larsen D.B., Seminowicz D.A., Schabrun S.M., et al. Posterior-superior insula repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation reduces experimental tonic pain and pain-related cortical inhibition in humans. Pain. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39679661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury N.S., Rogasch N.C., Chiang A.K.I., Millard S.K., Skippen P., Chang W.J., et al. The influence of sensory potentials on transcranial magnetic stimulation - electroencephalography recordings. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;140:98&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung S.W., Lewis B.P., Rogasch N.C., Saeki T., Thomson R.H., Hoy K.E., et al. Demonstration of short-term plasticity in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex with theta burst stimulation: a TMS-EEG study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2017;128(7):1117&#x2013;1126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciampi de Andrade, D., Garc&#xed;a-Larrea, L. Beyond trial-and-error: Individualizing therapeutic transcranial neuromodulation for chronic pain. Eur. J. Pain (London, England) 2023;27(9):1065-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7616049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37596980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinnera A.M., Casula E.P., Pezzopane V., D'Acunto A., Maiella M., Bonn&#xec; S., et al. Association of TMS-EEG interhemispheric imbalance with upper limb motor impairment in chronic stroke patients: an exploratory study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2025;171:95&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39889485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark B.C. Neuromuscular changes with aging and sarcopenia. J. Frailty Aging. 2019;8(1):7&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9725117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30734824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson A.N., Huang B.S., Macisaac S.E., Mody I., Carmichael S.T. Reducing excessive GABA-mediated tonic inhibition promotes functional recovery after stroke. Nature. 2010;468(7321):305&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3058798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21048709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cline C.C., Lucas M.V., Sun Y.M., Menezes M., Etkin A. Advanced artifact removal for automated TMS-EEG data processing. I Ieee Embs C Neur E. 2021:1039&#x2013;1042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole E.J., Enticott P.G., Oberman L.M., Gwynette M.F., Casanova M.F., Jackson S.L.J., et al. The potential of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for autism spectrum disorder: a consensus statement. Biol. Psychiatry. 2019;85(4):e21&#x2013;e22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6342639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30103951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comanducci A., Casarotto S., Rosanova M., Derchi C.C., Vigan&#xf2; A., Pirastru A., et al. Unconsciousness or unresponsiveness in akinetic mutism? Insights from a multimodal longitudinal exploration. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2024;59(5):860&#x2013;873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37077023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comolatti R., Hassan G., Mikulan E., Russo S., Colombo M.A., Litterio E., et al. Transcranial magnetic vs intracranial electric stimulation: a direct comparison of their effects via scalp EEG recordings. Brain Stimul. 2025;18(5):1444&#x2013;1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40730280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comolatti R., Pigorini A., Casarotto S., Fecchio M., Faria G., Sarasso S., et al. A fast and general method to empirically estimate the complexity of brain responses to transcranial and intracranial stimulations. Brain Stimul. 2019;12(5):1280&#x2013;1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31133480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cona F., Zavaglia M., Massimini M., Rosanova M., Ursino M. A neural mass model of interconnected regions simulates rhythm propagation observed via TMS-EEG. Neuroimage. 2011;57(3):1045&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21600291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conde V., Tomasevic L., Akopian I., Stanek K., Saturnino G.B., Thielscher A., et al. The non-transcranial TMS-evoked potential is an inherent source of ambiguity in TMS-EEG studies. Neuroimage. 2019;185:300&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30347282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortese F., Coppola G., Di Lenola D., Serrao M., Di Lorenzo C., Parisi V., et al. Excitability of the motor cortex in patients with migraine changes with the time elapsed from the last attack. J. Headache Pain. 2017;18(1):2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5218956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28063106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corthout E., Hallett M., Cowey A. TMS-induced blinking assessed with high-speed video: optical disruption of visual perception. Exp. Brain Res. Experimentelle Hirnforschung. 2011;210(2):243&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7334885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21431430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosentino G., Di Marco S., Ferlisi S., Valentino F., Capitano W.M., Fierro B., et al. Intracortical facilitation within the migraine motor cortex depends on the stimulation intensity. A paired-pulse TMS study. J. Headache Pain. 2018;19(1):65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6085216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30094517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosentino G., Fierro B., Brighina F. From different neurophysiological methods to conflicting pathophysiological views in migraine: a critical review of literature. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2014;125(9):1721&#x2013;1730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosentino G., Fierro B., Vigneri S., Talamanca S., Paladino P., Baschi R., et al. Cyclical changes of cortical excitability and metaplasticity in migraine: evidence from a repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Pain. 2014;155(6):1070&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24631596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosentino G., Fierro B., Vigneri S., Talamanca S., Palermo A., Puma A., et al. Impaired glutamatergic neurotransmission in migraine with aura? Evidence by an input-output curves transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Headache. 2011;51(5):726&#x2013;733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21521207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couto, B.A., Fecchio, M., Russo S, De Martino E, Parmigiani S, Sarasso S, et al. Extracting reproducible components from electroencephalographic responses to transcranial magnetic stimulation with group task-related component analysis. bioRxiv 2025:2025.06.02.657489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12784221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41523212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle H.L., Bailey N.W., Ponsford J., Hoy K.E. A comprehensive characterization of cognitive performance, clinical symptoms, and cortical activity following mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI) Appl. Neuropsychol. Adult. 2023:1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38015637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle H.L., Bailey N.W., Ponsford J., Hoy K.E. Investigation of neurobiological responses to theta burst stimulation during recovery from mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI) Behav. Brain Res. 2023;442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36702385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle H.L., Bailey N.W., Ponsford J., Hoy K.E. Recovery of clinical, cognitive and cortical activity measures following mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI): a longitudinal investigation. Cortex; A J. Devoted to the Study of the Nervous Syst. Behavior. 2023;165:14&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyle H.L., Ponsford J., Hoy K.E. Understanding individual variability in symptoms and recovery following mTBI: a role for TMS-EEG? Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2018;92:140&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29885426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cracco R.Q., Amassian V.E., Maccabee P.J., Cracco J.B. Comparison of human transcallosal responses evoked by magnetic coil and electrical stimulation. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1989;74(6):417&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2480220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristofari A., De Santis M., Lucidi S., Rothwell J., Casula E.P., Rocchi L. Machine learning-based classification to disentangle EEG responses to TMS and auditory input. Brain Sci. 2023;13(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10296660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37371346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croft R.J., Barry R.J. Removal of ocular artifact from the EEG: a review. Neurophysiol. Clinique = Clin. Neurophysiol. 2000;30(1):5&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10740792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curley W.H., Forgacs P.B., Voss H.U., Conte M.M., Schiff N.D. Characterization of EEG signals revealing covert cognition in the injured brain. Brain. 2018;141(5):1404&#x2013;1421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5917770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Agati E., Hoegl T., Dippel G., Curatolo P., Bender S., Kratz O., et al. Motor cortical inhibition in ADHD: modulation of the transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked N100 in a response control task. J. Neural Transm. (Vienna) 2014;121(3):315&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ambrosio S., Certo F., Bernardelli L., Pini L., Corbetta M., Pantoni L., et al. Detecting cortical reactivity alterations induced by structural disconnection in subcortical stroke. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;156:1&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37826930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ambrosio S., Jim&#xe9;nez-Jim&#xe9;nez D., Silvennoinen K., Zagaglia S., Perulli M., Poole J., et al. Physiological symmetry of transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked EEG spectral features. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2022;43(18):5465&#x2013;5477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9704783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35866186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadsena R., Wetz S., Hofmann A., Costa A.S., Romanzetti S., Lischewski S.A., et al. Evidence of clinical and brain recovery in post-COVID-19 condition: a three-year follow-up study. Brain Commun. 2025;7(5) fcaf366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12508649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41079753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danner N., Julkunen P., Kononen M., Saisanen L., Nurkkala J., Karhu J. Navigated transcranial magnetic stimulation and computed electric field strength reduce stimulator-dependent differences in the motor threshold. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2008;174(1):116&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18662721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danner N., K&#xf6;n&#xf6;nen M., S&#xe4;is&#xe4;nen L., Laitinen R., Mervaala E., Julkunen P. Effect of individual anatomy on resting motor threshold-computed electric field as a measure of cortical excitability. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2012;203(2):298&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22019330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darmani G., Bergmann T.O., Zipser C., Baur D., M&#xfc;ller-Dahlhaus F., Ziemann U. Effects of antiepileptic drugs on cortical excitability in humans: A TMS-EMG and TMS-EEG study. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2019;40(4):1276&#x2013;1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30549127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darmani G., Nieminen J.O., Bergmann T.O., Ramezanpour H., Ziemann U. A degraded state of consciousness in healthy awake humans? Brain Stimul. 2021;14:710&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darmani G., Ziemann U. Pharmacophysiology of TMS-evoked EEG potentials: a mini-review. Brain Stimul. 2019;12(3):829&#x2013;831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30837122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darmani G., Zipser C.M., B&#xf6;hmer G.M., Deschet K., M&#xfc;ller-Dahlhaus F., Belardinelli P., et al. Effects of the selective alpha5-GABAAR antagonist S44819 on excitability in the human brain: a TMS-EMG and TMS-EEG phase I study. J. Neurosci. 2016;36(49):12312&#x2013;12320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6601976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27927951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daskalakis Z.J., Farzan F., Barr M.S., Maller J.J., Chen R., Fitzgerald P.B. Long-interval cortical inhibition from the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex: a TMS-EEG study. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2008;33:2860&#x2013;2869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David O., Kilner J.M., Friston K.J. Mechanisms of evoked and induced responses in MEG/EEG. Neuroimage. 2006;31(4):1580&#x2013;1591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16632378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H.E., McCorkell L., Vogel J.M., Topol E.J. Long COVID: major findings, mechanisms and recommendations. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2023;21(3):133&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9839201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36639608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson G., Rieder A.D., Johnson M.H. Prediction of autism in infants: progress and challenges. Lancet Neurol. 2023;22(3):244&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10100853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36427512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson G.D. A summation technique for the detection of small evoked potentials. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13141922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Cheveign&#xe9; A., Arzounian D. Robust detrending, rereferencing, outlier detection, and inpainting for multichannel data. Neuroimage. 2018;172:903&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5915520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29448077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Cheveign&#xe9; A., Nelken I. Filters: when, why, and how (not) to use them. Neuron. 2019;102(2):280&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30998899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Martino E., Casali A., Casarotto S., Hassan G., Couto B.A., Rosanova M., et al. Evoked oscillatory cortical activity during acute pain: Probing brain in pain by transcranial magnetic stimulation combined with electroencephalogram. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2024;45(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11034005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38647038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Martino E., Casali A., Casarotto S., Hassan G., Rosanova M., Graven-Nielsen T., et al. Acute pain drives different effects on local and global cortical excitability in motor and prefrontal areas: insights into interregional and interpersonal differences in pain processing. Cereb. Cortex. 2023;33(18):9986&#x2013;9996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37522261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Martino E., Nascimento Couto B.A., Jakobsen A., Casali A.G., Bonde-Heriksen P.D., Graven-Nielsen T., et al. Pretreatment TMS-EEG connectivity assessment as a potential predictor of rTMS effectiveness in chronic pain: a feasibility pilot study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40082174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Tommaso M., Ambrosini A., Brighina F., Coppola G., Perrotta A., Pierelli F., et al. Altered processing of sensory stimuli in patients with migraine. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2014;10(3):144&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24535465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Felice A., Fiaschi A., Bongiovanni G.L., Savazzi S., Manganotti P. The sleep-deprived brain in normals and patients with juvenile myoclonic epilepsy: a perturbational approach to measuring cortical reactivity. Epilepsy Res. 2011;96(1&#x2013;2):123&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21726980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorme A. EEG is better left alone. Sci. Rep. 2023;13(1):2372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9911389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorme A., Martin J.A. 2021 IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (BIBM): IEEE. 2021. Automated data cleaning for the Muse EEG; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delorme A., Palmer J., Onton J., Oostenveld R., Makeig S. Independent EEG sources are dipolar. PLoS One. 2012;7(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3280242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22355308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Z.D., Lisanby S.H., Peterchev A.V. Electric field depth-focality tradeoff in transcranial magnetic stimulation: simulation comparison of 50 coil designs. Brain Stimul. 2013;6(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Z.D., Lisanby S.H., Peterchev A.V. Electric field depth-focality tradeoff in transcranial magnetic stimulation: simulation comparison of 50 coil designs. Brain Stimul. 2013;6:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dery J., De Guise E., Bussieres E.L., Lamontagne M.E. Prognostic factors for persistent symptoms in adults with mild traumatic brain injury: protocol for an overview of systematic reviews. Syst. Rev. 2021;10(1):254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34556172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desforges M., Hadas I., Mihov B., Morin Y., Rochette Bra&#xfc;n M., Lioumis P., et al. Dose-response of intermittent theta burst stimulation of the prefrontal cortex: A TMS-EEG study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;136:158&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35183861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devuyst, S., Dutoit T, Stenuit P, Kerkhofs M, Stanus E. Removal of ECG artifacts from EEG using a modified independent component analysis approach. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc 2008;2008:5204-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19163890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhami P., Atluri S., Lee J., Knyahnytska Y., Croarkin P.E., Blumberger D.M., et al. Neurophysiological markers of response to theta burst stimulation in youth depression. Depress. Anxiety. 2021;38(2):172&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33001549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhami P., Atluri S., Lee J.C., Knyahnytska Y., Croarkin P.E., Blumberger D.M., et al. Prefrontal cortical reactivity and connectivity markers distinguish youth depression from healthy youth. Cereb. Cortex. 2020;30(7):3884&#x2013;3894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32118262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhami P., Moreno S., Croarkin P.E., Blumberger D.M., Daskalakis Z.J., Farzan F. Baseline markers of cortical excitation and inhibition predict response to theta burst stimulation treatment for youth depression. Sci. Rep. 2023;13(1):19115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37925557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T., Matamala J.M., Howells J., Vucic S., Kiernan M.C. Early focality and spread of cortical dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A regional study across the motor cortices. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2020;131(4):958&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31959568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmadasa T., Pavey N., Tu S., Menon P., Huynh W., Mahoney C.J., et al. Novel approaches to assessing upper motor neuron dysfunction in motor neuron disease/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: IFCN handbook chapter. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2024;163:68&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38705104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Chiara G., Imperato A. Drugs abused by humans preferentially increase synaptic dopamine concentrations in the mesolimbic system of freely moving rats. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 1988;85(14):5274&#x2013;5278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC281732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2899326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>di Hou M., Santoro V., Biondi A., Shergill S.S., Premoli I. A systematic review of TMS and neurophysiological biometrics in patients with schizophrenia. J. Psychiatry Neurosci. 2021;46(6):E675&#x2013;E701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8695525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34933940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lazzaro V., Bella R., Benussi A., Bologna M., Borroni B., Capone F., et al. Diagnostic contribution and therapeutic perspectives of transcranial magnetic stimulation in dementia. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2021;132(10):2568&#x2013;2607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34482205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lazzaro V., Oliviero A., Pilato F., Saturno E., Dileone M., Mazzone P., et al. The physiological basis of transcranial motor cortex stimulation in conscious humans. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2004;115(2):255&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14744565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lazzaro V., Oliviero A., Profice P., Pennisi M.A., Di Giovanni S., Zito G., et al. Muscarinic receptor blockade has differential effects on the excitability of intracortical circuits in human motor cortex. Exp. Brain Res. Exp. Hirnforschung. 2000;135:455&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11156309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lorenzo F., Motta C., Casula E.P., Bonni S., Assogna M., Caltagirone C., et al. LTP-like cortical plasticity predicts conversion to dementia in patients with memory impairment. Brain Stimul. 2020;13(5):1175&#x2013;1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32485235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Lorenzo F., Ponzo V., Bonni S., Motta C., Negrao Serra P.C., Bozzali M., et al. LTP-like cortical plasticity is disrupted in Alzheimer's disease patients independently from age of onset. Ann. Neurol. 2016;80(2):202&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27255833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;ez-Cirarda M., Yus-Fuertes M., Sanchez-Sanchez R., Gonzalez-Rosa J.J., Gonzalez-Escamilla G., Gil-Mart&#xed;nez L., et al. Hippocampal subfield abnormalities and biomarkers of pathologic brain changes: from SARS-CoV-2 acute infection to post-COVID syndrome. EBioMedicine. 2023;94</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10366393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37453364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y., Sohn J.H., Kawczynski M.G., Trivedi H., Harnish R., Jenkins N.W., et al. A deep learning model to predict a diagnosis of Alzheimer disease by using (18)F-FDG PET of the BRAIN. Radiology. 2019;290(2):456&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6358051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30398430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirlich G., Vogl L., Plaschke M., Strian F. Cardiac field effects on the EEG. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1997;102(4):307&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9146492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati F.L., Kaskie R., Reis C.C., D'Agostino A., Casali A.G., Ferrarelli F. Reduced TMS-evoked fast oscillations in the motor cortex predict the severity of positive symptoms in first-episode psychosis. Prog. Neuropsychopharmacol. Biol. Psychiatry. 2021;111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34129889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati F.L., Mayeli A., Nascimento Couto B.A., Sharma K., Janssen S., Krafty R.J., et al. Prefrontal oscillatory slowing in early-course schizophrenia is associated with worse cognitive performance and negative symptoms: a transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalography study. Biol. Psychiatry Cogn. Neurosci. Neuroimag. 2025;10(2):158&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11759720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39059465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donati F.L., Mayeli A., Sharma K., Janssen S.A., Lagoy A.D., Casali A.G., et al. Natural oscillatory frequency slowing in the premotor cortex of early-course schizophrenia patients: a TMS-EEG study. Brain Sci. 2023;13(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10136843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37190501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dora C., Biswal P.K. Correlation-based ECG artifact correction from single channel EEG using modified variational mode decomposition. Comput. Methods Programs Biomed. 2020;183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31600608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downar J., Crawley A.P., Mikulis D.J., Davis K.D. A cortical network sensitive to stimulus salience in a neutral behavioral context across multiple sensory modalities. J. Neurophysiol. 2002;87(1):615&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11784775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubois B., Feldman H.H., Jacova C., Hampel H., Molinuevo J.L., Blennow K., et al. Advancing research diagnostic criteria for Alzheimer's disease: the IWG-2 criteria. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(6):614&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24849862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukic S., McMackin R., Costello E., Metzger M., Buxo T., Fasano A., et al. Resting-state EEG reveals four subphenotypes of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2022;145(2):621&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9014749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34791079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edlow B.L., Fecchio M., Bodien Y.G., Comanducci A., Rosanova M., Casarotto S., et al. Measuring consciousness in the intensive care unit. Neurocrit. Care. 2023;38(3):584&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11421303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A., Braak H., Del Tredici K., Lemon R., Ludolph A.C., Kiernan M.C. Cortical influences drive amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2017;88:917&#x2013;924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28710326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A., Kim S., Pant B. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS): a phylogenetic disease of the corticomotoneuron? Muscle Nerve. 1992;15:219&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1549143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisen A., Vucic S., Kiernan M.C. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis represents corticomotoneuronal system failure. Muscle Nerve. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11887532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39511939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel A.K., Fries P. Beta-band oscillations&#x2013;signalling the status quo? Curr. Opin. Neurobiol. 2010;20(2):156&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20359884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enticott P.G., Barlow K., Guastella A.J., Licari M.K., Rogasch N.C., Middeldorp C.M., et al. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) in autism spectrum disorder: protocol for a multicentre randomised controlled clinical trial. BMJ Open. 2021;11(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8264904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34233985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enticott P.G., Fitzgibbon B.M., Kennedy H.A., Arnold S.L., Elliot D., Peachey A., et al. A double-blind, randomized trial of deep Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (rTMS) for autism spectrum disorder. Brain Stimul. 2014;7(2):206&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24280031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ermolova M., Metsomaa J., Belardinelli P., Zrenner C., Ziemann U. Blindly separated spontaneous network-level oscillations predict corticospinal excitability. J. Neural Eng. 2024;21(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38834060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshel, N., Keller CJ, Wu W, Jiang J, Mills-Finnerty C, Huemer J, et al. Global connectivity and local excitability changes underlie antidepressant effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neuropsychopharmacology : official publication of the American College of Neuropsychopharmacology 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32053828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esser S.K., Huber R., Massimini M., Peterson M.J., Ferrarelli F., Tononi G. A direct demonstration of cortical LTP in humans: A combined TMS/EEG study. Brain Res. Bull. 2006;69(1):86&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16464689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fakoya, A.O., Hohman, M.H., Westbrook KE, Varacallo MA. Anatomy, Head and Neck: Facial Muscles. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL); 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farzan F. Transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalography for biomarker discovery in psychiatry. Biol. Psychiatry. 2024;95(6):564&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38142721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farzan F., Barr M.S., Hoppenbrouwers S.S., Fitzgerald P.B., Chen R., Pascual-Leone A., et al. The EEG correlates of the TMS-induced EMG silent period in humans. Neuroimage. 2013;83:120&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4211432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farzan F., Barr M.S., Levinson A.J., Chen R., Wong W., Fitzgerald P.B., et al. Evidence for gamma inhibition deficits in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex of patients with schizophrenia. Brain. 2010;133(Pt 5):1505&#x2013;1514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20350936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farzan F., Bortoletto M. Identification and verification of a 'true' TMS evoked potential in TMS-EEG. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35714721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farzan F., Vernet M., Shafi M.M., Rotenberg A., Daskalakis Z.J., Pascual-Leone A. Characterizing and modulating brain circuitry through transcranial magnetic stimulation combined with electroencephalography. Front. Neural Circuits. 2016;10:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5031704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27713691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecchio M., Pigorini A., Comanducci A., Sarasso S., Casarotto S., Premoli I., et al. The spectral features of EEG responses to transcranial magnetic stimulation of the primary motor cortex depend on the amplitude of the motor evoked potentials. PLoS One. 2017;12(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28910407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fecchio, M., Russo, S., Couto, B.A., Mikulan E, Pigorini A, Furregoni G, et al. The specific spatiotemporal evolution of TMS-evoked potentials reflects the engagement of cortical circuits. bioRxiv 2025:2025.06.25.661535.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin V.L., Owolabi M.O. Pragmatic solutions to reduce the global burden of stroke: a World Stroke Organization-Lancet Neurology Commission. Lancet Neurol. 2023;22(12):1160&#x2013;1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10715732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37827183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez L., Biabani M., Do M., Opie G.M., Hill A.T., Barham M.P., et al. Assessing cerebellar-cortical connectivity using concurrent TMS-EEG: a feasibility study. J. Neurophysiol. 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33788622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrarelli F., Kaskie R.E., Graziano B., Reis C.C., Casali A.G. Abnormalities in the evoked frontal oscillatory activity of first-episode psychosis: a TMS/EEG study. Schizophr. Res. 2019;206:436&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30473213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrarelli F., Massimini M., Sarasso S., Casali A., Riedner B.A., Angelini G., et al. Breakdown in cortical effective connectivity during midazolam-induced loss of consciousness. PNAS. 2010;107(6):2681&#x2013;2686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2823915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20133802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrarelli F., Phillips M.L. Examining and modulating neural circuits in psychiatric disorders with transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalography: present practices and future developments. Am. J. Psychiatry. 2021;178(5):400&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8119323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33653120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrarelli F., Sarasso S., Guller Y., Riedner B.A., Peterson M.J., Bellesi M., et al. Reduced natural oscillatory frequency of frontal thalamocortical circuits in schizophrenia. Arch. Gen. Psychiatry. 2012;69(8):766&#x2013;774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3394893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22474071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreri F., Guerra A., Vollero L., Ponzo D., M&#xe4;&#xe4;tta S., K&#xf6;n&#xf6;nen M., et al. TMS-EEG biomarkers of amnestic mild cognitive impairment due to alzheimer's disease: a proof-of-concept six years prospective study. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8645846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34880743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreri F., Guerra A., Vollero L., Ponzo D., Maatta S., Mervaala E., et al. Age-related changes of cortical excitability and connectivity in healthy humans: non-invasive evaluation of sensorimotor network by means of TMS-EEG. Neuroscience. 2017;357:255&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28624571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreri F., Pasqualetti P., M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4; S., Ponzo D., Ferrarelli F., Tononi G., et al. Human brain connectivity during single and paired pulse transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neuroimage. 2011;54(1):90&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreri F., Vecchio F., Vollero L., Guerra A., Petrichella S., Ponzo D., et al. Sensorimotor cortex excitability and connectivity in Alzheimer's disease: A TMS-EEG Co-registration study. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2016;37(6):2083&#x2013;2096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6867580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26945686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgibbon S.P., DeLosAngeles D., Lewis T.W., Powers D.M., Grummett T.S., Whitham E.M., et al. Automatic determination of EMG-contaminated components and validation of independent component analysis using EEG during pharmacologic paralysis. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2016;127(3):1781&#x2013;1793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floris D.L., Peng H., Warrier V., Lombardo M.V., Pretzsch C.M., Moreau C., et al. The link between autism and sex-related neuroanatomy, and associated cognition and gene expression. Am. J. Psychiatry. 2023;180(1):50&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36415971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong P.Y., Spampinato D., Michell K., Mancuso M., Brown K., Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J., et al. EEG responses induced by cerebellar TMS at rest and during visuomotor adaptation. Neuroimage. 2023;275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37230209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong T.G., Davis D., Growdon M.E., Albuquerque A., Inouye S.K. The interface between delirium and dementia in elderly adults. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14(8):823&#x2013;832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4535349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26139023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong T.G., Inouye S.K. The inter-relationship between delirium and dementia: the importance of delirium prevention. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2022;18(10):579&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9415264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36028563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Formaggio E., Tonellato M., Antonini A., Castiglia L., Gallo L., Manganotti P., et al. Oscillatory EEG-TMS reactivity in parkinson disease. J. Cli. Neurophysiol. 2023;40(3):263&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34280941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freche D., Naim-Feil J., Peled A., Levit-Binnun N., Moses E. A quantitative physical model of the TMS-induced discharge artifacts in EEG. PLoS Comput. Biol. 2018;14(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6063435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30016315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedberg M., Reeves J.A., Hussain S.J., Zaghloul K.A., Wassermann E.M. Identifying site- and stimulation-specific TMS-evoked EEG potentials using a quantitative cosine similarity metric. PLoS One. 2020;15(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6957143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31929531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried P.J., Santarnecchi E., Antal A., Bartres-Faz D., Bestmann S., Carpenter L.L., et al. Training in the practice of noninvasive brain stimulation: Recommendations from an IFCN committee. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2021;132(3):819&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11624139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33549501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friston K. Beyond phrenology: what can neuroimaging tell us about distributed circuitry? Annu. Rev. Neurosci. 2002;25:221&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12052909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frolich L., Dowding I. Removal of muscular artifacts in EEG signals: a comparison of linear decomposition methods. Brain Inform. 2018;5(1):13&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5893498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29322469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs M., Kastner J., Wagner M., Hawes S., Ebersole J.S. A standardized boundary element method volume conductor model. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2002;113(5):702&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11976050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabor, D. Theory of communication. Part 1: The analysis of information. J. Instit. Electr. Engineers-part III: Radio Commun. Eng. 1946;93(26):429-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao R., Penzes P. Common mechanisms of excitatory and inhibitory imbalance in schizophrenia and autism spectrum disorders. Curr. Mol. Med. 2015;15(2):146&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4721588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25732149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia J.O., Grossman E.D., Srinivasan R. Evoked potentials in large-scale cortical networks elicited by TMS of the visual cortex. J. Neurophysiol. 2011;106(4):1734&#x2013;1746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner R.C., Yaffe K. Epidemiology of mild traumatic brain injury and neurodegenerative disease. Mol. Cell. Neurosci. 2015;66(Pt B):75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4461453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25748121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gassmann L., Gordon P.C., Roy O., Kaut O., H&#xf6;mberg V., Ziemann U. Cerebellar TMS-EEG in a chronic stroke patient with connectional diaschisis of the dentato-thalamo-cortical tract. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;152:68&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37329656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N., Korgaonkar M.S., Menon P., Van den Bos M., Gomes L., Foster S., et al. Brain functional connectome abnormalities in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis are associated with disability and cortical hyperexcitability. Eur. J. Neurol. 2017;24(12):1507&#x2013;1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28926154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geevasinga N., Menon P., &#xd6;zdinler P.H., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Pathophysiological and diagnostic implications of cortical dysfunction in ALS. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2016;12(11):651&#x2013;661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27658852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gefferie S.R., Jim&#xe9;nez-Jim&#xe9;nez D., Visser G.H., Helling R.M., Sander J.W., Balestrini S., et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked electroencephalography responses as biomarkers for epilepsy: a review of study design and outcomes. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2023;44(8):3446&#x2013;3460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36896753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerwig M., Niehaus L., Stude P., Katsarava Z., Diener H.C. Beta-blocker migraine prophylaxis affects the excitability of the visual cortex as revealed by transcranial magnetic stimulation. J. Headache Pain. 2012;13(1):83&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3253148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghatak S., Talantova M., McKercher S.R., Lipton S.A. Novel therapeutic approach for excitatory/inhibitory imbalance in neurodevelopmental and neurodegenerative diseases. Annu. Rev. Pharmacol. Toxicol. 2021;61:701&#x2013;721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32997602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacino J.T., Ashwal S., Childs N., Cranford R., Jennett B., Katz D.I., et al. The minimally conscious state: definition and diagnostic criteria. Neurology. 2002;58(3):349&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11839831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giacino J.T., Katz D.I., Schiff N.D., Whyte J., Ashman E.J., Ashwal S., et al. Practice guideline update recommendations summary: Disorders of consciousness: Report of the Guideline Development, Dissemination, and Implementation Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology; the American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine; and the National Institute on Disability, Independent Living, and Rehabilitation Research. Neurology. 2018;91(10):450&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6139814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30089618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giedd J.N. The teen brain: insights from neuroimaging. J. Adolesc. Health. 2008;42(4):335&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18346658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Burden of Diseases Collaborators Global, regional, and national burden of disorders affecting the nervous system, 1990-2021: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet Neurol. 2024;23(4):344&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38493795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goadsby P.J., Holland P.R., Martins-Oliveira M., Hoffmann J., Schankin C., Akerman S. Pathophysiology of migraine: a Disorder of sensory processing. Physiol. Rev. 2017;97(2):553&#x2013;622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28179394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogtay N., Giedd J.N., Lusk L., Hayashi K.M., Greenstein D., Vaituzis A.C., et al. Dynamic mapping of human cortical development during childhood through early adulthood. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 2004;101(21):8174&#x2013;8179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC419576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15148381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogulski J., Cline C.C., Ross J.M., Parmigiani S., Keller C.J. Reliability of the TMS-evoked potential in dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. Cereb. Cortex. 2024;34(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11004671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38596882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsworthy M.R., Rogasch N.C., Ballinger S., Graetz L., Van Dam J.M., Harris R., et al. Age-related decline of neuroplasticity to intermittent theta burst stimulation of the lateral prefrontal cortex and its relationship with late-life memory performance. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2020;131(9):2181&#x2013;2191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32693192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Burgos G., Miyamae T., Reddy N., Dawkins S., Chen C., Hill A., et al. Mechanisms regulating the properties of inhibition-based gamma oscillations in primate prefrontal and parietal cortices. Cereb. Cortex. 2023;33(12):7754&#x2013;7770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10267634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36971419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon M. Artifacts created by imbalanced electrode impedance. Am. J. EEG Technol. 1980;20(4):149&#x2013;160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon P.C., Jovellar D.B., Song Y., Zrenner C., Belardinelli P., Siebner H.R., et al. Recording brain responses to TMS of primary motor cortex by EEG - utility of an optimized sham procedure. Neuroimage. 2021;118708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34743050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon P.C., Song Y., Jovellar B., Belardinelli P., Ziemann U. No evidence for interaction between TMS-EEG responses and sensory inputs. Brain Stimul. 2023;16(1):25&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36567062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon P.C., Song Y.F., Jovellar D.B., Rostami M., Belardinelli P., Ziemann U. Untangling TMS-EEG responses caused by TMS versus sensory input using optimized sham control and GABAergic challenge. J. Physiol. 2023;601(10):1981&#x2013;1998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36965075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorjan D., Gramann K., De Pauw K., Marusic U. Removal of movement-induced EEG artifacts: current state of the art and guidelines. J. Neural Eng. 2022;19(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35147512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosseries O., Sarasso S., Casarotto S., Boly M., Schnakers C., Napolitani M., et al. On the cerebral origin of EEG responses to TMS: insights from severe cortical lesions. Brain Stimul. 2015;8:142&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25481074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandchamp R., Delorme A. Single-trial normalization for event-related spectral decomposition reduces sensitivity to noisy trials. Front. Psychol. 2011;2:236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3183439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21994498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gran&#xf6; I., Mutanen T.P., Nieminen A.E., Nieminen J.O., Souza V.H., Ilmoniemi R.J., et al. The dependency of TMS-evoked potentials on electric-field orientation in the cortex. bioRxiv. 2025;2025(01)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40311844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray W.A., Palmer J.A., Wolf S.L., Borich M.R. Abnormal EEG responses to TMS during the cortical silent period are associated with hand function in chronic stroke. Neurorehabil. Neural Repair. 2017;31(7):666&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5526104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene C., Connolly R., Brennan D., Laffan A., O'Keeffe E., Zaporojan L., et al. Blood-brain barrier disruption and sustained systemic inflammation in individuals with long COVID-associated cognitive impairment. Nat. Neurosci. 2024;27(3):421&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10917679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38388736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grefkes C., Fink G.R. Recovery from stroke: current concepts and future perspectives. Neurol. Res. Pract. 2020;2:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7650109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groppa S., Oliviero A., Eisen A., Quartarone A., Cohen L.G., Mall V., et al. A practical guide to diagnostic transcranial magnetic stimulation: Report of an IFCN committee. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2012;123(5):858&#x2013;882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4890546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22349304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossmann A., Morlet J. Decomposition of Hardy functions into square integrable wavelets of constant shape. SIAM J. Math. Anal. 1984;15(4):723&#x2013;736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra A., L&#xf3;pez-Alonso V., Cheeran B., Suppa A. Variability in non-invasive brain stimulation studies: reasons and results. Neurosci. Lett. 2020;719</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra A., Rocchi L., Grego A., Berardi F., Luisi C., Ferreri F. Contribution of TMS and TMS-EEG to the understanding of mechanisms underlying physiological brain aging. Brain Sci. 2021;11(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33810206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidali G., Zazio A., Lucarelli D., Marcantoni E., Stango A., Barchiesi G., et al. Effects of transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) current direction and pulse waveform on cortico-cortical connectivity: A registered report TMS-EEG study. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37649453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunaydin S., Soysal A., Atay T., Arpaci B. Motor and occipital cortex excitability in migraine patients. Can. J. Neurol. Sci. 2006;33(1):63&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16583724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibollahi Saatlou F., Rogasch N.C., McNair N.A., Biabani M., Pillen S.D., Marshall T.R., et al. MAGIC: An open-source MATLAB toolbox for external control of transcranial magnetic stimulation devices. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(5):1189&#x2013;1191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29885859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadas I., Hadar A., Lazarovits A., Daskalakis Z.J., Zangen A. Right prefrontal activation predicts ADHD and its severity: A TMS-EEG study in young adults. Prog. Neuropsychopharmacol. Biol. Psychiatry. 2021;111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadas I., Sun Y., Lioumis P., Zomorrodi R., Jones B., Voineskos D., et al. Association of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation treatment with subgenual cingulate hyperactivity in patients with major depressive disorder a secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw. Open. 2019;6(2) e195578-e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6551850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31167023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadas I., Zomorrodi R., Hill A.T., Sun Y., Fitzgerald P.B., Blumberger D.M., et al. Subgenual cingulate connectivity and hippocampal activation are related to MST therapeutic and adverse effects. Transl. Psychiatry. 2020:392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7655940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33173028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen M.S., Ilmoniemi R.J. Interpreting magnetic fields of the brain: minimum norm estimates. Med. Biol. Eng. Compu. 1994;32(1):35&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8182960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamaneh M.B., Chitravas N., Kaiboriboon K., Lhatoo S.D., Loparo K.A. Automated removal of EKG artifact from EEG data using independent component analysis and continuous wavelet transformation. I.E.E.E. Trans. Biomed. Eng. 2014;61(6):1634&#x2013;1641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han S., Li X.X., Wei S., Zhao D., Ding J., Xu Y., et al. Orbitofrontal cortex-hippocampus potentiation mediates relief for depression: A randomized double-blind trial and TMS-EEG study. Cell Rep. Med. 2023;4(6) 101060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10313932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37263267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannula H., Ilmoniemi R.J. Basic principles of navigated TMS. Navigated Transcranial Magnetic Stimulat. Neurosurgery. 2017:3&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson P.T., Attal N., Baron R., Cruccu G. Toward a definition of pharmacoresistant neuropathic pain. Eur. J. Pain (London, England) 2009;13(5):439&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19324579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao W., Dai X., Wei M., Li S., Peng M., Xue Q., et al. Efficacy of transcranial photobiomodulation in the treatment for major depressive disorder: A TMS-EEG and pilot study. Photodermatol. Photoimmunol. Photomed. 2024;40(2) e12957-e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38470033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harita S., Momi D., Mazza F., Griffiths J.D. Mapping inter-individual functional connectivity variability in TMS targets for major depressive disorder. Front. Psychiatry / Front. Res. Foundat. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9260048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35815008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harquel S., Bacle T., Beynel L., Marendaz C., Chauvin A., David O. Mapping dynamical properties of cortical microcircuits using robotized TMS and EEG: towards functional cytoarchitectonics. Neuroimage. 2016;135:115&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27153976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harquel S., Cadic-Melchior A., Morishita T., Fleury L., Ceroni M., Menoud P., et al. Brain oscillatory modes as a proxy of stroke recovery. Neurorehabil. Neural Repair. 2025 15459683251363241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12686178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41273103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harquel S., Cadic-Melchior A., Morishita T., Fleury L., Witon A., Ceroni M., et al. Stroke recovery-related changes in cortical reactivity based on modulation of intracortical inhibition. Stroke. 2024;55(6):1629&#x2013;1640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38639087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan U., Pillen S., Zrenner C., Bergmann T.O. The Brain electrophysiological recording &amp; stimulation (BEST) toolbox. Brain Stimul. 2022;15(1):109&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34826626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haxel L., Ahola O., Belardinelli P., Ermolova M., Humaidan D., Macke J.H., et al. Decoding Motor excitability in TMS using EEG-features: an exploratory machine learning approach. IEEE Trans. Neural Syst. Rehabil. Eng. 2024:Pp.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40030511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache S. The International Classification of Headache Disorders, 3rd edition (beta version). Cephalalgia 2013;33(9):629-808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helfrich C., Pierau S.S., Freitag C.M., Roeper J., Ziemann U., Bender S. Monitoring cortical excitability during repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in children with ADHD: a single-blind, sham-controlled TMS-EEG study. PLoS One. 2012;7(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3503808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23185537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heller L., van Hulsteyn D.B. Brain stimulation using electromagnetic sources: theoretical aspects. Biophys. J . 1992;63(1):129&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1262130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1420862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helling R.M., Perenboom M.J.L., Bauer P.R., Carpay J.A., Sander J.W., Ferrari M.D., et al. TMS-evoked EEG potentials demonstrate altered cortical excitability in migraine with aura. Brain Topogr. 2023;36(2):269&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10014725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36781512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensel L., Grefkes C., Tscherpel C., Ringmaier C., Kraus D., Hamacher S., et al. Intermittent theta burst stimulation applied during early rehabilitation after stroke: study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2019;9(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6955550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31892668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Pavon J.C., Kugiumtzis D., Zrenner C., Kimiskidis V.K., Metsomaa J. Removing artifacts from TMS-evoked EEG: A methods review and a unifying theoretical framework. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022 109591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35421514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Pavon J.C., Metsomaa J., Mutanen T., Stenroos M., Maki H., Ilmoniemi R.J., et al. Uncovering neural independent components from highly artifactual TMS-evoked EEG data. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2012;209(1):144&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22687937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez-Pavon J.C., Veniero D., Bergmann T.O., Belardinelli P., Bortoletto M., Casarotto S., et al. TMS combined with EEG: Recommendations and open issues for data collection and analysis. Brain Stimul. 2023;16(2):567&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herring J.D., Thut G., Jensen O., Bergmann T.O. Attention modulates TMS-locked alpha oscillations in the visual cortex. J. Neurosci. 2015;35(43):14435&#x2013;14447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4623224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26511236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill A.T., Hadas I., Zomorrodi R., Voineskos D., Fitzgerald P.B., Blumberger D.M., et al. Characterizing cortical oscillatory responses in major depressive disorder before and after convulsive therapy: a TMS-EEG study. J. Affect. Disord. 2021;287:78&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33774319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirano Y., Uhlhaas P.J. Current findings and perspectives on aberrant neural oscillations in schizophrenia. Psychiatry Clin. Neurosci. 2021;75(12):358&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34558155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holiga &#x160;., Hipp J.F., Chatham C.H., Garces P., Spooren W., D&#x2019;Ardhuy X.L., et al. Patients with autism spectrum disorders display reproducible functional connectivity alterations. Sci. Transl. Med. 2019;11(481)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30814340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt F., Ozdamar O. Effects of rate (0.3-40/s) on simultaneously recorded auditory brainstem, middle and late responses using deconvolution. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2016;127(2):1589&#x2013;1602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26639172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hom&#xf6;lle S., Oostenveld R. Using a structured-light 3D scanner to improve EEG source modeling with more accurate electrode positions. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2019;326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31376413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou L.J., Song Z., Pan Z.J., Cheng J.L., Yu Y., Wang J. Decreased activation of subcortical brain areas in the motor fatigue state: an fMRI study. Front. Psychol. 2016;7:1154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4971080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27536264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howlin P., Arciuli J., Begeer S., Brock J., Clarke K., Costley D., et al. Research on adults with autism spectrum disorder: roundtable report. J. Intellect. Dev. Disabil. 2015;40(4):388&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoy K.E., Coyle H., Gainsford K., Hill A.T., Bailey N.W., Fitzgerald P.B. Investigating neurophysiological markers of impaired cognition in schizophrenia. Schizophr. Res. 2021;233:34&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34225025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hshieh T.T., Schmitt E.M., Fong T.G., Arnold S., Cavallari M., Dickerson B.C., et al. Successful aging after elective surgery II: Study design and methods. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2023;71(1):46&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9870853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36214228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu L., Xiao P., Zhang Z.G., Mouraux A., Iannetti G.D. Single-trial time-frequency analysis of electrocortical signals: baseline correction and beyond. Neuroimage. 2014;84:876&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24084069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y.T., Tan Z.L., Hirjak D., Northoff G. Brain-wide changes in excitation-inhibition balance of major depressive disorder: a systematic review of topographic patterns of GABA- and glutamatergic alterations. Mol. Psychiatry. 2023;28(8):3257&#x2013;3266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37495889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, G., Hu Z, Zhang L, Li L, Liang Z, Zhang Z. Removal of eye-blinking artifacts by ICA in cross-modal long-term EEG recording. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc 2020(Jul;2020):217-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33017968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y.-Z., Edwards M.J., Rounis E., Bhatia K.P., Rothwell J.C. Theta burst stimulation of the human motor cortex. Neuron. 2005;45(2):201&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15664172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z., Wang Y., Yan Y., Liu Y., Chen J., Liu H., et al. Identifying neural circuitry abnormalities in neuropathic pain with transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalogram co-registration. Neurotherapeutics. 2025;22(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12014317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39613525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber R., M&#xe4;ki H., Rosanova M., Casarotto S., Canali P., Casali A.G., et al. Human cortical excitability increases with time awake. Cereb. Cortex. 2013;23(2):332&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3539451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22314045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui J., Zomorrodi R., Lioumis P., Salavati B., Rajji T.K., Chen R., et al. Pharmacological mechanisms of interhemispheric signal propagation: a TMS-EEG study. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2020;45(6):932&#x2013;939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31357206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel F.C., Steven B., Hoppe J., Heise K., Thomalla G., Cohen L.G., et al. Deficient intracortical inhibition (SICI) during movement preparation after chronic stroke. Neurology. 2009;72(20):1766&#x2013;1772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2683737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iaccarino H.F., Singer A.C., Martorell A.J., Rudenko A., Gao F., Gillingham T.Z., et al. Gamma frequency entrainment attenuates amyloid load and modifies microglia. Nature. 2016;540(7632):230&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5656389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27929004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilmoniemi, R.J., Hernandez-Pavon JC, Makela NN, Metsomaa J, Mutanen TP, Stenroos M, et al. Dealing with artifacts in TMS-evoked EEG. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc 2015;2015:230-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26736242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilmoniemi R.J., Kicic D. Methodology for combined TMS and EEG. Brain Topogr. 2010;22(4):233&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20012350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilmoniemi R.J., Rogasch N.C., Casarotto S. In: The Oxford Handbook of Transcranial Stimulation. 2nd ed: Wassermann E.M., Peterchev A.V., Ziemann U., Siebner H.R., Walsh V., Lisanby S.H., editors. Oxford University Press; 2024. TMS measures explored by EEG recordings; pp. 508&#x2013;538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilmoniemi R.J., Ruohonen J., Karhu J. Transcranial magnetic stimulation&#x2013;a new tool for functional imaging of the brain. Crit. Rev. Biomed. Eng. 1999;27(3&#x2013;5):241&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10864281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilmoniemi R.J., Sarvas J. Mit Press; 2019. Brain Signals: Physics and Mathematics of MEG and EEG.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilmoniemi R.J., Virtanen J., Ruohonen J., Karhu J., Aronen H.J., N&#xe4;&#xe4;t&#xe4;nen R., et al. Neuronal responses to magnetic stimulation reveal cortical reactivity and connectivity. Neuroreport. 1997;8:3537&#x2013;3540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9427322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iramina K., Maeno T., Nonaka Y., Ueno S. Measurement of evoked electroencephalography induced by transcranial magnetic stimulation. J. Appl. Phys. 2003;93(10):6718&#x2013;6720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumi S., Takase M., Arita M., Masakado Y., Kimura A., Chino N. Transcranial magnetic stimulation-induced changes in EEG and responses recorded from the scalp of healthy humans. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1997;103(2):319&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9277634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jack C.R., Jr., Holtzman D.M. Biomarker modeling of Alzheimer's disease. Neuron. 2013;80(6):1347&#x2013;1358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3928967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24360540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson A.F., Bolger D.J. The neurophysiological bases of EEG and EEG measurement: a review for the rest of us. Psychophysiology. 2014;51(11):1061&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25039563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadidi A.F., Ryszczuk A., Voso D., Mastropasqua A., Tomasevic L., Siebner H.R. Open-source toolbox for EEG-based Stimulation Monitoring (EStiMo) of brain states during TMS burst delivery. Brain Stimulation: Basic, Translational, and Clinical Research in Neuromodulation. 2025;18(1):22&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39647614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamil Z., Saisanen L., Demjan M., Reijonen J., Julkunen P. The Effect of stimulation intensity, sampling frequency, and sample synchronization in TMS-EEG on the TMS pulse artifact amplitude and duration. IEEE Trans. Neural Syst. Rehabilit. Eng. 2024;32:2612&#x2013;2620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39024076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jannati A., Ryan M.A., Kaye H.L., Tsuboyama M., Rotenberg A. Biomarkers obtained by transcranial magnetic stimulation in neurodevelopmental disorders. J. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;39(2):135&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8810902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34366399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssens S.E.W., Sack A.T. Spontaneous fluctuations in oscillatory brain state cause differences in transcranial magnetic stimulation effects within and between individuals. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2021;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34924982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarczok T.A., Fritsch M., Kr&#xf6;ger A., Schneider A.L., Althen H., Siniatchkin M., et al. Maturation of interhemispheric signal propagation in autism spectrum disorder and typically developing controls: a TMS-EEG study. J. Neural Transm. 2016;123(8):925&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27177879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin G., Chen J., Du J., He L., Qi L., Wu D., et al. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation to treat benign epilepsy with centrotemporal spikes. Brain Stimul. 2022;15(3):601&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35427811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joy M.T., Carmichael S.T. Encouraging an excitable brain state: mechanisms of brain repair in stroke. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2021;22(1):38&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33184469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julkunen P., Kimiskidis V.K., Belardinelli P. Bridging the gap: TMS-EEG from lab to clinic. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35041855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julkunen P., P&#xe4;&#xe4;kk&#xf6;nen A., Hukkanen T., K&#xf6;n&#xf6;nen M., Tiihonen P., Vanhatalo S., et al. Efficient reduction of stimulus artefact in TMS-EEG by epithelial short-circuiting by mini-punctures. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2008;119(2):475&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18063410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julkunen P., S&#xe4;is&#xe4;nen L., K&#xf6;n&#xf6;nen M., Vanninen R., K&#xe4;lvi&#xe4;inen R., Mervaala E. TMS-EEG reveals impaired intracortical interactions and coherence in Unverricht-Lundborg type progressive myoclonus epilepsy (EPM1) Epilepsy Res. 2013;106(1&#x2013;2):103&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23642573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung T.P., Makeig S., Humphries C., Lee T.W., McKeown M.J., Iragui V., et al. Removing electroencephalographic artifacts by blind source separation. Psychophysiology. 2000;37(2):163&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10731767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juntunen A., M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4; S., K&#xf6;n&#xf6;nen M., Kallioniemi E., Niskanen E., Kaarre O., et al. Cortical thickness is inversely associated with transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked N45 potential among young adults whose heavy drinking began in adolescence. Alcohol, Clin. Exp. Res. 2023;47(7):1341&#x2013;1351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37526579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurczak M., Kolodziej M., Majkowski A. Implementation of a convolutional neural network for eye blink artifacts removal from the electroencephalography signal. Front. Neurosci. 2022;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8874023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35221897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaarre O., Kallioniemi E., K&#xf6;n&#xf6;nen M., Tolmunen T., Kekkonen V., Kivim&#xe4;ki P., et al. Heavy alcohol use in adolescence is associated with altered cortical activity: a combined TMS-EEG study. Addict. Biol. 2018;23(1):268&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28008690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabir A., Dhami P., Dussault Gomez M.A., Blumberger D.M., Daskalakis Z.J., Moreno S., et al. Influence of large-scale brain state dynamics on the evoked response to brain stimulation. J. Neurosci. 2024;44(39)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11426374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39164105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S., Kes&#xe4;niemi M., Nikouline V.V., Karhu J., Ollikainen M., Holi M., et al. Ethanol modulates cortical activity: direct evidence with combined TMS and EEG. Neuroimage. 2001;14(2):322&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11467906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S., Komssi S., Wilenius J., Ilmoniemi R.J. Prefrontal TMS produces smaller EEG responses than motor-cortex TMS: implications for rTMS treatment in depression. Psychopharmacology. 2005;181(1):16&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15719214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S., Komssi S., Wilenius J., Ilmoniemi R.J. Prefrontal transcranial magnetic stimulation produces intensity-dependent EEG responses in humans. Neuroimage. 2005;24(4):955&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15670672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S., Wilenius J. Effects of alcohol on TMS-evoked N100 responses. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2007;166(1):104&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17727957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S., Wilenius J., Nikulin V.V., Ollikainen M., Ilmoniemi R.J. Alcohol reduces prefrontal cortical excitability in humans: a combined TMS and EEG study. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2003;28(4):747&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12655321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalitzin S.N., Velis D.N., da Silva F.H. Stimulation-based anticipation and control of state transitions in the epileptic brain. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior : E&amp;B. 2010;17(3):310&#x2013;323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20163993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallioniemi E., Daskalakis Z.J. Identifying novel biomarkers with TMS-EEG - methodological possibilities and challenges. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35623474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallioniemi E., Saari J., Ferreri F., M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4; S. TMS-EEG responses across the lifespan: measurement, methods for characterisation and identified responses. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34856320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneko N., Wada M., Nakajima S., Takano M., Taniguchi K., Honda S., et al. Neuroplasticity of the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in patients with treatment-resistant depression as indexed with paired associative stimulation: a TMS&#x2013;EEG study. Cereb. Cortex. 2024;34(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10839839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38204301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappenman E.S., Luck S.J. The effects of electrode impedance on data quality and statistical significance in ERP recordings. Psychophysiology. 2010;47(5):888&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2902592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20374541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappos L., Wolinsky J.S., Giovannoni G., Arnold D.L., Wang Q., Bernasconi C., et al. Contribution of relapse-independent progression vs relapse-associated worsening to overall confirmed disability accumulation in typical relapsing multiple sclerosis in a pooled analysis of 2 randomized clinical trials. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(9):1132&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7281382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kariminezhad S., Zomorrodi R., Zrenner C., Blumberger D.M., Ameis S.H., Lin H.Y., et al. Assessing plasticity in the primary sensory cortex and its relation with atypical tactile reactivity in autism: a TMS-EEG protocol. PLoS One. 2024;19(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11594394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39591434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenemans J.L. Specific proactive and generic reactive inhibition. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2015;56:115&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26116545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerwin L.J., Keller C.J., Wu W., Narayan M., Etkin A. Test-retest reliability of transcranial magnetic stimulation EEG evoked potentials. Brain Stimul. 2018;11:536&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29342443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khademullah C.S., Aqrabawi A.J., Place K.M., Dargaei Z., Liang X., Pressey J.C., et al. Cortical interneuron-mediated inhibition delays the onset of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2020;143(3):800&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32203578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khedr E.M., Ahmed M.A., Mohamed K.A. Motor and visual cortical excitability in migraineurs patients with or without aura: transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neurophysiol. Clinique = Clin. Neurophysiol. 2006;36(1):13&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16530139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan M.C., Vucic S., Cheah B.C., Turner M.R., Eisen A., Hardiman O., et al. Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Lancet. 2011;377(9769):942&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiernan M.C., Vucic S., Talbot K., McDermott C.J., Hardiman O., Shefner J.M., et al. Improving clinical trial outcomes in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2021;17(2):104&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7747476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33340024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilavik B.E., Zaepffel M., Brovelli A., MacKay W.A., Riehle A. The ups and downs of &#x3b2; oscillations in sensorimotor cortex. Exp. Neurol. 2013;245:15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23022918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimiskidis V.K., Koutlis C., Tsimpiris A., K&#xe4;lvi&#xe4;inen R., Ryvlin P., Kugiumtzis D. Transcranial magnetic stimulation combined with EEG reveals covert states of elevated excitability in the human epileptic brain. Int. J. Neural Syst. 2015;25(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25986753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimiskidis V.K., Kugiumtzis D., Papagiannopoulos S., Vlaikidis N. Transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) modulates epileptiform discharges in patients with frontal lobe epilepsy: a preliminary EEG-TMS study. Int. J. Neural Syst. 2013;23(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23273131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimiskidis V.K., Tsimpiris A., Ryvlin P., Kalviainen R., Koutroumanidis M., Valentin A., et al. TMS combined with EEG in genetic generalized epilepsy: a phase II diagnostic accuracy study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2017;128(2):367&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28007469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchhoff, M., Humaidan, D., Ziemann U. Closed-Loop Phase Selection in EEG-TMS Using Bayesian Optimization. 2024 IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics (SMC)2024. p. 1730-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkovski M., Enticott P.G., Fitzgerald P.B. A review of the role of female gender in autism spectrum disorders. J. Autism Dev. Disord. 2013;43(11):2584&#x2013;2603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23525974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkovski M., Hill A.T., Rogasch N.C., Saeki T., Fitzgibbon B.M., Yang J., et al. A single- and paired-pulse TMS-EEG investigation of the N100 and long interval cortical inhibition in autism spectrum disorder. Brain Stimul. 2022;15(1):229&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkovski, M., Rogasch, N.C., Saeki T, Fitzgibbon BM, Enticott PG, Fitzgerald PB. Single pulse transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalogram reveals no electrophysiological abnormality in adults with high-functioning autism spectrum disorder. J. Child Adolescent Psychopharmacol., 7. p. 606-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27284688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Altomare D., Benussi A., Br&#xe9;chet L., Casula E.P., Dodich A., et al. The emerging field of non-invasive brain stimulation in Alzheimer's disease. Brain. 2024;147(12):4003&#x2013;4016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11734340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39562009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Bonn&#xec; S., Casula E.P., Iosa M., Paolucci S., Pellicciari M.C., et al. Effect of cerebellar stimulation on gait and balance recovery in patients with hemiparetic stroke: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76(2):170&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30476999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Bonni S., Pellicciari M.C., Casula E.P., Mancini M., Esposito R., et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation of the precuneus enhances memory and neural activity in prodromal Alzheimer's disease. Neuroimage. 2018;169:302&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29277405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Casula E.P., Bonn&#xec; S., Borghi I., Assogna M., Di Lorenzo F., et al. Effects of 52&#xa0;weeks of precuneus rTMS in Alzheimer's disease patients: a randomized trial. Alzheimers Res. Ther. 2025;17(1):69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11963669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40176122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Casula E.P., Bonn&#xec; S., Borghi I., Assogna M., Minei M., et al. Precuneus magnetic stimulation for Alzheimer's disease: a randomized, sham-controlled trial. Brain. 2022;145(11):3776&#x2013;3786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9679166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36281767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Di Lorenzo F., Bonni S., Ponzo V., Caltagirone C., Martorana A. Impaired LTP- but not LTD-like cortical plasticity in Alzheimer's disease patients. J. Alzheimer's Dis. : JAD. 2012;31(3):593&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22647254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Esposito Z., Kusayanagi H., Monteleone F., Codeca C., Di Lorenzo F., et al. CSF tau levels influence cortical plasticity in Alzheimer's disease patients. J. Alzheimer's Dis. : JAD. 2011;26(1):181&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21606570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch G., Motta C., Bonn&#xec; S., Pellicciari M.C., Picazio S., Casula E.P., et al. Effect of rotigotine vs placebo on cognitive functions among patients with mild to moderate Alzheimer disease: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw. Open. 2020;3(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7364345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komssi S., Aronen H.J., Huttunen J., Kes&#xe4;niemi M., Soinne L., Nikouline V.V., et al. Ipsi- and contralateral EEG reactions to transcranial magnetic stimulation. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2002;113(2):175&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11856623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komssi S., K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S. The novelty value of the combined use of electroencephalography and transcranial magnetic stimulation for neuroscience research. Brain Res. Rev. 2006;52(1):183&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16545462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komssi S., K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S., Ilmoniemi R.J. The effect of stimulus intensity on brain responses evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2004;21(3):154&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6871924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14755835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondziella D., Bender A., Diserens K., van Erp W., Estraneo A., Formisano R., et al. European Academy of Neurology guideline on the diagnosis of coma and other disorders of consciousness. Eur. J. Neurol. 2020;27(5):741&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32090418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondziella D., Friberg C.K., Frokjaer V.G., Fabricius M., M&#xf8;ller K. Preserved consciousness in vegetative and minimal conscious states: systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2016;87(5):485&#x2013;492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26139551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koob G.F., Bloom F.E. Cellular and molecular mechanisms of drug dependence. Science. 1988;242(4879):715&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2903550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koob G.F., Volkow N.D. Neurocircuitry of Addiction. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2010;35(1):217&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2805560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19710631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koponen L.M., Nieminen J.O., Ilmoniemi R.J. Multi-locus transcranial magnetic stimulation-theory and implementation. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(4):849&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29627272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koponen L.M., Nieminen J.O., Mutanen T.P., Ilmoniemi R.J. Noninvasive extraction of microsecond-scale dynamics from human motor cortex. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2018;39(6):2405&#x2013;2411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6866442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29498765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korhonen R.J., Hernandez-Pavon J.C., Metsomaa J., Maki H., Ilmoniemi R.J., Sarvas J. Removal of large muscle artifacts from transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked EEG by independent component analysis. Med. Biol. Eng. Compu. 2011;49(4):397&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21331656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kugiumtzis D., Kimiskidis V.K. Direct causal networks for the study of transcranial magnetic stimulation effects on focal epileptiform discharges. Int. J. Neural Syst. 2015;25(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25761527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasagna-Reeves C.A., Castillo-Carranza D.L., Sengupta U., Clos A.L., Jackson G.R., Kayed R. Tau oligomers impair memory and induce synaptic and mitochondrial dysfunction in wild-type mice. Mol. Neurodegener. 2011;6:39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3224595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21645391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laureys S., Celesia G.G., Cohadon F., Lavrijsen J., Le&#xf3;n-Carri&#xf3;n J., Sannita W.G., et al. Unresponsive wakefulness syndrome: a new name for the vegetative state or apallic syndrome. BMC Med. 2010;8:68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2987895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21040571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M.H., Perl D.P., Steiner J., Pasternack N., Li W., Maric D., et al. Neurovascular injury with complement activation and inflammation in COVID-19. Brain. 2022;145(7):2555&#x2013;2568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9278212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35788639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann D., Skrandies W. Reference-free identification of components of checkerboard-evoked multichannel potential fields. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1980;48(6):609&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6155251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitner M., Opriessnig P., Ropele S., Schmidt R., Leal-Garcia M., Fellner M., et al. Changes in thalamic functional connectivity in post-Covid patients with and without fatigue. Neuroimage. 2024;301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39419425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leodori G., Belvisi D., De Bartolo M.I., Fabbrini A., Costanzo M., Vial F., et al. Re-emergent tremor in Parkinson's disease: the role of the motor cortex. Mov. Disord. 2020;35(6):1002&#x2013;1011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8448579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32175656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leodori G., De Bartolo M.I., Guerra A., Fabbrini A., Rocchi L., Latorre A., et al. Motor cortical network excitability in Parkinson's disease. Mov. Disord. 2022;37(4):734&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35001420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leodori G., De Bartolo M.I., Piervincenzi C., Mancuso M., Ojha A., Costanzo M., et al. Mapping Motor cortical network excitability and connectivity changes in de novo Parkinson's disease. Mov. Disord. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38924157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leodori G., Fabbrini A., De Bartolo M.I., Costanzo M., Asci F., Palma V., et al. Cortical mechanisms underlying variability in intermittent theta-burst stimulation-induced plasticity: a TMS-EEG study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2021;132(10):2519&#x2013;2531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leodori G., Fabbrini A., Suppa A., Mancuso M., Tikoo S., Belvisi D., et al. Effective connectivity abnormalities in Lewy body disease with visual hallucinations. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;156:156&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37952445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leodori G., Mancuso M., Maccarrone D., Tartaglia M., Ianniello A., Certo F., et al. Neural bases of motor fatigue in multiple sclerosis: a multimodal approach using neuromuscular assessment and TMS-EEG. Neurobiol. Dis. 2023;180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36906073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leodori G., Mancuso M., Maccarrone D., Tartaglia M., Ianniello A., Certo F., et al. Insight into motor fatigue mechanisms in natalizumab treated multiple sclerosis patients with wearing off. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):17654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11291752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39085330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leske S., Dalal S.S. Reducing power line noise in EEG and MEG data via spectrum interpolation. Neuroimage. 2019;189:763&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6456018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30639330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy-Lamdan O., Zifman N., Sasson E., Efrati S., Hack D.C., Tanne D., et al. Evaluation of white matter integrity utilizing the DELPHI (TMS-EEG) system. Front. Neurosci. 2020;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33408607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Virtanen J.P., Oeltermann A., Schwarz C., Giese M.A., Ziemann U., et al. Lifting the veil on the dynamics of neuronal activities evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Elife. 2017;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5722613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29165241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Wang Y., Li W., Yang Y., Xia X. Measure functional network and cortical excitability in post-anoxic patients with unresponsive wakefulness syndrome diagnosed by behavioral scales. Front. Neurosci. 2023;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9874310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36711155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C.T., Juan C.H., Lin H.C., Cheng C.M., Wu H.T., Yang B.H., et al. Cortical excitatory and inhibitory correlates of the fronto-limbic circuit in major depression and differential effects of left frontal brain stimulation in a randomized sham-controlled trial. J. Affect. Disord. 2022;311:364&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35618168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Li X., Li J., Liu J., Luo R., Li Y., et al. Neurophysiological markers of disease severity and cognitive dysfunction in major depressive disorder: A TMS-EEG study. Int. J. Clin. Health Psychol. 2024;24(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11402404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39282218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Li X., Liu J., Wei S., Zhou D., Wang D., et al. Relationships between clinical symptoms, cognitive functioning, and TMS-evoked potential features in patients with major depressive disorder. Prog. Neuropsychopharmacol. Biol. Psychiatry. 2025;136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39550059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Chen M., Liu Q., Zheng C., Yu C., Hou G., et al. TMS-evoked potential in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex to assess the severity of depression disease: a TMS-EEG study. Front. Pharmacol. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10277673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37342593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby P. Endothelial inflammation in COVID-19. Science. 2024;386(6725):972&#x2013;973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39607920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light, G.A., Williams, L.E., Minow F, Sprock J, Rissling A, Sharp R, et al. Electroencephalography (EEG) and event-related potentials (ERPs) with human participants. Curr Protoc Neurosci 2010;Chapter 6:Unit 6 25 1-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2909037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20578033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin L.I. A concordance correlation coefficient to evaluate reproducibility. Biometrics. 1989;45(1):255&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2720055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lins O.G., Picton T.W., Berg P., Scherg M. Ocular artifacts in recording EEGs and event-related potentials. II: Source dipoles and source components. Brain Topogr. 1993;6(1):65&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8260328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lioumis P., Kicic D., Savolainen P., M&#xe4;kel&#xe4; J.P., K&#xe4;hk&#xf6;nen S. Reproducibility of TMS-evoked EEG responses. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2009;30(4):1387&#x2013;1396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6870729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18537115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lioumis P., Roine T., Grano I., Aydogan D.B., Ukharova E., Souza V.H., et al. Optimization of TMS target engagement: current state and future perspectives. Front. Neurosci. 2025;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11814169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39944889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lioumis P., Rosanova M. The role of neuronavigation in TMS-EEG studies: Current applications and future perspectives. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35872153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lissak I.A., Young M.J. Limitation of life sustaining therapy in disorders of consciousness: ethics and practice. Brain. 2024;147(7):2274&#x2013;2288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11224617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38387081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litvak V., Komssi S., Scherg M., Hoechstetter K., Classen J., Zaaroor M., et al. Artifact correction and source analysis of early electroencephalographic responses evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation over primary motor cortex. Neuroimage. 2007;37(1):56&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17574872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J.Z., Yao B., Siemionow V., Sahgal V., Wang X., Sun J., et al. Fatigue induces greater brain signal reduction during sustained than preparation phase of maximal voluntary contraction. Brain Res. 2005;1057(1&#x2013;2):113&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16129419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Liu A., Zhang X., Chen X., Qian R., Chen X. Removal of EMG artifacts from multichannel EEG signals using combined singular spectrum analysis and canonical correlation analysis. J Healthc Eng. 2019;2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6955116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31976053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q.-M., Lucas M., Badami F., Wu W., Etkin A., Yuan T.-F. Cortical plasticity differences in substance use disorders. Fundam. Res. 2024;4(6):1351&#x2013;1356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11670691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39734552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liuzzi G., Horniss V., Lechner P., Hoppe J., Heise K., Zimerman M., et al. Development of movement-related intracortical inhibition in acute to chronic subcortical stroke. Neurology. 2014;82:198&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24353337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loheswaran G., Barr M.S., Zomorrodi R., Rajji T.K., Blumberger D.M., Foll B.L., et al. Impairment of neuroplasticity in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex by alcohol. Sci. Rep. 2017;7(1):5276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5509647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28706262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Alonso V., Cheeran B., Rio-Rodriguez D., Fernandez-Del-Olmo M. Inter-individual variability in response to non-invasive brain stimulation paradigms. Brain Stimul. 2014;7(3):372&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24630849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lord C., Charman T., Havdahl A., Carbone P., Anagnostou E., Boyd B., et al. The Lancet Commission on the future of care and clinical research in autism. Lancet. 2022;399(10321):271&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34883054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucarelli D., Guidali G., Sulcova D., Zazio A., Bonfiglio N.S., Stango A., et al. Stimulation parameters recruit distinct cortico-cortical pathways: insights from microstate analysis on TMS-evoked potentials. Brain Topogr. 2025;38(3):39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11953218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40153104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luck S.J. second ed. MIT Press; 2014. An Introduction to the Event-Related Potential Technique.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludbrook J. Multiple comparison procedures updated. Clin. Exp. Pharmacol. Physiol. 1998;25(12):1032&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9888002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;scher C., Robbins T.W., Everitt B.J. The transition to compulsion in addiction. Nat. Rev. Neurosci. 2020;21(5):247&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32231315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly J.Q., Gaggioni G., Chellappa S.L., Papachilleos S., Brzozowski A., Borsu C., et al. Circadian regulation of human cortical excitability. Nat. Commun. 2016;7:11828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27339884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas A.I.R., Menon D.K., Manley G.T., Abrams M., Akerlund C., Andelic N., et al. Traumatic brain injury: progress and challenges in prevention, clinical care, and research. Lancet Neurol. 2022;21(11):1004&#x2013;1060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10427240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36183712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4; S., K&#xf6;n&#xf6;nen M., Kallioniemi E., Lakka T., Lintu N., Lindi V., et al. Development of cortical motor circuits between childhood and adulthood: A navigated TMS-HdEEG study. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2017;38(5):2599&#x2013;2615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6866783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28218489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;&#xe4;tt&#xe4; S., S&#xe4;is&#xe4;nen L., Kallioniemi E., Lakka T.A., Lintu N., Haapala E.A., et al. Maturation changes the excitability and effective connectivity of the frontal lobe: A developmental TMS-EEG study. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2019;40(8):2320&#x2013;2335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6865579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30648321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macaluso G.M., Pavesi G., Bonanini M., Mancia D., Gennari P.U. Motor-evoked potentials in masseter muscle by electrical and magnetic stimulation in intact alert man. Arch. Oral Biol. 1990;35(8):623&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2256816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maccabee P.J., Amassian V.E., Cracco R.Q., Cadwell J.A. An analysis of peripheral motor nerve stimulation in humans using the magnetic coil. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1988;70(6):524&#x2013;533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2461286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacFarlane M.P., Glenn T.C. Neurochemical cascade of concussion. Brain injury : [BI] 2015;29(2):139&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25587743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maekawa S., Al-Sarraj S., Kibble M., Landau S., Parnavelas J., Cotter D., et al. Cortical selective vulnerability in motor neuron disease: a morphometric study. Brain. 2004;127(Pt 6):1237&#x2013;1251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15130949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maertens de Noordhout A., Pepin J.L., Schoenen J., Delwaide P.J. Percutaneous magnetic stimulation of the motor cortex in migraine. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1992;85(2):110&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1373363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maest&#xfa; F., de Haan W., Busche M.A., DeFelipe J. Neuronal excitation/inhibition imbalance: core element of a translational perspective on Alzheimer pathophysiology. Ageing Res. Rev. 2021;69</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34029743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maidan I., Zifman N., Hausdorff J.M., Giladi N., Levy-Lamdan O., Mirelman A. A multimodal approach using TMS and EEG reveals neurophysiological changes in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat. Disord. 2021;89:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34216938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maiella M., Mencarelli L., Casula E.P., Borghi I., Assogna M., di Lorenzo F., et al. Breakdown of TMS evoked EEG signal propagation within the default mode network in Alzheimer's disease. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2024;167:177&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39332078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makeig S. Auditory event-related dynamics of the EEG spectrum and effects of exposure to tones. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1993;86(4):283&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7682932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makeig S., Bell A., Jung T.-P., Sejnowski T.J. Independent component analysis of electroencephalographic data. Adv. Neural Inf. Proces. Syst. 1995;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makeig S., Debener S., Onton J., Delorme A. Mining event-related brain dynamics. Trends Cogn. Sci. 2004;8(5):204&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15120678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;ki H., Ilmoniemi R.J. The relationship between peripheral and early cortical activation induced by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neurosci. Lett. 2010;478(1):24&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20435086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;ki H., Ilmoniemi R.J. Projecting out muscle artifacts from TMS-evoked EEG. Neuroimage. 2011;54(4):2706&#x2013;2710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21094260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makkonen M., Mutanen T., Metsomaa J., Zrenner C., Souza V., Ilmoniemi R. Real-time artifact detection and removal for closed-loop EEG-TMS. Int. J. Bioelectromagnet. 2021;23(2):1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malcharek M.J., Landgraf J., Hennig G., Sorge O., Aschermann J., Sablotzki A. Recordings of long-latency trigeminal somatosensory-evoked potentials in patients under general anaesthesia. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2011;122(5):1048&#x2013;1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso M., Cruciani A., Sveva V., Casula E., Brown K.E., Di Lazzaro V., et al. Changes in cortical activation by transcranial magnetic stimulation due to coil rotation are not attributable to cranial muscle activation. Brain Sci. 2024;14(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11048461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38671984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso M., Cruciani A., Sveva V., Casula E.P., Brown K., Rothwell J.C., et al. Somatosensory input in the context of transcranial magnetic stimulation coupled with electroencephalography: an evidence-based overview. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2023;155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37890602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso M., Sveva V., Cruciani A., Brown K., Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J., Rawji V., et al. Transcranial evoked potentials can be reliably recorded with active electrodes. Brain Sci. 2021;11(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33499330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maris E., Oostenveld R. Nonparametric statistical testing of EEG-and MEG-data. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2007;164(1):177&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17517438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markov N.T., Lindbergh C.A., Staffaroni A.M., Perez K., Stevens M., Nguyen K., et al. Age-related brain atrophy is not a homogenous process: different functional brain networks associate differentially with aging and blood factors. PNAS. 2022;119(49)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9894212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36459652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massimini M., Boly M., Casali A., Rosanova M., Tononi G. A perturbational approach for evaluating the brain's capacity for consciousness. Prog. Brain Res. 2009;177:201&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19818903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massimini M., Corbetta M., Sanchez-Vives M.V., Andrillon T., Deco G., Rosanova M., et al. Sleep-like cortical dynamics during wakefulness and their network effects following brain injury. Nat. Commun. 2024;15(1):7207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11341729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39174560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massimini M., Ferrarelli F., Esser S.K., Riedner B.A., Huber R., Murphy M., et al. Triggering sleep slow waves by transcranial magnetic stimulation. PNAS. 2007;104(20):8496&#x2013;8501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1895978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17483481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massimini M., Ferrarelli F., Huber R., Esser S.K., Singh H., Tononi G. Breakdown of cortical effective connectivity during sleep. Science. 2005;309(5744):2228&#x2013;2232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathalon D.H., Sohal V.S. Neural oscillations and synchrony in brain dysfunction and neuropsychiatric disorders: it's about time. JAMA Psychiat. 2015;72(8):840&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26039190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menardi A., Ozdemir R.A., Momi D., Tadayon E., Boucher P., Vallesi A., et al. Effect of group-based vs individualized stimulation site selection on reliability of network-targeted TMS. Neuroimage. 2022;119714</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36309331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mencarelli L., Torso M., Borghi I., Assogna M., Pezzopane V., Bonn&#xec; S., et al. Macro and micro structural preservation of grey matter integrity after 24 weeks of rTMS in Alzheimer's disease patients: a pilot study. Alzheimers Res. Ther. 2024;16(1):152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11225141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38970141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meneghini G., Engelhardt M., Burzlaff M., Zaykova A., Vajkoczy P., Lioumis P., et al. Probing cortical reactivity before and after brain tumor resection: A TMS-EEG case. Brain Stimul. 2025;18(1):19&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39644965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menke R.A.L., Proudfoot M., Talbot K., Turner M.R. The two-year progression of structural and functional cerebral MRI in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. NeuroImage Clin. 2018;17:953&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5752097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mennemeier M., Triggs W., Chelette K., Woods A., Kimbrell T., Dornhoffer J. Sham Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation Using Electrical Stimulation of the Scalp. Brain Stimul. 2009;2(3):168&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2774907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20160893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P., Geevasinga N., Yiannikas C., Howells J., Kiernan M., Vucic S. The sensitivity and specificity of threshold-tracking transcranial magnetic stimulation for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:478&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25843898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P., Geevasinga N., Yiannikas C., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Cortical contributions to the flail leg syndrome: pathophysiological insights. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2016;17(5&#x2013;6):389&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P., Higashihara M., van den Bos M., Geevasinga N., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Cortical hyperexcitability evolves with disease progression in ALS. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2020;7(5):733&#x2013;741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. ALS pathophysiology: insights from the split-hand phenomenon. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2014;125(1):186&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24051071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Cortical excitability varies across different muscles. J. Neurophysiol. 2018;120(3):1397&#x2013;1403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29975162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menon P., Yiannikas C., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Regional motor cortex dysfunction in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2019;6(8):1373&#x2013;1382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6689694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31402622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsomaa J., Belardinelli P., Ermolova M., Ziemann U., Zrenner C. Causal decoding of individual cortical excitability states. Neuroimage. 2021;245</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsomaa J., Sarvas J., Ilmoniemi R.J. Multi-trial evoked EEG and independent component analysis. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2014;228:15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24631321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsomaa J., Sarvas J., Ilmoniemi R.J. Blind source separation of event-related EEG/MEG. IEEE Trans. Biomed. Eng. 2016;64(9):2054&#x2013;2064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28113203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsomaa J., Song Y., Mutanen T.P., Gordon P.C., Ziemann U., Zrenner C., et al. Adapted beamforming: a robust and flexible approach for removing various types of artifacts from TMS-EEG data. Brain Topogr. 2024;37(5):659&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11634953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38598019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mevel K., Ch&#xe9;telat G., Eustache F., Desgranges B. The default mode network in healthy aging and Alzheimer's disease. Int. J. Alzheimers Dis. 2011;2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3132539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21760988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micera S., Caleo M., Chisari C., Hummel F.C., Pedrocchi A. Advanced neurotechnologies for the restoration of motor function. Neuron. 2020;105(4):604&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michel C.M., Murray M.M. Towards the utilization of EEG as a brain imaging tool. Neuroimage. 2012;61(2):371&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22227136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mimura Y., Nakajima S., Takano M., Wada M., Taniguchi K., Honda S., et al. Long-interval intracortical inhibition in individuals with autism spectrum disorders: A TMS-EEG study with source estimation analyses. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2025;178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40714440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miniussi C., Bortoletto M. Harnessing neural variability: Implications for brain research and non-invasive brain stimulation. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev. 2025;176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40752783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyauchi E., Ide M., Tachikawa H., Nemoto K., Arai T., Kawasaki M. A novel approach for assessing neuromodulation using phase-locked information measured with TMS-EEG. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6344580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30674902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moca V.V., Barzan H., Nagy-Dabacan A., Muresan R.C. Time-frequency super-resolution with superlets. Nat. Commun. 2021;12(1):337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7803992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33436585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moffa A.H., Nikolin S., Martin D., Loo C., Boonstra T.W. Reliability of transcranial magnetic stimulation evoked potentials to detect the effects of theta-burst stimulation of the prefrontal cortex. Neuroimage: Rep. 2022;2(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12172890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40567304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moisset X., Pereira B., Ciampi de Andrade D., Fontaine D., Lant&#xe9;ri-Minet M., Mawet J. Neuromodulation techniques for acute and preventive migraine treatment: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J. Headache Pain. 2020;21(1):142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7726868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokkink L.B., Terwee C.B., Patrick D.L., Alonso J., Stratford P.W., Knol D.L., et al. The COSMIN study reached international consensus on taxonomy, terminology, and definitions of measurement properties for health-related patient-reported outcomes. J. Clin. Epidemiol. 2010;63(7):737&#x2013;745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20494804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moliadze V., Lyzhko E., Schmanke T., Andreas S., Freitag C.M., Siniatchkin M. 1&#xa0;mA cathodal tDCS shows excitatory effects in children and adolescents: Insights from TMS evoked N100 potential. Brain Res. Bull. 2018;140:43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29625151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moliadze V., Zhao Y., Funke K. Effect of transcranial magnetic stimulation on single unit activity in cat primary visual cortex. J. Physiol. 2003;553(2):665&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2343567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12963791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molina V., Fern&#xe1;ndez-Linsenbarth I., Be&#xf1;o-Ruiz-de-la-Sierra R., Osorio-Iriarte E., Roig A., Arjona A., et al. Lower perturbational complexity index after transcranial magnetic stimulation in schizophrenia patients. Prog. Neuropsychopharmacol. Biol. Psychiatry. 2025;137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39828079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momi D., Ozdemir R.A., Tadayon E., Boucher P., Di Domenico A., Fasolo M., et al. Perturbation of resting-state network nodes preferentially propagates to structurally rather than functionally connected regions. Sci. Rep. 2021;11(1):12458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8203778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34127688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momi D., Ozdemir R.A., Tadayon E., Boucher P., Shafi M.M., Pascual-Leone A., et al. Network-level macroscale structural connectivity predicts propagation of transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neuroimage. 2021;229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33385561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momi D., Wang Z., Griffiths J.D. TMS-evoked responses are driven by recurrent large-scale network dynamics. Elife. 2023;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10121222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37083491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Kustner B., Martin C., Pastor L. Prevalence of psychotic disorders and its association with methodological issues. A systematic review and meta-analyses. PLoS One. 2018;13(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5896987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29649252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosher J.C., Leahy R.M., Lewis P.S. EEG and MEG: forward solutions for inverse methods. I.E.E.E. Trans. Biomed. Eng. 1999;46(3):245&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10097460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motta C., Di Lorenzo F., Ponzo V., Pellicciari M.C., Bonni S., Picazio S., et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation predicts cognitive decline in patients with Alzheimer's disease. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 2018;89(12):1237&#x2013;1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30464028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouraux A., Iannetti G.D. Nociceptive laser-evoked brain potentials do not reflect nociceptive-specific neural activity. J. Neurophysiol. 2009;101(6):3258&#x2013;3269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19339457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller J.K., Grigsby E.M., Prevosto V., Petraglia F.W., 3rd, Rao H., Deng Z.D., et al. Simultaneous transcranial magnetic stimulation and single-neuron recording in alert non-human primates. Nat. Neurosci. 2014;17(8):1130&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4115015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24974797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulleners W.M., Chronicle E.P., Vredeveld J.W., Koehler P.J. Visual cortex excitability in migraine before and after valproate prophylaxis: a pilot study using TMS. Eur. J. Neurol. 2002;9(1):35&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11784374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, S.C., Palmer LM, Nyffeler T, Muri RM, Larkum ME. Transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) inhibits cortical dendrites. eLife 2016;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4811769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26988796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanen T., M&#xe4;ki H., Ilmoniemi R.J. The effect of stimulus parameters on TMS-EEG muscle artifacts. Brain Stimul. 2013;6(3):371&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22902312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanen T., Nieminen J.O., Ilmoniemi R.J. TMS-evoked changes in brain-state dynamics quantified by using EEG data. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2013;7:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3635036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23630486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanen T.P., Biabani M., Sarvas J., Ilmoniemi R.J., Rogasch N.C. Source-based artifact-rejection techniques available in TESA, an open-source TMS-EEG toolbox. Brain Stimul. 2020;13(5):1349&#x2013;1351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32659484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanen T.P., Ilmoniemi I., Atti I., Metsomaa J., Ilmoniemi R.J. A simulation study: comparing independent component analysis and signal-space projection - source-informed reconstruction for rejecting muscle artifacts evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2024;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11112076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38784523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanen T.P., Kukkonen M., Nieminen J.O., Stenroos M., Sarvas J., Ilmoniemi R.J. Recovering TMS-evoked EEG responses masked by muscle artifacts. Neuroimage. 2016;139:157&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27291496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanen T.P., Metsomaa J., Liljander S., Ilmoniemi R.J. Automatic and robust noise suppression in EEG and MEG: The SOUND algorithm. Neuroimage. 2018;166:135&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29061529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutanen T.P., Metsomaa J., Makkonen M., Varone G., Marzetti L., Ilmoniemi R.J. Source-based artifact-rejection techniques for TMS-EEG. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36057330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mykland M.S., Uglem M., Neverdahl J.P., Oie L.R., Meisingset T.W., Dodick D.W., et al. Sleep restriction alters cortical inhibition in migraine: A transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;139:28&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35490438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mykland M.S., Uglem M., Stovner L.J., Brenner E., Snoen M.S., Gravdahl G.B., et al. Insufficient sleep may alter cortical excitability near the migraine attack: A blinded TMS crossover study. Cephalalgia. 2023;43(3) 3331024221148391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36786296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagel T. What is it like to be a bat? Phil. Rev. 1974;83(4):435&#x2013;450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naim-Feil J., Bradshaw J.L., Rogasch N.C., Daskalakis Z.J., Sheppard D.M., Lubman D.I., et al. Cortical inhibition within motor and frontal regions in alcohol dependence post-detoxification: a pilot TMS-EEG study. World J. Biol. Psychiatry. 2016;17:547&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26243644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naim-Feil J., Fitzgerald P.B., Rubinson M., Lubman D.I., Sheppard D.M., Bradshaw J.L., et al. Anomalies in global network connectivity associated with early recovery from alcohol dependence: a network transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalography study. Addict. Biol. 2022;27(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9285956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35229941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napolitano A., Schiavi S., La Rosa P., Rossi-Espagnet M.C., Petrillo S., Bottino F., et al. Sex differences in autism spectrum disorder: diagnostic, neurobiological, and behavioral features. Front. Psych. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9136002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35633791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasserie T., Hittle M., Goodman S.N. Assessment of the frequency and variety of persistent symptoms among patients with COVID-19: a systematic review. JAMA Netw. Open. 2021;4(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34037731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naumenko Y., Yuryshinetz I., Zabenko Y., Pivneva T. Mild traumatic brain injury as a pathological process. Heliyon. 2023;9(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10372741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37519712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarro, X., Porr&#xe9; F, Carrault G. ECG removal in preterm EEG combining empirical mode decomposition and adaptive filtering. IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP). Kyoto, Japan, 2012 p. 661-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neugebauer F., M&#xf6;ddel G., Rampp S., Burger M., Wolters C.H. The effect of head model simplification on beamformer source localization. Front. Neurosci. 2017;11:625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5701642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29209157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neverdahl J.P., Omland P.M., Uglem M., Engstrom M., Sand T. Reduced motor cortical inhibition in migraine: a blinded transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2017;128(12):2411&#x2013;2418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29096214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen J.D., Puonti O., Xue R., Thielscher A., Madsen K.H. Evaluating the influence of anatomical accuracy and electrode positions on EEG forward solutions. Neuroimage. 2023;277</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37392808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieminen J.O., Sinisalo H., Souza V.H., Malmi M., Yuryev M., Tervo A.E., et al. Multi-locus transcranial magnetic stimulation system for electronically targeted brain stimulation. Brain Stimul. 2022;15(1):116&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8807400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34818580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nihei K., McKee A.C., Kowall N.W. Patterns of neuronal degeneration in the motor cortex of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Acta Neuropathol. 1993;86:55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8396837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikouline V., Ruohonen J., Ilmoniemi R.J. The role of the coil click in TMS assessed with simultaneous EEG. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1999;110(8):1325&#x2013;1328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10454266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikulin V.V., Kicic D., Kahkonen S., Ilmoniemi R.J. Modulation of electroencephalographic responses to transcranial magnetic stimulation: evidence for changes in cortical excitability related to movement. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2003;18(5):1206&#x2013;1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12956719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitsche M.A., Kuo M.F., Grosch J., Bergner C., Monte-Silva K., Paulus W. D1-receptor impact on neuroplasticity in humans. J. Neurosci. 2009;29(8):2648&#x2013;2653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6666237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19244540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu Z., Jia L., Li Y., Yang L., Liu Y., Lian S., et al. Trial-by-trial variability of TMS-EEG in healthy controls and patients with depressive disorder. IEEE Trans. Neural Syst. Rehabilit. Eng. 2024;32:3869&#x2013;3877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39466867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y., Barr M.S., Zomorrodi R., Cash R.F.H., Lioumis P., Chen R., et al. Single-pulse transcranial magnetic stimulation-evoked potential amplitudes and latencies in the motor and dorsolateral prefrontal cortex among young, older healthy participants, and schizophrenia patients. J Pers Med. 2021;11(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7830964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33477346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y., Takano M., Wada M., Mimura Y., Nakajima S. Validation of the number of pulses required for TMS-EEG in the prefrontal cortex considering test feasibility. Neuroscience. 2024;554:63&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39002755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y., Zomorrodi R., Backhouse F., Cash R.F.H., Barr M.S., Rajji T.K., et al. Reduced prefrontal short-latency afferent inhibition in older adults and its relation to executive function: a TMS-EEG study. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2017;9:119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5411436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28512429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y., Zomorrodi R., Cash R.F., Barr M.S., Farzan F., Rajji T.K., et al. Characterization of the influence of age on GABA(A) and glutamatergic mediated functions in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex using paired-pulse TMS-EEG. Aging. 2017;9(2):556&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5361681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28209926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda Y., Zomorrodi R., Vila-Rodriguez F., Downar J., Farzan F., Cash R.F.H., et al. Impaired neuroplasticity in the prefrontal cortex in depression indexed through paired associative stimulation. Depress. Anxiety. 2018;35(5):d448&#x2013;d456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29637656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan M., Scott C., Hof P.R., Ansorge O. Betz cells of the primary motor cortex. J. Comp. Neurol. 2024;532(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10952528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38289193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Numssen O., Kuhnke P., Weise K., Hartwigsen G. Electric-field-based dosing for TMS. Imaging Neurosci. 2024;2:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12247572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40800463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez, P.L., Srinivasan, R. Electric fields of the brain: the neurophysics of EEG: Oxford University Press, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez P.L., Srinivasan R., Fields R.D. EEG functional connectivity, axon delays and white matter disease. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2015;126(1):110&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5018992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24815984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuyts, M., Beck, M.M., Banach A, Thielscher A, Meesen R, Tomasevic L, et al. Rostro-caudal TMS mapping of immediate transcranial evoked potentials reveals a pericentral crescendo-decrescendo pattern. bioRxiv 2025:2025.02.14.638272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40921260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Brien C.P. Neuroplasticity in addictive disorders. Dialogues Clin. Neurosci. 2009;11(3):350&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19877501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly C., Lewis J.D., Elsabbagh M. Is functional brain connectivity atypical in autism? a systematic review of EEG and MEG studies. PLoS One. 2017;12(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5414938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hearn K., Lynn A. Age differences and brain maturation provide insight into heterogeneous results in autism spectrum disorder. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2023;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9934814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36819297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberman L.M., Enticott P.G., Casanova M.F., Rotenberg A., Pascual-Leone A., McCracken J.T., et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation in autism spectrum disorder: Challenges, promise, and roadmap for future research. Autism Res. 2016;9(2):184&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4956084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26536383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh E.S., Fong T.G., Hshieh T.T., Inouye S.K. Delirium in older persons: advances in diagnosis and treatment. J. Am. Med. Assoc. 2017;318(12):1161&#x2013;1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28973626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumura Y., Asano Y., Takenaka S., Fukuyama S., Yonezawa S., Kasuya Y., et al. Brain activation by music in patients in a vegetative or minimally conscious state following diffuse brain injury. Brain injury : [BI] 2014;28(7):944&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24655034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opie G.M., Foo N., Killington M., Ridding M.C., Semmler J.G. Transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalography measures of cortical neuroplasticity are altered after mild traumatic brain injury. J. Neurotrauma. 2019;36(19):2774&#x2013;2784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30848163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opie G.M., Otieno L.A., Pourmajidian M., Semmler J.G., Sidhu S.K. Older adults differentially modulate transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalography measures of cortical inhibition during maximal single-joint exercise. Neuroscience. 2020;425:181&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31809730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opie G.M., Sidhu S.K., Rogasch N.C., Ridding M.C., Semmler J.G. Cortical inhibition assessed using paired-pulse TMS-EEG is increased in older adults. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(3):545&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29317185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ort, A., Smallridge JW, Sarasso S, Casarotto S, von Rotz R, Casanova A, et al. TMS-EEG and resting-state EEG applied to altered states of consciousness: oscillations, complexity, and phenomenology. iScience 2023;26(5):106589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10149373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37138774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortelli P., Ferrazzoli D., Sebastianelli L., Engl M., Romanello R., Nardone R., et al. Neuropsychological and neurophysiological correlates of fatigue in post-acute patients with neurological manifestations of COVID-19: Insights into a challenging symptom. J. Neurol. Sci. 2021;420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7834526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortelli P., Ferrazzoli D., Sebastianelli L., Maestri R., Dezi S., Spampinato D., et al. Altered motor cortex physiology and dysexecutive syndrome in patients with fatigue and cognitive difficulties after mild COVID-19. Eur. J. Neurol. 2022;29(6):1652&#x2013;1662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35138693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborne J. Notes on the use of data transformations. Pract. Assess. Res. Eval. 2002;8(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen A.M., Coleman M.R., Boly M., Davis M.H., Laureys S., Pickard J.D. Detecting awareness in the vegetative state. Science. 2006;313(5792):1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16959998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir R.A., Boucher P., Fried P.J., Momi D., Jannati A., Pascual-Leone A., et al. Reproducibility of cortical response modulation induced by intermittent and continuous theta-burst stimulation of the human motor cortex. Brain Stimul. 2021;14(4):949&#x2013;964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8565400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34126233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir, R.A., Passera B, Fried PJ, Press D, Shaughnessy LW, Buss S, et al. Neurophysiological signatures of default mode network dysfunction and cognitive decline in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. bioRxiv 2024:2024.09.16.613373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12662210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41313764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir R.A., Tadayon E., Boucher P., Momi D., Karakhanyan K.A., Fox M.D., et al. Individualized perturbation of the human connectome reveals reproducible biomarkers of network dynamics relevant to cognition. PNAS. 2020;117(14):8115&#x2013;8125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7149310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32193345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir R.A., Tadayon E., Boucher P., Sun H., Momi D., Ganglberger W., et al. Cortical responses to noninvasive perturbations enable individual brain fingerprinting. Brain Stimul. 2021;14(2):391&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33588105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palop J.J., Mucke L. Amyloid-beta-induced neuronal dysfunction in Alzheimer's disease: from synapses toward neural networks. Nat. Neurosci. 2010;13(7):812&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pankka H., Lehtinen J., Ilmoniemi R.J., Roine T. Enhanced EEG forecasting: a probabilistic deep learning approach. Neural Comput. 2025;37(4):793&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40030141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pantazatos S.P., McLntosh J.R., Saber G.T., Sun X., Doose J., Faller J., et al. The timing of transcranial magnetic stimulation relative to the phase of prefrontal alpha EEG modulates downstream target engagement. Brain Stimul. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37187457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paparella I., Cardone P., Zanichelli B., Lamalle L., Collette F., Sherif S., et al. 7&#xa0;Tesla magnetic resonance spectroscopy estimates of GABA concentration relate to physiological measures of tonic inhibition in the human motor cortex. J. Physiol. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40173216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paparella I., Vanderwalle G., Stagg C.J., Maquet P. An integrated measure of GABA to characterize post-stroke plasticity. NeuroImage Clinical. 2023;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10339061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37406594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmigiani S., Cline C.C., Sarkar M., Forman L., Truong J., Ross J.M., et al. Real-time optimization to enhance noninvasive cortical excitability assessment in the human dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2025;174:225&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40148152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmigiani S., Ross J.M., Cline C.C., Minasi C.B., Gogulski J., Keller C.J. Reliability and validity of transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalography biomarkers. Biol Psychiatry Cogn Neurosci Neuroimaging. 2023;8(8):805&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10276171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36894435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passera B., Chauvin A., Raffin E., Bougerol T., David O., Harquel S. Exploring the spatial resolution of TMS-EEG coupling on the sensorimotor region. Neuroimage. 2022;259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35777633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passera B., Harquel S., Chauvin A., G&#xe9;rard P., Lai L., Moro E., et al. Multi-scale and cross-dimensional TMS mapping: a proof of principle in patients with Parkinson's disease and deep brain stimulation. Front. Neurosci. 2023;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10192635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37214390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paus T., Sipila P.K., Strafella A.P. Synchronization of neuronal activity in the human primary motor cortex by transcranial magnetic stimulation: an EEG study. J. Neurophysiol. 2001;86(4):1983&#x2013;1990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei G., Liu X., Huang Q., Shi Z., Wang L., Suo D., et al. Characterizing cortical responses to short-term multidisciplinary intensive rehabilitation treatment in patients with Parkinson's disease: a transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalography study. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2022;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9669794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36408100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrino, G., Schuler AL, Cai Z, Marinazzo D, Tecchio F, Ricci L, et al. Assessing cortical excitability with electroencephalography: A pilot study with EEG-iTBS. Brain Stimulat., 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38286400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellicciari M.C., Bonni S., Ponzo V., Cinnera A.M., Mancini M., Casula E.P., et al. Dynamic reorganization of TMS-evoked activity in subcortical stroke patients. Neuroimage. 2018;175:365&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29635028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellicciari M.C., Brignani D., Miniussi C. Excitability modulation of the motor system induced by transcranial direct current stimulation: a multimodal approach. Neuroimage. 2013;83:569&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23845429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellicciari, M.C., Veniero D, Miniussi C. Characterizing the Cortical Oscillatory Response to TMS Pulse. Frontiers in cellular neuroscience 2017;11(38).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5326778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28289376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perell&#xf3;n-Alfonso R., Abellaneda-P&#xe9;rez K., Pileckyte I., Cabello-Toscano M., Mulet-Pons L., Vaqu&#xe9;-Alc&#xe1;zar L., et al. Spontaneous and perturbation-based EEG cortical excitability markers are associated with plasma p-tau181 concentration in healthy middle-aged adults. Heliyon. 2024;10(24)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11700258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39759333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera N.D., Alekseichuk I., Shirinpour S., Wischnewski M., Linn G., Masiello K., et al. Dissociation of centrally and peripherally induced transcranial magnetic stimulation effects in nonhuman primates. J. Neurosci. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10727178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37852789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri S., Kollewe K., Grothe C., Hori A., Dengler R., Bufler J., et al. GABA(A)-receptor mRNA expression in the prefrontal and temporal cortex of ALS patients. J. Neurol. Sci. 2006;250(1&#x2013;2):124&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17011586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri S., Krampfl K., Hashemi F., Grothe C., Hori A., Dengler R., et al. Distribution of GABAA receptor mRNA in the motor cortex of ALS patients. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 2003;62(10):1041&#x2013;1051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14575239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrichella S., Johnson N., He B. The influence of corticospinal activity on TMS-evoked activity and connectivity in healthy subjects: A TMS-EEG study. PLoS One. 2017;12(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5383066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigorini A., Casali A.G., Casarotto S., Ferrarelli F., Baselli G., Mariotti M., et al. Time-frequency spectral analysis of TMS-evoked EEG oscillations by means of Hilbert-Huang transform. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2011;198(2):236&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21524665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pion-Tonachini L., Kreutz-Delgado K., Makeig S. ICLabel: An automated electroencephalographic independent component classifier, dataset, and website. Neuroimage. 2019;198:181&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6592775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pletcher C., Dabbs K., Barzgari A., Pozorski V., Haebig M., Wey S., et al. Cerebral cortical thickness and cognitive decline in Parkinson's disease. Cereb. Cortex Commun. 2023;4(1) tgac044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36660417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poorganji M., Zomorrodi R., Hawco C., Hill A.T., Hadas I., Rajji T.K., et al. Differentiating transcranial magnetic stimulation cortical and auditory responses via single pulse and paired pulse protocols: A TMS-EEG study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2021;132(8):1850&#x2013;1858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34147010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premoli I., Bergmann T.O., Fecchio M., Rosanova M., Biondi A., Belardinelli P., et al. The impact of GABAergic drugs on TMS-induced brain oscillations in human motor cortex. Neuroimage. 2017;163:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28917695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premoli I., Biondi A., Carlesso S., Rivolta D., Richardson M.P. Lamotrigine and levetiracetam exert a similar modulation of TMS-evoked EEG potentials. Epilepsia. 2017;58(1):42&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5244669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27808418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premoli I., Castellanos N., Rivolta D., Belardinelli P., Bajo R., Zipser C., et al. TMS-EEG signatures of GABAergic neurotransmission in the human cortex. J. Neurosci. 2014;34(16):5603&#x2013;5612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6608220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24741050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premoli I., Kiraly J., M&#xfc;ller-Dahlhaus F., Zipser C.M., Rossini P., Zrenner C., et al. Short-interval and long-interval intracortical inhibition of TMS-evoked EEG potentials. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(4):818&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29572124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premoli I., Rivolta D., Espenhahn S., Castellanos N., Belardinelli P., Ziemann U., et al. Characterization of GABAB-receptor mediated neurotransmission in the human cortex by paired-pulse TMS-EEG. Neuroimage. 2014;103C:152&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25245814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premoli I., Rossini P.G., Goldberg P.Y., Posadas K., Green L., Yogo N., et al. TMS as a pharmacodynamic indicator of cortical activity of a novel anti-epileptic drug, XEN1101. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. 2019;6(11):2164&#x2013;2174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6856596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31568714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puri B.K., Agour M., Gunatilake K.D., Fernando K.A., Gurusinghe A.I., Treasaden I.H. Reduction in left supplementary motor area grey matter in adult female fibromyalgia sufferers with marked fatigue and without affective disorder: a pilot controlled 3-T magnetic resonance imaging voxel-based morphometry study. J. Int. Med. Res. 2010;38(4):1468&#x2013;1472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20926020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffin E., Harquel S., Passera B., Chauvin A., Bougerol T., David O. Probing regional cortical excitability via input-output properties using transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalography coupling. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2020;41(10):2741&#x2013;2761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32379389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffin E., Hummel F.C. Restoring motor functions after stroke: multiple approaches and opportunities. Neuroscientist. 2018;24(4):400&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29283026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiee F., Rezvani Habibabadi R., Motaghi M., Yousem D.M., Yousem I.J. Brain MRI in autism spectrum disorder: narrative review and recent advances. J. Magn. Reson. Imaging. 2022;55(6):1613&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34626442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragazzoni A., Pirulli C., Veniero D., Feurra M., Cincotta M., Giovannelli F., et al. Vegetative versus minimally conscious states: a study using TMS-EEG, sensory and event-related potentials. PLoS One. 2013;8(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3584112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23460826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raggi A., Leonardi M., Arruda M., Caponnetto V., Castaldo M., Coppola G., et al. Hallmarks of primary headache: part 1 - migraine. J. Headache Pain. 2024;25(1):189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11529271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39482575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajji T.K., Sun Y., Zomorrodi-Moghaddam R., Farzan F., Blumberger D.M., Mulsant B.H., et al. PAS-induced potentiation of cortical-evoked activity in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2013;38(12):2545&#x2013;2552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23820586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rau A., Arnold P.G., Frase S., Schr&#xf6;ter N., Mast H., Weiller C., et al. Cerebral microstructural alterations as an imaging biomarker for Post-COVID-condition. Sci. Rep. 2025;15(1):32483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12432129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40940410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridding M.C., Ziemann U. Determinants of the induction of cortical plasticity by non-invasive brain stimulation in healthy subjects. J. Physiol. 2010;588(13):2291&#x2013;2304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2915507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20478978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocchi L., Di Santo A., Brown K., Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J., Casula E., Rawji V., et al. Disentangling EEG responses to TMS due to cortical and peripheral activations. Brain Stimul. 2021;14(1):4&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33127580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodel R., Laskawi R., Markus H. Transcranial cortical magnetic stimulation of lower-lip mimetic muscles: effect of coil position on motor evoked potentials. ORL J. Otorhinolaryngol Relat. Spec. 1999;61(3):119&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10325549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogasch N.C., Biabani M., Mutanen T.P. Designing and comparing cleaning pipelines for TMS-EEG data: A theoretical overview and practical example. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogasch N.C., Daskalakis Z.J., Fitzgerald P.B. Mechanisms underlying long-interval cortical inhibition in the human motor cortex: a TMS-EEG study. J. Neurophysiol. 2013;109(1):89&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23100139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogasch N.C., Sullivan C., Thomson R.H., Rose N.S., Bailey N.W., Fitzgerald P.B., et al. Analysing concurrent transcranial magnetic stimulation and electroencephalographic data: a review and introduction to the open-source TESA software. Neuroimage. 2017;147:934&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27771347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogasch N.C., Thomson R.H., Daskalakis Z.J., Fitzgerald P.B. Short-latency artifacts associated with concurrent TMS-EEG. Brain Stimul. 2013;6(6):868&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23651674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogasch N.C., Thomson R.H., Farzan F., Fitzgibbon B.M., Bailey N.W., Hernandez-Pavon J.C., et al. Removing artefacts from TMS-EEG recordings using independent component analysis: importance for assessing prefrontal and motor cortex network properties. Neuroimage. 2014;101:425&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25067813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogasch N.C., Zipser C., Darmani G., Mutanen T.P., Biabani M., Zrenner C., et al. The effects of NMDA receptor blockade on TMS-evoked EEG potentials from prefrontal and parietal cortex. Sci. Rep. 2020;10(1):3168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7035341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32081901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolle C.E., Baumer F.M., Jordan J.T., Berry K., Garcia M., Monusko K., et al. Mapping causal circuit dynamics in stroke using simultaneous electroencephalography and transcranial magnetic stimulation. BMC Neurol. 2021;21(1):280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34271872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero Lauro L.J., Rosanova M., Mattavelli G., Convento S., Pisoni A., Opitz A., et al. TDCS increases cortical excitability: direct evidence from TMS-EEG. Cortex. 2014;58C:99&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24998337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero M.C., Davare M., Armendariz M., Janssen P. Neural effects of transcranial magnetic stimulation at the single-cell level. Nat. Commun. 2019;10(1):2642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6572776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31201331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosanova M., Casali A., Bellina V., Resta F., Mariotti M., Massimini M. Natural frequencies of human corticothalamic circuits. J. Neurosci. 2009;29(24):7679&#x2013;7685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6665626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19535579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosanova M., Fecchio M., Casarotto S., Sarasso S., Casali A.G., Pigorini A., et al. Sleep-like cortical OFF-periods disrupt causality and complexity in the brain of unresponsive wakefulness syndrome patients. Nat. Commun. 2018;9(1):4427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6200777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosanova M., Gosseries O., Casarotto S., Boly M., Casali A.G., Bruno M.A., et al. Recovery of cortical effective connectivity and recovery of consciousness in vegetative patients. Brain. 2012;135(Pt 4):1308&#x2013;1320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3326248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22226806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;sler K.M., Hess C.W., Schmid U.D. Investigation of facial motor pathways by electrical and magnetic stimulation: sites and mechanisms of excitation. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 1989;52(10):1149&#x2013;1156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1031699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2795040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross J.M., Santarnecchi E., Lian S.J., Fong T.G., Touroutoglou A., Cavallari M., et al. Neurophysiologic predictors of individual risk for post-operative delirium after elective surgery. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2023;71(1):235&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9870959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36226896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross J.M., Sarkar M., Keller C.J. Experimental suppression of transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalography sensory potentials. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2022;43(17):5141&#x2013;5153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9812254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35770956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi S., Ferro M., Cincotta M., Ulivelli M., Bartalini S., Miniussi C., et al. A real electro-magnetic placebo (REMP) device for sham transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) Clin. Neurophysiol. 2007;118(3):709&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17188568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossini P.M., Ferilli M.A., Rossini L., Ferreri F. Clinical neurophysiology of brain plasticity in aging brain. Curr. Pharm. Des. 2013;19(36):6426&#x2013;6439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23432716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostami M., Zomorrodi R., Rostami R., Hosseinzadeh G.A. Impact of methodological variability on EEG responses evoked by transcranial magnetic stimulation: A meta-analysis. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;142:154&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36037750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotenberg A. Prospects for clinical applications of transcranial magnetic stimulation and real-time EEG in epilepsy. Brain Topogr. 2010;22(4):257&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19921417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth B.J., Pascual-Leone A., Cohen L.G., Hallett M. The heating of metal electrodes during rapid-rate magnetic stimulation: a possible safety hazard. Electroencephalogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1992;85(2):116&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1373364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubenstein J.L.R., Merzenich M.M. Model of autism: Increased ratio of excitation/inhibition in key neural systems. Genes Brain Behav. 2003;2(5):255&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6748642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14606691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddy K.L., Woolley D.G., Mantini D., Balsters J.H., Enz N., Wenderoth N. Improving the quality of combined EEG-TMS neural recordings: Introducing the coil spacer. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2018;294:34&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29103999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruohonen J., Karhu J. Navigated transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neurophysiol. Clinique = Clin. Neurophysiol. 2010;40(1):7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20230931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruohonen J., Ollikainen M., Nikouline V., Virtanen J., Ilmoniemi R.J. Coil design for real and sham transcranial magnetic stimulation. I.E.E.E. Trans. Biomed. Eng. 2000;47(2):145&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10721620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo S., Claar L.D., Furregoni G., Marks L.C., Krishnan G., Zauli F.M., et al. Thalamic feedback shapes brain responses evoked by cortical stimulation in mice and humans. Nat. Commun. 2025;16(1):3627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12003640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40240330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo S., D'Ambrosio S., De Giampaulis P., Mora G., Massimini M., Sarasso S., et al. Probing cortical structural integrity after focal hemorrhagic stroke: A TMS-EEG case. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;140:159&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35779369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo S., Dimwamwa E.D., Stanley G.B. Layer 6 corticothalamic neurons induce high gamma oscillations through cortico-cortical and cortico-thalamo-cortical pathways. J. Neurosci. 2025;45(42)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12528831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40925672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo S., Sarasso S., Puglisi G.E., Dal Palu D., Pigorini A., Casarotto S., et al. TAAC - TMS adaptable auditory control: a universal tool to mask TMS clicks. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2022;370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35101524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saari J., Kallioniemi E., Tarvainen M., Julkunen P. Oscillatory TMS-EEG-responses as a measure of the cortical excitability threshold. IEEE Trans. Neural Syst. Rehabilitat. Eng. 2018;26(2):383&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29432109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachdev R.N., Ebner F.F., Wilson C.J. Effect of subthreshold up and down states on the whisker-evoked response in somatosensory cortex. J. Neurophysiol. 2004;92(6):3511&#x2013;3521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sack A.T., Cohen Kadosh R., Schuhmann T., Moerel M., Walsh V., Goebel R. Optimizing functional accuracy of TMS in cognitive studies: a comparison of methods. J. Cogn. Neurosci. 2009;21(2):207&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18823235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saez-Atienzar S., Bandres-Ciga S., Langston R.G., Kim J.J., Choi S.W., Reynolds R.H., et al. Genetic analysis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis identifies contributing pathways and cell types. Sci. Adv. 2021;7(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7810371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33523907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe4;is&#xe4;nen L., Julkunen P., Niskanen E., Danner N., Hukkanen T., Lohioja T., et al. Motor potentials evoked by navigated transcranial magnetic stimulation in healthy subjects. J. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2008;25(6):367&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salavati B., Daskalakis Z.J., Zomorrodi R., Blumberger D.M., Chen R., Pollock B.G., et al. Pharmacological modulation of long-term potentiation-like activity in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2018;12:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5928132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salavati B., Rajji T.K., Zomorrodi R., Blumberger D.M., Chen R., Pollock B.G., et al. Pharmacological manipulation of cortical inhibition in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2018;43(2):354&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5729552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28553835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvatore S.V., Lambert P.M., Benz A., Rensing N.R., Wong M., Zorumski C.F., et al. Periodic and aperiodic changes to cortical EEG in response to pharmacological manipulation. J. Neurophysiol. 2024;131(3):529&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11305649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38323322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarasso S., Boly M., Napolitani M., Gosseries O., Charland-Verville V., Casarotto S., et al. Consciousness and complexity during unresponsiveness induced by propofol, xenon, and ketamine. Curr. Biol. 2015;25(23):3099&#x2013;3105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26752078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarasso S., Casali A.G., Casarotto S., Rosanova M., Sinigaglia C., Massimini M. Consciousness and complexity: a consilience of evidence. Neurosci. Conscious. 2021;2021(2) niab023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10941977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38496724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarasso S., D'Ambrosio S., Fecchio M., Casarotto S., Vigan&#xf2; A., Landi C., et al. Local sleep-like cortical reactivity in the awake brain after focal injury. Brain. 2020;143(12):3672&#x2013;3684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7805800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33188680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarasso S., D'Ambrosio S., Russo S., Bernardelli L., Hassan G., Comanducci A., et al. Reduction of sleep-like perilesional slow waves and clinical evolution after stroke: A TMS-EEG study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2025;175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40424920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sassenhagen J., Draschkow D. Cluster-based permutation tests of MEG/EEG data do not establish significance of effect latency or location. Psychophysiology. 2019;56(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30657176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayal&#x131;, C., Gogulski, J., Gran&#xf6; I, Lioumis P, Barrett FS. Test-retest reliability of TMS-evoked potentials over fMRI-based definitions of non-motor cortical targets. bioRxiv 2024:2024.12.20.629675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiff N.D. Cognitive motor dissociation following severe brain injuries. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72(12):1413&#x2013;1415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26502348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid U.D., Moller A.R., Schmid J. The excitation site of the trigeminal nerve to transcranial magnetic stimulation varies and lies proximal or distal to the foramen ovale: an intraoperative electrophysiological study in man. Neurosci. Lett. 1992;141(2):265&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1436647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid U.D., Moller A.R., Schmid J. Transcranial magnetic stimulation of the trigeminal nerve: intraoperative study on stimulation characteristics in man. Muscle Nerve. 1995;18(5):487&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7739635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidgen J., Konrad K., Roessner V., Bender S. The external evocation and movement-related modulation of motor cortex inhibition in children and adolescents with Tourette syndrome - a TMS/EEG study. Front. Neurosci. 2023;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10620315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37928740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt H., Kn&#xf6;sche T.R. Action potential propagation and synchronisation in myelinated axons. PLoS Comput. Biol. 2019;15(10)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6818808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31622338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schriefer T.N., Mills K.R., Murray N.M., Hess C.W. Evaluation of proximal facial nerve conduction by transcranial magnetic stimulation. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry. 1988;51(1):60&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1032714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3351531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seki Y., Krain L., Yamada T., Kimura J. Transcranial magnetic stimulation of the facial nerve: recording technique and estimation of the stimulated site. Neurosurgery. 1990;26(2):286&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2308677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi H., Takeuchi S., Kadota H., Kohno Y., Nakajima Y. TMS-induced artifacts on EEG can be reduced by rearrangement of the electrode's lead wire before recording. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2011;122(5):984&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20920887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selkoe D.J. Alzheimer's disease is a synaptic failure. Science. 2002;298(5594):789&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12399581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shad E.H.T., Molinas M., Ytterdal T. Impedance and noise of passive and active dry EEG electrodes: a review. IEEE Sens. J. 2020;20:14565&#x2013;14577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafi M.M., Santarnecchi E., Fong T.G., Jones R.N., Marcantonio E.R., Pascual-Leone A., et al. Advancing the neurophysiological understanding of delirium. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc. 2017;65(6):1114&#x2013;1118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28165616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafi M.M., Vernet M., Klooster D., Chu C.J., Boric K., Barnard M.E., et al. Physiological consequences of abnormal connectivity in a developmental epilepsy. Ann. Neurol. 2015;77(3):487&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4394240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25858773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharples S.A., Gould J.A., Vandenberk M.S., Kalmar J.M. Cortical mechanisms of central fatigue and sense of effort. PLoS One. 2016;11(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4747526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26859391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She X., Nix K.C., Cline C.C., Qi W., Tugin S., He Z., et al. Stability of transcranial magnetic stimulation electroencephalogram evoked potentials in pediatric epilepsy. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):9045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11031596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38641629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She X., Qi W., Nix K.C., Menchaca M., Cline C.C., Wu W., et al. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation modulates brain connectivity in children with self-limited epilepsy with centrotemporal spikes. Brain Stimul. 2025;18(2):287&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12087383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40010636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheen J.Z., Mazza F., Momi D., Miron J.P., Mansouri F., Russell T., et al. N100 as a response prediction biomarker for accelerated 1&#xa0;Hz right DLPFC-rTMS in major depression. J. Affect. Disord. 2024;363:174&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39033822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefner J.M., Al-Chalabi A., Baker M.R., Cui L.Y., de Carvalho M., Eisen A., et al. A proposal for new diagnostic criteria for ALS. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2020;131:1975&#x2013;1978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen M., Li C., Wei X., Zhang L., Li Y., Wu H., et al. transcranial magnetic stimulation as a therapy for migraine: an overview of systematic reviews. J. Pain Res. 2023;16:3133&#x2013;3144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10505396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37724171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata S., Onishi H., Mima T. TMS-EEG signatures of the effects of transcranial static magnetic field stimulation (tSMS) on cortical excitability. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):22394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39333555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya K., Park S.B., Geevasinga N., Menon P., Howells J., Simon N.G., et al. Motor cortical function determines prognosis in sporadic ALS. Neurology. 2016;87(5):513&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27402895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebner H.R., Conde V., Tomasevic L., Thielscher A., Bergmann T.O. Distilling the essence of TMS-evoked EEG potentials (TEPs): A call for securing mechanistic specificity and experimental rigor. Brain Stimul. 2019;12(4):1051&#x2013;1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30962028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebner H.R., Funke K., Aberra A.S., Antal A., Bestmann S., Chen R., et al. Transcranial magnetic stimulation of the brain: What is stimulated? - a consensus and critical position paper. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;140:59&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9753778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35738037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva V.A., Baptista A.F., Fonseca A.S., Carneiro A.M., Brunoni A.R., Carrilho P.E.M., et al. Motor cortex repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in fibromyalgia: a multicentre randomised controlled trial. Br. J. Anaesth. 2025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12106861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40087077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvennoinen K., Balestrini S., Rothwell J.C., Sisodiya S.M. Transcranial magnetic stimulation as a tool to understand genetic conditions associated with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8432162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32783192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal A., Doerfling P., Fowler B. Effects of a dual task on the N100-P200 complex and the early and late Nd attention waveforms. Psychophysiology. 2002;39(2):236&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12212674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinisalo H., Rissanen I., Kahilakoski O.P., Souza V.H., Tommila T., Laine M., et al. Modulating brain networks in space and time: Multi-locus transcranial magnetic stimulation. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2024;158:218&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38184469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinitsyn D.O., Poydasheva A.G., Bakulin I.S., Legostaeva L.A., Iazeva E.G., Sergeev D.V., et al. Detecting the potential for consciousness in unresponsive patients using the perturbational complexity index. Brain Sci. 2020;10(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7760168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33260944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith J.R., DiSalvo M., Green A., Ceranoglu T.A., Anteraper S.A., Croarkin P., et al. Treatment response of transcranial magnetic stimulation in intellectually capable youth and young adults with autism spectrum disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neuropsychol. Rev. 2023;33(4):834&#x2013;855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10039963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36161554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohn Y.H., Voller B., Dimyan M., St Clair Gibson A., Hanakawa T., Leon-Sarmiento F.E., et al. Cortical control of voluntary blinking: a transcranial magnetic stimulation study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2004;115(2):341&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14744575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon E.A., Wang J.B., Oya H., Howard M.A., Trapp N.T., Uitermarkt B.D., et al. TMS provokes target-dependent intracranial rhythms across human cortical and subcortical sites. Brain Stimul. 2024;17(3):698&#x2013;712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11313454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38821396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y., Gordon P.C., Metsomaa J., Rostami M., Belardinelli P., Ziemann U. Evoked EEG responses to TMS targeting regions outside the primary motor cortex and their test-retest reliability. Brain Topogr. 2024;37(1):19&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10771591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37996562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y., Gordon P.C., Roy O., Metsomaa J., Belardinelli P., Rostami M., et al. Involvement of muscarinic acetylcholine receptor-mediated cholinergic neurotransmission in TMS-EEG responses. Prog. Neuropsychopharmacol. Biol. Psychiatry. 2025;136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39383933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano J.B., Ancochea J. On the new post COVID-19 condition. Arch Bronconeumol (Engl Ed) 2021;57(12):735&#x2013;736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8051002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33958231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spudich S., Nath A. Nervous system consequences of COVID-19. Science. 2022;375(6578):267&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35050660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stampanoni Bassi M., Iezzi E., Centonze D. Multiple sclerosis: inflammation, autoimmunity and plasticity. Handb. Clin. Neurol. 2022;184:457&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35034754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stango A., Zazio A., Barchiesi G., Bonfiglio N.S., Dognini E., Marcantoni E., et al. Immediate TMS-EEG responses reveal motor cortex excitability. Neuroimage. 2025;121666</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41423166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strafella R., Momi D., Zomorrodi R., Lissemore J., Noda Y., Chen R., et al. Identifying neurophysiological markers of intermittent theta-burst stimulation in treatment-resistant depression using transcranial magnetic stimulation- electroencephalography. Biol. Psychiatry. 2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37084864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strenge H., Jahns R. Activation and suppression of the trapezius muscle induced by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Electromyogr. Clin. Neurophysiol. 1998;38(3):141&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9637939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Blumberger D.M., Mulsant B.H., Rajji T.K., Fitzgerald P.B., Barr M.S., et al. Magnetic seizure therapy reduces suicidal ideation and produces neuroplasticity in treatment-resistant depression. Transl. Psychiatry. 2018;8:253 -.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6251931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30470735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Farzan F., Mulsant B.H., Rajji T.K., Fitzgerald P.B., Barr M.S., et al. Indicators for remission of suicidal ideation following magnetic seizure therapy in patients with treatment-resistant depression. JAMA Psychiat. 2016;73(4):337&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26981889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y., Lucas MV, Cline CC, Menezes MC, Kim S, Badami FS, et al. Densely sampled stimulus-response map of human cortex with single pulse TMS-EEG and its relation to whole brain neuroimaging measures. bioRxiv 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki M., Larkum M.E. Dendritic calcium spikes are clearly detectable at the cortical surface. Nat. Commun. 2017;8(1):276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5561206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28819259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takano M., Havlicek J., Phillips D., Nakajima S., Mimura M., Noda Y. Development of an advanced sham coil for transcranial magnetic stimulation and examination of its specifications. J Pers Med. 2021;11(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8617996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34834410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallus J., Lioumis P., Hamalainen H., Kahkonen S., Tenovuo O. Transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalography responses in recovered and symptomatic mild traumatic brain injury. J. Neurotrauma. 2013;30(14):1270&#x2013;1277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3713436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23384582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan B., Chen J., Liu Y., Lin Q., Wang Y., Shi S., et al. Differential analgesic effects of high-frequency or accelerated intermittent theta burst stimulation of M1 on experimental tonic pain: correlations with cortical activity changes assessed by TMS-EEG. Neurotherapeutics. 2024;21(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11585887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39304439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tangwiriyasakul C., Premoli I., Spyrou L., Chin R.F., Escudero J., Richardson M.P. Tensor decomposition of TMS-induced EEG oscillations reveals data-driven profiles of antiepileptic drug effects. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):17057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6864053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31745223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner D., Morgan-Short K., Luck S.J. How inappropriate high-pass filters can produce artifactual effects and incorrect conclusions in ERP studies of language and cognition. Psychophysiology. 2015;52(8):997&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4506207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25903295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatum W.O., Dworetzky B.A., Schomer D.L. Artifact and recording concepts in EEG. J. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2011;28(3):252&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21633251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#x103;u&#x1ab;an A.M., Casula E.P., Pellicciari M.C., Borghi I., Maiella M., Bonni S., et al. TMS-EEG perturbation biomarkers for Alzheimer's disease patients classification. Sci. Rep. 2023;13(1):7667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10175269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37169900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tecchio F., Giambattistelli F., Porcaro C., Cottone C., Mutanen T.P., Pizzella V., et al. Effective intracerebral connectivity in acute stroke: a TMS-EEG study. Brain Sci. 2023;13(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9954230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36831776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ter Braack E.M., de Vos C.C., van Putten M.J. Masking the auditory evoked potential in TMS-EEG: a comparison of various methods. Brain Topogr. 2015;28(3):520&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23996091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ter Braack E.M., Koopman A.E., van Putten M.J. Early TMS evoked potentials in epilepsy: a pilot study. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2016;127(9):3025&#x2013;3032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27472537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tervo A.E., Nieminen J.O., Lioumis P., Metsomaa J., Souza V.H., Sinisalo H., et al. Closed-loop optimization of transcranial magnetic stimulation with electroencephalography feedback. Brain Stimul. 2022;15(2):523&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8940636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35337598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thielscher A., Opitz A., Windhoff M. Impact of the gyral geometry on the electric field induced by transcranial magnetic stimulation. Neuroimage. 2011;54(1):234&#x2013;243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson A.J., Banwell B.L., Barkhof F., Carroll W.M., Coetzee T., Comi G., et al. Diagnosis of multiple sclerosis: 2017 revisions of the McDonald criteria. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(2):162&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29275977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thong S., Doery E., Biabani M., Rogasch N.C., Chong T.T., Hendrikse J., et al. Disinhibition across secondary motor cortical regions during motor sequence learning: A TMS-EEG study. J. Neurosci. 2025;45(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11841768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39658257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinkhauser G., Torrecillos F., Duclos Y., Tan H., Pogosyan A., Fischer P., et al. Beta burst coupling across the motor circuit in Parkinson's disease. Neurobiol. Dis. 2018;117:217&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6054304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29909050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokimura H., Yamagami M., Tokimura Y., Asakura T., Atsuchi M. Transcranial magnetic stimulation excites the root exit zone of the facial nerve. Neurosurgery. 1993;32(3) pp. 414&#x2013;6; discussion 5&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8384326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolner E.A., Chen S.P., Eikermann-Haerter K. Current understanding of cortical structure and function in migraine. Cephalalgia. 2019;333102419840643</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6859601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30922081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasevic L., Siebner H.R., Thielscher A., Manganelli F., Pontillo G., Dubbioso R. Relationship between high-frequency activity in the cortical sensory and the motor hand areas, and their myelin content. Brain Stimul. 2022;15:717&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35525389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasevic L., Takemi M., Siebner H.R. Synchronizing the transcranial magnetic pulse with electroencephalographic recordings effectively reduces inter-trial variability of the pulse artefact. PLoS One. 2017;12(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5608361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28934300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tononi G., Edelman G.M. Consciousness and complexity. Science. 1998;282(5395):1846&#x2013;1851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9836628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapp N.T., Tsang E.W., Bruss J., Russo S., Gander P.E., Berger J.I., et al. TMS-associated auditory evoked potentials can be effectively masked: Evidence from intracranial EEG. Brain Stimul. 2024;17(3):616&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12574715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38729299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treede R.D., Hoheisel U., Wang D., Magerl W. Central sensitization: clinical utility of a physiological concept for the International Statistical Classification of Diseases and Related Health Problems and for nociplastic pain. Pain. 2022;163(Suppl 1):S99&#x2013;s107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36099342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay S., Rogasch N.C., Premoli I., Blumberger D.M., Casarotto S., Chen R., et al. Clinical utility and prospective of TMS-EEG. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2019;130:802&#x2013;844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30772238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troebinger L., L&#xf3;pez J.D., Lutti A., Bradbury D., Bestmann S., Barnes G. High precision anatomy for MEG. Neuroimage. 2014;86:583&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3898940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23911673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troni W., Cantello R., Rainero I. Conduction velocity along human muscle fibers in situ. Neurology. 1983;33(11):1453&#x2013;1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6685238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tscherpel C., Dern S., Hensel L., Ziemann U., Fink G.R., Grefkes C. Brain responsivity provides an individual readout for motor recovery after stroke. Brain. 2020;143:1873&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7296846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32375172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tscherpel C., Mustin M., Massimini M., Paul T., Ziemann U., Fink G.R., et al. Local neuronal sleep after stroke: the role of cortical bistability in brain reorganization. Brain Stimul. 2024;17:836&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39019396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng Y.-H., Ozdemir R., Rodionov A., Ross J.M., Klooster D., Cavallari M., et al. Preoperative parietal TMS-EEG hyperexcitability in patients with subsequent postoperative delirium. Brain Stimul. 2025;18(1):609&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tukey J.W. We need both exploratory and confirmatory. Am. Statist. 1980;34(1):23&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M.R., Hammers A., Al-Chalabi A., Shaw C.E., Andersen P.M., Brooks D.J., et al. Distinct cerebral lesions in sporadic and 'D90A' SOD1 ALS: studies with [11C]flumazenil PET. Brain. 2005;128(Pt 6):1323&#x2013;1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15843422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueno S., Tashiro T., Harada K. Localized stimulation of neural tissues in the brain by means of a paired configuration of time&#x2010;varying magnetic fields. J. Appl. Phys. 1988;64(10):5862&#x2013;5864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhlhaas P.J., Singer W. Oscillations and neuronal dynamics in schizophrenia: the search for basic symptoms and translational opportunities. Biol. Psychiatry. 2015;77(12):1001&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25676489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uriguen J.A., Garcia-Zapirain B. EEG artifact removal-state-of-the-art and guidelines. J. Neural Eng. 2015;12(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25834104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentin A., Arunachalam R., Mesquita-Rodrigues A., Garcia Seoane J.J., Richardson M.P., Mills K.R., et al. Late EEG responses triggered by transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) in the evaluation of focal epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2008;49(3):470&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18028404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallesi A., Del Felice A., Capizzi M., Tafuro A., Formaggio E., Bisiacchi P., et al. Natural oscillation frequencies in the two lateral prefrontal cortices induced by Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation. Neuroimage. 2021;227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos M.A.J., Geevasinga N., Higashihara M., Menon P., Vucic S. Pathophysiology and diagnosis of ALS: insights from advances in neurophysiological techniques. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2019;20(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6600525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31185581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos M.A.J., Higashihara M., Geevasinga N., Menon P., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Imbalance of cortical facilitatory and inhibitory circuits underlies hyperexcitability in ALS. Neurology. 2018;91(18):e1669&#x2013;e1676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30282772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos M.A.J., Higashihara M., Geevasinga N., Menon P., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Pathophysiological associations of transcallosal dysfunction in ALS. Eur. J. Neurol. 2021;28:1172&#x2013;1180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Bos M.A.J., Menon P., Pavey N., Higashihara M., Kiernan M.C., Vucic S. Direct interrogation of cortical interneuron circuits in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Brain. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39385724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Kamp W., Maassen VanDenBrink A., Ferrari M.D., van Dijk J.G. Interictal cortical hyperexcitability in migraine patients demonstrated with transcranial magnetic stimulation. J. Neurol. Sci. 1996;139(1):106&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8836980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Werf Y.D., Sadikot A.F., Strafella A.P., Paus T. The neural response to transcranial magnetic stimulation of the human motor cortex. II. Thalamocortical contributions. Experim. Brain Res. Exp. Hirnforschung. 2006;175(2):246&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16832683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Duinen H., Renken R., Maurits N., Zijdewind I. Effects of motor fatigue on human brain activity, an fMRI study. Neuroimage. 2007;35(4):1438&#x2013;1449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17408974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Veen B.D., van Drongelen W., Yuchtman M., Suzuki A. Localization of brain electrical activity via linearly constrained minimum variance spatial filtering. I.E.E.E. Trans. Biomed. Eng. 1997;44(9):867&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9282479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasilenko S.A., Evans-Polce R.J., Lanza S.T. Age trends in rates of substance use disorders across ages 18&#x2013;90: differences by gender and race/ethnicity. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2017;180:260&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5757874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28938183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldsman M., Egorova N., Singh B., Mungas D., DeCarli C., Brodtmann A. Low-frequency oscillations in default mode subnetworks are associated with episodic memory impairments in Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol. Aging. 2017;59:98&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28866021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veniero D., Bortoletto M., Miniussi C. TMS-EEG co-registration: on TMS-induced artifact. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2009;120(7):1392&#x2013;1399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19535291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versace V., Ortelli P., Dezi S., Ferrazzoli D., Alibardi A., Bonini I., et al. Co-ultramicronized palmitoylethanolamide/luteolin normalizes GABA(B)-ergic activity and cortical plasticity in long COVID-19 syndrome. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;145:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9650483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36455453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versace V., Sebastianelli L., Ferrazzoli D., Romanello R., Ortelli P., Saltuari L., et al. Intracortical GABAergic dysfunction in patients with fatigue and dysexecutive syndrome after COVID-19. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2021;132(5):1138&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7954785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33774378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vetter D.E., Zrenner C., Belardinelli P., Mutanen T.P., Koz&#xe1;k G., Marzetti L., et al. Targeting motor cortex high-excitability states defined by functional connectivity with real-time EEG&#x2013;TMS. Neuroimage. 2023;284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10714128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38008297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink J.J.T., Klooster D.C.W., Ozdemir R.A., Westover M.B., Pascual-Leone A., Shafi M.M. EEG functional connectivity is a weak predictor of causal brain interactions. Brain Topogr. 2020;33(2):221&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7191224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32090281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virtanen J., Ruohonen J., Naatanen R., Ilmoniemi R.J. Instrumentation for the measurement of electric brain responses to transcranial magnetic stimulation. Med. Biol. Eng. Compu. 1999;37(3):322&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10505382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlachos I., Kugiumtzis D., Tsalikakis D.G., Kimiskidis V.K. TMS-induced brain connectivity modulation in Genetic Generalized Epilepsy. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2022;133:83&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34814019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voineskos D., Blumberger D.M., Rogasch N.C., Zomorrodi R., Farzan F., Foussias G., et al. Neurophysiological effects of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) in treatment resistant depression. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2021;132(9):2306&#x2013;2316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34167891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voineskos D., Blumberger D.M., Zomorrodi R., Rogasch N.C., Farzan F., Foussias G., et al. Altered transcranial magnetic stimulation-electroencephalographic markers of inhibition and excitation in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in major depressive disorder. Biol. Psychiatry. 2019;85:477&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30503506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkow N.D., Blanco C. Substance use disorders: a comprehensive update of classification, epidemiology, neurobiology, clinical aspects, treatment and prevention. World Psychiatry. 2023;22(2):203&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10168177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37159360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkow N.D., Koob G.F., McLellan A.T. Neurobiologic advances from the brain disease model of addiction. N. Engl. J. Med. 2016;374(4):363&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6135257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26816013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volz L.J., Rehme A.K., Michely J., Nettekoven C., Eickhoff S.B., Fink G.R., et al. Shaping early reorganization of neural networks promotes motor function after stroke. Cereb. Cortex. 2016;26(6):2882&#x2013;2894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4869817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26980614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Monakow C. Die lokalisation im grosshirn und der abbau der funktion durch kortikale herde. J Am M&#xe9;d Assoc. 1914 LXIII:797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S., Higashihara M., Sobue G., Atsuta N., Doi Y., Kuwabara S., et al. ALS is a multistep process in South Korean, Japanese, and Australian patients. Neurology. 2020;94(15) e1657-e63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32071166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S., Kiernan M.C. Novel threshold tracking techniques suggest that cortical hyperexcitability is an early feature of motor neuron disease. Brain. 2006;129:2436&#x2013;2446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16835248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vucic S., Stanley Chen K.H., Kiernan M.C., Hallett M., Benninger D.H., Di Lazzaro V., et al. Clinical diagnostic utility of transcranial magnetic stimulation in neurological disorders. Updated report of an IFCN committee. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2023;150:131&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10192339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vyazovskiy V.V., Cirelli C., Pfister-Genskow M., Faraguna U., Tononi G. Molecular and electrophysiological evidence for net synaptic potentiation in wake and depression in sleep. Nat. Neurosci. 2008;11(2):200&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18204445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada, M., Nakajima S, Honda S, Takano M, Taniguchi K, Homma S, et al. Decreased prefrontal glutamatergic function is associated with a reduced astrocyte-related gene expression in treatment-resistant depression. Transl. Psychiatry 2024 14:1 2024;14(1):1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11589749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39587054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada M., Nakajima S., Honda S., Takano M., Taniguchi K., Tsugawa S., et al. Reduced signal propagation elicited by frontal transcranial magnetic stimulation is associated with oligodendrocyte abnormalities in treatment-resistant depression. J. Psychiatry Neurosci. 2022;47(5):E325&#x2013;E335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9484613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36104082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walhovd K.B., Fjell A.M., Reinvang I., Lundervold A., Dale A.M., Eilertsen D.E., et al. Effects of age on volumes of cortex, white matter and subcortical structures. Neurobiol. Aging. 2005;26(9):1261&#x2013;1270. discussion 75&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16005549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallin A.K., Blennow K., Zetterberg H., Londos E., Minthon L., Hansson O. CSF biomarkers predict a more malignant outcome in Alzheimer disease. Neurology. 2010;74(19):1531&#x2013;1537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20458070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter W.G. The electro-encephalogram in cases of cerebral tumour: (Section of Neurology) Proc. R. Soc. Med. 1937;30(5):579&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2076018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19991061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton, D., Spencer DC, Nevitt SJ, Michael BD. Transcranial magnetic stimulation for the treatment of epilepsy. Cochrane Database System. Rev. 2021;4(4):Cd011025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8092469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33884611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Li Q., Wu Y., Ji G.J., Wu X., Xiao G., et al. Intermittent theta burst stimulation improved visual-spatial working memory in treatment-resistant schizophrenia: a pilot study. J. Psychiatr. Res. 2022;149:44&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35231791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Gong A., Feng Z., Bai Y., Ziemann U. Interactions of transcranial magnetic stimulation with brain oscillations: a narrative review. Front. Syst. Neurosci. 2024;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11652484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39698203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Dang Y., Bai Y., Xia X., Li X. Evaluating the effect of spinal cord stimulation on patient with disorders of consciousness: a TMS-EEG study. Comput. Biol. Med. 2023;166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37806053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Niu Z., Xia X., Bai Y., Liang Z., He J., et al. Application of fast perturbational complexity index to the diagnosis and prognosis for disorders of consciousness. IEEE Trans. Neural Syst. Rehabilitat. Eng. 2022;30:509&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35213312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werhahn K.J., Wiseman K., Herzog J., Forderreuther S., Dichgans M., Straube A. Motor cortex excitability in patients with migraine with aura and hemiplegic migraine. Cephalalgia. 2000;20(1):45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10817446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wessel J.R., Aron A.R. On the globality of motor suppression: unexpected events and their influence on behavior and cognition. Neuron. 2017;93(2):259&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5260803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28103476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitham E.M., Pope K.J., Fitzgibbon S.P., Lewis T., Clark C.R., Loveless S., et al. Scalp electrical recording during paralysis: quantitative evidence that EEG frequencies above 20 Hz are contaminated by EMG. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2007;118(8):1877&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17574912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittington M.A., Traub R.D., Jefferys J.G. Synchronized oscillations in interneuron networks driven by metabotropic glutamate receptor activation. Nature. 1995;373(6515):612&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7854418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P., Turner M.R., Abrahams S., Hammers A., Brooks D.J., Leigh P.N., et al. Neuronal loss associated with cognitive performance in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: an (11C)-flumazenil PET study. Amyotroph. Lateral Scler. 2008;9(1):43&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18270878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widmann A., Schr&#xf6;ger E., Maess B. Digital filter design for electrophysiological data&#x2013;a practical approach. J. Neurosci. Methods. 2015;250:34&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25128257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesman A.I., da Silva C.J., Degroot C., Fon E.A., Baillet S., Network Q.P. Adverse and compensatory neurophysiological slowing in Parkinson's disease. Prog. Neurobiol. 2023;231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10872886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37832713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesman A.I., da Silva C.J., Fon E.A., Baillet S. Alterations of cortical structure and neurophysiology in parkinson's disease are aligned with neurochemical systems. Ann. Neurol. 2024;95(4):802&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11023768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38146745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xf6;rg&#xf6;tter F., Suder K., Zhao Y., Kerscher N., Eysel U.T., Funke K. State-dependent receptive-field restructuring in the visual cortex. Nature. 1998;396(6707):165&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9823895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W., Keller C.J., Rogasch N.C., Longwell P., Shpigel E., Rolle C.E., et al. ARTIST: A fully automated artifact rejection algorithm for single-pulse TMS-EEG data. Hum. Brain Mapp. 2018;39(4):1607&#x2013;1625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6866546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29331054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Yuan Z., Chen Z., Liao Z., Li S., Feng Y., et al. Perturbational complexity index in assessing responsiveness to rTMS treatment in patients with disorders of consciousness: a cross-over randomized controlled trial study. J. Neuroeng. Rehabil. 2024;21(1):167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11411826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39300529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yabe I., Tsuji-Akimoto S., Shiga T., Hamada S., Hirata K., Otsuki M., et al. Writing errors in ALS related to loss of neuronal integrity in the anterior cingulate gyrus. J. Neurol. Sci. 2012;315(1&#x2013;2):55&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22226010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan E., Veitch M., Saripella A., Alhamdah Y., Butris N., Tang-Wai D.F., et al. Association between postoperative delirium and adverse outcomes in older surgical patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J. Clin. Anesth. 2023;90</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37515876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Han Y., Wang J., Zhou Y., Chen D., Wang M., et al. Effects of altered excitation-inhibition imbalance by repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for self-limited epilepsy with centrotemporal spikes. Front. Neurol. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10250617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37305755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Song P., Wang Y. Assessing the impact of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation on effective connectivity in autism spectrum disorder: An initial exploration using TMS-EEG analysis. Heliyon. 2024;10(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11140796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38828287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y., Wang J., Che X. Concurrent TMS-EEG to reveal the neuroplastic changes in the prefrontal and insular cortices in the analgesic effects of DLPFC-rTMS. Cereb. Cortex. 2022;32(20):4436&#x2013;4446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35059703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young M.J., Koch C., Claassen J., Fischer D., Aubinet C., Gosseries O., et al. An ethical framework to assess covert consciousness. Lancet Neurol. 2025;24(3):195&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39986307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young W., Shaw J., Bloom M., Gebeline-Myers C. Correlation of increase in phosphene threshold with reduction of migraine frequency: observation of levetiracetam-treated subjects. Headache. 2008;48(10):1490&#x2013;1498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19076647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuksel H., Topalkara K.K. Increased cortical excitability in female migraineurs: a transcranial magnetic stimulation study conducted in the preovulatory phase. J Clin Neurol. 2021;17(2):236&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33835744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zangen A., Zibman S., Tendler A., Barnea-Ygael N., Alyagon U., Blumberger D.M., et al. Pursuing personalized medicine for depression by targeting the lateral or medial prefrontal cortex with Deep TMS. JCI Insight. 2023;8(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9977507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36692954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazio A., Barchiesi G., Ferrari C., Marcantoni E., Bortoletto M. M1-P15 as a cortical marker for transcallosal inhibition: a preregistered TMS-EEG study. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 2022;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9523880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazio A., Bortoletto M., Ruzzoli M., Miniussi C., Veniero D. Perceptual and physiological consequences of dark adaptation: a TMS-EEG study. Brain Topogr. 2019;32(5):773&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31076949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeidan J., Fombonne E., Scorah J., Ibrahim A., Durkin M.S., Saxena S., et al. Global prevalence of autism: a systematic review update. Autism Res. 2022;15(5):778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35238171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zewdie E., Ciechanski P., Kuo H.C., Giuffre A., Kahl C., King R., et al. Safety and tolerability of transcranial magnetic and direct current stimulation in children: Prospective single center evidence from 3.5 million stimulations. Brain Stimul. 2020;13(3):565&#x2013;575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Zhang L., Liang B., Schroeder D., Zhang Z., Cox G.A., et al. Hyperactive somatostatin interneurons contribute to excitotoxicity in neurodegenerative disorders. Nat. Neurosci. 2016;19(4):557&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4811704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26900927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C., Gao Y.N., Qiao Q., Yang Z., Zhou W.W., Ding J.J., et al. Efficacy of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in preventing postoperative delirium in elderly patients undergoing major abdominal surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Brain Stimul. 2025;18(1):52&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39732191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U. I-waves in motor cortex revisited. Exp. Brain Res. Experimentelle Hirnforschung. 2020;238:1601&#x2013;1610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7413903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32185405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemann U., Reis J., Schwenkreis P., Rosanova M., Strafella A., Badawy R., et al. TMS and drugs revisited 2014. Clin. Neurophysiol. 2015;126:1847&#x2013;1868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25534482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zifman N., Levy-Lamdan O., Hiller T., Thaler A., Dolev I., Mirelman A., et al. TMS-evoked potentials unveil occipital network involvement in patients diagnosed with Parkinson's disease within 5 years of inclusion. NPJ Parkinsons Dis. 2024;10(1):182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11443052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39349492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zifman N., Levy-Lamdan O., Suzin G., Efrati S., Tanne D., Fogel H., et al. Introducing a novel approach for evaluation and monitoring of brain health across life span using direct non-invasive brain network electrophysiology. Front. Aging Neurosci. 2019;11:248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6745309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31551761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinn M.A., Zinn M.L., Valencia I., Jason L.A., Montoya J.G. Cortical hypoactivation during resting EEG suggests central nervous system pathology in patients with chronic fatigue syndrome. Biol. Psychol. 2018;136:87&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6064389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29802861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zipser C.M., Premoli I., Belardinelli P., Castellanos N., Rivolta D., Heidegger T., et al. Cortical Excitability and interhemispheric connectivity in early relapsing-remitting multiple sclerosis studied with TMS-EEG. Front. Neurosci. 2018;12:393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6002497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zrenner C., Desideri D., Belardinelli P., Ziemann U. Real-time EEG-defined excitability states determine efficacy of TMS-induced plasticity in human motor cortex. Brain Stimul. 2018;11(2):374&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29191438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zrenner C., Ziemann U. Closed-loop brain stimulation. Biol. Psychiatry. 2024;95(6):545&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10881194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37743002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>