<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41379632</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-9239</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Epilepsia open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Epilepsia Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Natural language processing-based emotion and usage analysis of an AI-powered chatbot for epilepsy support.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/epi4.70186</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Artificial intelligence (AI)-powered chatbots are increasingly used for patient education and mental health support, yet their effectiveness in epilepsy care remains underexplored. This study examines text-based interactions between users and EpiloBot, an epilepsy-focused chatbot, to understand conversational patterns and emotional trends using natural language processing (NLP) techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Text interactions from the chatbot's pretest phase (a total of 23 participants; 10 people with epilepsy, PWE, 10 caregivers, and 3 healthcare professionals) were analyzed using JMedRoBERTa (Japanese Medical RoBERTa, a model fine-tuned on Japanese medical literature) to classify user messages into content clusters and DeBERTa (Decoding-enhanced BERT with Disentangled Attention, a model developed by Microsoft Research) to track emotional shifts. For sentiment analysis, only five PWE who interacted frequently with EpiloBot (more than 80 times) were included. The study employed UMAP (Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection) clustering and k-means algorithms to differentiate between objective medical inquiries and subjective, nonurgent queries. Sentiment analysis was conducted to explore the chatbot's influence on emotional engagement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Two primary content clusters were identified: "Medical Inquiry Cluster"-Objective, treatment-related questions about epilepsy medications and management strategies. "Exploratory Use Cluster"-Subjective or emotional inquiries, often focused on coping strategies and personal reflection. Sentiment analysis using DeBERTa revealed that messages related to proactive learning (e.g., gaining social skills) were associated with increased positive emotions, while introspective, self-evaluative messages showed reduced positivity. These findings provide insights into how chatbots influence user emotions and engagement patterns.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">NLP-based chatbot analyses offer valuable insights into patient engagement and emotional support needs. The study highlights the importance of designing chatbots that balance medical guidance with psychological support, particularly for chronic disease management. Future improvements in chatbot algorithms should focus on context-aware interactions and empathic response generation to optimize patient outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PLAIN LANGUAGE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study analyzed how people interacted with EpiloBot, an artificial intelligence (AI)-powered chatbot for epilepsy education and support. Using advanced language processing (NLP) techniques, we examined user messages to understand chatbot usage patterns and emotional responses. Results showed that users engaged in two main ways: medical inquiries about epilepsy treatment and exploratory, nonurgent conversations. Emotion analysis revealed that proactive learning interactions increased positive emotions, while self-reflective questions led to more neutral or negative sentiments. These findings suggest that chatbots can provide emotional benefits, but future improvements should focus on empathetic AI responses and personalized support.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Epilepsia Open published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of International League Against Epilepsy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanuki</LastName><ForeName>Keiichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Science and Engineering, Saitama University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Institute of Innovative Technology, Saitama University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oba</LastName><ForeName>Ryoya</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Science and Engineering, Saitama University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nozawa</LastName><ForeName>Naoki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Science and Engineering, Saitama University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishihara</LastName><ForeName>Tomoki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oga</LastName><ForeName>Koko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwayama</LastName><ForeName>Takayuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2191-4146</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Showa Women's University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiganami</LastName><ForeName>Takafumi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobayashi</LastName><ForeName>Sayaka</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuga</LastName><ForeName>Hironori</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Center, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshimasu</LastName><ForeName>Haruo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuramochi</LastName><ForeName>Izumi</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6416-5213</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Saitama Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Center, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epileptology, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>23J13</GrantID><Agency>Collaborative Research Support Grant Saitama University and Saitama Medical University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23006</GrantID><Agency>Japan Epilepsy Research Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21K13709</GrantID><Agency>KAKENHI</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Epilepsia Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101692036</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-9239</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI chatbots</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DeBERTa</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">JMedRoBERTa</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emotion tracking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epilepsy support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">natural language processing (NLP)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sentiment analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41379632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epi4.70186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Han T, Ma S, Zhang J, Yang Y, Tian J, et&#xa0;al. Summary of ChatGPT&#x2010;related research and perspective towards the future of large language models. Meta&#x2010;Radiol. 2023;1:17. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.METRAD.2023.100017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casu M, Triscari S, Battiato S, Guarnera L, Caponnetto P. AI chatbots for mental health: a scoping review of effectiveness, feasibility, and applications. Appl Sci. 2024;14:5889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque R, Rubya S. An overview of chatbot&#x2010;based Mobile mental health apps: insights from app description and user reviews. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2023;22(11):e44838. https://doi.org/10.2196/44838</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landais R, Sultan M, Thomas RH. The promise of AI large language models for epilepsy care. Epilepsy Behav. 2024;154:109747. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yebeh.2024.109747</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HW, Shin D&#x2010;H, Kim J, Lee G&#x2010;H, Cho JW. Assessing the performance of ChatGPT's responses to questions related to epilepsy: a cross&#x2010;sectional study on natural language processing and medical information retrieval. Seizure. 2024;114:1&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seizure.2023.11.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasthuri E, Subbulakshmi S, Sreedharan R. Precaution chatbot for epilepsy patients using natural language processing and deep learning sequential model. Procedia Comput Sci. 2024;233:537&#x2013;546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirumala AKG, Mishra S, Trivedi N, Shivakumar D, Singh A, Shariff S. A cross&#x2010;sectional study to assess response generated by ChatGPT and ChatSonic to patient queries about epilepsy. Telemat InformatRep. 2024;13:100110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milne&#x2010;Ives M, de Cock C, Lim E, Shehadeh MH, de Pennington N, Mole G, et&#xa0;al. The effectiveness of artificial intelligence conversational agents in health care: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22:e20346. https://doi.org/10.2196/20346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Ott M, Goyal N, Du J, Joshi M, Chen D, et&#xa0;al. Roberta: A Robustly Optimized BERT pretraining approach. arXiv preprint. 2019; arXiv:1907.11692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugimoto K, Iki T, Chida Y, Kanazawa K, Aizawa A, Sugimoto K, et&#xa0;al. JMedRoBERTa: development and evaluation of a pre&#x2010;trained language model based on japanese medical literature. Proceedings of the 29th Annual Conference of the Association for Natural Language Processing. Kyoto, Japan: The Association for Natural Language Processing; 2023. p. 707&#x2013;712 [in Japanese].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He P, Liu X, Gao J, Chen W. DeBERTa: decoding&#x2010;enhanced BERT with disentangled attention. Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021), Virtual Event, Austria, May 3&#x2013;7. Vienna, Austria: OpenReview.net; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuramochi I, Oba R, Nozawa N, Ishihara T, Oga K, Iwayama T, et&#xa0;al. Evaluating the impact of an AI&#x2010;powered chatbot on epilepsy education and stigma reduction: a pre&#x2010;post intervention study using EpiloBot. Epilepsia Open, 2025. Online ahead of print. https://doi.org/10.1002/epi4.70095</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen CL, Halter R, Kotz D, Loeb L, Cook S, Pidgeon D, et&#xa0;al. Using natural language processing and sentiment analysis to augment traditional user&#x2010;centered design: development and usability study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020;8:e16862. https://doi.org/10.2196/16862</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li PL, Yang C, Liu S, Hu M. Comparing insights from inductive qualitative analysis versus automated NLP algorithms for analyzing feedback in digital randomized controlled trials. 45th Euromicro conference on software engineering and advanced applications (SEAA). Kallithea, Greece: SEAA; 2019. p. 347&#x2013;354.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>