<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41642878</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on the performance degradation and failure mechanism of exhaust Systems for explosion proof diesel engines in different mining applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0329903</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0329903</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0329903</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0329903</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mine explosion-proof diesel engines are critical for underground coal mining, yet the long-term performance degradation of their exhaust systems poses substantial risks to operational safety and environmental compliance-a gap not addressed in short-term performance-focused studies. This study investigates the degradation and failure mechanisms of dry, wet, and combined exhaust systems under simulated mining conditions using a JHP4105DZDFB-G engine. Experimental results show that the wet system exhibits the fastest degradation, with exhaust backpressure increasing by 15.2% within 500 hours of continuous operation under simulated mining conditions due to sludge accumulation, leading to a 12-15% power loss. In contrast, the dry system maintains lower emissions (NO&#x2093;, HC, CO, and PM were reduced by 68.36%, 71.71%, 55.39%, and 82.28% compared to the wet system) but suffers thermal fatigue in condensers after 1000 hours. The combined system shows hybrid failures, with PM emissions exceeding regulatory limits (0.4&#x2009;g/kWh) at 300 hours. Mechanistic analysis reveals that wet systems fail primarily due to mechanical blockage and corrosion, while dry systems succumb to thermal-mechanical fatigue. A multivariable regression model and machine-learning algorithms are developed to predict degradation thresholds, enabling proactive maintenance. Thermal management optimization for dry systems is proposed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Shi et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyuan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining Products Safety Approval and Certification Center Co., Ltd., Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Haitao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining Products Safety Approval and Certification Center Co., Ltd., Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining Products Safety Approval and Certification Center Co., Ltd., Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Yuegang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-9028-7554</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Information and Control Engineering, Qingdao University of Technology, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001335">Vehicle Emissions</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005742">Gasoline</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001335" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vehicle Emissions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003032" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coal Mining</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005107" MajorTopicYN="Y">Explosions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008906" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mining</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005742" MajorTopicYN="N">Gasoline</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41642878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12875450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0329903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-39415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya S, Fan L, Azam S, Liu S. Advances in coal mining technology and sustainable mining techniques. The Coal Handbook. Elsevier. 2023:263&#x2013;321. doi: 10.1016/b978-0-12-824328-2.00011-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-12-824328-2.00011-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>China National Coal Association. Annual report on China&#x2019;s coal industry. Beijing: China Coal Industry Publishing House. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>General technical specifications for mining explosion-proof diesel engines. 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emission Limits and Measurement Methods for Diesel Engines of Non-road Mobile Machinery. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y. A review on explosion-proof of technology of mine diesel engine. Journal of Internal Combustion Engine and Accessories. 2022;16 (5):123&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Z, Wei H, Li G, Wang Y, Li Q, Zheng X, et al. Research and Analysis of Explosion-Proof Diesel Engine Performance Based on Different Exhaust Gas Cooling Systems. Energies. 2025;18 (3):610. doi: 10.3390/en18030610</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en18030610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng H, Shi Z, Chen C. Study on influence of exhaust system structure types on performance of mining explosion-proof diesel engine. Coal Mine Machinery. 2024;45 (12):36&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Hu Z, Bao J, Yang W, Wang F, Tang B, et al. Development and test of tail gas purification device for explosion-proof diesel engine of trackless tyred vehicle. Mining Safety &amp; Environmental Protection. 2025;52 (02):164&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan F, Bao J, Ge S, Yin Y. Research status and prospect of key technologies for mine explosion-proof diesel engines. Coal Science and Technology. 2018;46 (09):176&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X, Bao J, Tan F. Transient characteristics and parameter optimization of mine explosion-proof diesel engines. Industrial Mine Automation. 2022;48 (02):138&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R. Numerical Simulation Study on Exhaust Flame Arrester and Exhaust Gas Treatment Box for Mine Diesel Engine. North University of China. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Liu J, Huang W, Wu Y. Failure Analysis of a Diesel Engine Exhaust Manifold. Inter Metalcast. 2022;17 (1):538&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1007/s40962-022-00796-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40962-022-00796-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Cao Z, Lian Z, Yu H. Thermal Fatigue Behavior and Cracking Characteristics of High Si-Mo Nodular Cast Iron for Exhaust Manifolds. J Iron Steel Res Int. 2013;20 (6):52&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/s1006-706x(13)60111-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1006-706x(13)60111-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeytin HK, Kubilay C, Aydin H, Ebrinc AA, Aydemir B. Effect of microstructure on exhaust manifold cracks produced from SiMo ductile iron. J Iron Steel Res Int. 2009;16 (3):32&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/s1006-706x(09)60040-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1006-706x(09)60040-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei T. Numerical analysis of jet dry exhaust pipe for explosion-proof diesel engine. Journal Wuhan University Technology Information Management Engineering Education. 2014;36 (5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nova I, Tronconi E. Urea-SCR technology for deNOx after treatment of diesel exhausts. Springer New York. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taglialatela F, Lavorgna M, Di Iorio S, Mancaruso E, Vaglieco BM. Real Time Prediction of Particle Sizing at the Exhaust of a Diesel Engine by Using a Neural Network Model. SAE Int J Engines. 2017;10 (4):2202&#x2013;8. doi: 10.4271/2017-24-0051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4271/2017-24-0051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pronk A, Coble J, Stewart PA. Occupational exposure to diesel engine exhaust: a literature review. J Expo Sci Environ Epidemiol. 2009;19 (5):443&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1038/jes.2009.21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jes.2009.21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3073453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19277070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susanto ARIF, Purwanto P, Sunoko HR, Setiani O. Diesel engine exhaust emissions survey of underground mine in Indonesia. Journal of Industrial Pollution Control. 2016;32 (2):608&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehnejad MA, Mohammadi A, Rezaei M, Ahangari H. Cracking failure analysis of an engine exhaust manifold at high temperatures based on critical fracture toughness and FE simulation approach. Engineering Fracture Mechanics. 2019;211:125&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.engfracmech.2019.02.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2019.02.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park KH, Choi BL, Lee KW, Kim KS, Earmme YY. Modelling and design of an exhaust manifold under thermomechanical loading. Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers, Part D: Journal of Automobile Engineering. 2006;220 (12):1755&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1243/09544070d06404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1243/09544070d06404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu D, Huang D, Juma A, Schreiber CM, Wang X, Zhou CQ. Numerical Simulation of Thermal Stress for a Liquid-Cooled Exhaust Manifold. Journal of Thermal Science and Engineering Applications. 2009;1 (3). doi: 10.1115/1.4001258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4001258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang RJ, Poe SC. Shape optimal design of an engine exhaust manifold. Structural Optimization. 1993;5 (4):233&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/bf01743584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf01743584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Liu J, Zhong G, Huang W, Zou R. Analysis of a diesel engine cylinder head failure caused by casting porosity defects. Engineering Failure Analysis. 2021;127:105498. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2021.105498</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2021.105498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Va&#x161;ko A. Comparison of mechanical and fatigue properties of SiMo- and SiCu-types of nodular cast iron. Materials Today: Proceedings. 2020;32:168&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2020.04.184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.04.184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanatoru I. The safety devices of flame-proof diesel mine engines. In: Cavtat (Dubrovnik), Yugoslavia, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Tang B, Bao J, Hu Z, Peng Z, Hu D, et al. Design and performance test of four elements combined exhaust aftertreatment system for mine explosion-proof diesel engine. Journal of China Coal Society. 2024;49 (5):2547&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JY, Corsetti ML, Biundo L, Dobson DA, Beason RE. Modeling and measuring exhaust backpressure resulting from flow restriction through an aftertreatment system. SAE Transactions. 2003;724&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Chen C, Lu N, Wang C. Deep Auto-Encoder and Deep Forest-Assisted Failure Prognosis for Dynamic Predictive Maintenance Scheduling. Sensors (Basel). 2021;21 (24):8373. doi: 10.3390/s21248373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21248373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8706898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34960474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins RF, Moura Branco C, Gon&#xe7;alves-Coelho AM, Gomes EC. A failure analysis of exhaust systems for naval gas turbines. Part I: Fatigue life assessment. Engineering Failure Analysis. 2009;16 (4):1314&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2008.08.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2008.08.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Hu Y, Yan S, Zhu J, Yang L, Dong Z. Failure analysis of a natural gas engine exhaust manifold. Engineering Failure Analysis. 2023;154:107660. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>