<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41933091</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Artificial intelligence-powered evaluation model for English translation education in university: combining quantitative and qualitative methods.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-46314-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Assessing students' learning outcomes and abilities has always been a key link for English translation education in universities. However, traditional evaluation methods often face problems such as strong subjectivity and long time consumption, and it is difficult to meet the needs of large-scale classroom environments. To address these issues, this paper proposes and verifies a translation teaching quality evaluation model based on artificial intelligence (AI), aiming to improve the objectivity, consistency and efficiency of the evaluation. A mixed-methods design with data triangulation is employed to analyze data through a combination of qualitative and quantitative approaches. The quantitative part collects assessment feedback data from 796 English-related majors through questionnaire surveys, and the qualitative part uses focus group discussions to deeply analyze students' acceptance and trust in the AI evaluation system and the impact of AI evaluation on the development of translation ability. The results show that the AI evaluation model contributes to improving the consistency of evaluation results and the pertinence of feedback, and students have a high overall trust in AI evaluation. Nevertheless, some students questioned the limitations of AI in the cultural context and creativity evaluation. Based on the research findings, this paper further proposes practical suggestions for combining AI evaluation with traditional teacher evaluation in translation education, emphasizing the synergy between teachers and AI technology to achieve comprehensive optimization of translation teaching evaluation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quan</LastName><ForeName>Xunlian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Anqing Normal University, Anqing, 246133, China. quanxl@aqnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Yinan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science, Anqing Normal University, Anqing, 246133, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023aqnuxxkc06</GrantID><Agency>Key Teaching Research Program of Anqing Normal University in Anhui Province (CN)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025zyxwjxalk250</GrantID><Agency>New Era Education Quality Project of Anhui Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Assessment feedback</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Comprehensive optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Data triangulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">English translation education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests. Ethical approval: The author declares that this research article complies with the ethical standards of this journal. All methods and experimental protocols were approved by the &#x200c;Ethics Committee of Anqing Normal University&#x200c; and performed in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations. Informed consent was obtained from all students who participated in the survey.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41933091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-46314-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-46314-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ramsden, P. A performance indicator of teaching quality in higher education: The course experience questionnaire. Stud. High. Educ. 16, 129&#x2013;150. https://doi.org/10.1080/03075079112331382944 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gile, D. Basic concepts and models for interpreter and translator training (John Benjamins Publishing Company, 2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pym, A. Exploring translation theories (Routledge, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shreve, G. M. The deliberate practice: Translation and expertise. J. Transl. Stud. 9, 27&#x2013;42 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark, I. Formative assessment: Assessment is for self-regulated learning. Educ. Psychol. Rev. 24, 205&#x2013;249. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-011-9191-6 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling-Hammond, L. &amp; Snyder, J. Authentic assessment of teaching in context. Teach. Teach. Educ. 16, 523&#x2013;545. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0742-051X(00)00015-9 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brookhart, S. M. Educational assessment knowledge and skills for teachers. Educ. Meas.: Issues Pract. 30, 3&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745-3992.2010.00195.x (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waddington, C. Different methods of evaluating student translations: The question of validity. Meta 46, 311&#x2013;325. https://doi.org/10.7202/004583arCopiedAnerrorhasoccurred (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawat, I., Kumar, R. R., Mutanda, T. &amp; Bux, F. Biodiesel from microalgae: A critical evaluation from laboratory to large scale production. Appl. Energy 103, 444&#x2013;467. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2012.10.004 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van de Vijver, F. &amp; Hambleton, R. K. Translating tests. Eur. Psychol. 1, 89&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.1027/1016-9040.1.2.89 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicol, D. J. &amp; Macfarlane-Dick, D. Formative assessment and self-regulated learning: A model and seven principles of good feedback practice. Stud. High. Educ. 31, 199&#x2013;218. https://doi.org/10.1027/1016-9040.1.2.89 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudolph, J., Tan, S. &amp; Tan, S. ChatGPT: Bullshit spewer or the end of traditional assessments in higher education?. J. Appl. Learn. Teach. 6, 342&#x2013;363 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, X. &amp; Stede, M. A survey of current machine learning approaches to student free-text evaluation for intelligent tutoring. Int. J. Artif. Intell. Educ. 33, 992&#x2013;1030. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40593-022-00323-0 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki, N., Turaev, S., Shuaib, K., Krishnan, A. &amp; Mohamed, E. Automating the mapping of course learning outcomes to program learning outcomes using natural language processing for accurate educational program evaluation. Educ. Inf. Technol. 28, 16723&#x2013;16742. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10639-023-11877-4 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, Y., Cai, Z., Tan, C.-W., Huang, Q. &amp; Liu, H. Natural language processing (NLP) in management research: A literature review. J. Manag. Anal. 7, 139&#x2013;172. https://doi.org/10.1080/23270012.2020.1756939 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, J. et al. Transforming assessment: The impacts and implications of large language models and generative AI. Educ. Meas.: Issues Pract. 43, 16&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1111/emip.12602 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitriadou, E. &amp; Lanitis, A. A critical evaluation, challenges, and future perspectives of using artificial intelligence and emerging technologies in smart classrooms. Smart Learn. Environ. 10, 12. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40561-023-00231-3 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambo, I. et al. Grad-AI: An automated grading tool for code assessment and feedback in programming course. Educ. Inf. Technol. 30(7), 9859&#x2013;9899. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10639-024-13218-5 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, L. &amp; Fu, J. Improving efficiency and accuracy in English translation learning: Investigating a semantic analysis correction algorithm. Appl. Artif. Intell. 37, 2219945. https://doi.org/10.1080/08839514.2023.2219945 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadler, D.&#xa0;R. Beyond feedback: Developing student capability in complex appraisal. In Approaches to assessment that enhance learning in higher education, 45&#x2013;60 (Routledge, 2014). https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315872322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis, C. M. et al. Review of computer vision application in in vitro fertilization: The application of deep learning-based computer vision technology in the world of IVF. J. Assist. Reprod. Genet. 38, 1627&#x2013;1639. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10815-021-02123-2 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonk, C.&#xa0;J. &amp; Graham, C.&#xa0;R. The handbook of blended learning: Global perspectives, local designs (Wiley+ ORM, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrison, D.&#xa0;R. &amp; Vaughan, N.&#xa0;D. Blended learning in higher education: Framework, principles, and guidelines (John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isteni&#x10d;, A. Blended learning in higher education: The integrated and distributed model and a thematic analysis. Discov. Educ. 3, 165. https://doi.org/10.1007/s44217-024-00239-y (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra, P. &amp; Koehler, M. J. Technological pedagogical content knowledge: A framework for teacher knowledge. Teach. Coll. Rec. 108, 1017&#x2013;1054 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bond, M., Mar&#xed;n, V. I., Dolch, C., Bedenlier, S. &amp; Zawacki-Richter, O. Digital transformation in German higher education: Student and teacher perceptions and usage of digital media. Int. J. Educ. Technol. High. Educ. 15, 1&#x2013;20 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, S. &amp; Hale, S. Translation and interpreting assessment in the context of educational measurement. Translation today: Trends and perspectives 205&#x2013;224 (2003). https://doi.org/10.21832/9781853596179-017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez Melis, N. &amp; Hurtado Albir, A. Assessment in translation studies: Research needs. Meta 46, 272&#x2013;287 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatim, B.&#xa0;A. Teaching and researching translation (Routledge, 2014). https://doi.org/10.4324/9781315832906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adab, B. Evaluating translation competence. In Developing translation competence, 215&#x2013;228 (John Benjamins Publishing Company, 2011). https://doi.org/10.1075/btl.38.20ada.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy, M. Computer-assisted language learning: Context and conceptualization (Oxford University Press, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves, T. Evaluating what really matters in computer-based education. Computer education: New perspectives 219&#x2013;246 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Link, S. &amp; Hegelheimer, V. Rethinking the role of automated writing evaluation (AWE) feedback in ESL writing instruction. J. Second. Lang. Writ. 27, 1&#x2013;18 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page, E.&#xa0;B. Project essay grade: Peg (Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Publishers, 2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara, D. S. &amp; Kendeou, P. The early automated writing evaluation (EAWE) framework. Assess. Educ.: Princ. Policy Pract. 29, 150&#x2013;182 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhary, K. Natural language processing. Fundamentals of artificial intelligence 603&#x2013;649 (Springer, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunjiu, L., Wei, W. &amp; Zheng, Y. Artificial intelligence-generated and human expert-designed vocabulary tests: A comparative study. Sage Open 12, 21582440221082130 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shan, X., Xu, Y., Wang, Y., Lin, Y.-S. &amp; Bao, Y. Cross-cultural implications of large language models: An extended comparative analysis. In International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction, 106&#x2013;118 (Springer, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, C. K. Y. A comprehensive ai policy education framework for university teaching and learning. Int. J. Educ. Technol. High. Educ. 20, 38 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepard, L. A. The role of classroom assessment in teaching and learning (American Educational Research Association, Washington, DC, 2001). CSE Technical Report 517, Center for the Study of Evaluation, UCLA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, M., Zhang, L. J. &amp; Biebricher, C. Investigating students&#x2019; cognitive processes in generative AI-assisted digital multimodal composing and traditional writing. Comput. Educ. 211, 104977. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2023.104977 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell, J.&#xa0;W. &amp; Creswell, J.&#xa0;D. Research design: Qualitative, quantitative, and mixed methods approaches (Sage publications, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achiam, J. et al. Gpt-4 technical report. arXiv preprint arXiv:2303.08774 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, D. T. K., Wu, W., Leung, J. K. L., Chiu, T. K. F. &amp; Chu, S. K. W. Design and validation of the ai literacy questionnaire: The affective, behavioural, cognitive and ethical approach. Br. J. Educ. Technol. 55, 1082&#x2013;1104. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjet.13411 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velander, J., Taiye, M. A., Otero, N. &amp; Milrad, M. Artificial intelligence in k-12 education: Eliciting and reflecting on Swedish teachers&#x2019; understanding of AI and its implications for teaching &amp; learning. Educ. Inf. Technol. 29, 4085&#x2013;4105. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10639-023-11990-4 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., Fengchao, Y. &amp; Zhang, E. A systematic review of learning task design for k-12 AI education: Trends, challenges, and opportunities. Comput. Educ.: Artif. Intell. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.caeai.2024.100217 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carolus, A., Koch, M. J., Straka, S., Latoschik, M. E. &amp; Wienrich, C. Mails-meta AI literacy scale: Development and testing of an AI literacy questionnaire based on well-founded competency models and psychological change-and meta-competencies. Comput. Hum. Behav.: Artif. Hum. 1, 100014 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai, X. et al. Developing and validating an instrument for teachers&#x2019; acceptance of artificial intelligence in education. Int. J. Educ. Technol. High. Educ. 30(10), 13439&#x2013;13461 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertzog, M. A. Considerations in determining sample size for pilot studies. Res. Nurs. &amp; Health 31, 180&#x2013;191 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johanson, G. A. &amp; Brooks, G. P. Initial scale development: Sample size for pilot studies. Educ. Psychol. Meas. 70, 394&#x2013;400 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norusis, M. SPSS 15.0 guide to data analysis (Prentice Hall Press, 2007). https://doi.org/10.5555/1396185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarstedt, M., Mooi, E., Sarstedt, M. &amp; Mooi, E. Regression analysis. A concise guide to market research: The process, data, and methods using IBM SPSS Statistics 209&#x2013;256 (2019). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-662-56707-4_7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, L. J., Muller, K. E., Wolfinger, R. D., Qaqish, B. F. &amp; Schabenberger, O. An R2 statistic for fixed effects in the linear mixed model. Stat. Med. 27, 6137&#x2013;6157 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guest, G., Bunce, A. &amp; Johnson, L. How many interviews are enough? An experiment with data saturation and variability. Field Methods 18, 59&#x2013;82 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhakal, K. Nvivo. J. Med. Libr. Assoc. 110, 270 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun, V. &amp; Clarke, V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual. Res. Psychol. 3, 77&#x2013;101. https://doi.org/10.1191/1478088706qp063oa (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heale, R. &amp; Forbes, D. Understanding triangulation in research. Evid.-Based Nurs. 16, 98&#x2013;98. https://doi.org/10.1136/eb-2013-101494 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uyan&#x131;k, G. K. &amp; G&#xfc;ler, N. A study on multiple linear regression analysis. Procedia - Soc. Behav. Sci. 106, 234&#x2013;240 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattie, J. &amp; Timperley, H. The power of feedback. Rev. Educ. Res. 77, 81&#x2013;112. https://doi.org/10.3102/003465430298487 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacker, J. V. et al. Trust in virtual teams: A multidisciplinary review and integration. Australas. J. Inf. Syst. https://doi.org/10.3127/ajis.v23i0.1757 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh, V., Morris, M.&#xa0;G., Davis, G.&#xa0;B. &amp; Davis, F.&#xa0;D. User acceptance of information technology: Toward a unified view. MIS quarterly 425&#x2013;478 (2003). https://ssrn.com/abstract=3375136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, D., Huang, Y. &amp; Xie, H. Digital game-based vocabulary learning: Where are we and where are we going?. Comput. Assist. Lang. Learn. 34, 751&#x2013;777. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2019.1640745 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shute, V. J. Focus on formative feedback. Rev. Educ. Res. 78, 153&#x2013;189. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654307313795 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker, R. S. &amp; Hawn, A. Algorithmic bias in education. Int. J. Artif. Intell. Educ. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40593-021-00285-9 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong, R. L. The midpoint on a five-point Likert-type scale. Percept. Mot. Ski. 64, 359&#x2013;362 (1987).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ab Hamid, M.&#xa0;R., Sami, W. &amp; Sidek, M.&#xa0;M. Discriminant validity assessment: Use of fornell &amp; larcker criterion versus HTMT criterion. In J. Phys.: Conf. Ser., vol. 890, 012163 (IOP Publishing, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raychaudhuri, S. Introduction to monte carlo simulation. In 2008 Winter simulation conference, 91&#x2013;100 (IEEE, 2008). https://doi.org/10.1109/WSC.2008.4736059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Salami, M. K., Makela, C. J. &amp; De Miranda, M. A. Assessing changes in teachers&#x2019; attitudes toward interdisciplinary stem teaching. Int. J. Technol. Des. Educ. 27, 63&#x2013;88 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St, L. et al. Analysis of variance (ANOVA). Chemom. Intell. Lab. Syst. 6, 259&#x2013;272 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werman, M., Peleg, S. &amp; Rosenfeld, A. A distance metric for multidimensional histograms. Comput. Vis., Graph., Image Process. 32, 328&#x2013;336 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmatillah, K. Translation errors in the process of translation. J. Engl. Educ. https://doi.org/10.20885/jee.v7i1.4466 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaigrain, K. &amp; Arhin, A. K. Using reliability and item analysis to evaluate a teacher-developed test in educational measurement and evaluation. Cogent Educ. 4, 1301013. https://doi.org/10.1080/2331186X.2017.1301013 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthmainnah, M., Cardoso, L., Alsbbagh, Y. A. M.&#xa0;R., Al Yakin, A. &amp; Apriani, E. Advancing sustainable learning by boosting student self-regulated learning and feedback through AI-driven personalized in EFL education. In International Conference on Explainable Artificial Intelligence in the Digital Sustainability, 36&#x2013;54 (Springer, 2024). https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-63717-9_3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwivedi, Y. K. et al. Artificial intelligence (AI): Multidisciplinary perspectives on emerging challenges, opportunities, and agenda for research, practice and policy. Int. J. Inf. Manag. 57, 101994. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2019.08.002 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, F. D., Bagozzi, R. &amp; Warshaw, P. Technology acceptance model. J. Manag. Sci. 35, 982&#x2013;1003. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-45274-2 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, C. K. Y. &amp; Tsi, L. H. Will generative AI replace teachers in higher education? A study of teacher and student perceptions. Stud. Educ. Eval. 83, 101395. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stueduc.2024.101395 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>