<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41682356</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reliable Communication in Distributed Photovoltaic Sensor Networks: A Large Language Model-Driven Approach.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">838</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s26030838</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Distributed photovoltaic (DPV) systems present a cost-effective and sustainable industrial energy solution, yet their reliable monitoring faces significant technological constraints. This paper proposes a hierarchical optimization framework that integrates hysteresis-based traffic shaping at the network layer with Large Language Model (LLM)-driven diagnostics at the application layer. The proposed dynamic algorithm minimizes latency and downtime by prioritizing critical fault data. Priority-based scheduling ensures this critical data is transmitted preferentially over routine sensor readings. At the application layer, the system utilizes physics-informed prompt engineering to perform zero-shot root cause analysis, circumventing the training data requirements of traditional classifiers. Under a 10 Mbps gateway bandwidth, our method achieves a 46.08% to 49.87% reduction in P50 latency compared to traditional approaches. Moreover, the LLM-powered diagnostic system provides detailed assessments, enabling precise fault diagnosis for DPV systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Wu</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power Dispatch Control Center, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang 550000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power Dispatch Control Center, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang 550000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power Dispatch Control Center, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang 550000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Guanghui</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power Dispatch Control Center, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang 550000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Ji</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power Dispatch Control Center, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang 550000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Power Dispatch Control Center, Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd., Guiyang 550000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Zhongming</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-2695-5139</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan 430072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2772-4856</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computer Science, Wuhan University, Wuhan 430072, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic Information and Communications, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan 430074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>060000KC24100003</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project of Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">distributed photovoltaic system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fault diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wireless transmission</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that this study received funding from Science and Technology Project of Guizhou Power Grid Co., Ltd. The funder had the following involvement with the study: Wu Dong was responsible for conceptualization and methodology design; Xu Liu contributed to methodology design; Qing Liu and Guanghui Zhang undertook the validation work; Ji Shi and Xun Zhao were responsible for resource coordination and preparation. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41682356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12899476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s26030838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s26030838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asmelash E., Prakash G. Future of Solar Photovoltaic: Deployment, Investment, Technology, Grid Integration and Socio-Economic Aspects. International Renewable Energy Agency; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates: 2019. pp. 1&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko&#xdf; D., Bytschkow D., Gupta P.K., Sch&#xe4;tz B., Sellmayr F., Bauerei&#xdf; S. Establishing a smart grid node architecture and demonstrator in an office environment using the soa approach; Proceedings of the 2012 First International Workshop on Software Engineering Challenges for the Smart Grid (SE-SmartGrids); Zurich, Switzerland. 3 June 2012; pp. 8&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Liu X., Xun Y., Yu S. Common mode noise reduction of three-level active neutral point clamped inverters with uncertain parasitic capacitance of photovoltaic panels. IEEE Trans. Power Electron. 2019;35:6974&#x2013;6988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degner T., Enders W., Sch&#xfc;lbe A., Daub H. EMC and safety design for photovoltaic systems (ESDEPS); Proceedings of the Sixteenth European Photovoltaic Solar Energy Conference; Glasgow, UK. 1&#x2013;5 May 2020; pp. 2253&#x2013;2256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiraprasertwong J., Jettanasen C. Analysis and mitigation of conducted electromagnetic interference in a photovoltaic single-phase inverter; Proceedings of the TENCON 2014&#x2014;2014 IEEE Region 10 Conference; Bangkok, Thailand. 22&#x2013;25 October 2014; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada T., Mori T., Tokuda M., Suenaga S., Igarashi H. 2005 International Symposium on Electromagnetic Compatibility, 2005. EMC 2005. Volume 1. IEEE; New York, NY, USA: 2005. Radiated electromagnetic field from a solar cell for CISPR radiated emission measurement method; pp. 112&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu I., Shinozuka T., Ishigami S., Matsumoto Y. Evaluation of electromagnetic radiation from the DC side of a photovoltaic power generation system. IEEE Electromagn. Compat. Mag. 2015;4:73&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1109/MEMC.2015.7204055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MEMC.2015.7204055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stracqualursi E., Di Lorenzo G., Calcara L., Araneo R. EMC Issues in High-Power Grid-Connected Photovoltaic Plants: An Update After 15 Years. IEEE Trans. Electromagn. Compat. 2024;66:1633&#x2013;1645. doi: 10.1109/TEMC.2024.3440848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TEMC.2024.3440848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kane M.M., Taylor N., M&#xe5;nsson D. Electromagnetic interference from solar photovoltaic systems: A Review. Electronics. 2024;14:31. doi: 10.3390/electronics14010031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14010031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu W., Zhang L., Yin H., Markel L.C., Liao D., McConnell B.W., Liu Y. Modeling, testing, and mitigation of electromagnetic pulse on PV systems. Sol. Energy. 2023;264:112010. doi: 10.1016/j.solener.2023.112010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solener.2023.112010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira R.I., Dupont I.M., Carvalho P.C., Juca S.C. IoT embedded linux system based on Raspberry Pi applied to real-time cloud monitoring of a decentralized photovoltaic plant. Measurement. 2018;114:286&#x2013;297. doi: 10.1016/j.measurement.2017.09.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2017.09.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kota V.R., Kommula B.N., Afzal A., Asif M., Hui L.T. Grid Integration of PV Systems with Advanced Control and Machine Learning Strategies. IEEE Access. 2025;13:138820&#x2013;138833. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3593044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3593044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirateruna E.S., Ashari M., Riawan D.C. Estimation and Assessment of Partial Shading Patterns in Large PV Farms using ANN Algorithm. IEEE Access. 2025;13:139189&#x2013;139202. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3596268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3596268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarif M., Moghaddass R. Advanced Anomaly Detection in Smart Grids Using Graph Convolutional Networks with Integrated Node and Line Sensor Data. IEEE Access. 2025;13:141170&#x2013;141186. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3595431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3595431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalilifar M., Shahrtash S.M. Early Detection of Voltage Instability: A Transparent, Rule-Based Method for Cyber-Resilient Grids. IEEE Access. 2025;13:142262&#x2013;142273. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3597555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3597555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y., He H., Zhang Z., Zhang X., Shen Z., Yin J., Miao X. Methods for Monitoring the Photovoltaic Panel: A Review; Proceedings of the 2024 12th International Conference on Agro-Geoinformatics (Agro-Geoinformatics); Novi Sad, Serbia. 15&#x2013;18 July 2024; pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge L., Du T., Li C., Li Y., Yan J., Rafiq M.U. Virtual collection for distributed photovoltaic data: Challenges, methodologies, and applications. Energies. 2022;15:8783. doi: 10.3390/en15238783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15238783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashidi Y., Moallem M., Vojdani S. Wireless Zigbee system for perormance monitoring of photovoltaic panels; Proceedings of the 2011 37th IEEE Photovoltaic Specialists Conference; Seattle, WA, USA. 19&#x2013;24 June 2011; pp. 003205&#x2013;003207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kekre A., Gawre S.K. Solar photovoltaic remote monitoring system using IOT; Proceedings of the 2017 International Conference on Recent Innovations in Signal Processing and Embedded Systems (RISE); Bhopal, India. 27&#x2013;29 October 2017; pp. 619&#x2013;623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., He S., Sun L., Jiang T., Zhang Q. Cross-technology communications for heterogeneous IoT devices through artificial doppler shifts. IEEE Trans. Wirel. Commun. 2018;18:796&#x2013;806. doi: 10.1109/TWC.2018.2883443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TWC.2018.2883443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Yang L., Zhang Q., Jiang T. Securing on-body IoT devices by exploiting creeping wave propagation. IEEE J. Sel. Areas Commun. 2018;36:696&#x2013;703. doi: 10.1109/JSAC.2018.2824939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSAC.2018.2824939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z., Wang W., Huang Q., Jiang T., Zhang Q. Securing IoT devices by exploiting backscatter propagation signatures. IEEE Trans. Mob. Comput. 2021;21:4595&#x2013;4608. doi: 10.1109/TMC.2021.3084754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TMC.2021.3084754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H., Wu Y., Li F., Kuang W., He Y., Zhang Q., Wang W. PassiveBLE: Towards Fully Commodity-Compatible BLE Backscatter; Proceedings of the 31th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking; Hong Kong, China. 4&#x2013;8 November 2025; pp. 1000&#x2013;1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H., Xie Y., Zhang X., Wang W., Zhang X., He J. Gpsmirror: Expanding accurate gps positioning to shadowed and indoor regions with backscatter; Proceedings of the 29th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking; Madrid, Spain. 2&#x2013;6 October 2023; pp. 1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H., Cui M., Wang N., Qiu L., Xiong J., Wang W. Gpsense: Passive sensing with pervasive gps signals; Proceedings of the 30th Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing And Networking; Washington, DC, USA. 30 September&#x2013;4 October 2024; pp. 1000&#x2013;1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji X., Zhang L., Zhang W., Peng F., Mao Y., Liao X., Zhang K. LEMAD: LLM-Empowered Multi-Agent System for Anomaly Detection in Power Grid Services. Electronics. 2025;14:3008. doi: 10.3390/electronics14153008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14153008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Liu Z. An Intelligent Educational System: Analyzing Student Behavior and Academic Performance Using Multi-Source Data. Electronics. 2025;14:3328. doi: 10.3390/electronics14163328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14163328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K., Yang S., Jeong J., Lee Y., Shin D. Enhancing Security and Applicability of Local LLM-Based Document Retrieval Systems in Smart Grid Isolated Environments. Electronics. 2025;14:3407. doi: 10.3390/electronics14173407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics14173407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeti S.R., Singh S. Monitoring system for photovoltaic plants: A review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2017;67:1180&#x2013;1207. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2016.09.088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2016.09.088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shandong University Power System Economic Operation Team  Energy &amp; Meteorology Research Service Platform. 2023.  [(accessed on 25 March 2025)].  Available online:  https://energymeteo-pseo.sdu.edu.cn/dataset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav G., Paul K. Architecture and security of SCADA systems: A review. Int. J. Crit. Infrastruct. Prot. 2021;34:100433. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcip.2021.100433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcip.2021.100433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>