<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41407254</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-9010</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RoFo : Fortschritte auf dem Gebiete der Rontgenstrahlen und der Nuklearmedizin</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rofo</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Digital Transformation and Artificial Intelligence in Radiology: Challenges and Opportunities for Clinical Practice, Research, and the Next Generation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2741-9717</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Radiology is at the center of the digital transformation of the healthcare system. As a highly digital field, radiology is well-suited for the early implementation and critical evaluation of innovative technologies, such as artificial intelligence (AI). This review aims to comprehensively and distinctly present the opportunities and challenges of digital transformation in radiology, focusing on clinical applications, research, and promoting young talents.This narrative review is based on selective evaluation of relevant scientific literature and publications from the last 10 years. Relevant German- and English-language articles on the digital transformation of radiology were considered, particularly those addressing digital infrastructure, artificial intelligence, ethical and regulatory frameworks, and education and training.Digitalization offers significant opportunities for radiology. In addition to advancing imaging procedures and automating image analysis with AI, digitalization optimizes workflows, enables personalized diagnostics, and fosters new care models, such as teleradiology. However, there are also key challenges: Data protection issues, a lack of standardization, insufficient validation, and regulatory hurdles are hindering its widespread implementation in hospitals. To future-proof radiology, it is essential to promote young talent and incorporate digital skills in the curriculum. &#xb7; Due to its digital structure, radiology is particularly well-suited to integrating new medical technologies.. &#xb7; Some AI-powered applications have been adopted in everyday clinical practice but they require further validation.. &#xb7; A key task for the future is systematically training prospective radiologists in digital skills.. &#xb7; Hoffmann E, Bannas P, Bayerl N et al. Digital Transformation and Artificial Intelligence in Radiology: Challenges and Opportunities for Clinical Practice, Research, and the Next Generation. Rofo 2025; DOI 10.1055/a-2741-9717.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoffmann</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0958-6699</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic of Radiology, University of M&#xfc;nster, M&#xfc;nster, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bannas</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayerl</LastName><ForeName>Nadine</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Radiology, University Hospital Erlangen, Friedrich-Alexander University Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg (FAU), Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cyran</LastName><ForeName>Clemens C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, LMU University Hospital, LMU Munich, M&#xfc;nchen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dietzel</LastName><ForeName>Matthias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9248-1398</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Radiology, University Hospital Erlangen, Friedrich-Alexander University Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg (FAU), Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eisenbl&#xe4;tter</LastName><ForeName>Michel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept. of Diagnostic &amp; Interventional Radiology, University Hospital OWL of Bielefeld University Campus Hospital Lippe, Detmold, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hilger</LastName><ForeName>Ingrid</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Radiology, Institute of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology, Jena University Hospital, Friedrich Schiller University Jena, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jung</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, Clinic Nordfriesland, Husum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiessling</LastName><ForeName>Fabian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7341-0399</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Experimental Molecular Imaging, RWTH Aachen University, Aachen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fraunhofer Institute for Digital Medicine MEVIS, Bremen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathy</LastName><ForeName>Claudius Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Radiology, University Hospital Erlangen, Friedrich-Alexander University Erlangen-N&#xfc;rnberg (FAU), Erlangen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;ller</LastName><ForeName>Lukas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University Medical Center of the Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schick</LastName><ForeName>Fritz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Experimental Radiology, Department of Diagnostic Radiology, Eberhard Karls University of T&#xfc;bingen, Tuebingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wegner</LastName><ForeName>Franz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Interventional Radiology, University Hospital Schleswig-Holstein Campus L&#xfc;beck, L&#xfc;beck, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B&#xe4;uerle</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University Medical Center of the Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adams</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Diagnostic and Interventional Radiology, Faculty of Medicine, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><Language>ger</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Digitale Transformation und k&#xfc;nstliche Intelligenz in der Radiologie: Herausforderungen und Chancen f&#xfc;r Klinik, Forschung und Nachwuchs.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Rofo</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7507497</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1438-9010</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText>Die Radiologie steht im Zentrum der digitalen Transformation des Gesundheitswesens. Als hochdigitalisierte Fachdisziplin ist sie pr&#xe4;destiniert f&#xfc;r die fr&#xfc;he Implementierung und kritische Bewertung innovativer Technologien wie der K&#xfc;nstlichen Intelligenz (KI). Ziel dieser &#xdc;bersichtsarbeit ist es, die Chancen und Herausforderungen der digitalen Transformation in der Radiologie umfassend und differenziert darzustellen, wobei der Fokus auf klinische Anwendungen, Forschung und Nachwuchsf&#xf6;rderung liegt.Diese narrative &#xdc;bersichtsarbeit basiert auf einer selektiven Auswertung aktueller wissenschaftlicher Literatur sowie positionsrelevanter Fachver&#xf6;ffentlichungen der letzten 10 Jahre. Ber&#xfc;cksichtigt wurden deutsch- und englischsprachige Beitr&#xe4;ge, die f&#xfc;r die digitale Transformation der Radiologie relevant sind, insbesondere zu den Themenbereichen digitale Infrastruktur, k&#xfc;nstliche Intelligenz, ethische und regulatorische Rahmenbedingungen sowie Aus- und Weiterbildung.Die Digitalisierung er&#xf6;ffnet der Radiologie erhebliche Potenziale: Neben der Weiterentwicklung bildgebender Verfahren und der automatisierten Bildanalyse mittels KI optimiert sie Arbeitsabl&#xe4;ufe, erm&#xf6;glicht personalisierte Diagnostik und f&#xf6;rdert neue Versorgungsmodelle wie die Teleradiologie. Gleichzeitig bestehen jedoch auch zentrale Herausforderungen: Datenschutz, mangelnde Standardisierung, unzureichende Validierung und regulatorische H&#xfc;rden behindern eine fl&#xe4;chendeckende Implementierung in der Klinik. Um die Radiologie zukunftssicher aufzustellen, sind Nachwuchsf&#xf6;rderung und die curriculare Integration digitaler Kompetenzen essenziell. &#xb7; Aufgrund ihrer digitalen Struktur ist die Radiologie besonders gut geeignet, neue Technologien in der Medizin zu integrieren.. &#xb7; KI-basierte Anwendungen sind teilweise bereits im klinischen Alltag etabliert, ben&#xf6;tigen jedoch eine weiterf&#xfc;hrende Validierung.. &#xb7; Eine zentrale Zukunftsaufgabe ist die systematische Ausbildung digitaler Kompetenzen bei angehenden Radiolog:innen.. &#xb7; Hoffmann E, Bannas P, Bayerl N et al. Digital Transformation and Artificial Intelligence in Radiology: Challenges and Opportunities for Clinical Practice, Research, and the Next Generation. Rofo 2025; DOI 10.1055/a-2741-9717.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Thieme. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Die Autorinnen/Autoren geben an, dass kein Interessenkonflikt besteht.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41407254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2741-9717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>