<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41662501</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-9774</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Computers, informatics, nursing : CIN</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Comput Inform Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Video-based Handover Training on Nursing Students' Teamwork Attitude: A Mixed-Methods Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CIN.0000000000001496</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Generation Z nursing students, accustomed to text and video communication, face challenges in direct interaction, relationship building, and clinical adaptation. This study aims to investigate the effects of handover training using video-based debriefings on nursing students' teamwork attitudes. This mixed-methods study employed a sequential exploratory design. The study was conducted from March to October 2024. Handover training using video-based debriefings was administered to 37 fourth-year nursing students. Pre-test and post-test surveys assessing teamwork attitudes were conducted, and 15 participants engaged in individual interviews. Teamwork attitudes were analyzed using a paired t-test, and the qualitative data were analyzed using content analysis. Teamwork attitudes significantly improved from 4.28 to 4.58 out of 5. Three themes emerged: (1) recognizing handover-related challenges that hinder patient care provision; (2) learning the power of collaboration to support continuity of care; and (3) achieving patient-centered care through effective teamwork. Handover training using video-based debriefings effectively enhances communication, collaboration, and nursing students' understanding of teamwork by fostering both self-reflection and peer reflection. These improvements are anticipated to ultimately support the delivery of safer, high-quality, and patient-centered care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Seung Hee</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Dankook University, Cheonan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoo</LastName><ForeName>Hye Jin</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9337-5167</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Nursing, Kyung Hee University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Comput Inform Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101141667</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1538-2931</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient handover</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient safety</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41662501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CIN.0000000000001496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00024665-990000000-00482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Yoo HJ. Therapeutic communication using mirroring interventions in nursing education: a mixed methods study. Asian Nursing Research 2024;18(5):435&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le A, Lee MA, Wilson J. Nursing handoff education: an integrative literature review. Nurse Education in Practice 2023;68:103570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukoh MX, Siah CJR. A systematic review on the structured handover interventions between nurses in improving patient safety outcomes. Journal of Nursing Management 2020;28(3):744&#x2013;755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien LJ, Slade D, Dahm MR, et al. Improving patient-centred care through a tailored intervention addressing nursing clinical handover communication in its organizational and cultural context. Journal of Advanced Nursing 2022;78(5):1413&#x2013;1430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderzwan KJ, Kilroy S, Daniels A, O&#x2019;Rourke J. Nurse-to-nurse handoff with distractors and interruptions: an integrative review. Nurse Education in Practice 2023;67:103550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalaf Z. Improving patient handover: a narrative review. African Journal of Paediatric Surgery 2023;20(3):166&#x2013;170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi JY, Byun M, Kim EJ. Educational interventions for improving nursing shift handovers: a systematic review. Nurse Education in Practice 2024;74:103846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pun J. Factors associated with nurses&#x2019; perceptions, their communication skills and the quality of clinical handover in the Hong Kong context. BMC Nursing 2021;20(1):95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rueda-Medina B, Reina-Cabello JC, Buend&#xed;a-Castro M, et al. Effectiveness of video-assisted debriefing versus oral debriefing in simulation-based interdisciplinary health professions education: a randomized trial. Nurse Education in Practice 2024;75:103901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H, Yeon K, Han ST. A review on the use of effect size in nursing research. Journal of Korean Academy of Nursing 2015;45(5):641&#x2013;649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DP, Amodeo AM, Krokos KJ, Slonim A, Herrera H. Assessing teamwork attitudes in healthcare: development of the TeamSTEPPS teamwork attitudes questionnaire. Quality and Safety in Health Care 2010;19(6):e49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller JM. Motivational and instructional design: a theoretical perspective. Journal of Instructional Development 1979;2(4):26&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh HF, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qualitative Health Research 2005;15(9):1277&#x2013;1288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. The problem of rigor in qualitative research. Advances in Nursing Science 1986;8(3):27&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tacchini-Jacquier N, Hertzog H, Ambord K, Urben P, Turini P, Verloo H. An evidence-based, nursing handover standard for a multisite public hospital in Switzerland: web-based, modified Delphi study. JMIR Nursing 2020;3(1):e17876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhudy LM, Johnson MR, Krecke CA, et al. Standardized change-of-shift handoff: Nurses&#x2019; perspectives and implications for evidence-based practice. American Journal of Critical Care 2022;31(3):181&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung JYS, Li WHC, Ho LLK, Cheung AT, Chung JOK. Newly graduate nurse perception and experience of clinical handover. Nurse Education Today 2021;97:104693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh S, Ramamoorthy L, Pottakat B. Impact of structured clinical handover protocol on communication and patient satisfaction. Journal of Patient Experience 2021;8:2374373521997733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek H, Han K, Cho H, Ju J. Nursing teamwork is essential in promoting patient-centered care: a cross-sectional study. BMC Nursing 2023;22(1):433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi N, Kim J, Kim H. The influence of patient-centeredness on patient safety perception among inpatients. PLOS One 2021;16(2):e0246928.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>