<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41757298</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2624-9367</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in sports and active living</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Sports Act Living</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Tai Chi on the pain intensity or disability of patients with chronic low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1676045</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1676045</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1676045</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fspor.2026.1676045</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Chronic low back pain (CLBP) is a leading cause of disability worldwide and remains challenging to manage despite numerous treatment options. Tai Chi (TC), a traditional mind-body exercise, has been increasingly used as a non-pharmacological approach for CLBP, but previous trials and reviews have reported inconsistent results, particularly regarding disability outcomes and the influence of different TC parameters. This systematic review and meta-analysis aimed to synthesize current evidence on the effects of TC on pain intensity, disability, and other health-related outcomes in adults with CLBP, and to explore the potential impact of TC styles and training characteristics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) comparing TC with control interventions in adults with CLBP were searched in six English and Chinese databases from inception to May 2025. Primary outcomes were pain intensity and disability; secondary outcomes included physical function, general health, muscle function, and proprioception. Risk of bias was assessed using the Cochrane Risk of Bias tool, and the certainty of evidence was rated with the Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) approach. Where appropriate, meta-analyses and subgroup and sensitivity analyses were conducted. Publication bias was examined using funnel plots and Egger's regression test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fourteen RCTs (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;960) met the inclusion criteria. Compared with control conditions, TC was associated with reduced pain intensity (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-2.14; 95% CI: -2.84 to -1.44; <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.00001; GRADE: moderate) and improvements in disability measures (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;-1.45; 95% CI: -2.49 to -0.40; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.007; GRADE: very low) and nine disability-related subdomains (pain intensity, personal care, lifting, walking, standing, sitting, sleeping, social life, and traveling). Benefits were also observed for physical function, muscle function, and quality of life, although evidence for proprioception was inconsistent. Subgroup analyses suggested that Chen-style TC and higher training frequency (&gt;3 times/week) might be associated with larger pain reductions, but heterogeneity across studies remained substantial and the certainty of evidence ranged from moderate for pain intensity to very low for most disability outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">TC may be a safe and potentially effective adjunctive intervention for individuals with CLBP, with clinically relevant reductions in pain and improvements in physical function for some patients. However, substantial heterogeneity, small sample sizes in several trials, and low certainty of evidence for disability outcomes warrant cautious interpretation. Further high-quality, adequately powered RCTs with standardized TC protocols are needed to confirm these findings and to clarify the optimal style and training dose of TC for CLBP management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYSTEMATIC REVIEW REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PROSPERO CRD420251072382.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Li, Tang, Zhang, Tang, Wei and Tang.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Rehabilitation Department, Ningbo Rehabilitation Hospital, Ningbo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education Department, Shenyang University of Chemical Technology, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuting</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Marine, Ningbo University, Ningbo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Lifeng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Rehabilitation Department, Ningbo Rehabilitation Hospital, Ningbo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Kun</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Rehabilitation Department, Ningbo Rehabilitation Hospital, Ningbo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurological Rehabilitation Department, Ningbo Rehabilitation Hospital, Ningbo, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Sports Act Living</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101765780</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2624-9367</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tai Chi</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low back pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41757298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12935452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2026.1676045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Treede R-D, Rief W, Barke A, Aziz Q, Bennett MI, Benoliel R, et al. Chronic pain as a symptom or a disease: the IASP classification of chronic pain for the international classification of diseases (ICD-11). Pain. (2019) 160(1):19&#x2013;27. 10.1097/j.pain.0000000000001384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000001384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadler SG, Spink MJ, Ho A, Jonge XJD, Chuter VH. Restriction in lateral bending range of motion, lumbar lordosis, and hamstring flexibility predicts the development of low back pain: a systematic review of prospective cohort studies. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. (2017) 18:1&#x2013;15. 10.1186/s12891-017-1534-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-017-1534-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5418732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28476110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q, Zhou X, Liang H, Guo Y, He K, Shen L, et al. Tuina versus physiotherapy or a combination of both for the management of chronic nonspecific low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Complement Ther Med. (2024) 86(10309):8. 10.1016/j.ctim.2024.103098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2024.103098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39395482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meucci RD, Fassa AG, Faria NMX. Prevalence of chronic low back pain: systematic review. Rev Saude Publica. (2015) 49:73. 10.1590/S0034-8910.2015049005874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0034-8910.2015049005874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4603263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26487293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solloway MR, Taylor SL, Shekelle PG, Miake-Lye IM, Beroes JM, Shanman RM, et al. An evidence map of the effect of Tai Chi on health outcomes. Syst Rev. (2016) 5:1&#x2013;11. 10.1186/s13643-016-0300-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-016-0300-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4962385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27460789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall A, Copsey B, Richmond H, Thompson J, Ferreira M, Latimer J, et al. Effectiveness of tai chi for chronic musculoskeletal pain conditions: updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Ther. (2017) 97(2):227&#x2013;38. 10.2522/ptj.20160246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20160246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27634919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, Ernst E. Systematic reviews of t'ai chi: an overview. Br J Sports Med. (2012) 46(10):713&#x2013;8. 10.1136/bjsm.2010.080622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2010.080622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21586406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatchel RJ, Peng YB, Peters ML, Fuchs PN, Turk DC. The biopsychosocial approach to chronic pain: scientific advances and future directions. Psychol Bull. (2007) 133(4):581. 10.1037/0033-2909.133.4.581</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.133.4.581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong LJ, Lauche R, Klose P, Bu JH, Yang XC, Guo CQ, et al. Tai chi for chronic pain conditions: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sci Rep. (2016) 6(1):25325. 10.1038/srep25325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep25325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4850460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27125299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z-W, Yang Z, Yang J, Chen Y-F, Zhang X-B, Song C-L. Tai Chi for spatiotemporal gait features and dynamic balancing capacity in elderly female patients with non-specific low back pain: a six-week randomized controlled trial. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. (2022) 35(6):1311&#x2013;9. 10.3233/BMR-210247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BMR-210247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35599469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou L, Zhang Y, Liu Y, Tian X, Xiao T, Liu X, et al. The effects of tai chi chuan versus core stability training on lower-limb neuromuscular function in aging individuals with non-specific chronic lower back pain. Medicina. (2019) 55(3):60. 10.3390/medicina55030060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina55030060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H, Yang M, Li M, Xi R, Sun Q, Lin Q. Effects of different parameters of Tai Chi on the intervention of chronic low back pain: a meta-analysis. PLoS One. (2024) 19(7):e0306518. 10.1371/journal.pone.0306518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0306518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11232984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38980862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui S, Liu L, Zhang F. The clinical effect and safety of non-pharmacological Chinese medicine therapy in treating chronic nonspecific low back pain: a systematic review and network meta-analysis protocol. Front Pharmacol. (2025) 16:1514231. 10.3389/fphar.2025.1514231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2025.1514231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12174129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40535765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Y, Hu Y, Ouyang J, Huang R. Four MBE therapies to improve pain scores, physical functioning, and quality of life in patients with chronic nonspecific low back pain: network meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Eur J Pain. (2025) 29(8):e70092. 10.1002/ejp.70092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejp.70092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40739731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotiropoulos S, Papandreou M, Mavrogenis A, Tsaroucha A, Georgoudis G. The effects of Qigong and Tai Chi exercises on chronic low back pain in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cureus. (2025) 17(5):e84342. 10.7759/cureus.84342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.84342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12173434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40530198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Br Med J. (2021) 372:n71. 10.1136/bmj.n7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M. (2024). A study of the effect of tai chi and pilates intervention in patients with nonspecific lower back pain. Thesis, Cnki.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He SP. Research on the Effection of Tai Chi Practice on Muscle Acting among Patients with Chronic Low Back Pain. Shang Hai, China: Shanghai University of Sport; (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall AM, Maher CG, Lam P, Ferreira M, Latimer J. Tai chi exercise for treatment of pain and disability in people with persistent low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care Res. (2011) 63(11):1576&#x2013;83. 10.1002/acr.20594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.20594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22034119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong X. (2017). Mprovement of tai chi chuan &#x201c;flash back&#x201d; method to lumbosacral multifidus muscle function in patients with chronic nonspecific low back pain. Thesis, Cnki.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, J&#xfc;ni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The cochrane Collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Br Med J. (2011) 343:d5928. 10.1136/bmj.d5928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, Kunz R, Falck-Ytter Y, Alonso-Coello P, et al. GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. Br Med J. (2008) 336(7650):924&#x2013;6. 10.1136/bmj.39489.470347.AD</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.39489.470347.AD</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2335261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR. Introduction to Meta-Analysis. Hoboken (NJ): John Wiley &amp; Sons; (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. Br Med J. (1997) 315(7109):629&#x2013;34. 10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot&#x2013;based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. (2000) 56(2):455&#x2013;63. 10.1111/j.0006-341X.2000.00455.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0006-341X.2000.00455.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Yeung A, Xiao T, Tian X, Kong Z, Zou L, et al. Chen-style tai chi for individuals (aged 50 years old or above) with chronic non-specific low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2019) 16(3):517. 10.3390/ijerph16030517</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16030517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6388249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30759778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu M, Ke J, Zeng T, Chen J, Wu Y, Chen F. Observation on the rehabilitation effect of Tai Chi exercise on patients with lumbar muscle strain. Chin J Ethnomed Ethnopharmacy. (2017) 26(17):110&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muharram A, Liu W, Want Z, Sun L, Wu W. Shadowboxing for relief of chronic low back pain. Int J Athl Ther Train. (2011) 16(6):29&#x2013;33. 10.1123/ijatt.16.6.29</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijatt.16.6.29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X. (2013). Effects of Taichi exercise on the knee and ankle joint proprioception of patients with chronic low back pain. Thesis, Cnki.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong X, Jin RJ, Li P, Yi L. The effects of tai chi tui shou for non-specific low back pain. Chin Manipul Rehabil Med. (2016) 7:25&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R. Effects of simplified Tai Chi quan on pressure pain thresholds of lower back muscles and dysfunction of patients with low back pain (Thesis). Shanghai University of Sport, Cnki; (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weifen W, Muheremu A, Chaohui C, Wenge L, Lei S. Effectiveness of tai chi practice for non-specific chronic low back pain on retired athletes: a randomized controlled study. J Musculoskelet Pain. (2013) 21(1):37&#x2013;45. 10.3109/10582452.2013.763394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10582452.2013.763394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W. 2013. Taijiquan exercise on the event related potential of patients with chronic low back pain of experimental research. Thesis, Cnki.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki H, Aono S, Inoue S, Imajo Y, Nishida N, Funaba M, et al. Clinically significant changes in pain along the pain intensity numerical rating scale in patients with chronic low back pain. PLoS One. (2020) 15(3):e0229228. 10.1371/journal.pone.0229228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0229228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32126108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan X, Soh KG, Mun CY, Soh KL. Effects of different types of Tai Chi intervention on motor function in older adults: a systematic review. Aging Clin Exp Res. (2025a) 37(1):32. 10.1007/s40520-024-02894-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40520-024-02894-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11754367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39841325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin J, Zhang Y, Wu L, He Z, Huang J, Tao J, et al. Effect of Tai Chi alone or as additional therapy on low back pain: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Medicine. (2019) 98(37):e17099. 10.1097/MD.0000000000017099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000017099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6750325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31517838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng PW. Tai chi and chronic pain. Regional Anesth Pain Med. (2012) 37(4):372&#x2013;82. 10.1097/AAP.0b013e31824f6629</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AAP.0b013e31824f6629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22609642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geneen LJ, Moore RA, Clarke C, Martin D, Colvin LA, Smith BH. Physical activity and exercise for chronic pain in adults: an overview of cochrane reviews. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. (2017) 4(4):CD011279. 10.1002/14651858.CD011279.pub3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011279.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5461882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28436583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora NK, Donath L, Owen PJ, Miller CT, Saueressig T, Winter F, et al. The impact of exercise prescription variables on intervention outcomes in musculoskeletal pain: an umbrella review of systematic reviews. Sports Med. (2024) 54(3):711&#x2013;25. 10.1007/s40279-023-01966-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01966-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10978700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38093145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu D, Wu M, Zhang J, Song W, Zhu L. Effect of qigong on pain and disability in patients with chronic non-specific low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Orthop Surg Res. (2025) 20(1):194. 10.1186/s13018-025-05576-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-025-05576-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11849339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39994723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HS, Kim K. Effects of 12 weeks tai chi exercise and education intervention program on glucose control, sexual function and immune function for women with type 2 diabetes. J Korean Acad Fund Nurs. (2013) 20(4):389&#x2013;99. 10.7739/jkafn.2013.20.4.389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7739/jkafn.2013.20.4.389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>