<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41796141</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2047-7538</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Light, science &amp; applications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Light Sci Appl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Upconversion optical entropy encoding for infrared complex-amplitude imaging.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">158</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41377-026-02215-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Upconversion detection of infrared radiation by cost-effective silicon photodetectors in visible bands has spurred a revolution in infrared imaging technology, unlocking a wide range of applications in biological imaging, optical spectroscopy, and optical data storage. Despite significant progress in upconversion detection, real-time, concurrent, complex-amplitude imaging of both phase and amplitude information, indispensable for disclosing the full signature of infrared scenes, remains a daunting challenge, impeding their widespread applications. By integrating the unique advantages of both coherent and incoherent approaches, we propose the concept of upconversion optical entropy encoding and demonstrate a video-rate infrared complex-amplitude imaging system. This is achieved by leveraging the synergistic interaction between light scattering in disordered photonic structures and lanthanide upconversion photoluminescence. By tailoring the information entropy of upconversion speckles, infrared light-field information can be captured in a single visible snapshot and explicitly reconstructed, assisted by a deep learning network, enabling infrared complex-amplitude imaging at a video rate of 25 frames per second (fps) and with high-fidelity 8-bit grayscale modulation. The high photosensitivity of the developed infrared imaging system enables a power detection limit of 0.2 nW &#x3bc;m<sup>-2</sup>, three orders of magnitude lower than that of conventional parametric upconversion imaging. As a proof of concept, we demonstrate its applications in capturing video frames of natural scene images and classifying images of speed-limit signs for autonomous driving. This approach can be readily integrated with other cross-band imaging methods, paving the way for various infrared application scenarios that require video-rate, high-photosensitivity, and high-fidelity protocols.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Sheng-Ke</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Electromagnetics and Acoustics, Key Laboratory of Electromagnetic Wave Science and Detection Technology, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Tuqiang</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1376-2106</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Photonic Technology for Integrated Sensing and Communication, Ministry of Education of China, Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Advanced Photonics Technology, School of Information Engineering, Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Chao-Xian</ForeName><Initials>CX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Electromagnetics and Acoustics, Key Laboratory of Electromagnetic Wave Science and Detection Technology, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ai-Hua</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4414-018X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Ze-Huan</ForeName><Initials>ZH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Electromagnetics and Acoustics, Key Laboratory of Electromagnetic Wave Science and Detection Technology, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1679-3271</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Photonic Technology for Integrated Sensing and Communication, Ministry of Education of China, Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou, China. yixu@gdut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Advanced Photonics Technology, School of Information Engineering, Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou, China. yixu@gdut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiangping</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0955-2613</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Photonic Technology, College of Physics and Optoelectronic Engineering, Jinan University, Guangzhou, China. xiangpingli@jnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jin-Hui</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4766-2784</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Electromagnetics and Acoustics, Key Laboratory of Electromagnetic Wave Science and Detection Technology, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China. jimchen@xmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shenzhen Research Institute of Xiamen University, Shenzhen, China. jimchen@xmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Innovation Laboratory for Sciences and Technologies of Energy Materials of Fujian Province (IKKEM), Xiamen, China. jimchen@xmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>12274357</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Light Sci Appl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610753</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2047-7538</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41796141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12968082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41377-026-02215-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41377-026-02215-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. B. &amp; Paliwal, J. Near-infrared spectroscopy and imaging in food quality and safety. <i>Sens. Instrum. Food Qual. Saf.</i><b>1</b>, 193&#x2013;207 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. et al. Continuous-wave frequency upconversion with a molecular optomechanical nanocavity. <i>Science</i><b>374</b>, 1264&#x2013;1267 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34855500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dam, J. S., Tidemand-Lichtenberg, P. &amp; Pedersen, C. Room-temperature mid-infrared single-photon spectral imaging. <i>Nat. Photonics</i><b>6</b>, 788&#x2013;793 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian, L. H. et al. A broadband hyperspectral image sensor with high spatio-temporal resolution. <i>Nature</i><b>635</b>, 73&#x2013;81 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11541218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39506154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z. et al. Applications of ultrafast nano-spectroscopy and nano-imaging with tip-based microscopy. <i>eLight</i><b>5</b>, 1 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z. Q. et al. Quantum storage of three-dimensional orbital-angular-momentum entanglement in a crystal. <i>Phys. Rev. Lett.</i><b>115</b>, 070502 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26317702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. Luminescence modulation of ordered upconversion nanopatterns by a photochromic diarylethene: rewritable optical storage with nondestructive readout. <i>Adv. Mater.</i><b>22</b>, 633&#x2013;637 (2010).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20217763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J., Liu, Z. &amp; Li, F. Y. Upconversion nanophosphors for small-animal imaging. <i>Chem. Soc. Rev.</i><b>41</b>, 1323&#x2013;1349 (2012).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, E. et al. Label-free mid-infrared dichroism-sensitive photoacoustic microscopy for histostructural analysis of engineered heart tissues. <i>Light Sci. Appl</i><b>15</b>, 49 (2026).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12764944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41484058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, S. et al. Laser-driven luminescent ceramic-converted near-infrared II light source for advanced imaging and detection techniques. <i>Light Sci. Appl.</i><b>14</b>, 317 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12426208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40935868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ran, P. et al. Single-shot X-ray and near-infrared (NIR) dual-mode fusion imaging based on bifunctional NIR scintillators. <i>Light Sci. Appl.</i><b>14</b>, 315 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12426231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40935831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lich, J. L. et al. Single-shot 3D incoherent imaging with diffuser endoscopy. <i>Light Adv. Manuf.</i><b>5</b>, 15 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xe4;llhammer, J. E. The road ahead for car night-vision. <i>Nat. Photonics</i><b>5</b>, 12&#x2013;13 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf8;gstedt, L. et al. Upconversion-based lidar measurements of atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub>. <i>Opt. Express</i><b>24</b>, 5152&#x2013;5161 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29092342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia, H. Y. et al. Long-range micro-pulse aerosol lidar at 1.5 &#xb5;m with an upconversion single-photon detector. <i>Opt. Lett.</i><b>40</b>, 1579&#x2013;1582 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25831389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, B. et al. Controlling upconversion nanocrystals for emerging applications. <i>Nat. Nanotechnol.</i><b>10</b>, 924&#x2013;936 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26530022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, S. H. et al. Advances in highly doped upconversion nanoparticles. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>9</b>, 2415 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6010470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29925838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barh, A. et al. Parametric upconversion imaging and its applications. <i>Adv. Opt. Photonics</i><b>11</b>, 952&#x2013;1019 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, L. L. et al. Incoherent broadband mid-infrared detection with lanthanide nanotransducers. <i>Nat. Photonics</i><b>16</b>, 712&#x2013;717 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho-Morales, R. et al. Infrared upconversion imaging in nonlinear metasurfaces. <i>Adv. Photonics</i><b>3</b>, 036002 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, Z. W. et al. Dual-band polarized upconversion photoluminescence enhanced by resonant dielectric metasurfaces. <i>eLight</i><b>3</b>, 21 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. Q. et al. Multidimensional vision sensors for information processing. <i>Nat. Nanotechnol.</i><b>19</b>, 919&#x2013;930 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38877323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oike, Y. Expanding human potential through imaging and sensing technologies. Proceedings of the International Electron Devices Meeting (IEDM). San Francisco, CA, USA: IEEE, 2022, 1.2.1-1.2.5, 10.1109/IEDM45625.2022.10019533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, Q. B. et al. Disordered metasurface enabled single-shot full-stokes polarization imaging leveraging weak dichroism. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>14</b>, 7180 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10630513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37935685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, X. et al. Ultra-compact snapshot spectral light-field imaging. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>13</b>, 2732 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9117667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, H. T. et al. High-efficiency coherent microwave-to-optics conversion via off-resonant scattering. <i>Nat. Photonics</i><b>16</b>, 291&#x2013;296 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midwinter, J. E. Image conversion from 1.6 <i>&#xb5;</i> to the visible in lithium niobate. <i>Appl. Phys. Lett.</i><b>12</b>, 68&#x2013;70 (1968).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Q. et al. Single upconversion nanoparticle imaging at sub-10 W cm<sup>-2</sup> irradiance. <i>Nat. Photonics</i><b>12</b>, 548&#x2013;553 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6599589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31258619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon, J. et al. Measuring the scattering tensor of a disordered nonlinear medium. <i>Nat. Phys.</i><b>19</b>, 1709&#x2013;1718 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Z. et al. Broadband infrared imaging governed by guided-mode resonance in dielectric metasurfaces. <i>Light Sci. Appl.</i><b>13</b>, 249 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11387824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39256381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlickriede, C. et al. Imaging through nonlinear metalens using second harmonic generation. <i>Adv. Mater.</i><b>30</b>, 1703843 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29315903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, X. D. et al. Spiral phase contrast imaging in nonlinear optics: seeing phase objects using invisible illumination. <i>Optica</i><b>5</b>, 208&#x2013;212 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, D. Z. et al. Efficient nonlinear beam shaping in three-dimensional lithium niobate nonlinear photonic crystals. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>10</b>, 4193 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6744429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31519901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin, J. et al. InGaP &#x3c7;<sup>(2)</sup> integrated photonics platform for broadband, ultra-efficient nonlinear conversion and entangled photon generation. <i>Light Sci. Appl</i><b>13</b>, 290 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11473533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39402033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, H. &amp; Eliezer, Y. Harnessing disorder for photonic device applications. <i>Appl. Phys. Rev.</i><b>9</b>, 011309 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shechtman, Y. et al. Phase retrieval with application to optical imaging: a contemporary overview. <i>IEEE Signal Process. Mag.</i><b>32</b>, 87&#x2013;109 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. B. et al. Single-nanocrystal sensitivity achieved by enhanced upconversion luminescence. <i>Nat. Nanotechnol.</i><b>8</b>, 729&#x2013;734 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23995455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, K. &amp; Park, Y. Exploiting the speckle-correlation scattering matrix for a compact reference-free holographic image sensor. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>7</b>, 13359 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5095564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27796290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, H. et al. Measuring large optical transmission matrices of disordered media. <i>Phys. Rev. Lett.</i><b>111</b>, 153902 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4073614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24160602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, T. Q. et al. Non-orthogonal optical multiplexing empowered by deep learning. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>15</b>, 1580 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10881499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38383508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, L. Y. et al. X-ray-to-NIR multi-wavelength imaging through stochastic photoluminescence and compressed encoding. <i>Matter</i><b>7</b>, 2431&#x2013;2447 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, H., Sun, L. D. &amp; Yan, C. H. Energy transfer in lanthanide upconversion studies for extended optical applications. <i>Chem. Soc. Rev.</i><b>44</b>, 1608&#x2013;1634 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25242465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, S. F. et al. Geometric deep optical sensing. <i>Science</i><b>379</b>, eade1220 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36927029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballard, Z. et al. Machine learning and computation-enabled intelligent sensor design. <i>Nat. Mach. Intell.</i><b>3</b>, 556&#x2013;565 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K. Q. et al. On the use of deep learning for phase recovery. <i>Light Sci. Appl.</i><b>13</b>, 4 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10758000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo, C. et al. Deep learning in optical metrology: a review. <i>Light Sci. Appl.</i><b>11</b>, 39 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8866517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35197457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivenson, Y. et al. Phase recovery and holographic image reconstruction using deep learning in neural networks. <i>Light Sci. Appl.</i><b>7</b>, 17141 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6060068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30839514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbastathis, G., Ozcan, A. &amp; Situ, G. H. On the use of deep learning for computational imaging. <i>Optica</i><b>6</b>, 921&#x2013;943 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahavy, T. et al. Deep learning reconstruction of ultrashort pulses. <i>Optica</i><b>5</b>, 666&#x2013;673 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32225978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, S. K. et al. Harnessing disordered photonics via multi-task learning towards intelligent four-dimensional light field sensors. <i>PhotoniX</i><b>4</b>, 26 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, W. R. et al. Single-shot recognition of 3D phase images with deep learning. <i>Laser Photonics Rev.</i><b>16</b>, 2100719 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon, C. E. A mathematical theory of communication. <i>Bell Syst. Tech. J.</i><b>27</b>, 379&#x2013;423 (1948).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, B. Z. et al. Rare-earth doping in nanostructured inorganic materials. <i>Chem. Rev.</i><b>122</b>, 5519&#x2013;5603 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34989556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, J. et al. ImageNet: a large-scale hierarchical image database. Proceedings of the 2009 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition. Miami, FL, USA: IEEE, 2009, 248&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, K. M. et al. Deep residual learning for image recognition. Proceedings of the 2016 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition. Las Vegas, NV, USA: IEEE, 2016, 770&#x2013;778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. et al. Phase-matching controlled orbital angular momentum conversion in periodically poled crystals. <i>Phys. Rev. Lett.</i><b>125</b>, 143901 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33064525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, Y. D. et al. Dispersion-assisted high-dimensional photodetector. <i>Nature</i><b>630</b>, 77&#x2013;83 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38750367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, J. A. et al. Encoding amplitude information onto phase-only filters. <i>Appl. Opt.</i><b>38</b>, 5004&#x2013;5013 (1999).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18323991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, F. et al. Size-dependent lanthanide energy transfer amplifies upconversion luminescence quantum yields. <i>Nat. Photonics</i><b>18</b>, 440&#x2013;449 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devaud, L. et al. Speckle engineering through singular value decomposition of the transmission matrix. <i>Phys. Rev. Lett.</i><b>127</b>, 093903 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34506182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, H., Rasul, K. &amp; Vollgraf, R. Fashion-MNIST: a novel image dataset for benchmarking machine learning algorithms. Print at https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.07747 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T. Y. et al. Image sensing with multilayer nonlinear optical neural networks. <i>Nat. Photonics</i><b>17</b>, 408&#x2013;415 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>