<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41389370</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2192-6506</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>91</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ChemPlusChem</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Chempluschem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recent Advances in Inorganic Oxide-Based Resistive Random Access Memory: Challenges and Strategies for Practical Applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e202500487</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e202500487</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cplu.202500487</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Memory is the backbone of modern computing systems, enabling efficient data storage and functionality. Among emerging nonvolatile memories, resistive random-access memory (RRAM) has garnered significant attention due to its fast switching speed, high scalability, low power consumption, and CMOS compatibility, which makes it suitable for neuromorphic architectures. RRAM operation relies on the history-dependent modulation of resistance in a dielectric layer in response to external stimuli. Recent developments have focused on the wide array of memory-active materials, particularly inorganic and organic compounds, each offering distinct operational modes, tunable switching characteristics, and pathways toward multilevel, low-power, and neuromorphic memory devices. This review summarizes the latest advances in oxide-based RRAM devices, a foundational platform that has driven critical breakthroughs from the initial memristor concept to modern filamentary switching mechanisms. It compares these developments with conventional memory technologies and discusses current challenges and future prospects. Furthermore, we highlight its emerging role in neuromorphic computing, underscoring its potential to revolutionize brain-inspired hardware.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pritam</LastName><ForeName>Anurag</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Kanpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tyndall National Institute, University College Cork, Cork, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahapatra</LastName><ForeName>Anwesha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Kanpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Ritu</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Kanpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alam</LastName><ForeName>Shamiul</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering &amp; Computer Science, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aziz</LastName><ForeName>Ahmedullah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering &amp; Computer Science, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mondal</LastName><ForeName>Prakash Chandra</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9415-5147</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur, Kanpur, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023-0535</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GOIPD/2023/1225</GrantID><Agency>Irish Research Council</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Chempluschem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101580948</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2192-6506</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RRAM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">array level integration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">memristors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromorphic computing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxide material</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">two&#x2010;terminal devices</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41389370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cplu.202500487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>A. S&#x142;awek, L. Alluhaibi, E. Kowalewska, et al., &#x201c;Memristors Based on Ni(II)&#x2010;tetraaza[14] annulene Complexes: Toward an Unconventional Resistive Switching Mechanism,&#x201d; Advanced Electronic Materials 10 (2024): 2300818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Szaci&#x142;owski, &#x201c;Digital Information Processing in Molecular Systems,&#x201d; Chemical Reviews 108 (2008): 3481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Slesazeck and T. Mikolajick, &#x201c;Nanoscale Resistive Switching Memory Devices: A Review,&#x201d; Nanotechnology 30 (2019): 352003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. Yang, D. B. Strukov, and D. R. Stewart, &#x201c;Memristive Devices for Computing. Preprint at Nature Publishing Group,&#x201d; Nature Nanotechnology 8 (2013): 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. A. Bespalov, N. A. Dyuzhev, and V. Yu Kireev, &#x201c;Possibilities and Limitations of CMOS Technology for the Production of Various Microelectronic Systems and Devices,&#x201d; Nanobiotechnology Reports 17 (2022): 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Greif, A. Kimmig, S. El Bobbou, P. Jurisch, and J. Ovtcharova, &#x201c;Strategic View on the Current Role of AI in Advancing Environmental Sustainability: A SWOT Analysis,&#x201d; Discover Artificial Intelligence 4 (2024): 45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Qazi, M. E. Sinangil, and A. P. Chandrakasan, &#x201c;Challenges and Directions for Low-Voltage SRAM,&#x201d; IEEE Design and Test of Computers 28 (2011): 32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Mittal, G. Verma, B. Kaushik, and F. A. Khanday, &#x201c;A Survey of SRAM-based In-Memory Computing Techniques and Applications,&#x201d; Journal of Systems Architecture 119 (2021): 102276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kumar and V. K. Tomar, &#x201c;A Review on Performance Evaluation of Different Low Power SRAM Cells in Nano-Scale Era,&#x201d; Wireless Personal Communications 117 (2021): 1959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. K. Song, J. H. Kang, X. Zhang, et al., &#x201c;Recent Advances and Future Prospects for Memristive Materials, Devices, and Systems,&#x201d; ACS Nano 17 (2023): 11994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. J. Yang, M. D. Pickett, X. Li, D. A. A. Ohlberg, D. R. Stewart, and R. S. Williams, &#x201c;Memristive Switching Mechanism for Metal/Oxide/Metal Nanodevices,&#x201d; Nature Nanotechnology 3 (2008): 429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Zahoor, T. Z. Azni Zulkifli, and F. A. Khanday, &#x201c;Resistive Random Access Memory (RRAM): an Overview of Materials, Switching Mechanism, Performance, Multilevel Cell (mlc) Storage, Modeling, and Applications,&#x201d; Nanoscale Research Letters 15 (2020): 90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Lee, &#x201c;Progress in Non-Volatile Memory Devices Based on Nanostructured Materials and Nanofabrication,&#x201d; Journal of Materials Chemistry 21 (2011): 14097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Chen, Z. Yang, H. Hartmann, A. Besmehn, Y. Yang, and I. Valov, &#x201c;Electrochemical Ohmic Memristors for Continual Learning,&#x201d; Nature Communications 16 (2025): 2348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Corinto, P. P. Civalleri, and L. O. Chua, &#x201c;Classification of Mem-Devices,&#x201d; 2015 IEEE 15th International Conference on Nanotechnology (IEEE&#x2010;NANO) (IEEE, 2015): 629&#x2013;632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Najmaei, A. L. Glasmann, M. A. Schroeder, W. L. Sarney, M. L. Chin, and D. M. Potrepka, &#x201c;Advancements in Materials, Devices, and Integration Schemes for a New Generation of Neuromorphic Computers,&#x201d; Materials Today 59 (2022): 80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Lodhi, S. Saini, A. Dwivedi, A. Khandelwal, and S. P. Tiwari, &#x201c;Bipolar Resistive Switching Properties of TiOx/Graphene Oxide Doped PVP Based Bilayer ReRAM,&#x201d; Journal of Micromechanics and Microengineering 32 (2022): 044001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Saha, E. M. Sahad, S. Sathyanarayana, and B. C. Das, &#x201c;Solution-Processed Robust Multifunctional Memristor of 2D Layered Material Thin Film,&#x201d; ACS Nano 18 (2024): 1137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Paul, A. A. Mukundan, K. K. Tiwari, A. Ghosh, and C. Singh Thakur, &#x201c;Demonstration of Intrinsic STDP Learning Capability in All-2D Multi-State MoS2 Memory and its Application in Modelling Neuromorphic Speech Recognition,&#x201d; 2d Materials 8 (2021): 045031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Abdi, L. Alluhaibi, E. Kowalewska, et al., &#x201c;Reservoir Computing and Photoelectrochemical Sensors: A Marriage of Convenience,&#x201d; Coordination Chemistry Reviews 487 (2023): 215155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Pedretti and D. Ielmini, &#x201c;In-Memory Computing with Resistive Memory Circuits: Status and Outlook,&#x201d; Electronics (Basel) 10 (2021): 1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Kim, A. A. Sharma, R. Mateescu, et al., &#x201c;Locally Rewritable Codes for Resistive Memories,&#x201d; in IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 34 (Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc., 2016), 2470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K.&#x2010;C. Chang, T.&#x2010;C. Chang, T.&#x2010;M. Tsai, et al., &#x201c;Physical and Chemical Mechanisms in Oxide-Based Resistance Random Access Memory,&#x201d; Nanoscale Research Letters 10 (2015): 120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Y. Chen, S. Brivio, C. C. Chang, et al., &#x201c;Resistive Random Access Memory (RRAM) Technology: From Material, Device, Selector, 3D Integration to Bottom-up Fabrication,&#x201d; Journal of Electroceramics 39 (2017): 21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. R. S. Reddy, V. R. Nallagatla, Y. A. Kumar, and G. Murali, &#x201c;Enhanced Resistive Switching Properties of HfAlOx/ZrO2- Based RRAM Devices,&#x201d; Progress in Natural Science: Materials International 32 (2022): 602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, S. Joshi, S. E. Savel&#x2019;ev, et al., &#x201c;Memristors with Diffusive Dynamics as Synaptic Emulators for Neuromorphic Computing,&#x201d; Nature Materials 16 (2017): 101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. K. Sangwan and M. C. Hersam, &#x201c;Neuromorphic Nanoelectronic Materials,&#x201d; Nature Nanotechnology 15 (2020): 517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. H. Yoon, S. J. Song, I. H. Yoo, et al., &#x201c;Highly Uniform, Electroforming-Free, and Self-Rectifying Resistive Memory in the Pt/Ta2O5/HfO2-x/tin Structure,&#x201d; Advanced Functional Materials 24 (2014): 5086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Hwang and J. S. Lee, &#x201c;Recent Advances in Memory Devices with Hybrid Materials,&#x201d; Advanced Electronic Materials 5 (2019): 1800519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Lee, H. Kim, D. J. Yun, S. W. Rhee, and K. Yong, &#x201c;Resistive Switching Characteristics of ZnO Thin Film Grown on Stainless Steel for Flexible Nonvolatile Memory Devices,&#x201d; Applied Physics Letters 95 (2009): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Zhang, Y. Li, C. Zhang, et al., &#x201c;Synchronous Regulation of Hydrophobic Molecular Architecture and Interface Engineering for Robust WORM&#x2010;Type Memristor,&#x201d; Advanced Functional Materials 34 (2024): 2404625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Gupta, S. Kapur, S. Saurabh, and A. Grover, &#x201c;Resistive Random Access Memory: A Review of Device Challenges,&#x201d; IETE Technical Review (Institution of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineers India) 37 (2020): 377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Banerjee, &#x201c;Challenges and Applications of Emerging Nonvolatile Memory Devices,&#x201d; Electronics (Switzerland) 9 (2020): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Banerjee, Q. Liu, and H. Hwang, &#x201c;Engineering of Defects in Resistive Random Access Memory Devices,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physics 127 (2020): 051101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Lanza, H. &#x2010;S. P. Wong, E. Pop, D. Ielmini, et al., &#x201c;Recommended Methods to Study Resistive Switching Devices,&#x201d; Advanced Electronic Materials 5 (2019): 2404625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. K. Upadhyay, H. Jiang, Z. Wang, S. Asapu, Q. Xia, and J. Joshua Yang, &#x201c;Memory Devices for Neuromorphic Computing,&#x201d; Advanced Materials Technologies 4 (2019): 1800589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Valov, I. Sapezanskaia, A. Nayak, et al., &#x201c;Atomically Controlled Electrochemical Nucleation at Superionic Solid Electrolyte Surfaces,&#x201d; Nature Materials 11 (2012): 530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Nayak, T. Tsuruoka, K. Terabe, T. Hasegawa, and M. Aono, &#x201c;Theoretical Investigation of Kinetics of a Cu2S-Based Gap-type Atomic Switch,&#x201d; Applied Physics Letters 98 (2011): 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Waser and M. Aono, &#x201c;Nanoionics&#x2010;Based Resistive Switching Memories,&#x201d; Nature Materials 6 (2007): 833&#x2013;840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. A. Chekol, S. Menzel, R. W. Ahmad, R. Waser, and S. Hoffmann&#x2010;Eifert, &#x201c;Effect of the Threshold Kinetics on the Filament Relaxation Behavior of Ag-Based Diffusive Memristors,&#x201d; Advanced Functional Materials 32 (2022): 2200549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Pradhan, A. Mahapatra, P. P. Samal, P. Mishra, P. Kumar, and A. Nayak, &#x201c;Liquid-Liquid Interface-Assisted Self-Assembly of Ag-Doped ZnO Nanosheets for Atomic Switch Application,&#x201d; The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 15 (2024): 165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. I. Meijer, U. Staub, M. Janousch, S. L. Johnson, B. Delley, and T. Neisius, &#x201c;Valence States of Cr and the Insulator-to-Metal Transition in Cr-Doped SrTiO3,&#x201d; Physical Review B 72 (2005): 155102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. D. Ha, G. H. Aydogdu, and S. Ramanathan, &#x201c;Metal-Insulator Transition and Electrically Driven Memristive Characteristics of SmNiO3 Thin Films,&#x201d; Applied Physics Letters 98 (2011): 124110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Tsuruoka, T. Hasegawa, K. Terabe, and M. Aono, &#x201c;Quantum Conductance in Silicon Oxide Resistive Memory Devices,&#x201d; Nanotechnology 23 (2012): 435705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Mehonic, A. Vrajitoarea, S. Cueff, et al., &#x201c;Revealing the Quantum Nature of the Voltage-Induced Conductance Changes in Oxygen Engineered Yttrium Oxide-Based RRAM Devices,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 3 (2013): 2708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. L. Aguirre, E. Piros, N. Kaiser, et al., &#x201c;Quantized Conductance Operation Near a Single-Atom Point Contact in a Polymer-Based Atomic Switch,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 14 (2024): 1122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Krishnan, M. Muruganathan, T. Tsuruoka, H. Mizuta, and M. Aono, &#x201c;Conductance Quantization in Resistive Random Access Memory,&#x201d; Japanese Journal of Applied Physics 56 (2017): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Li, S. Long, Y. Liu, et al., &#x201c;Quantized Conductance Atomic Switch,&#x201d; Nanoscale Research Letters 10 (2015): 420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Terabe, T. Hasegawa, T. Nakayama, and M. Aono, &#x201c;Conductance Quantization and Synaptic Behavior in a Ta2O5-Based Atomic Switch,&#x201d; Nature 433 (2005): 47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Udaya Mohanan, &#x201c;Resistive Switching Devices for Neuromorphic Computing: From Foundations to Chip Level Innovations,&#x201d; Nanomaterials 14 (2024): 527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Maity, R. Bharti, A. K. Mukherjee, and A. D. Thakur, &#x201c;Demonstration of Asymmetric Hebbian Learning Based on Analog Resistive Switching in Ag/Co3O4/p-Si Memristor,&#x201d; Applied Physics Letters 126 (2025): 013504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D.&#x2010;Y. Cho, K. Kim, K.&#x2010;S. Lee, M. L&#xfc;bben, S. Chen, and I. Valov, &#x201c;Chemical Influence of Carbon Interface Layers in Metal/Oxide Resistive Switches,&#x201d; ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 15 (2023): 18528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Murtagh, B. Walls, and I. V. Shvets, &#x201c;Controlling the Resistive Switching Hysteresis in VO2 Thin Films via Application of Pulsed Voltage,&#x201d; Applied Physics Letters 117 (2020): 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. H. Yoon, Z. Wang, K. M. Kim, et al., &#x201c;An Artificial Nociceptor Based on a Diffusive Memristor,&#x201d; Nature Communications 9 (2018): 417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Ielmini, R. Bruchhaus, and R. Waser, &#x201c;Thermochemical Resistive Switching: Materials, Mechanisms, and Scaling Projections,&#x201d; Phase Transitions 84 (2011): 570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Gayakvad, K. Somdatta, V. Mathe, T. Dongale, W. M., and K. Patankar, &#x201c;Spinel Ferrites for Resistive Random Access Memory Applications,&#x201d; Emergent Materials 7 (2024): 103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. M. Simanjuntak, C.&#x2010;L. Hsu, T. Abbey, et al., &#x201c;Conduction Channel Configuration Controlled Digital and Analog Response in TiO2-Based Inorganic Memristive Artificial Synapses,&#x201d; APL Materials 9 (2021): 121103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. K. Koh, P. A. Dananjaya, H. Y. Poh, et al., &#x201c;Unravelling the Origins of the Coexisting Localized-Interfacial Mechanism in Oxide-Based Memristors in CMOS-Integrated Synaptic Device Implementations,&#x201d; Nanoscale Horizons 9 (2024): 828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Kim, H. Son, I. Kim, et al., &#x201c;Reversible Switching Mode Change in Ta2O5-Based Resistive Switching Memory (ReRAM),&#x201d; Scientific Reports 10 (2020): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kim, S. Han, G. Kim, Y. Kim, and S. Y. Kim, &#x201c;Halide Perovskites for Resistive Random-Access Memories,&#x201d; Journal of Materials Chemistry C 7 (2019): 5226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. C. Chang, K. C. Chang, T. M. Tsai, T. J. Chu, and S. M. Sze, &#x201c;Resistance Random Access Memory,&#x201d; Materials Today 19 (2016): 254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Kumar, R. Aluguri, U. Chand, and T. Y. Tseng, &#x201c;Metal Oxide Resistive Switching Memory: Materials, Properties and Switching Mechanisms,&#x201d; Ceramics International 43 (2017): S547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Aglieri, A. Zaffora, G. Lullo, et al., &#x201c;Resistive Switching in Microscale Anodic Titanium Dioxide-Based Memristors,&#x201d; Superlattices and Microstructures 113 (2018): 135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Menzel, M. Von Witzleben, V. Havel, and U. B&#xf6;ttger, &#x201c;The Ultimate Switching Speed Limit of Redox-Based Resistive Switching Devices,&#x201d; Faraday Discussions 213 (2019): 197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Kindsm&#xfc;ller, C. Schmitz, C. Wiemann, et al., &#x201c;Valence Change Detection in Memristive Oxide Based Heterostructure Cells by Hard X-Ray Photoelectron Emission Spectroscopy,&#x201d; APL Materials 6 (2018): 046106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Huang, T. Shen, L.&#x2010;H. Lee, C. Wen, and S. Lee, &#x201c;Low-Power Resistive Random Access Memory by Confining the Formation of Conducting Filaments,&#x201d; AIP Advances 6 (2016): 065022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. W. Burr, M. J. Breitwisch, M. Franceschini, et al., &#x201c;Phase Change Memory Technology,&#x201d; Journal of Vacuum Science &amp; Technology B, Nanotechnology and Microelectronics: Materials, Processing Measurement, and Phenomena 28 (2010): 223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Xu, S. Chen, Y. Pan, et al., &#x201c;Preparation of Organic N-Fused Perylenediimide-Mxene Hybrid Material for Robust Versatile Memristive Device,&#x201d; International Journal of Extreme Manufacturing 7 (2025): 025507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. C. G. Naber, K. Asadi, P. W. M. Blom, D. M. De Leeuw, and B. De Boer, &#x201c;Organic Nonvolatile Memory Devices Based on Ferroelectricity,&#x201d; Advanced Materials (deerfield Beach, Fla.) 22 (2010): 933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Jana and A. Roy Chaudhuri, &#x201c;Oxygen Vacancy Engineering and Its Impact on Resistive Switching of Oxide Thin Films for Memory and Neuromorphic Applications,&#x201d; Chips 3 (2024): 235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Huang, X. Liang, Y. Wang, et al., &#x201c;Fully Integrated Multi-Mode Optoelectronic Memristor Array for Diversified In-Sensor Computing,&#x201d; Nature Nanotechnology 20 (2025): 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Tan, Z. Liu, W. Huang, and H. Zhang, &#x201c;Non-Volatile Resistive Memory Devices Based on Solution-Processed Ultrathin Two-Dimensional Nanomaterials,&#x201d; Chemical Society Reviews 44 (2015): 2615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Li, R. Wang, S. T. Han, and Y. Zhou, &#x201c;Ferroelectric Polymers for Non-Volatile Memory Devices: A Review,&#x201d; Polymer International 69 (2020): 533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Heremans, G. H. Gelinck, R. M&#xfc;ller, K. J. Baeg, D. Y. Kim, and Y. Y. Noh, &#x201c;Polymer and Organic Nonvolatile Memory Devices,&#x201d; Chemistry of Materials : A Publication of the American Chemical Society 23 (2011): 341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, Z. Feng, M. Luo, et al., &#x201c;High-Performance Perovskite Memristor by Integrating a Tip-Shape Contact,&#x201d; Journal of Materials Chemistry C 9 (2021): 15435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Betal, J. Bera, and S. Sahu, &#x201c;Non-Volatile Memristor-Based Artificial Synaptic Behavior of Redox-Active Organic Composites,&#x201d; Journal of Materials Chemistry C 11 (2023): 4674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Mahapatra, A. Ghoshal, R. K. Parashar, S. Pal, S. Adhikary, and P. C. Mondal, &#x201c;Counterions Drive Memory Functionality in Two&#x2010;Terminal Viologen&#x2010;Based Molecular Junctions,&#x201d; Small 21 (2025): 2503767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Franco, A. Kiazadeh, R. Martins, S. Lanceros&#x2010;M&#xe9;ndez, and E. Carlos, &#x201c;Printed Memristors: An Overview of Ink, Materials, Deposition Techniques, and Applications,&#x201d; Advanced Electronic Materials 10 (2024): 2400212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Panca, J. Panidi, H. Faber, S. Stathopoulos, T. D. Anthopoulos, and T. Prodromakis, &#x201c;Flexible Oxide Thin Film Transistors, Memristors, and Their Integration,&#x201d; Advanced Functional Materials 33 (2023): 2213762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. M. Simanjuntak, D. Panda, K. H. Wei, and T. Y. Tseng, &#x201c;Status and Prospects of ZnO-Based Resistive Switching Memory Devices,&#x201d; Nanoscale Research Letters 11 (2016): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. G. Wang, X. Qian, Y. Q. Cao, et al., &#x201c;Excellent Resistive Switching Properties of Atomic Layer-Deposited Al2O3/HfO2/Al2O3 Trilayer Structures for Non-Volatile Memory Applications,&#x201d; Nanoscale Research Letters 10 (2015): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K.&#x2010;C. Chang, T. Tsai, T. Chang, et al., &#x201c;The Effect of Silicon Oxide Based RRAM with Tin Doping,&#x201d; Electrochemical and Solid&#x2010;State Letters 15 (2012): H65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. W. Hickmott, &#x201c;Low-Frequency Negative Resistance in Thin Anodic Oxide Films,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physics 33 (1962): 2669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ismail, C. Mahata, and S. Kim, &#x201c;Forming-free Pt/Al2O3/HfO2/HfAlxO2/tin Memristor with Controllable Multilevel Resistive Switching and Neuromorphic Characteristics for Artificial Synapse,&#x201d; Journal of Alloys and Compounds 892 (2022): 162141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J.&#x2010;Y. Chen, M.&#x2010;C. Wu, Y.&#x2010;H. Ting, W.&#x2010;C. Lee, P.&#x2010;H. Yeh, and W.&#x2010;W. Wu, &#x201c;Applications of p-n Homojunction ZnO Nanowires to One-Diode One-Memristor RRAM Arrays,&#x201d; Scripta Materialia 187 (2020): 439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Bousoulas, P. Asenov, I. Karageorgiou, D. Sakellaropoulos, S. Stathopoulos, and D. Tsoukalas, &#x201c;Engineering Amorphous-Crystalline Interfaces in TiO2-x/TiO2-y-Based Bilayer Structures for Enhanced Resistive Switching and Synaptic Properties,&#x201d; Journal of Applied Physics 120 (2016): 154501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Farooq, &#x201c;Study of Resistive Switching in Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Thin Film for the Application of Non-Volatile Memory: A Review.,&#x201d; International Journal for Research in Applied Science and Engineering Technology 7 (2019): 3030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.&#x2010;X. Chen, S.&#x2010;P. Chang, S.&#x2010;J. Chang, W.&#x2010;K. Hsieh, and C.&#x2010;H. Lin, &#x201c;Highly Stable Ultrathin TiO2-Based Resistive Random Access Memory with Low Operation Voltage,&#x201d; ECS Journal of Solid State Science and Technology 7 (2018): Q3183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. H. Jaafar, M. M. Al Chawa, F. Cheng, et al., &#x201c;Polymer/TiO2 Nanorod Nanocomposite Optical Memristor Device,&#x201d; The Journal of Physical Chemistry C 125 (2021): 14965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Luo, X. Zhang, Y. Hu, et al., &#x201c;Self-Rectifying and Forming-Free,&#x201d; IEEE Electron Device Letters 39 (2018): 664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ismail, C. Mahata, M. Kang, and S. Kim, &#x201c;Robust Resistive Switching Constancy and Quantum Conductance in High-k Dielectric-Based Memristor for Neuromorphic Engineering,&#x201d; Nanoscale Research Letters 17 (2022): 61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. U. Khalid, S. W. Kim, J. Lee, et al., &#x201c;Resistive Switching Device Based on SrTiO3/PVA Hybrid Composite Thin Film as Active Layer,&#x201d; Polymer 189 (2020): 122183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Li, W. Hui, X. Ran, et al., &#x201c;Metal Halide Perovskites for Resistive Switching Memory Devices and Artificial Synapses,&#x201d; Journal of Materials Chemistry C 7 (2019): 7476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Zhu, Y. Li, W. Shen, Z. Zhou, L. Liu, and X. Zhang, &#x201c;Resistive Random Access Memory &amp; its Applications in Storage &amp; Nonvolatile Logic,&#x201d; Journal of Semiconductors 38 (2017): 071002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. B. Silva, F. L. Faita, K. Kamakshi, et al., &#x201c;Enhanced Resistive Switching Characteristics in Pt/BaTiO3/ITO Structures through Insertion of HfO2:Al2O3 (HAO) Dielectric Thin Layer,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 7 (2017): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. X. Li, R. Li, D. Ma, B. Li, K. Li, and Z. Hu, &#x201c;Resistive Switching Behaviors in the BaTiO3/La0.7Sr0.3Mno3 Layered Heterostructure Driven by External Electric Field.,&#x201d; Journal of Magnetism and Magnetic Materials 497 (2020): 165879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Y. Zheng, Y. Bai, Y. Shao, et al., &#x201c;Understanding and Modulation of Resistive Switching Behaviors in PbZr0.52Ti0.48O3/La0.67Sr0.33MnO3/Nb: SrTiO3 Multilayer Junctions,&#x201d; Applied Surface Science 574 (2022): 151711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Lee, S. Yoo, K. J. Yoon, et al., &#x201c;Resistance Switching Behavior of Atomic Layer Deposited SrTiO3 Film Through Possible Formation of Sr2Ti6O13 or Sr1Ti11O20 Phases,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 6 (2016): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Kumari, I. Varun, S. P. Tiwari, and A. Dixit, &#x201c;Non-Volatile Bipolar Resistive Switching in Sol-Gel Derived BiFeO3 Thin Films,&#x201d; Superlattices and Microstructures 120 (2018): 67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Kumari, I. Varun, S. P. Tiwari, and A. Dixit, &#x201c;Interfacial Layer Assisted, Forming Free, and Reliable Bipolar Resistive Switching in Solution Processed BiFeO3 Thin Films,&#x201d; Aip Advances 10 (2020): 025110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. B. Yan and J. M. Liu, &#x201c;Coexistence of High Performance Resistance and Capacitance Memory Based on Multilayered Metal-Oxide Structures,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 3 (2013): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ambrosi, A. Bricalli, M. Laudato, and D. Ielmini, &#x201c;Impact of Oxide and Electrode Materials on the Switching Characteristics of Oxide ReRAM Devices,&#x201d; Faraday Discussions 213 (2019): 87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Moazzeni, H. Riyahi Madvar, S. Hamedi, and Z. Kordrostami, &#x201c;Fabrication of Graphene Oxide-Based Resistive Switching Memory by the Spray Pyrolysis Technique for Neuromorphic Computing,&#x201d; ACS Applied Nano Materials 6 (2023): 2236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. P. Swathi and S. Angappane, &#x201c;Enhanced Resistive Switching Performance of Hafnium Oxide-Based Devices: Effects of Growth and Annealing Temperatures,&#x201d; Journal of Alloys and Compounds 913 (2022): 165251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. V. Tominov, Z. E. Vakulov, N. V. Polupanov, et al., &#x201c;Nanoscale-Resistive Switching in Forming-Free Zinc Oxide Memristive Structures,&#x201d; Nanomaterials 12 (2022): 455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Hellenbrand, B. Bakhit, H. Dou, et al., &#x201c;Thin Film Design of Amorphous Hafnium Oxide Nanocomposites Enabling Strong Interfacial Resistive Switching Uniformity,&#x201d; Science Advances 9 (2023): 1946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Mikhaylov, A. Belov, D. Korolev, et al., &#x201c;Multilayer Metal&#x2010;Oxide Memristive Device with Stabilized Resistive Switching,&#x201d; Advanced Materials Technologies 5 (2020): 1900607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. H. Jaafar and N. T. Kemp, &#x201c;Wavelength Dependent Light Tunable Resistive Switching Graphene Oxide Nonvolatile Memory Devices,&#x201d; Carbon 153 (2019): 81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Tsuruoka, K. Terabe, T. Hasegawa, and M. Aono, &#x201c;Forming and Switching Mechanisms of a Cation-Migration-Based Oxide Resistive Memory,&#x201d; Nanotechnology 21 (2010): 425205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Krishnan, T. Tsuruoka, C. Mannequin, and M. Aono, &#x201c;Mechanism for Conducting Filament Growth in Self-Assembled Polymer Thin Films for Redox-Based Atomic Switches,&#x201d; Advanced Materials 28 (2016): 640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Tsuruoka, I. Valov, S. Tappertzhofen, et al., &#x201c;Redox Reactions at Cu,Ag/Ta2O5 Interfaces and the Effects of Ta2O5 Film Density on the Forming Process in Atomic Switch Structures,&#x201d; Advanced Functional Materials 25 (2015): 6374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Zaffora, D. Cho, K. Lee, et al., &#x201c;Electrochemical Tantalum Oxide for Resistive Switching Memories,&#x201d; Advanced Materials 29 (2017): 1703357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Cho, C. Yun, S. Tappertzhofen, et al., &#x201c;Self-Assembled Oxide Films with Tailored Nanoscale Ionic and Electronic Channels for Controlled Resistive Switching,&#x201d; Nature Communications 7 (2016): 12373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Munjal and N. Khare, &#x201c;Valence Change Bipolar Resistive Switching Accompanied with Magnetization Switching in CoFe2O4 Thin Film,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 7 (2017): 12427.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Huang, A. J. Tan, M. Mann, U. Bauer, R. Ouedraogo, and G. S. D. Beach, &#x201c;Three-Terminal Resistive Switch Based on Metal/Metal Oxide Redox Reactions,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 7 (2017): 7452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Nili, S. Walia, S. Balendhran, D. B. Strukov, M. Bhaskaran, and S. Sriram, &#x201c;Nanoscale Resistive Switching in Amorphous Perovskite Oxide (a-SrTiO3) memristors,&#x201d; Advanced Functional Materials 24 (2014): 6741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Tsai, J. Chen, C. Huang, et al., &#x201c;A High&#x2010;Entropy&#x2010;Oxides&#x2010;Based Memristor: Outstanding Resistive Switching Performance and Mechanisms in Atomic Structural Evolution,&#x201d; Advanced Materials 35 (2023): 2302979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Zidan, J. P. Strachan, and W. D. Lu, &#x201c;The Future of Electronics Based on Memristive Systems,&#x201d; Nature Electronics 1 (2018): 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Xia, C. Zhang, Z. Xu, et al., &#x201c;Organic Iontronic Memristors for Artificial Synapses and Bionic Neuromorphic Computing,&#x201d; Nanoscale 16 (2023): 1471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Gokmen, &#x201c;Enabling Training of Neural Networks on Noisy Hardware,&#x201d; Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence 4 (2021): 699148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, Q. Zhang, Y. Li, et al., &#x201c;Memristor-Integrated Sensing Systems Leveraging Quantum Conductance Effect for Artificial Bioelectronics,&#x201d; Applied Physics Reviews 12 (2025): 021328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Gokmen and W. Haensch, &#x201c;Algorithm for Training Neural Networks on Resistive Device Arrays,&#x201d; Frontiers in Neuroscience 14 (2020): 103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Kim, T. Gokmen, H. Miyazoe, et al., &#x201c;Neural Network Learning using Non-Ideal Resistive Memory Devices,&#x201d; Frontiers in Nanotechnology 4 (2022): 1008266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Sebastian, M. Le Gallo, R. Khaddam&#x2010;Aljameh, and E. Eleftheriou, &#x201c;Memory Devices and Applications for In-Memory Computing,&#x201d; Nature Nanotechnology 15 (2020): 529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Noh, H. Kwak, J. Son, et al., &#x201c;Retention-Aware Zero-Shifting Technique for Tiki-Taka Algorithm-Based Analog Deep Learning Accelerator,&#x201d; Science Advances 10 (2024): 3350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Abedin, N. Gong, K. Beckmann, et al., &#x201c;Material to System-Level Benchmarking of CMOS-Integrated RRAM with Ultra-Fast Switching for Low Power On-Chip Learning.,&#x201d; Scientific Reports 13 (2023): 14963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Stecconi, V. Bragaglia, M. J. Rasch, et al., &#x201c;Cryogenic Analog 1T-ReRAM with Enhanced Dynamic Range and Suppressed Noise for Cold Neural Networks.,&#x201d; Nano Letters 24 (2024): 866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Ram, D. Lombardo, E. Zaccaria, et al., &#x201c;Edge Training and Inference with Analog ReRAM Technology for Hand Gesture Recognition,&#x201d; 2024 IEEE International Electron Devices Meeting (IEDM) (IEEE, 2024): 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Clerico, A. Dutta, D. F. Falcone, et al., &#x201c;Analog Resistive Switching Devices for Training Deep Neural Networks with the Novel Tiki-Taka Algorithm,&#x201d; 2025 IEEE International Symposium on Circuits and Systems (ISCAS) (IEEE, 2025): 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. F. Falcone, S. Menzel, T. Stecconi, et al., &#x201c;Analytical Modelling of the Transport in Analog Filamentary Conductive-Metal-Oxide/HfOx ReRAM Devices,&#x201d; Nanoscale Horizons 9 (2024): 775.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. S. Jeong, R. Thomas, R. S. Katiyar, et al., &#x201c;Emerging Memories: Resistive Switching Mechanisms and Current Status,&#x201d; Reports on Progress in Physics 75 (2012): 076502.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>