<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41613093</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2296-2565</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transforming health equity through academic integration: ripple effects of high-impact practices in CBPR with refugee-origin Montagnard youth.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1672085</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1672085</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1672085</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1672085</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This community case study describes an innovative model of academic integration, the integration of university-based high-impact practices (HIPs) with Community-Based Participatory Research (CBPR)-an approach rooted in co-learning, shared power, and mutual benefits-to advance health equity for low-income Asian American refugee-origin communities (LIAACRO) in central North Carolina. The Montagnard Hypertension Project (MHyP), a community-initiated collaboration, embedded five HIPs, service learning, undergraduate research, diversity/global learning experiences, internships, and capstone projects, within a CBPR framework to bring community partners into academic spaces as cultural experts and co-researchers. This academic integration enabled Montagnard college students (MCS) to access institutional resources, gain research competencies, and lead culturally responsive health outreach. Montagnards, an indigenous people from Vietnam's Central Highlands, experience persistent invisibility in U.S. health and social systems due to data aggregation and the Asian American "model minority" myth. Through the MHyP, the MCS leveraged their cultural knowledge and lived experiences to co-develop culturally and linguistically appropriate research protocols, design and implement community health promotion initiatives, facilitate intergenerational dialogue, and document traditional practices. Using a ripple effects framework, we retrospectively assess multilevel changes (individual, community, and institutional) that extend beyond the project's scope. Findings demonstrate how carefully and strategically integrating HIPs can strengthen CBPR's principles of co-learning, shared leadership and decision-making, empowerment, and mutual benefit. The model offers a replicable pathway for public health researchers and practitioners to engage marginalized communities in ways that promote educational advancement, community values and empowerment, and institutional transformation. This case contributes to the field by showing how academic institutions and public health practitioners can reimagine and successfully mobilize institutional resources, including curricula, internal funding, and campus spaces, to support sustainable, equity-driven community engagement.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Morrison, Sudha, Young and Adrong.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morrison</LastName><ForeName>Sharon D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Education, University of North Carolina Greensboro, Greensboro, NC, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sudha</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Development and Family Studies, University of North Carolina Greensboro, Greensboro, NC, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montagnard/Asian Community Disparities Research Network, Greensboro, NC, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adrong</LastName><ForeName>H'Yua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montagnard Association of North Carolina, Greensboro, NC, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101616579</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-2565</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069576" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Equity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012036" MajorTopicYN="Y">Refugees</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009657" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">North Carolina</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055812" MajorTopicYN="Y">Community-Based Participatory Research</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="N">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014495" MajorTopicYN="N">Universities</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="N">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001213" MajorTopicYN="Y">Asian</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-Based Participatory Research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health equity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-impact practices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">refugee-origin youth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ripple effects</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared that this work was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41613093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12846956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1672085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yi SS, Kwon SC, Sacks R, Trinh-Shevrin C. Commentary: persistence and health-related consequences of the model minority stereotype for Asian Americans. Ethn Dis. (2016) 26:133&#x2013;8. doi: 10.18865/ed.26.1.133,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18865/ed.26.1.133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4738850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26843806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin A. A brief look at low-income Asian Americans and Pacific islanders. Center for Economic and Policy Research (2022). Available online at: https://www.cepr.net/a-brief-look-at-low-income-asian-americans-and-pacific-islanders/ (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudha S, Morrison SD. We are not all &#x201c;model&#x201d;: health of older Asian refugees in the United States In: Springer handbook of aging, health, and public policy. Singapore: Springer; (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe-Kim J, Takeuchi DT, Hong S, Zane N, Sue S, Spencer MS, et al. Use of mental health-related services among immigrant and US-born Asian Americans: results from the national Latino and Asian American study. Am J Public Health. (2007) 97:91&#x2013;8. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2006.098541,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2006.098541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1716256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17138905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sentell T, Shumway M, Snowden L. Access to mental health treatment by English language proficiency and race/ethnicity. J Gen Intern Med. (2007) 22:289&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1007/s11606-007-0345-7,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-007-0345-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2150610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17957413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Vargas-Bustamante A, Mortensen K, Ortega AN. Racial and ethnic disparities in health care access and utilization under the affordable care act. Med Care. (2016) 54:140&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1097/MLR.0000000000000467,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MLR.0000000000000467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4711386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26595227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gee GC, Ponce N. Associations between racial discrimination, limited English proficiency, and health-related quality of life among 6 Asian ethnic groups in California. Am J Public Health. (2010) 100:888&#x2013;95. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2009.178012,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2009.178012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2853608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20299644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallerstein NB, Quispe M, Dickson E, Kaur J. Community-based participatory research for health equity In: Galea S, Ettman CK, Vlahov D, editors. Urban health. New York: Oxford University Press; (2019). 803&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel BA, Eng E, Schulz AJ, Parker EA. Methods for community-based participatory research for health. 2nd ed. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freire P. Pedagogy of the oppressed. New York: Herder and Herder; (1970).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderbroek I, Reyes-Garc&#xed;a V, de Albuquerque UP, Bussmann R, Pieroni A. Local knowledge: Who cares?. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. (2011) 7:35. doi: 10.1186/1746-4269-7-35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1746-4269-7-35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22113005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkler M, Wallerstein N. Community-based participatory research for health: from process to outcomes. 2nd ed. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reason P, Torbert WR. The action turn: toward a transformational social science. Concepts Transform. (2001) 6:1&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1075/cat.6.1.02rea</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1075/cat.6.1.02rea</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson E. Community-based participatory action research. In: Liamputtong P., ed. Handbook of research methods in health social sciences. Singapore: Springer; (2019) doi: 10.1007/978-981-10-5251-4_87</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-10-5251-4_87</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis BH, Kia-Keating M, Yusuf SA, Lincoln A, Nur A. Ethical research in refugee communities and the use of community participatory methods. Transcult Psychiatry. (2007) 44:459&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1177/1363461507081642,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1363461507081642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro FG, Barrera M, Jr, Martinez CR, Jr. The cultural adaptation of prevention interventions: resolving tensions between fidelity and fit. Prev Sci. (2004) 5:41&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1023/B:PREV.0000013980.12412.cd,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/B:PREV.0000013980.12412.cd</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15058911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaskin RJ, Brown P, Venkatesh S, Vidal A. Building community capacity. New York: Aldine de Gruyter; (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllister CL, Green BL, Terry MA, Herman V, Mulvey L. Parents, practitioners, and researchers: community-based participatory research with early head start. Am J Public Health. (2003) 93:1672&#x2013;9. doi: 10.2105/ajph.93.10.1672,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/ajph.93.10.1672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1448031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14534219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam NS, Khan S, Kwon S, Jang D, Ro M, Trinh-Shevrin C. Methodological issues in the collection, analysis, and reporting of granular data in Asian American populations: historical challenges and potential solutions. J Health Care Poor Underserved. (2010) 21:1354&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1353/hpu.2010.0939,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/hpu.2010.0939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3086449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21099084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trickett EJ. Multilevel community-based culturally situated interventions and community impact: an ecological perspective. Am J Community Psychol. (2009) 43:257&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1007/s10464-009-9227-y,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10464-009-9227-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19333751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallerstein N. Empowerment to reduce health disparities. Scand J Public Health. (2002) 30:72&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1080/140349502760407709,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/140349502760407709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12227969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds AD, Bacon R. Interventions supporting the social integration of refugee children and youth in school communities: a review of the literature. Adv Soc Work. (2018) 18:745&#x2013;66. doi: 10.18060/21664</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18060/21664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betancourt TS, Frounfelker RL, Mishra T, Hussein A, Falzarano R. Addressing health disparities in the mental health of refugee children and adolescents through community-based participatory research: a study in 2 communities. Am J Public Health. (2015) 105:S475&#x2013;82. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2014.302504,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2014.302504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25905818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frounfelker RL, Miconi D, Farrar J, Brooks MA, Rousseau C, Betancourt TS. Mental health of refugee children and youth: epidemiology, interventions, and future directions. Annu Rev Public Health. (2020) 41:159&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1146/annurev-publhealth-040119-094230,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-publhealth-040119-094230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31910713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peralta KJ. Toward a deeper appreciation of participatory epistemology in community-based participatory research. PRISM J Reg Engagem. (2017) 6:45&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayan MJ, Daum C. Worth the risk? Muddled relationships in community-based participatory research. Qual Health Res. (2016) 26:69&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1177/1049732315613982,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732315613982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26612889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallerstein N, Duran B. The conceptual, historical and practice roots of community-based participatory research and related participatory traditions In: Minkler M, Wallerstein N, editors. Community-based participatory research for health. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; (2003)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuh GD. High-impact educational practices: what they are, who has access to them, and why they matter. Washington, DC: Association of American Colleges and Universities; (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finley A, McNair T. Assessing underserved students' engagement in high-impact practices. Washington, DC: Association of American Colleges and Universities; (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilgo CA, Sheets JK, Pascarella ET. The link between high-impact practices and student learning: some longitudinal evidence. High Educ. (2015) 69:509&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1007/s10734-014-9788-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10734-014-9788-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pike GR, Kuh GD, McCormick AC. An investigation of the contingent relationships between learning community participation and student engagement. Res High Educ. (2011) 52:300&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1007/s11162-010-9192-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11162-010-9192-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinschmidt KM, Maez P, Iuliano JE, Nigon BM. Using active learning strategies linked to CBPR principles in a semester-long class project to teach qualitative research methods in public health. Pedagogy Health Promot. (2019) 5:36&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1177/2373379918761976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2373379918761976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kia-Keating M, Juang LP. Participatory science as a decolonizing methodology: leveraging collective knowledge from partnerships with refugee and immigrant communities. Cultur Divers Ethnic Minor Psychol. (2022) 28:299&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1037/cdp0000514,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/cdp0000514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35007114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inkelas KK, Daver ZE, Vogt KE, Leonard JB. Living-learning programs and first-generation college students' academic and social transition to college. Res High Educ. (2007) 48:403&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1007/s11162-006-9031-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11162-006-9031-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison SD, Young AJ, Sudha S. Youth capacity building and leadership through CBPR and conflict transformation with the Montagnard refugee-origin community. J Leadersh Stud. (2023) 17:53&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1002/jls.21857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jls.21857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen Kollock DA, Flage L, Chazdon S, Paine N, Higgins L. Ripple effect mapping: a &#x201c;radiant&#x201d; way to capture program impacts. J Ext. (2012) 50:1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.34068/joe.50.05.33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34068/joe.50.05.33</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emery M, Higgins L, Chazdon S, Hansen D. Using ripple effect mapping to evaluate program impact: choosing or combining the methods that work best for you. J Ext. (2015) 53:1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.34068/joe.53.02.28</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34068/joe.53.02.28</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chazdon S, Emery M, Hansen D, Higgins L, Sero R. A field guide to ripple effects mapping. Minneapolis: University Digital Conservancy; (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobels J, Wheeler J, Dunleavy-Harris K, Holmes R, Inman-Ward A, Potts A, et al. Ripple effects mapping: capturing the broader impacts of systems change efforts in public health. BMC Med Res Methodol. (2022) 22:72. doi: 10.1186/s12874-022-01570-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-022-01570-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8930282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35300619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho H, Salmon CT. Unintended effects of health communication campaigns. J Commun. (2007) 57:293&#x2013;317. doi: 10.1111/j.1460-2466.2007.00344.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1460-2466.2007.00344.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guta A, Flicker S, Roche B. Governing through community allegiance: a qualitative examination of peer research in community-based participatory research. Crit Public Health. (2013) 23:432&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1080/09581596.2012.761675,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09581596.2012.761675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3827674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24273389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damon W, Callon C, Wiebe L, Small W, Kerr T, McNeil R, et al. Community-based participatory research in a heavily researched inner city neighbourhood: perspectives of people who use drugs on their experiences as peer researchers. Soc Sci Med. (2017) 176:85&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2017.01.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2017.01.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5438752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey R. Montagnards: their history and culture. Cultural Orientation Resource Center, Center for Applied Linguistics (2002). Available online at: http://www.culturalorientation.net/library/publications/montagnards-cp (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey GC. Free in the forest: ethnohistory of the Vietnamese central highlands, 1954&#x2013;1976. New Haven: Yale University Press; (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krogstad J. M., Im C. Key facts about Asians in the U.S. Pew Research Center. (2025). Available online at: https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2025/05/01/key-facts-about-asians-in-the-us/ (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison SD, Sudha S, Denzongpa K, Adrong H, Bernot K, Malotky M, et al. Using community-based participatory research to characterize health and lifestyle behaviors of Montagnards, a refugee-origin Asian-American subgroup. J Immigr Minor Health. (2022) 24:1103&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1007/s10903-021-01272-x,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10903-021-01272-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison SD, Sudha S, Young A, Dharod J, Nie YB, Siu HW, et al. When community calls, we collaborate! Community-based participatory research with the multilingual Montagnard refugee community. Prog Community Health Partnersh. (2018) 12:179&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1353/cpr.2018.0038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/cpr.2018.0038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30270228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintanilha M, Mayan MJ, Thompson J, Bell RC. Different approaches to cross-lingual focus groups: lessons from a cross-cultural community-based participatory research project in the ENRICH study. Int J Qual Methods. (2015) 14:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1177/1609406915621419,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406915621419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott K, Ummer O, LeFevre AE. The devil is in the detail: reflections on the value and application of cognitive interviewing to strengthen quantitative surveys in global health. Health Policy Plan. (2021) 36:982&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1093/heapol/czab048,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czab048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8227989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33978729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Bonner program. Princeton, NJ: Bonner Foundation. Available online at: http://www.bonner.org/the-bonner-program (Accessed June 23, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lederach JP. The little book of conflict transformation. Intercourse, PA: Good Books; (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lederach JP. Conflict transformation In: Burgess G, Burgess H, editors. Beyond intractability. Boulder: Conflict Information Consortium, University of Colorado Boulder; (2003)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bush RAB, Folger JP. The promise of mediation: the transformative approach to conflict. Rev ed. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez N, Moll LC, Amanti C. Funds of knowledge: theorizing practices in households, communities, and classrooms. Mahwah: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yosso TJ. Whose culture has capital? A critical race theory discussion of community cultural wealth. Race Ethn Educ. (2005) 8:69&#x2013;91. doi: 10.4324/9781003005995-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9781003005995-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter AB, Laursen SL, Seymour E. Becoming a scientist: the role of undergraduate research in students' cognitive, personal, and professional development. Sci Educ. (2007) 91:36&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1002/sce.20173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sce.20173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell SH, Hancock MP, McCullough J. Benefits of undergraduate research experiences. Science. (2007) 316:548&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1126/science.1140384,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1140384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17463273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauhart RC, Grahe JE. Designing and teaching undergraduate capstone courses. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuseo J. The case for promoting the development of creative and critical thinking in capstone courses In: Gardner JN, Van der Veer G, editors. The senior year experience. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; (1998). 44&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Museus SD, Yi V, Saelua N. The impact of culturally engaging campus environments on sense of belonging. Rev High Educ. (2017) 40:187&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1353/rhe.2017.0001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/rhe.2017.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terenzini PT, Cabrera AF, Colbeck CL, Bjorklund SA, Parente JM. Racial and ethnic diversity in the classroom: does it promote student learning? J High Educ. (2001) 72:509&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1080/00221546.2001.11777112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00221546.2001.11777112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurtado S, Alvarez CL, Guillermo-Wann C, Cuellar M, Arellano L. A model for diverse learning environments In: Smart JC, Paulsen MB, editors. Higher education: handbook of theory and research. Dordrecht: Springer; (2012). 41&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bush C., Renfrew B., Ksor R., Ksor V., Siu X. Medicinal and food plant uses of Montagnard Communities in Greensboro, North Carolina. Ethnobotany Project Greensboro: Montagnard/Asian Community Disparities Research Network, Montagnard Association of North Carolina; 2015&#x2013;2019. Available online at: https://www.montagnardda.org/research-network/projects/food-farming-ethnobotany/ethnobotany-project (Accessed June 29, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DW. The meaning and the measure of health literacy. J Gen Intern Med. (2006) 21:878&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1111/j.1525-1497.2006.00540.x,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1525-1497.2006.00540.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1831571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16881951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudha S., Morrison S. D., Young A. J., Adrong H. This is health for our families! - Montagnard hypertension prevention. Report to the CDLC 2016. Greensboro: University of North Carolina, Greensboro. (2016). p. 1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Amin S, Morrison SD, Sudha S. Small and invisible, yet strong and impactful---North Carolina's Montagnard community responds to COVID-19. N C Med J. (2020) 81:408. doi: 10.18043/ncm.81.6.408,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18043/ncm.81.6.408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33139479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montagnard Dega Association . Traditional arts. Greensboro (NC): Montagnard Dega Association; (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montagnard Dega Association . MAO. Greensboro (NC): Montagnard Dega Association; (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>North Carolina Governor's Office . New Americans: recommendations to strengthen inclusion in North Carolina. Raleigh (NC): State of North Carolina; (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>North Carolina Institute of Medicine . Immigrant mental health. Durham (NC): North Carolina Institute of Medicine; (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montagnard Dega Association . Community advisory council. Greensboro (NC): Montagnard Dega Association; (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malotky M, Malotky MKH, Mayes KM, Price KM, Smith G, Mann SN, et al. Fostering inclusion through an interinstitutional community-engaged course-based undergraduate research experience. J Microbiol Biol Educ. (2020) 21:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1128/jmbe.v21i1.1939,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jmbe.v21i1.1939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32431766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudha S., Morrison S. D., Mitchell I. Our elders, our legacy: needs assessment of older adults in the Montagnard refugee community, Greensboro NC (2023). Available online at: https://libres.uncg.edu/ir/uncg/f/S_Sudha_Our_2023.pdf (Accessed November 18, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montagnard/Southeast Asian Community Disparities Research Network . Abridged youth into community: Curriculum vitae. Network documentation of community projects and outcomes 2012&#x2013;2019. Greensboro: Montagnard Dega Association; (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young A, Morrison S, Sudha S. Montagnard/Southeast Asian community disparities research network into community: Community outcomes and impacts award statement. Documentation of sustained CBPR partnership development and community capacity building outcomes. Greensboro: University of North Carolina Greensboro; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozano K, Alam W, Aktar B, Okoth L, Chumo I, Quach JA, et al. Seven core competencies and conditions for equitable partnerships and power sharing in community-based participatory research. BMJ Glob Health. (2024) 9:e015497. doi: 10.1136/bmjgh-2023-015497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2023-015497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11574420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39551576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickson E, Kuhlemeier A, Adsul P, Sanchez-Youngman S, Myers K, Akintobi TH, et al. Developing the engage for equity institutional multi-sector survey: assessing academic institutional culture and climate for community-based participatory research (CBPR). J Clin Transl Sci. (2025) 9:e44. doi: 10.1017/cts.2025.20,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cts.2025.20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11975786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40201647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster-Fishman PG, Nowell B, Yang H. Putting the system back into systems change: a framework for understanding and changing organizational and community systems. Am J Community Psychol. (2007) 39:197&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1007/s10464-007-9109-0,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10464-007-9109-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17510791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallerstein N, Oetzel J, Duran B, Tafoya G, Belone L, Rae R. What predicts outcomes in CBPR? In: Wallerstein N, Duran B, Oetzel JG, Minkler M, editors. Community-based participatory research for health: advancing social and health equity. 3rd ed. San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; (2017). 371&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bringle RG, Hatcher JA. Implementing service learning in higher education. J High Educ. (1996) 67:221&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1080/00221546.1996.11780257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00221546.1996.11780257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brownell JE, Swaner LE. Five high-impact practices: research on learning outcomes, completion and quality. Washington, DC: Association of American Colleges and Universities; (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valdez CR, Petruzzi L, Schnarrs PW, Banks T, Coombe CM, Israel BA. Forging partnerships for health equity research: transformative capacity-building for community-academic teams. Front Public Health. (2025) 13:1617711. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2025.1617711,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2025.1617711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12339544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40800020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cargo M, Mercer SL. The value and challenges of participatory research: strengthening its practice. Annu Rev Public Health. (2008) 29:325&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1146/annurev.publhealth.29.091307.083824,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.publhealth.29.091307.083824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18173388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias JK, Richmond CA, Luginaah I. Community-based participatory research (CBPR) with indigenous communities: producing respectful and reciprocal research. J Empir Res Hum Res Ethics. (2013) 8:129&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1525/jer.2013.8.2.129,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1525/jer.2013.8.2.129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23651937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawcett SB, Schultz JA, Watson-Thompson J, Fox MH, Bremby R. Building multisectoral partnerships for population health and health equity. Prev Chronic Dis. (2010) 7:A118. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/pcd/issues/2010/nov/10_0079.htm (Accessed November 18, 2025)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20950525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart A, Maddison E, Wolff D. Community-university partnerships in practice. Leicester: NIACE; (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christopher S, Watts V, McCormick AK, Young S. Building and maintaining trust in a community-based participatory research partnership. Am J Public Health. (2008) 98:1398&#x2013;406. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2007.125757,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2007.125757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2446462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18556605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams M, Payne P. Engaging undergraduates in co-curricular community-based research: strategies for success. J Community Engag High Educ. (2019) 13:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washburn LT, Traywick L, Thornton L, Vincent J, Brown T. Using ripple effects mapping to evaluate a community-based health program: perspectives of program implementers. Health Promot Pract. (2020) 21:601&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1177/1524839918804506,</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524839918804506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30366499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotti C, Longo NV, Plaut J, Bush A. Learning through collaboration: reflections on cultivating cross-institutional capacity for place-based community engagement. Metrop Univ. (2024) 35:85&#x2013;106. doi: 10.18060/27708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18060/27708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuh GD, O'Donnell K. Ensuring quality and taking high-impact practices to scale. Washington, DC: Association of American Colleges and Universities; (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hara S, Naicker S. Local commitment and global reach: advancing sustainable capacity building in higher education. WORLD. (2022) 3:783&#x2013;801. doi: 10.3390/world3040044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/world3040044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>