<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41626292</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2352-8737</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Alzheimer's &amp; dementia (New York, N. Y.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Alzheimers Dement (N Y)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exclusions affect representativeness of Alzheimer's disease trial participants.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70191</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70191</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70191</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/trc2.70191</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study assessed how medical exclusion criteria of a prevention Alzheimer's disease trial impact potential eligibility and sample characteristics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Medical exclusion criteria from the Anti-Amyloid Treatment in Asymptomatic Alzheimer's Disease (A4) trial were applied to <i>N</i> = 3695 participants from the population-based Health Retirement Study (HRS) with linked Medicare data. We determined the proportion of hypothetical eligibility. Multivariate Poisson regression was used to estimate associations between sociodemographic characteristics and eligibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the participants, 74.2% (<i>N</i> = 2742) were deemed ineligible. Accounting for all sociodemographic characteristics, older age, female gender, fewer years of education, lower net worth, and body mass index of 30+ was associated with a higher odds of being deemed ineligible. Ethnocultural identity and living arrangement were not associated with eligibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results suggest that certain sociodemographic factors may limit eligibility for a prevention Alzheimer's disease trial due to the presence of exclusionary medical conditions. This highlights the need to make trials more inclusive.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HIGHLIGHTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 2742 participants (74.2%) were deemed ineligible for the Anti-Amyloid Treatment in Asymptomatic Alzheimer's Disease (A4) trial based on the medical exclusion criteria.The most common medical exclusion in this sample was for cardiovascular conditions.Ineligibility was associated with age, education, net worth, and body mass index.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia: Translational Research &amp; Clinical Interventions published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Alzheimer's Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashford</LastName><ForeName>Miriam T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4045-6435</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Advanced Imaging Research Center San Francisco Veteran's Administration Medical Center San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences University of California, San Francisco San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center - San Francisco Northern California Institute for Research and Education (NCIRE) San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tank</LastName><ForeName>Rachana</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Biomedical Imaging University of California, San Francisco San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dementia Research Centre, UCL Institute of Neurology University College London London UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kabeto</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed U</ForeName><Initials>MU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine University of Michigan Ann Arbor Michigan USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nosheny</LastName><ForeName>Rachel L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Advanced Imaging Research Center San Francisco Veteran's Administration Medical Center San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences University of California, San Francisco San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiner</LastName><ForeName>Michael W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Advanced Imaging Research Center San Francisco Veteran's Administration Medical Center San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center - San Francisco Northern California Institute for Research and Education (NCIRE) San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Biomedical Imaging University of California, San Francisco San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine University of California San Francisco San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology University of California San Francisco San Francisco California USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weir</LastName><ForeName>David R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Social Research University of Michigan Ann Arbor Michigan USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langa</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine University of Michigan Ann Arbor Michigan USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Social Research University of Michigan Ann Arbor Michigan USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Healthcare Policy and Innovation University of Michigan Ann Arbor Michigan USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>F32 AG072730</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K01 AG088464</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Alzheimers Dement (N Y)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101650118</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2352-8737</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer's</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health and Retirement Study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Latino</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eligibility criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enrollment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ethnicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recruitment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Miriam T. Ashford reports grants from the National Institute on Aging (NIA; made to the institution) and declares no potential conflicts of interest. Rachana Tank and Mohammed U. Kabeto declare no potential conflicts of interest. Rachel L. Nosheny reports grants from the National Institutes of Health (NIH), grants from Genentech, Inc., and grants from the California Department of Public Health during the conduct of the study. Michael W. Weiner reports grants from the NIH, from the Department of Defense (DOD), from the Patient&#x2010;Centered Outcomes Research Institute (PCORI), from California Department of Public Health (CDPH), from the University of Michigan, from Siemens, from Biogen, from Hillblom Foundation, from the Alzheimer's Association, from the State of California, from Johnson &amp; Johnson, from Kevin and Connie Shanahan, from general electric (GE), from vanderbilt university medical center (VUmc), from Australian Catholic University (HBI&#x2010;BHR), from The Stroke Foundation, and from the Veterans Administration; personal fees from Acumen Pharmaceutical, from Cerecin, from Dolby Family Ventures, from Eli Lilly, from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp., from the National Institute on Aging&#xa0;(NIA), from Nestle/Nestec, from PCORI/patient&#x2010;powered research network&#xa0;(PPRN), from Roche, from the University of Southern California (USC), from NervGen, from Baird Equity Capital, from BioClinica, from Cytox, from Duke University, personal fees from Eisai, personal fees from FUJIFILM&#x2010;Toyama Chemical (Japan), personal fees from Garfield Weston, from Genentech, from Guidepoint Global, from Indiana University, from Japanese Organization for Medical Device Development, Inc. (JOMDD), from Medscape, from Peerview Internal Medicine, rom Roche, from T3D Therapeutics, from WebMD, from Vida Ventures, from The Buck Institute for Research on Aging, from China Association for Alzheimer's Disease (CAAD), from the Japan Society for Dementia Research, and from the Korean Dementia Society, outside the submitted work; and holds stocks or options with Alzheon Inc., Alzeca, and Anven. David R. Weir receives grant from the NIA.National Institute on Aging (U01 AG009740) for the Health and Retirement Study (HRS). Kenneth M. Langa receives grants from the NIH and the Alzheimer's Association; consulting fees from NIH&#x2010;funded projects at Harvard, the University of Pennsylvania, the University of Minnesota, the University of Colorado, and the University of Southern California; expert testimony related to decisional capacity in a person with dementia; and participation on a Data Safety Monitoring Board for a clinical trial at Indiana University. Any author disclosures are available in the Supporting Information.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41626292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12851896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/trc2.70191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">TRC270191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dhillon S. Aducanumab: first approval. Drugs. 2021;81(12):1437&#x2010;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34324167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Dyck CH, Swanson CJ, Aisen P, et&#xa0;al. Lecanemab in early Alzheimer's disease. N Engl J Med. 2023;388(1):9&#x2010;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Zhang Y, Wang J, Xia Y, Zhang J, Chen L. Recent advances in Alzheimer's disease: mechanisms, clinical trials and new drug development strategies. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2024;9(1):211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11344989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39174535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooldijk SS, Licher S, Wolters FJ. Characterizing demographic, racial, and geographic diversity in dementia research: a systematic review. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(10):1255&#x2010;1261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmore&#x2010;Bykovskyi AL, Jin Y, Gleason C, et&#xa0;al. Recruitment and retention of underrepresented populations in Alzheimer's disease research: a systematic review. Alzheimers Dement Transl Res Clin Interv. 2019;5:751&#x2010;770. doi: 10.1016/j.trci.2019.09.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trci.2019.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6944728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31921966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Alzheimer's disease facts and figures. Alzheimer's Association; 2023. Available from: https://www.alz.org/media/documents/alzheimers&#x2010;facts&#x2010;and&#x2010;figures.pdf
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayeda ER, Glymour MM, Quesenberry CP, Whitmer RA. Inequalities in dementia incidence between six racial and ethnic groups over 14 years. Alzheimers Dement. 2016;12(3):216&#x2010;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4969071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26874595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M&#x2010;X, Cross P, Andrews H, et&#xa0;al. Incidence of AD in African&#x2010;Americans, Caribbean Hispanics, and Caucasians in northern Manhattan. Neurology. 2001;56(1):49&#x2010;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11148235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennon JC, Aita SL, Bene VAD, et&#xa0;al. Black and White individuals differ in dementia prevalence, risk factors, and symptomatic presentation. Alzheimers Dement. 2022;18(8):1461&#x2010;1471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9160212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34854531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp ES, Gatz M. The relationship between education and dementia an updated systematic review. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord. 2011;25(4):289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3193875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21750453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson JL, Ryan L, Silverberg N, Cahan V, Bernard MA. Obstacles and opportunities in Alzheimer's clinical trial recruitment. Health Affairs. 2014;33(4):574&#x2010;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4167360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24711317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weemering DN, Beelen A, Kliest T, van Leeuwen LA, van den Berg LH, van Eijk RP. Trial participation in neurodegenerative diseases: barriers and facilitators: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Neurology. 2024;103(1):e209503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11244742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38830181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langbaum JB, Zissimopoulos J, Au R, et&#xa0;al. Recommendations to address key recruitment challenges of Alzheimer's disease clinical trials. Alzheimers Dement. 2023;19(2):696&#x2010;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9911558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35946590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aranda MP, Marquez DX, Gallagher&#x2010;Thompson D, et&#xa0;al. A call to address structural barriers to Hispanic/Latino representation in clinical trials on Alzheimer's disease and related dementias: A micro&#x2010;meso&#x2010;macro perspective. Alzheimers Dement Transl Res Clin Interv. 2023;9(2):e12389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10242183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37287471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indorewalla KK, O'Connor MK, Budson AE, Guess C, Jackson J. Modifiable barriers for recruitment and retention of older adults participants from underrepresented minorities in Alzheimer's disease research. J Alzheimers Dis. 2021;80(3):927&#x2010;940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8150544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33612540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell PM. External validity of randomised controlled trials: &#x201c;to whom do the results of this trial apply?&#x201d;. Lancet. 2005;365(9453):82&#x2010;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15639683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Loke YK. Drug safety assessment in clinical trials: methodological challenges and opportunities. Trials. 2012;13:1&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3502602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22906139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trivedi RB, Humphreys K. Participant exclusion criteria in treatment research on neurological disorders: are unrepresentative study samples problematic? Contemp Clin Trials. 2015;44:20&#x2010;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26188162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsat ND, Palmowski A, Palmowski Y, Boers M, Buttgereit F. Recruitment and retention of older people in clinical research: a systematic literature review. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2020;68(12):2955&#x2010;2963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33075140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson TS, Ayanian JZ, Souza J, Landon BE. Representativeness of participants eligible to be enrolled in clinical trials of aducanumab for Alzheimer disease compared with Medicare beneficiaries with Alzheimer disease and mild cognitive impairment. JAMA. 2021;326(16):1627&#x2010;1629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8430904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34499725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittock RR, Aakre JA, Castillo AM, et&#xa0;al. Eligibility for anti&#x2010;amyloid treatment in a population&#x2010;based study of cognitive aging. Neurology. 2023;101(19):e1837&#x2010;e1849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10663008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37586881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defrancesco M, Gizewski ER, Mangesius S, et&#xa0;al. Investigating patient eligibility for anti&#x2010;amyloid monoclonal antibody treatment of Alzheimer's disease: real&#x2010;world data from an Austrian psychiatric memory clinic population. BJPsych Open. 2024;10(5):e160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11457211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39308280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider LS, Olin JT, Lyness SA, Chui HC. Eligibility of Alzheimer's disease clinic patients for clinical trials. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1997;45(8):923&#x2010;928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9256842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franzen S, Smith JE, van den Berg E, et&#xa0;al. Diversity in Alzheimer's disease drug trials: the importance of eligibility criteria. Alzheimers Dement. 2022;18(4):810&#x2010;823. doi: 10.1002/alz.12433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alz.12433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34590409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grill JD, Flournoy C, Dhadda S, et&#xa0;al. Eligibility rates among racially and ethnically diverse US participants in phase 2 and phase 3 placebo&#x2010;controlled, double&#x2010;blind, randomized trials of Lecanemab and Elenbecestat in early Alzheimer disease. Ann Neurol. 2024;95(2):288&#x2010;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11733864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37830926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molina&#x2010;Henry DP, Raman R, Liu A, et&#xa0;al. Racial and ethnic differences in plasma biomarker eligibility for a preclinical Alzheimer's disease trial. Alzheimers Dement. 2024;20(6):3827&#x2010;3838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11180863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38629508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathirana TI, Jackson CA. Socioeconomic status and multimorbidity: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Aust N Z J Public Health. 2018;42(2):186&#x2010;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29442409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshakhs M, Jackson B, Ikponmwosa D, Reynolds R, Madlock&#x2010;Brown C. Multimorbidity patterns across race/ethnicity as stratified by age and obesity. Sci Rep. 2022;12(1):9716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9188579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35690677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnega A, Faul JD, Ofstedal MB, Langa KM, Phillips JW, Weir DR. Cohort profile: the health and retirement study (HRS). Int J Epidemiol. 2014;43(2):576&#x2010;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3997380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24671021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juster FT, Suzman R. An overview of the health and retirement study. J Hum Resour. 1995;30:S7&#x2010;S56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Hurd MD, Meijer E, Moldoff MB, Rohwedder S. Improved wealth measures in the Health and Retirement. Study asset reconciliation and cross&#x2010;wave imputation; 2016. Working Papers from RAND Corporation. https://www.rand.org/content/dam/rand/pubs/working_papers/WR1100/WR1150/RAND_WR1150.pdf
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperling RA, Rentz DM, Johnson KA, et&#xa0;al. The A4 study: stopping AD before symptoms begin? Sci Transl Med. 2014;6(228):228fs13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4049292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24648338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elixhauser A, Steiner C, Harris DR, Coffey RM. Comorbidity measures for use with administrative data. Med Care. 1998;36(1):8&#x2010;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9431328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare Medicaid Services . Chronic Condition Data Warehouse User Manual, Version 2.0. CMS Research Data Assistant Center (ResDAC); 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Classifications Software (CCS) for ICD&#x2010;9&#x2010;CM. Agency for Health Care Policy and Research; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crimmins EM, Kim JK, Langa KM, Weir DR. Assessment of cognition using surveys and neuropsychological assessment: the health and retirement study and the aging, demographics, and memory study. J Gerontol Series B: Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2011;66(suppl 1):i162&#x2010;i71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3165454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21743047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen H, Manolova G, Daskalopoulou C, Vitoratou S, Prince M, Prina AM. Prevalence of multimorbidity in community settings: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of observational studies. J Comorbid. 2019;9:2235042&#xd7;19870934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6710708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31489279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah GA, Brown DW. An overview of cardiovascular disease burden in the United States. Health Aff. 2007;26(1):38&#x2010;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brain J, Greene L, Tang EY, et&#xa0;al. Cardiovascular disease, associated risk factors, and risk of dementia: An umbrella review of meta&#x2010;analyses. Front Epidemiol. 2023;3:1095236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10910908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38455934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santiago JA, Potashkin JA. The impact of disease comorbidities in Alzheimer's disease. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;13:631770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7906983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozaffarian D, Benjamin EJ, Go AS, et&#xa0;al. Heart disease and stroke statistics&#x2014;2016 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2016;133(4):e38&#x2010;e360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insel PS, Donohue MC, Sperling R, Hansson O, Mattsson&#x2010;Carlgren N. The A4 study: &#x3b2;&#x2010;amyloid and cognition in 4432 cognitively unimpaired adults. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2020;7(5):776&#x2010;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7261742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rentz DM, Rosenberg P, Sperling R, et&#xa0;al. Characterizing clinical progression in cognitively unimpaired older individuals with brain amyloid: results from the A4 study. J Prev Alzheimers Dis. 2024;11(4):814&#x2010;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11266445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39044489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Council on Education . Race and Ethnicity in Higher Education: 2024 Status Report; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperling RA, Donohue MC, Raman R, et&#xa0;al. Association of factors with elevated amyloid burden in clinically normal older individuals. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(6):735&#x2010;745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7136861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32250387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2015 Obesity Collaborators . Health effects of overweight and obesity in 195 countries over 25 years. New Engl J Med. 2017;377(1):13&#x2010;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin P&#x2010;J, Daly AT, Olchanski N, et&#xa0;al. Dementia diagnosis disparities by race and ethnicity. Med Care. 2021;59(8):679&#x2010;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8263486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34091580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EJ, Kim T, Conigliaro J, Liebschutz JM, Paasche&#x2010;Orlow MK, Hanchate AD. Racial and ethnic disparities in diagnosis of chronic medical conditions in the USA. J Gen Intern Med. 2018;33:1116&#x2010;1123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6025658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29736755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang KG, Rodgers CR, Lee E, L&#xea; Cook B. Disparities in mental health care utilization and perceived need among Asian Americans: 2012&#x2010;2016. Psychiatr Serv. 2020;71(1):21&#x2010;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31575351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacNaughton NS. Health disparities and health&#x2010;seeking behavior among Latino men: a review of the literature. J Transcult Nurs. 2008;19(1):83&#x2010;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18165429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>