<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41813915</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>TinyML pipeline for efficient crack classification in UAV-based structural health inspections.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8964</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-43534-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Structural health monitoring (SHM) of civil, aerospace, and energy infrastructure increasingly relies on UAVs with vision sensors for efficient inspections. Crack classification is a central task, yet cloud-based inference introduces bandwidth, power, connectivity, and privacy challenges that limit its practicality. This study presents a fully self-contained Tiny Machine Learning (TinyML) pipeline for onboard crack classification on a milliwatt-level STM32H7 microcontroller. Using MobileNetV1x0.25 as the baseline, we systematically evaluate the full measurement pipeline, including image capture, preprocessing, and inference on a low-power embedded system. Two preprocessing strategies, a handcrafted sequence (grayscale, contrast, denoise, median, binarization) and a greedy algorithm-based composite method, are compared. Four compression techniques, namely post-training quantization (PTQ), quantization-aware training (QAT), pruning, and weight clustering, are assessed individually and in combination. The optimized pipeline achieves an F1-score of 0.938, an improvement of 11.4% over state-of-the-art deployments. At the same time, it requires only 2.9 MB RAM and 309 KB flash, with an end-to-end latency of 461.6 ms and an energy cost of 623.16 mJ per inference. On a DJI Mini 4 Pro UAV, continuous operation reduces flight time by just 1.31 minutes (4%), compared to 8 minutes (24%) when using Jetson-based platforms. Overall, this work delivers a reproducible benchmark for UAV-based SHM, demonstrating a practical balance of accuracy, resource efficiency, and energy consumption, and advancing the feasibility of on-device crack classification in highly resource-constrained environments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yuxuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Intelligent Science and Engineering, Beijing University of Agriculture, Beijing, China. yuxuan.zhang@miun.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer and Electrical Engineering, Mid Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden. yuxuan.zhang@miun.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>N&#xfc;rnberg</LastName><ForeName>Arne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer and Electrical Engineering, Mid Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rau</LastName><ForeName>Luciano Sebastian Martinez</ForeName><Initials>LSM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer and Electrical Engineering, Mid Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Instituto de Investigaci&#xf3;n en Se&#xf1;ales, Sistemas e Inteligencia Computacional, sinc(i), FICH-UNL/CONICET, Santa Fe, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vu</LastName><ForeName>Quynh Nguyen Phuong</ForeName><Initials>QNP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer and Electrical Engineering, Mid Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Yuchen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yantai Research Institute, Harbin Engineering University, Yantai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oelmann</LastName><ForeName>Bengt</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer and Electrical Engineering, Mid Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bader</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer and Electrical Engineering, Mid Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Convolutional neural networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Crack classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Embedded systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Model compression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Structure health monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TinyML</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41813915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12987979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-43534-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-43534-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lu, Y. et al. End-to-end graph neural network framework for precise localization of internal leakage valves in marine pipelines based on intelligent graphs. <i>Adv. Eng. Inform.</i><b>68</b>, 103716 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aei.2025.103716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, H., Chen, G., Hong, H. &amp; Zhu, X. Remote structural health monitoring for industrial wind turbines using short-range doppler radar. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>70</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2021).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, S., Zhang, X., Chang, Y. &amp; Shen, Y. An improved structural health monitoring method utilizing sparse representation for acoustic emission signals in rails. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>72</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2023).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argentino, A. <i>et al.</i> Data normalization for the continuous monitoring of a steel truss bridge: A case study from the italian railway line. <i>Journal of Infrastructure Intelligence and Resilience</i> 100171 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinabadi, H. Z., Nazari, B., Amirfattahi, R., Mirdamadi, H. R. &amp; Sadri, A. R. Wavelet network approach for structural damage identification using guided ultrasonic waves. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>63</b>, 1680&#x2013;1692 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2014.2299528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthumala, U., Zhang, Y., Martinez-Rau, L.&#xa0;S. &amp; Bader, S. Comparison of tiny machine learning techniques for embedded acoustic emission analysis. In <i>2024 IEEE 10th World Forum on Internet of Things (WF-IoT)</i>, 444&#x2013;449 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, S., Zhang, X., Chang, Y. &amp; Shen, Y. An improved structural health monitoring method utilizing sparse representation for acoustic emission signals in rails. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>72</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2023).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakaria, M., Karaaslan, E. &amp; Catbas, F. N. Advanced bridge visual inspection using real-time machine learning in edge devices. <i>Advances in Bridge Engineering</i><b>3</b>, 27 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43251-022-00073-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heichel, J. <i>et al.</i> A System for Real-Time Display and Interactive Training of Predictive Structural Defect Models Deployed on UAV. In <i>2023 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS)</i>, 1221&#x2013;1225 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller, H., Niculescu, V., Polonelli, T., Magno, M. &amp; Benini, L. Robust and efficient depth-based obstacle avoidance for autonomous miniaturized uavs. <i>IEEE Trans. Rob.</i><b>39</b>, 4935&#x2013;4951 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TRO.2023.3315710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tse, K.-W., Pi, R., Yang, W., Yu, X. &amp; Wen, C.-Y. Advancing uav-based inspection system: The ussa-net segmentation approach to crack quantification. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>73</b>, 1&#x2013;14 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2024.3418073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, A., Kumar, A., Jha, A.&#xa0;K. &amp; Trivedi, A. Crack Detection of Structures using Deep Learning Framework. In <i>2020 3rd International Conference on Intelligent Sustainable Systems (ICISS)</i>, 526&#x2013;533 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z., Al-Huda, Z., Peng, B. &amp; Hu, J. A bio-inspired network with automatic brightness adaptation for pavement crack detection in different environments. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>73</b>, 1&#x2013;15 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Martinez-Rau, L.&#xa0;S., Oelmann, B. &amp; Bader, S. Enabling autonomous structural inspections with tiny machine learning on uavs. In <i>2024 IEEE Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. <i>et al.</i> On-device crack segmentation for edge structural health monitoring. In <i>2025 IEEE Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moosmann, J. <i>et al.</i> Ultra-efficient on-device object detection on ai-integrated smart glasses with tinyissimoyolo. In <i>European Conference on Computer Vision</i>, 262&#x2013;280 (Springer, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Martinez-Rau, L.&#xa0;S., Vu, Q. N.&#xa0;P., Oelmann, B. &amp; Bader, S. Survey of quantization techniques for on-device vision-based crack detection. In <i>2025 IEEE International Instrumentation and Measurement Technology Conference (I2MTC)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Pullin, R., Oelmann, B. &amp; Bader, S. On-device fault diagnosis with augmented acoustic emission data: A case study on carbon fiber panels. <i>IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas.</i><b>74</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ad&#x131;n, V., Zhang, Y., And&#xf2;, B., Oelmann, B. &amp; Bader, S. Tiny machine learning for real-time postural stability analysis. In <i>2023 IEEE Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Rau, L.&#xa0;S., Zhang, Y., Oelmann, B. &amp; Bader, S. Tinyml anomaly detection for industrial machines with periodic duty cycles. In <i>2024 IEEE Sensors Applications Symposium (SAS)</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakaryapour Sayyad, F., Shallari, I., Mousavirad, S.&#xa0;J. &amp; O&#x2019;Nils, M. Model evaluation and selection for robust and efficient advertisement detection in print media. In Singh, M. <i>et al.</i> (eds.) <i>Advances in Computing and Data Sciences</i>, 211&#x2013;224 (Springer Nature Switzerland, Cham, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. A novel hybrid yolo approach for precise paper defect detection with a dual-layer template and an attention mechanism. <i>IEEE Sens. J.</i><b>24</b>, 11651&#x2013;11669 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2024.3356356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, K. et al. Psdnet: Plant status detection network utilized in an intelligent bougainvillea glabra sensing and watering system. <i>IEEE Sens. J.</i><b>24</b>, 18685&#x2013;18698 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2024.3390681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg, O. A. B. et al. Tcl: Time-dependent clustering loss for optimizing post-training feature map quantization for partitioned dnns. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>13</b>, 103640&#x2013;103648 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2025.3579107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg, O. A.&#xa0;B. <i>et al.</i> Efficient inference of parallel partitioned hybrid-vision transformers. In <i>Proceedings of the 4th International Workshop on Real-time and IntelliGent Edge computing</i>, 1&#x2013;6 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorafshan, S., Thomas, R. J. &amp; Maguire, M. SDNET2018: An annotated image dataset for non-contact concrete crack detection using deep convolutional neural networks. <i>Data Brief</i><b>21</b>, 1664&#x2013;1668 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dib.2018.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6247444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30505897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradski, G. The opencv library. <i>Dr. Dobb&#x2019;s Journal of Software Tools</i> (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Zhang, J., Zhao, T., Wang, Z. &amp; Wang, Z. Reconstruction of the meso-scale concrete model using a deep convolutional generative adversarial network (dcgan). <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>370</b>, 130704 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jungnickel, D. <i>The Greedy Algorithm, 129&#x2013;153</i> (Springer, Berlin Heidelberg, Berlin, Heidelberg, 1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DJI. Dji mini 4 pro - specs. Available at https://www.dji.com/mini-4-pro/specs (2025/08/01).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>