<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41483312</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1750-0680</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Carbon balance and management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Carbon Balance Manag</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analyzing the carbon emission efficiency and influencing factors of China's thermal power generation sector based on super-SBM and ESTDA models.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>30</StartPage><MedlinePgn>30</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">30</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13021-025-00377-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The progress of carbon emission reduction and the effectiveness of the energy transition in the thermal power generation industry (TPI) directly impact both the quality of the implementation of China's dual carbon goals and the broader landscape of sustainable development. To precisely analyze the core patterns of low-carbon transformation in the industry, this study overcame the limitations of existing research on the thermal power sector's carbon emission efficiency (TPCEE) indicator system. These limitations include insufficient industry adaptability, an inadequate characterization of efficiency evolution dynamics, and an insufficient representation of regional differences. It innovatively constructed a TPCEE indicator system, focusing on the spatiotemporal evolution mechanisms and influencing factors of TPCEE. An integrated research framework of "efficiency measurement, spatiotemporal analysis, influencing factor exploration" was established. In addition, based on panel data from 30 Chinese provinces covering the period 2005-2022, empirical research was conducted using the Super-SBM model, exploratory spatiotemporal data analysis, and the Tobit model. The findings indicated that: (1) the TPCEE showed an overall fluctuating downward trend during the period of 2005-2022, and high-TPCEE areas were located primarily in North China and coastal provinces, while low-TPCEE regions were scattered in Northwest, Northeast, Central, and Southwest China. (2) Given the probability of spatiotemporal coalescence exceeding 70%, the spatial structure of the TPCEE was comparatively stable, showing distinct path dependence. (3) At the national level, the industrial structure, power generation mix, energy intensity, and degree of government intervention contributed to overall efficiency improvements. From a regional perspective, the impact of these factors on the TPCEE exhibited significant regional heterogeneity. The government may use the results as a foundation for building regional energy-saving and emission-reduction plans, as well as to encourage low-carbon transition and sustainable development in the Chinese TPI.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Yin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Chongqing University of Technology, Chongqing, 400054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Dalai</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Chongqing University of Technology, Chongqing, 400054, China. madalai@cqut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Chongqing University of Technology, Chongqing, 400054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Fengtai</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Chongqing University of Technology, Chongqing, 400054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Pengli</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Chongqing University of Technology, Chongqing, 400054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Kaihua</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Economics and Finance, Chongqing University of Technology, Chongqing, 400054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>23SKGH248</GrantID><Agency>Chongqing Municipal Education Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KJZD-K202501111</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Research Program of Chongqing Municipal Education Commission</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Carbon Balance Manag</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271519</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1750-0680</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon emission efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Influencing factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial and temporal evolution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Super-SBM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thermal power generation sector</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participtae: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41483312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12866585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-025-00377-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13021-025-00377-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma D, Yan Y, Xiao Y, Zhang F, Zha H, Chang R, et al. Research on the spatiotemporal evolution and influencing factors of urbanization and carbon emission efficiency coupling coordination: from the perspective of global countries. J Environ Manage. 2024;360:121153. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38772234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen R, Heng Z, Jin Y. How to break carbon lock-in of thermal power industry in China&#x2014;a tripartite evolutionary game analysis. Appl Energy. 2025;377:124504. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.124504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.124504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Feng S, Guo S, Ye X. The spatial-temporal evolution analysis of carbon emission of china&#x2019;s thermal power industry based on the three-stage SBM&#x2014;DEA model. Int J Clim Change Strateg Manag Emerald Publishing Ltd. 2023;15:247&#x2013;63. 10.1108/IJCCSM-08-2022-0115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/IJCCSM-08-2022-0115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Yin H, Zhao Y. Impact of environmental regulations on the efficiency and CO2 emissions of power plants in China. Appl Energy. 2015;149:238&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.03.112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.03.112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Lin B. Carbon dioxide-emission in China&#x5f3;s power industry: evidence and policy implications. Renew Sustain Energy Rev. 2016;60:258&#x2013;67. 10.1016/j.rser.2016.01.058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2016.01.058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azam M, Nawaz S, Rafiq Z, Iqbal N. A spatial-temporal decomposition of carbon emission intensity: a sectoral level analysis in Pakistan. Environ Sci Pollut Res. 2021;28:21381&#x2013;95. 10.1007/s11356-020-12088-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-12088-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali U, Guo Q, Kartal MT, Nurgazina Z, Khan ZA, Sharif A. The impact of renewable and non-renewable energy consumption on carbon emission intensity in China: fresh evidence from novel dynamic ARDL simulations. J Environ Manage. 2022;320:115782. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.115782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.115782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35963066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Huang C. How does urbanization affect carbon emission efficiency? Evidence from China. J Clean Prod. 2020;272:122828. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.122828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.122828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng L, Lu H, Liu Y, Zhou Y, Hu H. Analysis of regional differences and influencing factors on China&#x2019;s carbon emission efficiency in 2005&#x2013;2015. Energies. 2019;12:3081. 10.3390/en12163081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en12163081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Zhang C, Li R. Does renewable energy consumption improve environmental efficiency in 121 countries? A matter of income inequality. Sci Total Environ. 2023;882:163471. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.163471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.163471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sala-Garrido R, Maziotis A, Mocholi-Arce M, Molinos-Senante M. Assessing eco-efficiency of wastewater treatment plants: a cross-evaluation strategy. Sci Total Environ. 2023;900:165839. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.165839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.165839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37506908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Chen L, Wang J, Liao L. The impact of disposability characteristics on carbon efficiency from a potential emissions reduction perspective. J Clean Prod. 2023;408:137180. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.137180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.137180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan D, Lei Y, Li L, Song W. Carbon emission efficiency and spatial clustering analyses in China&#x2019;s thermal power industry: evidence from the provincial level. J Clean Prod. 2017;156:518&#x2013;27. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.04.063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.04.063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Y, Ma D, Zhang F, Zhao N, Wang L, Guo Z, et al. Spatiotemporal differentiation of carbon emission efficiency and influencing factors: from the perspective of 136 countries. Sci Total Environ. 2023;879:163032. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.163032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.163032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36965718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang T, Fang D, Yu B. Carbon emission efficiency of thermal power generation in China: empirical evidence from the micro-perspective of power plants. Energy Policy. 2022;165:112955. 10.1016/j.enpol.2022.112955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enpol.2022.112955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M, Khan Z, Anser MK, Jabeen G. Do rural-urban migration and industrial agglomeration mitigate the environmental degradation across China&#x2019;s regional development levels? Sustain Prod Consum. 2021;27:679&#x2013;97. 10.1016/j.spc.2021.01.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spc.2021.01.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Wang Z, Zhu M, Hu C, Liu C. Study on the spatial&#x2013;temporal evolution and driving mechanism of urban land green use efficiency in the Yellow River Basin cities. Ecol Indic. 2023;154:110672. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Q, Xue L, Zhang H, Chen P, Yang J, Niu B. Spatiotemporal analysis of carbon emission efficiency across economic development stages and synergistic emission reduction in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. J Environ Manage. 2025;377:124609. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39986159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rey SJ, Janikas MV, STARS. Space-Time analysis of regional systems. In: Fischer MM, Getis A, editors. Handb appl Spat anal Softw tools methods appl [Internet]. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2010. pp. 91&#x2013;112. [cited 2025 Apr 24]. 10.1007/978-3-642-03647-7_6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rey SJ, Murray AT, Anselin L. Visualizing regional income distribution dynamics. Lett Spat Resour Sci. 2011;4:81&#x2013;90. 10.1007/s12076-010-0048-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12076-010-0048-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Xie Z, Wu R, Feng K. How does urbanization affect the carbon intensity of human well-being? A global assessment. Appl Energy. 2022;312:118798. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2022.118798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2022.118798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou D, Zhang X, Wang X. Research on coupling degree and coupling path between China&#x2019;s carbon emission efficiency and industrial structure upgrading. Environ Sci Pollut Res. 2020;27:25149&#x2013;62. 10.1007/s11356-020-08993-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-08993-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32347503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong F, Li Y, Gao Y, Zhu J, Qin C, Zhang X. Energy transition and carbon neutrality: exploring the non-linear impact of renewable energy development on carbon emission efficiency in developed countries. Resour Conserv Recycl. 2022;177:106002. 10.1016/j.resconrec.2021.106002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2021.106002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Wang L. How does trade openness impact carbon intensity? J Clean Prod. 2021;295:126370. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.126370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.126370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Zhang F. Does increasing investment in research and development promote economic growth decoupling from carbon emission growth? An empirical analysis of BRICS countries. J Clean Prod. 2020;252:119853. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.119853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.119853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong F, Zhu J, Li Y, Chen Y, Gao Y, Hu M, et al. How green technology innovation affects carbon emission efficiency: evidence from developed countries proposing carbon neutrality targets. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2022;29:35780&#x2013;99. 10.1007/s11356-022-18581-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-022-18581-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35061172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma D, Xiao Y, Ma D, Xiao Y, Guo Z. Environmental regulation, technological progress and carbon emission efficiency: an empirical analysis based on panel data of Chinese provinces. Opportunities and Challenges in Sustainability. 2022. 10.56578/ocs010105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56578/ocs010105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao P, Zeng L, Li P, Lu H, Hu H, Li C, et al. China&#x2019;s transportation sector carbon dioxide emissions efficiency and its influencing factors based on the EBM DEA model with undesirable outputs and spatial Durbin model. Energy. 2022. 10.1016/j.energy.2021.121934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2021.121934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling Y, Xia S, Cao M, He K, Lim MK, Sukumar A, et al. Carbon emissions in China&#x2019;s thermal electricity and heating industry: an input-output structural decomposition analysis. J Clean Prod. 2021;329:129608. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.129608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.129608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Shao H. Spatiotemporal interactions and influencing factors for carbon emission efficiency of cities in the Yangtze River Economic Belt, China. Sustain Cities Soc. 2024;103:105248. 10.1016/j.scs.2024.105248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2024.105248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng P, Li J, Zhai M, Huang S. Coupling of economic growth and reduction in carbon emissions at the efficiency level: evidence from China. Energy. 2020;213:118747. 10.1016/j.energy.2020.118747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.118747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tone K. A slacks-based measure of efficiency in data envelopment analysis. Eur J Oper Res. 2001;130:498&#x2013;509. 10.1016/S0377-2217(99)00407-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0377-2217(99)00407-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tone K. A slacks-based measure of super-efficiency in data envelopment analysis. Eur J Oper Res. 2002;143:32&#x2013;41. 10.1016/S0377-2217(01)00324-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0377-2217(01)00324-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei C, Wang S, Zhao X. Spatial-temporal variation and coupling relationship between primary energy consumption and economic growth: a global assessment. Energy. 2025;323:135873. 10.1016/j.energy.2025.135873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2025.135873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Y, Ma D, Li C, Hu C, Deng P, Chang R, et al. Under the sustainable development goals: a research on the coupling coordination relationship of water- energy- food globally. Energy Econ. 2025;150:108873. 10.1016/j.eneco.2025.108873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eneco.2025.108873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rey SJ, Janikas MV. STARS: Space&#x2013;Time analysis of regional systems. Geogr Anal. 2006;38:67&#x2013;86. 10.1111/j.0016-7363.2005.00675.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0016-7363.2005.00675.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X, Rey S. A framework for exploratory space-time analysis of economic data. Ann Reg Sci. 2013;50:315&#x2013;39. 10.1007/s00168-011-0470-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00168-011-0470-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma D, Hu C, Yan Y, Zhang F, Zhang J, Deng P, et al. A comprehensive analysis of the spatiotemporal dynamics and determinants of carbon emission efficiency in China&#x2019;s manufacturing sector. J Environ Manage. 2025;381:125269. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.125269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.125269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40215859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobin J. Estimation of relationships for limited dependent variables. Econometrica. 1958;26:24&#x2013;36. 10.2307/1907382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1907382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang D, Yu B. Driving mechanism and decoupling effect of PM2.5 emissions: empirical evidence from china&#x2019;s industrial sector. Energy Policy. 2021;149:112017. 10.1016/j.enpol.2020.112017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enpol.2020.112017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pingkuo L, Jiahao W. Study on the diffusion of CCUS technology under carbon trading mechanism: based on the perspective of tripartite evolutionary game among thermal power enterprises, government and public. J Clean Prod. 2024;438:140730. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.140730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.140730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Lin Z, Wu J, Li P, Zhang C, Liu Y, et al. AI-based carbon peak prediction and energy transition optimization for thermal power industry in energy-intensive regions of China. Energy Conversion and Management: X. 2025;25:100884. 10.1016/j.ecmx.2025.100884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecmx.2025.100884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, Fang D, Yu H, Zhao C. Temporal-spatial determinants of renewable energy penetration in electricity production: evidence from EU countries. Renew Energy. 2021;180:438&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.renene.2021.08.079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2021.08.079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo Z, Xu X, Long Y. Study on the economic comparison and low-carbon benefits of major low-carbon thermal power technologies in China. Energy Rep. 2025;14:1392&#x2013;402. 10.1016/j.egyr.2025.07.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2025.07.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Bo H. How carbon trading in the power sector affects carbon emission efficiency: an empirical study based on Chinese provincial panel data. J Urban Manag [Internet]. 2025. 10.1016/j.jum.2025.08.004. [cited 2025 Sept 18].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jum.2025.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X, Huang L, Sui X. Capacity optimization of existing reservoir hydropower expansion and its impact on power system flexibility. Appl Energy. 2025;377:124549. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.124549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2024.124549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L, Bai L, Liu Y, Yang Y, Guo X. Research on the impact of COVID-19 on the spatiotemporal distribution of carbon dioxide emissions in China. Heliyon. 2023;9:e13963. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e13963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9951609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36855647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Chen B, Ho HC, Kwan M-P, Liu D, Wang F, et al. Observed inequality in urban greenspace exposure in China. Environ Int. 2021;156:106778. 10.1016/j.envint.2021.106778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2021.106778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34425646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Tang J, Huang F. The impact of industrial structure adjustment on the spatial industrial linkage of carbon emission: from the perspective of climate change mitigation. J Environ Manage. 2023;345:118620. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2023.118620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2023.118620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37544026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>