<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41466969</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-1411</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Attitudes, Perceptions and Determinants of Non-Medically Indicated Caesarean Section Preference Among Pregnant Women in Thailand: A Three-Phase Mixed-Methods Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5577</StartPage><EndPage>5596</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5577-5596</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/IJWH.S570370</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Non-medically indicated caesarean section (CS) is a growing contributor to rising CS rates globally and in Thailand, influenced by maternal preference, socio-cultural factors and clinical decision-making. Understanding women's perspectives is essential to guide counselling strategies and inform policy targeted at reducing unnecessary CS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To explore pregnant women's attitudes, perceptions and determinants of preference for non-medically indicated CS and identify factors associated with CS preference.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This prospective, descriptive, three-phase mixed-methods study was conducted from May 1 to July 30, 2024. The study was conducted at an antenatal clinic. The study comprised three phases: in-depth interviews with 40 pregnant women, questionnaire development and validation, and a survey of 400 participants. Descriptive statistics summarised had demographic data, while univariable chi-squared tests and multivariable logistic regression analysed factors associated with non-medically indicated CSs. Odds ratios and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were reported, with statistical significance set at <i>P</i>&#x202f;&lt;&#x202f;0.05. The main outcomes and measures were the attitudes, perceptions, policy, implementation science, counselling frameworks, and clinician-patient power dynamics of pregnant women towards non-medically indicated caesarean sections.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among the 400 women surveyed, 75% preferred vaginal delivery as a more natural and less risky option. However, 60% 60% reported they would still agree to a CS if recommended by a doctor, indicating high reliance on physician guidance even in situations without clear medical indication. Key factors affecting delivery preferences included prior caesarean delivery (adjusted odds ratio&#x202f;2.5, 95% CI&#x202f;1.5&#x2012;4.0) and maternal age over 35 years (adjusted odds ratio&#x202f;1.8, 95% CI&#x202f;1.1&#x2012;2.9). Comprehensive counselling was deemed essential by 80% of participants, who reported greater confidence in choosing vaginal delivery after thorough discussions of risks and benefits. Auspicious timing influenced 39.5%, while 37.3% were swayed by pain perception. Higher education levels, assisted conception methods and concerns about safety, such as blood loss, also shaped CS preferences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pregnant women in Thailand generally prefer vaginal birth but are highly influenced by physician recommendations. Strengthening counselling, addressing misconceptions and incorporating shared decision-making into routine antenatal care may reduce non-indicated CS demand. Findings support future development of counselling frameworks and policy interventions to promote safe, evidence-based delivery choices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="THAI CLINICAL TRIALS REGISTRY REFERENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">TCTR 20230913007: Date of registration 13 September 2023.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Chawanpaiboon et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chawanpaiboon</LastName><ForeName>Saifon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3207-6187</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, 10700, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anuwutnavin</LastName><ForeName>Sanitra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, 10700, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Titapant</LastName><ForeName>Vitaya</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, 10700, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanjanapongporn</LastName><ForeName>Attapol</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Sciences, Faculty of Social Sciences and Humanities Mahidol University, Nakhon Pathom, 73170, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pooliam</LastName><ForeName>Julaporn</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiological Unit, Office for Research and Development, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, 10700, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srichai</LastName><ForeName>Rangsima</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, 10700, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101531698</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1179-1411</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Non-medically indicated caesarean section (CS) rates continue to rise in Thailand, despite the procedure carrying increased risk compared with vaginal birth when not clinically required. Understanding how women make decisions regarding delivery methods is therefore an important public health priority. This mixed-methods study examined pregnant women&#x2019;s attitudes, perceptions and factors influencing CS preference. Data were collected in three phases, including qualitative interviews, questionnaire development and a survey of 400 participants. Although most women initially preferred vaginal birth, many indicated they would consent to CS if advised by their doctor. Determining factors included previous CS, advanced maternal age, medical comorbidities, labour pain concerns and cultural practices such as selecting an auspicious birth date. Clear counselling from healthcare providers strengthened women&#x2019;s confidence in choosing vaginal delivery. These findings can inform counselling approaches and policy aimed at reducing unnecessary CS and promoting informed decision-making. What is already known on this topic? Non-medically indicated caesarean sections (CS) have been increasing globally, influenced by factors such as physician recommendations, maternal age, and safety concerns. However, little is known about the perspectives of pregnant women in Thailand regarding CS and the cultural or socio-demographic factors shaping their preferences. What this study adds? This study reveals that Thai pregnant women&#x2019;s preferences for CS are shaped by prior CS experience, advanced maternal age, and assisted conception methods. Factors such as pain perception, cultural considerations like auspicious timing, and the influence of comprehensive medical counselling significantly impact their decision-making. How this study might affect research, practice or policy? The findings emphasize the importance of tailored medical counselling to address misconceptions and provide balanced information, potentially reducing unnecessary CS rates. Insights from this study could inform patient education strategies and support evidence-based policymaking to promote safer delivery practices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Chawanpaiboon et al.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">attitudes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caesarean sections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decision-making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed-methods study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-medically indicated</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opinions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perceptions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perspective</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pregnant women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41466969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12744229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJWH.S570370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">570370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Boerma T, Ronsmans C, Melesse DY, et al. Global epidemiology of use of and disparities in caesarean sections. <i>Lancet</i>. 2018;392(10155):1341&#x2013;1348. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31928-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31928-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30322584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S, Li X, Wu Z. Rising cesarean delivery rate in primiparous women in urban China: evidence from three nationwide household health surveys. <i>Am J Obstet Gynecol</i>. 2006;195(6):1527&#x2013;1532. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2006.03.044
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2006.03.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16677593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chawanpaiboon S, Sutantawibul A. Mode of delivery at siriraj hospital: a ten-year review (2001-2010). <i>Thai J Obstet Gynaecol</i>. 2011;19:181&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titapant V, Phithakwatchara N. Trends in modes of delivery in Siriraj Hospital. <i>Siriaj Med J</i>. 2007;59:271&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17375625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumbiganon P, Laopaiboon M, G&#xfc;lmezoglu AM, et al. Method of delivery and pregnancy outcomes in Asia: the WHO global survey on maternal and perinatal health 2007-08. <i>Lancet</i>. 2010;375(9713):490&#x2013;499. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(09)61870-5
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(09)61870-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20071021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah A, Fawole B, M&#x2019;Imunya JM, et al. Cesarean delivery outcomes from the WHO global survey on maternal and perinatal health in Africa. <i>Int J Gynaecol Obstet</i>. 2009;107(3):191&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/j.ijgo.2009.08.013
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijgo.2009.08.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19782977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villar J, Valladares E, Wojdyla D, et al. Caesarean delivery rates and pregnancy outcomes: the 2005 WHO global survey on maternal and perinatal health in Latin America. <i>Lancet</i>. 2006;367(9525):1819&#x2013;1829. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(06)68704-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(06)68704-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16753484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Appropriate technology for birth. <i>Lancet</i>. 1985;2(8452):436&#x2013;437.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2863457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molina G, Weiser TG, Lipsitz SR, et al. Relationship between cesarean delivery rate and maternal and neonatal mortality. <i>JAMA</i>. 2015;314(21):2263&#x2013;2270. doi: 10.1001/jama.2015.15553
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2015.15553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26624825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R. Parturition. <i>N Engl J Med</i>. 2007;356(3):271&#x2013;283. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra061360
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra061360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villar J, Carroli G, Zavaleta N, et al. Maternal and neonatal individual risks and benefits associated with caesarean delivery: multicentre prospective study. <i>BMJ</i>. 2007;335(7628):1025. doi: 10.1136/bmj.39363.706956.55
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.39363.706956.55</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2078636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17977819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Signore C, Klebanoff M. Neonatal morbidity and mortality after elective cesarean delivery. <i>Clin Perinatol</i>. 2008;35(2):361&#x2013;371. (). doi: 10.1016/j.clp.2008.03.009
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clp.2008.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2475575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18456074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mylonas I, Friese K. Indications for and risks of elective cesarean section. <i>Dtsch Arztebl Int</i>. 2015;112(29&#x2013;30):489&#x2013;495. doi: 10.3238/arztebl.2015.0489
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.2015.0489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4555060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26249251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaqoub RM, Khouj MA, Alsaif AA, Eissa GA, Alhemdi JA, Albasri S. Awareness and knowledge of caesarean section complications among women in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. <i>Cureus</i>. 2022;14(12):e32152. doi: 10.7759/cureus.32152
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.32152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9807024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36601190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza JP, G&#xfc;lmezoglu A, Lumbiganon P, et al. Caesarean section without medical indications is associated with an increased risk of adverse short-term maternal outcomes: the 2004-2008 WHO global survey on maternal and perinatal health. <i>BMC Med</i>. 2010;8:71. doi: 10.1186/1741-7015-8-71
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-8-71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2993644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21067593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siabani S, Jamshidi K, Mohammadi MM. Attitude of pregnant women towards Normal delivery and factors driving use of caesarian section in Iran (2016). <i>Biopsychosoc Med</i>. 2019;13:8. doi: 10.1186/s13030-019-0149-0
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13030-019-0149-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6442400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30976296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamasmit W, Chaithongwongwatthana S. Attitude and preference of Thai pregnant women towards mode of delivery. <i>J Med Assoc Thai</i>. 2012;95(5):619&#x2013;624.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22994018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bam V, Lomotey AY, Kusi-Amponsah Diji A, Budu HI, Bamfo-Ennin D, Mireku G. Factors influencing decision-making to accept elective caesarean section: a descriptive cross-sectional study. <i>Heliyon</i>. 2021;7(8):e07755. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2021.e07755
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2021.e07755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8365447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34430742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maitanmi BT, Oluyomi OV, Aderemi IO, et al. Knowledge, attitude and perception of cesarean section among pregnant women attending antenatal clinic at Babcock University Teaching Hospital, Ilishan-Remo, Ogun State. <i>J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med</i>. 2023;36(2):2278019. doi: 10.1080/14767058.2023.2278019
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14767058.2023.2278019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37953257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eide KT, B&#xe6;r&#xf8;e K. How to reach trustworthy decisions for caesarean sections on maternal request: a call for beneficial power. <i>J Med Ethics</i>. 2020;47(12):e45. doi: 10.1136/medethics-2020-106071
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/medethics-2020-106071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8639926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33055135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S, Daly D, Begley C, et al. Factors influencing decision-making for caesarean section in Sweden - a qualitative study. <i>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</i>. 2018;18(1):377. doi: 10.1186/s12884-018-2007-7
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-018-2007-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6142337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30223780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinlan JD, Murphy NJ. Cesarean delivery: counseling issues and complication management. <i>Am Fam Physician</i>. 2015;91(3):178&#x2013;184.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25822271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashimi A, Amole T, Aliyu L. Knowledge and attitude of pregnant women to caesarean section in a semi-urban community in northwest Nigeria. <i>J West Afr Coll Surg</i>. 2013;3(2):46&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4220474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25453019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziken M, Omo-Aghoja L, Okonofua F. Perceptions and attitudes of pregnant women towards caesarean section in urban Nigeria. <i>Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand</i>. 2007;86(1):42&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1080/00016340600994950
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00016340600994950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17230288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson M, Alvan J, Pettersson A, Hildingsson I. Conflicting attitudes between clinicians and women regarding maternal requested caesarean section: a qualitative evidence synthesis. <i>BMC Pregnancy Childbirth</i>. 2023;23(1):210. doi: 10.1186/s12884-023-05471-2
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-023-05471-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10044365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36978038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RC, Mulligan A. &#x2018;Maternal request&#x2019; caesarean sections and medical necessity. <i>Clin Ethics</i>. 2023;18(3):312&#x2013;320. doi: 10.1177/14777509231183365
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14777509231183365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7614977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37635933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>