<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMC Infect Dis</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMC Infect Dis</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">36</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">bmcid</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMC Infectious Diseases</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1471-2334</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13049801</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13049801.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13049801</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13049801</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41749138</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-12833-6</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">12833</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Prevalence, clinical features and determinants of cutaneous leishmaniasis in central Ethiopia</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yohannes</surname><given-names initials="T">Tagesech</given-names></name><address><email>tagutafe@gmail.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beyene</surname><given-names initials="G">Getenet</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Geleta</surname><given-names initials="D">Daniel</given-names></name><address><email>daniel@ju.edu.et</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mekonnen</surname><given-names initials="Z">Zeleke</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/05eer8g02</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.411903.e</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 2034 9160</institution-id><institution>School of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, </institution><institution>Jimma University, </institution></institution-wrap>Jimma, Ethiopia </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/0106a2j17</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.494633.f</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 4901 9060</institution-id><institution>Department of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, </institution><institution>Wolaita Sodo University, </institution></institution-wrap>Sodo, Ethiopia </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/05eer8g02</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.411903.e</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 2034 9160</institution-id><institution>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Faculty of Public Health, </institution><institution>Jimma University, </institution></institution-wrap>Jimma, Ethiopia </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>27</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>26</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503805</issue-id><elocation-id>714</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>6</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>5</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>27</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>05</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-05 10:25:13.070"><day>05</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="12879_2026_Article_12833.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1" abstract-type="structured"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Cutaneous Leishmaniasis (CL) represents the prevalent form of leishmaniasis affecting the most disadvantaged communities globally. It presents a notable public health concern, particularly in low and middle-income countries like Ethiopia. Numerous research efforts have addressed the problem of CL across Ethiopia, yet the central region, specifically the Kambata Zone, remained understudied. Consequently, this study aimed to investigate the prevalence, clinical features, and determinants of CL infection in the area.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">A community-based cross-sectional study was conducted in the Kambata Zone from February 1 to August 30, 2024, including participants of all ages and both sexes. Study participants were randomly selected, and data were collected using a pre-tested structured questionnaire. Clinical samples were obtained from individuals suspected of having cutaneous leishmaniasis (CL) by aspirating ulcers or nodules, and the samples were examined using Giemsa-stained smear microscopy. Data were entered into Epi Info software and analyzed using SPSS version 25.0. Descriptive statistics were used to summarize the data, while bivariate and multivariate logistic regression models were applied to identify factors associated with CL infection. Results are presented as adjusted odds ratios (AOR) with 95% confidence intervals (CI), and statistical significance was set at <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">Among 306 participants, microscopic examination identified 45 cases of CL, yielding a prevalence of 14.7% (45/306) [95% CI: 10.94–18.48%]. Clinically, lesions most commonly affected the nose (26/45, 57.7%), with the majority of cases presenting two lesions (31/45, 68.8%), and 20/45 cases (44.4%) persisting for more than one year. Multivariate logistic regression analysis showed that being male (AOR = 4.32; 95% CI: 2.03–6.82; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.03), age under 18 years (AOR = 3.32; 95% CI: 1.76–5.12; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.02), rural residence (35/45; AOR = 2.64; 95% CI: 1.79–12.55; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01), a family history of CL (AOR = 4.65; 95% CI: 1.44–10.89; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01), and the presence of a household garden (AOR = 7.91; 95% CI: 1.25–19.97; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01) were statistically significant determinants of CL infection.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par4">The study revealed a higher prevalence of CL that demonstrates various clinical features in Ethiopia. Notably, the occurrence of the infection is linked with age, sex, rural residence, previous infection, and presence of a garden, implicating the importance of targeted preventive and control measures.</p></sec><sec><title>Trial registration</title><p id="Par5">Not applicable.</p></sec><sec><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12879-026-12833-6.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Clinical features</kwd><kwd>Cutaneous leishmaniasis</kwd><kwd>Determinant factors</kwd><kwd>Ethiopia</kwd><kwd>Prevalence</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Background</title><p id="Par6">Leishmaniasis is a neglected tropical disease caused by intracellular protozoa of the genus <italic toggle="yes">Leishmania</italic> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>], with around 20 species capable of infecting humans [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. The disease is transmitted through the bite of infected female Phlebotomus sand flies and is endemic in 98 countries, spanning tropical and subtropical regions of Africa, the Americas, and parts of Western Asia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. Despite its widespread occurrence, leishmaniasis predominantly affects impoverished populations in developing countries, contributing to significant public health challenges [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>].</p><p id="Par7">Clinically, leishmaniasis presents in three main forms: cutaneous leishmaniasis (CL), visceral leishmaniasis (VL), and mucocutaneous leishmaniasis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. Notably, CL is the most common form, causing 0.7–1.2 million new cases annually worldwide [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. It primarily manifests as skin lesions, often ulcerative, on exposed body areas, resulting in permanent scarring and substantial psychosocial impacts [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. Globally, the prevalence of CL has increased from 2.1 million cases in 2002 to nearly 4 million in 2015, reflecting both an expanding geographic distribution and heightened reporting [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. CL is endemic in 20 New World and 67 Old World countries and is particularly common in highland areas at elevations of 1,400–3,175 m above sea level [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>].</p><p id="Par8">In Ethiopia, CL remains a major public health concern, especially in the northern and southern highlands [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. Annually, an estimated 20,000–50,000 new cases are reported nationwide, including approximately 300 cases in the Silti district [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. Recent evidence also indicates the emergence of CL in previously non-endemic districts, with 80 out of 170 suspected areas now confirmed as endemic [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. These observations highlight the dynamic epidemiology of CL in Ethiopia and emphasize the need for localized data to guide effective interventions.</p><p id="Par9">The high burden of CL in rural and neglected communities is closely linked to socio-environmental and behavioral factors, including poverty, poor housing, overcrowding, proximity to animal shelters, and nighttime outdoor activities [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. Broader drivers, such as environmental and climatic changes, population displacement due to conflict, treatment resistance, and immunodeficiency (particularly HIV co-infection), further exacerbate disease transmission and complicate control efforts [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Although CL is generally non-fatal, it causes considerable morbidity, disfigurement, and social stigma, often leading to neglect by health programs and misconceptions in affected communities [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. In Ethiopia, data on the burden, determinants, and geographic distribution of CL are scarce, particularly in the Kambata Zone [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. This lack of epidemiological evidence impedes advocacy and the allocation of resources necessary for effective disease control. Addressing these gaps, the present study aims to assess the prevalence, clinical features, and determinants of CL in the Kambata Zone, Central Ethiopia, to inform strategies for improved prevention, diagnosis, and management both in the study area and beyond.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Materials and methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Study design, setting, and period</title><p id="Par10">A community-based cross-sectional study was conducted in the Kambata Zone, located in the Central Ethiopia Regional State, approximately 250 km southwest of Addis Ababa. The zone is bordered by Wolaita to the south, Dawuro to the southwest, Tembaro Special Woreda to the west, Hadiya to the northwest, Gurage to the north, and Alaba to the east. According to the 2007 Central Statistical Agency census, Kambata Zone has a population of 680,837, comprising 336,676 men and 344,161 women, with a population density of 502.13 people per km² across an area of 1,355.89 km². Urban residents constitute 97,797(14.36%) of the population, with Durame serving as the administrative center and Shinshicho as another major town. The zone exhibits varied topography and climate, ranging from temperate to cool in the northern highlands to tropical in the southern lowlands. The rainy season typically occurs from April to mid-September, peaking between mid-June and September. The study was conducted from February 1 to August 30, 2024 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Populations, criteria and data sources</title><p id="Par11">The study included individuals of all ages and sexes who were permanent residents of the area and provided informed consent for skin slit examinations. Exclusions were made for those who declined to participate, temporary visitors, individuals with severe co-morbidities, minors without consent, and those who had previously received treatment for leishmaniasis. Data and samples were collected from the participants in their respective settings.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Sample size determination and sampling techniques</title><p id="Par12">The sample size was calculated using the single population proportion formula with the OpenEpi Sample Size Calculator. The study was based on a 95% confidence level, an overall prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis in the district (14%) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], and a margin of error of 5%, which yielded an initial sample size of 234 participants. To account for a design effect of 1.5 associated with the multistage sampling technique and a projected non-response rate of 10%, the final calculated sample size increased to 306 participants [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. Initially, eight zonal districts were randomly selected using a lottery method. From each district, one kebele was chosen through the same lottery process. Households within each kebele were allocated proportionally based on population size, and systematic random sampling was used to select these households. In cases where a selected household was unavailable to participate, the next eligible household was approached to ensure the sample remained robust. Within each household, study units were selected using simple random sampling techniques. The data involved conducting face-to-face interviews to gather socio-demographic and clinical characteristics, along with obtaining skin scraping samples for microscopic analysis.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Data collection tool, procedure and quality control</title><p id="Par13">A semi-structured questionnaire, developed through a review of relevant literature, was employed to collect socio-demographic and other pertinent data from the study units. Data collection was carried out by a multidisciplinary team, which included a one laboratory technologist, one nurse and one dermatologist and ultimately covered 3,940 households across the selected four villages. The survey instrument was initially developed in English and then translated into Amharic and Kambategna. A language professional, blinded to the translation process, conducted a back-translation into English to ensure alignment with the original version. Field enumerators participated in a comprehensive one-day training session that covered the research objectives, ethical considerations, and data collection protocols. They were also trained on how to clinically recognize cutaneous leishmaniasis, differentiating it from other skin diseases using practical exercises in the clinic, videos, and handheld pictures.</p><p id="Par14">Strict adherence to standard operating procedures (SOPs) was maintained to ensure the sterility of laboratory kits, which underwent regular cleanliness checks. Daily inspections were conducted to verify the sterility of these kits. Microscopes were consistently calibrated and maintained to optimize their performance, while we also used known positive and negative controls to ensure the accuracy and reliability of the results. Before full implementation, a pilot test was conducted on a subset of 5% of the target population to assess the clarity and comprehensibility of the questionnaire.</p><p id="Par15">Data integrity was monitored daily by the principal investigator and team leader, who promptly addressed any instances of missing or inconsistent data. The collected data was subsequently anonymized and securely stored in a locked cabinet under the supervision of the principal investigator to ensure confidentiality.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Clinical samples and laboratory diagnosis</title><p id="Par16">Clinical samples were collected from active lesions, ulcers, or nodules in suspected cases of cutaneous leishmaniasis using aspiration with a scalpel and blade. The procedure began with thorough cleansing of the lesion area using a 70% alcohol swab. A small, approximately 5 mm superficial incision was made at the active edge, reaching the dermis. The base of the incision was gently scraped to collect tissue fluid and pulp, while minimizing excessive bleeding. The collected material was transferred to a clean slide, where it was spread thinly and evenly. The smear was allowed to air dry completely before fixation with methanol. Following this, the slide was stained with a 10% Giemsa stain for 25 min to visualize Leishman-Donovan bodies. Microscopic examination was performed with a 100x objective to detect intracellular amastigotes. This microscopy method demonstrated a sensitivity of 87.9% and a specificity of 100% for detecting cutaneous leishmaniasis infection. It showed a positive predictive value of 100% and a negative predictive value of 72.1%, enabling direct visualization of amastigotes in over 88% of cases [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Data processing and analysis</title><p id="Par17">Data were entered into Epi Info software version 4.6 and then exported for analysis in SPSS version 25.0. The data was summarized using descriptive statistics to present frequencies, and percentages of the variables. For inferential analysis, both bivariable and multivariable logistic regression models were employed to investigate the relationships between socio-demographic characteristics, environmental health, housing conditions, and the participants’ diagnostic results. In the initial binary analysis, variables with a significance level of <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.25 were identified as candidate variables and included in the subsequent multivariable logistic regression. The final selection of statistically significant variables was determined using logistic regression, with a significance level of <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05. The associations were quantified using adjusted odds ratios with 95% confidence intervals.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec10"><title>Socio-demographic characteristics of participants</title><p id="Par18">The analysis of socio-demographic characteristics from a study involving 306 (100% response rate) participants in the Kambata Zone provides insightful findings about the population composition. The results show a balanced sex distribution, with 51.3% males and 48.7% females. The majority of participants, 73.5%, were under 18 years old, indicating a predominantly young population. Furthermore, 59.2% of participants came from rural backgrounds, while 40.8% were from urban settings. In terms of occupations, students constituted the largest group at 39.9%, followed by farmers (23.2%), housewives (21.2%), and merchants (18.8%). A significant majority (72.5%) reported having formal education, with 27.5% having no formal education. The religious landscape was predominantly Protestant (61.1%), followed by Orthodox (22.5%), Muslim (5.2%), and Catholic (11.1%). Income assessments revealed that 62.4% were in the low-income category, 29.7% in medium income, and 7.8% in moderate income. Only 10.8% reported a family history of CL, while 30.4% had a history of medication use (Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par19">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Socio-demographic characteristics of study participants (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 306) in Kambata zone</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Variables</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Categories</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frequency</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Percent (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Sex</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">157</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">51.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">149</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">48.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Age</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 18</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">225</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">≥ 18</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">81</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rural</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">181</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">59.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Living Setting</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Urban</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">125</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">Occupation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Housewife</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">65</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Farmer</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Merchant</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">48</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Student</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">122</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Educational status</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Had formal education</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">222</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Had no formal education</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">84</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">Religion</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Protestant</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">187</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">61.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Orthodox</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">69</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">22.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Muslim</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Catholic</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">34</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Income</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Low</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">191</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">62.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Medium</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">91</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Moderate</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Family history of CL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">273</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">89.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Medication history</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">93</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">213</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">69.6</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Environmental and housing characteristics of participants</title><p id="Par20">The tabulated study data highlights various key variables and their respective categories among the research participants. Among the individuals surveyed, 56.9% reported the presence of a small garden, while 43.1% indicated its absence. A notable majority of households (78.4%) reported ownership of domestic animals, while 21.6% did not have any. Population movement was observed in 30.1% of cases, with 69.9% reporting no such movement. The presence of a latrine was noted in 69.6% of households, while 30.4% lacked this essential facility. Only 12.7% of participants admitted to practicing open defecation, with the majority (87.3%) not engaging in this behavior. The primary materials used for house walls were mud (66.3%) or stone (33.7%), and cracks were identified in 70.9% of the houses. Furthermore, approximately 42.5% of individuals reported using bed nets, while 57.5% did not utilize them (Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>).</p><p id="Par21">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Environmental health and housing condition of (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 306) the study participants</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Variables</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Categories</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Frequency</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Percent (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Presence of small garden</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">174</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">56.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">132</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">43.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Presence of domestic animals</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">240</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">78.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">66</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Population movement</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">92</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">214</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">69.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Presence of latrine</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">213</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">69.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">93</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Open defecation habit</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">267</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">87.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">House wall materials</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mud</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">203</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">66.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Stone</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">103</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Cracks founds on houses</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">217</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">70.9</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">89</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Utilization of bed nets</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">130</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">42.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">176</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">57.5</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Prevalence and clinical features of cutaneous leishmaniasis in study participants</title><p id="Par22">Out of 306 participants, 45 cases tested positive for the infection microscopically, representing 14.7% (95% CI: 10.94% to 18.48%) of the sample. The analysis highlighted the prominent localization of primary infections on the nose, accounting for a substantial 26(57.7%) of cases, followed by the hand at 8(17.7%). The majority of individuals, 31 (68.8%), exhibited dual lesions, while single lesions were less prevalent at 5(11.1%). Regarding infection history, a striking 39(86.6%) of cases were experiencing their initial infection, with only 6(13.3%) showing signs of recurrent infections. Chronicity emerged as a notable feature, with 20(44.4%) of cases reporting an infection lasting over one year. The duration of infections was fairly evenly distributed, with 12(26.6%) lasting less than 5 months and 13(28.8%) enduring between 6 months to a year (Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par23">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Prevalence and clinical features of cutaneous leishmaniasis in (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 306) study participants</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Variables</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Categories</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic>)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Percent (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Microscopy result</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Positive</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">45</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Negative</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">261</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="5" colspan="1">Anatomical lesion site</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">For head</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hand</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Nose</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">57.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Check</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Lip</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="4" colspan="1">Number of lesions</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">One</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Two</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">68.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Three</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">More than three</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Number of infections</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">One</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">86.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">More than one</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="3" colspan="1">Duration of infection</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; than 5month</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6-1year</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Greater than one year</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">44.4</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par24">The distribution and clinical features of microscopically confirmed cutaneous leishmaniasis in the study participants offer significant insights into the disease. Individuals who tested positive displayed a variety of skin lesions on the face, nose, cheek, and leg. These lesions presented with ulcerated, nodular, and crusted appearances, providing visual examples of the clinical manifestations of CL in the specific study population through accompanying pictures (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par25">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>The spectrum of microscopically confirmed CL lesions in the study participant</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e939" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12879_2026_12833_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Determinant factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis among the participants</title><p id="Par26">Bivariable logistic regression analysis identified several determinants associated with cutaneous leishmaniasis (CL) at <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.25, including sex, age, place of residence, educational status, occupation, medical history, income level, family history of CL, population mobility, presence of wall cracks, presence of a small garden, open defecation practices, housing construction materials, domestic animals, availability of latrines, and bed net utilization. These variables were subsequently entered simultaneously into a multivariable logistic regression model to control for potential confounding. After adjustment, five determinants remained independently associated with CL at <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05 (Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>). Specifically, male participants had a significantly higher likelihood of CL compared with females (AOR = 4.32; 95% CI: 2.03–6.82; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.03), and participants younger than 18 years had over three times the likelihood of infection compared with adults aged ≥ 18 years (AOR = 3.32; 95% CI: 1.76–5.12; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.02). Similarly, rural residence was associated with a higher likelihood of CL compared with urban residence (AOR = 2.64; 95% CI: 1.79–12.55; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01), while a positive family history of CL substantially increased the likelihood of infection (AOR = 4.65; 95% CI: 1.44–10.89; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01). The presence of a small garden around the household showed the strongest association, with nearly eight-fold higher likelihood of CL compared with households without a garden (AOR = 7.91; 95% CI: 1.25–19.97; <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01) (Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>).</p><p id="Par27">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Final logistic regression model identifying determinants of Cutaneous Leishmaniasis among 306 study participants in central Ethiopia</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Variables</th><th align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Categories</th><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Microscopic CL Smear Status</th><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Bivariate Analysis Output</th><th align="left" colspan="2" rowspan="1">Multivariate Analysis Output</th></tr><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Positive</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Negative</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic>-value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">UOR (95% CI)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic>-value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">AOR (95% CI)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Sex</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.06</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.83 (1.08–4.02)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.03*</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.32 (2.03–6.82)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">133</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Age (years)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 18</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">197</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.07</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.87 (0.26–0.94)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.02*</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.32 (1.76–5.12)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">≥ 18</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">64</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Living setting</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rural</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">144</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.27 (0.12–0.59)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01*</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.64 (1.79–12.55)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Urban</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">117</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Education level</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Had formal education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">122</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.02</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.42 (0.19–0.88)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.61</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.73 (0.21–2.54)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Had no formal education</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">139</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Occupation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Employed</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">118</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.03</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.46 (0.22–0.96)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.48</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.69 (0.24–1.98)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Unemployed</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">143</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Medical history</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Previous illness</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">26</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">88</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.21 (1.18–4.15)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.33</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.41 (0.69–2.88)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No illness</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">173</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Income level</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Low income</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">29</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">96</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.47 (1.31–4.66)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.27</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.53 (0.71–3.31)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Middle/High income</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">165</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Family history of CL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.00 (1.01–6.04)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01*</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.65 (1.44–10.89)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">255</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Population mobility</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mobile</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">91</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.02</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.09 (1.13–3.86)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.44</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.32 (0.65–2.69)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not mobile</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">170</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Home with cracks</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">176</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">41</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.20 (0.07–0.58)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.41</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.45 (0.04–4.76)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Presence of small garden</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">165</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.86 (3.18–14.89)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01*</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.91 (1.25–19.97)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">36</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">96</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Utilization of bed nets</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">91</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">170</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.28 (1.63–11.23)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.84</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.87 (0.33–0.93)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Open defecation practice</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Yes</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">102</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.36 (1.27–4.38)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.38</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.44 (0.63–3.31)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">No</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">159</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Home construction materials</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mud/Wood</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">110</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.58 (1.39–4.79)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.41</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.39 (0.62–3.14)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cement</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">151</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Domestic animals</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Present</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">129</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.94 (1.55–5.58)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.29</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.51 (0.70–3.25)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Absent</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">132</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="2" colspan="1">Availability of latrine</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Not available</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">97</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.01</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.41 (1.30–4.48)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.36</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.46 (0.64–3.32)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Available</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">164</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Note: * Refers to a statistically significant association</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par28">The findings of this community-based cross-sectional study provide valuable insights into the prevalence, clinical features, and determinants of cutaneous leishmaniasis in central Ethiopia. The study reveals that the prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis in the study area was 14.7%, which is comparable to a previous study conducted in the Saesie Tsaeda-emba district of eastern Tigray [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. The findings were lower than the prevalence conducted in Borumeda Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>], Addis Ababa [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>] and the pooled CL prevalence conducted in Ethiopia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>] which were 22.4%, 33%, and 20.04%, respectively. The findings were higher than the prevalence conducted in the Aleku area in 2017 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>], Dessie town [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>] and Bilala-Shaye [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>], which were 6.98%, 1.5%, and 2.5%, respectively. The differences in the prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis among various regions can be linked to the endemic nature of the disease in particular geographical areas, the design of the study, and the characteristics of the study participants.</p><p id="Par29">Cutaneous leishmaniasis is usually noted on exposed parts of the body, mainly arms, face, and legs. The clinical manifestations are extremely diverse, including unusual sites and atypical morphologies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. In our study the majority of CL patients had lesions on their nose. This finding was in contrast to a study done in Dessie town of Amhara regional state [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>], in Borumeda Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>], and in Nefas Mewcha Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>], in which most of the skin lesions in the patients were on their faces. Also in contrast with a study conducted in Pakistan, the highest percentage of infections was observed on the legs [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>], and a study conducted in Saudi Arabia indicates that the most affected body parts were hands and feet [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. The site difference of CL lesions in different areas might be due to the sand fly preference of blood-feeding sites in different settings.</p><p id="Par30">Many of the cutaneous leishmaniasis patients in this study exhibited single lesions, consistent with findings from previous studies conducted in Dessie town [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>], Nefas Mewcha Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>], Borumeda Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>], and the Aleku Area of Sayo District [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]. The occurrence of single or multiple skin lesions based on the number of sand fly bites may be attributed to the predominantly adult population, where a single bite from the fly could provide sufficient blood for sustenance.</p><p id="Par31">In terms of the duration of cutaneous leishmaniasis (CL), a majority of 20 individuals (6.5%) in our study had a duration of CL exceeding one year, aligning with findings from studies conducted in Nefas Mewcha Hospital, Lay Gayint District [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>], and the Aleku Area of Sayo District, Western Ethiopia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]. This is in contrast to the observations from Dessie town [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. The persistence of lesions for an extended period without effective treatment is a notable concern. The responses gathered from individuals in our study area suggest a reliance on traditional remedies for CL, leading to delayed hospital presentation only when lesions fail to heal spontaneously or do not respond to traditional treatments. As a result, the delayed healing of lesions and prolonged persistence are evident in these cases.</p><p id="Par32">In this study, it was observed that males were more susceptible to Cutaneous Leishmaniasis compared to females. Multivariate logistic regression analysis identified sex as a significant determinant of cutaneous leishmaniasis, with males having 4.32 times higher likelihood of infection compared to females. This finding is consistent with research conducted in Boru Meda Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>], Hoveyzeh County, Khuzestan Province [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>], Saesie Tsaeda-emba district, eastern Tigray [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], Bilala-Shaye [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>] in north-central Ethiopia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>], Gondar Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>], and Pakistan [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>], all of which reported notable gender-based differences in CL incidence among males and females.</p><p id="Par33">This difference in CL incidence between males and females may be attributed to the higher involvement of males in outdoor activities. In contrast, a study conducted in Nekemte reported a nearly equal ratio of CL cases between sexes (1:1) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>], while another study in north-central Ethiopia found a comparable prevalence of cases in both males and females [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. Additionally, a study in Nefas Mewcha Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>], revealed no significant variance in CL distribution based on gender. These discrepancies could be influenced by variations in agricultural and cultural practices across different regions and countries.</p><p id="Par34">Our research findings indicate a higher prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis among individuals aged &lt; 18 years, consistent with studies from Hoveyzeh County, Khuzestan Province [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], Saesie Tsaeda-emba district, eastern Tigray [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], Bilala-Shaye [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>], and north-central Ethiopia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. The higher prevalence of CL among individuals &lt; 18 years can be explained by interrelated determinants. Immature immunity (host factor) increases susceptibility, which is compounded by behavioral factors such as frequent outdoor activities and limited use of protective measures that elevate exposure to sand fly bites. This exposure is further influenced by environmental factors, including proximity to vector habitats and conditions that favor sand fly breeding. Together, these interconnected host, behavioral, and environmental determinants contribute to the observed higher CL burden in younger individuals. The increased prevalence of CL infection in younger individuals may be attributed to their heightened exposure to sand fly bites on various occasions. Moreover, the immature immune systems of young people may contribute to the manifestation of signs and symptoms of cutaneous leishmaniasis.</p><p id="Par35">The study participants in this research were predominantly from rural districts, with a high number of confirmed Cutaneous Leishmaniasis cases originating from these areas. The multivariable analysis conducted in this study indicated that individuals residing in rural districts were 2.644 times more likely to be affected by the disease compared to their urban counterparts. Similar findings were reported in a study conducted in Nekemte [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>] and a report from Borumeda Hospital [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>], highlighting the increased risk of infection in rural settings compared to urban areas. Rural populations, who often engage in agricultural activities and animal husbandry, face higher exposure to Cutaneous Leishmaniasis than their urban counterparts [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. This heightened risk is exacerbated by socio-environmental factors such as poor environmental hygiene, the presence of human and animal reservoirs, and specific working conditions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>].</p><p id="Par36">Moreover, a significant number of study participants who tested positive for Cutaneous Leishmaniasis had a family history of the disease. Living with a household member who has common skin lesions emerged as a key factor in disease transmission, with individuals having a family history of Cutaneous Leishmaniasis being 4.650 times more likely to contract the disease according to the multivariable logistic regression analysis. These results align with a study conducted in Borumeda Hospital, Northeast Ethiopia [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>], which identified the presence of CL in neighboring lesions as an independent predictor of cutaneous leishmaniasis prevalence. The vectors responsible for the transmission of parasites can easily spread the disease in nearby settings, making individuals living alone or in close proximity to infected individuals more susceptible to infection. Consequently, the likelihood of contracting an infection from the immediate vicinity is significantly higher in such scenarios.</p><p id="Par37">Lastly, the presence of small gardens around homes has been identified as a significant determinant factor associated with the prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis. Individuals residing in such environments were detected to have a 7.91 times greater likelihood of contracting the disease compared to those without gardens. This observation aligns with findings from a study conducted at Borumeda Hospital in North-East Ethiopia, where proximity to farmland (within 300 m) was also noted as an independent determinats of CL prevalence [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. Biologically, small gardens provide suitable habitats for sand flies, which are known vectors for CL. These areas often feature vegetation, moisture, and organic matter, creating an ideal microenvironment for the sand fly population to thrive [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Consequently, gardens may enhance the likelihood of sand fly encounters with humans, thereby increasing the risk of disease transmission implicating the need for further investigation into vector habitats and their impact on public health in endemic regions.</p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Strength and limitation</title><p id="Par38">The community-level research conducted has provided valuable insights emphasizing the importance of health education campaigns and the need for future prevention and control strategies for cutaneous leishmaniasis in the study area. These findings have implications for generalizing to the entire population of the study area. However, it is crucial to acknowledge the limitations of this study. The study’s reliance on a limited number of closed-ended questions may have restricted respondents from providing additional insights beyond the structured questions. Additionally, the use of face-to-face interviews in a cross-sectional study could have introduced social desirability bias, influencing respondents to provide more socially acceptable answers. The study’s limitation of not covering all seasons might have impacted the understanding of seasonal trends in CL. Lastly, the exclusive use of microscopic diagnostic methods may have limited the overall comprehensiveness of the findings regarding these trends.</p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par39">This study revealed a prevalence rate of 14.7% for cutaneous leishmaniasis. Factors such as Being male, age below 18, residing in rural areas, having a family history of cutaneous leishmaniasis, and the presence of gardens were identified as determinants of cutaneous leishmaniasis. In response to these findings, the study suggests enhancing community-based health education, implementing environmental management practices (such as reducing vegetation around homes), and bolstering vector control measures in endemic regions. Recommendations also include conducting seasonal surveillance to monitor prevalence patterns and conducting further investigations into the environmental variables influencing cutaneous leishmaniasis prevalence, particularly concerning gardens and agricultural practices.</p></sec><sec id="Sec17" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>Below is the link to the electronic supplementary material.</p><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="12879_2026_12833_MOESM1_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Supplementary Material 1: An English Version of Questionnaire for the Study</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>The authors acknowledge the ethical clearance providers, data collectors, and study subjects who gave their time for the interview and tolerated the pain associated with the aspiration of clinical samples for laboratory testing.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>The research was conceived and designed by TY, who also performed the laboratory work with ZM, DG and GB. All authors, including TY, ZM, GB, and DG, made significant contributions to the data cleaning, analysis, interpretation, visualization, and manuscript writing. They were also involved in fund acquisition, supervised data collection, provided technical insights on data interpretation, and critically revised the manuscript for important intellectual content. DG has been responsible for editing the final version of the article, and all authors have read and approved the final manuscript. Finally, TY and DG have been assigned the responsibility of manuscript publication processing.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>The study was funded by Jimma and Walaita sodo University a prominent Ethiopian institution, but the universities did not participate in the publication process or the payment of publication fees.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The datasets utilized and analyzed during this study are available from the corresponding author at tagutafe@gmail.com upon reasonable request.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar1"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par40">The study adhered to the Declaration of Helsinki guidelines and obtained ethical approval from the Jimma University Health Institute ethical review board (with reference number “Ref. No: JUIH/IRB/684/23”) and permission from the Kambata Zone Health Bureau. All participants (or guardians for children under 18 years) provided written informed consent for the collection of data, samples, and photographs. Suspected cases of Cutaneous Leishmaniasis were referred to a clinic for diagnosis and treatment, where patients received a brief educational session.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par41">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par42">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>AOR</term><def><p id="Par43">Adjusted Odds ratio</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>COR</term><def><p id="Par44">Crude odds ratio</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>CI</term><def><p id="Par45">Confidence interval</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>CL</term><def><p id="Par46">Cutaneous Leishmaniasis</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>IRB</term><def><p id="Par47">Institutional review board</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SPSS</term><def><p id="Par48">Statically package for social science</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>VL</term><def><p id="Par49">Visceral Leishmaniasis</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>WHO</term><def><p id="Par50">World Health Organization</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Neway</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis in alert Center, retrospective Analysis, addis Ababa</article-title><source>J Heal Syst Policies</source><year>2021</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>111</fpage><lpage>20</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Neway S. Prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis in alert center, retrospective analysis, Addis Ababa. J Heal Syst Policies. 2021;3:111–20.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pal</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ejeta</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Girma</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Etiology, clinical Spectrum, Epidemiology, Diagnosis, public health significance and control of leishmaniasis: A comprehensive review</article-title><source>Acta Sci Microbiol</source><year>2022</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>140</fpage><lpage>51</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Pal M, Ejeta I, Girma A, et al. Etiology, clinical Spectrum, Epidemiology, Diagnosis, public health significance and control of leishmaniasis: A comprehensive review. Acta Sci Microbiol. 2022;5:140–51.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdel</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hassanein</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cutaneous leishmaniasis in Tabuk, Saudi Arabia: epidemiological trends from 2006 to 2021</article-title><source>Pan Afr Med J</source><year>2023</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.11604/pamj.2023.45.11.38632</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10323816</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37426462</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Abdel R, Hassanein M. Cutaneous leishmaniasis in Tabuk, Saudi Arabia: epidemiological trends from 2006 to 2021. Pan Afr Med J. 2023;45:1–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.11604/pamj.2023.45.11.38632</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10323816</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37426462</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Oryan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Akbari</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Worldwide risk factors in leishmaniasis</article-title><source>Asian Pac J Trop Med</source><year>2016</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>925</fpage><lpage>32</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.apjtm.2016.06.021</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27794384</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Oryan A, Akbari M. Worldwide risk factors in leishmaniasis. Asian Pac J Trop Med. 2016;9:925–32.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27794384</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.apjtm.2016.06.021</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tamiru</surname><given-names>HF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mashalla</surname><given-names>YJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohammed</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cutaneous leishmaniasis a neglected tropical disease: community knowledge, attitude and practices in an endemic area, Northwest Ethiopia</article-title><source>BMC Infect Dis</source><year>2019</year><volume>19</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12879-019-4506-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31619180</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6796443</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Tamiru HF, Mashalla YJ, Mohammed R, et al. Cutaneous leishmaniasis a neglected tropical disease: community knowledge, attitude and practices in an endemic area, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Infect Dis. 2019;19:1–10.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31619180</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12879-019-4506-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6796443</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Adegboye</surname><given-names>OA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Leung</surname><given-names>DHY</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Institutional knowledge at Singapore management university joint Spatial time series epidemiological analysis of malaria and cutaneous leishmaniasis infection</article-title><source>Epidemiol Infect</source><year>2017</year><volume>145</volume><fpage>685</fpage><lpage>700</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1017/S0950268816002764</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27903308</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9507751</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Adegboye OA, Leung DHY. Institutional knowledge at Singapore management university joint Spatial time series epidemiological analysis of malaria and cutaneous leishmaniasis infection. Epidemiol Infect. 2017;145:685–700.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27903308</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1017/S0950268816002764</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9507751</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alatawi</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alanazi</surname><given-names>AMM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Albalawi</surname><given-names>IAS</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Knowledge and attitude regarding cutaneous leishmaniasis among adult population in Tabuk, Saudi Arabia</article-title><source>Cureus</source><year>2024</year><volume>16</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>12</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7759/cureus.52614</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10875712</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38374837</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Alatawi AM, Alanazi AMM, Albalawi IAS, et al. Knowledge and attitude regarding cutaneous leishmaniasis among adult population in Tabuk, Saudi Arabia. Cureus. 2024;16:1–12.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.7759/cureus.52614</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10875712</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38374837</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alamro</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alsaqri</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Aljulajil</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Public knowledge and practices regarding cutaneous leishmaniasis: a cross-sectional study</article-title><source>Int J Med Dev Ctries</source><year>2024</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>3058</fpage><lpage>66</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Alamro SM, Alsaqri RA, Aljulajil A, et al. Public knowledge and practices regarding cutaneous leishmaniasis: a cross-sectional study. Int J Med Dev Ctries. 2024;8:3058–66.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Birhanu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Molla</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Toyib</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The trends of cutaneous leishmaniasis increment in Northeast Ethiopia, a five year retrospective study</article-title><source>World J Nurs Sci</source><year>2019</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>80</fpage><lpage>7</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Birhanu M, Molla M, Toyib M, et al. The trends of cutaneous leishmaniasis increment in Northeast Ethiopia, a five year retrospective study. World J Nurs Sci. 2019;5:80–7.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Iqbal</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iram</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nisar</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Epidemiology and clinical features of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan</article-title><source>Brazilian J Biol</source><year>2024</year><volume>84</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1590/1519-6984.249124</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35946727</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Iqbal W, Iram U, Nisar S, et al. Epidemiology and clinical features of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan. Brazilian J Biol. 2024;84:1–7.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/1519-6984.249124</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35946727</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Razieh B, Farash H, Ali S, et al. Changes in the epidemiology of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Northeastern Iran. Turkiye Parazitol Derg. 2020;44(1):52–57.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.4274/tpd.galenos.2019.6137</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32212595</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sunyoto</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Verdonck</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Safi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Uncharted territory of the epidemiological burden of cutaneous leishmaniasis in sub- saharan Africa — A systematic review</article-title><source>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</source><year>2018</year><volume>12</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>20</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0006914</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6219817</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30359376</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Sunyoto T, Verdonck K, Safi S, et al. Uncharted territory of the epidemiological burden of cutaneous leishmaniasis in sub- Saharan Africa — A systematic review. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2018;12(10):1–20.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pntd.0006914</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6219817</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30359376</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bisetegn</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zeleke</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gadisa</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Clinical, parasitological and molecular profiles of cutaneous leishmaniasis and its associated factors among clinically suspected patients attending Borumeda Hospital, North-East Ethiopia</article-title><source>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</source><year>2020</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>13</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0008507</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7473553</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32841279</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Bisetegn H, Zeleke AJ, Gadisa E, et al. Clinical, parasitological and molecular profiles of cutaneous leishmaniasis and its associated factors among clinically suspected patients attending Borumeda Hospital, North-East Ethiopia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2020;14:1–13.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pntd.0008507</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7473553</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32841279</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bantie</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kassaw</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Demelash</surname><given-names>AT</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Magnitude and associated factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis among patients visiting Nefas Mewcha primary hospital, Northern Ethiopia, 2022: an institution- ­ based Cross- ­ sectional study</article-title><source>BMJ Open</source><year>2024</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2023-075549</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10773395</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38176880</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Bantie B, Kassaw G, Demelash AT, et al. Magnitude and associated factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis among patients visiting Nefas Mewcha primary hospital, Northern Ethiopia, 2022: an institution- ­ based Cross- ­ sectional study. BMJ Open. 2024;14:1–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmjopen-2023-075549</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10773395</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38176880</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tesfay</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mardu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Berhe</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Household knowledge, practice and treatment seeking behaviors towards cutaneous leishmaniasis in the endemic rural communities of Ganta- afeshum district, Tigrai, Northern Ethiopia, 2019: a cross-sectional study</article-title><source>Trop Dis Travel Med Vaccines</source><year>2021</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s40794-021-00144-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8204582</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34130733</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Tesfay K, Mardu F, Berhe B, et al. Household knowledge, practice and treatment seeking behaviors towards cutaneous leishmaniasis in the endemic rural communities of Ganta- afeshum district, Tigrai, Northern Ethiopia, 2019: a cross-sectional study. Trop Dis Travel Med Vaccines. 2021;4:1–10.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s40794-021-00144-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8204582</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34130733</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shita</surname><given-names>EY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nibret</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Munshea</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Burden and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in ethiopia: a systematic review and meta - analysis</article-title><source>Int J Dermatol</source><year>2022</year><volume>63</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>111</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ijd.16265</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35569096</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Shita EY, Nibret E, Munshea A, et al. Burden and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in ethiopia: a systematic review and meta - analysis. Int J Dermatol. 2022;63:1–111.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ijd.16265</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35569096</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ullah</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cutaneous leishmaniasis – Awareness, knowledge and practices among general population in rural and urban areas in Malakand region, Pakistan</article-title><source>Brazilian J Biol</source><year>2022</year><volume>82</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>6</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1590/1519-6984.238665</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33787717</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Khan W, Khan I, Ullah H, et al. Cutaneous leishmaniasis – Awareness, knowledge and practices among general population in rural and urban areas in Malakand region, Pakistan. Brazilian J Biol. 2022;82:1–6.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/1519-6984.238665</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33787717</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Merdekios</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kote</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pareyn</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Prevalence and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in a newly identified endemic site in South-Ethiopia</article-title><source>PLoS ONE</source><year>2024</year><volume>19</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>12</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0311917</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11684615</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39775255</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Merdekios B, Kote M, Pareyn M, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in a newly identified endemic site in South-Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2024;19:1–12.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0311917</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11684615</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39775255</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Henten</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Van, Fikre</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Melkamu</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Evaluation of the CL detect rapid test in Ethiopian patients suspected for cutaneous leishmaniasis</article-title><source>Negl Trop Dis</source><year>2022</year><volume>16</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pntd.0010143</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8797207</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35041672</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Henten S, Van, Fikre H, Melkamu R, et al. Evaluation of the CL detect rapid test in Ethiopian patients suspected for cutaneous leishmaniasis. Negl Trop Dis. 2022;16(1):1–14.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pntd.0010143</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8797207</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35041672</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lavergne</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iriart</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chauvin</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Contribution of molecular diagnosis to the management of cutaneous leishmaniasis in travellers</article-title><source>Clin Microbiol Infect</source><year>2014</year><volume>20</volume><fpage>O528</fpage><lpage>30</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/1469-0691.12487</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24279601</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Lavergne RA, Iriart X, Chauvin P, et al. Contribution of molecular diagnosis to the management of cutaneous leishmaniasis in travellers. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2014;20:O528–30.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24279601</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/1469-0691.12487</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Berhanu</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dugassa</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maru</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cutaneous leishmaniasis in Kutaber District, ethiopia: Prevalence, sand fly fauna and community knowledge, attitude and practices</article-title><source>Heliyon</source><year>2023</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>14</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e18286</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10382297</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37520994</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Berhanu A, Dugassa S, Maru M, et al. Cutaneous leishmaniasis in Kutaber District, ethiopia: Prevalence, sand fly fauna and community knowledge, attitude and practices. Heliyon. 2023;9:1–14.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e18286</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10382297</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37520994</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alemayehu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kelbore</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Alemayehu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Knowledge, attitude, and practice of the rural community about cutaneous leishmaniasis in Wolaita zone, Southern Ethiopia</article-title><source>PLoS ONE</source><year>2023</year><volume>18</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>13</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0283582</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10047512</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36976758</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">Alemayehu B, Kelbore AG, Alemayehu M, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practice of the rural community about cutaneous leishmaniasis in Wolaita zone, Southern Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(3):1–13.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0283582</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10047512</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36976758</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ngere</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boru</surname><given-names>WG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Isack</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Burden and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in a peri-urban settlement inKenya, 2016 Isaac</article-title><source>PLoS ONE</source><year>2020</year><volume>15</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>17</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0227697</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6977748</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31971945</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Ngere I, Boru WG, Isack A, et al. Burden and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in a peri-urban settlement inKenya, 2016 Isaac. PLoS ONE. 2020;15:1–17.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0227697</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6977748</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31971945</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alizadeh</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gorouhi</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sharifi</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Risk factors of anthroponotic cutaneous leishmaniasis among residents in endemic communities in Southeast of Iran in 2019</article-title><source>J Environ Heal Sustain Dev</source><year>2021</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>1219</fpage><lpage>30</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Alizadeh I, Gorouhi MA, Sharifi I, et al. Risk factors of anthroponotic cutaneous leishmaniasis among residents in endemic communities in Southeast of Iran in 2019. J Environ Heal Sustain Dev. 2021;6:1219–30.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beyene</surname><given-names>GN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Assefa</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mokonnon</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Early implanon discontinuation and associated factors among implanon women users visiting public health facilities, in Kembata zone of Southern ethiopia: an institution based cross-sectional study</article-title><source>Front Glob Women’s Heal</source><year>2022</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>3</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fgwh.2022.909411</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9426357</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36051576</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Beyene GN, Assefa N, Mokonnon TM, et al. Early implanon discontinuation and associated factors among implanon women users visiting public health facilities, in Kembata zone of Southern Ethiopia: an institution based cross-sectional study. Front Glob Women’s Heal. 2022;3:1–3.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fgwh.2022.909411</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9426357</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36051576</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bsrat</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Berhe</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Balkew</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Epidemiological study of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Saesie Tsaeda-emba district, Eastern Tigray, Northern Ethiopia</article-title><source>Parasites Vectors</source><year>2015</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>9</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13071-015-0758-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25889827</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4359476</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Bsrat A, Berhe N, Balkew M, et al. Epidemiological study of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Saesie Tsaeda-emba district, eastern Tigray, northern Ethiopia. Parasites Vectors. 2015;8:1–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25889827</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s13071-015-0758-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4359476</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR27" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sharma</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mudgal</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thakur</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>How to calculate sample size for observational and experiential nursing research studies?</article-title><source>Natl J Physiol Pharm Pharmacol</source><year>2019</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>1</fpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR27" publication-type="journal">Sharma S, Mudgal S, Thakur K, et al. How to calculate sample size for observational and experiential nursing research studies? Natl J Physiol Pharm Pharmacol. 2019;10:1.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR28" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rasti</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghorbanzadeh</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kheirandish</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Comparison of Molecular, Microscopic, and culture methods for diagnosis of cutaneous leishmaniasis</article-title><source>J Clin Lab Anal</source><year>2016</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>610</fpage><lpage>5</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcla.21910</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26891976</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6807126</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR28" publication-type="journal">Rasti S, Ghorbanzadeh B, Kheirandish F, et al. Comparison of Molecular, Microscopic, and culture methods for diagnosis of cutaneous leishmaniasis. J Clin Lab Anal. 2016;30:610–5.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26891976</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/jcla.21910</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6807126</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR29" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tadele</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Samuel</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fite</surname><given-names>MB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Prevalence and knowledge of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Aleku area of Sayo District, Western Ethiopia: Community- based Cross-Sectional study</article-title><source>J Med Public Heal ISSN</source><year>2024</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>97</fpage><lpage>101</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR29" publication-type="journal">Tadele G, Samuel A, Fite MB, et al. Prevalence and knowledge of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Aleku area of Sayo District, Western Ethiopia: community- based cross-sectional study. J Med Public Heal ISSN. 2024;5:97–101.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR30" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Eshetu</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mamo</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Cutaneous leishmaniasis in north-central ethiopia: Trend, clinical forms, geographic distribution, and determinants</article-title><source>Trop Med Health</source><year>2020</year><volume>48</volume><fpage>2</fpage><lpage>10</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s41182-020-00231-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32518497</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7271444</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR30" publication-type="journal">Eshetu B, Mamo H. Cutaneous leishmaniasis in north-central ethiopia: Trend, clinical forms, geographic distribution, and determinants. Trop Med Health. 2020;48:2–10.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32518497</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s41182-020-00231-w</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7271444</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Afghan AK, Kassi M, Kasi PM, et al. Clinical manifestations and distribution of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Pakistan. J Trop Med. 2011:1–8.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1155/2011/359145</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3235881</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22174721</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR32" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>De</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Karachi</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis in the largest populated City Karachi, Pakistan</article-title><source>Brazilian J Biol</source><year>2023</year><volume>83</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>6</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/1519-6984.247583</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34932616</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR32" publication-type="journal">De P, Karachi D. Prevalence of cutaneous leishmaniasis in the largest populated City Karachi, Pakistan. Brazilian J Biol. 2023;83:1–6.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1590/1519-6984.247583</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34932616</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR33" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kian</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A retrospective anal y Sis of human cutaneous leishmaniasis epidemiolog y during 2016–2021 in Hove y Zeh count y, Khuzestan</article-title><source>Jundishapur J Heal Sci 2024</source><year>2024</year><volume>16</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>9</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR33" publication-type="journal">Kian M. A retrospective anal y Sis of human cutaneous leishmaniasis epidemiolog y during 2016–2021 in Hove y Zeh count y, Khuzestan. Jundishapur J Heal Sci 2024. 2024;16:1–9.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Zeleke AJ, Derso A, Yeshanew A, et al. Research article a ten-year trend of cutaneous leishmaniasis at university of Gondar Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia: 2009–2018. J Parasitol Res. 2021:1–7.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1155/2021/8860056</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7969101</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33777444</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR35" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaba</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohammed</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mosisa</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Trends of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Western</article-title><source>Biosci Biotechnol Res Commun</source><year>2024</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>154</fpage><lpage>62</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.21786/bbrc/17.3.5</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR35" publication-type="journal">Kaba Z, Mohammed Y, Mosisa G. Trends of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Western. Biosci Biotechnol Res Commun. 2024;17:154–62.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Davoodi T, Khamesipour A, Shahabi S, et al. Geographical distribution and molecular epidemiology of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Fars Province, southern Iran. Environ Sci Pollut Res. 2021:1–9.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s11356-021-15865-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34396481</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR37" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bamorovat</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sharifi</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tavakoli Oliaee</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Determinants of unresponsiveness to treatment in cutaneous leishmaniasis: A focus on anthroponotic form due to leishmania tropica</article-title><source>Front Microbiol</source><year>2021</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.638957</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8203913</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34140933</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR37" publication-type="journal">Bamorovat M, Sharifi I, Tavakoli Oliaee R, et al. Determinants of unresponsiveness to treatment in cutaneous leishmaniasis: A focus on anthroponotic form due to leishmania tropica. Front Microbiol. 2021;12:1–15.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fmicb.2021.638957</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8203913</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34140933</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>