<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMC Pulm Med</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMC Pulm Med</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">64</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">bmcpm</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMC Pulmonary Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1471-2466</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12924497</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12924497.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12924497</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12924497</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41606552</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12890-026-04144-y</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">4144</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The predictive value of combined detection of serum IL-33, TSLP and eosinophils in the treatment effect and exacerbation risk of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names initials="J">Jie</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gu</surname><given-names initials="H">Haitong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names initials="X">Xiao</given-names></name><address><email>Chenxiaoaid599@126.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/013xs5b60</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.24696.3f</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0369 153X</institution-id><institution>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Tongren Hospital, </institution><institution>Capital Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>Beijing, 100730 China </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/013xs5b60</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.24696.3f</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0369 153X</institution-id><institution>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Beijing Tongren Hospital, </institution><institution>Capital Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>Beijing, 100730 China </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/013xs5b60</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.24696.3f</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0369 153X</institution-id><institution>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Beijing Tongren Hospital, </institution><institution>Capital Medical University, </institution></institution-wrap>Beijing, 100730 China </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03c6k3q87</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.490276.e</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0005 0259 8496</institution-id><institution>General Medicine, </institution><institution>Rehabilitation Hospital Affiliated to National Research Center for Rehabilitation Technical Aids, </institution></institution-wrap>No. 1, Ronghua Middle Road, Beijing Economic and Technological Development Zone (Yizhuang), Beijing, 100176 China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>28</day><month>1</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>26</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503783</issue-id><elocation-id>89</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>23</day><month>8</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>23</day><month>1</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>28</day><month>01</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>22</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-02-22 10:25:13.957"><day>22</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="12890_2026_Article_4144.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a prevalent respiratory condition with high morbidity and mortality. This study aimed to investigate the relationship between interleukin-33 (IL-33), thymic stromal lymphopoietin (TSLP), and eosinophilic granulocyte (EOS) levels and the treatment effect and exacerbation risk of COPD.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">A total of 225 COPD patients who were diagnosed and treated in our hospital from October 2021 to September 2024 were selected as the research objects for retrospective analysis and study, and were recorded as the COPD group. 200 subjects who underwent physical examination in our hospital at the same period were selected as the control group. The serum levels of IL-33, TSLP and EOS were compared between the two groups. The patients were divided into the effective group (102 cases) and the ineffective group (123 cases) according to the reduction of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease assessment test (CAT) score not less than 2 points or lung function grade not less than 1 grade after 1 week of treatment (considered effective). After a 12-month follow-up, patients were further divided into acute exacerbation (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 104) and non-acute exacerbation (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 121) groups according to the occurrence of acute exacerbation (patients’ clinical symptoms deteriorated beyond the daily range in a short period of time and needed to change treatment). The changes of serum IL-33, TSLP and EOS levels in patients with different treatment effects and exacerbation risks were detected. The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve was used to analyze the predictive value of serum IL-33, TSLP and EOS alone and in combination for the treatment effect and malignant risk of COPD. Multivariate Logistic regression was used to analyze the influencing factors of ineffective treatment and exacerbation in COPD patients.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">Patients with COPD showed higher serum IL-33 and EOS levels and lower TSLP compared to the control group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05). Compared with the effective group, patients in the ineffective group showed significantly higher serum levels of IL-33 and EOS and a significantly lower level of TSLP (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05). Patients in the acute exacerbation group showed higher serum levels of IL-33 and EOS and a lower level of TSLP than the non-acute exacerbation group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05). The area under the curve (AUC) of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS in detecting the treatment effect of COPD was 0.803, 0.778, and 0.870, respectively. The AUC of combined detection was 0.938, suggesting that the combined detection had a higher predictive value. The AUC for IL-33, TSLP, and EOS were 0.679, 0.716, and 0.891, respectively, with a combined detection AUC of 0.931. For the assessment of COPD exacerbation risk, the combined detection of three indicators had higher clinical value. Multivariate Logistic regression analysis showed that after adjusting for confounding factors such as age, sex, smoking status, and basic pulmonary function, elevated serum IL-33 and EOS levels were still independent risk factors for treatment failure (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05), while elevated TSLP level was a protective factor (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05). In terms of predicting the risk of acute exacerbation, the elevated EOS level was an independent risk factor (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), and the independent predictive value of IL-33 and TSLP did not reach statistical significance (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &gt; 0.05).</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par4">The levels of IL-33 and EOS were significantly increased, and the level of TSLP was significantly decreased in patients with effective treatment and acute exacerbation of COPD. The above indicators could be used as important indicators to predict the treatment effect and malignant risk of COPD, and the combined detection had high sensitivity and specificity.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>IL-33</kwd><kwd>TSLP</kwd><kwd>Eosinophils</kwd><kwd>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</kwd><kwd>Treatment effect</kwd><kwd>Risk of exacerbation</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Background</title><p id="Par13">Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is a commonly found respiratory disease with high morbidity and mortality [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. During the exacerbation of COPD, neutrophils are extensively activated and aggregated. Neutrophils induce a surge in chronic mucus secretion in the airways by releasing biologically active compounds such as elastase, further damaging the structures of the lungs such as bronchi and alveoli [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. The damage caused by exacerbation of COPD is irreversible. Without timely and effective control measures, the persistent respiratory inflammation reaction will further worsen, vascular endothelial cells will be severely damaged, further exacerbating the damage to lung function. Each year, 22% to 40% of patients with COPD experience at least one moderate or severe exacerbation, while 9% to 16% of patients experience more than one exacerbation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. The pathogenesis of COPD has not been fully elucidated. In the past few years, research has been based on identifying biomarkers, which will provide information regarding disease classification, treatment response, or the risk of future deterioration. Therefore, there is an urgent need to explore methods that can better and timely evaluate the treatment effectiveness and prognosis of COPD.</p><p id="Par14">Interleukin-33 (IL-33) and Thymic stromal lymphopoietin (TSLP) are both inflammation related factors involved in the upstream of the Th2 inflammatory pathway [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Research [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>] has detected lower serum IL-33 levels in stable COPD patients than those with acute exacerbation. Serum IL-33 was negatively correlated with cardiovascular function, and was believed to have a certain impact on the clinical symptoms of COPD patients. A study has found [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>] that TSLP synthesized and secreted by airway epithelial cells is a key pro-inflammatory cytokine in chronic airway diseases, as well as a key factor and promoter of helper T cell 2 (Th2) type immune inflammatory response. Eosinophils (EOS) is a type of white blood cell and a sensitive marker of airway inflammation. Research has found [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>] that EOS is highly expressed during the onset of wheezing diseases such as sinusitis and asthma, and is closely related to prognosis. A study shows that about 40% of stable COPD patients are accompanied with EOS infiltration in the airways, which exerts an important role in the onset and progression of COPD. COPD patients with high EOS can quickly alleviate symptoms by using systemic hormones during the acute exacerbation phase, exhibiting clinical characteristics different from those of normal EOS patients [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>].</p><p id="Par15">In this study, the changes of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels in COPD patients were detected. The predictive value of those three indicators for treatment efficacy and outcome of COPD patients was valued, aiming to provide certain guidance strategies for the clinical treatment.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Materials and methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>General materials</title><p id="Par16">The retrospective analysis was conducted on 225 COPD patients (the COPD group) admitted in our hospital during October 2021 to September 2029. Inclusion criteria: (1) All patients met the diagnostic and treatment criteria of COPD [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>], and had been confirmed by imaging; (2) All patients did not use drugs such as glucocorticoids that might affect the research results in two months prior to participating in the study; (3) Patients had complete clinical data. Exclusion criteria: (1) Patients with lung disease or underdeveloped lung function; (2) Patients with cognitive dysfunction or abnormal mental state; (3) Patients with liver, kidney or heart dysfunction. Patients in the control group were 200 cases who underwent health checkups during the same period. These 176 males and 49 females in the COPD group aged 35–75 years, with the average age of (59.82 ± 9.26) years. Among them, 87 cases had smoking history, with a smoking index of (323.19 ± 50.49) years/tube; 146 males and 54 females aged (35–75) years formed the control group, with an average age of (60.06 ± 10.78) years. Among them, 66 cases had smoking history, with a smoking index of (317.74 ± 45.82) years/tube. The general information between the two groups had no significant difference (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &gt; 0.05).</p><p id="Par17">Patients were graded as the effective group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 102 cases, a decrease of no less than 2 points in COPD assessment test (CAT) score or a decrease of no less than 1 level in lung function grading) and the ineffective group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 123 cases, CAT score decreased below 2 points or lung function grading decreased below 1 level) according to the reduction of the CAT score after 1 week of treatment. The follow up lasted for 12 months after treatment. According to the occurrence of acute exacerbation, patients were divided into 104 cases in the acute exacerbation group (the patients’ clinical symptoms worsened beyond the daily range in a short period of time, who needed different therapies) and 121 cases in the non-acute exacerbation group. The algorithm for patient assignment was shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>.</p><p id="Par18">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>The selection process of general data</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e347" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12890_2026_4144_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Methods</title><p id="Par19">Methods of pulmonary function assessment: All patients with COPD were tested for pulmonary function by Jaeger MasterScreen spirometer during the stable period of admission (non-acute exacerbation). Forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV1) and forced vital capacity (FVC) were measured, and FEV1/FVC ratio and FEV1%pred were calculated. COPD severity was graded according to the Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease (GOLD) criteria: GOLD grade 1 (mild): FEV1/FVC &lt; 70% and FEV1%pred ≥ 80%; GOLD grade 2 (moderate): FEV1/FVC &lt; 70% and 50% ≤ FEV1%pred &lt; 80%; GOLD grade 3 (severe): FEV1/FVC &lt; 70% and 30% ≤ FEV1%pred &lt; 50%; GOLD grade 4 (very severe): FEV1/FVC &lt; 70% and FEV1%pred &lt; 30%.</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Blood sample collection</title><p id="Par20">For the following detection, 3 mL of elbow median venous blood was collected from each subject on an empty stomach for more than 8 h and placed in a vacuum anticoagulant tube containing potassium ethylenediaminetetraacetate for rest. The low-temperature high-speed centrifuge (Wuhan Kehaojia Biotechnology Co., Ltd., model: 5424R) was used to separate serum and blood cells. The supernatant of serum was collected carefully and stored in an ultra-low temperature refrigerator at -80℃ (Qingdao Haier Biomedical Co., Ltd., model: DW-86L828ST) for subsequent detection of serum indicators.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Outcome measures</title><p id="Par21">(1) IL-33 and TSLP levels were detected by Enzyme linked immunosorbent assay using the testing kits (Shanghai Jianglai Biotechnology Co., Ltd.) strictly following the instructions. (2) The serum EOS level was detected using a fully automated blood analyzer (Shanghai Jumu Medical Equipment Co., Ltd., model: MEK-7222 K). (3) The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves were employed to evaluate the predictive value of IL-33, TSLP, and EOS on COPD treatment efficacy and malignant risk.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Statistical analysis</title><p id="Par22">Data analysis was performed using SPSS 23.0 statistical software. Measurement data, such as IL-33, TSLP, and EOS, were represented by (‾<italic toggle="yes">x</italic> ± <italic toggle="yes">s</italic>), and inter group comparisons was conducted using t-tests. Enumeration data between groups were compared using <italic toggle="yes">χ</italic><sup><italic toggle="yes">2</italic></sup> tests and expressed as [cases (%)], with indicators including gender, smoking history, etc. The ROC curves were established for analyze the predictive value of IL-33, TSLP, and EOS on COPD treatment efficacy and malignant risk. To explore the independent predictive value of serum levels of IL-33, TSLP and EOS for the clinical outcomes of COPD, this study constructed a multivariate Logistic regression model. In brief, multivariable logistic regression analyses were performed with " ineffective treatment” and “exacerbation” as dependent variables (assignment: yes = 1, no = 0). The independent variables included were age, sex (assignment: male = 1, female = 0), smoking history (assignment: yes = 1, no = 0), baseline FEV1%pred (continuous variable), serum levels of IL-33, TSLP and EOS (all continuous variables). <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05 was considered as significant difference.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec12"><title>Baseline pulmonary function and general data characteristics of COPD patients in different groups</title><p id="Par23">The proportion of patients with severe to very severe pulmonary function (GOLD level 3 and 4) in the ineffective treatment group was significantly higher than that in the effective treatment group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>). FEV1/FVC ratio and FEV1%pred in the ineffective group were lower than those in the effective group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>). There were no significant differences in age, gender and smoking history between the two groups (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &gt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par24">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Baseline pulmonary function and general data characteristics of COPD patients in different groups</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Indicators</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Effective group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 102)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ineffective group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 123)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Value of statistics</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Acute exacerbation group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 104)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">non-acute exacerbation (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 121)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Value of statistics</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age (Year, ‾<italic toggle="yes">x</italic> ± <italic toggle="yes">s</italic>)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">59.56 ± 9.43</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60.08 ± 9.12</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t = 0.419, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.675</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">59.74 ± 9.35</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">59.91 ± 9.21</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t = 0.137, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.891</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Gender (Male/Female, N, %)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">80 (78.4) / 22 (21.6)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">96 (78.1) / 27 (21.9)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">χ²=0.005, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.945</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">82 (78.8) / 22 (21.2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">94 (77.7) / 27 (22.3)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">χ²=0.044, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.833</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Smoking history (Yes/No, N, %)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">36 (35.3) / 66 (64.7)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">51 (41.5) / 72 (58.5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">χ²=0.895, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.344</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40 (38.5) / 64 (61.5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">47 (38.8) / 74 (61.2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">χ²=0.004, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.953</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="7" rowspan="1">Pulmonary function characteristics</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="7" rowspan="1"> GOLD grade</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> Grade 2 (N, %)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">58 (56.9)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40 (32.5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">χ²=18.179, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">35 (33.7)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">63 (52.1)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">χ²=7.955, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> = 0.019</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> Grade 3 (N, %)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">41 (40.2)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">64 (52.0)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">56 (53.8)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">49 (40.5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> Grade 4 (N, %)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 (2.9)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19 (15.4)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13 (12.5)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9 (7.4)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> FEV1/FVC (%, ‾<italic toggle="yes">x</italic> ± <italic toggle="yes">s</italic>)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">56.81 ± 7.59</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">48.37 ± 8.21</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t = 7.942, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">47.65 ± 7.97</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">56.94 ± 8.15</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t = 8.612, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"> FEV1%pred (%, ‾<italic toggle="yes">x</italic> ± <italic toggle="yes">s</italic>)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">55.26 ± 10.84</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">42.33 ± 11.58</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t = 8.582, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">41.81 ± 10.79</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">53.64 ± 12.13</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t = 7.673, <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par25">In the comparison of the risk of acute exacerbation, the proportion of patients with severe to very severe pulmonary function impairment (grades 3 and 4) was significantly higher than that of the non-acute exacerbation group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>). FEV1/FVC ratio and FEV1%pred in acute exacerbation group were significantly lower than those in non-acute exacerbation group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>). There were no significant differences in age, gender and smoking history between the two groups (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &gt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels detection</title><p id="Par26">Compared with the control group, the serum levels of IL-33 and EOS were higher and TSLP were lower in the COPD group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001, Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>).</p><p id="Par27">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Analysis of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels in control group and COPD patients (‾<italic toggle="yes">x</italic> ± <italic toggle="yes">s</italic>)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The COPD group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 225)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The control group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 200)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IL-33 (pg/mL)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">317.40 ± 48.63</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">270.26 ± 71.47</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.023</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">TSLP (pg/L)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">177.08 ± 39.40</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">213.36 ± 68.42</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6.788</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">EOS (×10<sup>− 2</sup>)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.34 ± 2.25</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.29 ± 0.44</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37.392</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Analysis of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels in patients with different treatment effects</title><p id="Par28">In comparison with the effective group, the ineffective group had higher IL-33 and EOS content in the serum, and lower content of TSLP (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001, Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par29">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Analysis of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels in patients with different treatment effects (‾<italic toggle="yes">x</italic> ± <italic toggle="yes">s</italic>)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The effective group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 102)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">The ineffective group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 123)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IL-33 (pg/mL)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">287.28 ± 57.13</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">356.16 ± 61.20</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.660</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">TSLP (pg/L)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">192.77 ± 41.61</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">147.58 ± 46.85</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.574</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">EOS (×10<sup>− 2</sup>)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.11 ± 0.73</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.46 ± 1.42</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">40.894</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Analysis of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS content in patients with different deterioration risks</title><p id="Par30">Compared with non-acute exacerbation group, acute exacerbation group had higher content of IL-33 and EOS in serum, and lower TSLP content (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001, Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>).</p><p id="Par31">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Analysis of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels in patients with different deterioration risks (‾<italic toggle="yes">x</italic> ± <italic toggle="yes">s</italic>)</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Non-acute exacerbation group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 121)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Acute exacerbation group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 104)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IL-33 (pg/mL)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">302.40 ± 53.61</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">342.18 ± 63.25</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.106</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">TSLP (pg/L)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">182.08 ± 34.16</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">156.62 ± 28.66</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.999</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">EOS (×10<sup>− 2</sup>)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.25 ± 0.96</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.14 ± 1.27</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39.543</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.001</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>The predictive value of IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels for the therapeutic effect of COPD</title><p id="Par32">ROC curve analysis showed that the AUC of IL-33, TSLP, and EOS was 0.803, 0.778, and 0.870, respectively. The AUC of the combined detection was 0.938, indicating that the combined detection had higher predictive value in the evaluation of COPD treatment efficacy (Table <xref rid="Tab5" ref-type="table">5</xref>; Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).</p><p id="Par33">
<table-wrap id="Tab5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><p>The predictive value of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels for the therapeutic effect of COPD</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Indicators</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">AUC</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sensitivity (%)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Specificity (%)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cut-off value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Youden’s index</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">95% CI</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IL-33</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.803</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73.58</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71.08</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">320.30 pg/mL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.447</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.764–0.843</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">TSLP</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.778</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">67.89</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">77.45</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">169.37 pg/L</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.453</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.736–0.821</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">EOS</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.870</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">70.33</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">88.73</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.79 × 10<sup>− 2</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.591</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.838–0.902</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Combined detection</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.938</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">89.43</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">86.28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">—</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.757</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.817–0.959</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par34">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>The predictive value of ROC curve analysis of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels for COPD treatment efficacy</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1055" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12890_2026_4144_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>The predictive value of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels for the risk of exacerbation of COPD</title><p id="Par35">ROC curve analysis showed that the AUC of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS detected separately was 0.679, 0.716, and 0.891, while the AUC of combined detection was 0.931, indicating that the combination of the three indicators had higher clinical predictive value for evaluating the risk of COPD deterioration (Table <xref rid="Tab6" ref-type="table">6</xref>; Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par36">
<table-wrap id="Tab6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 6</label><caption><p>The predictive value of serum IL-33, TSLP, and EOS levels for the risk of exacerbation of COPD</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Indicators</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">AUC</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sensitivity (%)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Specificity (%)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cut-off value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Youden’s index</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">95%CI</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">IL-33</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.679</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">49.28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">81.74</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">315.29 pg/mL</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.310</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.630–0.729</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">TSLP</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.716</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">83.25</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">51.45</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">166.33 pg/L</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.347</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.669–0.763</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">EOS</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.891</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">78.47</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85.48</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.65 × 10<sup>− 2</sup></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.639</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.862–0.920</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Combined detection</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.931</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">83.73</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85.89</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">—</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.696</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.910–0.952</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par37">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>The predictive value of ROC curve serum IL-33, TSLP and EOS levels for the risk of exacerbation of COPD</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1170" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="12890_2026_4144_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec18"><title>Analysis of the influencing factors of ineffective treatment and exacerbation in COPD patients by multivariate Logistic regression</title><p id="Par38">The results showed that after adjusting for confounding factors such as age, sex, smoking status, and basic pulmonary function, elevated serum IL-33 and EOS levels were still independent risk factors for treatment failure (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05), but elevated TSLP level was a protective factor (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab7" ref-type="table">7</xref>). In terms of predicting the risk of acute exacerbation, the elevated EOS level was an independent risk factor (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001), and the independent predictive value of IL-33 and TSLP did not reach statistical significance (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &gt; 0.05, Table <xref rid="Tab7" ref-type="table">7</xref>).</p><p id="Par39">
<table-wrap id="Tab7" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 7</label><caption><p>Analysis of the influencing factors of ineffective treatment in COPD patients by multivariate logistic regression</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Indicators</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">β</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">SE</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Wald</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">OR</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>
</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">95%CI</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Serum IL-33</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.452</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.189</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.783</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.572</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.016</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.085–2.276</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">EOS levels</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.618</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.223</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.675</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.854</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.006</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.201–2.869</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">TSLP levels</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-0.387</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.172</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.098</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.680</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.024</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.479–0.966</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.021</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.015</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.960</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.021</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.162</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.992–1.051</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Gender (Male)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.258</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.316</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.669</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.294</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.413</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.712–2.353</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Smoking (Yes)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.412</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.305</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.836</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.510</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.175</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.852–2.669</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Basic lung function</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-0.012</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.008</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.250</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.988</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.134</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.973–1.003</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Serum IL-33</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.215</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.156</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.902</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.240</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.168</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.913–1.687</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">EOS levels</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.892</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.241</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13.659</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.441</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.000</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.583–3.762</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">TSLP levels</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-0.153</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.148</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.081</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.858</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.299</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.636–1.158</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.035</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.018</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.764</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.036</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.052</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.999–1.074</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Gender (Male)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.321</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.345</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.874</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.378</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.350</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.738–2.570</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Smoking (Yes)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.528</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.332</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.547</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.695</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.111</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.928–3.109</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Basic lung function</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">-0.018</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.009</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.000</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.982</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.045</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.965–0.999</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par40">This study, through a retrospective analysis of 225 COPD patients, found that serum IL-33 was significantly correlated with elevated EOS levels, decreased TSLP levels, treatment ineffectiveness, and increased risk of acute exacerbation. The combined detection of IL-33, TSLP and EOS demonstrated superior efficacy in predicting treatment response (AUC = 0.938) and risk of deterioration (AUC = 0.931). Multivariate Logistic regression analysis further confirmed that, after adjusting for traditional confounding factors, IL-33 and EOS were independent risk factors for treatment failure, while TSLP was a protective factor; EOS was also an independent risk factor for predicting acute exacerbation.</p><p id="Par41">Regarding IL-33, the results of this study showed that its level was elevated in the serum of COPD patients, and it was even higher in the treatment ineffective group. This finding was consistent with the conclusion reported by Joo H et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>] that the plasma IL-33 level in patients with acute exacerbation of COPD was elevated. IL-33, as an epithelial-derived alarm factor, is released by airway epithelial cells in response to damage factors such as smoke stimulation. IL-33, by activating the signaling pathway mediated by the ST2 receptor, drives type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) and Th2-type inflammatory responses, exacerbating airway mucus hypersecretion and tissue remodeling [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. After effective treatment, the level of IL-33 was decreased, which might be related to the reduction of epithelial damage and the competitive inhibition of soluble ST2 receptor [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. This study not only confirmed the correlation between IL-33 and the acute inflammatory state of the disease, but also further suggested that its baseline level might have predictive value for the initial treatment response, thereby expanding the clinical application scope of this indicator.</p><p id="Par42">Regarding TSLP, this study observed a notable phenomenon: the serum TSLP levels in patients with COPD who responded to treatment were actually higher than those in the non-responsive group. This was different from the widely recognized pro-inflammatory role of TSLP in typical Th2 diseases such as asthma. This difference may reveal the distinct immune-inflammatory microenvironment of COPD and asthma. The study by Hong H et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>] indicated that in certain combined airway diseases, TSLP may exert anti-inflammatory effects by inhibiting the NF-κB pathway. The study conducted by Moghoofei M et al. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>] also indicated that the level of TSLP in the sputum of COPD patients was associated with the degree of inflammation control. In COPD, the intense inflammation dominated by neutrophils may inversely inhibit the expression of TSLP. When the treatment takes effect and excessive inflammation is controlled, this inhibition weakens, and the potential protective functions of TSLP in tissue repair and immune regulation become apparent, thereby leading to an increase in its serum level [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. Therefore, serum TSLP may serve as a positive biological signal indicating that inflammation has been controlled and the repair mechanism has been initiated in COPD.</p><p id="Par43">Regarding EOS, this study confirmed that its serum level was significantly elevated in patients with treatment failure and acute exacerbation, and it was a strong independent risk factor for predicting acute exacerbation in the multivariate analysis. This was fully in line with the pathological and physiological understanding of EOS as a key effector cell in type 2 inflammation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>]. The IL-5 and eosinophil chemotactic factors produced in the airway inflammatory environment are key signals for bone marrow mobilization and tissue recruitment of EOS [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Effective treatments such as inhaled glucocorticoids can inhibit the production of these cytokines and promote the apoptosis of EOS, thereby reducing their levels in peripheral blood and airways [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. The results of this study once again emphasized the significance of peripheral blood eosinophil count in the classification of COPD phenotypes (such as the high eosinophil phenotype) and in prognosis assessment, supporting its use as a practical biomarker in clinical practice.</p><p id="Par44">This study evaluated a combined predictive model involving IL-33, TSLP and EOS, and found that its performance was significantly superior to that of any single indicator. After controlling for age, gender, smoking history and baseline lung function in the multivariate regression model, it was still confirmed that IL-33 and EOS made independent contributions to the treatment response, as well as to the acute exacerbation. This provided a comprehensive evaluation approach for clinical practice, integrating the markers of innate immunity (IL-33, TSLP) and adaptive immunity (EOS). Although some studies suggest that a single cytokine may have limitations as a biomarker [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>], numerous studies have shown that a multi-marker combined strategy can enhance the ability to differentiate or predict the prognosis of complex disease states (such as asthma-pulmonary hypertension overlap) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. The combined detection model constructed in this study was helpful for more accurately identifying the subgroups of COPD patients who responded poorly to conventional treatment and had a high risk of long-term deterioration, providing a basis for the early implementation of intensified or personalized interventions.</p><p id="Par45">The novelty of this study lied in the combined detection model of serum IL-33, TSLP and EOS, in predicting the therapeutic response and short-term deterioration risk of COPD. Compared to a single indicator, this combination may provide a more comprehensive view of the inflammatory activity. Through simple blood tests conducted at the time of admission, it was possible to assist in identifying high-risk patients and optimize treatment decisions. Furthermore, the study had clarified a unique pattern of the correlation between TSLP and treatment response in COPD, enriching our understanding of its complex biological role in non-asthmatic airway diseases.</p><p id="Par46">This study had several limitations. Firstly, the retrospective single-center design may introduce selection bias. The conclusion needs to be verified by multi-center prospective studies. Secondly, the sample size was limited, and the efficacy of subgroup analysis may be insufficient. Thirdly, the follow-up period was set at 12 months. The period was relatively short for assessing the long-term natural course and recurrent deterioration risks of COPD. Finally, the study only detected inflammatory markers in peripheral blood and failed to simultaneously obtain local samples such as sputum or bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, thus unable to directly reflect the inflammatory state of the airway microenvironment. In the future, studies that are forward-looking, have large sample sizes, long follow-up periods, and integrate multiple-dimensional biomarkers are needed to further validate and refine the findings of this research.</p></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par47">In general, patients in treatment ineffective group and acute exacerbation group had higher IL-33, EOS levels and lower TSLP levels. These above indicators could serve as important indicators for predicting the treatment effect and deterioration risk of COPD, and combined detection had high sensitivity and specificity.</p></sec></body><back><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>TSLP</term><def><p id="Par5">Thymic stromal lymphopoietin</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>IL-33</term><def><p id="Par6">Interleukin-33</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>COPD</term><def><p id="Par7">Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>CAT</term><def><p id="Par8">COPD Assessment Test</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>ROC</term><def><p id="Par9">Receiver Operating Characteristic</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>AUC</term><def><p id="Par10">Area under the curve</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>EOS</term><def><p id="Par11">Eosinophils</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>FeNO</term><def><p id="Par12">Fractional exhaled nitric oxide</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>None.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Authors’ contributions</title><p>Jie Xu confirmed the authenticity of all the raw data and edited the manuscript, Jie Xu and Yong Wang collected data and processed the data. Haitong Gu and Xiao Chen conducted the statistics. Xiao Chen reviewed and revised the article. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>None.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The datasets used and/or analyzed during the current study are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar6"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par48">This study was approved by The Ethics Committee of Beijing Tongren Hospital, Capital Medical University.</p><p id="Par49"> Informed consent was obtained from participants for the participation in the study and all methods were carried out in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations.</p></notes><notes id="FPar7"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par50">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar8" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par51">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Corlateanu</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mendez</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and phenotypes: a state-of-the-art</article-title><source>Pulmonology</source><year>2020</year><volume>26</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>95</fpage><lpage>100</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2019.10.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31740261</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Corlateanu A, Mendez Y, Wang Y, et al. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and phenotypes: a state-of-the-art. Pulmonology. 2020;26(2):95–100.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31740261</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2019.10.006</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Analyses of factors associated with acute exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A review</article-title><source>Int J Chronic Obstr Pulm Dis</source><year>2023</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>2707</fpage><lpage>23</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/COPD.S433183</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10683659</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38034468</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Qian Y, Cai C, Sun M, et al. Analyses of factors associated with acute exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: A review. Int J Chronic Obstr Pulm Dis. 2023;18:2707–23.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/COPD.S433183</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10683659</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38034468</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alkhathlan</surname><given-names>BS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barradell</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Greening</surname><given-names>NJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Real-time experience of an acute exacerbation of COPD: A qualitative exploration</article-title><source>Chron Respir Dis</source><year>2025</year><volume>22</volume><fpage>14799731251340407</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/14799731251340407</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40359900</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12075960</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Alkhathlan BS, Barradell AC, Greening NJ, et al. Real-time experience of an acute exacerbation of COPD: A qualitative exploration. Chron Respir Dis. 2025;22:14799731251340407.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40359900</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/14799731251340407</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12075960</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Paplinska-Goryca M, Misiukiewicz-Stepien P, Proboszcz M et al. The expressions of TSLP, IL-33, and IL-17A in monocyte derived dendritic cells from asthma and COPD patients are related to Epithelial-Macrophage interactions. Cells. 2020;9(9).<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/cells9091944</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7565129</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32842623</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Predictive value of serum interleukin-33 and thymic stromal lymphopoietin for the risk of acute exacerbation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</article-title><source>Front Med (Lausanne)</source><year>2025</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>1592734</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fmed.2025.1592734</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41048933</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12488408</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Yin S, Xu K, Wu S, et al. Predictive value of serum interleukin-33 and thymic stromal lymphopoietin for the risk of acute exacerbation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Front Med (Lausanne). 2025;12:1592734.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41048933</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fmed.2025.1592734</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12488408</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moermans</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Damas</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guiot</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Sputum IL-25, IL-33 and TSLP, IL-23 and IL-36 in airway obstructive diseases. Reduced levels of IL-36 in eosinophilic phenotype</article-title><source>Cytokine</source><year>2021</year><volume>140</volume><fpage>155421</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.cyto.2021.155421</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33486314</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Moermans C, Damas K, Guiot J, et al. Sputum IL-25, IL-33 and TSLP, IL-23 and IL-36 in airway obstructive diseases. Reduced levels of IL-36 in eosinophilic phenotype. Cytokine. 2021;140:155421.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33486314</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.cyto.2021.155421</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Eosinophils correlate with Epithelial-Mesenchymal transition in chronic rhinosinusitis with nasal polyps</article-title><source>Its Relat Specialties</source><year>2022</year><volume>84</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>70</fpage><lpage>80</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1159/000516847</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34229321</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Wang M, Sun Y, Li C, et al. Eosinophils correlate with Epithelial-Mesenchymal transition in chronic rhinosinusitis with nasal polyps. Its Relat Specialties. 2022;84(1):70–80. ORL; journal for oto-rhino-laryngology.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1159/000516847</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34229321</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pham</surname><given-names>DD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>JY</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Different impacts of blood and sputum eosinophil counts on lung function and clinical outcomes in asthma: findings from the COREA cohort</article-title><source>Lung</source><year>2022</year><volume>200</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>697</fpage><lpage>706</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00408-022-00583-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36264333</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Pham DD, Lee JH, Kim JY, et al. Different impacts of blood and sputum eosinophil counts on lung function and clinical outcomes in asthma: findings from the COREA cohort. Lung. 2022;200(6):697–706.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36264333</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s00408-022-00583-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Trudo</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kallenbach</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vasey</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Clinical and economic burden of eosinophilic COPD in A large retrospective US cohort</article-title><source>Int J Chronic Obstr Pulm Dis</source><year>2019</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>2625</fpage><lpage>37</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/COPD.S220009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6884975</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32063703</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Trudo F, Kallenbach L, Vasey J, et al. Clinical and economic burden of eosinophilic COPD in A large retrospective US cohort. Int J Chronic Obstr Pulm Dis. 2019;14:2625–37.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/COPD.S220009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6884975</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32063703</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hopkinson</surname><given-names>NS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Molyneux</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pink</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: diagnosis and management: summary of updated NICE guidance</article-title><source>BMJ (Clinical Res ed)</source><year>2019</year><volume>366</volume><fpage>l4486</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.l4486</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31358491</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Hopkinson NS, Molyneux A, Pink J, et al. Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: diagnosis and management: summary of updated NICE guidance. BMJ (Clinical Res ed). 2019;366:l4486.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bmj.l4486</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31358491</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Joo</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Min</surname><given-names>KH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Association between plasma interleukin-33 level and acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</article-title><source>BMC Pulm Med</source><year>2021</year><volume>21</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>86</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12890-021-01423-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33722239</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7962403</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Joo H, Park SJ, Min KH, et al. Association between plasma interleukin-33 level and acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. BMC Pulm Med. 2021;21(1):86.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33722239</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12890-021-01423-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7962403</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mathioudakis</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Janssens</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sivapalan</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Acute exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: in search of diagnostic biomarkers and treatable traits</article-title><source>Thorax</source><year>2020</year><volume>75</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>520</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2019-214484</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32217784</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7279206</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Mathioudakis AG, Janssens W, Sivapalan P, et al. Acute exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: in search of diagnostic biomarkers and treatable traits. Thorax. 2020;75(6):520–7.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32217784</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2019-214484</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7279206</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fanny</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nascimento</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baron</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The IL-33 receptor ST2 regulates pulmonary inflammation and fibrosis to bleomycin</article-title><source>Front Immunol</source><year>2018</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>1476</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2018.01476</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29988569</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6026799</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Fanny M, Nascimento M, Baron L, et al. The IL-33 receptor ST2 regulates pulmonary inflammation and fibrosis to bleomycin. Front Immunol. 2018;9:1476.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29988569</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fimmu.2018.01476</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6026799</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hailey</surname><given-names>KL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vitorino</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Cigarette smoke triggers IL-33-associated inflammation in a model of Late-Stage chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</article-title><source>Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol</source><year>2019</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>567</fpage><lpage>74</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1165/rcmb.2018-0402OC</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30973786</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6827064</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Lee JH, Hailey KL, Vitorino SA, et al. Cigarette smoke triggers IL-33-associated inflammation in a model of Late-Stage chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2019;61(5):567–74.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30973786</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1165/rcmb.2018-0402OC</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6827064</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tao</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Type 2 innate lymphoid cells participate in IL-33-stimulated Th2-associated immune response in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</article-title><source>Exp Ther Med</source><year>2019</year><volume>18</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>3109</fpage><lpage>16</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31572551</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3892/etm.2019.7924</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6755436</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Jiang M, Tao S, Zhang S, et al. Type 2 innate lymphoid cells participate in IL-33-stimulated Th2-associated immune response in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Exp Ther Med. 2019;18(4):3109–16.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31572551</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3892/etm.2019.7924</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6755436</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Role of IL-25, IL-33, and TSLP in triggering united airway diseases toward type 2 inflammation</article-title><source>Allergy</source><year>2020</year><volume>75</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>2794</fpage><lpage>804</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/all.14526</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32737888</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Hong H, Liao S, Chen F, et al. Role of IL-25, IL-33, and TSLP in triggering united airway diseases toward type 2 inflammation. Allergy. 2020;75(11):2794–804.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32737888</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/all.14526</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moghoofei</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Azimzadeh Jamalkandi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moein</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Bacterial infections in acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Infection</source><year>2020</year><volume>48</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>35</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s15010-019-01350-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31482316</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Moghoofei M, Azimzadeh Jamalkandi S, Moein M, et al. Bacterial infections in acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infection. 2020;48(1):19–35.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31482316</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s15010-019-01350-1</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murrison</surname><given-names>LB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Preusse</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>TSLP disease-associated genetic variants combined with airway TSLP expression influence asthma risk</article-title><source>J Allergy Clin Immunol</source><year>2022</year><volume>149</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>79</fpage><lpage>88</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2021.05.033</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34111451</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9119142</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Murrison LB, Ren X, Preusse K, et al. TSLP disease-associated genetic variants combined with airway TSLP expression influence asthma risk. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2022;149(1):79–88.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34111451</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jaci.2021.05.033</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9119142</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Research progress of serum eosinophil in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and asthma</article-title><source>Open Life Sci</source><year>2023</year><volume>18</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>20220779</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1515/biol-2022-0779</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38077793</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10710216</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Wu C. Research progress of serum eosinophil in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and asthma. Open Life Sci. 2023;18(1):20220779.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38077793</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1515/biol-2022-0779</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10710216</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Portel</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fabry-Vendrand</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Texier</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Characteristics of severe Non-Eosinophilic asthma: analysis of data from 1075 patients included in the FASE-CPHG study</article-title><source>J Asthma Allergy</source><year>2023</year><volume>16</volume><fpage>9</fpage><lpage>21</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2147/JAA.S375325</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36628339</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9826639</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Portel L, Fabry-Vendrand C, Texier N, et al. Characteristics of severe Non-Eosinophilic asthma: analysis of data from 1075 patients included in the FASE-CPHG study. J Asthma Allergy. 2023;16:9–21.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36628339</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/JAA.S375325</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9826639</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Inhibition of CREB promotes glucocorticoids action on airway inflammation in pediatric asthma by promoting ferroptosis of eosinophils</article-title><source>Allergol Immunopathol (Madr)</source><year>2023</year><volume>51</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>164</fpage><lpage>74</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.15586/aei.v51i4.873</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37422794</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Yu T, Yu Y, Ma Y, et al. Inhibition of CREB promotes glucocorticoids action on airway inflammation in pediatric asthma by promoting ferroptosis of eosinophils. Allergol Immunopathol (Madr). 2023;51(4):164–74.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37422794</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15586/aei.v51i4.873</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jogdand P, Siddhuraj P, Mori M, et al. Eosinophils, basophils and type 2 immune microenvironments in COPD-affected lung tissue. Eur Respir J. 2020;55(5):1900110. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1183/13993003.00110-2019</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7236868</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32060064</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lv</surname><given-names>MY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Qiang</surname><given-names>LX</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>ZH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The lower the eosinophils, the stronger the inflammatory response? The relationship of different levels of eosinophils with the degree of inflammation in acute exacerbation chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD)</article-title><source>J Thorac Dis</source><year>2021</year><volume>13</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>232</fpage><lpage>43</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.21037/jtd-20-2178</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33569203</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7867852</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Lv MY, Qiang LX, Li ZH, et al. The lower the eosinophils, the stronger the inflammatory response? The relationship of different levels of eosinophils with the degree of inflammation in acute exacerbation chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (AECOPD). J Thorac Dis. 2021;13(1):232–43.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33569203</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.21037/jtd-20-2178</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7867852</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Połomska J, Sikorska-Szaflik H, Drabik-Chamerska A, et al. Exploring TSLP and IL-33 serum levels and genetic variants: unveiling their limited potential as biomarkers for mild asthma in children. J Clin Med. 2024;13(9):2542. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/jcm13092542</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11084404</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38731070</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Serum interleukin-33 combined with FEF75% z-score and FeNO improves the diagnostic accuracy of asthma in children</article-title><source>J Pediatr (Rio J)</source><year>2024</year><volume>100</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>81</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jped.2023.08.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37741632</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10751693</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Yang Q, Zheng Y, Dong J, et al. Serum interleukin-33 combined with FEF75% z-score and FeNO improves the diagnostic accuracy of asthma in children. J Pediatr (Rio J). 2024;100(1):81–7.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37741632</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jped.2023.08.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10751693</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hirano</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsunaga</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sugiura</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Relationship between alveolar nitric oxide concentration in exhaled air and small airway function in COPD</article-title><source>J Breath Res</source><year>2013</year><volume>7</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>046002</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1088/1752-7155/7/4/046002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24091810</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Hirano T, Matsunaga K, Sugiura H, et al. Relationship between alveolar nitric oxide concentration in exhaled air and small airway function in COPD. J Breath Res. 2013;7(4):046002.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24091810</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1088/1752-7155/7/4/046002</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>