<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Craniofac Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Craniofac Surg</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2035</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">lwwopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">SCS</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>The Journal of Craniofacial Surgery</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1049-2275</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-3732</issn><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-is-collection-domain</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-collection-title</meta-name><meta-value>Lippincott Open Access</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12928772</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12928772.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12928772</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12928772</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41108327</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/SCS.0000000000012060</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">SCS-25-0871</article-id><article-version-alternatives><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-version article-version-type="Version of Record" vocab="JAV" vocab-identifier="http://www.niso.org/publications/rp/RP-8-2008.pdf">3</article-version></article-version-alternatives><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Articles</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>The Development and Validation of CranioFix: An Augmented-Reality Biomodel for Craniomaxillofacial Education</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Al-Shaqsi</surname><given-names initials="S">Sultan</given-names></name><degrees>MBChB, PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">*</xref><email>drsultanalshaqsi@gmail.com</email></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Teshima</surname><given-names initials="TL">Tara L.</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">†</xref><email>taralynnteshima@gmail.com</email></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names initials="G">Glenn</given-names></name><degrees>M.Arch</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">†</xref><email>glenn@calaverasurgicaldesign.com</email></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Antonyshyn</surname><given-names initials="O">Oleh</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">†</xref><email>oantonyshyn@rogers.com</email></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1">
<label>*</label>Khoula Hospital, Ministry of Health, Sultanate of Oman</aff><aff id="aff2">
<label>†</label>Division of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada</aff><author-notes><corresp>Address correspondence and reprint requests to Sultan Al-Shaqsi, MBChB, PhD, Khoula Hospital, Ministry of Health, Sultanate of Oman. Mina Al-Fahal, Muscat, Sultanate of Oman; E-mail: <email>drsultanalshaqsi@gmail.com</email>
</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><season>Mar-Apr</season><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>17</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>37</volume><issue>3-4</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">508181</issue-id><fpage>506</fpage><lpage>510</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>22</day><month>6</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>1</day><month>9</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>23</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>24</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-02-24 16:25:13.537"><day>24</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright © 2025 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of Mutaz B. Habal, MD.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-No Derivatives License 4.0</ext-link> (CCBY-NC-ND), where it is permissible to download and share the work provided it is properly cited. The work cannot be changed in any way or used commercially without permission from the journal.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="scs-37-0506.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="scs-37-0506.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>Objective:</title><p>To describe the development, implementation, and validation of CranioFix, an augmented-reality (AR)-enhanced educational toolkit for the training of craniomaxillofacial trauma management, specifically orbit-zygomatic complex (OZC) fractures.</p></sec><sec><title>Background:</title><p>Surgical training in craniomaxillofacial trauma presents significant challenges due to the complexity of the anatomy, limited exposure to trauma cases, and the need for hands-on technical skill acquisition. Augmented-reality simulation technologies offer a promising solution to these limitations.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods:</title><p>CranioFix was developed as a hybrid AR and physical simulation model consisting of a 3D-printed skull with realistic tissue overlays, integrated surgical instruments, and a smartphone-based AR application. The app provides guided surgical instruction, anatomic overlays, and self-assessment tools. A validation study involving 15 surgeons and surgical trainees was conducted in a war-zone mission setting.</p></sec><sec><title>Results:</title><p>Participants reported significant improvement in confidence levels for OZC trauma management (mean precourse 3.2/10 versus postcourse 6.3/10). The educational content received high ratings for usefulness (9.1/10), interactivity (8.3/10), and overall design (8.2/10). All participants endorsed CranioFix as a valuable training tool and recommended its expansion to other craniofacial procedures.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion:</title><p>CranioFix is an effective, portable, and scalable AR-based simulation platform that enhances surgical training in craniomaxillofacial trauma. It is particularly valuable in resource-constrained or disrupted settings and has the potential for wide application in global surgical education.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><title>Key Words:</title><kwd>AR</kwd><kwd>augmented reality</kwd><kwd>craniomaxillofacial</kwd><kwd>education</kwd><kwd>orbit</kwd><kwd>simulation</kwd><kwd>trauma</kwd><kwd>zygoma</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>Craniomaxillofacial surgery requires advanced anatomic knowledge, spatial reasoning, and procedural precision to manage the intricate structures of the face and skull. Among its most technically demanding procedures is the management of facial trauma, including orbito-zygomatic complex (OZC) fractures. These injuries disrupt the structural and esthetic harmony of the midface, often requiring multivector fracture reduction and internal fixation. Surgical training in this area is challenging, not only because of the steep learning curve, but also due to the rarity and variability of complex trauma cases.</p><p>Traditional surgical education has relied heavily on the apprenticeship model, which is increasingly limited by time constraints, ethical considerations, and variability in clinical exposure. This problem is particularly pronounced in low-resource settings and conflict zones, where access to surgical mentors and live operative opportunities is scarce. The need for a scalable, cost-effective, and high-fidelity training solution has never been more urgent.</p><p>Simulation-based surgical education has emerged as a critical adjunct to clinical training, with benefits including hands-on practice, reduced patient risk, and structured competency assessment. Technologies such as virtual reality (VR), augmented reality (AR), and mixed reality (MR) have been integrated into craniofacial surgical education with promising results. VR systems have demonstrated utility in orthognathic planning and procedural walkthroughs; however, they often lack tactile realism and can be prohibitively expensive.<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup>
</p><p>Augmented reality, by contrast, allows for an interactive overlay of digital content on physical models, thereby combining visual instruction with tactile engagement. Several AR applications have been explored in craniomaxillofacial surgery. For example, Guo et al<sup><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> developed an interactive AR platform to guide midface fracture reduction. Ruggiero et al<sup><xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> validated an AR-assisted tool for preoperative planning in pediatric craniofacial surgery. Stucki et al<sup><xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref></sup> reviewed multiple AR systems used in maxillofacial surgical navigation and education. While these tools have demonstrated strong potential, most remain limited to preoperative visualization or academic research environments. Very few are designed for hands-on simulation or surgical training in remote or disrupted contexts.</p><p>This gap in applied AR simulation motivated the development of CranioFix, a hybrid educational platform combining a 3D-printed facial fracture model with an integrated smartphone-based AR application. The project aimed to provide a portable and realistic simulator for OZC fracture repair. The model is designed to provide guided instruction and self-assessment without the need for expert supervision. Furthermore, it enables training in austere or disrupted environments, including war zones, where traditional teaching models are not feasible.</p><p>This article describes the design, development, and initial validation of CranioFix, implemented during a humanitarian surgical mission in Ukraine. The tool’s performance was evaluated in terms of user satisfaction, impact on learner confidence, and applicability in diverse training environments.</p><sec sec-type="methods"><title>METHODS</title><sec sec-type="intro"><title>Overview of Educational System Design</title><p>CranioFix is a hybrid augmented-reality (AR) and biophysical simulation platform developed for the surgical education of craniomaxillofacial trauma, focusing on orbito-zygomatic complex (OZC) fractures. The system was designed to address key barriers in surgical training—limited operative exposure, geographic disparities, and inconsistent access to mentorship—by providing a portable, self-directed, and interactive learning experience.</p><p>Its educational design was grounded in the principles of deliberate practice, as described by Ericsson et al,<sup><xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> which emphasize repetitive skill execution, structured feedback, and progressively challenging tasks to build surgical proficiency. It also follows a mastery learning framework, ensuring that users demonstrate competence before progressing to more advanced stages.</p><p>CranioFix consists of 3 integrated components:<list list-type="order"><list-item><p>A high-fidelity physical fracture model with realistic anatomic features.</p></list-item><list-item><p>A smartphone-based AR application that provides instructional overlays and self-assessment.</p></list-item><list-item><p>A comprehensive toolkit with analog surgical instruments and fixation hardware.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>The system was developed with modularity and scalability in mind, enabling use in both structured classroom environments and independent, remote settings.</p></sec><sec><title>Biophysical Fracture Model Fabrication</title><p>The physical model was based on anonymized CT scan data of a 26-year-old male with a right-sided OZC fracture. Using Rhinoceros 3D (McNeel &amp; Associates, USA), the craniofacial skeleton was segmented, modified, and digitally reconstructed to reflect fracture morphology and facilitate component-based manufacturing.<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>3D printing:</p><p>Skeletal and support components were printed using Fused Deposition Modeling (FDM) on Zortrax M200 printers (Zortrax, Poland). Acrylonitrile Butadiene Styrene (ABS) was selected for its strength, machinability, and cost-effectiveness.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Soft tissue simulation:</p><p>The overlying facial soft tissues, intraorbital contents, and muscular planes were cast using Smooth-On Dragon Skin platinum-cured silicone (Shore A hardness: 10). This provided realistic elasticity for incisions, retraction, and dissection.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Assembly: The model was modular, enabling partial disassembly for repair, and featured interlocking skeletal elements designed to simulate real-life fracture alignment and reduction mechanics.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>(Fig. <xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">1</xref> illustrates the exploded view of the model components; Fig. <xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> shows the fully assembled system.)</p><fig position="float" id="F1" orientation="portrait"><label>FIGURE 1</label><caption><p>The components of the physical model in CranioFix.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="scs-37-0506-g001.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F2" orientation="portrait"><label>FIGURE 2</label><caption><p>The underlying facial skeleton is associated with its skin envelope.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="scs-37-0506-g002.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Augmented Reality Application (CranioFix App)</title><p>The AR application was developed using Unity 3D and Vuforia Engine SDK, ensuring compatibility with iOS devices (iPhone and iPad). The app integrates with the physical model through fiducial markers printed on the baseplate, enabling automatic real-time registration of digital overlays to anatomic regions.</p><p>The app features eight sequential modules guiding users through the full management of an OZC fracture:<list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Case launch and clinical scenario</p><p>A trauma case is launched using a QR code. The scenario includes history, mechanism of injury, and presenting signs.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Anatomy review</p><p>Skin, subcutaneous, and skeletal landmarks are overlaid onto the model, with interactive toggling. These overlays dynamically adjust based on camera position and distance.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Diagnosis module</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Clinical: Simulates examination findings (eg, enophthalmos and step deformity).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Radiologic: Interactive DICOM-style CT viewer with highlighted fracture lines and learning points.</p></list-item></list></list-item><list-item><p>Operative planning</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Preoperative checklists (eg, antibiotics, consent).</p></list-item><list-item><p>AR-guided incision mapping (blepharoplasty, mid-lid, and buccal sulcus).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Animated incision demonstrations for each exposure.</p></list-item></list></list-item><list-item><p>Surgical execution</p><p>Users make simulated incisions on the silicone layer, perform tissue elevation, and reduce the fracture using the interlocking bone model. Tactile feedback mimics resistance and alignment forces.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Fixation module</p><p>AR overlays indicate recommended plate positions and screw configurations. A library of plate shapes and bending suggestions is included.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Postoperative management</p><p>Guidance is provided on swelling control, vision monitoring, imaging, and complication avoidance.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Assessment and feedback</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>Users complete multiple-choice quizzes and may record their performance for expert feedback. The app is structured to allow progression only after module completion, reinforcing mastery learning.</p><p>(Screenshots of modules are included in Figs. <xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>–<xref rid="F5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>.)</p><fig position="float" id="F3" orientation="portrait"><label>FIGURE 3</label><caption><p>The complete set of the physical model in CranioFix.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="scs-37-0506-g003.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F4" orientation="portrait"><label>FIGURE 4</label><caption><p>The skin overlay with marked incisions projected over the physical model.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="scs-37-0506-g004.jpg"/></fig><fig position="float" id="F5" orientation="portrait"><label>FIGURE 5</label><caption><p>The use of the CranioFix toolkit by trainees in Ukraine.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="scs-37-0506-g005.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Surgical Instrumentation Kit</title><p>A surgical simulation kit was included to replicate standard trauma instrumentation:<list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Manual tools: Scalpels, malleable retractors, periosteal elevators, skin hooks.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Powered instruments: Rechargeable handheld drill with multiple burr sizes.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Fixation tools: Miniature screws, orbital implants, bending pliers, and screwdrivers (sized to the 3D model).</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>The kit enables trainees to engage in a full hands-on reconstruction workflow, including dissection, reduction, and osteosynthesis.</p></sec><sec><title>Validation Study</title><sec><title>Setting and Participants</title><p>A pilot validation study was conducted in May 2023 at the Lutsk Surgical Skills Lab in Ukraine, during a humanitarian surgical education mission. The setting was selected due to disruptions in conventional surgical training following the Russian invasion, creating an urgent need for portable and autonomous learning systems.<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Participants (n=15):</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Eight plastic surgery trainees.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Two board-certified plastic surgeons.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Two head and neck surgeons.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Two oral and maxillofacial surgeons.</p></list-item><list-item><p>One ophthalmologist.</p></list-item></list></list-item><list-item><p>Participant profile:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Mean age: 38.9 years (range: 23–58).</p></list-item><list-item><p>88.2% treated 50 to 100 facial fractures annually.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Thirty-three treated ≥10 OZC fractures per year.</p></list-item></list></list-item></list>
</p></sec><sec><title>Evaluation Tools and Metrics</title><p>Participants completed structured surveys before and after the training session using a 10-point Likert scale. Metrics included:<list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Self-rated confidence in OZC fracture diagnosis and management.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Usefulness and content quality.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Interactivity and realism of simulation.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Visual and AR overlay quality.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Willingness to reuse and recommend the system.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>Open-ended comments were also collected for qualitative analysis of strengths, limitations, and recommendations for improvement.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>RESULTS</title><sec sec-type="subjects"><title>Participant Demographics</title><p>A total of 15 participants completed the validation workshop. The cohort included:<list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Eight plastic surgery trainees (53%).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Two board-certified plastic surgeons (13%).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Two head and neck surgeons (13%).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Two oral and maxillofacial surgeons (13%).</p></list-item><list-item><p>One ophthalmologist (7%).</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>The mean participant age was 38.9 years (range 23–58 y). A majority (88.2%) reported managing between 50 and 100 facial trauma cases annually. Notably, 5 to 10 of these cases were estimated to involve OZC fractures, suggesting substantial clinical exposure among participants.</p></sec><sec><title>Quantitative Outcomes</title><p>Pretraining and post-training comparisons demonstrated measurable improvements in user confidence and strong endorsements of the CranioFix platform:<table-wrap position="anchor" id="TU1" orientation="portrait"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><col align="left" width="1*" span="1"/><col align="left" width="1*" span="1"/><col align="left" width="1*" span="1"/><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Evaluation metric</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Mean score (pre)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Mean score (post)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Confidence in diagnosing and managing OZC</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• 3.2 / 10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• 6.3 / 10</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p>Participants also rated specific elements of the CranioFix platform on a 10-point Likert scale:<table-wrap position="anchor" id="TU2" orientation="portrait"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><col align="left" width="1*" span="1"/><col align="left" width="1*" span="1"/><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Parameter</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Mean score (out of 10)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Usefulness of educational content</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• 9.1</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Interactivity of simulation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• 8.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Visual quality of AR overlays</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• 7.8</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Realism and tactile feedback</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• 8.2</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• Likelihood to recommend to peers</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">• 10.0</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p>All 15 participants indicated that they would recommend CranioFix to colleagues, and 93% expressed interest in using expanded modules for other craniofacial procedures (eg, orbital tumors, post-traumatic enophthalmos, and Le Fort injuries).</p></sec><sec><title>Qualitative Feedback</title><p>Open-ended survey responses highlighted several recurring themes:</p><p>Value in disrupted settings:<list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>“This would be extremely useful in places where there are no cadaver labs or limited faculty.”</p><p>App-enhanced learning:</p></list-item><list-item><p>“The step-by-step AR guidance makes the procedure much easier to understand and practice.”</p><p>Feedback and assessment potential:</p></list-item><list-item><p>“It’s very helpful to record and review my steps. I can see what I missed.”</p><p>Suggestions for future development:</p></list-item><list-item><p>“Please include modules for cranial vault reconstruction and panfacial trauma.”</p></list-item><list-item><p>Participants praised the real-world applicability of the simulation, noting that the combined use of tactile feedback and dynamic visual instruction provided a uniquely immersive learning experience.</p></list-item></list>
</p></sec><sec><title>Instructor Observations</title><p>Faculty members overseeing the workshop noted several positive instructional trends:<list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Rapid learner engagement: Participants required minimal orientation to begin using the tool effectively, indicating an intuitive design.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Tactile reinforcement: Learners adjusted incisions and fixation technique based on tactile feedback, demonstrating kinesthetic learning.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Team leadership and collaboration skills. At least 2 surgeons are required to expose, reduce, and fix the fracture. Pairs of learners developed skills optimizing team dynamics in completing simulated fracture repair.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Peer teaching effect: Several participants spontaneously taught others, reinforcing the system’s potential for decentralized education.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>The ability of the tool to enable both structured instruction and self-directed learning was seen as a major strength, particularly in the humanitarian and conflict-zone context in which the validation occurred.</p></sec></sec><sec><title>CONCLUSION AND FUTURE DIRECTIONS</title><p>CranioFix is a novel, hybrid educational platform that merges physical simulation with augmented reality to provide high-fidelity training in craniomaxillofacial trauma surgery. Its development responds to a critical global need for accessible, scalable, and realistic training tools—particularly in environments where operative exposure is limited or disrupted, such as conflict zones and under-resourced regions.<sup><xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup>
</p><p>Validation of the system in a humanitarian mission setting demonstrated that CranioFix significantly improves learner confidence, is well received across multiple surgical specialties, and supports both independent learning and instructor-guided sessions. Its intuitive design, tactile realism, and visual interactivity were consistently rated highly by users, highlighting its potential to enhance surgical education in both academic and field-based environments.<sup><xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>–<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup>
</p><sec><title>Future Directions</title><p>The success of the initial implementation opens several avenues for further development:<list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Procedure library expansion:</p><p>Future modules will include other craniofacial procedures such as:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Orbital floor reconstruction</p></list-item><list-item><p>Cranial vault remodeling (eg, for craniosynostosis).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Le Fort fractures</p></list-item><list-item><p>Post-traumatic enophthalmos and nasoethmoidal injuries.</p></list-item></list></list-item><list-item><p>AI integration for skill assessment:</p><p>A next-generation version of the app will include AI-driven analytics to evaluate surgical technique, hand movements, incision placement, and fixation accuracy using device-based video capture. This will enable automated, objective feedback and personalized learning pathways.<sup><xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup>
</p></list-item><list-item><p>Smart-glasses AR deployment:</p><p>Development is underway to port the platform to wearable AR devices (eg, Microsoft HoloLens, Magic Leap), allowing hands-free interaction and potential intraoperative utility.<sup><xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup>
</p></list-item><list-item><p>Formal educational trials:</p><p>Controlled studies will be conducted to compare CranioFix training outcomes against traditional teaching modalities, with a focus on long-term retention, procedural accuracy, and learner satisfaction.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Global Dissemination and Localization:</p></list-item></list>
</p><p>Translation of app content and adaptation of facial models to reflect regional anatomic and ethnic variations will facilitate broader international deployment, particularly in Asia, the Middle East, and Africa.</p><p>By combining innovative technology with educational best practices, CranioFix has the potential to democratize access to high-quality surgical training and contribute meaningfully to capacity building in global surgical systems.</p></sec></sec></body><back><ack><sec><title>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</title><p>
<italic toggle="yes">This project is generously supported by the Royal College of Canada International Development, Aid and Collaboration Grant and The Temetry Foundation through the Sunnybrook Foundation</italic>.</p></sec></ack><fn-group><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ericsson</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Krampe</surname><given-names>RT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tesch-Römer</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>The role of deliberate practice in the acquisition of expert performance</article-title>. <source>Psychol Rev</source>
<year>1993</year>;<volume>100</volume>:<fpage>363</fpage>–<lpage>406</lpage>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>McGaghie</surname><given-names>WC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Issenberg</surname><given-names>SB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>ER</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Medical education featuring mastery learning with deliberate practice can lead to better health for individuals and populations</article-title>. <source>Acad Med</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>86</volume>:<fpage>e8</fpage>–<lpage>e9</lpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22030671</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1097/ACM.0b013e3182308d37</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>McGaghie</surname><given-names>WC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Issenberg</surname><given-names>SB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Barsuk</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>A critical review of simulation-based mastery learning with translational outcomes</article-title>. <source>Med Educ</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>48</volume>:<fpage>375</fpage>–<lpage>385</lpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24606621</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/medu.12391</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kaplan</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Marques</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Scharf</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Virtual reality and augmented reality in plastic and craniomaxillofacial surgery: a scoping review</article-title>. <source>Bioengineering</source>
<year>2023</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<fpage>480</fpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37106667</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/bioengineering10040480</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10136227</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stucki</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dastgir</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Baur</surname><given-names>DA</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Use of virtual and augmented reality in oral and maxillofacial surgery: a review</article-title>. <source>Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol</source>
<year>2024</year>;<volume>137</volume>:<fpage>12</fpage>–<lpage>18</lpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37723007</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.oooo.2023.07.001</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Forte</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Davies</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Interactive augmented reality software for facial reconstructive surgeries</article-title>. <source>Comput Methods Programs Biomed</source>
<year>2024</year>;<volume>244</volume>:<fpage>107970</fpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38101087</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.cmpb.2023.107970</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ruggiero</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cercenelli</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Emiliani</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Augmented reality accuracy in pediatric craniofacial surgery: a prospective study</article-title>. <source>J Clin Med</source>
<year>2023</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>2693</fpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37048777</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/jcm12072693</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10095377</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Noel</surname><given-names>OF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lopez</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Alperovich</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Simulation education in plastic surgery: current state and future directions</article-title>. <source>Art Surg</source>
<year>2023</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<fpage>1</fpage>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Velarde</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cafino</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Isla</surname><given-names>A</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Virtual surgical planning in craniomaxillofacial surgery: a structured review</article-title>. <source>Comput Assist Surg</source>
<year>2023</year>;<volume>28</volume>:<fpage>2271160</fpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1080/24699322.2023.2271160</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37862041</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Recker</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>KC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Reynolds</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Innovations in craniofacial surgery</article-title>. <source>Advancements in OMFS, ENT, and Facial Plastic Surgery</source>. <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>
<year>2023</year>:<fpage>1</fpage>–<lpage>35</lpage>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wright</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ford</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Qamar</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Design and validation of a 3D printed craniofacial simulator: a novel tool for surgical education</article-title>. <source>Cleft Palate Craniofac J</source>
<year>2024</year>;<volume>61</volume>:<fpage>997</fpage>–<lpage>1006</lpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36635983</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/10556656221151096</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Uhl</surname><given-names>JF</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sufianov</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ruiz</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>3D printed models for cranioplasty simulation in craniosynostosis: a comparative study</article-title>. <source>Brain Sci</source>
<year>2023</year>;<volume>13</volume>:<fpage>894</fpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37371373</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/brainsci13060894</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10296687</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tuffiash</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Roring</surname><given-names>RW</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ericsson</surname><given-names>KA</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Expert performance in complex skill domains: adaptations on a theme</article-title>. <source>J Exp Psychol Appl</source>
<year>2007</year>;<volume>13</volume>:<fpage>124</fpage>–<lpage>131</lpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17924798</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1037/1076-898X.13.3.124</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dubron</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Verbist</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jacobs</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>AR and VR applications in orbital trauma: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>J Clin Med</source>
<year>2023</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>5203</fpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37629251</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/jcm12165203</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10455745</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Panchal</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hoffman</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>An augmented reality model for evaluating traumatic craniofacial fractures</article-title>. <source>FACE</source>
<year>2024</year>;<volume>5</volume>:<fpage>525</fpage>–<lpage>532</lpage>; <comment>27325016241256671</comment>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Badash</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Burtt</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Solorzano</surname><given-names>CA</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Innovations in surgery simulation: a review of past, current and future techniques</article-title>. <source>Ann Transl Med</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<fpage>453</fpage>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28090509</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.21037/atm.2016.12.24</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5220028</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>Development and application of a virtual surgical system for training in orbital fracture repair</article-title>. <source>J Craniomaxillofac Surg</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>48</volume>:<fpage>56</fpage>–<lpage>62</lpage>
31911012
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wijnen</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hunt</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Tino</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>3D printed anatomical models and simulators for surgical education: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>3D Print Med</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<fpage>18</fpage>
32761490
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zaid</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fadda</surname><given-names>MT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Aboalshamat</surname><given-names>KT</given-names></name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Augmented reality and surgical education in medical training: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>Int J Surg</source>
<year>2022</year>;<volume>101</volume>:<fpage>106603</fpage>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gong</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<etal/>
</person-group>. <article-title>AR-based intraoperative navigation in oral and maxillofacial surgery: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>J Stomatol Oral Maxillofac Surg</source>
<year>2022</year>;<volume>123</volume>:<fpage>e590</fpage>–<lpage>e597</lpage>
</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>