<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41618308</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of remote ischemic preconditioning on upper extremity strength in healthy male adults: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>50</StartPage><MedlinePgn>50</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">50</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01494-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Remote ischemic preconditioning (RIPC) is a non-invasive intervention involving brief, repeated limb ischemia and is suggested to enhance muscle performance. However, findings in healthy men remain inconsistent, and few studies have examined upper-limb strength. This meta-analysis provides the first quantitative synthesis of acute RIPC effects on upper-body strength in healthy male adults, aiming to clarify its efficacy and practical relevance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">English (PubMed, Web of Science, Embase, Cochrane Library) and Chinese (CNKI, Wanfang, VIP, CBM) databases were systematically searched up to March 16, 2025. Randomized crossover trials examining acute RIPC effects on upper-limb strength in healthy male adults were included. Primary outcomes involved maximal, explosive, and endurance strength measures. The review was registered with PROSPERO (CRD420251184757). Data were pooled using random-effects models, and heterogeneity was assessed via the I&#xb2; statistic. Prespecified subgroup analyses examined moderators such as RIPC protocol (cycle number/duration) and strength outcome type (maximal, explosive, endurance).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Six randomized crossover trials involving 84 participants met inclusion criteria. The meta-analysis showed a small, positive, but non-significant overall effect of RIPC on upper-limb strength (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.24, 95% CI: -0.02 to 0.51, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.07) with low-to-moderate heterogeneity (I&#xb2; = 32%). Subgroup analyses revealed no significant effects for maximal (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.03, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.85) or explosive strength (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.13, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.75). A moderate but non-significant improvement was observed for strength endurance (SMD&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.54, 95% CI: -0.01 to 1.10, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.054) with moderate heterogeneity (I&#xb2; = 60%). Neither the number of ischemia&#x2013;reperfusion cycles (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.40 for subgroup difference) nor the test time window (&lt;&#x2009;30&#xa0;min vs.&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;30&#xa0;min, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.37) significantly moderated the effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This first meta-analysis on RIPC and upper-limb strength suggests that acute RIPC does not reliably improve upper-body strength in healthy male adults. Despite a moderate effect size observed for strength endurance, the lack of statistical significance and the 95% confidence interval crossing zero indicate considerable uncertainty in this finding. Together with the limited and heterogeneous evidence, this indicates that current protocols do not consistently enhance strength performance. RIPC should therefore be regarded as a theoretically promising but practically unverified approach. Larger, well-controlled trials are needed to determine whether specific RIPC parameters or time windows can produce reproducible performance gains.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-025-01494-8.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sport Training of General Administration of Sport of China, International Joint Laboratory on High Performance Sports Research, Beijing Sport University, No. 48, Xinxi Road, Beijing, 100084, China. lijian2506@bsu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Ruolan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sport Training of General Administration of Sport of China, International Joint Laboratory on High Performance Sports Research, Beijing Sport University, No. 48, Xinxi Road, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sport Training of General Administration of Sport of China, International Joint Laboratory on High Performance Sports Research, Beijing Sport University, No. 48, Xinxi Road, Beijing, 100084, China. bsuzb99@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Tianshuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sport Training of General Administration of Sport of China, International Joint Laboratory on High Performance Sports Research, Beijing Sport University, No. 48, Xinxi Road, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Jiashuang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sport Training of General Administration of Sport of China, International Joint Laboratory on High Performance Sports Research, Beijing Sport University, No. 48, Xinxi Road, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shiran</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sport Training of General Administration of Sport of China, International Joint Laboratory on High Performance Sports Research, Beijing Sport University, No. 48, Xinxi Road, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Zhentian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Sport Training of General Administration of Sport of China, International Joint Laboratory on High Performance Sports Research, Beijing Sport University, No. 48, Xinxi Road, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Nutrition Center, National Institute of Sports Medicine, No. 2, Sports Stadium Road, Beijing, 100763, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2025KYPT04</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2025KYPT04</GrantID><Agency>the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthy male adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Remote ischemic preconditioning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Upper extremity strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. (This meta-analysis synthesized data from previously published studies, and no new human subjects were involved. Therefore, ethical approval and participant consent were not required for this study.) Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41618308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12862904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01494-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01494-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hausenloy DJ, Yellon DM. Ischaemic conditioning and reperfusion injury. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2016;13(4):193&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrcardio.2016.5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26843289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murry CE, Jennings RB, Reimer KA. Preconditioning with ischemia: a delay of lethal cell injury in ischemic myocardium. Circulation. 1986;74(5):1124&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.74.5.1124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3769170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, Burr J, Scott BR, Owens J, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of Methodology, Application, and safety. Front Physiol. 2019;10:533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6530612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryds K, Nielsen RR, Jorsal A, Hansen MS, Ringgaard S, Refsgaard J, et al. Effect of long-term remote ischemic conditioning in patients with chronic ischemic heart failure. Basic Res Cardiol. 2017;112(6):67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00395-017-0658-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29071437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador AF, De Aguiar RA, Lisb&#xf4;a FD, Pereira KL, Cruz RSDO, Caputo F. Ischemic preconditioning and exercise performance: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016;11(1):4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2015-0204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26218309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey TG, Jones H, Gregson W, Atkinson G, Cable NT, Thijssen DHJ. Effect of ischemic preconditioning on lactate accumulation and running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(11):2084&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318262cb17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22843115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharbanda RK, Mortensen UM, White PA, Kristiansen SB, Schmidt MR, Hoschtitzky JA, et al. Transient limb ischemia induces remote ischemic preconditioning in vivo. Circulation. 2002;106(23):2881&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.0000043806.51912.9B</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12460865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rassaf T, Fl&#xf6;gel U, Drexhage C, Hendgen-Cotta U, Kelm M, Schrader J. Nitrite reductase function of deoxymyoglobin: oxygen sensor and regulator of cardiac energetics and function. Circul Res. 2007;22(12):1749&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17495223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotz C, Herrmann J, Notz Q, Meybohm P, Kehl F. Mitochondria and Pharmacologic cardiac Conditioning&#x2014;At the heart of ischemic injury. IJMS. 2021;22(6):3224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22063224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33810024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loukogeorgakis SP, Panagiotidou AT, Broadhead MW, Donald A, Deanfield JE, MacAllister RJ. Remote ischemic preconditioning provides early and late protection against endothelial Ischemia-Reperfusion injury in humans. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;46(3):450&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2005.04.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16053957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thielmann M, Kottenberg E, Kleinbongard P, Wendt D, Gedik N, Pasa S, et al. Cardioprotective and prognostic effects of remote ischaemic preconditioning in patients undergoing coronary artery bypass surgery: a single-centre randomised, double-blind, controlled trial. Lancet. 2013;382(9892):597&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(13)61450-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23953384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbock A, Schmidt C, Van Aken H, Wempe C, Martens S, Zahn PK, et al. Effect of remote ischemic preconditioning on kidney injury among High-Risk patients undergoing cardiac surgery: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2015;2(21):2133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26024502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin PJ, Ferguson RA, Gissane C, Bailey SJ, Patterson SD. Ischemic preconditioning enhances critical power during a 3 minute all-out cycling test. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(9):1038&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2017.1349923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey TG, Birk GK, Cable NT, Atkinson G, Green DJ, Jones H et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning prevents reduction in brachial artery flow-mediated dilation after strenuous exercise. American Journal of Physiology-Heart and Circulatory Physiology. 2012;303(5):H533&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22730390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jean-St-Michel E, Manlhiot C, Li J, Tropak M, Michelsen MM, Schmidt MR, et al. Remote preconditioning improves maximal performance in highly trained athletes. Volume 43. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise; 2011;1280&#x2013;6. 7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva Telles LG, Leit&#xe3;o L, Da Silva Ara&#xfa;jo G, Serra R, Junqueira CGS, Ribeiro AADS, et al. Remote and local ischemic preconditioning increases isometric strength and muscular endurance in recrea-tional trained individuals. Retos. 2023;47:941&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47197/retos.v47.93385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niespodzi&#x144;ski B, Mieszkowski J, Kochanowicz M, Kochanowicz A, Antosiewicz J. Effect of 10 consecutive days of remote ischemic preconditioning on local neuromuscular performance. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2021;60:102584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelekin.2021.102584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34388409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausenloy DJ, Yellon DM. Remote ischaemic preconditioning: underlying mechanisms and clinical application. Cardiovascular Res. 2008;79(3):377&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvn114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18456674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus AS, Pasha EP, Machin DR, Alkatan M, Kloner RA, Tanaka H. Bilateral upper limb remote ischemic preconditioning improves anaerobic power. TOSMJ. 2015;9(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Bezodis NE, Glaister M, Pattison JR. The effect of ischemic preconditioning on repeated sprint cycling performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(8):1652&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25412297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marocolo M, Da Mota G, Pelegrini V, Appell Coriolano HJ. Are the beneficial effects of ischemic preconditioning on performance partly a placebo effect? Int J Sports Med. 2015;9(10):822&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26058479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza HLR, Oliveira GT, Meireles A, Dos Santos MP, Vieira JG, Arriel RA, et al. Does ischemic preconditioning enhance sports performance more than placebo or no intervention? A systematic review with meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2025;14:101010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2024.101010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39536913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Wu W, Qiang L, Wang C, He Z, Wang Y. The effect of ischemic preconditioning on physical fitness and performance: a meta-analysis in healthy adults. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2024 Oct 18 [cited 2024 Nov 24]; Available from: https://link.springer.com/10.1007/s00421-024-05633-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39422720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crisafulli A, Tangianu F, Tocco F, Concu A, Mameli O, Mulliri G, et al. Ischemic preconditioning of the muscle improves maximal exercise performance but not maximal oxygen uptake in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(2):530&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00266.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21617078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kido K, Suga T, Tanaka D, Honjo T, Homma T, Fujita S, et al. Ischemic preconditioning accelerates muscle deoxygenation dynamics and enhances exercise endurance during the work-to-work test. Physiol Rep. 2015;3(5):e12395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4463825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25952936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradis-Desch&#xea;nes P, Joanisse DR, Billaut F. Ischemic preconditioning increases muscle perfusion, oxygen uptake, and force in strength-trained athletes. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41(9):938&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27574913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka D, Suga T, Tanaka T, Kido K, Honjo T, Fujita S, et al. Ischemic preconditioning enhances muscle endurance during sustained isometric exercise. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37(08):614&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0035-1565141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27176889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira TN, Sabino-Carvalho JLC, Lopes TR, Ribeiro IC, Succi JE, Da Silva AC, et al. Ischemic preconditioning and repeated sprint swimming: A placebo and Nocebo study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(10):1967&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Guti&#xe9;rrez D, S&#xe1;ez A, G&#xf3;mez-G&#xe1;lvez P, Paradas C, Escudero LM. Rules of tissue packing involving different cell types: human muscle organization. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):40444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep40444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5223128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28071729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu G, Durduran T, Lech G, Zhou C, Chance B, Mohler ER, et al. Time-dependent blood flow and oxygenation in human skeletal muscles measured with noninvasive near-infrared diffuse optical spectroscopies. J Biomed Opt. 2005;10(2):024027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1117/1.1884603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15910100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SY, Hausenloy DJ. Remote Ischemic Conditioning: From Bench to Bedside. Front Physio. 2012 [cited 2025 Sept 30];3. Available from: http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fphys.2012.00027/abstract</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3282534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22363297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surkar SM, Bland MD, Mattlage AE, Chen L, Gidday JM, Lee JM et al. Effects of remote limb ischemic conditioning on muscle strength in healthy young adults: A randomized controlled trial. Vassalle C, editor. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(2):e0227263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6999897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32017777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heusch G, B&#xf8;tker HE, Przyklenk K, Redington A, Yellon D. Remote ischemic conditioning. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2015;65(2):177&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2014.10.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4297315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25593060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silva Novaes J, Da Silva Telles LG, Monteiro ER, Da Silva Araujo G, Vingren JL, Silva Panza P, et al. Ischemic preconditioning improves resistance training session performance. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2021;35(11):2993&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32224716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ischemic Preconditioning Improves the Bench-Press Maximal Strength in Resistance-Trained Men. Int J Exerc Sci. 2023 [cited 2024 Nov 25];16(4). Available from: https://digitalcommons.wku.edu/ijes/vol16/iss4/6/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10124736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37113512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telles LG, Billaut F, De Souza Ribeiro A, Junqueira CG, Leit&#xe3;o L, Barreto AC et al. Ischemic Preconditioning with High and Low Pressure Enhances Maximum Strength and Modulates Heart Rate Variability. IJERPH. 2022;19(13):7655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9265721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35805313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela PL, Mart&#xed;n-Candilejo R, S&#xe1;nchez-Mart&#xed;nez G, Bouzas Marins JC, De La Villa P, Sillero-Quintana M. Ischemic preconditioning and muscle force capabilities. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2021;35(8):2187&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30908369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu X, Xia Q, Xu J, Tang L. Assessment of the impact of Sensor-Based ischemic preconditioning with different cycling periods on upper limb strength in bodybuilding athletes. Sens 2024;24(18):5943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11435447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39338688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellini D, Chapman C, Peden D, Hoekstra SP, Ferguson RA, Leicht CA. Ischaemic preconditioning improves upper-body endurance performance without altering V&#x307;O<sub>2</sub> kinetics. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23(8):1538&#x2013;46.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2022.2103741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35848989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Z, Dong H, Wu Y, Zhou S, Li H, Huang P et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning enhances aerobic performance by accelerating regional oxygenation and improving cardiac function during acute hypobaric hypoxia exposure. Front Physiol 2022;13:950086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9500473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36160840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa TC, Machado AC, Braz ID, Fernandes IA, Vianna LC, Nobrega ACL, et al. Remote ischemic preconditioning delays fatigue development during handgrip exercise. Scandinavian Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(3):356&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24731023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang JA, Kim J. Remote ischaemic preconditioning &#x2013; translating cardiovascular benefits to humans. J Physiol. 2022;600(13):3053&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9327506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ter Beek F, Jokumsen PS, Sloth BN, Stevenson AJT, Larsen RG. Ischemic preconditioning attenuates rating of perceived exertion but does not improve maximal oxygen consumption or maximal power output. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2022;36(9):2479&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32341247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng CF, Kuo YH, Hsu WC, Chen C, Pan CH. Local and remote ischemic preconditioning improves sprint interval exercise performance in team sport athletes. IJERPH. 2021;18(20):10653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182010653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8535734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34682399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cocking S, Wilson MG, Nichols D, Cable NT, Green DJ, Thijssen DHJ, et al. Is there an optimal Ischemic-Preconditioning dose to improve cycling performance? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(3):274&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28657799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caru M, Levesque A, Lalonde F, Curnier D. An overview of ischemic preconditioning in exercise performance: A systematic review. J Sport Health Sci. 2019;8(4):355&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6620415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien L, Jacobs I. Methodological variations contributing to heterogenous ergogenic responses to ischemic preconditioning. Front Physiol. 2021;12:656980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.656980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33995123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>