<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41627231</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3732</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of craniofacial surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Craniofac Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ventral Compression of the Trigeminal Nerve by the Superior Cerebellar Artery: A Novel Intraoperative Classification and Clinical Significance.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SCS.0000000000012505</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The superior cerebellar artery (SCA) is the most common offending vessel in microvascular decompression (MVD) for trigeminal neuralgia (TN). Among its variations, ventral compression presents unique surgical challenges, yet systematic classification remains limited. This study aimed to establish a novel intraoperative classification of ventral SCA compression and to evaluate its surgical and clinical relevance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively reviewed patients with TN who underwent MVD by the senior author between February 2019 and February 2024. Intraoperative video recordings were analyzed to categorize ventral-type SCA compression into 4 subtypes, based on the anatomic relationship with the trigeminal nerve and the facial-vestibulocochlear nerve complex. Patient demographics, operative findings, decompression techniques, and postoperative outcomes were compared across subtypes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eighty-eight patients with SCA compression were identified and classified into 4 subtypes: type 0 (36.4%), SCA rostral to the trigeminal nerve; type I (35.2%), SCA ventral to the nerve without extending below its inferior border; type II (18.2%), SCA looping ventrally with its lowest point between the trigeminal and facial-vestibulocochlear nerves; and type III (10.2%), SCA extending ventrally beyond the superior border of the facial-vestibulocochlear complex. No statistically significant differences were observed in postoperative pain relief or complication rates across subtypes (P&gt;0.05). However, surgical complexity varied considerably, with hidden compression at the trigeminal root entry zone and excessive vascular tortuosity contributing to greater intraoperative difficulty. Tailored surgical strategies, including the "push-and-flip" technique, enabled safe and effective decompression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study proposes a novel intraoperative classification of ventral SCA compression in TN. While short-term clinical outcomes were similar across subtypes, the classification emphasizes key anatomic variations that significantly affect surgical complexity. Recognition of these subtypes may facilitate operative planning, improve surgical safety, and reduce the risk of recurrence in patients undergoing MVD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by Mutaz B. Habal, MD.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Pan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-1862-8172</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Wenxiong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China National Clinical Research Center for Neurological Diseases, Beijing.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Feiyu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Nanjing BenQ Medical Center, The Affiliated BenQ Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Dong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Liangyuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zou</LastName><ForeName>Yuanjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Nanjing Brain Hospital, Nanjing Medical University.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Craniofac Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9010410</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1049-2275</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microvascular decompression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurovascular compression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superior cerebellar artery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trigeminal neuralgia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41627231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SCS.0000000000012505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001665-990000000-03724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Li M, Zhang Z, et al. Association between mental disorders and trigeminal neuralgia: a cohort study and Mendelian randomization analysis. J Headache Pain 2025;26:74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jannetta PJ. Microsurgical Approach to the Trigeminal Nerve for Tic Douloureux Pain-Its Neurosurgical Management. Karger Publishers; 1976:180&#x2013;200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia L, Zhong J, Zhu J, et al. Effectiveness and safety of microvascular decompression surgery for treatment of trigeminal neuralgia: a systematic review. J Craniofac Surg 2014;25:1413&#x2013;1417</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLaughlin MR, Jannetta PJ, Clyde BL, et al. Microvascular decompression of cranial nerves: lessons learned after 4400 operations. J Neurosurg 1999;90:1&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas KL, Vilensky JA. The anatomy of vascular compression in trigeminal neuralgia. Clin Anat 2014;27:89&#x2013;93</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoefer IE, den Adel B, Daemen MJ, et al. Biomechanical factors as triggers of vascular growth. Cardiovasc Res 2013;99:276&#x2013;283</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong J, Huang DL, Sagher O, et al. Parameters influencing augmentation of cerebral blood flow by cervical spinal cord stimulation. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2004;146:1227&#x2013;1234</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu MX, Zhong J, Dou NN, et al. Management of symptomatic hemifacial spasm or trigeminal neuralgia. Neurosurg Rev 2016;39:411&#x2013;418</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Shao D, Zheng X, et al. Comparison of endoscopic and microscopic microvascular decompression for treating primary trigeminal neuralgia. Front Neurol 2025;16:1583192</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filimonova EA, Pashkov AA, Yarnykh VL, et al. Assessment of trigeminal nerve root demyelination in patients with primary trigeminal neuralgia using macromolecular proton fraction imaging. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2025;46:602&#x2013;610</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache Society (IHS). The International Classification of Headache Disorders, 3rd eds.. Cephalalgia 2018;38:1&#x2013;211</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W, Ding F, Hu X, et al. Trigeminal nerve isolation application in microvascular decompression for treating trigeminal neuralgia: a retrospective study. J Craniofac Surg 2023;34:1559&#x2013;1562</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers CL, Shetter AG, Fiedler JA, et al. Gamma knife radiosurgery for trigeminal neuralgia: the initial experience of The Barrow Neurological Institute. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 2000;47:1013&#x2013;1019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker FG, Jannetta PJ, Bissonette DJ, et al. The long-term outcome of microvascular decompression for trigeminal neuralgia. NEJM 1996;334:1077&#x2013;1084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng J, Liu J, Zhang Z, et al. Outcomes and safety of repeated microvascular decompression for recurrent trigeminal neuralgia. Neurosurg Rev 2025;48:407</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>