<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41502640</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>48</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evolution of Overburden Fractures and the Water-Conducting Fracture Zone in Closely Spaced Coal Mine Seams under Highly Water-Rich Aquifers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>59802</StartPage><EndPage>59815</EndPage><MedlinePgn>59802-59815</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c09774</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Risks of water-related mine incidents are related to water source, pathways, and water inrush intensity. This study aims to clarify the evolution of overburden fractures under repeated mining in closely spaced coal seams and to identify the presence of a connection between the damaged overburden and the overlying highly water-rich aquifer. Longfeng Coal Mine in northern Guizhou was taken as a case study. A coupled UDEC-DIC methodology was applied to identify fracture evolution and the development of water-conducting fracture zones during the downward mining of closely spaced coal seams. This approach allows an integrated study of fracture patterns, displacement, stress, and strain fields. Four key strata from the working face upward were identified, with breaking intervals of 22.72, 22.78, 24.08, and 100.79 m, respectively. The uppermost layer is a highly water-rich aquifer. During the early mining stage, risks of overburden collapse and fracture development were relatively minor. However, after advancing 30 m, overburden collapse, subsidence, and the vertical and horizontal development of fractures gradually intensified. After 110 m, fracture development gradually stabilized. The combination of UDEC numerical simulation and DIC digital speckle technology showed increasing vertical displacement and vertical stress of the overburden with the advance of the working face. During the evolution process, the overburden showed "saddle"- and "arch"-shaped patterns. The amplitudes of both the stress peak and displacement peak first showed a rapid increase, followed by a slow increase, and then finally a rapid increase. However, the displacement peak eventually stabilized, whereas the stress peak continued to increase. The strain peak fluctuated between increasing and decreasing trends over two cycles. The height of the water-conducting fracture zone first gradually increased, then rapidly increased, and lastly followed a stable increasing pattern. With the downward advance of the mine shaft, the increase in the fracture zone height showed a temporary halt and progressed again after the overburden of the lower coal seam collapsed and connected to the upper goaf. During the mining of the #5 coal seam, fracture height reached 41.7-42.8 m, thereby connecting to the highly water-rich Changxing Formation aquifer, resulting in a water inrush risk. Subsequent to the mining of the #5 and #9 coal seams, fracture height ultimately reached 90.2-91.2 m, connecting two highly water-rich aquifers and presenting a serious water hazard risk. The research findings hold significant theoretical and practical importance for water hazard prevention and water resource protection in coal mines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining College, Guizhou University, Guiyang 550025, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71206</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Lulin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3643-2169</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining College, Guizhou University, Guiyang 550025, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71206</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Resources and Environment, Guizhou University, Guiyang 550025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Urban Planing, Liupanshui Normal University, Liupanshui, Guizhou 553004, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">518081</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Yujun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining College, Guizhou University, Guiyang 550025, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71206</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Weide</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guizhou Lindong Coal Industry Development Co., Ltd. Longfeng Coal Mine, Jinsha, Guizhou 551800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xilong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining College, Guizhou University, Guiyang 550025, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71206</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Ximin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mining College, Guizhou University, Guiyang 550025, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71206</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41502640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12772411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c09774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dai X., Gao R., Du F., Yu B., Meng X., Tai Y.. Evolution and Control of Overburden Fracture in Extra-Thick Coal Seam Mining with Hard Roofs: Ground Grouting Sealing and Case Study. Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ. 2024;83(7):262. doi: 10.1007/s10064-024-03762-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-024-03762-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Tian C., Mao J., Chen F.. Forecasting Coal Demand in Key Coal Consuming Industries Based on the Data-Characteristic-Driven Decomposition Ensemble Model. Energy. 2023;282:128841. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.128841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.128841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao K., Tu S., Wang Y., Li J., Zhao H., Guo B.. Utilization of Broken Rock in Shallow Gobs for Mitigating Mining-Induced Water Inrush Disaster Risks and Environmental Damage: Experimental Study and Permeability Model. Sci. Total Environ. 2023;903:166812. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.166812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.166812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37673245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao H., Hao X., Wu P., Li X., Han Z., Cao X., Yang B., Zhang R., Zhang K., Chen M., Zhang S.. Different Hydrogeological Characteristics of Springs Associated with Abandoned Coal Mines in Well-Developed Karst Area. J. Hydrol. 2025;653:132683. doi: 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2025.132683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2025.132683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Ren Y., Peng S. S., Cheng H., Wang N., Luo J.. Measurement of Overburden Failure Zones in Close-Multiple Coal Seams Mining. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 2021;31(1):43&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2020.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2020.12.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong F., Yin H., Ren H., Cheng W., Tai S., Miao T., Zhang Y., Wu B.. Trapezoidal Failure Behavior and Fracture Evolution Mechanism of Overburden in Extra-Thick Coal Mining in Weakly Cemented Strata. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2024;57:11239. doi: 10.1007/s00603-024-04147-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-024-04147-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng G., Xu W., Shi B., Wu J., Sun B., Zhu H.. Experimental Study on the Deformation and Failure Mechanism of Overburden Rock during Coal Mining Using a Comprehensive Intelligent Sensing Method. J. Rock Mech. Geotech. Eng. 2022;14(5):1626&#x2013;1641. doi: 10.1016/j.jrmge.2022.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrmge.2022.07.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Kong D., Wu G., Cheng Z., Song G., Shang Y.. Failure Mechanism and Movement Characteristics of Overlying Strata in Longwall Mining Face with Thick Aquifer. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2024;57(9):6787&#x2013;6809. doi: 10.1007/s00603-024-03929-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-024-03929-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J., Li Z., Feng G., Zhang H., Qi C., Zhang J.. Failure Analysis of Coal Pillars and Overburden from Underground Water Reservoir under the Mining-Water Invasion Coupling Effect. Eng. Failure Anal. 2023;151:107406. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Wang Z., Wang Q., Zou S., Yang X.. Study on the Application of Comprehensive Gas Control Technology for Source-Separated Three-Dimensional Gas Extraction in Large Mining Faces. ACS Omega. 2024;9:32777&#x2013;32788. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c03161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c03161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11292661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39100357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan G., Ma L., Sun J., Zhang P., Chen R., Pei G., Ma W.. Study on Air Leakage Law and Coal Spontaneous Combustion Danger Area in Goaf of Ultra-Long Fully Mechanized Mining Faces with Large Mining Height. ACS Omega. 2025;10(31):34160&#x2013;34175. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c10545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c10545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12355326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40821585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y., Zhao F., Fu Y., Zhao L., Liu W., Zhou X.. Hydraulic Fracturing Simulation Experiments and Fracture Characterization of Coal Reservoirs in the Dahebian Syncline. ACS Omega. 2025;10(19):19394&#x2013;19409. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c10461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c10461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12096213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40415826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xinlei L., Ziyuan R., Zhengzheng C., Hao R.. Study on Coal Drawing Parameters of Deeply Buried Hard Coal Seams Based on PFC. Sci. Rep. 2025;15(1):21934. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-08154-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-08154-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12216397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40596559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaoshang S., Chaoyang S., Zhiming Z., Haixiao L., Zhenhua L., Feng D., Zhengzheng C., Pengtao L., Lin L.. Overburden Failure Characteristics and Fracture Evolution Rule under Repeated Mining with Multiple Key Strata Control. Sci. Rep. 2025;15(1):28029. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-14068-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-14068-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12313934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40745199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Huan H., Lin H., Li Z., Du F., Cao Z., Fan X., Ren H.. Determination Method of Rational Position for Working Face Entries in Coordinated Mining of Section Coal Pillars and Lower Sub-Layer. Sci. Rep. 2025;15(1):29440. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-15115-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-15115-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12339699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40790342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z., Zhang C., Wang Y., Yang S., Li Q.. Collaborative Movement Characteristics of Overlying Rock and Loose Layer Based on Block&#x2013;Particle Discrete-Element Simulation Method. Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol. 2025;12(1):17. doi: 10.1007/s40789-025-00762-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-025-00762-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakhno I., Sakhno S., Petrenko A., Barkova O., Kobylianskyi B.. Numerical Simulation of the Surface Subsidence Evolution Caused by the Flooding of the Longwall Goaf during Excavation of Thin Coal Seams. IOP Conf. Ser.: Earth Environ. Sci. 2023;1254(1):012057. doi: 10.1088/1755-1315/1254/1/012057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1755-1315/1254/1/012057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Zuo J., Karakus M., Liu L., Zhou H., Yu M.. A New Theoretical Method to Predict Strata Movement and Surface Subsidence Due to Inclined Coal Seam Mining. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2021;54(6):2723&#x2013;2740. doi: 10.1007/s00603-021-02424-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-021-02424-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W., Zhang Q., Luan Y., Zhang X.-P.. A Study of Surface Subsidence and Coal Pillar Safety for Strip Mining in a Deep Mine. Environ. Earth Sci. 2018;77(17):627. doi: 10.1007/s12665-018-7810-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-018-7810-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gai Q., He M., Gao Y., Li S.. Mechanism of Floor Damage Reduction in Non-Pillar Mining with Automatically Formed Roadway: A Model Test Study. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2025;58(8):9573&#x2013;9600. doi: 10.1007/s00603-025-04563-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-025-04563-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Fang S., Wang Y., Shi X., Yao Z., Zhang T.. Instability Prevention and Control of Waste Dump Slopes with Different Consolidation Degrees under the Influence of Rainfall. Geohazard Mech. 2025;3(1):73&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1016/j.ghm.2024.09.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ghm.2024.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao L., Yang R., Chen B., Zhang Y. V.. Determinants and Prediction of Carbon Emissions in Guizhou, a New Economic Growth Pole in Southwest China. J. Cleaner Prod. 2023;417:138049. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.138049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.138049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Huang M., Zhu Y., Qin Y., Shi Y., Dou K. M.. Geochemistry and Enrichment Mechanism of Critical Elements (Li and Zr-Nb-Hf-Ta-REY) in the Coals from Western Guizhou Province, China: Source and Sedimentary Environment. Ore Geol. Rev. 2025;176:106402. doi: 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Zuo S., Yu B., Zheng K., Chen S., Huang L.. Spatial Patterns and Controlling Factors of the Evolution Process of Karst Depressions in Guizhou Province, China. J. Geogr. Sci. 2023;33(10):2052&#x2013;2076. doi: 10.1007/s11442-023-2165-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11442-023-2165-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuhao L., Dezhong K., Peng L., Zhijie W., Fei L., Yujun Z., Guiyi W.. The Migration and Evolution Law of Overlying Strata and the Instability and Failure Characteristics of End Face Roof under the Condition of Ascending Mining in Close Distance Coal Seam: Case Study. Eng. Failure Anal. 2024;165:108809. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J., Li W., Fan K., Qiao W., Wang Q., Li L.. A Method for Predicting the Water-Flowing Fractured Zone Height Based on an Improved Key Stratum Theory. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 2023;33(1):61&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2022.09.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2022.09.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning S., Zhu W., Xie J., Song S., Wang X., Yu D., Lou J., Xu J.. Influence of Stress Distribution in Coal Seams of Non-Uniform Extremely Thick Key Stratum and Disaster-Causing Mechanisms. Sci. Rep. 2022;12(1):14465. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-18641-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-18641-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9402551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36002536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Gan Q., Zhao Y., Zhu G., Nie X., Yang K., Li J.. Investigations into Mining-Induced Stress&#x2013;Fracture&#x2013;Seepage Field Coupling Effect Considering the Response of Key Stratum and Composite Aquifer. Rock Mech. Rock Eng. 2019;52(10):4017&#x2013;4031. doi: 10.1007/s00603-019-01811-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-019-01811-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Xie J., Zhu W., Xu J.. The Field Monitoring Experiment of the High-Level Key Stratum Movement in Coal Mining Based on Collaborative DOFS and MPBX. Sci. Rep. 2022;12(1):665. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-04578-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-04578-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8758663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L., Ma Y., Elmo D., Ding S., Zhu H., Liu H., Li W., Chen W.. Parameters and Surrounding Rock Control of Gob-Side Driving under Double Key Stratum after Roof Cutting. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):5106. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-55679-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-55679-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10907563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38429392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Chen Y., Wang Y., Bai Q.. Discrete Element Method Simulation of Granular Materials Considering Particle Breakage in Geotechnical and Mining Engineering: A Short Review. Green Smart Min. Eng. 2024;1(2):190&#x2013;207. doi: 10.1016/j.gsme.2024.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gsme.2024.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Liu C., Guo X., Wu X.. Instability Motion Characteristics of Overburden Rock and the Distribution Pattern of Fissures in Shallow Thick Seam Mining. Sci. Rep. 2022;12(1):6184. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-10205-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-10205-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9007980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35418565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao Y., Shi Q., Liu K.-H., Li Q.-W., Wang Z.-P.. The Evolution Characteristics of Fractures in Overlying Rock for Underground Coal Fires. Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ. 2023;82(8):290. doi: 10.1007/s10064-023-03321-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-023-03321-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T., Zhang Y., Zhang J., Lin H., Bao R., He Y., Yan Y., Luo P., Wu H., Sun J.. et al. Study on the Stability and Reasonable Width of Coal Pillars in &#x201c;Three Soft&#x201d; Coal Seams Based on a Physical Similarity Simulation Experiment. Appl. Sci. 2024;14:6127. doi: 10.3390/app14146127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14146127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Zou Q., Gao S., Zhan J., Chen C., Ran Q., Sun X.. Long-Term Evolution of Overlying Rock Fractures in Mined-out Areas and Its Effect on Gas Flow Conductivity. Fuel. 2023;353:129213. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2023.129213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.129213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang D., Sun Y., Xu J., Zhao L.. Study on the Evolution of Fractures in Overlying Strata during Repeated Mining of Coal Seams at Extremely Close Distances. Front. Earth Sci. 2024;12:1472939. doi: 10.3389/feart.2024.1472939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2024.1472939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning J., Wang J., Tan Y., Xu Q.. Mechanical Mechanism of Overlying Strata Breaking and Development of Fractured Zone during Close-Distance Coal Seam Group Mining. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 2020;30(2):207&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2019.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2019.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Zhou K., Xiong X., Gao F., Zhou J.. Research on Height Prediction of Water-Conducting Fracture Zone in Coal Mining Based on Intelligent Algorithm Combined with Extreme Boosting Machine. Expert Syst. Appl. 2024;249:123669. doi: 10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2024.123669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B., He S., Bai K., Lu X., Wang W.. Elastic Wave Prospecting of Water-Conducting Fractured Zones in Coal Mining. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):7036. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-57557-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-57557-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10963782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38528085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng L., Liu X., Qiu Q., Tian Y., Ren W., Xu J., Wang X.. Failure and Development Height of Overlying Rock of a Water Flowing Fracture in Goaf under a Karst Aquifer. Sci. Rep. 2025;15(1):2473. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-86676-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-86676-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11747405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39833268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Su H., Wang C., Li J.. Research on the Evolution and Height Prediction of WCFZ in Shallow Close Coal Seams Mining. Geomech. Geophys. Geo-Energy Geo-Resour. 2023;9(1):128. doi: 10.1007/s40948-023-00662-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40948-023-00662-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai W., He F., Li L., Song J., Xu X., Lv K., Li X., Wang D., Zhang J.. Roof Cutting Mechanism and Surrounding Rock Control of Small Pillar Along-Gob Roadway Driving in Super High Coal Seam. Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ. 2023;82(4):151. doi: 10.1007/s10064-023-03189-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-023-03189-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Ma L., Ngo I., Zhai J.. Prediction of the Height of Water-Conductive Fractured Zone under Continuous Extraction and Partial Backfill Mining Method&#xe5f8;a Case Study. Sustainability. 2022;14(11):6582. doi: 10.3390/su14116582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su14116582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng J., Sheng S., Xu Y., Luo Y., Islam M. M.. Deformation Prediction of Overlying Strata in Multi-Seam Mining Based on the Influence Function Method-Key Stratum Hybrid Model. Geomech. Geophys. Geo-Energy Geo-Resour. 2024;10(1):178. doi: 10.1007/s40948-024-00875-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40948-024-00875-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Zhang J., Huang Y., Gao R.. Measurement and Numerical Analysis of Influence of Key Stratum Breakage on Mine Pressure in Top-Coal Caving Face with Super Great Mining Height. J. Cent. South Univ. 2017;24(8):1881&#x2013;1888. doi: 10.1007/s11771-017-3595-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-017-3595-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng L., Wang X., Lan H., Ren W., Tian Y., Xu J., Tian S.. Study of the Development Patterns of Water-Conducting Fracture Zones under Karst Aquifers and the Mechanism of Water Inrush. Sci. Rep. 2024;14(1):20790. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-71853-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-71853-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11379689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39242957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>