<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41783454</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0860-021X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>43</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biology of sport</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Sport</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Changes in physical fitness and body composition of athletes after the COVID-19 lockdown: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression, with assessment of the certainty of evidence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>463</StartPage><EndPage>488</EndPage><MedlinePgn>463-488</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/biolsport.2026.153307</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This systematic review with meta-analysis analysed the effects of COVID-19 lockdowns on physical fitness and body composition in athletes. A comprehensive search was conducted in three databases (PubMed, Web of Science, and Scopus) up to January 2025 (included). Studies were included based on PICO criteria, involving adult athletes, original articles, and any quantitative assessment of physical fitness and/or body composition conducted within one month before and two weeks after the lockdown. The Joanna Briggs Institute Critical Appraisal Checklist was used to assess the risk of bias, while the Cochrane Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) approach evaluated the certainty of evidence. A total of 14 studies (261 athletes) with a low risk of bias met the inclusion criteria. Narrative synthesis revealed that the effects of lockdowns on athletes' physical fitness and body composition were varied, with consistent impairments (e.g., endurance-related fitness), relative stability (e.g., body mass, CMJ height, maximal strength), and mixed results (e.g., sprinting). A meta-analysis of 11 studies indicated a non-significant effect of lockdown on body mass (effect size [ES]=-0.115, 95% confidence interval [CI] -0.214 to 0.164, P=0.797). Similarly, 10 studies showed a variable, non-significant reduction in CMJ height (ES=-0.303, 95% CI -0.655 to 0.045, P=0.097). However, CMJ relative peak power (six studies) demonstrated a trivial-small negative effect (ES=-0.199, 95% CI -0.341 to -0.058, P=0.019). These findings should be interpreted with caution as the certainty of evidence was very low. While evidence remains limited, targeted and individualised training might help mitigate some of the detraining effects observed during a lockdown, particularly in endurance-related fitness outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Institute of Sport &#x2013; National Research Instutite.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Washif</LastName><ForeName>Jad Adrian</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Performance Branch, Sports Performance Division, National Sports Institute of Malaysia, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trabelsi</LastName><ForeName>Khaled</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>High Institute of Sport and Physical Education of Sfax, University of Sfax, Sfax, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement Sciences and Sports Training, School of Sport Science, The University of Jordan, Amman, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagaduan</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Melbourne School of Psychological Sciences, The University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perreras</LastName><ForeName>Marie Stella Louise</ForeName><Initials>MSL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine and Science Graduate School, Konkuk University, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moussa-Chamari</LastName><ForeName>Imen</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Coaching Department; College of Sport Sciences, Qatar University, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yousfi</LastName><ForeName>Narimen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit "Sport Sciences, Health and Movement", Higher Institute of Sports and Physical Education of Kef, University of Jendouba, Kef, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tunisian Research Laboratory "Sport Performance Optimisation", National Center of Medicine and Science in Sport, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pyne</LastName><ForeName>David B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chamari</LastName><ForeName>Karim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Office, Naufar, Wellness and Recovery Center, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher institute of Sport and Physical Education, ISSEP Ksar Sa&#xef;d, Manouba University, Tunis, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Sport</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0860-021X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body fat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Detraining</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Home training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Isolation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Modified exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS CoV 2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>All authors have no conflict of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41783454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12954494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2026.153307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Trabelsi K, Ammar A, Masmoudi L, Boukhris O, Chtourou H, Bouaziz B, Brach M, Bentlage E, How D, Ahmed M, Mueller P, Mueller N, Hsouna H, Romdhani M, Hammouda O, Paineiras-Domingos LL, Braakman-Jansen A, Wrede C, Bastoni S, Pernambuco CS, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Taheri M, Irandoust K, Khacharem A, Bragazzi NL, Strahler J, Adrian Washif J, Andreeva A, Bailey SJ, Acton J, Mitchell E, Bott NT, Gargouri F, Chaari L, Batatia H, Khoshnami SC, Samara E, Zisi V, Sankar P, Ahmed WN, Ali GM, Abdelkarim O, Jarraya M, El Abed K, Moalla W, Souissi N, Aloui A, Souissi N, Gemert-Pijnen LV, Riemann BL, Riemann L, Delhey J, G&#xf3;mez-Raja J, Epstein M, Sanderman R, Schulz S, Jerg A, Al-Horani R, Mansi T, Dergaa I, Jmail M, Barbosa F, Ferreira-Santos F, &#x160;imuni&#x10d; B, Pi&#x161;ot R, Pi&#x161;ot S, Gaggioli A, Steinacker J, Zmijewski P, Clark CCT, Apfelbacher C, Glenn JM, Saad HB, Chamari K, Driss T, Hoekelmann A. Globally altered sleep patterns and physical activity levels by confinement in 5056 individuals: ECLB COVID-19 international online survey. Biol Sport. 2021; 38(4):495&#x2013;506. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2021.101605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.101605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Farooq A, Krug I, Pyne DB, Verhagen E, Taylor L, Wong DP, Mujika I, Cortis C, Haddad M, Ahmadian O, Al Jufaili M, Al-Horani RA, Al-Mohannadi AS, Aloui A, Ammar A, Arifi F, Aziz AR, Batuev M, Beaven CM, Beneke R, Bici A, Bishnoi P, Bogwasi L, Bok D, Boukhris O, Boullosa D, Bragazzi N, Brito J, Cartagena RPP, Chaouachi A, Cheung SS, Chtourou H, Cosma G, Debevec T, DeLang MD, Dellal A, D&#xf6;nmez G, Driss T, Pe&#xf1;a Duque JD, Eirale C, Elloumi M, Foster C, Franchini E, Fusco A, Galy O, Gastin PB, Gill N, Girard O, Gregov C, Halson S, Hammouda O, Hanzl&#xed;kov&#xe1; I, Hassanmirzaei B, Haugen T, H&#xe9;bert-Losier K, Mu&#xf1;oz Hel&#xfa; H, Herrera-Valenzuela T, Hettinga FJ, Holtzhausen L, Hue O, Dello Iacono A, Ihalainen JK, James C, Janse van Rensburg DC, Joseph S, Kamoun K, Khaled M, Khalladi K, Kim KJ, Kok LY, MacMillan L, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Matsunaga R, Memishi S, Millet GP, Moussa-Chamari I, Musa DI, Nguyen HMT, Nikolaidis PT, Owen A, Padulo J, Pagaduan JC, Perera NP, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Pillay L, Popa A, Pudasaini A, Rabbani A, Rahayu T, Romdhani M, Salamh P, Sarkar AS, Schillinger A, Seiler S, Setyawati H, Shrestha N, Suraya F, Tabben M, Trabelsi K, Urhausen A, Valtonen M, Weber J, Whiteley R, Zrane A, Zerguini Y, Zmijewski P, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Ben Saad H, Chamari K.. Training during the COVID-19 lockdown: knowledge, beliefs, and practices of 12,526 athletes from 142 countries and six continents. Sports Med. 2022; 52(4):933&#x2013;948. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01573-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01573-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8536915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar A, Trabelsi K, Brach M, Chtourou H, Boukhris O, Masmoudi L, Bouaziz B, Bentlage E, How D, Ahmed M, Mueller P, Mueller N, Hammouda O, Paineiras-Domingos LL, Braakman-Jansen A, Wrede C, Bastoni S, Pernambuco CS, Mataruna L, Taheri M, Irandoust K, Khacharem A, Bragazzi NL, Strahler J, Washif JA, Andreeva A, Glenn JM, Bott NT, Gargouri F, Chaari L, Batatia H, Khoshnami SC, Samara E, Zisi V, Sankar P, Ahmed WN, Ali GM, Abdelkarim O, Jarraya M, Abed KE, Moalla W, Romdhani M, Aloui A, Souissi N, Lisette Van Gemert P, Riemann BL, Riemann L, Delhey J, G&#xf3;mez-Raja J, Epstein M, Sanderman R, Schulz S, Jerg A, Al-Horani R, Mansi T, Jmail M, Barbosa F, Ferreira-Santos F, &#x160;imuni&#x10d; B, Pi&#x161;ot R, Pi&#x161;ot S, Gaggioli A, Zmijewski P, Bailey SJ, Steinacker J, Chamari K, Driss T, Hoekelmann A.. Effects of home confinement on mental health and lifestyle behaviours during the COVID-19 outbreak: insights from the ECLB-COVID19 multicentre study. Biol Sport. 2021; 38(1):9&#x2013;21. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2020.96857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.96857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7996377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33795912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galy O, Washif JA, Wattelez G, Farooq A, Hue O, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Beaven CM, Seiler S, Ding D, Pyne DB, Chamari K. Training strategies of 10,074 athletes from 121 countries based on human development index in early COVID-19 lockdown. Sci Rep. 2024; 14(1):8866. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-59375-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-59375-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11024144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38632327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Rae DE, N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Ammar A, Chtourou H, Al Horani R, Ben Saad H, Bragazzi N, D&#xf6;nmez G, Driss T, Fullagar HHK, Farooq A, Garbarino S, Hammouda O, Hassanmirzaei B, Khalladi K, Khemila S, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Moussa-Chamari I, Mujika I, Mu&#xf1;oz Hel&#xfa; H, Norouzi Fashkhami A, Paineiras-Domingos LL, Rahbari Khaneghah M, Saita Y, Trabelsi K, Vitale JA, Washif JA, Weber J, Souissi N, Taylor L, Chamari K.. COVID-19 lockdowns: a worldwide survey of circadian rhythms and sleep quality in 3911 athletes from 49 countries, with data-driven recommendations. Sports Med. 2022; 52(6):1433&#x2013;1448. doi: 10.1007/s40279-021-01601-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01601-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8652380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34878639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Saad HB, Zmijewski P, Farhat R, Romdhani M, Souissi A, Washif JA, Taheri M, Guelmami N, Souissi N, Chamari K. Large-scale sporting events during the COVID-19 pandemic: Insights from the FIFA World Cup 2022 in Qatar with an analysis of patterns of COVID-19 metrics. Biol Sport. 2023; 40(4):1249&#x2013;1258. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2023.131109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2023.131109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10588590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37867752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martens G, Delvaux F, Forthomme B, Kaux JF, Urhausen A, Bieuzen F, Leclerc S, Winkler L, Brocherie F, Nedelec M, Morales-Artacho AJ, Ruffault A, Macquet AC, Guilhem G, Hannouche D, Tscholl PM, Seil R, Edouard P, Croisier JL. Exercise-based injury prevention in high-level and professional athletes: narrative review and proposed standard operating procedure for future lockdownlike contexts after COVID-19. Front Sports Act Living. 2021; 3:745765. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2021.745765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.745765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34977567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazett-Jones DM, Garcia MC, Taylor-Haas JA, Long JT, Rauh MJ, Paterno MV, Ford KR. Impact of COVID-19 social distancing restrictions on training habits, injury, and care seeking behavior in youth long-distance runners. Front Sports Act Living. 2020; 2:586141. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2020.586141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2020.586141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paludo AC, Karpinski K, Silva SEF, Kumst&#xe1;t M, Sajdlov&#xe1; Z, Milanovic Z. Effect of home training during the COVID-19 lockdown on physical performance and perceptual responses of team-sport athletes: a mini-review. Biol Sport. 2022; 39(4):1095&#x2013;1102. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2022.117040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2022.117040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9536370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muriel X, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Cerezuela-Espejo V, Pallar&#xe9;s JG. Training load and performance impairments in professional cyclists during COVID-19 lockdown. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020; 16(5):735&#x2013;738. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32820136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pla R, Bosquet L, McGibbon K, Mujika I, Aubry A. Heart rate variability in elite swimmers before, during and after COVID-19 lockdown: A brief report on time domain analysis. Appl Sci. 2021; 11(17):8106. doi: 10.3390/app11178106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11178106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Washif JA, Taylor L, Chamari K. Athletes&#x2019; Sleep During the Lockdown International Survey&#x201d; Group Members . Soccer players&#x2019; sleep quality and training load were affected by the COVID-19 lockdown: an international survey. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2023; 18(5):530&#x2013;540. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2022-0187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2022-0187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37030665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Mujika I, DeLang MD, Brito J, Dellal A, Haugen T, Hassanmirzaei B, Wong DP, Farooq A, D&#xf6;nmez G, Kim KJ, Duque JDP, MacMillan L, Matsunaga R, Rabbani A, Romdhani M, Tabben M, Zerguini Y, Zmijewski P, Pyne DB, Chamari K. Training practices of football players during the early COVID-19 lockdown worldwide. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022; 18(1):37&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2022-0186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2022-0186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36470251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Font R, Irurtia A, Gutierrez J, Salas S, Vila E, Carmona G. The effects of COVID-19 lockdown on jumping performance and aerobic capacity in elite handball players. Biol Sport. 2021; 38(4):753&#x2013;9. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2021.109952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.109952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rampinini E, Donghi F, Martin M, Bosio A, Riggio M, Maffiuletti NA. Impact of COVID-19 lockdown on Serie A soccer players&#x2019; physical qualities. Int J Sports Med. 2021; 42(10):917&#x2013;923. doi: 10.1055/a-1345-9262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1345-9262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33621997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa BV, Maldonado AJ, de Araujo AO, Neves LM, Rossi FE. Impact of the COVID-19 lockdown on the body composition and physical performance of athletes: a systematic review with meta-analysis and meta-regression. Healthcare (Basel). 2023; 11(16):2319. doi: 10.3390/healthcare11162319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare11162319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10454760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37628517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paravlic AH, Simunic B, Pisot S, Kleva M, Teraz K, Vogrin M, Marusic U, Pisot R. Lower-limb muscle contractile properties, explosive power and the subjective response of elite soccer players to the COVID-19 lockdown. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022; 19(1):474. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19010474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19010474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8744705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Kok LY, James C, Beaven CM, Farooq A, Pyne DB, Chamari K. Athlete level, sport-type, and gender influences on training, mental health, and sleep during the early COVID-19 lockdown in Malaysia. Front Physiol. 2023; 13:1093965. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2022.1093965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.1093965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9875133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36714309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagaduan JC, Washif JA, Krug I, Ammar A, Saad HB, James C, Cortis C, Trabelsi K, Haddad M, Bok D, Hassanmirzaei B, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Farooq A, Chen, YS, Gastin P, Chamari K. Training practices of Filipino athletes during the early COVID-19 lockdown. Kinesiology. 2022; 54(2):335&#x2013;346. doi: 10.26582/k.54.2.15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26582/k.54.2.15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri M, Saad HB, Washif JA, Reynoso-S&#xe1;nchez LF, Mirmoezzi M, Youzbashi L, Trabelsi K, Moshtagh M, Mu&#xf1;oz-Hel&#xfa; H, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Seghatoleslami A, Torabi F, Soylu Y, Kurt C, Vancini RL, Delkash S, Rezaei MS, Ashouri M, Tahira S, Sayyah M, Chtourou H, Dergaa I, Strahler J, Guimar&#xe3;es-Mataruna AF, Lebaron TW, Ezdini ES, Alizade A, Zouhal H, Tarnava AT, Clark C, Bigdeli N, Ammar A, Eken &#xd6;, Ayed KB, Bragazzi NL, Nobari H, Thuany M, Weiss K, Knechtle B, Irandoust K.. Comparative study of the long-term impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on mental health and nutritional practices among international elite and sub-elite athletes: a sample of 1420 participants from 14 countries. Sports Med Open. 2023; 9(1):104. doi: 10.1186/s40798-023-00653-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00653-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10632320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37938473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taheri M, Irandoust K, Reynoso-S&#xe1;nchez LF, Mu&#xf1;oz-Hel&#xfa; H, Cruz-Morales KN, Torres-Ram&#xed;rez R, Mirmoezzi M, Youzbashi L, Mirakhori F, Dergaa I, Vancini RL, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Korinna Zazueta-Beltr&#xe1;n D, Zouhal H, Morales-Beltr&#xe1;n RA, Soylu Y, Molgado-Sifuentes A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Hern&#xe1;ndez J, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Cruz G, Bojorquez Castro LB, Kurt C, Trabelsi K, Chtourou H, Seghatoleslami A, L&#xf3;pez-Camacho MO, Mendoza-Baldenebro RE, Torabi F, Ben Saad H, Washif JA, Strahler J, Guimar&#xe3;es-Mataruna AF, Lebaron TW, Shaabani Ezdini E, Rezaei MS, Moshtagh M, Yagin FH, G&#xfc;l&#xfc; M, Esmaeili A, M&#xfc;ller P, Ammar A, Scoditti E, Garbarino S, Puce L, Bragazzi NL, Nobari H.. Effects of home confinement on physical activity, nutrition, and sleep quality during the COVID-19 outbreak in amateur and elite athletes. Front Nutr. 2023; 10:1143340. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1143340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1143340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10150803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37139442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera-Valenzuela T, Narrea Vargas JJ, Merlo R, Vald&#xe9;s-Badilla PA, Pardo-Tamayo C, Franchini E. Effect of the COVID-19 quarantine on body mass among combat sports athletes. Nutr Hosp. 2020; 37(6):1186&#x2013;1189. doi: 10.20960/nh.03207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20960/nh.03207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33119395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddad M, Abbes Z, Mujika I, Chamari K. Impact of COVID-19 on swimming training: practical recommendations during home confinement/isolation. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021; 18(9):4767. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18094767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18094767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8124287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33947100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mon-L&#xf3;pez D, de la Rubia Riaza A, Hontoria Gal&#xe1;n M, Refoyo Roman I. The impact of Covid-19 and the effect of psychological factors on training conditions of handball players. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020; 17(18):6471. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17186471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17186471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7558666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32899526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carnevale Pellino V, Lovecchio N, Puci MV, Marin L, Gatti A, Pirazzi A, Negri F, Ferraro OE, Vandoni M. Effects of the lockdown period on the mental health of elite athletes during the COVID-19 pandemic: A narrative review. Sport Sci Health. 2022; 18(4):1187&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1007/s11332-022-00964-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-022-00964-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35693326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia L, Carter MV, Cusano A, Li X, Kelly JD IV, Bartley JD, Parisien RL. The effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on the mental and emotional health of athletes: a systematic review. Am J Sports Med. 2023; 51(8):2207&#x2013;2215. doi: 10.1177/03635465221087473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03635465221087473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10333562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35413208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson L, Flannigan C, Polychronopoulos P, MacKenzie R, Drust B, Milsom J. Lessons from the COVID-19 pandemic: insights into effective training strategies for physical development in football. Int J Sports Sci Coach. 2023; 18(2):403&#x2013;413. doi: 10.1177/17479541221081782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17479541221081782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9014339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38603107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sannicandro I, Bisciotti GN. Soccer functional assessment pre and postisolation due to Covid-19: detraining effects on strength, aerobic values and lower limb strength asymmetry. Medicina dello Sport. 2021; 74(4):590&#x2013;8. doi: 10.23736/S0025-7826.21.03996-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0025-7826.21.03996-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batalha N, Sousa JP, Fernandes O, Dias E, Parraca JA, Villafaina S. Effects of an 11-week detraining, imposed by the COVID-19 confinement, on handball players&#x2019; shoulder rotator isokinetic profile, shoulder range of motion, and ball release velocity. Medicina (Kaunas). 2023; 59(9):1548. doi: 10.3390/medicina59091548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina59091548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10533007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37763667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatih YM, Ko&#xe7; &#xd6;F, I&#x15f;&#x131;k B, Erda&#x11f;&#x131; K. The effect on performance of detraining during Covid-19 pandemic period in amateur soccer players. Progr Nutr. 2022; 23(4). doi: 10.23751/pn.v23i4.11671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23751/pn.v23i4.11671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen S, Johansen D, Casolo A, Randers MB, Sagelv EH, Welde B, Winther AK, Pettersen SA. Maximal strength, sprint, and jump performance in high-level female football players are maintained with a customized training program during the COVID-19 lockdown. Front Physiol. 2021; 12:623885. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2021.623885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2021.623885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7952977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leo P, Mujika I, Lawley J. Influence of COVID-19 restrictions on training and physiological characteristics in U23 elite cyclists. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2021; 7(1):1. doi: 10.3390/jfmk7010001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk7010001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8788453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35076533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Albuquerque Freire L, Tannure M, Sampaio M, Slimani M, Znazen H, Bragazzi NL, Aedo-Mu&#xf1;oz E, Sobarzo Soto DA, Brito CJ, Miarka B. COVID-19related restrictions and quarantine COVID-19: effects on cardiovascular and yo-yo test performance in professional soccer players. Front Psychol. 2020; 11:589543. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2020.589543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.589543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir C, Subasi B, Harput G. Effects of the COVID-19 confinement period on hip strength, flexibility and muscle injury rate in professional soccer players. Phys Sportsmed. 2023; 51(1):56&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1080/00913847.2021.1985384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00913847.2021.1985384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34570674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fikenzer S, Fikenzer K, Laufs U, Falz R, Pietrek H, Hepp P. Impact of COVID-19 lockdown on endurance capacity of elite handball players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2021; 61(7):977&#x2013;982. doi: 10.23736/S0022-4707.20.11501-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23736/S0022-4707.20.11501-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33269880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda J, Kondo E, Takai E, Eda N, Azuma Y, Motonaga K, Dohi M, Kamei A. The effects of the COVID-19 environments on changes in body composition in Japanese elite fencing athlete. Sports (Basel). 2021; 9(7):95. doi: 10.3390/sports9070095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports9070095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8309863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34202335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parpa K, Michaelides M. The impact of COVID-19 lockdown on professional soccer players&#x2019; body composition and physical fitness. Biol Sport. 2021; 38(4):733&#x2013;740. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2021.109452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2021.109452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8670810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34937985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M, Moher D, Bossuyt P, Boutron I, Hoffmann T, Mulrow C, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff J, Akl E, Brennan S, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw J, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu M, Li T, Loder E, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness L, Stewart L, Thomas J, Tricco A, Welch V, Whiting P, McKenzie J. PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021; 372:n160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishikawa-Pacher A. Research questions with PICO: a universal mnemonic. Publications. 2022; 10(3):21. doi: 10.3390/publications10030021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/publications10030021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma LL, Wang YY, Yang ZH, Huang D, Weng H, Zeng XT. Methodological quality (risk of bias) assessment tools for primary and secondary medical studies: what are they and which is better?. Mil Med Res. 2020; 7:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7049186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32111253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buccheri RK, Sharifi C. Critical appraisal tools and reporting guidelines for evidence-based practice. Worldviews Evid Based Nurs. 2017; 14(6):463&#x2013;472. doi: 10.1111/wvn.12258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/wvn.12258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28898556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besbes A, Khemiss M, Bragazzi N, Ben Saad H. The impacts of Ramadan intermittent fasting on saliva flow-rate and metabolic data: A systematic review. Front Nutr. 2022; 9:873502. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2022.873502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2022.873502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9019589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35464020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, Kunz R, Vist G, Brozek J, Norris S, Falck-Ytter Y, Glasziou P, DeBeer H, Jaeschke R, Rind D, Meerpohl J, Dahm P, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction-GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011; 64(4):383&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21195583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drevon D, Fursa SR, Malcolm AL. Intercoder reliability and validity of WebPlotDigitizer in extracting graphed data. Behav Modif. 2017; 41(2):323&#x2013;339. doi: 10.1177/0145445516673998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0145445516673998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27760807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal R. Meta-analytic procedures for social research. Newbury Park, CA: Sage Publications; 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. 2nd ed. Routledge; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from the pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods. 2007; 11, 364&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003; 327(7414):557&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 6.0. 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (US) . Methods guide for effectiveness and comparative effectiveness reviews [Internet]. Rockville (MD): Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (US); 2008. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK47095/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21433403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begg CB, Mazumdar M. Operating characteristics of a rank correlation test for publication bias. Biometrics. 1994; 50(4):1088101. doi: 10.2307/2533446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2533446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7786990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997; 315(7109):629&#x2013;634. doi: 10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: A simple funnel-plot-based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000; 56(2):455&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1111/j.0006-341x.2000.00455.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0006-341x.2000.00455.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan E, Montalvo S, Gonzalez MP, Dietze-Hermosa M, See M, Dorgo S. Changes in vertical jump performance and body composition before and after COVID-19 lockdown. J Hum Sport Exerc. 2021; 18(1): 224&#x2013;241. doi: 10.14198/jhse.2023.181.18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14198/jhse.2023.181.18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen DD, Restrepo A, Richter C, Harry JR, Franchi MV, Restrepo C, Poletto R, Taberner M. Detraining of specific neuromuscular qualities in elite footballers during COVID-19 quarantine. Sci Med Footb. 2021; 5(sup1):26&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1080/24733938.2020.1834123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24733938.2020.1834123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35077322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spyrou K, Alcaraz PE, Mar&#xed;n-Cascales E, Herrero-Carrasco R, Cohen DD, Calleja-Gonzalez J, Pereira LA, Loturco I, Freitas TT. Effects of the COVID-19 lockdown on neuromuscular performance and body composition in elite futsal players. J Strength Cond Res. 2021; 35(8):2309&#x2013;2315. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34100785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villaseca-Vicu&#xf1;a R, P&#xe9;rez-Contreras J, Merino-Mu&#xf1;oz P, Aedo-Mu&#xf1;oz E, Gonz&#xe1;les Jurado JA, Zabaloy S. Effects of COVID-19 lockdown on body composition and physical performance of elite female football players. Women Sport Phys Act J. 2022; 30(1):44&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1123/wspaj.2022-0002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/wspaj.2022-0002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela PL, Rivas F, S&#xe1;nchez-Mart&#xed;nez G. Effects of COVID-19 lockdown and a subsequent retraining period on elite athletes&#x2019; workload, performance, and autonomic responses: a case series. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2021; 16(11):1707&#x2013;1711. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2020-0735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33873155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambro&#x17c;y T, Rydzik &#x141;, Obmi&#x144;ski Z, Klimek AT, Serafin N, Litwiniuk A, Czaja R, Czarny W. The impact of reduced training activity of elite kickboxers on physical fitness, body build, and performance during competitions. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021; 18(8):4342. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18084342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18084342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33923913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scoz RD, Burigo RL, Ferreira IC, Hespanhol L, Silveira Ramos AP, Schlosser A, Baltazar Mendes JJ, Alves Ferreira LM, Amorim CF. Strength level of professional elite soccer players after the COVID-19 lockdown period: a retrospective double-arm cohort study. J Sports Med (Hindawi Publ Corp). 2022; 2022(1):8242210. doi: 10.1155/2022/8242210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/8242210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35252459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campa F, Bongiovanni T, Trecroci A, Rossi A, Greco G, Pasta G, Coratella G. Effects of the COVID-19 lockdown on body composition and bioelectrical phase angle in serie A soccer players: a comparison of two consecutive seasons. Biology (Basel). 2021; 10(11):1175. doi: 10.3390/biology10111175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biology10111175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8614814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34827168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaster DT, Gill N, Cronin J, McGuigan M. The development, retention and decay rates of strength and power in elite rugby union, rugby league and American football: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2013; 43:367&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1007/s40279-013-0031-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0031-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23529287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabaloy S, Freitas TT, Pareja-Blanco F, Alcaraz PE, Loturco I. Narrative review on the use of sled training to improve sprint performance in team sport athletes. Strength Cond J. 2023; 45(1):13&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Horst N, Priesterbach A, Backx F, Smits DW. Hamstring-and-lowerback flexibility in male amateur soccer players. Clin J Sport Med. 2017; 27(1):20&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1097/JSM.0000000000000294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JSM.0000000000000294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26829607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvurdu S, Baykal C, Akyildiz Z, &#x15e;enel &#xd6;, Silva AF, Conte D, Clemente FM. Impact of prolonged absence of organized training on body composition, neuromuscular performance, and aerobic capacity: a study in youth male soccer players exposed to COVID-19 lockdown. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022; 19(3):1148. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19031148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19031148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8834273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35162174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering BA, Mujika I, Sharp MA, Foulis S. Maintaining physical performance: the minimal dose of exercise needed to preserve endurance and strength over time. J. Strength Cond. Res. 2021; 35:1449&#x2013;1458. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33629972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I., Padilla S. Detraining: loss of training-induced physiological and performance adaptations. Part I: short term insufficient training stimulus. Sports Med. 2000; 30:79&#x2013;87. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200030020-00002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200030020-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Detraining: loss of training-induced physiological and performance adaptations. Part II: long term insufficient training stimulus. Sports Med. 2000; 30:145&#x2013;54. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200030030-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200030030-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10999420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koundourakis NE, Androulakis NE, Malliaraki N, Tsatsanis C, Venihaki M, Margioris AN. Discrepancy between exercise performance, body composition, and sex steroid response after a six-week detraining period in professional soccer players. PLoS One. 2014; 9(2):e87803. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0087803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0087803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3929557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24586293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J, Pan T, Jiang Y, Shen Y. Effects of short-and long-term detraining on maximal oxygen uptake in athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Biomed Res Int. 2022; 2022(1):2130993. doi: 10.1155/2022/2130993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/2130993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9398774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36017396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente FM, Ramirez-Campillo R, Sarmento H. Detrimental effects of the off-season in soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2021; 51:795&#x2013;814. doi: 10.1007/s40279-020-01407-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01407-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33400214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Seiler S, Haugen T, Farooq A, Quarrie K, Janse van Rensburg DC, Krug I, Verhagen E, Wong DP, Mujika I, Cortis C, Haddad M, Ahmadian O, Al Jufaili M, Al-Horani RA, Al-Mohannadi AS, Aloui A, Ammar A, Arifi F, Aziz AR, Batuev M, Beaven CM, Beneke R, Bici A, Bishnoi P, Bogwasi L, Bok D, Boukhris O, Boullosa D, Bragazzi N, Brito J, Palacios Cartagena RP, Chaouachi A, Cheung SS, Chtourou H, Cosma G, Debevec T, DeLang MD, Dellal A, D&#xf6;nmez G, Driss T, Pe&#xf1;a Duque JD, Eirale C, Elloumi M, Foster C, Franchini E, Fusco A, Galy O, Gastin PB, Gill N, Girard O, Gregov C, Halson S, Hammouda O, Hanzl&#xed;kov&#xe1; I, Hassanmirzaei B, H&#xe9;bert-Losier K, Mu&#xf1;oz Hel&#xfa; H, Herrera-Valenzuela T, Hettinga FJ, Holtzhausen L, Hue O, Dello Iacono A, Ihalainen JK, James C, Joseph S, Kamoun K, Khaled M, Khalladi K, Kim KJ, Kok LY, MacMillan L, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Matsunaga R, Memishi S, Millet GP, Moussa-Chamari I, Musa DI, Nguyen HMT, Nikolaidis PT, Owen A, Padulo J, Pagaduan JC, Perera NP, P&#xe9;rez-G&#xf3;mez J, Pillay L, Popa A, Pudasaini A, Rabbani A, Rahayu T, Romdhani M, Salamh P, Sarkar AS, Schillinger A, Setyawati H, Shrestha N, Suraya F, Tabben M, Trabelsi K, Urhausen A, Valtonen M, Weber J, Whiteley R, Zrane A, Zerguini Y, Zmijewski P, Ben Saad H, Pyne DB, Taylor L, Chamari K.. COVID-19 lockdown: a global study investigating the effect of athletes&#x2019; sport classification and sex on training practices. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2022; 17(8):1242&#x2013;1256. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2021-0543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2021-0543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35894967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Muscular characteristics of detraining in humans. Med Sci Sports Exer. 2001; 33(8):1297&#x2013;1303. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200108000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200108000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11474330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira LA, Freitas TT, Pivetti B, Alcaraz PE, Jeffreys I, Loturco I. Short-term detraining does not impair strength, speed, and power performance in elite young soccer players. Sports (Basel). 2020; 8(11):141. doi: 10.3390/sports8110141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports8110141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardakis L, Michailidis Y, Mandroukas A, Zelenitsas C, Mavrommatis G, Metaxas T. Effects of a shock microcycle after COVID-19 lockdown period in elite soccer players. Sci Sports. 2022; 37(7):572&#x2013;580. doi: 10.1016/j.scispo.2022.07.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2022.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9420708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36062208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HH, Tsai WC, Tu JH, Wu BH, Chen CH. Online and supervised exercise improves physical performance: a study conducted during COVID-19. Sport Sci Health. 2025. doi: 10.1007/s11332-025-01335-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-025-01335-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita D, Yamazaki K, Yamagishi T, Tsubokura H, Washif JA, Mujika I. Training practices of Japanese elite team and combat sport athletes during the COVID-19 pandemic: An interview study with support staff. Front Sports Act Living. 2025; 7:1557774. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2025.1557774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2025.1557774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12443745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40980083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent HK, Patel S, Zaremski JL. Impact of COVID on sports injury patterns, changes in mental well-being, and strategies to prepare for future pandemics in sport. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2022; 21(6):196&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1249/JSR.0000000000000966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0000000000000966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35703746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Mohd Kassim SFA, Lew PCF, Chong CSM, James C. Athlete&#x2019;s perceptions of a quarantine training camp during the COVID-19 lockdown. Front Sports Act Living. 2021; 14(2):622858. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2020.622858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2020.622858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33521634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Ammar A, Trabelsi K, Chamari K, Chong CSM, Mohd Kassim SFA, Lew PCF, Farooq A, Pyne DB, James C.. Regression analysis of perceived stress among elite athletes from changes in diet, routine and well-being: effects of the COVID-19 lockdown and bubble training camps. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021; 19(1):402. doi: 10.3390/ijerph19010402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19010402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8744934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35010662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa MJ, Garrido ND, Marinho DA, Santos CC. How much the swimming performance leading to Tokyo 2020 Olympic Games was impaired due to the COVID-19 lockdown? J Sports Sci Med. 2021; 20(4):714&#x2013;720. doi: 10.52082/jssm.2021.714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52082/jssm.2021.714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35321138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banning A, van Meurs E, Dreisk&#xe4;mper D. COVID-19 affected elite track-and-field athletes&#x2019; Olympic preparation before Tokyo 2020 compared to Rio 2016. Sci Rep. 2025; 15(1):6044. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-86883-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-86883-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11840131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39971930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosova S, Kosova MK. The effect of the detraining period caused by the COVID-19 pandemic on the change of direction performance of fencers. Phys Educ Stud. 2021; 25(1):4&#x2013;9. doi: 10.15561/20755279.2021.0101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15561/20755279.2021.0101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Hettinga FJ, Ammar A, van Rensburg DC, Materne O, Trabelsi K, Romdhani M, Farooq A, Pyne DB, Chamari K. Supporting athletes during a challenging situation: recommendations from a global insight of COVID-19 home-based training experience. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024; 16(1):83. doi: 10.1186/s13102-024-00869-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-024-00869-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11017558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38622683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousfi N, Bragazzi NL, Briki W, Zmijewski P, Chamari K. The COVID-19 pandemic: how to maintain a healthy immune system during the lockdown&#x2013;a multidisciplinary approach with special focus on athletes. Biol Sport. 2020; 37(3):211&#x2013;216. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2020.95125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2020.95125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7433333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32879542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romdhani M, Ammar A, Trabelsi K, Chtourou H, Vitale JA, Masmoudi L, N&#xe9;d&#xe9;lec M, Rae DE, Al Horani RA, Ben Saad H, Bragazzi N, D&#xf6;nmez G, Dergaa I, Driss T, Farooq A, Hammouda O, Harroum N, Hassanmirzaei B, Khalladi K, Khemila S, Mataruna-Dos-Santos LJ, Moussa-Chamari I, Mujika I, Mu&#xf1;oz Hel&#xfa; H, Norouzi Fashkhami A, Paineiras-Domingos LL, Khaneghah MR, Saita Y, Souabni M, Souissi N, Washif JA, Weber J, Zmijewski P, Taylor L, Garbarino S, Chamari K. Ramadan observance exacerbated the negative effects of COVID-19 lockdown on sleep and training behaviors: a international survey on 1,681 muslim athletes. Front Nutr. 2022; 9:925092. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2022.925092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2022.925092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9283087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35845770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif J, Pyne DB, Sandbakk &#xd8;, Trabelsi K, Aziz AR, Beaven C, Krug I, Mujika I, Ammar A, Chaouachi A, Moussa-Chamari I, Aloui A, Chtourou H, Farooq A, Haddad M, Romdhani M, Salamh P, Tabben M, Wong DP, Zerguini Y, DeLang MD, Taylor L, Saad HB, Chamari K. Ramadan intermittent fasting induced poorer training practices during the COVID-19 lockdown: A global cross-sectional study with 5529 athletes from 110 countries. Biol Sport. 2022; 39(4):1103&#x2013;1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9536381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36247962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamari K, Saad HB, Dhahbi W, Washif JA, El Omri A, Zmijewski P, Dergaa I. Mpox in sports: A comprehensive framework for anticipatory planning and risk mitigation in football based on lessons from COVID-19. Biol Sport. 2024; 41(4):317&#x2013;335. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.144014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.144014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11475015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39416489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dergaa I, Saad HB, El Omri A, Glenn J, Clark C, Washif JA, Guelmami N, Hammouda O, Al-Horani R, Reynoso-S&#xe1;nchez L, Romdhani M. Using artificial intelligence for exercise prescription in personalised health promotion: A critical evaluation of OpenAI&#x2019;s GPT-4 model. Biol Sport. 2024; 41(2):221&#x2013;241. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.133661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.133661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10955739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washif JA, Pagaduan J, James C, Dergaa I, Beaven CM. Artificial intelligence in sport: exploring the potential of using ChatGPT in resistance training prescription. Biol Sport. 2024; 41(2):209&#x2013;220. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2024.132987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2024.132987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10955742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38524820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>