<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41654621</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sulfuric acid corrosion resistance of recycled aggregate concrete containing magnetized water.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7770</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-38607-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Excessive consumption of natural aggregates in concrete production has led to resource depletion and environmental degradation. Recycled aggregate concrete (RAC) offers a sustainable alternative; however, its mechanical strength and durability are often inferior, especially under aggressive acidic environments such as acid rain. This study aims to enhance the mechanical and durability performance of RAC by combining magnetized water (MW) and nano-silica (NS) as complementary modification techniques. A total of 80 concrete mixtures were prepared with varying recycled concrete aggregate (RCA) contents (0&#x2013;100%), NS dosages (0&#x2013;6%), and MW exposure times (0&#x2013;30&#xa0;min). The specimens were exposed to simulated acid rain with pH values of 2.5, 4.0, 5.5, and 7.0 for 28, 56, and 90 days. Tests for compressive strength, electrical resistivity, mass loss, and sorptivity coefficient were conducted to evaluate performance. Results showed that the use of RCA reduced compressive strength by up to 25.4%, while increasing the acidity from pH 7 to 2.5 caused an additional 16.2&#x2013;25.4% decline. However, the synergistic use of 6% NS and 30-min MW improved compressive strength by up to 14.1% compared to control specimens. Similarly, the combination of MW and NS enhanced electrical resistivity by 12&#x2013;38% and reduced mass loss and compressive strength by 33% and 32%, respectively, demonstrating a denser and more durable microstructure. These findings confirm that MW and NS mitigate the detrimental effects of acid exposure and recycled aggregates by accelerating cement hydration, refining pore structure, and strengthening the interfacial transition zone. The optimal mix was found at 25% RCA, 6% NS, and 30&#xa0;min MW exposure, which achieved superior performance across all parameters. It is concluded that the combined application of MW and NS offers a feasible and eco-efficient approach to improve the corrosion resistance and sustainability of RAC under acid rain. Future studies are recommended to investigate the long-term field performance of RAC in other aggressive media such as chloride environments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-38607-3.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bamshad</LastName><ForeName>Omid</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Imam Khomeini International University, Qazvin, Iran. Omid.bamshad@ut.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salehi</LastName><ForeName>Sheyda</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil, Environmental and Land Management Engineering, Politecnico di Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Habibi</LastName><ForeName>Alireza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture, Building and Civil Engineering, Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manouchehri</LastName><ForeName>Navid</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Price Faculty of Engineering, University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montazeri</LastName><ForeName>Parvin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Imam Khomeini International University, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hakamian</LastName><ForeName>Iman</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahdikhani</LastName><ForeName>Mahdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Imam Khomeini International University, Qazvin, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acid rain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corrosion resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Durability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetized water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41654621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12949232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-38607-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-38607-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hamada, H. M. et al. Optimization of sustainable concrete characteristics incorporating palm oil clinker and nano-palm oil fuel ash using response surface methodology. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>413</b>, 118054 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2022.118054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shawais, Z. A., Abdulhaleem, K. N., Hamada, H. &amp; Mohammed, V. R. Influence of recycled coarse aggregate and steel fiber on the workability and strength of self-compacting concrete. <i>Earth Environ. Sci.</i><b>1374</b>, 12084 (2024). IOP Conf. Ser.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montazeri, P., Bamshad, O., Aghililotf, M. &amp; Singh, P. Mechanical and durability-based life cycle assessment of rice husk Ash containing concrete, case stud. <i>Constr. Mater.</i> e05241. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Gao, J., Liu, C. &amp; Chen, G. Cementitious properties of sustainable alkali-activated materials with ground GGBS-based geopolymer waste powder as recycled precursor. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>88</b>, 109210 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Gao, J., Liu, C., Guo, Z. &amp; Luo, X. Reusing waste clay brick powder for low-carbon cement concrete and alkali-activated concrete: A critical review. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>449</b>, 141755 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H., Gao, J., Liu, C., Luo, X. &amp; Chen, G. Combine use of 100% thermoactivated recycled cement and recycled aggregate for fully recycled mortar: properties evaluation and modification. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>450</b>, 141841 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comprising, C., Sand, D., Materials, C., Response, U. &amp; Methodology, S. Optimization and modeling of 7-day ultra-high-performance concrete comprising desert sand and supplementary cementitious materials using response surface methodology. <i>Buildings</i><b>14</b>, 2075&#x2013;5309 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada, H. M., Al-attar, A. A., Tayeh, B., Bin, F. &amp; Yahaya, M. Optimizing the concrete strength of lightweight concrete containing nano palm oil fuel ash and palm oil clinker using response surface method. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>16</b>, e01061 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada, H. M., Al-attar, A. A., Tayeh, B., Yahaya, F. B. M. &amp; Aisheh, Y. I. A. Optimising concrete containing palm oil clinker and palm oil fuel ash using response surface method. <i>Ain Shams Eng. J.</i><b>14</b>, 102150 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asej.2023.102150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Yan, L., Fu, Q. &amp; Kasal, B. A comprehensive review on recycled aggregate and recycled aggregate concrete. <i>Resour. Conserv. Recycl</i>. <b>171</b>, 105565 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2021.105565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi, A., Tavakoli, H., Esmaeili, A. &amp; Golzary, A. Comparative life cycle assessment (LCA) of concrete mixtures: A critical review. <i>Eur. J. Environ. Civ. Eng.</i><b>27</b>, 1285&#x2013;1303 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19648189.2022.2078885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. et al. Prediction and multi-objective optimization of workability and compressive strength of recycled self-consolidating mortar using Taguchi design method, <i>Heliyon</i>. (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10248084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37303530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. &amp; Ramezanianpour, A. M. Assessing the sustainability potential of circular geopolymer concrete: A life cycle assessment and multi-criteria decision making approach. <i>Mater. Today Sustain.</i><b>33</b>, 101297 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. et al. Predicting corrosion of recycled aggregate concrete under sulfuric acid rain using machine learning and uncertainty analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>438</b>, 137146 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. &amp; Ramezanianpour, A. M. Optimizing concrete for circularity: a comparative life cycle assessment of geopolymer and ordinary concrete. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut Res.</i><b>31</b>, 1&#x2013;24 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39244520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi, A., Bamshad, O., Golzary, A., Buswell, R. &amp; Osmani, M. Biases in life cycle assessment of circular concrete. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>192</b>, 114237 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2023.114237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi, A., Ramezanianpour, A. M. &amp; Mahdikhani, M. RSM-based optimized mix design of recycled aggregate concrete containing supplementary cementitious materials based on waste generation and global warming potential. <i>Resour. Conserv. Recycl</i>. <b>167</b>, 105420 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2021.105420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. &amp; Mohammad, A. Evaluating geopolymer concrete viability: Cradle-to-cradle durability-based life cycle cost assessment. <i>Environ. Dev. Sustain.</i> (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi, A., Buswell, R., Osmani, M. &amp; Aziminezhad, M. Sustainability principles in 3D concrete printing: analysing trends, classifying strategies, and future directions. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>98</b>, 111354 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, L. et al. Characterizing the generation and flows of construction and demolition waste in China. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>136</b>, 405&#x2013;413. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.01.055 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.01.055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrew, R. M. Global CO2 emissions from cement production. <i>Earth Syst. Sci. Data</i>. <b>10</b>, 195&#x2013;217 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-10-195-2018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NYC Department of Design &amp; Construction, Construction &amp; demolition waste manual, 1&#x2013;24. (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulhaleem, K. N., Mohammed, V. R., Hamada, H. M., Humada, A. M. &amp; Majdi, A. Effect of recycled aggregate concrete and steel fibers on the strength of self-compacting concrete. <i>E3S Web Conf.</i><b>427</b>, 2012 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202342702012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skariah, B. et al. Geopolymer concrete incorporating recycled aggregates: A comprehensive review ordinary Portland cement. <i>Clean. Mater.</i><b>3</b>, 100056 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clema.2022.100056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. Development of nano-silica treatment methods to enhance recycled aggregate concrete. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>118</b>, 103963. 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.103963 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.103963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed, V. R., Abdulhaleem, K. N., Hamada, H. M., Humada, A. M. &amp; Majdi, A. Effect of recycled aggregate concrete and steel fibers on the fresh properties of self-compacting concrete. <i>E3S Web Conf.</i><b>427</b>, 2013 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/e3sconf/202342702013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R., Yu, N. &amp; Li, Y. Methods for improving the microstructure of recycled concrete aggregate: A review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>242</b>, 118164. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118164 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mistri, A., Kumar, S., Dhami, N., Mukherjee, A. &amp; Barai, S. V. A review on different treatment methods for enhancing the properties of recycled aggregates for sustainable construction materials. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>233</b>, 117894. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117894 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L., Jin, M., Zhou, S., Tang, S. &amp; Lu, X. Investigation of microstructure of C-S-H and micro-mechanics of cement pastes under NH4NO3 dissolution by 29Si MAS NMR and microhardness. <i>Measurement</i><b>185</b>, 110019. 10.1016/j.measurement.2021.110019 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2021.110019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam, V. W. Y., Butera, A., Le, K. N. &amp; Li, W. Utilising CO2 technologies for recycled aggregate concrete: A critical review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>250</b>, 118903. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118903 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy, B. S. K., Ghorpade, V. G. &amp; Rao, H. S. Influence of magnetic water on strength properties of concrete. <i>Indian J. Sci. Technol.</i><b>7</b>, 14&#x2013;18 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17485/ijst/2014/v7i1.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, C., Zhou, Q., Wang, W., Wei, S. &amp; Wang, C. Freeze-thaw resistance of recycled aggregate concrete damaged by simulated acid rain. <i>J. Clean. Prod. J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>280</b>, 124396. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124396 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanger, M., Natarajan, B. M., Wang, B., Edil, T. &amp; Ginder-Vogel, M. Recycled concrete aggregate in base course applications: review of field and laboratory investigations of leachate pH. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>385</b>, 121562 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2019.121562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31732334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Zhu, Z., Sun, X. &amp; Wang, X. Deterioration of fracture toughness of concrete under acid rain environment. <i>Eng. Fail. Anal.</i><b>77</b>, 76&#x2013;84. 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2017.02.013 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2017.02.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, F., Chen, M., Huang, H., Xie, L. &amp; Wang, C. Thin-Walled structures circular concrete Fi Lled steel tubular (CFST) columns under cyclic load and acid rain attack: test simulation. <i>Thin Walled Struct.</i><b>122</b>, 90&#x2013;101. 10.1016/j.tws.2017.10.005 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tws.2017.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, M. et al. Experimental investigation on the potential use of magnetic water as a water reducing agent in high strength concrete. <i>Mater. (Basel)</i>. <b>15</b>, 5219 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15155219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35955156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barhmaiah, B., Priyanka, M. L. &amp; Padmakar, M. Strength analysis and validation of recycled aggregate concrete. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>37</b>, 2312&#x2013;2317. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail, S. &amp; Ramli, M. Engineering properties of treated recycled concrete aggregate (RCA) for structural applications. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>44</b>, 464&#x2013;476. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.03.014 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.03.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, Y., Hanif, A., Kazmi, S. M. S., Munir, M. J. &amp; Park, C. Properties enhancement of recycled aggregate concrete through pretreatment of coarse aggregates e comparative assessment of assorted techniques. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>191</b>, 339&#x2013;349. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.04.192 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.04.192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katkhuda, H. &amp; Shatarat, N. Improving the mechanical properties of recycled concrete aggregate using chopped basalt fibers and acid treatment. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>140</b>, 328&#x2013;335. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.02.128 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.02.128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam, V. W. Y., Tam, C. M. &amp; Le, K. N. Removal of cement mortar remains from recycled aggregate using pre-soaking approaches. <b>50</b>, 82&#x2013;101. 10.1016/j.resconrec.2006.05.012 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. &amp; Mahdikhani, M. Rheological properties of self- compacting mortar made with magnetic water. <i>J. Eng. Constr. Manag</i>. <b>5</b>, 19&#x2013;22 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. et al. Effects of nano-SiO2 modification on rubberised mortar and concrete with recycled coarse aggregates. <i>Nanotechnol Rev.</i><b>11</b>, 473&#x2013;496 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ntrev-2022-0024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, W. &amp; Lim, C. W. Production of sustainable and structural Fi Ber reinforced recycled aggregate concrete with improved fracture properties: A review. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>279</b>, 123832. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.123832 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.123832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotto-ramos, A., D&#xe1;vila, S., Torres-garc&#xed;a, W. &amp; C&#xe1;ceres-fern&#xe1;ndez, A. Experimental design of concrete mixtures using recycled plastic, fly ash, and silica nanoparticles. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>254</b>, 119207. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119207 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazmi, S. M. S. et al. Effect of recycled aggregate treatment techniques on the durability of concrete: A comparative evaluation. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>264</b>, 120284. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120284 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siahkouhi, M. et al. Comparative life cycle assessment of smart self-sensing concrete sensor vs. conventional polyester foil strain gauge sensor: A cradle-to-grave study, case stud. <i>Constr. Mater.</i><b>23</b>, e05415 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farnam, S. M., Mansourpoor, A., Bamshad, O. &amp; Maleki, Z. A novel method for evaluating bonding performance and mechanical properties of steel fiber concrete containing Metakaolin. <i>J. Eng. Constr. Manag</i>. <b>9</b>, 46&#x2013;54 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. et al. Investigation of electromagnetic wave absorption of concrete containing metakaolin and carbon black. <i>Clin. Cancer Investig J.</i><b>11</b>, CCLS220256 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, L. et al. Characterizing the generation and flows of construction and demolition waste in China. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>136</b>, 405&#x2013;413. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.01.055 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.01.055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, U., Sun, C., Lo, I. M. C. &amp; Cheng, J. C. P. Comparative environmental evaluation of aggregate production from recycled waste materials and Virgin sources by LCA. <i>Resour. Conserv. Recycl</i>. <b>109</b>, 67&#x2013;77. 10.1016/j.resconrec.2016.02.009 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2016.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziminezhad, M., Habibi, A., Jamhiri, B., Bamshad, O. &amp; Aziminezhad, M. Beyond carbon: an integrated LCA &#x2013; MCDA framework for circularity measurement of ordinary and geopolymer concrete. <i>Environ. Impact Assess. Rev.</i><b>116</b>, 108133 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eiar.2025.108133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman, J. V. M. &amp; Ramasamy, V. Various treatment techniques involved to enhance the recycled coarse aggregate in concrete: A review. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>45</b>, 6356&#x2013;6363. 10.1016/j.matpr.2020.10.935 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.10.935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghililotf, M., Mohammad, A. &amp; Bamshad, O. Deicer-salt scaling resistance of recycled aggregate concrete containing natural zeolite. <i>Results Eng.</i><b>27</b>, 106095 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rineng.2025.106095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O., Ramezanianpour, A. M. &amp; Habibi, A. Freeze-thaw resistance and chloride permeability of circular CKD-based alkali-activated concrete. <i>Structures</i><b>78</b>, 109308 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2025.109308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghililotf, M., Ramezanianpour, A. M., Bamshad, O. &amp; Hajimohammadi, A. Long-term performance of recycled aggregate concrete incorporating natural zeolite. <i>Struct. Concr</i> 1&#x2013;31. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, J., Li, W., Fan, Y. &amp; Huang, X. An overview of study on recycled aggregate concrete in China (1996&#x2013;2011). <i>Constr.Build. Mater.</i><b>31</b>, 364&#x2013;383. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2011.12.074 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2011.12.074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-hawary, M. &amp; Al-sulily, A. Internal curing of recycled aggregates concrete. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>275</b>, 122911 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.122911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim, S. T., Meyer, C. &amp; Herfellner, S. Effects of internal curing on the strength, drying shrinkage and freeze &#x2013; thaw resistance of concrete containing recycled concrete aggregates. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>91</b>, 288&#x2013;296. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.05.045 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.05.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, C. et al. Performance enhancement of recycled concrete aggregate - a review. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>112</b>, 466&#x2013;472. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.08.057 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.08.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, C. et al. Chloride transport and induced steel corrosion in recycled aggregate concrete: A review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>282</b>, 122547. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122547 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y., Zhang, Y. &amp; Zhang, P. Methods for improving the durability of recycled aggregate concrete: A review. <i>J. Mater. Res. Technol.</i><b>15</b>, 6367&#x2013;6386. 10.1016/j.jmrt.2021.11.085 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2021.11.085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, Y. F., Hu, Z. Q., Zhang, Y. Z. &amp; Liu, J. L. Deterioration of compressive property of concrete under simulated acid rain environment. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>24</b>, 1975&#x2013;1983. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.04.002 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.04.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O., Hakamian, I., Fallah, M., Habibi, A. &amp; Mahdikhani, M. Long-term corrosion behavior of reinforced recycled aggregate concrete under acid rain condition. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>22</b>, e04834 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, L., Lai, Y., Rashadul, M., Pramanic, I. &amp; Zhang, W. Deterioration of Portland cement pervious concrete in sponge cities subjected to acid rain. <i>Mater. (Basel)</i>. <b>14</b>, 2670 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14102670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8161043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34065191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallahshirvani, M., Bamshad, O., Mahdikhani, M. &amp; Sharifi, R. Investigation of mechanical properties and durability of concrete samples containing nanosilica in acidic flooded condition. <i>J. Eng. Constr. Manag</i>. <b>4</b>, 1&#x2013;7 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallahshirvani, M., Bamshad, O. &amp; Mahdikhani, M. Investigating the mechanical properties and durability of concrete samples containing nano-silica under acid rain conditions. <i>J. Eng. Constr. Manag</i>. <b>4</b>, 7&#x2013;13 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, M., Wang, K. &amp; Xie, L. Deterioration mechanism of cementitious materials under acid rain attack. <i>Eng. Fail. Anal.</i><b>27</b>, 272&#x2013;285. 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2012.08.007 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2012.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, S., Qi, L. &amp; Zhou, D. Investigation of the effects of acid rain on the deterioration of cement concrete using accelerated tests established in laboratory. <i>Atmos. Environ.</i><b>38</b>, 4457&#x2013;4466 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosenv.2004.05.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, C., Zhu, Z., Wang, Z. &amp; Qiu, H. Deterioration of concrete fracture toughness and elastic modulus under simulated acid-sulfate environment. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>176</b>, 490&#x2013;499. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.049 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying-fang, F. A. N. Hai-yang, pore structure in concrete exposed to acid deposit. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>49</b>, 407&#x2013;416 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.08.075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caifeng, L., Wei, W., Qingsong, Z., Shenghuai, W. &amp; Chen, W. Mechanical behavior degradation of recycled aggregate concrete after simulated acid rain spraying. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>262</b>, 121237. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.121237 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.121237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdikhani, M., Bamshad, O. &amp; Fallah Shirvani, M. Mechanical properties and durability of concrete specimens containing nano silica in sulfuric acid rain condition. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>167</b>, 929&#x2013;935 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.01.137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukharjee, B. B. &amp; Barai, S. V. Influence of nano-silica on the properties of recycled aggregate concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>55</b>, 29&#x2013;37. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.01.003 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.01.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, C., Huang, L., Yan, L., Jin, R. &amp; Chen, H. Mechanical properties of recycled aggregate concrete modified by nano-particles. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>241</b>, 118030 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, N. &amp; Wu, C. Effect of magnetic field treated water on mortar and concrete containing fly ash. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>25</b>, 681&#x2013;688 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0958-9465(02)00098-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afshin, H., Gholizadeh, M. &amp; Khorshidi, N. Improving mechanical properties of high strength concrete by magnetic water technology. <i>Sci. Iran.</i><b>17</b>, 74&#x2013;79 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmaraj, R. et al. Investigation of mechanical and durability properties of concrete mixed with water exposed to a magnetic field. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i><b>2021</b>, 2821419. 10.1155/2021/2821419 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. M. &amp; Manar, D. F. Effect of static magnetic field treatment on fresh concrete and water reduction potential. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>14</b>, e00535 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadgouda, P. A. et al. Investigation of fresh &amp; hardened properties of concrete manufactured with magnetically treated water. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i>10.1016/j.matpr.2023.03.726 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S. M. Effect of magnetic water on engineering properties of concrete. <i>Al-Rafidain Eng.</i><b>17</b>, 71&#x2013;82 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholizadeh, M. &amp; Arabshahi, H. The effect of magnetic water on strength parameters of concrete. <i>J. Eng. Technol. Res.</i><b>3</b>, 77&#x2013;81 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sameer, N. M., Kumar, G. N. &amp; Kumar, T. N. Experimental investigation on effect of magnetic water on concrete by partial replacement of cement with steel slag and quartz Powder, Mod. Approaches Mach. Learn. Cogn. Sci. A walkthrough. <i>Cham Springer Int. Publ</i> 501&#x2013;516. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Magid, T. I. M., Hamdan, R. M., Abdelgader, A. A. B., Omer, M. E. A. &amp; Ahmed, N. M. R. A. Effect of magnetized water on workability and compressive strength of concrete. <i>Procedia Eng.</i><b>193</b>, 494&#x2013;500 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.proeng.2017.06.242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholhaki, M., Kehroddin, A., Hajforoush, M. &amp; Kazemi, M. An investigation on the fresh and hardened properties of self-compacting concrete incorporating magnetic water with various pozzolanic materials. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>158</b>, 173&#x2013;180 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.09.135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, N., Wu, Y. &amp; Mar, C. Effect of magnetic water on the engineering properties of concrete containing granulated blast-furnace slag. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>30</b>, 599&#x2013;605 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(00)00215-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkerany, A. M., Elshikh, M. M. Y., Elshami, A. A. &amp; Youssf, O. Effect of water magnetization technique on the properties of metakaolin-based sustainable concrete. <i>Constr. Mater.</i><b>3</b>, 434&#x2013;448 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamed, Y. R., Elshikh, M. M. Y., Elshami, A. A., Matthana, M. H. S. &amp; Youssf, O. Mechanical properties of fly ash and silica fume based geopolymer concrete made with magnetized water activator. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>411</b>, 134376 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khorshidi, N., Ansari, M. &amp; Bayat, M. An investigation of water magnetization and its influence on some concrete specificities like fluidity and compressive strength. <i>Comput. Concr</i>. <b>13</b>, 649&#x2013;657 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12989/cac.2014.13.5.649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toledo, E. J. L., Ramalho, T. C. &amp; Magriotis, Z. M. Influence of magnetic field on physical &#x2013; chemical properties of the liquid water: insights from experimental and theoretical models. <i>J. Mol. Struct.</i><b>888</b>, 409&#x2013;415 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2008.01.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adegbemileke, S. A., Osuji, S. O. &amp; Ogirigbo, O. R. An assessment of the pozzolanic potential and mechanical properties of Nigerian calcined clays for sustainable ternary cement blends. <i>Sustain. Struct.</i><b>4</b>, 57 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, O. A., Zuaiter, H. A. &amp; Jawa, M. M. Carbonation and chloride penetration resistance of sustainable structural concrete with alkali-activated and ordinary Portland cement binders: a critical review. <i>Sustain. Struct.</i><b>5</b>, 75 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54113/j.sust.2025.000075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury, J. A., Islam, M. S., Islam, M. A., Al Bari, M. A. &amp; Debnath, A. K. Analysis of mechanical properties of fly ash and boiler slag integrated geopolymer composites. <i>Sustain. Struct.</i><b>5</b>, 73 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathiparan, N. &amp; Subramaniam, D. N. Optimizing fly ash and rice husk ash as cement replacements on the mechanical characteristics of pervious concrete. <i>Sustain. Struct. ISSN</i>. <b>5</b>, 65 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaidi, S. A., Khan, M. A. &amp; Naqvi, T. A review on the properties of recycled aggregate concrete (RAC) modified with nano-silica. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i>10.1016/j.matpr.2023.03.674 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2023.03.674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senff, L., Hotza, D., Repette, W. L., Ferreira, V. M. &amp; Labrincha, J. A. Mortars with nano-SiO2 and micro-SiO2 investigated by experimental design. <i>Constr. Build. Mater. J.</i><b>24</b>, 1432&#x2013;1437 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez, J. M. et al. Influence of nanosilica and a polycarboxylate ether superplasticizer on the performance of lime mortars. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>43</b>, 12&#x2013;24. 10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.10.007 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.10.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla, J. A. et al. Influence of nano-TiO2, nano-Fe2O3, nanoclay and nano-CaCO3 on the properties of cement/geopolymer concrete. <i>Clean. Mater.</i><b>4</b>, 100061 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clema.2022.100061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, Z. et al. Improving recycled aggregate concrete by compression casting and nano - silica. <i>Nanotechnol Rev.</i><b>11</b>, 1273&#x2013;1290 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ntrev-2022-0065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukharjee, B. B. &amp; Barai, S. V. Influence of incorporation of nano-silica and recycled aggregates on compressive strength and microstructure of concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>71</b>, 570&#x2013;578. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.08.040 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.08.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W. et al. Effects of nanoparticle on the dynamic behaviors of recycled aggregate concrete under impact loading. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>112</b>, 58&#x2013;66. 10.1016/j.matdes.2016.09.045 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2016.09.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh, F., Chavda, V., Minhaj, N. &amp; Arel, H. S. Effect of mixing methods of nano silica on properties of recycled aggregate concrete. <i>Struct. Concr</i>. <b>19</b>, 387&#x2013;399 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.201700091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. et al. Effect of Fenton pre-oxidation on mobilization of nutrients and efficient subsequent bioremediation of crude oil-contaminated soil. <i>Chemosphere</i><b>180</b>, 1&#x2013;10. 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2017.03.087 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2017.03.087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28376354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahiri, F. &amp; Eskandari-naddaf, H. Optimizing the compressive strength of concrete containing micro-silica, nano-silica, and polypropylene fibers using extreme vertices mixture design. <i>Front. Struct. Civ. Eng.</i><b>13</b>, 821&#x2013;830 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11709-019-0518-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewiadomski, P., Stefaniuk, D. &amp; Ho&#x142;a, J. Microstructural analysis of self-compacting concrete modified with the addition of nanoparticles. <i>Procedia Eng.</i><b>172</b>, 776&#x2013;783. 10.1016/j.proeng.2017.02.122 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.proeng.2017.02.122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamshad, O. Investigating the efficiency and compressive strength of self- compacting mortar containing micro-silica and super-lubricant. <i>Ournal Eng. Constr. Manag</i>. <b>4</b>, 30&#x2013;34 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahapatra, C. K. &amp; Barai, S. V. Temperature impact on residual properties of self-compacting based hybrid fiber reinforced concrete with fly Ash and colloidal nano silica. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>198</b>, 120&#x2013;132. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.155 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdem, S., Hanbay, S. &amp; G&#xfc;ler, Z. Micromechanical damage analysis and engineering performance of concrete with colloidal nano-silica and demolished concrete aggregates. <i>Constr. Build. Mater. J.</i><b>171</b>, 634&#x2013;642 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghorbani, S. et al. Simultaneous effect of granite waste dust as partial replacement of cement and magnetized water on the properties of concrete exposed to NaCl and H2SO4 solutions. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>288</b>, 123064. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123064 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devi, S. C. &amp; Khan, R. A. Effect of sulfate attack and carbonation in graphene oxide&#x2013;reinforced concrete containing recycled concrete aggregate. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>32</b>, 4020339 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0003415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshta, M. M., Elshikh, M. M. Y., Kaloop, M. R., Hu, J. &amp; ELMohsenf, I. A. Effect of magnetized water on characteristics of sustainable concrete using volcanic ash. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>361</b>, 129640 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, M. et al. Influence of magnetic water on concrete properties with different magnetic field exposure times. <i>Materiales</i><b>15</b>, 4291 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15124291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9227616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35744364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ELShami, A. A., Essam, N. &amp; Yousry, E. M. Improvement of hydration products for self-compacting concrete by using magnetized water. <i>Frat Ed. Integrit&#xe0; Strutt</i>. <b>61</b>, 352&#x2013;371 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi, A., Mohammad, A., Mahdikhani, M. &amp; Bamshad, O. RSM-based evaluation of mechanical and durability properties of recycled aggregate concrete containing GGBFS and silica fume. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>270</b>, 121431 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younis, K. H. &amp; Mustafa, S. M. Feasibility of using nanoparticles of SiO2 to improve the performance of recycled aggregate concrete. <i>Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng.</i><b>2018</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/1512830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khreef, S. M. &amp; Abbas, Z. K. The effects of using magnetized water in reactive powder concrete with different curing methods. <i>4th Int. Conf. Eng. Sci.</i><b>1067</b>, 12017 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, A., Laad, A., Singh, K. &amp; Murari, K. Effect of magnetic water on properties of concrete. <i>Int. J. Eng. Sci. Comput.</i><b>7</b>, 11864&#x2013;11866 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamkhade, P. H., Pathak, N. J. &amp; Potnis, S. C. Experimental investigation of ceramic waste concrete using magnetized water. <i>Int. Res. J. Eng. Technol.</i><b>4</b>, 196&#x2013;200 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C 150-07. Standard specification for Portland cement. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> 1&#x2013;8. (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C 136-01. Standard test method for sieve analysis of fine and coarse aggregates. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> 1&#x2013;5. (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C 127-01. Standard test method for density, relative density (specific gravity), and absorption of coarse aggregate. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> 1&#x2013;6. (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C 128-01. Standard test method for density, relative density (specific gravity), and absorption of fine aggregate. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> 1&#x2013;6. (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C131/C131M-20. Standard test method for resistance to degradation of Small-Size coarse aggregate by abrasion and impact in the Los Angeles machine. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> 1&#x2013;5. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C143/C 143&#xa0;M-03. Standard test method for slump of Hydraulic-Cement concrete. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhrissat, T. Investigation of the effect of magnetic water and polyethylene fiber insertion in concrete mix. <i>J. Compos. Sci.</i><b>7</b>, 303 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcs7070303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BS 1881&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;116. Method for determination of compressive strength of concrete cubes. <i>Br. Stand. Inst.</i> (1983).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C 1202-12. Standard test method for electrical indication of concrete&#x2019;s ability to resist chloride. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> 1&#x2013;8. (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C 1585-04. Standard test method for measurement of rate of absorption of water by hydraulic-cement concrete. <i>Am. Soc. Test. Mater.</i> (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sevim, O., Demir, &#x130;., Alakara, E. H., Guzelkucuk, S. &amp; Bayer, &#x130;. R. The effect of magnetized water on the fresh and hardened properties of slag/fly ash-based cementitious composites. <i>Buildings</i><b>13</b>, 271 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13020271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanzadi, M., Tadayon, M., Sepehri, H. &amp; Sepehri, M. Influence of nano-silica particles on mechanical properties and permeability of concrete. In <i>Second Int. Conf. Sustain. Constr. Mater. Technol. Ancona Italy June</i> 28&#x2013;30. (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LalP. &amp; KavithaP.E. Modified magnetized water concrete using nanosilica. In <i>Proc. SECON 2020 Struct. Eng. Constr. Manag</i>. Vol. 4, 421-431 10.1007/978-3-030-55115-5 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandramouli, K., Pannirselvam, N., Chaitanya, J. &amp; Kumar, D. V. Experimental investigation on magnetized water concrete by partial replacement of cement with silica fume. In <i>AIP Conf. Proc.</i> 2810 (AIP Publishing, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaifar, O., Ghanepour, M. &amp; Amini, M. M. A novel magnetic approach to improve compressive strength and magnetization of concrete containing nano silica and steel fibers. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>91</b>, 109342. 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109342 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zha, X. &amp; Lu, J. Study of durability of recycled concrete under the environment of the acid rain. <i>Appl. Mech. Mater.</i><b>71</b>, 5042&#x2013;5045 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMM.71-78.5042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandit, R. D. &amp; Wadekar, A. Performance evaluation of magnetic field treated water on convectional concrete containing fly ash. <i>Int. J. Sci. Technol. Manag</i>. <b>5</b>, 68&#x2013;77 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahedi, M., Akbar, A. &amp; Mohammad, A. Evaluation of the mechanical properties and durability of cement mortars containing nanosilica and rice husk ash under chloride ion penetration. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>78</b>, 354&#x2013;361. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.01.045 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.01.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nili, M., Ehsani, A. &amp; Shabani, K. Influence of nano-SiO2 and microsilica on concrete performance. In <i>Proc. Second Int. Conf. Sustain. Constr. Mater. Technol.</i> 1&#x2013;5. (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallah, S. &amp; Nematzadeh, M. Mechanical properties and durability of high-strength concrete containing macro-polymeric and polypropylene fibers with nano-silica and silica fume. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>132</b>, 170&#x2013;187 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.11.100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew, P. G. <i>Design of Experiments with MINITAB, ASQ Qual. Press.</i> (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, M. et al. Influence of magnetic water on concrete properties with different magnetic field exposure times. <i>Mater. Artic</i>. <b>15</b>, 4291 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9227616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35744364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, M. et al. Experimental investigation on the potential use of magnetic water as a water reducing agent in high strength concrete. <i>Mater. Artic</i>. <b>15</b>, 5219 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35955156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irfan, M. F., Usman, M. R. &amp; Rashid, A. A detailed statistical study of heterogeneous, homogeneous and nucleation models for dissolution of waste concrete sample for mineral carbonation. <i>Energy</i><b>158</b>, 580&#x2013;591 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2018.06.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdikhani, M. &amp; Bamshad, O. The effect of magnetic water on the mechanical properties of hardened self-compacting mortar. <i>J. Eng. Constr. Manag</i>. <b>4</b>, 42&#x2013;46 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>