<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41355068</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1263</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of applied toxicology : JAT</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Appl Toxicol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health Risk of Rainwater in Erbil, Kurdistan-Iraq: Atmospheric Deposition and Public Health Implication.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jat.70022</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigated the chemical properties and concentrations of major pollutants, including toxic elements, across four zones of Erbil City: city center, industrial, residential, and suburban areas, with samples collected from five sub-sites in each zone. The pH, electrical conductivity (EC), total dissolved solids (TDS), nitrate (NO<sub>3</sub>), sulfate (SO<sub>4</sub>), ammonium (NH<sub>4</sub>) and major toxic elements including chromium (Cr), zinc (Zn), arsenic (As), cadmium (Cd), mercury (Hg), and lead (Pb) were analyzed. In the study area, the pH values ranged from 5.1 to 6.7 with industrial sites revealing slightly acidic conditions (5.1-5.3). Industrial zones revealed elevated EC (&gt;&#x2009;690&#x2009;&#x3bc;S/cm) and TDS (&gt;&#x2009;500&#x2009;mg/L), alongside high NO<sub>3</sub> concentrations (7.5 to 8.1&#x2009;mg/L). Heavy metal analysis revealed that heavy metal concentrations were highest in industrial areas, with Pb reaching 48.0&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/L, Cd 2.1&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/L, Cr 4.5&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/L, and As 3.60&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/L, which were higher than WHO guidelines. While in residential areas, NH<sub>4</sub> levels were (&gt;&#x2009;0.32&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.02&#x2009;mg/L). Sulfate concentrations varied between 0.50 and 2.0&#x2009;mg/L, with industrial sites showing the highest values, and concentrations increased. The results demonstrated that the city center and residential areas showed moderate contamination, while suburban areas demonstrated the lowest pollutant concentrations and revealed minimal anthropogenic influence. The study demonstrated that around 70% of samples posed moderate to high noncarcinogenic risks for children in the studied sites.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qader</LastName><ForeName>Muzhda Q</ForeName><Initials>MQ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3561-7137</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Hawler Medical University, Erbil, Kurdistan Region, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaibur</LastName><ForeName>Molla R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7413-2135</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Science and Technology, Faculty of Applied Science and Technology, Jashore University of Science and Technology, Jashore, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Banna</LastName><ForeName>Dara A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing-Nursing Faculty, Tishk International University, Erbil, Kurdistan Region of Iraq, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hassan</LastName><ForeName>Fikrat M</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, College of Science for Women, University of Baghdad, Baghdad, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharif</LastName><ForeName>Chiyai M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Science and Health, College of Science, Salahaddin University, Erbil, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jirjees</LastName><ForeName>Shevan J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth and Petroleum Sciences, College of Science, Salahaddin University, Erbil, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tenebe</LastName><ForeName>Imokhai T</ForeName><Initials>IT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Appl Toxicol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8109495</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0260-437X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anthropogenic activities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atmospheric deposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">climate change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health risk assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pollution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rainwater</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41355068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jat.70022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdel&#x2010;Razzaq, F. A.&#x2010;W., S. K. Yaseen, and A. A. R. Dhaigham. 2023. &#x201c;Design and Construction of Anair Pollution Detection System Using a Laser Beam and Absorption Spectroscopy.&#x201d; Baghdad Science Journal 20, no. 3: 25. https://doi.org/10.21123/bsj.2022.7650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adegunwa, A., F. M. Adebiyi, and O. Asubiojo. 2020. &#x201c;Evaluating Aerial Pollution Using Rainwater Chemistry for Sustainable Environmental Development.&#x201d; Management of Environmental Quality: An International Journal 31, no. 3: 713&#x2013;739. https://doi.org/10.1108/MEQ&#x2010;07&#x2010;2019&#x2010;0146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Sawafi, A. G., and D. F. Al Maliki. 2020. &#x201c;Assessment of Rainwater Pollution and Bio&#x2010;Monitoring of Trace Metals air Pollution by two Types of Plants in Southern Iraq, Basrah City.&#x201d; Annals of Tropical Medicine &amp; Public Health 23: 231&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al&#x2010;Kharabsheh, A. 2020. &#x201c;Challenges to Sustainable Water Management in Jordan.&#x201d; Jordan Journal of Earth &amp; Environmental Sciences 11, no. 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anad, A. M., A. F. Hassoon, and M. H. Al&#x2010;Jiboori. 2022. &#x201c;Assessment of air Pollution Around Durra Refinery (Baghdad) From Emission NO2 gas at April Month.&#x201d; Baghdad Science Journal 19, no. 3: 0515. https://doi.org/10.21123/bsj.2022.19.3.0515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anzecc, A. 2000. Australian and New Zealand Guidelines for Fresh and Marine Water Quality. Australian and New Zealand Environment and Conservation Council and Agriculture and Resource Management Council of Australia and New Zealand, Canberra, 1, 1&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>APA, A. P. H. A. 2017. Standard Methods for the Examination of Water and Wastewater. American Public Health Association.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bootdee, S., S. Sillapapiromsuk, and S. Kawichai. 2025. &#x201c;Trace Elements in Indoor Dust Exposure From Child Development Centers and Health Risk Assessment in Haze and Industrial Areas, Thailand.&#x201d; Toxics 13, no. 7: 547. https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics13070547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burri, N. M., R. Weatherl, C. Moeck, and M. Schirmer. 2019. &#x201c;A Review of Threats to Groundwater Quality in the Anthropocene.&#x201d; Science of the Total Environment 684: 136&#x2013;154. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.05.236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, B., Z. Sun, D. Bai, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;The Identification of Soil Heavy Metal Sources and Environmental Risks in Industrial City Peri&#x2010;Urban Areas: A Case Study From a Typical Peri&#x2010;Urban Area in Western Laizhou, Shandong, China.&#x201d; Sustainability 16, no. 11: 4655. https://doi.org/10.3390/su16114655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cash, K., and R. Wright. 2001. &#x201c;Canadian Water Quality Guidelines for the Protection of Aquatic Life.&#x201d; CCME.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary, I. J., R. Chauhan, S. S. Kale, et&#xa0;al. 2025. "Groundwater Nitrate Contamination and its Effect on Human Health: A Review." Water Conservation Science and Engineering 10, no. 1: 33. https://doi.org/10.1007/s41101&#x2010;025&#x2010;00359&#x2010;y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clair, T. A., and A. Hindar. 2005. &#x201c;Liming for the Mitigation of Acid Rain Effects in Freshwaters: a Review of Recent Results.&#x201d; Environmental Reviews 13, no. 3: 91&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contardo, T., A. Vannini, K. Sharma, P. Giordani, and S. Loppi. 2020. &#x201c;Disentangling Sources of Trace Element air Pollution in Complex Urban Areas by Lichen Biomonitoring. A Case Study in Milan (Italy).&#x201d; Chemosphere 256: 127155. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.127155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Y. 2021. &#x201c;Pollution in Rainwater Harvesting: a Challenge for Sustainability and Resilience of Urban Agriculture.&#x201d; Journal of Hazardous Materials Letters 2: 100037. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hazl.2021.100037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta, J., and P. P. Singh. 2021. &#x201c;Air Pollutants and Acid Precipitation: Impact on Ecology and Human Health.&#x201d; In Multidimensional Approaches to Impacts of Changing Environment on Human Health, 3&#x2013;25. CRC Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertop, H., J. Koci&#x119;cka, A. Atilgan, D. Liberacki, M. Niemiec, and R. Rolbiecki. 2023. &#x201c;The Importance of Rainwater Harvesting and Its Usage Possibilities: Antalya Example (Turkey).&#x201d; Water 15, no. 12: 2194. https://doi.org/10.3390/w15122194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goran, S. M., D. A. Rasul, and D. S. Ismaeel. 2021. &#x201c;Assessment of Ground Water Quality for Drinking Purpose in the Shaqlawa Area, Erbil&#x2010;KRI.&#x201d; Zanco Journal of Pure and Applied Sciences 33, no. 2: 19&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan, Q., T. Meng, C. Guan, J. Chen, H. Li, and X. Zhou. 2024. &#x201c;Multi&#x2010;Scale Analysis of Carbon Emissions in Coastal Cities Based on Multi&#x2010;Source Data: a Case Study of Qingdao, China.&#x201d; Land 13, no. 11. https://doi.org/10.3390/land13111861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan, N. E. 2023. &#x201c;A Comparative Investigation of Rain Water Quality Parameters Between Natural and Industrial Areas in Duhok Governorate, Kurdistan Region&#x2010;Iraq.&#x201d; Environmental Science Archives 2, no. 2: 131. https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8107283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi, A., A. Naghizadeh, H. Biglari, R. Peirovi, A. Ghasemi, and A. Zarei. 2020. &#x201c;Assessment of Human Health Risks and Pollution Index for Heavy Metals in Farmlands Irrigated by Effluents of Stabilization Ponds.&#x201d; Environmental Science and Pollution Research 27: 10317&#x2013;10327. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356&#x2010;020&#x2010;07642&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keresztesi, &#xc1;., I.&#x2010;A. Nita, M.&#x2010;V. Birsan, et&#xa0;al. 2020. &#x201c;Assessing the Variations in the Chemical Composition of Rainwater and air Masses Using the Zonal and Meridional Index.&#x201d; Atmospheric Research 237: 104846. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosres.2020.104846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim, H.&#x2010;S., J.&#x2010;S. Lee, H.&#x2010;T. Chon, and M. Sager. 2008. &#x201c;Heavy Metal Contamination and Health Risk Assessment in the Vicinity of the Abandoned Songcheon Au&#x2013;Ag Mine in Korea.&#x201d; Journal of Geochemical Exploration 96, no. 2&#x2013;3: 223&#x2013;230. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gexplo.2007.04.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., X. Li, Q. Ge, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Carbonate Radical Ion as a Key Driver of Rapid Atmospheric Sulfate Formation. npj Climate and Atmospheric.&#x201d; Science 8, no. 1: 45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;, Q., Q. Xiao, Y. Wang, et&#xa0;al. 2021. &#x201c;Risk Assessment and Hotspots Identification of Heavy Metals in Rice: a Case Study in Longyan of Fujian Province, China.&#x201d; Chemosphere 270: 128626. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.128626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, H.&#x2010;W., M.&#x2010;L. Hung, and P.&#x2010;C. Chen. 2007. &#x201c;A Systemic Health Risk Assessment for the Chromium Cycle in Taiwan.&#x201d; Environment International 33, no. 2: 206&#x2013;218. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2006.09.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud, N., D. Al&#x2010;Shahwani, H. Al&#x2010;Thani, and R. J. Isaifan. 2023. &#x201c;Risk Assessment of the Impact of Heavy Metals in Urban Traffic Dust on Human Health.&#x201d; Atmosphere 14, no. 6: 1049. https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos14061049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamun, A., and H. O. Sharif. 2024. "Quantification of Nitrate Level in Shallow and Deep Groundwater Wells for Drinking, Domestic and Agricultural Uses in Northeastern Arid Regions of Saudi Arabia." Limnological Review 24, no. 3: 178&#x2013;191. https://doi.org/10.3390/limnolrev24030010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Means, B. 1989. Risk&#x2010;Assessment Guidance for Superfund. Volume 1. Human Health Evaluation Manual. Part A. Interim Report (Final). Retrieved From</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao, Y., R. Wang, C. Lu, J. Zhao, and Q. Deng. 2017. &#x201c;Lifetime Cancer Risk Assessment for Inhalation Exposure to di (2&#x2010;Ethylhexyl) Phthalate (DEHP).&#x201d; Environmental Science and Pollution Research 24: 312&#x2013;320. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356&#x2010;016&#x2010;7797&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed, S. J., S. M. Ahmed, M. Q. Qadr, H. Blbas, A. N. Ali, and A. F. Saber. 2025. &#x201c;Climate Change Anxiety Symptoms in the Kurdistan Region of Iraq.&#x201d; Journal of Pioneering Medical Sciences 14: 23&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.47310/jpms2025140104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguri, T., G. Suzuki, H. Matsukami, et&#xa0;al. 2018. &#x201c;Exposure Assessment of Heavy Metals in an e&#x2010;Waste Processing Area in Northern Vietnam.&#x201d; Science of the Total Environment 621: 1115&#x2013;1123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.10.115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qader, M. Q. 2025. &#x201c;Urbanization and Water Insecurity in Semi&#x2010;Arid Regions: a Multi&#x2010;Index Assessment of Water Quality, Ecological Risk, and Public Health Impacts.&#x201d; Journal of Applied Toxicology 45, no. 11: 1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1002/jat.4949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qader, M. Q., O. S. Ayanlade, A. N. Ali, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Climate Change Anxiety and Its Effect on Emotional and Functional Health: Regional Analysis.&#x201d; Acta Psychologica 260: 1&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actpsy.2025.105724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, M. M., M. A. Islam, M. Bodrud&#x2010;Doza, et&#xa0;al. 2018. &#x201c;Spatio&#x2010;Temporal Assessment of Groundwater Quality and Human Health Risk: a Case Study in Gopalganj, Bangladesh.&#x201d; Exposure and Health 10: 167&#x2013;188. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12403&#x2010;017&#x2010;0253&#x2010;y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakib, M. R. J., M. A. Rahman, A. P. Onyena, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;A Comprehensive Review of Heavy Metal Pollution in the Coastal Areas of Bangladesh: Abundance, Bioaccumulation, Health Implications, and Challenges.&#x201d; Environmental Science and Pollution Research 29, no. 45: 67532&#x2013;67558. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356&#x2010;022&#x2010;22122&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashid, A., B. J. Schutte, A. Ulery, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;Heavy Metal Contamination in Agricultural Soil: Environmental Pollutants Affecting Crop Health.&#x201d; Agronomy 13, no. 6: 1521. https://doi.org/10.3390/agronomy13061521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sager, M. 2020. &#x201c;Urban Soils and Road Dust&#x2014;Civilization Effects and Metal Pollution&#x2014;a Review.&#x201d; Environments 7, no. 11: 98. https://doi.org/10.3390/environments7110098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salih, Z. R., B. A. Othman, and S. J. Aweez. 2024. &#x201c;Assessment of Heavy Metals in Rainfall as an Indicator of Air Pollution From Erbil Steel Factory in Iraq.&#x201d; Environmental Monitoring and Assessment 196, no. 3: 319. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10661&#x2010;024&#x2010;12501&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena, V. 2025. &#x201c;Water Quality, air Pollution, and Climate Change: Investigating the Environmental Impacts of Industrialization and Urbanization.&#x201d; Water, Air, &amp; Soil Pollution 236, no. 2: 73. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11270&#x2010;024&#x2010;07702&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, F., L. Mao, R. Sun, J. Du, Z. Tan, and M. Ding. 2019. &#x201c;Contamination Evaluation and Source Identification of Heavy Metals in the Sediments From the Lishui River Watershed, Southern China.&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 16, no. 3: 336. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph16030336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, K. R., R. Dutta, A. S. Kalamdhad, and B. Kumar. 2020. &#x201c;Review of Existing Heavy Metal Contamination Indices and Development of an Entropy&#x2010;Based Improved Indexing Approach.&#x201d; Environment, Development and Sustainability 22: 7847&#x2013;7864. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668&#x2010;019&#x2010;00549&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Environmental Protection Agency. 1986. &#x201c;Guidelines for the Health Risk Assessment of Chemical Mixtures.&#x201d; Federal Register 51, no. 185: 34014&#x2013;34025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). 2011. Exposure Factors Handbook: 2011 Edition. National Center for Environmental Assessment.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilde, F. D., and D. B. Radtke (1998). Handbooks for Water&#x2010;Resources Investigations: National Field Manual for the Collection of Water&#x2010;Quality Data. Field Measurements (Vol. 9): US Department of the Interior, US Geological Survey.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., S. Wang, Z. Ni, H. Li, L. May, and J. Pu. 2021. &#x201c;Emerging Water Pollution in the World's Least Disturbed Lakes on Qinghai&#x2010;Tibetan Plateau.&#x201d; Environmental Pollution 272: 116032. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2020.116032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousefi, T., J. Varvani, B. S. E. Abad, A. Ahmadi, and N. Abdi. 2024. &#x201c;Integrated Study of Air Pollutant Emissions From Different Sources in Isfahan City of Iran.&#x201d; Water, Air, &amp; Soil Pollution 235, no. 3: 194. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11270&#x2010;024&#x2010;06992&#x2010;y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, J., G. Han, S. Zhang, et&#xa0;al. 2022. &#x201c;Rainwater Chemical Evolution Driven by Extreme Rainfall in Megacity: Implication for the Urban air Pollution Source Identification.&#x201d; Journal of Cleaner Production 372: 133732. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.133732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., J. Wang, S. Wang, C. Wang, F. Yang, and T. Li. 2024. &#x201c;Chemical Characteristics of Long&#x2010;Term Acid Rain and Its Impact on Lake Water Chemistry: a Case Study in Southwest China.&#x201d; Journal of Environmental Sciences 138: 121&#x2013;131. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jes.2023.03.028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, G., R. Zhang, Y. Han, J. Meng, Q. Qiao, and H. Li. 2021. &#x201c;Pollution Characteristics, Spatial Distribution, and Source Identification of Heavy Metals in Road Dust in a Central Eastern City in China: a Comprehensive Survey.&#x201d; Environmental Monitoring and Assessment 193: 1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10661&#x2010;021&#x2010;09584&#x2010;z.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>