<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41408684</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2265</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical endocrinology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Exercise-Induced Hormonal Changes on Skeletal Muscle Physiology.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cen.70086</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The purpose of the study was to determine changes in anabolic and catabolic hormone levels in response to various training regimens and to analyse their effect on skeletal muscle adaptation mechanisms through experimental measurement of physiological changes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study used laboratory biochemical assays to assess anabolic and catabolic hormone levels, clinical observation to measure physiological changes (muscle mass, strength, endurance), and statistical methods (ANOVA, t-tests, correlation analysis) to assess group differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND MEASUREMENTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study conducted an experimental analysis of hormonal changes in response to various types of physical activity, in particular, strength training, HIIT, and aerobic exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">It was found that strength training contributed to the greatest increase in the level of anabolic hormones, which correlated with an increase in muscle mass (+12%) and strength (+35%), while HIIT provided a balanced improvement in strength indicators and endurance. Aerobic exercise caused minor changes in anabolic hormone levels but a significant increase in VO&#x2082;max (+30%) with an increase in cortisol (+5%). Changes in the levels of myokines were also found; in particular, irisin and osteocalcin, which play an important role in metabolic adaptation. The anabolic response was more pronounced in the younger participants (18-35 years), while in the older groups (36-50 and 51-60 years), the increase in muscle mass was less significant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The identified patterns are important for sports medicine, endocrinology, and rehabilitation, in particular, for maintaining muscle mass and correcting hormonal changes in different age groups.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Shengwen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-9313-8229</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Jiangxi University of Science and Technology, Ganzhou, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0346653</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0300-0664</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interleukin&#x2010;6</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irisin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myokines</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41408684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.70086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Physical Activity, World Health Organization, (2024), https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/physical-activity.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. J. Kraemer and A. D. Rogol, The Endocrine System in Sports and Exercise (Blackwell Publishing, 2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. S. &#x160;ojat, &#x201c;The Endocrine Olympics Where Endocrinology Meets Professional Sport,&#x201d; European Society of Endocrinology 12 (2021): 1&#x2013;16, https://www.ese-hormones.org/media/tzsm5zci/eyes-news-2021-_autumn-issue-12.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Guidance, American Association of Clinical Endocrinology (AACE Clinical Guidance Forum, 2025) https://pro.aace.com/clinical-guidance.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Feng and R. F. Shi, &#x201c;Exercise and Estrogen in Skeletal Muscle,&#x201d; Chinese Bulletin of Life Sciences 31, no. 10 (2019): 1047&#x2013;1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Landen, D. Hiam, S. Voisin, M. Jacques, S. Lamon, and N. Eynon, &#x201c;Physiological and Molecular Sex Differences in Human Skeletal Muscle in Response to Exercise Training,&#x201d; Journal of Physiology 601, no. 3 (2023): 419&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Gharahdaghi, B. E. Phillips, N. J. Szewczyk, K. Smith, D. J. Wilkinson, and P. J. Atherton, &#x201c;Links Between Testosterone, Oestrogen, and the Growth Hormone/Insulin&#x2010;Like Growth Factor Axis and Resistance Exercise Muscle Adaptations,&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 11 (2021): 621226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, R. He, Q. Wang, et al., &#x201c;Effects and Mechanisms of Different Aerobic Exercise Loads on Skeletal Muscle Inflammatory Response and Insulin Signaling Pathway in Obese Rats,&#x201d; Chinese Journal of Tissue Engineering Research 27, no. 8 (2023): 1237&#x2013;1244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, W. Wei, Z. Zhao, K. Sun, W. Gao, and Z. Xiao, &#x201c;Effects of Different Levels of Blood Flow Restriction During Low&#x2010;Intensity Resistance Exercise on Serum Growth Hormone and Testosterone Secretion During Low&#x2010;Intensity Resistance Exercise,&#x201d; China Sport Science and Technology 55 (2019): 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. W. Van Every, A. C. D'Souza, and S. M. Phillips, &#x201c;Hormones, Hypertrophy, and Hype: An Evidence&#x2010;Guided Primer on Endogenous Endocrine Influences on Exercise&#x2010;Induced Muscle Hypertrophy,&#x201d; Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews 52, no. 4 (2024): 117&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Kashikova, E. Nabiyev, R. Askerov, et al., &#x201c;Epidemiology of Proximal Femural Fractures Among the Elderly People of Almaty City,&#x201d; Medical Journal of the Islamic Republic of Iran 38, no. 1 (2024): 57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. M. Tulewicz&#x2010;Marti, K. Lewandowski, and G. Rydzewska, &#x201c;Bone Metabolism Alteration in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 11, no. 14 (2022): 4138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gomarasca, G. Banfi, and G. Lombardi, &#x201c;Chapter Four&#x2014;Myokines: The Endocrine Coupling of Skeletal Muscle and Bone,&#x201d; Advances in Clinical Chemistry 94 (2020): 155&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. W. Pataky, S. Dasari, K. L. Michie, et al., &#x201c;Impact of Biological Sex and Sex Hormones on Molecular Signatures of Skeletal Muscle at Rest and in Response to Distinct Exercise Training Modes,&#x201d; Cell Metabolism 35, no. 11 (2023): 1996&#x2013;2010.e6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Romero&#x2010;Parra, R. Cupeiro, V. M. Alfaro&#x2010;Magallanes, et al., &#x201c;Exercise&#x2010;Induced Muscle Damage During the Menstrual Cycle: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 35, no. 2 (2021): 549&#x2013;561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Kruk, B. H. Aboul&#x2010;Enein, and E. Duchnik, &#x201c;Exercise&#x2010;Induced Oxidative Stress and Melatonin Supplementation: Current Evidence,&#x201d; Journal of Physiological Sciences 71, no. 1 (2021): 27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. T. Mangine, J. R. Hoffman, A. M. Gonzalez, et al., &#x201c;Exercise&#x2010;Induced Hormone Elevations Are Related to Muscle Growth,&#x201d; Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research 31, no. 1 (2017): 45&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Zhetenbayev, G. Balbayev, T. Iliev, and B. Bakhtiyar, &#x201c;Investigation of a Passive Ankle Joint Exoskeleton Designed for Movements With Dorsal and Plantar Flexion &#x2020;,&#x201d; Engineering Proceedings 41, no. 1 (2023): 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Shulgau, S. Sergazy, T. Krivoruchko, N. Kenzhebayeva, B. Sagindykova, and A. Gulyayev, &#x201c;Osteoprotective Properties of RNA&#x2010;Containing Drug Osteochondrin S on the Model of Insufficiency of Sex Hormones in Rats,&#x201d; International Journal of Morphology 35, no. 4 (2017): 1233&#x2013;1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. W. D. West and S. M. Phillips, &#x201c;Anabolic Processes in Human Skeletal Muscle: Restoring the Identities of Growth Hormone and Testosterone,&#x201d; Physician and Sportsmedicine 38, no. 3 (2010): 97&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zouhal, A. Jayavel, K. Parasuraman, et al., &#x201c;Effects of Exercise Training on Anabolic and Catabolic Hormones With Advanced Age: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 52, no. 2 (2022): 1353&#x2013;1368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. M. Gonzalez, J. R. Hoffman, J. R. Stout, D. H. Fukuda, and D. S. Willoughby, &#x201c;Intramuscular Anabolic Signaling and Endocrine Response Following Resistance Exercise: Implications for Muscle Hypertrophy,&#x201d; Sports Medicine 46, no. 5 (2016): 671&#x2013;685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Hatakeyama, S. Inoue, H. Jiang, R. Yokoi, and H. Moriyama, &#x201c;Exercise&#x2010;Induced Interactions Between Skeletal Muscle and Bone via Myokines and Osteokine in Mice: Role of FNDC5/irisin, IGF&#x2010;1, and Osteocalcin,&#x201d; Bone 190 (2025): 117314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Krzysztofik, M. Spieszny, R. Trybulski, et al., &#x201c;Acute Effects of Isometric Conditioning Activity on the Viscoelastic Properties of Muscles and Sprint and Jumping Performance in Handball Players,&#x201d; Journal of Strength &amp; Conditioning Research 37, no. 7 (2023): 1486&#x2013;1494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Hoffmann and C. Weigert, &#x201c;Skeletal Muscle as an Endocrine Organ: The Role of Myokines in Exercise Adaptations,&#x201d; Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine 7, no. 11 (2017): a029793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Zotaj, R. Milloshi, S. Sokoli, and H. Doci, &#x201c;Effectiveness of Physiotherapy Rehabilitation Approaches for Parkinson's Disease: A Durr&#xeb;s Case Study,&#x201d; Physiotherapy Research International 29, no. 4 (2024): e2124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Tulewicz&#x2010;Marti, P. Szwarc, M. Wi&#x119;cek, et al., &#x201c;Effect of Intravenous Iron Administration on Bone Mineral and Iron Homeostasis in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease&#x2014;Results of a Prospective Single&#x2010;Centre Study,&#x201d; Journal of Personalized Medicine 13, no. 3 (2023): 458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. S. Tsai and H. S. Wang, &#x201c;The Effect of Exercise Intervention on the Myokine Irisin: A Literature Review,&#x201d; Journal of Exercise Physiology &amp; Fitness 21 (2015): 71&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Korotych, &#x201c;Assessment of Physical (Somatic) Health of Young Men in the Construction of Health Improving Strength Training,&#x201d; Bulletin of Medical and Biological Research 6, no. 2 (2024): 25&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. Thyfault and A. Bergouignan, &#x201c;Exercise and Metabolic Health: Beyond Skeletal Muscle,&#x201d; Diabetologia 63, no. 8 (2020): 1464&#x2013;1474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Trybulski, G. Wojda&#x142;a, D. I. Alexe, et al., &#x201c;Acute Effects of Different Intensities During Bench Press Exercise on the Mechanical Properties of Triceps Brachii Long Head,&#x201d; Applied Sciences 12, no. 6 (2022): 3197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Trybulski, A. Ku&#x17c;d&#x17c;a&#x142;, M. Bichowska&#x2010;Paw&#x119;ska, et al., &#x201c;Immediate Effect of Cryo&#x2010;Compression Therapy on Biomechanical Properties and Perfusion of Forearm Muscles in Mixed Martial Arts Fighters,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 13, no. 4 (2024): 1177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. U&#x11f;ra&#x15f; and O. &#xd6;z&#xe7;elik, &#x201c;Impact of Exercise Induced Skeletal Muscle Strain on Energy Regulatory Hormones of Irisin and nesfatin&#x2010;1 in Sedentary Males,&#x201d; Turkish Bulletin of Hygiene and Experimental Biology 77, no. 2 (2020): 227&#x2013;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. L. Sokolovskyi, Study of the Impact of Crossfit Training on the Physiological Condition of Participants (Khmelnytskyi National University, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. A. Shvets and O. M. Hasiuk, &#x201c;Cortisol Levels and the Dynamics of Behavioral Reactions in Mice under the Influence of interleukin&#x2010;2 in the Conditions of Physical Training,&#x201d; Bulletin of Medical and Biological Research 3, no. 2 (2021): 95&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. E. Fink, &#x201c;The Role of Hormones in Exercise&#x2010;Induced Muscle Hypertrophy,&#x201d; in Endocrinology of Physical Activity and Sport, eds. A. C. Hackney and N. W. Constantini, (Humana, 2020), 391&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. C. Hackney, &#x201c;Menstrual Cycle Hormonal Changes and Energy Substrate Metabolism in Exercising Women: A Perspective,&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 18, no. 19 (2021): 10024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Sakaguchi, S. Gunjotikar, M. Tanaka, et al., &#x201c;Evaluation and Rehabilitation After Adult Lumbar Spine Surgery,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 13, no. 10 (2024): 2915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Y. Luk, D. E. Levitt, J. C. Boyett, et al., &#x201c;Resistance Exercise&#x2010;Induced Hormonal Response Promotes Satellite Cell Proliferation in Untrained Men but Not in Women,&#x201d; American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Endocrinology and Metabolism 317, no. 2 (2019): E421&#x2013;E432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Alves, V. Toro, G. Barrientos, I. Bartolom&#xe9;, D. Mu&#xf1;oz, and M. Maynar, &#x201c;Hormonal Changes in High&#x2010;Level Aerobic Male Athletes During a Sports Season,&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 17, no. 16 (2020): 5833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Latka, W. Ko&#x142;odziej, R. Rajski, D. Pawu&#x15b;, J. Chowaniec, and D. Latka, &#x201c;Outpatient Spine Surgery in Poland: A Survey on Popularity, Challenges, and Future Perspectives,&#x201d; Risk Management and Healthcare Policy 16 (2023): 1839&#x2013;1848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Suwa&#x142;a, J. Rzeszuto, R. Glonek, M. Krintus, and R. Junik, &#x201c;Is Restless Legs Syndrome De Facto Thyroid Disease?,&#x201d; Biomedicines 10, no. 10 (2022): 2502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Egan and A. P. Sharples, &#x201c;Molecular Responses to Acute Exercise and Their Relevance for Adaptations in Skeletal Muscle to Exercise Training,&#x201d; Physiological Reviews 103, no. 3 (2023): 2057&#x2013;2170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Kim, J. Y. Choi, S. Moon, D. H. Park, H. B. Kwak, and J. H. Kang, &#x201c;Roles of Myokines in Exercise&#x2010;Induced Improvement of Neuropsychiatric Function,&#x201d; Pfl&#xfc;gers Archiv&#x2010;European Journal of Physiology 471, no. S1 (2019): 491&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. C. Araujo, A. M. M. Neto, M. Fujimori, et al., &#x201c;Immune and Hormonal Response to High&#x2010;Intensity Exercise During Orienteering,&#x201d; International Journal of Sports Medicine 40, no. 12 (2019): 768&#x2013;773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. E. Alexander, A. C. Pollock, and S. Lamon, &#x201c;The Effect of Sex Hormones on Skeletal Muscle Adaptation in Females,&#x201d; European Journal of Sport Science 22, no. 7 (2022): 1035&#x2013;1045.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>