<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41634096</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanical and microstructural assessment of conventional carbon and stainless steel shear stud welded connections.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7049</StartPage><MedlinePgn>7049</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7049</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-37051-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Shear studs are crucial for composite action between a bridge&#x2019;s superstructure and deck. While carbon steel shear studs weld well onto ASTM A709 Grade 50 steel, their use with weathering bridge steels, particularly ASTM A709 Grade 50CR, has been associated in the literature with potential service-life concerns such as galvanic corrosion arising from metallic dissimilarities. Austenitic stainless steel shear studs have therefore been proposed for use with martensitic ASTM A709 Grade 50CR; however, literature on their mechanical behavior is limited, and code guidance is lacking. This study aims to investigate the mechanical performance and failure mechanisms in conventional carbon and austenitic stainless steel shear studs welded to ASTM A709 Grade 50 and Grade 50CR base metals. Shear and tensile tests were performed on three stud&#x2013;base metal configurations: (1) a carbon steel shear stud welded to an ASTM A709 Grade 50 plate, (2) a carbon steel shear stud welded to an ASTM A709 Grade 50CR plate, and (3) an austenitic stainless steel shear stud welded to an ASTM A709 Grade 50CR plate. Weld-zone microstructural analysis and microhardness traverses were conducted for each stud&#x2013;plate assembly. Tensile and shear testing demonstrated an increase in tensile and shear capacities and an increase in ductility for austenitic studs compared with carbon steel studs. Microstructural analysis revealed martensite formation in the coarse-grained heat-affected zone (CGHAZ) of the carbon steel stud welds with Vickers hardness measurements reaching 390 HV0.5. The stainless steel shear stud welds consistently reached 430 HV0.5 in the CGHAZ and weld microstructure, which may be attributed to the formations of martensite, secondary phases, and carbides in these regions. These elevated hardness levels may affect local toughness and increase susceptibility to cold cracking. This significant hardness increase underscores the need to maintain pre&#x2011;qualified stud&#x2011;welding parameters including heat input, correct stud seating and hold, and surface cleanliness, to ensure consistent weld reliability. The results obtained from this study aim to provide bridge owners valuable insights into the performance and reliability of stainless steel shear studs for bridge applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sajid</LastName><ForeName>Hizb Ullah</ForeName><Initials>HU</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2370-8592</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center, Genex Systems LLC, McLean, VA, 22101, USA. hizb.sajid.ctr@dot.gov.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slein</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7961-7091</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center, Federal Highway Administration, McLean, VA, 22101, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arc stud welding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shear studs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stainless steel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weld microhardness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weld microstructure</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41634096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12920901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-37051-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-37051-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Medlock, R., Gilmer, H., Miller, D. &amp; Ream, A. <i>Bridge Welding Reference Manual</i> (Federal Highway Administration, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers, H. A. Principles and practices of stud welding. <i>PCI J.</i><b>46</b>, 46&#x2013;58. 10.15554/pcij.09012001.46.58 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15554/pcij.09012001.46.58</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildebrand, J. &amp; Soltanzadeh, H. A review on assessment of fatigue strength in welded studs. <i>Int. J. Steel Struct.</i><b>14</b>, 421&#x2013;438. 10.1007/s13296-014-2020-2 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13296-014-2020-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouras, J. M., Sutton, J. P., Frank, K. H. &amp; Williamson, E. B. <i>The Tensile Capacity of Welded Shear Studs. R</i>eport No. FHWA/TX-09/9-5498-2. Research and Technology Implementation Office. Texas Department of Transportation. Austin, TX. (2008)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AASHTO. <i>LRFD Bridge Design Specifications</i>, 9th edn (American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM International. <i>ASTM A709/A709M Standard Specification for Structural Steel for Bridges</i> (ASTM International, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajid, H. U., Kiran, R., Qi, X., Bajwa, D. S. &amp; Battocchi, D. Employing corn derived products to reduce the corrosivity of pavement deicing materials. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>263</b>, 120662. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120662 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, D. C. Spectroscopic identification of protective and non-protective corrosion coatings on steel structures in marine environments. <i>Corros. Sci.</i><b>47</b>, 2550&#x2013;2570 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2004.10.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDad, B., Laffrey, D. C., Dammann, M. &amp; Medlock, R. D. <i>Performance of Weathering Steel in TxDOT Bridges. </i>Report No. FHWA/TX-99/1818-1. Constructions Division, Materials Section. Texas Department of Transportation. Austin, TX. (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crampton, D. D., Holloway, K. P., Fraczek, J. &amp; Wiss, J. <i>Assessment of Weathering Steel Bridge Performance in Iowa and Development of Inspection and Maintenance Techniques. </i>Final Report SPR 90-00-RB17-012<i>. Office of Bridges and Structures, Iowa Department of Transportation. Ames, IA.</i> (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FHWA. Technical advisory: uncoated weathering steel in structures. Technical Advisory 5140.22. Federal Highway Administration, Washington, DC (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann, J. L. <i>Inspection Finding Follow-up Actions for Uncoated Weathering Steel Bridges. Memorandum HIBS-1</i> (Federal Highway Administration, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Transportation Safety Board. <i>Collapse of the Fern Hollow Bridge. Highway Investigation Report HIR-24-02</i> (National Transportation Safety Board, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slein, R., Ocel, J. &amp; Greybeal, B. <i>Forbes Avenue Over Fern Hollow Bridge Collapse Investigation: Steel Mechanical and Materials Testing Factual Report 23&#x2013;036</i> (National Transportation Safety Board, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell, J., Shenton, H. W., Bai, T. &amp; Rupp, J. T. <i>Weathering Steel Performance Data Collection. </i>Report No. FHWA-HRT-23-116. Office of Infrastructure Research and Development. Federal Highway Administration. McLean, VA. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lottes, S. A. &amp; Sitek, M. A. <i>Large Eddy Simulation and Analysis of Truck Generated Droplet Spray Transport at Bridges</i> (Argonne National Laboratory, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Presswood, R., Afshan, S., Meza, F., Baddoo, N., Shaheen, M., and Desnerck, P. Experimental study on the behaviour of austenitic stainless steel and carbon steel welded shear connectors. <i>Eng. Struct.</i><b>321</b>, 118930. 10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.118930 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2024.118930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher, F. B. <i>Improved Corrosion-Resistant Steel for Highway Bridges Construction. </i>Report No. FHWA-HRT-11-062. Office of Infrastructure Research and Development, Federal Highway Administration. McLean, VA. (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groshek, I. G. Corrosion behavior of ASTM A1010 stainless steel for applications in bridge components. Thesis, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebdon, M. H. &amp; Provines, J. T. The use of ASTM A1010 (A709 GR50CR) stainless steel for bridges in the United States. <i>J. Perform. Constr. Facil.</i><b>34</b>, 4020108. 10.1061/(ASCE)CF.1943-5509.0001498 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)CF.1943-5509.0001498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provines, J., Sharp, S. R., Ozbulut, O. E. &amp; Daghash, S. <i>Maintenance-Free Corrosion-Resistant Steel Plate for Bridges. </i>Report No. FHWA/VTRC 19-R21. (Virginia Department of Transportation, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seradj, H. Weldability of ASTM A1010 steel. In <i>Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Short and Medium Span Bridges</i>, vol. 2, 1&#x2013;9 (Canadian Society for Civil Engineering, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seradj, H. Oregon&#x2019;s ASTM A1010 bridges. In <i>Proceedings of the Iowa DOT A1010 Steel Workshop</i> (Iowa DOT, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, A., Dzikowski, P. &amp; Borowski, E. <i>FDOT Procedures for Welding, Testing, and Fabricating Weathering Stainless Steel for Bridge Applications</i> (Florida Department of Transportation, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russian, O. &amp; Ocel, J. Mechanical performance of welds using ASTM A709 grade 50CR steel as base metal. <i>J. Constr. Steel Res.</i><b>170</b>, 106121 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2020.106121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provines, J. T., Sharp, S. R. &amp; Moruza, A. K. <i>Documentation and Evaluation of ASTM A709 Grade 50CR Steel Bridges on Virginia&#x2019;s Eastern Shore .</i>Report No. VTRC 24-R2 (Virginia Department of Transportation, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM International. <i>ASTM A1010/A1010M Standard Specification for Higher-Strength Martensitic Stainless Steel Plate, Sheet, and Strip</i> (ASTM International, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Z. R., Lu, Y. H., Ding, X. F. &amp; Shoji, T. Microstructural and hardness investigations on a dissimilar metal weld between low alloy steel and alloy 82 weld metal. <i>Mater. Charact.</i><b>121</b>, 166&#x2013;174 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2016.09.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, K.J., Yoo, S.C., Kim, T., Bahn, C.B. and Kim, J.H. Effects of aging temperature on microstructural evolution at dissimilar metal weld interfaces. <i>J. Nucl. Mater.</i><b>462</b>, 54&#x2013;63 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnucmat.2015.03.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W., Lu, Y., Ding, X. &amp; Shoji, T. Microstructures and microhardness at fusion boundary of 316 stainless steel/Inconel 182 dissimilar welding. <i>Mater. Charact.</i><b>107</b>, 255&#x2013;261. 10.1016/j.matchar.2015.07.018 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2015.07.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Xu, J., Shoji, T., Takeda, Y., Yuya, H. and Ooyama, M.&#xa0;Microstructure and pitting behavior of the dissimilar metal weld of 309L cladding and low alloy steel A533B. <i>J. Nucl. Mater.</i><b>508</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnucmat.2018.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wint, N., Leung, J., Sullivan, J. H., Penney, D. J. &amp; Gao, Y. The galvanic corrosion of welded ultra-high strength steels used for automotive applications. <i>Corros. Sci.</i><b>136</b>, 366&#x2013;373 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2018.03.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, D., Zhao, H. Y., Tang, D. Y. &amp; Ma, Q. Corrosion behavior study of 22MnB5 steel and its weld using electrochemical method. <i>Appl. Mech. Mater.</i><b>496</b>, 340&#x2013;343 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMM.496-500.340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deen, K. M., Ahmad, R., Khan, I. H. &amp; Farahat, Z. Microstructural study and electrochemical behavior of low alloy steel weldment. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>31</b>, 3051&#x2013;3055 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2010.01.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia, C., Martin, F., De Tiedra, P., Blanco, Y. &amp; Lopez, M. Pitting corrosion of welded joints of austenitic stainless steels studied by using an electrochemical minicell. <i>Corros. Sci.</i><b>50</b>, 1184&#x2013;1194 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2007.11.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Ding, J., Ming, H., Zhang, Z. &amp; Wang, J. Characterization of low alloy ferritic steel&#x2013;Ni base alloy dissimilar metal weld interface by SPM techniques, SEM/EDS, TEM/EDS and SVET. <i>Mater. Charact.</i><b>100</b>, 50&#x2013;60 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchar.2014.12.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng, S., Huang, Y., Xuan, F. &amp; Yang, F. Pit evolution around the fusion line of a NiCrMoV steel welded joint caused by galvanic and stress-assisted coupling corrosion. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>8</b>, 3399&#x2013;3409 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C7RA11837F</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9077683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35542958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM International. <i>ASTM A108 Standard Specification for Steel Bar, Carbon and Alloy, Cold-Finished</i> (ASTM International, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Welding Society. <i>AWS D1.1/D1.1&#xa0;M:2020 Structural Welding Code&#x2014;Steel</i>, 24th edn (American Welding Society, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM International. <i>ASTM A276/A276M Standard Specification for Stainless Steel Bars and Shapes</i> (ASTM International, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Welding Society. <i>AWS D1.6 Structural Welding Code&#x2014;Stainless Steel</i> (American Welding Society, 1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials, American Welding Society. <i>AASHTO/AWS D1.5&#xa0;M/D1.5 Bridge Welding Code</i>, 8th edn (American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Precast/Prestressed Concrete Institute. <i>MNL-120-10 PCI Design Handbook: Precast and Prestressed Concrete</i>, 7th edn (Precast/Prestressed Concrete Institute, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajid, H. U., Naik, D. L. &amp; Kiran, R. Microstructure&#x2013;mechanical property relationships for post-fire structural steels. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>32</b>10.1061/(asce)mt.1943-5533.0003190 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik, D. L., Sajid, H. U. &amp; Kiran, R. Texture-based metallurgical phase identification in structural steels: A supervised machine learning approach. <i>Met. (Basel)</i>. <b>9</b>, 546 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met9050546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vander Voort, G. F. <i>ASM Handbook Volume 9: Metallography and Microstructures</i> (ASM International, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bramfitt, B. L. &amp; Benscoter, A. O. <i>Metallographer&#x2019;s Guide: Practice and Procedures for Irons and Steels</i> (ASM International, 2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM International. <i>ASTM E92 Standard Test Methods for Vickers Hardness and Knoop Hardness of Metallic Materials</i> (ASTM International, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messler, R. W. Jr <i>Principles of Welding: Processes, Physics, Chemistry, and Metallurgy</i> (Wiley, 2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;tz, O. &amp; Henkel, K-M. Investigations on the microstructure of drawn Arc stud welds on structural steels by quantitative metallography. <i>Weld. World</i>. <b>67</b>, 195&#x2013;208 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40194-022-01417-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banaschik, R., Br&#xe4;tz, O. &amp; Henkel, K-M. Systematic expansion of the microstructural characterization of ferritic weld metals. <i>Pract. Metallogr</i>. <b>54</b>, 669&#x2013;684 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3139/147.110466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster, J. F. 8&#x2014;Carbon and ferritic alloy steels. In <i>Metallurgy of Welding, Woodhead Publishing Series in Welding and Other Joining Technologies</i>, 6th edn, 211&#x2013;309 (Woodhead Publishing, 1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajid, H. U. &amp; Kiran, R. Influence of stress concentration and cooling methods on post-fire mechanical behavior of ASTM A36 steels. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>186</b>, 920&#x2013;945. 10.1016/J.CONBUILDMAT.2018.08.006 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CONBUILDMAT.2018.08.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, B. C., Lee, S., Kim, N. J. &amp; Lee, D. Y. Microstructure and local brittle zone phenomena in high-strength low-alloy steel welds. <i>Metall. Mater. Trans. A</i>. <b>22</b>, 139&#x2013;149. 10.1007/BF03350956 (1991).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03350956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tronskar, J. P. &amp; Andresen, V. Avoiding local brittle zones in offshore pipeline girth welds for reeling installation involving large plastic strain. In <i>Conference Proceedings: International Conference on Offshore Mechanics and Arctic Engineering</i>, V003T03A041 (American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha, M., Yadav, S. &amp; Ghosh, S. A novel observation of Widmanst&#xe4;tten ferrite and pearlite by thermo-mechanical processing of interstitial-free steel. <i>Mater. Manuf. Processes</i>. <b>37</b>, 1766&#x2013;1771. 10.1080/10426914.2022.2049302 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10426914.2022.2049302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitz-Gerald, J. M., Agnew, S. R. &amp; Xia, X. <i>Report No. VTRC 20-R24 Welding of ASTM A709 50CR Using Austenitic Filler Wires with Varying Heat Inputs and Maximum Interpass Temperatures</i> (Virginia Department of Transportation, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grobler, C. Weldability Studies on 12% and 14% Chromium Steels. Dissertation, University of Pretoria (1987).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>