<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41326532</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrated radiometric and mineralogical investigation of radioactive mineralization in the El-Erediya Shear Zone, Eastern Desert, Egypt.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>42914</StartPage><MedlinePgn>42914</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">42914</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-27562-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The shear zone cut through the western southern part of El-Erediya granite pluton represents one of the most promising radioactive minerals occurrences in Egypt's Eastern Desert. To explore this shear zone, exploratory tunnels were dug at wadi level. The present study aims to map the potential mineralization, determine geological units, and their relations with mineralizations along the main adit and shear zone of El-Erediya exploratory tunnels. Fuzzy C-means analysis (FCM) is applied to measured ground gamma ray spectrometry data (eU, eTh, and K<sup>40</sup>). FCM identified three distinct radiometric clusters, revealing the spatial association of radioelement enrichment. The variation in the occurrence of different geological features within these clusters indicates that post-magmatic processes significantly influence the distribution and concentration of radioelements throughout the study area. Mineralogical investigations identified the occurrences of pyrite, chalcopyrite, arsenopyrite, marcasite, magnetite, goethite, hematite, uranophane, uranopilite, kasolite, betafite, plumbobetafite, ishikawite, thorite, zircon, and xenotime that have either magmatic or non-magmatic (hydrothermal and supergene) origins. Additionally, mineralogical investigations show that most of the radioactive minerals are found in cluster No. 2. These minerals are associated with opaque minerals (e.g., pyrite, hematite, goethite, pyrolusite, and fluorite), which serve as capturing agents for uranyl-ions from hydrothermal solutions. The integration of radiometric and mineralogical analysis provides an effective tool for identifying potential zones of radioactive mineralization and enhances understanding of their lithological controls.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rageh</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9919-804X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geology Department, Faculty of Science, South Valley University, Qena, 83523, Egypt. hassan55rageh51@sci.svu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdel-Hakeem</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geology Department, Faculty of Science, South Valley University, Qena, 83523, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Tahir</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geology Department, Faculty of Science, South Valley University, Qena, 83523, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeid</LastName><ForeName>Ehab Abu</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nuclear Materials Authority, Maadi, Cairo, 11511, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Milano</LastName><ForeName>Maurizio</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8907-6428</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth, Environment and Resources Sciences (DiSTAR), University of Naples Federico II, 80126, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbas</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8907-9963</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Earth, Environment and Resources Sciences (DiSTAR), University of Naples Federico II, 80126, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">El-Erediya shear zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FCM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ore microscopic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radioactive minerals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radioelement anomalies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SEM&#x2013;EDX analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XRD analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41326532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12673134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-27562-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-27562-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Foote, R. S. &amp; Humphrey, N. B. Airborne radiometric techniques and applications to uranium exploration. In <i>Exploration for Uranium Ore Deposits</i>, 17&#x2013;34 (1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo, B. B. &amp; Pitcher, D. H. A case history on the use of regional aeromagnetic and radiometric data sets for lode gold exploration in Ghana. In&#xa0;<i>SEG Technical Program Expanded Abstracts, Society of Exploration Geophysicists</i>, 592&#x2013;595.&#x200f; 10.1190/1.1826712 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasty, R. L. &amp; Shives, R. B. K. Applications of gamma ray spectrometry to mineral exploration and geological mapping. In <i>Workshop Presented at Exploration 97: Fourth Decennial Conference on Mineral Exploration</i> (1997).&#x200f;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham, D. F. &amp; Bonham-Carter, G. F. Airborne radiometric data-A tool for reconnaissance geological mapping using a GIS. <i>Photogramm. Eng. Remote Sens. (U. S.)</i><b>59</b>(8) (1993).&#x200f;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrson, H. &amp; Nash, C. Integrated lithostructural mapping of the Rossing area, Namibia, using high-resolution aeromagnetic, aeroradiometric, Landsat data and aerial photographs. <i>Explor. Geophys.</i><b>28</b>(1), 185&#x2013;191. 10.1071/eg997185 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/eg997185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charbonneau, B. W., Holman, P. B. &amp; Hetu, R. J. Airborne gamma spectrometer magnetic-VLF survey of north-eastern Alberta. In <i>Exploring for Minerals in Alberta: Geological Survey of Canada Geoscience contributions, Canada-Alberta Agreement on Mineral Development</i> (ed Macqueen, R.W.), vol. 500, 107&#x2013;131 (Geological Survey of Canada, Ottawa, 1997).&#x200f;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaques, A. L., Wellman, P., Whitaker, A. &amp; Wyborn, D. High-resolution geophysics in modern geological mapping. <i>J. Aust. Geol. Geophys.</i><b>17</b>, 159&#x2013;174 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, S. E., Corner, R. J., Groves, P. R. &amp; Grealish, G. J. Use of airborne gamma radiometric data for soil mapping. <i>Soil Res.</i><b>34</b>(1), 183&#x2013;194. 10.1071/SR9960183 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/SR9960183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilford, J., Bierwirth, P. E. &amp; Craig, M. A. Application of airborne gamma-ray spectrometry in soil/regolith mapping and applied geomorphology. <i>J. Aust. Geol. Geophys.</i><b>17</b>, 201&#x2013;216 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler, U. et al. A gamma-ray spectrometry approach to field separation of illuviation-type WRB reference soil groups in northern Thailand. <i>J. Plant Nutr. Soil Sci.</i><b>174</b>(4), 536&#x2013;544. 10.1002/jpln.200800323 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jpln.200800323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Egmond, F., Loonstra, E. &amp; Limburg, J. Gamma ray sensor for topsoil mapping: The mole. In <i>Proximal Soil Sensing Progress in Soil Science</i> Vol. 1 (eds Viscarra Rossel, R. et al.) 323&#x2013;332 (Springer, Dordrecht, 2011). 10.1007/978-90-481-8859-8_27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beamish, D. Gamma ray attenuation in the soils of Northern Ireland, with special reference to peat. <i>J. Environ. Radioact.</i><b>115</b>, 13&#x2013;27. 10.1016/j.jenvrad.2012.05.031 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvrad.2012.05.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22858640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhardt, N. &amp; Herrmann, L. Fusion of indigenous knowledge and gamma spectrometry for soil mapping to support knowledge-based extension in Tanzania. <i>Food Secur.</i><b>9</b>(6), 1271&#x2013;1284 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12571-017-0663-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanderson, D. C. W., Allyson, J. D., Tyler, A. N. &amp; Scott, E. M. Environmental applications of airborne gamma ray spectrometry. In <i>Application of Uranium Exploration Data and Techniques in Environmental Studies, IAEA-TECDOC-827</i>, 71&#x2013;79 (IAEA, Vienna, 1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford, K. L. et al. The role of gamma-ray spectrometry in radon risk evaluation: a case history from Oka, Quebec. <i>Geosci. Can.</i><b>28</b>, 2 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahti, M., Jones, D., Multala, J. &amp; Rainey, M. P. Environmental applications of airborne radiometric surveys. Expanded abstracts. In&#xa0;<i>63 rd Annual Conference, European Association of Geoscientists and Engineers</i> (2001).&#x200f;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef, M. A. &amp; Elkhodary, S. T. Utilization of airborne gamma ray spectrometric data for geological mapping, radioactive mineral exploration and environmental monitoring of southeastern Aswan city, South Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Geophys. J. Int.</i><b>195</b>(3), 1689&#x2013;1700. 10.1093/gji/ggt375 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gji/ggt375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCay, A. T., Harley, T. L., Younger, P. L., Sanderson, D. C. &amp; Cresswell, A. J. Gamma-ray spectrometry in geothermal exploration: State of the art techniques. <i>Energies</i><b>7</b>(8), 4757&#x2013;4780. 10.3390/en7084757 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en7084757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero, J. L. Uses of the gamma-ray spectrometer in mineral exploration. <i>Geophysics</i><b>25</b>(5), 1054&#x2013;1076. 10.1190/1.1438787 (1960).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1190/1.1438787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnley, A. G. &amp; Ford, K. L. Regional airborne gamma-ray surveys: A review. In <i>Proceedings of Exploration&#x2019;87: Third Decennial International Conference on Geophysical and Geochemical Exploration for Minerals and Groundwater</i>, vol. 3 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar, A. A. <i>Application of Aerial Radiometry to the Study of the Geology of Wadi El-Gidami, Eastern Desert (with Aeromagnetic Application)</i>, Ph.D. Thesis, Faculty of Science, Cairo University (1973).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kassas, I. A. <i>Radioactivity and Geology of Wadi Atalla Area, Eastern Desert of Egypt, A.R.E</i>, Ph. D. Thesis, Ein Shams University, vol. 502 (1974).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tahir, M. A. <i>Radioactivity and Mineralization of Granitic Rocks of EI-Erediya Occurrence and Comparison to EI Missikat-Rei EI Garra Occurrence, Eastern Desert, Egypt</i>, Ph.D. Thesis, AI Azhar University, vol. 132 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein, H. A., El Tahir, M. A. &amp; Abu-Deif, A. Uranium mineralization through exploratory mining work, south Qena-Safaga midway, Eastern Desert, Egypt. In <i>3rd Mining, Petroleum and Metallurgy Conference. Egypt, Cairo University</i>, vol. 1, 92&#x2013;105 (1992).&#x200f;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Deif, A., Abouelnaga, H. S. &amp; Hassanein, H. I. Distribution of radioelements and its relation to uranium migration, El Erediya exploratory tunnels, central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>J. King Abdulaziz Univ. (Earth Sci.)</i><b>13</b>, 19&#x2013;40 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4197/Ear.13-1.2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitkin, J. A. &amp; Duval, J. S. Design parameters for aerial gamma-ray surveys. <i>Geophysics</i><b>45</b>(9), 1427&#x2013;1439 (1980).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1190/1.1441131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg, J. K. Characteristics and origin of Egyptian younger granites. <i>Geol. Soc. Am. Bull.</i><b>92</b>(5), 749&#x2013;840. 10.1130/0016-7606(1981)92%3c224:CAOOEY%3e2.0.CO;2 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1130/0016-7606(1981)92&lt;224:CAOOEY&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fullagar, P. D. Pan African age granites of northeastern Africa: new or reworked sialic materials. In <i>The Geology of Libya</i> (eds Salem, M. J. &amp; Busrewil, M. T.) 1051&#x2013;1053 (Academic Press, 1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Dief, A. <i>The Relation Between the Uranium Mineralization and Tectonics in Some Pan-African Granite, West of Safaga, Eastern Desert, Egypt</i>. Ph.D. Thesis, Assuit University, vol. 218 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhit, F. S. <i>Geology and Radioactive Mineralization of Gabal EL-Missikat Area, Eastern Desert, Egypt.</i> Ph.D. Thesis, Ain Shams University, vol. 289 (1978).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Deif, A. <i>Geology of Uranium Mineralization in El-Missikat Area, Qena-Safaga Road, Eastern Desert, Egypt</i>. M.Sc. Thesis, Al-Azhar University, vol. 103 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhit, F. S., Assaf, H. A., &amp; Dief, A. A. Correlation study on the geology and radioactivity of surface and subsurface working at El Missikat area, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt.&#xa0;<i>Mining Geology,&#xa0;35(193), 345&#x2013;354.&#x200f;</i>10.11456/shigenchishitsu1951.35.345 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein, H. A., Hassan, M, A., El-Tahir, M. A., Abou-Deif, A. <i>Uranium-Bearing Siliceous Veins in Younger Granites, Eastern Desert, Egypt</i>&#xa0;(No. IAEA-TECDOC-361) (1986).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhit, F. S. Determination of uranium possibility occurrence in the late orogenic granites of Upper Proterozoic, Eastern Desert. <i>Egypt. Mining Geol.</i><b>37</b>(201), 29&#x2013;43. 10.11456/shigenchishitsu1951.37.29 (1987).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11456/shigenchishitsu1951.37.29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhit, F. S. &amp; Kassas, I. A. E. Distribution and orientation of radioactive veins in the El Erediya-El Missikat area, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Int. J. Remote Sens.</i><b>10</b>(3), 565&#x2013;581. 10.1080/01431168908903893 (1989).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431168908903893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein, H. A. M. &amp; Sayyah, T. A. <i>Uranium Potential of the Younger Granites of Egypt</i>&#xa0;(No. IAEA-TECDOC-650) (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kammar, A. M., El-Hazik, N., Mahdi, M. &amp; Aly, N. Geochemistry of accessory minerals associated with radioactive mineralisation in the central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>J. Afr. Earth Sci.</i><b>25</b>(2), 237&#x2013;252. 10.1016/S0899-5362(97)00101-2 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0899-5362(97)00101-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabie, S. I., Abdelhadi, H. M. &amp; Ali, A. S. Application of ground geophysical data to the uranium occurrences of El-Erediya area, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Radiat. Phys. Chem.</i><b>49</b>(2), 225&#x2013;231 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0969-806X(95)00175-W</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabie, S. I., Abdel-Meguid, A. A. &amp; Assran, A. S. Geological and geophysical exploration for uranium mineralization in the El-Erediya Prospect Area, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Proc. Int. Conf. Basement Tectonics</i><b>6</b>, 169&#x2013;189. 10.1007/978-94-011-5098-9_7 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-94-011-5098-9_7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla, H. M. &amp; El Afandy, A. H. Geochemistry and genesis of uranium mineralization at Missikat-Erediya area, central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Egyptian Mineral</i><b>16</b>, 1&#x2013;33 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El-Naby, H. H. Genesis of secondary uranium minerals associated with jasperoid veins, El Erediya area, Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Mineralium Deposita</i><b>43</b>(8), 933&#x2013;944. 10.1007/s00126-007-0171-1 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00126-007-0171-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raslan, M. F. Occurrence of uraniferous iron grains at Gabal Gattar, El Missikat and El Erediya Granites in Eastern Desert of Egypt. <i>Resour. Geol.</i><b>59</b>(1), 99&#x2013;105. 10.1111/j.1751-3928.2008.00082.x (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1751-3928.2008.00082.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsaid, M., Aboelkhair, H., Dardier, A., Hermas, E. &amp; Minoru, U. Processing of multispectral ASTER data for mapping alteration minerals zones: As an aid for uranium exploration in Elmissikat-Eleridiya granites, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Open Geol. J.</i>10.2174/1874262901408010069 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874262901408010069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbdElMonsif, M. &amp; AbuZeid, E. K. Behavior of the trace and rare earth elements in the pegmatitic rocks of El Missikat-El Erediya area, Central Eastern Desert Egypt. <i>Nucl. Sci. Sci. J.</i><b>9</b>(2), 85&#x2013;99. 10.21608/nssj.2020.265530 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/nssj.2020.265530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassaan, M. M. et al. Prognostic exploration of UF-Au-Mo-W younger granites for geochemical pathfinders, genetic affiliations, and tectonic setting in El-Erediya-El-Missikat Province, Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Minerals</i><b>12</b>(5), 518. 10.3390/min12050518 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min12050518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osman, A. M., Salman, A. B., El-Mansi, M. M., Abdel Ghani, I. M. &amp; Abdallah, S. M. Mineralogy and uranium distribution in some subsurface sections from El-Missikat and El-Erediya uranium occurrences, Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Delta J. Sci</i><b>29</b>, 18&#x2013;38 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/djs.2005.158259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalaby, M. H., Bishta, A. Z., Roz, M. E. &amp; El Zalaky, M. A. Integration of geologic and remote sensing studies for the discovery of uranium mineralization in some granite plutons, Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>J. King Abdulaziz Univ. Earth Sci.</i><b>21</b>(1), 125 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raslan, M. F. Au-bearing Pyrite and Pt-Re-rich molybdenite in the sulphide mineralized younger granites in the Eastern Desert of Egypt. <i>Int. J. Min. Sci.</i><b>7</b>(1), 1&#x2013;9. 10.20431/2454-9460.0701001 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20431/2454-9460.0701001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Hakeem, M., El-Tahir, M., Zeid, E. A. &amp; Rageh, H. Genetic implications of Th/U, Th/K, and U/K ratios for U mineralizations: A case study from El-Missikat and El-Erediya shear zones, Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Geochem. Trans.</i><b>24</b>(1), 3. 10.1186/s12932-023-00083-3 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12932-023-00083-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10580569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37847428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shereif, A. S., Shebl, A., Mahmoud, A. S. &amp; Cs&#xe1;mer, &#xc1;. Enhanced lithological mapping in El-Missikat and El-Erediya Areas, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt, leveraging remote sensing techniques and machine learning algorithms. <i>IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens.</i>10.1109/TGRS.2024.3471982 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2024.3471982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rageh, H. <i>Geology and Radioactivity of Some Sites Around Qena-Safaga Road, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt</i>, M. Sc. Thesis, South Valley University, vol. 175 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayakumar, D., Rao, G. S., Singh, W. D., Kumar, M. &amp; Pal, S. K. Cluster analysis of geophysical data for geology differentiation in Agnigundala mineralized belt of Cuddapah Basin, India. <i>J. Earth Syst. Sci.</i><b>134</b>(1), 46. 10.1007/s12040-024-02482-1 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12040-024-02482-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimori, R. K., Ragland, P. C., Rogers, J. J. W. &amp; Greenberg, J. K. Uranium deposits in granitic rocks. In <i>Energy Research and Development Administration Technical Report-GJBX-13 (77), Grand Junction, Clorado</i>, 1&#x2013;93 (1977).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers, J. J. W. &amp; Adams, J. A. S. Thorium and uranium. In <i>Handbook of Geochemistry (II-5)</i> (eds Wedepohl, K. H. et al.) 798&#x2013;822 (Springer, 1978).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Condomines, M., Morand, P. &amp; All&#xe9;gre, C. J. <sup>230</sup>Th-<sup>238</sup>U radioactive disequilibria in tholeiites from the FAMOUS zones (Mid-Atlantic Ridge, 36&#xb0; 50&#x2032; N): Th and Sr isotopic geochemistry. <i>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</i><b>55</b>, 247&#x2013;256. 10.1016/0012-821X(81)90104-7 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0012-821X(81)90104-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Condomines, M., Morand, P., All&#xe9;gre, C. J. &amp; Sigvaldason, G. <sup>230</sup>Th-<sup>238</sup>U disequilibria in historical lavas from Iceland. <i>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</i><b>55</b>, 393&#x2013;406. 10.1016/0012-821X(81)90167-9 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0012-821X(81)90167-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>All&#xe9;gre, C. J., Dupr&#xe9;, B. &amp; Lewin, E. Thorium/uranium ration of the Earth. <i>Chem. Geol.</i><b>56</b>, 219&#x2013;227. 10.1016/0009-2541(86)90005-7 (1986).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2541(86)90005-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galbraith, J. H. &amp; Saunders, D. F. Rock classification by characteristics of aerial gamma-ray measurements. <i>J. Geochem. Explor.</i><b>18</b>, 49&#x2013;73. 10.1016/0375-6742(83)90080-8 (1983).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0375-6742(83)90080-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shives, R. B. K., Charbonneau, B. W. &amp; Ford, K. L. The detection of potassic alteration by gamma-ray spectrometry&#x2014;recognition of alteration related to mineralization. <i>Geophysics</i><b>65</b>(6), 2001&#x2013;2011. 10.1190/1.1444884 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1190/1.1444884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardier, A. M. &amp; El-Galy, M. M. Contribution to the U-Th distribution in the older and younger granite along Qena-Safaga road, Egypt. <i>J. Geol.</i><b>44</b>(1), 55&#x2013;64 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle, R. W. Deposits of thorium and uranium and their indicator elements. <i>Dev. Econ. Geol.</i><b>16</b>, 39&#x2013;121 (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waber, N., Schorscher, H. D. &amp; Peters, T. J. Hydrothermal and supergene uranium mineralization at the Osamu Utsumi mine, Po&#xe7;os de Caldas, Minas Gerais, Brazil. <i>J. Geochem. Explor.</i><b>45</b>, 53&#x2013;112. 10.1016/0375-6742(92)90122-O (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0375-6742(92)90122-O</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honghai, F. et al. Genesis and uranium sources of leucogranite-hosted uranium deposits in the Gaudeanmus Area, Central Damara Belt, Namibia: Study of element and Nd isotope geochemistry. <i>Acta Geol. Sin.</i><b>91</b>(6), 2126&#x2013;2137. 10.1111/1755-6724.13453 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1755-6724.13453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden, P., Herd, D. &amp; Kinnaird, J. A. The significance of Uranium and Thorium concentrations in pegamtitic leucogranites (alaskites), R&#xf6;ssing Mine, Swakopmund, Namibia. <i>Communs Geol. Surv. Namibia</i><b>10</b>, 43&#x2013;49 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolonin, A. V. &amp; Gradovsky, I. F. Supergene processes and uranium ore formation in the Ronneburg Ore Field, Germany. <i>Geol. Ore Depos.</i><b>54</b>(2), 122&#x2013;131. 10.1134/S1075701512020031 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S1075701512020031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coney, P. J. &amp; Reynolds, S. J. <i>Cordilleran Metamorphic Core Complexes and Their Uranium Favorability</i>. Final report&#xa0;(No. GJBX-258 (80)). Arizona Univ (1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burt, D. M. Compositional and phase relations among rare earth element minerals. In <i>Geochemistry and Mineralogy of Rare Earth Elements</i> (eds Lipin, B. R. &amp; McKay, G. A.) 259&#x2013;302 (Mineralogical Society of America, 1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Deif, A., El-Husseiny, M. O., El-Balakssy, S. S., &amp; Abu Zeid, E. K. Wall rock alteration and uranium mineralization at M-III uranium occurrence, Gabal El Missikat younger granites, central Eastern Desert, Egypt. In <i>2nd International Conference on the Geology of the Tethys</i>, Faculty of Science, Cairo University, Egypt, 647&#x2013;654 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanggh, G., Wang, X., Chai, X., Liu, J. &amp; Deng, N. Adsorption of uranium (VI) from aqueous solution on calcined and acid-activated kaolin. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>47</b>(3&#x2013;4), 448&#x2013;451. 10.1016/j.clay.2009.11.003 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2009.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massey, M. S., Pacheco, J. S. L., Nelson, J., Fendorf, S. &amp; Maher, K. Uranium Incorporation into Amorphous Silica. <i>Environ. Sci. Technol.</i><b>48</b>(15), 8636&#x2013;8644 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es501064m</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24984107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Y. et al. The physical chemistry of uranium (VI) immobilization on manganese oxides. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>391</b>, 122207. 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.122207 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.122207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32036313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, T. et al. Mass transfer during hematitization and implications for uranium mineralization in the Zoujiashan Deposit, Xiangshan Volcanic Basin. <i>J. Earth Sci.</i><b>33</b>(2), 422&#x2013;434 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12583-021-1479-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nash, J. T. Uranium and thorium in granitic rocks of northeastern Washington and northern Idaho, with comments on uranium resource potential. <i>U.S. Geological Survey, Open-File Report 79-233</i>, 1&#x2013;47 (1979).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Geochemical properties and mineralization of thorium. <i>Ore Energy Resour. Geol.</i><b>18</b>, 100081. 10.1016/j.oreoa.2024.100081 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oreoa.2024.100081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, L. Abundance of chemical elements in oceanic and continental crust. <i>Geoteactonica et Metallogenia</i><b>18</b>(1), 19&#x2013;27 (1984) (<b>in Chinese with English abstract</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, Y. H. &amp; Mior Shallehhuddin, B. M. J. Promising uranium the Central Belt Area, Peninsular Malaysia. In <i>Uranium Deposits in Asia and the Pacific: Geology and Exploration, Vienna, Austria</i>, 97&#x2013;107. Prospects in IAEA-Tc-543/7&#xc6;&#x200f; (1988).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuach, J., Hewton, R. S. and Cavey, G. Exploration targets for volcano genic, base-metal sulphide deposits on Pilley&#x2019;s Island, Newfoundland. In <i>Ore Horizons</i>, vol. 1, 89&#x2013;98 (Newfoundland and Labrador Department of Mines and Energy, Geological Survey Branch, 1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegab, M. A. E. R., AbouElMagd, I. &amp; AbdElWahid, K. H. Revealing Potential mineralization zones utilizing Landsat-9, ASTER and airborne radiometric data at Elkharaza-Dara Area, North Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Egypt. J. Remote Sens. Space Sci.</i><b>27</b>(4), 716&#x2013;733. 10.1016/j.ejrs.2024.10.005 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejrs.2024.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santaguida, F., Hannington, M. D. &amp; Jowett, E. C. An alteration and sulphur isotope study of the Pilley&#x2019;s Island massive sulphides, central Newfoundland. In <i>Current Research, Part D; Geological Survey of Canada, Paper 92-1D</i>, 265&#x2013;274 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walther, J. A. <i>Essentials of Geochemistry</i> Vol. 704 (Jones and Bartlett, 2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sherif, A. M. Mineralogical characterization of the alteration facies at gabal el-missikat area, central Eastern desert, Egypt. <i>Nucl. Sci. Sci. J.</i><b>2</b>(1), 1&#x2013;21 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langmuir, D. Uranium solution-mineral equilibria at low temperatures with applications to sedimentary ore deposits. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i><b>42</b>(6), 547&#x2013;569. 10.1016/0016-7037(78)90001-7 (1978).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-7037(78)90001-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speer, J. A., Solberg, T. N. &amp; Becker, S. W. Petrography of the uranium-bearing minerals of the Liberty Hill Pluton, South Carolina; Phase assemblages and migration of uranium in granitoid rocks. <i>Econ. Geol.</i><b>76</b>(8), 2162&#x2013;2175. 10.2113/gsecongeo.76.8.2162 (1981).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2113/gsecongeo.76.8.2162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, N. A. <i>Comparative Study of the Accessory Heavy Minerals in Some Radioactive Rocks of Gabal El-missikat and Gabal El-Erediya, Eastern Desert. Egypt and Their Alluvial Deposits</i>. M. Sc. Thesis, Cairo University, vol. 236 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammar, F. A., Omar, S. A. M. &amp; El-Sawey, E. L. S. H. Genetic affiliation of gold and uranium mineralization in El-Missikat granite, Central Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Nucl. Sci. Sci. J.</i><b>5</b>(1), 33&#x2013;47. 10.21608/nssj.2016.30823 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/nssj.2016.30823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorman, D. H. &amp; Nuffield, E. W. Studies of radioactive compounds: VIII&#x2014;uranophane and beta-uranophane. <i>Am. Mineral. J. Earth Planet. Mater.</i><b>40</b>(7&#x2013;8), 634&#x2013;645 (1955).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rimsaite, J. Alteration of radioactive minerals in granite and related secondary uranium mineralizations. In <i>Ore Genesis: The State of the Art. Spical Publication of the Society for Geology Applied to Mineral Deposits</i> (eds Amstutz, G. C., El-Goresy, A., Frenzel, G., Kluth, C. &amp; Moh, G.), 269&#x2013;280 (1982).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason, B. <i>Principles of Geochemistry</i> 3rd edn. (Wiley, New York, 1966).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardier, A. M. <i>Geology, Petrology and Radioactivity of Some Granitic Masses in the Area of Gabal Abu Diab, Eastern Desert, Egypt</i>. Doctoral dissertation, Ph. D. Thesis. Faculty of Science, Ain Shams University, vol. 179 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briqueu, L., Bougault, H. &amp; Joron, J. L. Quantification of Nb, Ta, Ti and V anomalies in magmas associated with subduction zones: Petrogenetic implications. <i>Earth Planet. Sci. Lett.</i><b>68</b>(2), 297&#x2013;308. 10.1016/0012-821X(84)90161-4 (1984).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0012-821X(84)90161-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, S. R. &amp; McLennan, S. M. The continental crust: Its composition and evolution. <i>Phys. Earth Planet. Inter.</i><b>165</b>(3&#x2013;4), 197&#x2013;213 (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmail, E. M. Mineralogical studies of the stream sediments in Khour Abalea Abu Rusheid area, South Eastern Desert, Egypt. <i>Middle East J Appl Sci.</i><b>6</b>(4), 867&#x2013;877 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisbet, H. et al. An experimental study of the solubility and speciation of thorium in chloride-bearing aqueous solutions at temperatures up to 250 C. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i><b>239</b>, 363&#x2013;373. 10.1016/j.gca.2018.08.001 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gca.2018.08.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirtopanu, P., Jakab, G., Andersen, C. J. &amp; Fairhurst, J. R. Thorite, thorogummite and xenotime-(Y) occurrence in Ditrau alkaline intrusive massif, East Carpathians, Romania. <i>Proc. Rom. Acad. Ser. Chem. Life Sci. Geosci.</i><b>15</b>(2), 111&#x2013;132 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xf6;rster, H. J. Composition and origin of intermediate solid solutions in the system thorite&#x2013;xenotime&#x2013;zircon&#x2013;coffinite. <i>Lithos</i><b>88</b>(1&#x2013;4), 35&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.lithos.2005.08.003 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2005.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. The origin of uranium deposits related to the Huangmeijian A-type granite from the Lu-Zong volcanic basin, South China: Constraints from zircon U-Pb geochronology and mineral chemistry. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>141</b>, 104665. 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2021.104665 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2021.104665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Q., Chen, B., Li, Q. &amp; Jin, H. Distribution and mineralogical features of thorite in the Bayan Obo deposit: Implications for hydrothermal metasomatic Th re-enrichment. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>164</b>, 105831. 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2023.105831 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2023.105831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkland, C. L., Smithies, R. H., Taylor, R. J. M., Evans, N. &amp; McDonald, B. Zircon Th/U ratios in magmatic environs. <i>Lithos</i><b>212</b>, 397&#x2013;414. 10.1016/j.lithos.2014.11.021 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lithos.2014.11.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubatto, D. Zircon: The metamorphic mineral. <i>Rev. Mineral. Geochem.</i><b>83</b>, 261&#x2013;295. 10.2138/rmg.2017.83.9 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2138/rmg.2017.83.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakymchuk, C., Kirkland, C. I. &amp; Clark, C. Th/U ratios in metamorphic zircon. <i>J. Metamorphic Geol.</i><b>36</b>, 715&#x2013;737. 10.1111/jmg.12307 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jmg.12307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai, W. et al. Hydrothermal zircon: Characteristics, genesis and metallogenic implications. <i>Ore Geol. Rev.</i><b>149</b>, 1&#x2013;16. 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2022.105111 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2022.105111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., Yang, Y., Xing, Y., Jiang, X., Li, X. &amp; Li, T. Study on the relationship between uranium mineralization and fluorite and polymer. In <i>Progress Report on Nuclear Science and Technology in China (Vol. 6). Proceedings of Academic Annual Meeting of China Nuclear Society in 2019, No. 1&#x2014;Uranium Geology Sub-volume</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi-Puig, T., Sol&#xe9;, J. &amp; Alba-Aldave, L. Uranium in fluorite, a case study: The La Azul fluorspar deposit, Taxco, Guerrero, Mexico. <i>Minerals</i><b>13</b>(12), 1495. 10.3390/min13121495 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min13121495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shata, A. E. &amp; El Balakassy, S. S. Supergene enrichments of uranium mineralization within Mn-Fe deposits of Um Bogma area, Southwest Sinai, Egypt. <i>Sedimentol. Egypt</i><b>20</b>, 35&#x2013;48 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallam, O. R. Origin of Mn-Fe ore bearing radioactive minerals at Um Bogma area, Southwestern Sinai, Egypt. <i>Nucl. Sci. Sci. J.</i><b>9</b>(1), 79&#x2013;102 (2020).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>