<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41299696</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1479-5876</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of translational medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Transl Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise intensity-mediated regulation of gut epithelial cells and immune function in gut microbiota dysbiosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>10</StartPage><MedlinePgn>10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12967-025-07492-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The gut epithelium and resident microbiota critically regulate intestinal barrier integrity, immune homeostasis, and systemic health. Emerging evidence from human studies and clinical trials indicates that exercise intensity modulates these components differentially.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This narrative review synthesizes human and clinical trial data on exercise intensity effects on gut epithelial function, immune responses, and microbiota dynamics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Moderate-intensity continuous training (MICT; 30&#x2013;60&#xa0;min at 50&#x2013;70% VO&#x2082; max) enhances tight junction proteins (e.g., ZO-1, occludin; &#x2191;15&#x2013;20% in RCTs), reduces oxidative stress, and shifts cytokines toward anti-inflammatory profiles (IL-10 &#x2191;, TNF-&#x3b1; &#x2193;), improving barrier integrity and microbial diversity (alpha-diversity &#x2191;10&#x2013;20% over 8&#x2013;12 weeks; e.g., enrichment of Lactobacillus, Bifidobacterium, Faecalibacterium prausnitzii, Roseburia hominis). Clinical trials in metabolic syndrome and mild IBD confirm these benefits. In contrast, high-intensity interval training (HIIT; &gt;70% VO&#x2082; max for &gt;&#x2009;90&#xa0;min) transiently elevates permeability (zonulin/LPS &#x2191; in 20&#x2013;30% of untrained participants), dysbiosis (SCFA-producers &#x2193;, Escherichia coli/Fusobacterium &#x2191;), and inflammation (CRP/IL-6 &#x2191;), particularly under confounders like dehydration or poor diet. HIIT improves insulin sensitivity but risks microbial imbalance without recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">A bidirectional gut-exercise axis emerges, with MICT linked to IBS symptom relief and reduced colitis severity in trials; probiotics/prebiotics mitigate HIIT risks. Gaps include cellular mechanisms, inter-individual variability (genetics, diet, hydration), and long-term impacts. Multi-omics trials are needed for personalized exercise prescriptions in disease states.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoseini</LastName><ForeName>Rastegar</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8685-2471</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Razi University, Taq Bostan, University Street, P.O.Box. 6714414971, Kermanshah, Iran. R.hoseini@razi.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahim</LastName><ForeName>Hiwa Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science for Health and Performance, College of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Halabja, Kurdistan Region, Halabja, 46018, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saifalddin</LastName><ForeName>Dara Latif</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science for Health and Performance, College of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Halabja, Kurdistan Region, Halabja, 46018, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kareem</LastName><ForeName>Dashni Anwer</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science for Health and Performance, College of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Halabja, Kurdistan Region, Halabja, 46018, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fatah</LastName><ForeName>Arazw Mahmood</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Science for Health and Performance, College of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, University of Halabja, Kurdistan Region, Halabja, 46018, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Transl Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-5876</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diversity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intensity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microbiota</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: Not applicable. Consent for publication: All authors provided input into the manuscript, reviewed the final draft, and provided consent for publication. Conflict of interest: The authors affirm that the research was carried out without any commercial or financial relationships that could be interpreted as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41299696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12764056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-025-07492-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12967-025-07492-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rinninella E, Raoul P, Cintoni M, Franceschi F, Miggiano GAD, Gasbarrini A, Mele MC. What is the healthy gut microbiota composition? A changing ecosystem across age, environment, diet, and diseases. Microorganisms. 2019;7(1):14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6351938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30634578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oroian BA, Ciobica A, Timofte D, Stefanescu C, Serban IL. New Metabolic, Digestive, and oxidative stress-Related manifestations associated with posttraumatic stress disorder. Oxidative Med Cell Longev. 2021;2021(1):5599265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8712172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34966477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu J, Feng S, Guo C, Xue B, He K, Li L. Immunological mechanisms of inflammatory diseases caused by gut microbiota dysbiosis: A review. Biomed Pharmacother. 2023;164:114985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37311282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Q, Feng X, Hu Y, Su S. The human gut microbiota is associated with host lifestyle: A comprehensive narrative review. Front Microbiol. 2025;16:1549160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12233163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40625617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari P, Dwivedi R, Bansal M, Tripathi M, Dada R. Role of gut microbiota in neurological disorders and its therapeutic significance. J Clin Med. 2023;12(4):1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9965848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36836185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbara G, Barbaro MR, Fuschi D, Palombo M, Falangone F, Cremon C, Marasco G, Stanghellini V. Corrigendum: inflammatory and microbiota-related regulation of the intestinal epithelial barrier. Front Nutr. 2021;8:790387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8591313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34790692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbara G, Barbaro MR, Fuschi D, Palombo M, Falangone F, Cremon C, Marasco G, Stanghellini V. Inflammatory and microbiota-related regulation of the intestinal epithelial barrier. Front Nutr. 2021;8:718356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34589512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan I, Issac PK, Rahman MM, Guru A, Arockiaraj J. Gut-brain axis a key player to control gut dysbiosis in neurological diseases. Mol Neurobiol. 2024;61(12):9873&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37851313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcock A, Hocking C. An occupational perspective of health. Taylor &amp; Francis; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cataldi S, Bonavolont&#xe0; V, Poli L, Clemente FM, De Candia M, Carvutto R, Silva AF, Badicu G, Greco G, Fischetti F. The relationship between physical activity, physical exercise, and human gut microbiota in healthy and unhealthy subjects: a systematic review. Biology. 2022;11(3):479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8945171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35336852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varghese S, Rao S, Khattak A, Zamir F, Chaari A. Physical exercise and the gut microbiome: a bidirectional relationship influencing health and performance. Nutrients. 2024;16(21):3663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11547208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39519496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh A, Srinivasan D, Subbarayan R, Chauhan A, Krishnamoorthy L, Kumar J, Krishnan M, Shrestha R. Enhancing colorectal cancer treatment: the role of bifidobacterium in modulating gut immunity and mitigating Capecitabine-Induced toxicity. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2025;69(9):e70023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40109200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Hul M, Cani PD, Petitfils C, De Vos WM, Tilg H, El-Omar EM. What defines a healthy gut microbiome? Gut. 2024;73(11):1893&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11503168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39322314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA, Forster SC, Giles EM. Exercise, gut Microbiome, and gastrointestinal diseases: therapeutic impact and molecular mechanisms. Gastroenterology; 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39978410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craven J, Cox AJ, Bellinger P, Desbrow B, Irwin C, Buchan J, McCartney D, Sabapathy S. The influence of exercise training volume alterations on the gut microbiome in highly-trained middle-distance runners. Eur J Sport Sci. 2022;22(8):1222&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34034615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bycura D, Santos AC, Shiffer A, Kyman S, Winfree K, Sutliffe J, Pearson T, Sonderegger D, Cope E, Caporaso JG. Impact of different exercise modalities on the human gut Microbiome. Sports. 2021;9(2):14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7909775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33494210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couvert A, Goumy L, Maillard F, Esbrat A, Lanchais K, Saugrain C, Verdier C, Dor&#xe9; E, Chevarin C, Adjtoutah D. Effects of a cycling versus running HIIT program on fat mass loss and gut microbiota composition in men with overweight/obesity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2024;56(5):839&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38233990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torquati L, Gajanand T, Cox E, Willis C, Zaugg J, Keating S, Coombes J. Effects of exercise intensity on gut microbiome composition and function in people with type 2 diabetes. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23(4):530&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35107058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronin O, Barton W, Skuse P, Penney NC, Garcia-Perez I, Murphy EF, Woods T, Nugent H, Fanning A, Melgar S. A prospective metagenomic and metabolomic analysis of the impact of exercise and/or Whey protein supplementation on the gut microbiome of sedentary adults. MSystems. 2018;3(3):00044&#x2013;00018. 10.1128/msystems.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/msystems</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5915698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29719871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rettedal EA, Cree JM, Adams SE, MacRae C, Skidmore PM, Cameron-Smith D, Gant N, Blenkiron C, Merry TL. Short&#x2010;term high&#x2010;intensity interval training exercise does not affect gut bacterial community diversity or composition of lean and overweight men. Exp Physiol. 2020;105(8):1268&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32478429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karl JP, Margolis LM, Madslien EH, Murphy NE, Castellani JW, Gundersen Y, Hoke AV, Levangie MW, Kumar R, Chakraborty N. Changes in intestinal microbiota composition and metabolism coincide with increased intestinal permeability in young adults under prolonged physiological stress. Am J Physiology-Gastrointestinal Liver Physiol. 2017;312(6):G559&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28336545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min L, Ablitip A, Wang R, Luciana T, Wei M, Ma X. Effects of exercise on gut microbiota of adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2024;16(7):1070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11013040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38613103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J, Yan W, Sun X, Chen J. The role of exercise-induced short-chain fatty acids in the gut&#x2013;muscle axis: implications for sarcopenia prevention and therapy. Front Microbiol. 2025;16:1665551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12540370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41132381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen JM, Shahzad S, Kanaley JA, Ericsson AC, Dhillon J. The effects of 6 Wk of resistance training on the gut Microbiome and cardiometabolic health in young adults with overweight and obesity. J Appl Physiol. 2024;136(2):349&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38059291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullen JM, Shahzad S, Dhillon J. A systematic review on the effects of exercise on gut microbial diversity, taxonomic composition, and microbial metabolites: identifying research gaps and future directions. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1292673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10770260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38187136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancino Ram&#xed;rez J, Gonz&#xe1;lez Rojas L, Magne F, Gotteland M. Modulation of gut microbiota through physical activity in individuals with obesity&#x2014;a systematic review. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2024;50:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39637368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Li Y, Wang Y, Chen J, Liu Y. The athlete gut microbiome: a narrative review of multi-omics insights and next-generation probiotic strategies. Nutrients. 2025;17(20):3260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12566858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41156512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aya V, Pardo-Rodriguez D, Vega LC, Cala MP, Ram&#xed;rez JD. Integrating metagenomics and metabolomics to study the gut Microbiome and host relationships in sports across different energy systems. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):15356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12048592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40316630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dmytriv TR, Storey KB, Lushchak VI. Intestinal barrier permeability: the influence of gut microbiota, nutrition, and exercise. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1380713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11260943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39040079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severo JS, Silva ACAd S, BLBd, Reinaldo TS, Oliveira AMd, Lima RSP, Torres-Leal FL. Santos AAd, Silva mtbd: physical exercise as a therapeutic approach in Gastrointestinal diseases. J Clin Med. 2025;14(5):1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11899784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40095789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall AB, Yassour M, Sauk J, Garner A, Jiang X, Arthur T, Lagoudas GK, Vatanen T, Fornelos N, Wilson R. A novel Ruminococcus gnavus clade enriched in inflammatory bowel disease patients. Genome Med. 2017;9(1):103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5704459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29183332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campaniello D, Corbo MR, Sinigaglia M, Speranza B, Racioppo A, Altieri C, Bevilacqua A. How diet and physical activity modulate gut microbiota: evidence, and perspectives. Nutrients. 2022;14(12):2456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9227967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35745186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedroza Matute S, Iyavoo S. Exploring the gut microbiota: lifestyle choices, disease associations, and personal genomics. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1225120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10585655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37867494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boytar AN, Nitert MD, Morrision M, Skinner TL, Jenkins DG. Exercise-induced changes to the human gut microbiota and implications for colorectal cancer: a narrative review. J Physiol. 2022;600(24):5189&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10099575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun S, Seo Y, Lee Y, Lee DT. Gut Microbiome related to metabolic diseases after moderate-to-vigorous intensity exercise. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2024;22(4):375&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11342187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39185003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauss M, G&#xe9;rard P, Mosca A, Leclerc M. Interplay between exercise and gut Microbiome in the context of human health and performance. Front Nutr. 2021;8:637010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34179053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JS, Simpson BS, Murphy KJ. The role of a mediterranean diet and physical activity in decreasing age-related inflammation through modulation of the gut microbiota composition. Br J Nutr. 2022;128(7):1299&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34423757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C, Liu S, Chen L, Shen J, Niu Y, Wang T, Zhang W, Fu L. Effect of exercise and butyrate supplementation on microbiota composition and lipid metabolism. J Endocrinol. 2019;243(2):125&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31454784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribichini E, Scalese G, Cesarini A, Mocci C, Pallotta N, Severi C, Corazziari ES. Exercise-Induced Gastrointestinal symptoms in endurance sports: A review of Pathophysiology, symptoms, and nutritional management. Dietetics. 2023;2(3):289&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo B, Xiang D, Nieman DC, Chen P. The effects of moderate exercise on chronic stress-induced intestinal barrier dysfunction and antimicrobial defense. Brain Behav Immun. 2014;39:99&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24291325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mailing L. Diet and exercise modulate the gut microbiome with implications for health and disease. University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wo&#x17a;niak D, Cichy W, Przys&#x142;awski J, Drzyma&#x142;a-Czy&#x17c; S. The role of microbiota and enteroendocrine cells in maintaining homeostasis in the human digestive tract. Adv Med Sci. 2021;66(2):284&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34098509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis SP, Bolin LP, Crane PB, Wei H, Crandell J. Non-pharmacological interventions to manage fatigue in adults with inflammatory bowel disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2020;41:101229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32836107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryani D, Alfaqih MS, Gunadi JW, Sylviana N, Goenawan H, Megantara I, Lesmana R. Type, intensity, and duration of exercise as regulator of gut Microbiome profile. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2022;21(3):84&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35245243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mach N, Fuster-Botella D. Endurance exercise and gut microbiota: A review. J Sport Health Sci. 2017;6(2):179&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6188999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolfi C, Maresca C, Monteleone G, Laudisi F. Implication of intestinal barrier dysfunction in gut dysbiosis and diseases. Biomedicines. 2022;10(2):289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8869546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35203499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorenza M, Gunnarsson T, Hostrup M, Iaia F, Schena F, Pilegaard H, Bangsbo J. Metabolic stress-dependent regulation of the mitochondrial biogenic molecular response to high&#x2010;intensity exercise in human skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2018;596(14):2823&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6046074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29727016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark A, Mach N. Exercise-induced stress behavior, gut-microbiota-brain axis and diet: a systematic review for athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2016;13:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5121944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27924137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Liu R, Song Z, Zhang X. Exercise, Diet, and brain health: from the perspective of gut microbiota regulation. Nutrients. 2025;17(10):1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12539670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40431427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M, Qu Y, Zheng Y, Guo H. The effect of exercise on depression and gut microbiota: possible mechanisms. Brain Res Bull. 2025;220:111130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39557221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estaki M, Pither J, Baumeister P, Little JP, Gill SK, Ghosh S, Ahmadi-Vand Z, Marsden KR, Gibson DL. Cardiorespiratory fitness as a predictor of intestinal microbial diversity and distinct metagenomic functions. Microbiome. 2016;4:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4976518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27502158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederberger E, Parnham MJ. The impact of diet and exercise on drug responses. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(14):7692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8304791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Li J, Zhou Q, Wang C, Hu J, Liu C. Effects of physical exercise on the microbiota in irritable bowel syndrome. Nutrients. 2024;16(16).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11356817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro FM, Petriz B, Marques G, Kamilla LH, Franco OL. Is there an exercise-intensity threshold capable of avoiding the leaky gut? Front Nutr. 2021;8:627289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7982409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33763441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabr MAs, Lee J-M, Saint-Maurice PF, Yoo H, Welk GJ. Validity of physical activity monitors for assessing lower intensity activity in adults. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Activity. 2014;11:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4192284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25260625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atakan MM, Li Y, Ko&#x15f;ar &#x15e;N, Turnag&#xf6;l HH, Yan X. Evidence-based effects of high-intensity interval training on exercise capacity and health: A review with historical perspective. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(13):7201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8294064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34281138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calbet JA, Mart&#xed;n-Rodr&#xed;guez S, Martin-Rincon M, Morales-Alamo D. An integrative approach to the regulation of mitochondrial respiration during exercise: focus on high-intensity exercise. Redox Biol. 2020;35:101478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32156501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toffoli G. Perceived exertion: metrological approaches and applications to endurance performance in able-bodied and spinal cord injured populations. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahim HA, Damirchi A, Babaei P. Comparison of HIIT and MICT and further detraining on metabolic syndrome and Asprosin signaling pathway in metabolic syndrome model of rats. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):11313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11101655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38760452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh SS, Wang J, Yannie PJ, Ghosh S. Intestinal barrier dysfunction, LPS translocation, and disease development. J Endocr Soc. 2020;4(2):bvz039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7033038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32099951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoque KM, Chakraborty S, Sheikh IA, Woodward OM. New advances in the pathophysiology of intestinal ion transport and barrier function in diarrhea and the impact on therapy. Expert Rev anti-infective Therapy. 2012;10(6):687&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22734958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson JK, Johansson ME. The role of goblet cells and mucus in intestinal homeostasis. Nat Reviews Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;19(12):785&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36097076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soderholm AT, Pedicord VA. Intestinal epithelial cells: at the interface of the microbiota and mucosal immunity. Immunology. 2019;158(4):267&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6856932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31509239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ordille AJ, Phadtare S. Intensity-specific considerations for exercise for patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterol Rep. 2023;11:goad004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9940700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36814502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Ah Morano AE, Dorneles GP, Peres A, Lira FS. The role of glucose homeostasis on immune function in response to exercise: the impact of low or higher energetic conditions. J Cell Physiol. 2020;235(4):3169&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31565806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu X, Yu X, Nov&#xe1;k P, Gui Q, Yin K. Enhancing intestinal barrier efficiency: A novel metabolic diseases therapy. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1120168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10018175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36937361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panwar S, Sharma S, Tripathi P. Role of barrier integrity and dysfunctions in maintaining the healthy gut and their health outcomes. Front Physiol. 2021;12:715611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey A, Lunding LP, Ehlers JC, Weckmann M, Zissler UM, Wegmann M. More than just a barrier: the immune functions of the airway epithelium in asthma pathogenesis. Front Immunol. 2020;11:761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7198799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R, Zhang L, Li P, Pang K, Liu H, Tian L. Epithelial barrier in the nasal mucosa, related risk factors and diseases. Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2023;184(5):481&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10137320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36724763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supruniuk E, G&#xf3;rski J, Chabowski A. Endogenous and exogenous antioxidants in skeletal muscle fatigue development during exercise. Antioxidants. 2023;12(2):501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9952836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36830059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unsal V, Dalk&#x131;ran T, &#xc7;i&#xe7;ek M, K&#xf6;l&#xfc;k&#xe7;&#xfc; E. The role of natural antioxidants against reactive oxygen species produced by cadmium toxicity: a review. Adv Pharm Bull. 2020;10(2):184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7191230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32373487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruk J, Aboul-Enein HY, K&#x142;adna A, Bowser JE. Oxidative stress in biological systems and its relation with pathophysiological functions: the effect of physical activity on cellular redox homeostasis. Free Radic Res. 2019;53(5):497&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Docherty S, Harley R, McAuley JJ, Crowe LA, Pedret C, Kirwan PD, Siebert S, Millar NL. The effect of exercise on cytokines: implications for musculoskeletal health: a narrative review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabilitation. 2022;14(1):5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34991697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojcik-Grzybek D, Hubalewska-Mazgaj M, Surmiak M, Sliwowski Z, Dobrut A, Mlodzinska A, Wojcik A, Kwiecien S, Magierowski M, Mazur-Bialy A. The combination of intestinal alkaline phosphatase treatment with moderate physical activity alleviates the severity of experimental colitis in obese mice via modulation of gut microbiota, Attenuation of Proinflammatory cytokines, oxidative stress biomarkers and DNA oxidative damage in colonic mucosa. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(6):2964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8955215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35328382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente-Su&#xe1;rez VJ, Beltr&#xe1;n-Velasco AI, Redondo-Fl&#xf3;rez L, Mart&#xed;n-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Tornero-Aguilera JF. Global impacts of Western diet and its effects on metabolism and health: A narrative review. Nutrients. 2023;15(12):2749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10302286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37375654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Li Z, Liu J. Amino acids regulating skeletal muscle metabolism: mechanisms of action, physical training dosage recommendations and adverse effects. Nutr Metabolism. 2024;21(1):41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11220999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38956658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Silveira MP, da Silva Fagundes KK, Bizuti MR, Starck &#xc9;, Rossi RC, de Resende e Silva DT. Physical exercise as a tool to help the immune system against COVID-19: an integrative review of the current literature. Clin Experimental Med. 2021;21(1):15&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7387807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32728975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanada S, Pirzadeh M, Carver KY, Deng JC. Respiratory viral infection-induced Microbiome alterations and secondary bacterial pneumonia. Front Immunol. 2018;9:2640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6250824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30505304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao T, Verma HK, Pande B, Costanzo V, Ye W, Cai Y, Bhaskar L. Physical activity and nutritional influence on immune function: an important strategy to improve immunity and health status. Front Physiol. 2021;12:751374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8531728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34690818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Sun Y, Wang Q, Yu S, Li Y, Yao B, Yang X. Astragalus polysaccharides-induced gut microbiota play a predominant role in enhancing of intestinal barrier function of broiler chickens. J Anim Sci Biotechnol. 2024;15(1):106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11302362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39103958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao N, Rezaee F. Airway epithelial cell junctions as targets for pathogens and antimicrobial therapy. Pharmaceutics. 2022;14(12):2619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9786141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36559113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y, Ding J, Zhao R, Song Y, Yoo J, Moon H, Koo S, Kim JS, Shen J. Intrinsic immunomodulatory hydrogels for chronic inflammation. Chem Soc Rev. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39499495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasb M, Li F, Dayoub L, Wu T, Wei M, Chen N. Bridging the gap: integrating exercise mimicry into chronic disease management through suppressing chronic inflammation. J Adv Res. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11976426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38704088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Bueno R, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez-Cort&#xe9;s R, Calatayud J, Andersen LL, del Pozo Cruz B, Petermann-Rocha F. The triad of physical activity: an optimal combination for cardiovascular health. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39725179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limbach M. Physical performance of allogeneic stem cell transplant candidates prior to transplantation. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crea E. Effects of repeated high-intensity interval training interventions on oxidative metabolism adaptations in human skeletal muscle. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong C, Yang M, Yue N, Zhang Y, Tian C, Wei D, Shi R, Yao J, Wang L, Li D. Restore intestinal barrier integrity: an approach for inflammatory bowel disease therapy. J Inflamm Res. 2024:5389&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11330754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39161679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;zener ZC, Cevhertas L, Nadeau K, Akdis M, Akdis CA. Environmental factors in epithelial barrier dysfunction. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2020;145(6):1517&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32507229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo WT, Odenwald MA, Turner JR, Zuo L. Tight junction proteins occludin and ZO-1 as regulators of epithelial proliferation and survival. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2022;1514(1):21&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9427709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z, Liu H, Wang X. Advancements in Understanding bacterial enteritis pathogenesis through organoids. Mol Biol Rep. 2024;51(1):512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38622483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leyane TS, Jere SW, Houreld NN. Oxidative stress in ageing and chronic degenerative pathologies: molecular mechanisms involved in counteracting oxidative stress and chronic inflammation. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(13):7273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9266760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35806275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y, Zhang H, Guo W, Yu L. Potential role of Ghrelin in the regulation of inflammation. FASEB J. 2022;36(9):e22508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35983825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Rodr&#xed;guez EC, L&#xf3;pez VJ. Hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy (HIE). Front Neurol. 2024;15:1389703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11300279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39108657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rallis D, Dermitzaki N, Baltogianni M, Kapetaniou K, Giapros V. Balance of antioxidants vs. oxidants in perinatal asphyxia. Appl Sci. 2024;14(21):9651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun N, Ogulur I, Mitamura Y, Yazici D, Pat Y, Bu X, Li M, Zhu X, Babayev H, Ardicli S. The epithelial barrier theory and its associated diseases. Allergy. 2024;79(12):3192&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11657050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39370939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outla Z, Prechova M, Korelova K, Gemperle J, Gregor M. Mechanics of cell sheets: plectin as an integrator of cytoskeletal networks. Open Biology. 2025;15(1):240208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11774597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39875099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y, Jiang B, Zhao J. Induction mechanisms of autophagy and Endoplasmic reticulum stress in intestinal ischemia-reperfusion injury, inflammatory bowel disease, and colorectal cancer. Biomed Pharmacother. 2024;170:115984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38070244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y, Fernandez-Garcia B, Lehmann HI, Li G, Kroemer G, L&#xf3;pez-Ot&#xed;n C, Xiao J. Exercise sustains the hallmarks of health. J Sport Health Sci. 2023;12(1):8&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9923435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36374766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalli CAM, Gabbiadini R, Dal Buono A, Quadarella A, De Marco A, Repici A, Bezzio C, Simonetta E, Aliberti S, Armuzzi A. Lung involvement in inflammatory bowel diseases: shared pathways and unwanted connections. J Clin Med. 2023;12(19):6419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10573999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37835065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breed D. Physiological responses of wild antelope to exercise training as a prospective treatment to prevent capture myopathy. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa B, Gouveia MJ, Vale N. Oxidative stress induced by antivirals: implications for adverse outcomes during pregnancy and in newborns. Antioxidants. 2024;13(12):1518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11727424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39765846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codella R, Luzi L, Terruzzi I. Exercise has the guts: how physical activity May positively modulate gut microbiota in chronic and immune-based diseases. Dig Liver Disease. 2018;50(4):331&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29233686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Beltagi M, Saeed NK, Bediwy AS, El-Sawaf Y, Elbatarny A, Elbeltagi R. Exploring the gut-exercise link: A systematic review of Gastrointestinal disorders in physical activity. World J Gastroenterol. 2025;31(22):106835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12175863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40539198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karhu E, Forsg&#xe5;rd RA, Alanko L, Alfthan H, Pussinen P, H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen E, Korpela R. Exercise and Gastrointestinal symptoms: running-induced changes in intestinal permeability and markers of Gastrointestinal function in asymptomatic and symptomatic runners. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(12):2519&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5694518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29032392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekirov I, Russell SL, Antunes LCM, Finlay BB. Gut microbiota in health and disease. Physiol rev. 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu GD, Bushmanc FD, Lewis JD. Diet, the human gut microbiota, and IBD. Anaerobe. 2013;24:117&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23548695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandpal M, Indari O, Baral B, Jakhmola S, Tiwari D, Bhandari V, Pandey RK, Bala K, Sonawane A, Jha HC. Dysbiosis of gut microbiota from the perspective of the gut&#x2013;brain axis: role in the provocation of neurological disorders. Metabolites. 2022;12(11):1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9692419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36355147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothschild D, Weissbrod O, Barkan E, Kurilshikov A, Korem T, Zeevi D, Costea PI, Godneva A, Kalka IN, Bar N. Environment dominates over host genetics in shaping human gut microbiota. Nature. 2018;555(7695):210&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vich Vila A, Collij V, Sanna S, Sinha T, Imhann F, Bourgonje AR, Mujagic Z, Jonkers DM, Masclee AA, Fu J. Impact of commonly used drugs on the composition and metabolic function of the gut microbiota. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6969170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31953381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das B, Nair GB. Homeostasis and dysbiosis of the gut Microbiome in health and disease. J Biosci. 2019;44(5):117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31719226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hearris MA, Hammond KM, Fell JM, Morton JP. Regulation of muscle glycogen metabolism during exercise: implications for endurance performance and training adaptations. Nutrients. 2018;10(3):298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5872716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29498691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke SF, Murphy EF, O&#x2019;Sullivan O, Lucey AJ, Humphreys M, Hogan A, Hayes P, O&#x2019;Reilly M, Jeffery IB, Wood-Martin R. Exercise and associated dietary extremes impact on gut microbial diversity. Gut. 2014;63(12):1913&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25021423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PETERS HP, De Vries W, Vanberge-Henegouwen G, Akkermans L. Potential benefits and hazards of physical activity and exercise on the Gastrointestinal tract. Gut. 2001;48(3):435&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1760153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11171839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gisolfi CV. Is the GI system built for exercise? Physiology. 2000;15(3):114&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11390892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Luz Scheffer D, Latini A. Exercise-induced immune system response: Anti-inflammatory status on peripheral and central organs. Biochim Et Biophys Acta (BBA)-Molecular Basis Disease. 2020;1866(10):165823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7188661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32360589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barton W, Penney NC, Cronin O, Garcia-Perez I, Molloy MG, Holmes E, Shanahan F, Cotter PD, O&#x2019;Sullivan O. The Microbiome of professional athletes differs from that of more sedentary subjects in composition and particularly at the functional metabolic level. Gut. 2018;67(4):625&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28360096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordero A, Masi&#xe1; MD, Galve E. Physical exercise and health. Revista Espa&#xf1;ola De Cardiolog&#xed;a (English Edition). 2014;67(9):748&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25172071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Q, Jiang S, Du G. Effects of exercise frequency on the gut microbiota in elderly individuals. Microbiologyopen. 2020;9(8):e1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32356611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bressa C, Bail&#xe9;n-Andrino M, P&#xe9;rez-Santiago J, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Soltero R, P&#xe9;rez M, Montalvo-Lominchar MG, Mat&#xe9;-Mu&#xf1;oz JL, Dom&#xed;nguez R, Moreno D, Larrosa M. Differences in gut microbiota profile between women with active lifestyle and sedentary women. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(2):e0171352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5302835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28187199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto M, Inoue R, Tsukahara T, Ushida K, Chiji H, Matsubara N, Hara H. Voluntary running exercise alters microbiota composition and increases n-butyrate concentration in the rat cecum. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2008;72(2):572&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18256465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes RL. A review of the role of the gut Microbiome in personalized sports nutrition. Front Nutr. 2020;6:504337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6966970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31998739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T-W, Park Y-M, Holscher HD, Padilla J, Scroggins RJ, Welly R, Britton SL, Koch LG, Vieira-Potter VJ, Swanson KS. Physical activity differentially affects the cecal microbiota of ovariectomized female rats selectively bred for high and low aerobic capacity. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(8):e0136150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4547806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26301712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mailing LJ, Allen JM, Buford TW, Fields CJ, Woods JA. Exercise and the gut microbiome: a review of the evidence, potential mechanisms, and implications for human health. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2019;47(2):75&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30883471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NP, Gleeson M, Shephard RJ, Gleeson M, Woods JA, Bishop NC, Fleshner M, Green C, Pedersen BK, Hoffman-Goetz L. Position statement part one: immune function and exercise. Exerc Immunol Rev. 2011;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21446352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle T, Heyworth J, Bull F, McKerracher S, Platell C, Fritschi L. Timing and intensity of recreational physical activity and the risk of subsite-specific colorectal cancer. Cancer Causes Control. 2011;22(12):1647&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21922204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Bander Z, Nitert MD, Mousa A, Naderpoor N. The gut microbiota and inflammation: an overview. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(20):7618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7589951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33086688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teodoro TH, Costa KPM, Prestes J, Campanholi J, Navalta J, Pereira GB. The effects of acute and chronic exercise on immune markers of TH1/TH2 cells in older adults: a systematic review. Front Physiol. 2025;16:1453747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11850391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40008210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman-Goetz L, Quadrilatero J. Treadmill exercise in mice increases intestinal lymphocyte loss via apoptosis. Acta Physiol Scand. 2003;179(3):289&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14616245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki K, Tominaga T, Ruhee RT, Ma S. Characterization and modulation of systemic inflammatory response to exhaustive exercise in relation to oxidative stress. Antioxidants. 2020;9(5):401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7278761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32397304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook MD, Allen JM, Pence BD, Wallig MA, Gaskins HR, White BA, Woods JA. Exercise and gut immune function: evidence of alterations in colon immune cell homeostasis and Microbiome characteristics with exercise training. Immunol Cell Biol. 2016;94(2):158&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26626721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batacan R, Fenning A, Dalbo V, Scanlan A, Duncan M, Moore R, Stanley D. A gut reaction: the combined influence of exercise and diet on Gastrointestinal microbiota in rats. J Appl Microbiol. 2017;122(6):1627&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28276612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phelps CM, Willis NB, Duan T, Lee AH, Zhang Y, Pandey SP, Laughlin CR, Rosen AB, McPherson AC, Shapira JH. Exercise-induced microbiota metabolite enhances CD8 T cell antitumor immunity promoting immunotherapy efficacy. Cell. 2025;188(20):5680&#x2013;700. e5628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12258965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40639377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonomini-Gnutzmann R, Plaza-Diaz J, Jorquera-Aguilera C, Rodriguez-Rodriguez A, Rodriguez-Rodriguez F. Effect of intensity and duration of exercise on gut microbiota in humans: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(15):9518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuhl M, Schneider S, Lanphere K, Conn C, Dokladny K, Moseley P. Exercise regulation of intestinal tight junction proteins. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(12):980&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamprecht M, Frauwallner A. Exercise, intestinal barrier dysfunction and probiotic supplementation. Med Sport Sci. 2012;59:47&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23075554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollander D, Kaunitz JD. The leaky gut: tight junctions but loose associations? Dig Dis Sci. 2020;65(5):1277&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7193723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31471860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabzevari Rad R. The impact of different training intensities on athletes&#x2019; immune system function and the management of upper respiratory traction infections: a narrative review. Sport Sci Health. 2024;20(2):415&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam H, Tsai SH, Figueiredo C, Jackson GS, Marcotte-Ch&#xe9;nard A, Bosak J, Moreno&#x2010;Caba&#xf1;as A, Lira FS, Little JP. Direct assessment of leukocyte signalling and cytokine secretion reveals exercise intensity&#x2010;dependent reductions in anti&#x2010;inflammatory cytokine action. J Physiol. 2024;602(12):2717&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38776176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambat A, Antony L, Maji A, Ghimire S, Mattiello S, Kashyap PC, More S, Sebastian V, Scaria J. Enhancing recovery from gut Microbiome dysbiosis and alleviating DSS-induced colitis in mice with a consortium of rare short-chain fatty acid-producing bacteria. Gut Microbes. 2024;16(1):2382324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11290756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39069899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerqueira &#xc9;, Marinho DA, Neiva HP, Louren&#xe7;o O. Inflammatory effects of high and moderate intensity exercise&#x2014;a systematic review. Front Physiol. 2020;10:489354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6962351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31992987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koochaki R, Amini E, Zarehossini S, Zareh D, Haftcheshmeh SM, Jha SK, Kesharwani P, Shakeri A, Sahebkar A. Alkaloids in cancer therapy: targeting the tumor microenvironment and metastasis signaling pathways. Fitoterapia. 2024;179:106222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39343104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archontakis-Barakakis P, Mavridis T, Chlorogiannis DD, Barakakis G, Laou E, Sessler DI, Gkiokas G, Chalkias A. Intestinal oxygen utilisation and cellular adaptation during intestinal ischaemia&#x2013;reperfusion injury. Clin Translational Med. 2025;15(1):e70136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11670310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39724463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinca-Morros S, &#xc1;lvarez-Herms J. The importance of maintaining and improving a healthy gut microbiota in athletes as a preventive strategy to improve heat tolerance and acclimatization. Microorganisms. 2024;12(6):1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38930542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickard JM, Zeng MY, Caruso R, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez G. Gut microbiota: role in pathogen colonization, immune responses, and inflammatory disease. Immunol Rev. 2017;279(1):70&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5657496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28856738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charitos IA, Colella M, Carretta DM, Santacroce L. Probiotics, gut microbiota and physical activity: a close relationship. Sports Med Health Sci. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Hu Y, Ma B, Wang Z, Wei B. Gut microbiota and exercise: probiotics to modify the composition and roles of the gut microbiota in the context of 3P medicine. Microb Ecol. 2025;88(1):1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12049406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40319213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monda V, Villano I, Messina A, Valenzano A, Esposito T, Moscatelli F, Viggiano A, Cibelli G, Chieffi S, Monda M. Exercise modifies the gut microbiota with positive health effects. Oxidative Med Cell Longev. 2017;2017(1):3831972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5357536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28357027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>