<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41735393</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation of hydrogen influence on compression ignition engine fuelled with pyrolysis blends using experimental and RSM methods.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10304</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-39172-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study experimentally investigates the performance, combustion, and emission characteristics of a single-cylinder diesel engine operated in dual-fuel mode using pyrolysis oil and gaseous hydrogen. Four fuel combinations were examined: neat diesel (100D), diesel&#x2013;hydrogen (50D50H), diesel&#x2013;pyrolysis oil (90D10P), and diesel&#x2013;pyrolysis oil with hydrogen enrichment (90D10P&#x2009;+&#x2009;50&#xa0;LPH). The engine was operated at a constant speed of 1,500&#xa0;rpm under varying load conditions (0&#x2013;100%), and the results were analysed using response surface methodology (RSM). The 50D50H blend achieved the highest brake thermal efficiency, showing a 21.4% improvement over neat diesel, along with a minimum brake-specific fuel consumption of 0.22&#xa0;kg/kWh. The maximum in-cylinder pressure (69 bar) and peak heat release rate (75&#xa0;J/CA) were observed for the 90D10P&#x2009;+&#x2009;50 LPH blend. Emission analysis indicated that this blend produced the lowest carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide, hydrocarbon, and nitrogen oxide emissions among all tested fuels, while the lowest NO<sub>x</sub> emission of 350&#xa0;ppm was recorded for the 50D50H blend. Statistical validation using analysis of variance (ANOVA) yielded regression coefficients (R<sup>2</sup>) between 0.8 and 1, demonstrating strong agreement between experimental results and model predictions. The findings confirm that the combined application of pyrolysis oil and hydrogen in dual-fuel operation significantly enhances engine efficiency while effectively reducing exhaust emissions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>K Sunil</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Saveetha School of Engineering, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 602105, India. sunilkumarkresearcher@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Surakasi</LastName><ForeName>Raviteja</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Lendi Institute of Engineering and Technology, Jonnada, Vizianagaram, Andhra Pradesh, 535005, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kareemullah</LastName><ForeName>Md</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Graphic Era (Deemed to Be University), Dehradun, Uttarakhand, 248002, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Research Impact and Outcome, Chitkara University, Rajpura, Punjab, 140417, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamangar</LastName><ForeName>Sarfaraz</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department, College of Engineering, King Khalid University, 61421, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arabi</LastName><ForeName>Amir Ibrahim Ali</ForeName><Initials>AIA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department, College of Engineering, King Khalid University, 61421, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Emma</LastName><ForeName>Addisu Frinjo</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Engineering and Technology, School of Mechanical and Automotive Engineering, Dilla University, Gedeo Zone, South Ethiopia Regional State, Po. Box 419, Dilla, Ethiopia. addisuf@du.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RGP2/491/46</GrantID><Agency>King Khalid University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dual engine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Green energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrogen gas</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pyrolysis oil</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Response surface methodology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41735393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13031710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-39172-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-39172-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vellaiyan, S. Synthesis and characterisation of waste-derived biodiesel and enhancement of its energy and environmental metrics using cetane improver: an experimental study. <i>International Journal of Ambient Energy</i>, <b>45</b> (1), 2409817&#x2013;2409825 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01430750.2024.2409825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahesha, C. R., Rani, G. J., Dattu, V. S., Rao, Y. K., Madhusudhanan, J., Sekhar, S. C., &amp; Sathyamurthy, R. Optimization of transesterification production of biodiesel from Pithecellobium dulce seed oil. <i>Energy Reports</i>, <b>8</b>, 489&#x2013;497 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2022.10.228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;al&#x131;k, A. Determination of vibration characteristics of a compression ignition engine operated by hydrogen-enriched diesel and biodiesel fuels. <i>Fuel</i><b>230</b>, 355&#x2013;358 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2018.05.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, S., DhakshinaMoorthy, M. &amp; Subramanian, S. Effect of natural antioxidant additive on hydrogen-enriched biodiesel operated compression ignition engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>47</b>(48), 20771&#x2013;20783 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.04.207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elnajjar, E., Al-Omari, S. A. B., Selim, M. Y. E. &amp; Purayil, S. T. P. CI engine performance and emissions with waste cooking oil biodiesel boosted with hydrogen supplement under different load and engine parameters. <i>Alex. Eng. J.</i><b>61</b>(6), 4793&#x2013;4805 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2021.10.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akcay, M., Yilmaz, I. T. &amp; Feyzioglu, A. Effect of hydrogen addition on performance and emission characteristics of a common-rail CI engine fueled with diesel/waste cooking oil biodiesel blends. <i>Energy</i><b>212</b>, 118538 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.118538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaurasiya, P. K., Rajak, U., Veza, I., Verma, T. N. &amp; A&#x11f;bulut, &#xdc;. Influence of injection timing on performance, combustion and emission characteristics of a diesel engine running on hydrogen-diethyl ether, n-butanol and biodiesel blends. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>47</b> (41), 18182&#x2013;18193 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.03.268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvam, C. and Devarajan, Y., Evaluating the performance, combustion, and emission characteristics of decanol-enhanced sterculia foetida biodiesel in diesel engines. <i>Results in Engineering</i>, <b>26</b> (104936), 1&#x2013;11 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S. H. et al. Use of hydrogen in dual-fuel diesel engines. <i>Prog. Energy Combust. Sci.</i><b>98</b>, 101100 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pecs.2023.101100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada, L., Moreno, E., Gonzalez-Quiroga, A., Bula, A. &amp; Duarte-Forero, J. Experimental assessment of performance and emissions for hydrogen-diesel dual fuel operation in a low displacement compression ignition engine. <i>Heliyon</i>, <b>8</b>(4). (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9039835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35497035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panait, A. et al. The use of hydrogen in the automotive diesel engine&#x2014;An efficient solution to control its operation with reduced carbon emissions. <i>Sustainability</i><b>17</b>(22), 10369 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su172210369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhtar, M.U.S., Asfand, F., Khan, M.I., Mishra, R. &amp; Ball, A.D., Performance and emissions characteristics of hydrogen-diesel dual-fuel combustion for heavy-duty engines. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i>. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, D. et al. Performance optimization of a diesel engine fueled with hydrogen/biodiesel with water addition based on the response surface methodology. <i>Energy</i><b>263</b>, 125869 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2022.125869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. A comprehensive review of exergy analysis in biodiesel-powered engines for sustainable power generation. <i>Sustain. Energy Technol. Assess.</i><b>68</b>, 103869 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiyagarajan, S. et al. Effect of hydrogen on compression-ignition (CI) engine fueled with vegetable oil/biodiesel from various feedstocks: A review. <i>Int. J. Hydrogen Energy</i><b>47</b>(88), 37648&#x2013;37667 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.12.147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pullagura, G. et al. Enhancing performance characteristics of biodiesel-alcohol/diesel blends with hydrogen and graphene nanoplatelets in a diesel engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>50</b>, 1020&#x2013;1034 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.09.313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, K., Dwivedi, G., Verma, T. N. &amp; Shukla, A. K. Energy, exergy, emissions and sustainability assessment of hydrogen supplemented diesel dual fuel turbocharged common rail direct injection diesel engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy.</i><b>104</b>, 378&#x2013;392 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devarajan, Y., &amp; Selvam, C. Utilization of sterculia foetida oil as a sustainable feedstock for biodiesel production: optimization, performance, and emission analysis. <i>Results in Engineering</i>, <b>24</b> (2), 103196 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Algayyim, S. J. M. et al. Influence of natural gas and hydrogen properties on internal combustion engine performance, combustion, and emissions: A review. <i>Fuel</i><b>362</b>, 130844 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.130844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pachiannan, T., Zhong, W., He, Z., Alharbi, S. A. &amp; Brindhadevi, K. Assessing the performance, and emissions characteristics of a diesel engine fueled with soya seed biodiesel blended with oxy-hydrogen. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>139</b>, 1008&#x2013;1014 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bala Prasad, K. et al. Effect of split fuel injection strategies on the diverse characteristics of CRDI diesel engine operated with tamarind biodiesel. <i>Energy Sour. Part A Recovery Util. Environ Eff.</i><b>47</b>(1), 3566&#x2013;3584 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam, S., Rajkumar, T., Subramanian, S. &amp; Palani, S. Investigation of combustion, emission, and performance parameters of a natural antioxidant additives using hydrogen and biodiesel as dual fuel in CI engine operation. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>110</b>, 44&#x2013;54 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W. et al. Quantification of NOx sources contribution to ambient nitrate aerosol, uncertainty analysis and sensitivity analysis in a megacity. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>926</b>, 171583 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.171583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38461977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alruqi, M., Sharma, P., Deepanraj, B. &amp; Shaik, F. Renewable energy approach towards powering the CI engine with ternary blends of algal biodiesel-diesel-diethyl ether: Bayesian optimized Gaussian process regression for modeling-optimization. <i>Fuel</i><b>334</b>, 126827 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2022.126827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, D. et al. Utilization of renewable and sustainable diesel/methanol/n-butanol (DMB) blends for reducing the engine emissions in a diesel engine with different pre-injection strategies. <i>Energy</i><b>269</b>, 126785 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.126785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J. et al. Investigation on traffic carbon emission factor based on sensitivity and uncertainty analysis. <i>Energies</i><b>17</b>(7), 1774 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17071774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alrbai, M. et al. Performance and sensitivity analysis of raw biogas combustion under homogenous charge compression ignition conditions. <i>Energy</i><b>283</b>, 128486 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.128486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winangun, K., Setiyawan, A. &amp; Sudarmanta, B. The combustion characteristics and performance of a diesel dual-fuel (DDF) engine fueled by palm oil biodiesel and hydrogen gas. <i>Case Stud. Thermal Eng.</i><b>42</b>, 102755 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2023.102755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xfc;ccar, G. Experimental study on vibration and noise characteristics of a diesel engine fueled with mustard oil biodiesel and hydrogen gas mixtures. <i>Biofuels</i>. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiyagarajan, S. et al. Effect of hydrogen on compression-ignition (CI) engine fueled with vegetable oil/biodiesel from various feedstocks: A review. <i>Int. J. Hydrogen Energy</i><b>47</b>(88), 37648&#x2013;37667 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.12.147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, Y., Medwell, P. R., Gee, A. J., Foo, K. K. &amp; Dally, B. B. Fundamental insights into the effect of blending hydrogen flames with sooting biofuels. <i>Fuel</i><b>331</b>, 125618 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2022.125618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. The environmental potential of hydrogen addition as complementation for diesel and biodiesel: A comprehensive review and perspectives. <i>Fuel</i><b>342</b>, 127794 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.127794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayd&#x131;n, S. Comprehensive analysis of combustion, performance and emissions of power generator diesel engine fueled with different source of biodiesel blends. <i>Energy</i><b>205</b>, 118074 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2020.118074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simsek, S. &amp; Uslu, S. Experimental study of the performance and emissions characteristics of fusel oil/gasoline blends in spark ignited engine using response surface methodology. <i>Fuel</i><b>277</b>, 118182 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2020.118182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamarulzaman, M. K. &amp; Abdullah, A. Multi-objective optimization of diesel engine performances and exhaust emissions characteristics of Hermetia illucens larvae oil-diesel fuel blends using response surface methodology. <i>Energy Sour. Part A Recovery Util. Environ. Eff.</i><b>47</b>, 1&#x2013;14 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenano&#x11f;lu, R., Baltac&#x131;o&#x11f;lu, M. K., Demir, M. H. &amp; &#xd6;zdemir, M. E. Performance &amp; emission analysis of HHO enriched dual-fuelled diesel engine with artificial neural network prediction approaches. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>45</b>(49), 26357&#x2013;26369 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2020.02.108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltacioglu, M. K., Arat, H. T., &#xd6;zcanli, M. &amp; Aydin, K. Experimental comparison of pure hydrogen and HHO (hydroxy) enriched biodiesel (B10) fuel in a commercial diesel engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>41</b>(19), 8347&#x2013;8353 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2015.11.185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elgarhi, I., El-Kassaby, M. M. &amp; Eldrainy, Y. A. Enhancing compression ignition engine performance using biodiesel/diesel blends and HHO gas. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>45</b>(46), 25409&#x2013;25425 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2020.06.273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafi, B. et al. Effects of low-level hydroxy as a gaseous additive on performance and emission characteristics of a dual fuel diesel engine fueled by diesel/biodiesel blends. <i>Eng. Appl. Comput. Fluid Mech.</i><b>15</b>(1), 236&#x2013;250 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M. B. et al. Impact of HHO gas enrichment and high purity biodiesel on the performance of a 315 cc diesel engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>46</b>(37), 19633&#x2013;19644 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.03.112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian, B., Lakshmaiya, N., Ramasamy, D. &amp; Devarajan, Y. Detailed analysis on engine operating in dual fuel mode with different energy fractions of sustainable HHO gas. <i>Environ. Prog. Sustain. Energy</i><b>41</b>(5), e13850 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ep.13850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudrajat, A. et al. Performance analysis of biodiesel engine by addition of HHO gas as a secondary fuel. <i>J. Tribol.</i><b>26</b>, 120&#x2013;134 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finesso, R. &amp; Spessa, E. A real time zero-dimensional diagnostic model for the calculation of in-cylinder temperatures, HRR and nitrogen oxides in diesel engines. <i>Energy Convers. Manag.</i><b>79</b>, 498&#x2013;510 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2013.12.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesa, E. S. C., Quintana, S. H. &amp; Bedoya, I. D. Combustion stability, RGF and pressure referencing effect on HRR for a high compression ratio SI engine with natural gas lean mixtures. <i>Case Stud. Therm. Eng.</i><b>53</b>, 103891 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2023.103891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W. et al. Experimental and theoretical analysis of effects of equivalence ratio on mixture properties, combustion, thermal efficiency and exhaust emissions of a pilot-ignited NG engine at low loads. <i>Fuel</i><b>171</b>, 125&#x2013;135 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2015.12.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L., Wei, H., Pan, J., Liu, C. &amp; Shu, G. Understanding the correlation between auto-ignition, heat release and knocking characteristics through optical engines with high compression ratio. <i>Fuel</i><b>261</b>, 116405 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thangaraj, S. &amp; Govindan, N. Evaluating combustion, performance and emission characteristics of diesel engine using karanja oil methyl ester biodiesel blends enriched with HHO gas. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>43</b>(12), 6443&#x2013;6455 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2018.02.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan, S., Thiruselvam, K. &amp; Jayavelu, S. Towards green mobility: investigating hydrogen-enriched waste plastic biodiesel blends with n-butanol for sustainable diesel engine applications. <i>Energy Adv.</i><b>4</b>(6), 763&#x2013;775 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5YA00002E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewangan, A. et al. Production of oxy-hydrogen gas and the impact of its usability on CI engine combustion, performance, and emission behaviours. <i>Energy</i><b>278</b>, 127937 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian, B. &amp; Thangavel, V. Experimental investigations on performance, emission and combustion characteristics of diesel-hydrogen and diesel-HHO gas in a dual fuel CI engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>45</b>(46), 25479&#x2013;25492 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2020.06.280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir, U., &#xc7;elebi, S. &amp; &#xd6;zer, S. Experimental investigation of the effect of fuel oil, graphene and HHO gas addition to diesel fuel on engine performance and exhaust emissions in a diesel engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>52</b>, 1434&#x2013;1446 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gad, M. S. &amp; Razek, S. A. Impact of HHO produced from dry and wet cell electrolyzers on diesel engine performance, emissions and combustion characteristics. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>46</b>(43), 22277&#x2013;22291 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.04.077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsujimura, T. &amp; Suzuki, Y. The utilization of hydrogen in hydrogen/diesel dual fuel engine. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>42</b>(19), 14019&#x2013;14029 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2017.01.152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseini, S. M. &amp; Ahmadi, R. Performance and emissions characteristics in the combustion of co-fuel diesel-hydrogen in a heavy duty engine. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>205</b>, 911&#x2013;925 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2017.08.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewangan, A. et al. Production of oxy-hydrogen gas and the impact of its usability on CI engine combustion, performance, and emission behaviors. <i>Energy</i><b>278</b>, 127937 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akal, D., &#xd6;ztuna, S. &amp; B&#xfc;y&#xfc;kak&#x131;n, M. K. A review of hydrogen usage in internal combustion engines (gasoline-Lpg-diesel) from combustion performance aspect. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>45</b>(60), 35257&#x2013;35268 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2020.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alrazen, H. A., Talib, A. A., Adnan, R. &amp; Ahmad, K. A. A review of the effect of hydrogen addition on the performance and emissions of the compression&#x2013;Ignition engine. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>54</b>, 785&#x2013;796 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2015.10.088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosha, P. et al. Impact of compression ratio on combustion behavior of hydrogen enriched biogas-diesel operated CI engine. <i>Fuel</i><b>310</b>, 122321 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2021.122321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakar, R. A. et al. Experimental analysis on the performance, combustion/emission characteristics of a DI diesel engine using hydrogen in dual fuel mode. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>52</b>, 843&#x2013;860 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.04.129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareei, J., Rohani, A. &amp; Mahmood, W. M. F. W. Simulation of a hydrogen/natural gas engine and modelling of engine operating parameters. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>43</b>(25), 11639&#x2013;11651 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2018.02.047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muniyappan, M. et al. Hydrogen behavior in dual fuel mode diesel engine with nano diesel. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>37</b>, 2401&#x2013;2405 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.08.248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro, N., Toledo, M. &amp; Amador, G. An experimental investigation of the performance and emissions of a hydrogen-diesel dual fuel compression ignition internal combustion engine. <i>Appl. Therm. Eng.</i><b>156</b>, 660&#x2013;667 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2019.04.078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareei, J., Rohani, A. &amp; Alvarez, J. R. N. The effect of EGR and hydrogen addition to natural gas on performance and exhaust emissions in a diesel engine by AVL fire multi-domain simulation, GPR model, and multi-objective genetic algorithm. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>47</b>(50), 21565&#x2013;21581 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.04.294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaichan, M. T. The effects of hydrogen addition to diesel fuel on the emitted particulate matters. <i>Int. J. Sci. Eng. Res.</i><b>6</b>(6), 1081&#x2013;1087 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy, K. J., Rao, G. A. P., Reddy, R. M. &amp; A&#x11d;bulut, &#xdc;. Artificial intelligence-based forecasting of dual-fuel mode CI engine behaviors powered with the hydrogen-diesel blends. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>87</b>, 1074&#x2013;1086 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J. H., Cheung, C. S., Zhao, W. Z., Ning, Z. &amp; Leung, C. W. Impact of intake hydrogen enrichment on morphology, structure and oxidation reactivity of diesel particulate. <i>Appl. Energy</i><b>160</b>, 442&#x2013;455 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.09.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frantzis, C., Zannis, T., Savva, P. G. &amp; Yfantis, E. A. A review on experimental studies investigating the effect of hydrogen supplementation in CI diesel engines&#x2014;The case of HYMAR. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b>(15), 5709 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15155709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez, J. J., Cova-Bonillo, A., Wu, H., Barba, J. &amp; Rodr&#xed;guez-Fern&#xe1;ndez, J. Low temperature autoignition of diesel fuel under dual operation with hydrogen and hydrogen-carriers. <i>Energy Convers. Manag.</i><b>258</b>, 115516 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2022.115516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, F., Xu, L. &amp; Wang, Y. Application of hydrogen enriched natural gas in spark ignition IC engines: From fundamental fuel properties to engine performances and emissions. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>82</b>, 1457&#x2013;1488 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.05.227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Investigation of the gas injection rate shape on combustion, knock and emissions behavior of a rotary engine with hydrogen direct-injection enrichment. <i>Int. J. Hydrog. Energy</i><b>46</b>(27), 14790&#x2013;14804 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.01.234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasker, J. P. &amp; Porpatham, E. Effects of compression ratio and hydrogen addition on lean combustion characteristics and emission formation in a compressed natural gas fuelled spark ignition engine. <i>Fuel</i><b>208</b>, 260&#x2013;270 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2017.07.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi, G. H., Lee, J. C., Chung, Y. J., Caton, J. &amp; Han, S. B. Effect of hydrogen enriched LPG fuelled engine with converted from a diesel engine. <i>J. Energy Eng.</i><b>15</b>(3), 139&#x2013;145 (2006).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>