<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41281922</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2279-9028</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of public health research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Public Health Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Magnitude of risky sexual behavior and associated factors among secondary school students in southern Ethiopia, 2023.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22799036251396737</StartPage><MedlinePgn>22799036251396737</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">22799036251396737</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/22799036251396737</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Risky sexual behavior (RSB) among youth can lead to serious socio-economic and health problems, such as unwanted pregnancy and acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS). Little is known about RSB among secondary school students in the South Omo zone, South Ethiopia. Therefore, this study aimed to assess the magnitude of RSB and its determinants among secondary school students in the study area.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">An institution-based cross-sectional study was conducted in January 2023. A multistage sampling method was used to select 538 students. A structured self-administered questionnaire was used to collect data. Binary logistic regression analysis was used to determine associated factors. The level of statistical significance was declared to have a p-value less than 0.05 in multivariate analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The prevalence of RSB among study participants was 25.9% (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;22.3, 29.9%). It was significantly associated with having close sexually active close friends (adjusted odds ratio (AOR)&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.09; 95% CI: 1.90-5.02), attending night clubs (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.56; 95% CI: 1.35-4.86), drinking alcohol (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.90; 95% CI: 1.10-3.29), experiencing parental neglect (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.10; 95% CI: 1.35-3.29) and poor HIV/AIDS knowledge (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.76; 95% CI: 1.12-2.77).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">RSB among secondary school students in the South Omo zone was high. It was associated with the presence of sexually active friends, attendance at night clubs, alcohol consumption, parental neglect experience, and poor HIV/AIDS knowledge. Subsequently, it is necessary to strengthen HIV/AIDS education in schools, promote parental engagement in adolescent health, and raising community awareness on the risks of alcohol use and nightclub attendance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tesfaye</LastName><ForeName>Getamesay Aynalem</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5059-7632</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Department, Jinka University, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wana</LastName><ForeName>Ermias Wabeto</ForeName><Initials>EW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6079-2642</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Department, Jinka University, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ambaw</LastName><ForeName>Maranata Dawit</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Department, Jinka University, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alemayehu</LastName><ForeName>Bewuket Addis</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Department, Jinka University, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tesfaye</LastName><ForeName>Emebet Aynalem</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public Health Officer, Omorate Health Center, Omorate, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Public Health Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101580775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2279-9028</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV/AIDS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high school student</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risky sexual behavior</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41281922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12638684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/22799036251396737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_22799036251396737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO recommendations on adolescent sexual and reproductive health and rights. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Investing in our future : a framework for accelerating action for the sexual and reproductive health of the young people. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimbuene ZT, Emina JBO, Sankoh O. UNAIDS &#x2018;multiple sexual partners&#x2019; core indicator: promoting sexual networks to reduce potential biases. Global Health Action 2014; 7: 23103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3955766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24647127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandor A, Kaltenthaler E, Higgins A, et al. Sexual health risk reduction interventions for people with severe mental illness: a systematic review. BMC Public Health 2015; 15: 1&#x2013;13. DOI: 10.1186/s12889-015-1448-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1448-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4330652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25886371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. The health of young people: A challenge and a promise. Geneva: World Health Organization, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underwood JM, Brener N, Thornton J, et al. Overview and Methods for the Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System &#x2014; United States, 2019. MMWR 2020; 69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall PA, Holmqvist M, Sherry SB. Risky Adolescent Sexual Behavior: A Psychological Perspective for Primary Care Clinicians. Topics in Advanced Practice Nursing eJournal 2004; 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global Health Sector Strategy on HIV, 2016&#x2013;2021: Towards Ending AIDS. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS. Global AIDS Update 2021. Geneva: United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS), 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HIV/AIDS Prevention and Control Office. HIV Prevention in Ethiopia National Road Map 2018 - 2020. Addis Ababa: Federal HIV/AIDS Prevention and Control Office, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Youth Risk Behavior Survey Data Summary &amp; Trends Report: 2009&#x2013;2019. 2019. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asamoah BO, Agardh A. Individual- and Family-Level Determinants of Risky Sexual Behavior Among Swedish- and Foreign-Born Young Adults 18&#x2013;30 Years of Age, Residing in Sk&#xe5;ne, Sweden. Archives of Sexual Behavior 2018; 47: 517&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5775364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28560591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campo-Arias A, Ceballo GA, Herazo E. Prevalence of pattern of risky behaviors for reproductive and sexual health among middle- and high-school students. Revista Latino-Americana de Enfermagem 2010; 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20549114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodz NA, Mutalip MHA, Mahmud MAF, et al. Risky Sexual Behaviours among School-going Adolescent in Malaysia-Findings from National Health and Morbidity Survey 2017. Journal of Environmental Science and Public Health 2019; 3: 226&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali MM, Merdad L, Bellizzi S. Socioeconomic variations in risky sexual behavior among adolescents in 14 sub-Saharan Africa countries who report ever having had sex. International Journal for Equity in Health 2021; 20: 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33407497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ifeadike CO, Nnebue CC, Oparaji CI, et al. Sexual risk behaviors and associated factors among senior secondary schools adolescents in Owerri, Imo State Nigeria. International STD Research &amp; Reviews 2018; 7: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia Ministry of Health. National Adolescent and Youth Reproductive Health Strategy (2016-2020). Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia Ministry of Health, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Statistical Agency. Ethiopia Demographic and Health Survey 2016. Addis Ababa, Ethiopia and Maryland, USA: Central Statistical Agency (CSA) and ICF, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigussie T, Legese T, Abebe L, et al. Magnitude of risky sexual behaviors, determinants, and consequences among high school and preparatory school students in Mizan Aman Town, Ethiopia. Journal of Midwifery and Reproductive Health 2020; 8: 2096&#x2013;2104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srahbzu M, Tirfeneh E. Risky sexual behavior and associated factors among adolescents aged 15&#x2013;19 years at Governmental High Schools in Aksum Town, Tigray, Ethiopia. BioMed Research International 2020; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32904524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gizaw A, Jara D, Ketema K. Risky Sexual Practice and Associated Factors among High School Adolescent in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2014. Fam Med Med Sci Res 2014; 3: 141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasahun AW, Yitayal M, Girum T, et al. Risky Sexual Behavior and Associated Factors Among High School Students in Gondar City, Northwest Ethiopia. International Journal of Public Health Science 2017; 6: 257&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alebel Yaregal D, Mesele Damte A, et al. Prevalence and Associated Factors of Risky Sexual Behaviours Among in-School Youth in Lalibela Town, North Wollo Zone, Amhara Regional Sate, Ethiopia: A Cross-Sectional Study Design. Science Journal of Public Health 2016; 4: 57&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firomsa HT, Eshetu G, Abebe M, et al. Risky sexual behaviors and associated factors among high and preparatory school youth, East Wollega, Ethiopia, 2017: A cross-sectional study design. Journal of Public Health and Epidemiology 2019; 11: 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lydall J. The Threat of the HIV/AIDS Epidemic in South Omo Zone, Southern Ethiopia. Northeast African Studies 2000; 7: 41&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wikipedia. South Omo Zone, https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_Omo_Zone (2022, accessed May 23, 2022 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassa GM, Degu G, Yitayew M, et al. Risky Sexual Behaviors and Associated Factors among Jiga High School and Preparatory School Students, Amhara Region, Ethiopia. International Scholarly Research Notices 2016; 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4925954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27403456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2021 Standard High School YRBS. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girmay A, Mariye T. Risky sexual behavior practice and associated factors among secondary and preparatory school students of Aksum town, northern Ethiopia, 2018. BMC Res Notes 2019; 12: 698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31655614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphya A, Steeleb M, Dubec SR, et al. Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs) Questionnaire and Adult Attachment Interview (AAI): Implications for parent child relationships. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect 2014; 38: 224&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24670331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocalevent R-D, Berg L, Beutel ME, et al. Social support in the general population standardization of the Oslo social support scale (OSSS-3). BMC Psychology 2018; 6: 31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6050647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30016997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megersa ND, Teshome GS. Risky sexual behavior and associated factors among preparatory school students in Arsi Negelle Town Oromia, Ethiopia. International Journal of Public Health Science 2020; 9: 162&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsley DA, Kuh E, Welsch RE. Regression diagnostics: Identifying influential data and sources of collinearity. John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadugu S, Ryali V, Srivastava K, et al. Understanding sexuality among Indian urban school adolescents. Ind Psychiatry J 2011; 20: 49&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3425247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22969181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassahun EA, Gelagay AA, Muche AA, et al. Factors associated with early sexual initiation among preparatory and high school youths in Woldia town, northeast Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health 2019; 19: 378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30947690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>keto T, Tilahun A, Mamo A. Knowledge, attitude and practice towards risky sexual behaviors among secondary and preparatory students of Metu town, south western Ethiopia. BMC Public Health 2020; 20: 1394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32928174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risley C, Douglas K, Karimi M, et al. Trends in Sexual Risk Behavioral Responses among High School Students between Mississippi and the United States: 2001 to 2019 YRBSS. J Sch Health 2023; 93: 500&#x2013;507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36973577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thepthien Bo, Celyn. Risky sexual behavior and associated factors among sexually-experienced adolescents in Bangkok, Thailand: fndings from a school web-based survey. Reproductive Health 2022; 19: 127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9148491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35643503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndagijimana E, Biracyaza E, Nzayirambaho M. Risky sexual behaviors and their associated factors within high school students from Coll&#xe8;ge Saint Andr&#xe9; in Kigali, Rwanda: An institution-based cross-sectional study. Front Reprod Health 2023; 5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10020213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36936133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fajobi O, Adebayo EO, Femi AA, et al. Social media engagement and risky sexual behaviours among out-of-school adolescents in Ile-Ife, South-west, Nigeria. Vulnerable Children and Youth Studies 2025; 20: 1&#x2013;15. DOI: 10.1080/17450128.2025.2478161</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17450128.2025.2478161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okoye HU, Saewyc E. Influence of socio-contextual factors on the link between traditional and new media use, and young people&#x2019;s sexual risk behaviour in Sub-Saharan Africa: a secondary data analysis. Reproductive Health 2024; 21: 138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11443646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39350211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeze GA, Gebeyehu NA, Wassie AY, et al. Factors associated with risky sexual behaviour among secondary and preparatory students in Wolaita Sodo town, Southern Ethiopia; Institution based cross-sectional study. Afri Health Sci 2021; 21: 1830&#x2013;1841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8889837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35283985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aynalem BY, Alemu AA, Zeleke LB, et al. Risky sexual behavior and associated factors among secondary and above-education-level students in Ethiopia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Family Med Prim Care 2022; 11: 5024&#x2013;5030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9731005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36505598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imaledo JA, Peter-Kio OB, Asuquo EO. Pattern of risky sexual behavior and associated factors among undergraduate students of the University of Port Harcourt, Rivers State, Nigeria. Pan African Medical Journal 2012; 9: 97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23133697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fikre S, Tenkolu G, Mamo ZB. Risky Sexual Behavior and Associated Factors among Street Youth in Dilla Town, Gedeo Zone, South Ethiopia, 2018. Ethiop J Health Sci 2021; 31: 947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8843147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35221610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoateng AY, Kalule-Sabiti I, Arkaah YJ. The Effect of Socio-Demographic Factors on Risky-Sexual Behaviours of Adolescents in the North West Province of South Africa. African Population Studies 2014; 28: 487&#x2013;498.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>