<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41439521</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1708-8240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of esthetic and restorative dentistry : official publication of the American Academy of Esthetic Dentistry ... [et al.]</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Esthet Restor Dent</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long Term Clinical and Aesthetic Outcomes of Implants Placed With Immediate and Early Protocol in the Anterior Maxilla: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jerd.70085</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this review was to assess the long-term clinical and aesthetic outcomes of implants placed with immediate and early protocols in the anterior maxilla with a follow-up greater than 5&#x2009;years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An electronic search in Pubmed, Embase, CINAHL via EBSCO, and the Cochrane database was performed to identify studies on single-tooth implants placed with immediate (Type 1) and early (Type 2) placement protocols in the anterior maxilla that reported outcomes on aesthetics, hard and soft tissue changes with a mean follow up &#x2265;&#x2009;5&#x2009;years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifteen studies on immediate and early protocol single implants placed in the anterior maxilla with a &#x2265;&#x2009;5&#x2009;year follow up were included. A lack of studies comparing the two placement protocols was observed. Soft tissue changes were found to be acceptable for immediately placed implants, with seven studies reporting mean mid-buccal gingival recession of 0.15&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.27&#x2009;mm and mean papillary height loss of 0.07&#x2009;mm mesial and 0.20&#x2009;mm distal after a follow up of &#x2265;&#x2009;5&#x2009;years. Advanced buccal recession (&gt;&#x2009;1&#x2009;mm) occurred in 12.17% of cases. Ten of the 15 included studies reported a mean bone loss of 0.68&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.42&#x2009;mm. Favorable aesthetic outcomes were reported by most studies with a 2.83% incidence of aesthetic failures (aesthetic score &lt;&#x2009;50% of maximum achievable). The few studies that reported on patient-centered outcomes showed a high level of patient satisfaction post treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Immediate and early implant placement protocols showed acceptable soft tissue and aesthetic outcomes, with suboptimal aesthetic outcomes reported in 2.83% of cases. More long-term follow-up studies are necessary to identify factors that influence aesthetic outcomes in implants placed with various placement protocols in the anterior maxilla.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Briggs</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Dentistry, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arora</LastName><ForeName>Himanshu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7181-0006</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Dentistry, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ivanovski</LastName><ForeName>Saso</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5339-0936</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Dentistry, The University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Esthet Restor Dent</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101096515</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1496-4155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aesthetic zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior maxilla</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental implants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early placement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immediate implant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immediate placement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long&#x2010;term</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 1 placement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 placement</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41439521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jerd.70085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>L. Den Hartog, J. J. R. Huddleston Slater, A. Vissink, H. J. A. Meijer, and G. M. Raghoebar, &#x201c;Treatment Outcome of Immediate, Early and Conventional Single&#x2010;Tooth Implants in the Aesthetic Zone: A Systematic Review to Survival, Bone Level, Soft&#x2010;Tissue, Aesthetics and Patient Satisfaction,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 35, no. 12 (2008): 1073&#x2013;1086, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;051X.2008.01330.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. P. Lang, L. Pun, K. Y. Lau, K. Y. Li, and M. C. Wong, &#x201c;A Systematic Review on Survival and Success Rates of Implants Placed Immediately Into Fresh Extraction Sockets After at Least 1 Year,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 23, no. Suppl 5 (2012): 39&#x2013;66, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0501.2011.02372.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Adell, U. Lekholm, B. Rockler, and P. I. Br&#xe5;nemark, &#x201c;A 15&#x2010;Year Study of Osseointegrated Implants in the Treatment of the Edentulous Jaw,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral Surgery 10, no. 6 (1981): 387&#x2013;416, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0300&#x2010;9785(81)80077&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. I. Branemark, B. O. Hansson, R. Adell, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Osseointegrated Implants in the Treatment of the Edentulous Jaw. Experience From a 10&#x2010;Year Period,&#x201d; Scandinavian Journal of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery. Supplementum 16 (1977): 1&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. O. Gallucci, A. Hamilton, W. Zhou, D. Buser, and S. Chen, &#x201c;Implant Placement and Loading Protocols in Partially Edentulous Patients: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 29, no. S16 (2018): 106&#x2013;134, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Hammerle, S. Chen, and T. Wilson, &#x201c;Consensus Statements and Recommended Clinical Procedures Regarding the Placement of Implants in Extraction Sockets,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 19 (2004): 26&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. T. Chen and D. Buser, &#x201c;Esthetic Outcomes Following Immediate and Early Implant Placement in the Anterior Maxilla: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 29 (2014): 186&#x2013;215, https://doi.org/10.11607/jomi.2014suppl.g3.3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Schwartz&#x2010;Arad and G. Chaushu, &#x201c;The Ways and Wherefores of Immediate Placement of Implants Into Fresh Extraction Sites: A Literature Review,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 68, no. 10 (1997): 915&#x2013;923, https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.1997.68.10.915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Arora, N. Khzam, D. Roberts, W. L. Bruce, and S. Ivanovski, &#x201c;Immediate Implant Placement and Restoration in the Anterior Maxilla: Tissue Dimensional Changes After 2&#x2013;5 Year Follow Up,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 19, no. 4 (2017): 694&#x2013;702, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. Covani, R. Crespi, R. Cornelini, and A. Barone, &#x201c;Immediate Implants Supporting Single Crown Restoration: A 4&#x2010;Year Prospective Study,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 75, no. 7 (2004): 982&#x2013;988, https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.2004.75.7.982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. H. H&#xe4;mmerle, U. Br&#xe4;gger, B. Schmid, and N. P. Lang, &#x201c;Successful Bone Formation at Immediate Transmucosal Implants: A Clinical Report,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 13, no. 4 (1998): 522&#x2013;530.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Khzam, H. Arora, P. Kim, A. Fisher, N. Mattheos, and S. Ivanovski, &#x201c;Systematic Review of Soft Tissue Alterations and Esthetic Outcomes Following Immediate Implant Placement and Restoration of Single Implants in the Anterior Maxilla,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 86, no. 12 (2015): 1321&#x2013;1330, https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.2015.150287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. P. Lang, U. Br&#xe4;gger, C. H. F. H&#xe4;mmerle, and F. Sutter, &#x201c;Immediate Transmucosal Implants Using the Principle of Guided Tissue Regeneration. I. Rationale, Clinical Procedures and 30&#x2010;Month Results,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 5, no. 3 (1994): 154&#x2013;163, https://doi.org/10.1034/j.1600&#x2010;0501.1994.050306.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. W. Slagter, L. den Hartog, N. A. Bakker, A. Vissink, H. J. Meijer, and G. M. Raghoebar, &#x201c;Immediate Placement of Dental Implants in the Esthetic Zone: A Systematic Review and Pooled Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 85, no. 7 (2014): e241&#x2013;e250, https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.2014.130632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Chen, T. Wilson, and H. Hammerle, &#x201c;Immediate or Early Placement of Implants Following Tooth Extraction: Review of Biologic Basis, Clinical Procedures, and Outcomes,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 19, no. sS (2004): 12&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Sanz, M. Garcia&#x2010;Gargallo, D. Herrera, C. Martin, E. Figuero, and M. Sanz, &#x201c;Surgical Protocols for Early Implant Placement in Post&#x2010;Extraction Sockets: A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 23, no. Suppl 5 (2012): 67&#x2013;79, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0501.2011.02339.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. H. Bassir, K. El Kholy, C. Y. Chen, K. H. Lee, and G. Intini, &#x201c;Outcome of Early Dental Implant Placement Versus Other Dental Implant Placement Protocols: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 90, no. 5 (2019): 493&#x2013;506, https://doi.org/10.1002/jper.18&#x2010;0338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Pommer, M. Danzinger, L. Leite Aiquel, J. Pitta, and R. Haas, &#x201c;Long&#x2010;Term Outcomes of Maxillary Single&#x2010;Tooth Implants in Relation to Timing Protocols of Implant Placement and Loading: Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 32, no. Suppl 21 (2021): 56&#x2013;66, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. F&#xfc;rhauser, D. Florescu, T. Benesch, R. Haas, G. Mailath, and G. Watzek, &#x201c;Evaluation of Soft Tissue Around Single&#x2010;Tooth Implant Crowns: The Pink Esthetic Score,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 16, no. 6 (2005): 639&#x2013;644, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0501.2005.01193.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. C. Belser, L. Gr&#xfc;tter, F. Vailati, M. M. Bornstein, H. P. Weber, and D. Buser, &#x201c;Outcome Evaluation of Early Placed Maxillary Anterior Single&#x2010;Tooth Implants Using Objective Esthetic Criteria: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional, Retrospective Study in 45 Patients With a 2&#x2010; to 4&#x2010;Year Follow&#x2010;Up Using Pink and White Esthetic Scores,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 80, no. 1 (2009): 140&#x2013;151, https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.2009.080435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Francisco, D. Marques, C. Pinto, L. Aiquel, and J. Caram&#xea;s, &#x201c;Is the Timing of Implant Placement and Loading Influencing Esthetic Outcomes in Single&#x2010;Tooth Implants?&#x2010;A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 32, no. Suppl 21 (2021): 28&#x2013;55, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Qian, B. V&#xe1;nkos, K. Kelemen, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Comparison of Implant Placement and Loading Protocols for Single Anterior Maxillary Implants: A Systematic Review and Network Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry 133, no. 3 (2025): 677&#x2013;688, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2024.05.033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cosyn, A. Eghbali, A. Hermans, S. Vervaeke, H. De Bruyn, and R. Cleymaet, &#x201c;A 5&#x2010;Year Prospective Study on Single Immediate Implants in the Aesthetic Zone,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 43, no. 8 (2016): 702&#x2013;709, https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpe.12571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Arora and S. Ivanovski, &#x201c;Correlation Between Pre&#x2010;Operative Buccal Bone Thickness and Soft Tissue Changes Around Immediately Placed and Restored Implants in the Maxillary Anterior Region: A 2&#x2010;Year Prospective Study,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 28, no. 10 (2017): 1188&#x2013;1194, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.12939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Moher, A. Liberati, J. Tetzlaff, and D. G. Altman, &#x201c;Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta&#x2010;Analyses: The PRISMA Statement,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 62, no. 10 (2009): 1006&#x2013;1012, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2009.06.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. J. Ho, S. M. Liew, C. J. Ng, R. Hisham Shunmugam, and P. Glasziou, &#x201c;Development of a Search Strategy for an Evidence Based Retrieval Service.(Research Article),&#x201d; PLoS One 11, no. 12 (2016): e0167170, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0167170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Degidi, D. Nardi, G. Daprile, and A. Piattelli, &#x201c;Buccal Bone Plate in the Immediately Placed and Restored Maxillary Single Implant: A 7&#x2010;Year Retrospective Study Using Computed Tomography,&#x201d; Implant Dentistry 21, no. 1 (2012): 62&#x2013;66, https://doi.org/10.1097/ID.0b013e31823fce9f.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Guarnieri, A. Ceccherini, and M. Grande, &#x201c;Single&#x2010;Tooth Replacement in the Anterior Maxilla by Means of Immediate Implantation and Early Loading: Clinical and Aesthetic Results at 5&#x2009;Years,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 17, no. 2 (2015): 314&#x2013;326, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Barone, S. Marconcini, E. Giammarinaro, E. Mijiritsky, F. Gelpi, and U. Covani, &#x201c;Clinical Outcomes of Implants Placed in Extraction Sockets and Immediately Restored: A 7&#x2010;Year Single&#x2010;Cohort Prospective Study,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 18, no. 6 (2016): 1103&#x2013;1112, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Buser, V. Chappuis, M. M. Bornstein, J. G. Wittneben, M. Frei, and U. C. Belser, &#x201c;Long&#x2010;Term Stability of Contour Augmentation With Early Implant Placement Following Single Tooth Extraction in the Esthetic Zone: A Prospective, Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study in 41 Patients With a 5&#x2010; to 9&#x2010;Year Follow&#x2010;Up,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 84, no. 11 (2013): 1517&#x2013;1527, https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.2013.120635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Chappuis, L. Rahman, R. Buser, S. F. M. Janner, U. C. Belser, and D. Buser, &#x201c;Effectiveness of Contour Augmentation With Guided Bone Regeneration: 10&#x2010;Year Results,&#x201d; Journal of Dental Research 97, no. 3 (2018): 266&#x2013;274, https://doi.org/10.1177/0022034517737755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. F. Cooper, G. Reside, F. Raes, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Immediate Provisionalization of Dental Implants in Grafted Alveolar Ridges in the Esthetic Zone: A 5&#x2010;Year Evaluation,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 34, no. 4 (2014): 477&#x2013;486, https://doi.org/10.11607/prd.2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Seyssens, A. Eghbali, and J. Cosyn, &#x201c;A 10&#x2010;Year Prospective Study on Single Immediate Implants,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 47, no. 10 (2020): 1248&#x2013;1258, https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpe.13352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. F&#xfc;rhauser, G. Mailath&#x2010;Pokorny, R. Haas, D. Busenlechner, G. Watzek, and B. Pommer, &#x201c;Immediate Restoration of Immediate Implants in the Esthetic Zone of the Maxilla via the Copy&#x2010;Abutment Technique: 5&#x2010;Year Follow&#x2010;Up of Pink Esthetic Scores,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 19, no. 1 (2017): 28&#x2013;37, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Gotfredsen, &#x201c;A 10&#x2010;Year Prospective Study of Single Tooth Implants Placed in the Anterior Maxilla,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 14, no. 1 (2012): 80&#x2013;87, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1708&#x2010;8208.2009.00231.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Raes, A. Eghbali, V. Chappuis, F. Raes, H. De Bruyn, and J. Cosyn, &#x201c;A Long&#x2010;Term Prospective Cohort Study on Immediately Restored Single Tooth Implants Inserted in Extraction Sockets and Healed Ridges: CBCT Analyses, Soft Tissue Alterations, Aesthetic Ratings, and Patient&#x2010;Reported Outcomes,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 20, no. 4 (2018): 522&#x2013;530, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U. Kuchler, V. Chappuis, R. Gruber, N. P. Lang, and G. E. Salvi, &#x201c;Immediate Implant Placement With Simultaneous Guided Bone Regeneration in the Esthetic Zone: 10&#x2010;Year Clinical and Radiographic Outcomes,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 27, no. 2 (2016): 253&#x2013;257, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.12586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Wessels, S. Vervaeke, L. Seyssens, A. Eghbali, and J. Cosyn, &#x201c;A 5&#x2010;Year Cohort Study on Early Implant Placement With Guided Bone Regeneration or Alveolar Ridge Preservation With Connective Tissue Graft,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 22, no. 6 (2020): 697&#x2013;705, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Mijiritsky, A. Barone, I. C. Cinar, K. Nagy, and M. Shacham, &#x201c;3D Considerations and Outcomes of Immediate Single Implant Insertion and Provisionalization at the Maxillary Esthetic Zone: A Long&#x2010;Term Retrospective Follow&#x2010;Up Study of up to 18 Years,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 10, no. 18 (2021): 4138, https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm10184138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Zhao, H. Xu, W. Wang, and X. Li, &#x201c;Single Immediate Implant Placement into Anterior Maxillary Sockets with Facial Bone Defects: A 5&#x2010;Year Retrospective Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 38, no. 2 (2023): 374&#x2013;380, https://doi.org/10.11607/jomi.10160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. F. Cooper, G. J. Reside, F. Raes, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Immediate Provisionalization of Dental Implants Placed in Healed Alveolar Ridges and Extraction Sockets: A 5&#x2010;Year Prospective Evaluation,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 29, no. 3 (2014): 709&#x2013;717, https://doi.org/10.11607/jomi.3617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cosyn, A. Eghbali, H. De Bruyn, K. Collys, R. Cleymaet, and T. De Rouck, &#x201c;Immediate Single&#x2010;Tooth Implants in the Anterior Maxilla: 3&#x2010;Year Results of a Case Series on Hard and Soft Tissue Response and Aesthetics,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 38, no. 8 (2011): 746&#x2013;753, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;051X.2011.01748.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. M. McCormack, D. J. de L. Horne, and S. Sheather, &#x201c;Clinical Applications of Visual Analogue Scales: A Critical Review,&#x201d; Psychological Medicine 18, no. 4 (1988): 1007&#x2013;1019, https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291700009934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. D. Slade, &#x201c;Derivation and Validation of a Short&#x2010;Form Oral Health Impact Profile,&#x201d; Community Dentistry and Oral Epidemiology 25, no. 4 (1997): 284&#x2013;290, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0528.1997.tb00941.x.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>