<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41139221</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Altitude or heat training to increase haemoglobin mass and endurance exercise performance in elite sport.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP287700</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>High-altitude training has been a well-integrated tool in elite endurance sport for decades. The underlying premise is that physiological responses to high-altitude exposure, such as an increase in haemoglobin mass, are correlated with exercise performance. In this review, we highlight that physiological adaptations to a given magnitude of hypoxic exposure induce a highly variable range of responses in humans. For haemoglobin mass, this can vary from near nothing to previously unseen augmentations. At present, however, it remains inconclusive whether responses observed after one high-altitude training camp can be reproduced at the individual level during a subsequent camp. Exercise training performed in a warm environment or by wearing heat-capturing garments in a cooler environment has been termed 'heat training' and has, in recent years, become an increasingly popular alternative to altitude training. After a 3- to 5-week period of heat training, a robust increase in haemoglobin mass has repeatedly been reported, although the associated performance gains are only small. Accordingly, heat training should probably not be implemented before all other steps involved in elite training are in place and, importantly, heat training should not be performed at the expense of other important aspects of elite life. Thus, heat training might serve as a substitute for altitude training. Ultimately, it can be recommended that elite athletes experiment with either approach and that the choice of implementation should be made at the individual level, ensuring that the applied stress (hypoxia or heat) is tolerated adequately by the athlete.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). The Journal of Physiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lundby</LastName><ForeName>Carsten</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1684-0026</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Clinical Biomechanics, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robach</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6205-7761</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National School for Mountain Sports, site of the National School of Skiing and Mountaineering (ENSA), Chamonix, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">altitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41139221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP287700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Astridge, D. J., McKenna, M., Campbell, A., &amp; Turner, A. P. (2024). Haemoglobin mass responses and performance outcomes among high&#x2010;performance swimmers following a 3&#x2010;week live&#x2010;high, train&#x2010;high camp at 2320 m. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 124(8), 2389&#x2013;2399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bejder, J., Andersen, A. B., Buchardt, R., Larsson, T. H., Olsen, N. V., &amp; Nordsborg, N. B. (2017). Endurance, aerobic high&#x2010;intensity, and repeated sprint cycling performance is unaffected by normobaric &#x201c;Live high&#x2010;train Low&#x201d;: A double&#x2010;blind placebo&#x2010;controlled cross&#x2010;over study. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 117(5), 979&#x2013;988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bejder, J., &amp; Nordsborg, N. B. (2018). Specificity of &#x201c;live high&#x2010;train low&#x201d; altitude training on exercise performance. Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews, 46(2), 129&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie, F., Millet, G. P., Hauser, A., Steiner, T., Rysman, J., Wehrlin, J. P., &amp; Girard, O. (2015). &#x201c;Live high&#x2010;train low and high&#x201d; hypoxic training improves team&#x2010;sport performance. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 47(10), 2140&#x2013;2149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carin, R., Faucher, C., Connes, P., Viard, V., Martin, M., Ducray, M., Pla, R., Merino, M., Gaston, A. F., Lacroix, J., Doucende, G., Joly, P., Stauffer, E., Brugniaux, J., Verg&#xe8;s, S., Brocherie, F., Pichon, A., Robach, P., &amp; Nader, E. (2025). Persisting elevation of total hemoglobin mass after altitude training in elite swimmers: a potential role of prolonged erythrocyte survival. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 329(4), H789&#x2013;H800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr, A. J., Saunders, P. U., Vallance, B. S., Garvican&#x2010;Lewis, L. A., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2015). Increased hypoxic dose after training at low altitude with 9h per night at 3000m normobaric hypoxia. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine, 14, 776&#x2013;782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerda&#x2010;Kohler, H., Haichelis, D., Reuquen, P., Miarka, B., Homer, M., Zapata&#x2010;Gomez, D., &amp; Aedo&#x2010;Munoz, E. (2022). Training at moderate altitude improves submaximal but not maximal performance&#x2010;related parameters in elite rowers. Frontiers in Physiology, 13, 931325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cubel, C., Fischer, M., Stampe, D., Klaris, M. B., Bruun, T. R., Lundby, C., Nordsborg, N. B., &amp; Nybo, L. (2024). Time&#x2010;course for onset and decay of physiological adaptations in endurance trained athletes undertaking prolonged heat acclimation training. Temperature (Austin), 11(4), 350&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cubel, C., Klaris, M. B., Larsen, J. V., Faiss, R., Nybo, L., &amp; Lundby, C. (2025). Haematological adaptations to high&#x2010;altitude and heat acclimation training in elite male cyclists. Experimental Physiology. Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1113/EP092968</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czuba, M., Fidos&#x2010;Czuba, O., Ploszczyca, K., Zajac, A., &amp; Langfort, J. (2018). Comparison of the effect of intermittent hypoxic training vs. the live high, train low strategy on aerobic capacity and sports performance in cyclists in normoxia. Biology of Sport, 35(1), 39&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn, A., Lo, V., &amp; Donnelly, S. (2007). The role of the kidney in blood volume regulation: The kidney as a regulator of the hematocrit.American Journal of the Medical Sciences, 334(1), 65&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans, E., Walhin, J. P., Hengist, A., Betts, J. A., Dearlove, D. J., &amp; Gonzalez, J. T. (2023). Ketone monoester ingestion increases postexercise serum erythropoietin concentrations in healthy men. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Endocrinology and Metabolism, 324(1), E56&#x2010;E61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faiss, R., Raberin, A., Brocherie, F., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2024). Repeated&#x2010;sprint training in hypoxia: A review with 10 years of perspective. Journal of Sports Sciences, 43(19), 2164&#x2013;2178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvican&#x2010;Lewis, L. A., Halliday, I., Abbiss, C. R., Saunders, P. U., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2015). Altitude exposure at 1800 m increases haemoglobin mass in distance runners. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine, 14(2), 413&#x2013;417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvican, L., Martin, D., McDonald, W., &amp; Gore, C. (2010). Seasonal variation of haemoglobin mass in internationally competitive female road cyclists. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 109(2), 221&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvican, L. A., Saunders, P. U., Pyne, D. B., Martin, D. T., Robertson, E. Y., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2012). Hemoglobin mass response to simulated hypoxia &#x201c;blinded&#x201d; by noisy measurement? Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 112(10), 1797&#x2013;1798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, R. L., Witkowski, S., Zhang, Y., Alfrey, C., Sivieri, M., Karlsen, T., Resaland, G. K., Harber, M., Stray&#x2010;Gundersen, J., &amp; Levine, B. D. (2002). Determinants of erythropoietin release in response to short&#x2010;term hypobaric hypoxia. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 92(6), 2361&#x2013;2367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson, O. R., Taylor, L., Watt, P. W., &amp; Maxwell, N. S. (2017). Cross&#x2010;adaptation: Heat and cold adaptation to improve physiological and cellular responses to hypoxia. Sports Medicine, 47(9), 1751&#x2013;1768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser, A., Schmitt, L., Troesch, S., Saugy, J. J., Cejuela&#x2010;Anta, R., Faiss, R., Robinson, N., Wehrlin, J. P., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2016). Similar haemoglobin mass response in hypobaric and normobaric hypoxia in athletes. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 48(4), 734&#x2013;741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heikura, I. A., Burke, L. M., Bergland, D., Uusitalo, A. L. T., Mero, A. A., &amp; Stellingwerff, T. (2018). Impact of energy availability, health, and sex on haemoglobin&#x2010;mass responses following live&#x2010;high&#x2010;train&#x2010;high altitude training in elite female and male distance athletes. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 13(8), 1090&#x2013;1096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inness, M. W. H., Billaut, F., &amp; Aughey, R. J. (2017). Live&#x2010;high train&#x2010;low improves repeated time&#x2010;trial and Yo&#x2010;Yo IR2 performance in sub&#x2010;elite team&#x2010;sport athletes. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport, 20(2), 190&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanta, J. M., Lundsgaard, A., Schaufuss, A., Kleinert, M., Kiens, B., &amp; Fritzen, A. M. (2025). Induction of erythropoietin by dietary medium&#x2010;chain triacylglycerol in humans. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Endocrinology and Metabolism, 328(2), E210&#x2013;E216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keiser, S., Fl&#xfc;ck, D., H&#xfc;ppin, F., Stravs, A., Hilty, M. P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2015). Heat training increases exercise capacity in hot but not in temperate conditions: A mechanistic counter&#x2010;balanced cross&#x2010;over study. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 309(5), H750&#x2013;H761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keiser, S., Meinild&#x2010;Lundby, A. K., Steiner, T., Trosch, S., Rauber, S., Krafft, A., Burkhardt, T., Hilty, M. P., Siebenmann, C., Wehrlin, J. P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2017). Detection of blood volumes and haemoglobin mass by means of CO re&#x2010;breathing and indocyanine green and sodium fluorescein injections. Scandinavian Journal of Clinical and Laboratory Investigation, 77(3), 164&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kettunen, O., Leppavuori, A., Mikkonen, R., Peltonen, J. E., Nummela, A., Wikstrom, B., &amp; Linnamo, V. (2023). Hemoglobin mass and performance responses during 4 weeks of normobaric &#x201c;live high&#x2010;train low and high&#x201d;. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 33(8), 1335&#x2013;1344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein, M., Kaestner, L., Bogdanova, A. Y., Minetti, G., Rudloff, S., Lundby, C., Makhro, A., Seiler, E., van Cromvoirt, A., Fenk, S., Simionato, G., Hertz, L., Recktenwald, S., Sch&#xe4;fer, L., Haider, T., Fried, S., Borsch, C., Marti, H. H., Sander, A., &amp; Mairb&#xe4;url, H. (2021). Absence of neocytolysis in humans returning from a 3&#x2010;week high&#x2010;altitude sojourn. Acta Physiologica (Oxford, England), 232(3), e13647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koivisto&#x2010;M&#xf8;rk, A. E., Svendsen, I. S., Skattebo, &#xd8;., Hall&#xe9;n, J., &amp; Paulsen, G. (2021). Impact of baseline serum ferritin and supplemental iron on altitude&#x2010;induced haemoglobin mass response in elite athletes. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 31(9), 1764&#x2013;1773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krumm, B., Vallance, B., Burke, L., Garcia, J., Bouten, J., Brocherie, F., Saugy, J. J., Botre, F., &amp; Faiss, R. (2024). High&#x2010;level performances following low altitude training and tapering in warm environments in elite racewalkers. European Journal of Sport Science, 24(8), 1120&#x2013;1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuorelahti, T., Ihalainen, J. K., Linnamo, V., Badenhorst, C., Kettunen, O., &amp; Mikkonen, R. S. (2025). Influence of &#x201c;live high&#x2010;train low&#x201d; on haemoglobin mass and post&#x2010;exercise hepcidin response in female endurance athletes. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 125(9), 2503&#x2013;2514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, B. D., &amp; Stray&#x2010;Gundersen, J. (1997). &#x201c;Living high&#x2010;training low&#x201d;: Effect of moderate&#x2010;altitude acclimatization with low&#x2010;altitude training on performance. Journal of Applied Physiology, 83(1), 102&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardi, G., Lanteri, P., Fiorella, P. L., Simonetto, L., Impellizzeri, F. M., Bonifazi, M., Banfi, G., &amp; Locatelli, M. (2013). Comparison of the haematological profile of elite road cyclists during the 2010 and 2012 GiroBio ten&#x2010;day stage races and relationships with final ranking. PLoS ONE, 8(4), e63092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby, C., Hamarsland, H., Hansen, J., Bj&#xf8;rndal, H., Berge, S. N., Hammarst&#xf6;m, D., &amp; R&#xf8;nnestad, B. R. (2023). Hematological, skeletal muscle fiber, and exercise performance adaptations to heat training in elite female and male cyclists. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 135(1), 217&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby, C., &amp; Robach, P. (2016). Does &#x2018;altitude training&#x2019; increase exercise performance in elite athletes? Experimental Physiology, 101(7), 783&#x2013;788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby, C., &amp; Robach, P. (2024). Toxic trend: Inhalation of the silent killer carbon monoxide by athletes to increase haemoglobin mass. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 137(4), 820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby, C., Siebenmann, C., &amp; Robach, P. (2012). Reply to Garvican, Saunders, Pyne, Martin, Robertson, and Gore. Journal of Applied Physiology, 112(10), 1799.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean, B. D., Buttifant, D., Gore, C. J., White, K., &amp; Kemp, J. (2013). Year&#x2010;to&#x2010;year variability in haemoglobin mass response to two altitude training camps. British Journal of Sports Medicine, 47(Suppl 1), i51&#x2010;i58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Z., Gao, H., Li, T., Ge, P., Xu, Y., &amp; Gao, B. (2021). Effects of eight weeks altitude training on the aerobic capacity and microcirculation function in trained rowers. High Altitude Medicine &amp; Biology, 22(1), 24&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen, C. J., Junge, N., Piil, J. F., Morris, N. B., Oberholzer, L., Siebenmann, C., Lundby, C., &amp; Nybo, L. (2019). Prolonged heat acclimation and aerobic performance in endurance trained athletes. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 1372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero, D., &amp; Lundby, C. (2017). Refuting the myth of non&#x2010;response to exercise training: &#x2018;non&#x2010;responders&#x2019; do respond to higher dose of training. The Journal of Physiology, 595(11), 3377&#x2013;3387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero, D., &amp; Lundby, C. (2018). Regulation of red blood cell volume with exercise training. Comprehensive Physiology, 9(1), 149&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero, D., &amp; Lundby, C. (2019). Arterial O2 content regulates plasma erythropoietin concentration independently of arterial O2 tension: A randomized controlled experimental study. Kidney International, 95(1), 173&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero, D., Rauber, S., Goetze, J. P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2016). Reduction in central venous pressure enhances erythropoietin synthesis: Role of volume&#x2010;regulating hormones. Acta Physiologica (Oxford, England), 218(2), 89&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika, I., Bourdillon, N., Zelenkova, I., Vergnoux, F., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2024). Hematological and performance adaptations to altitude training (2,320 m) in elite middle&#x2010;distance and distance swimmers. Frontiers in Physiology, 15, 1474479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nordenberg, D., Yip, R., &amp; Binkin, N. J. (1990). The effect of cigarette smoking on haemoglobin levels and anemia screening. Journal of the American Medical Association, 264(12), 1556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nummela, A., Eronen, T., Koponen, A., Tikkanen, H., &amp; Peltonen, J. E. (2021). Variability in haemoglobin mass response to altitude training camps. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 31(1), 44&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybo, L., R&#xf8;nnestad, B., &amp; Lundby, C. (2024). High or hot&#x2010;perspectives on altitude camps and heat&#x2010;acclimation training as preparation for prolonged stage races. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 34(1), e14268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberholzer, L., Siebenmann, C., Mikkelsen, C. J., Junge, N., Piil, J. F., Morris, N. B., Goetze, J. P., Meinild Lundby, A. K., Nybo, L., &amp; Lundby, C. (2019). Hematological adaptations to prolonged heat acclimation in endurance&#x2010;trained males. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 1379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, H. Y., Kim, S., &amp; Nam, S. S. (2017). Four&#x2010;week &#x201c;living high training low&#x201d; program enhances 3000&#x2010;m and 5000&#x2010;m time trials by improving energy metabolism during submaximal exercise in athletes. Journal of Exercise Nutrition &amp; Biochemistry, 21(1), 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, H. Y., Park, W., &amp; Lim, K. (2019). Living high&#x2010;training low for 21 days enhances exercise economy, hemodynamic function, and exercise performance of competitive runners. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine, 18(3), 427&#x2013;437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peltonen, J. E., Leppavuori, A., Lehtonen, E., Mikkonen, R. S., Kettunen, O., Nummela, A., Ohtonen, O., Gagnon, D. D., Wehrlin, J. P., Wilber, R. L., &amp; Linnamo, V. (2024). Combined intermittent hypoxic exposure at rest and continuous hypoxic training can maintain elevated haemoglobin mass after a hypoxic camp. Journal of Applied Physiology, 137(2), 409&#x2013;420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;riard, J. D., Eijsvogels, T. M. H., &amp; Daanen, H. A. M. (2021). Exercise under heat stress: Thermoregulation, hydration, performance implications, and mitigation strategies. Physiological Reviews, 101(4), 1873&#x2013;1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poff&#xe9;, C., Robberechts, R., Van Thienen, R., &amp; Hespel, P. (2023). Exogenous ketosis elevates circulating erythropoietin and stimulates muscular angiogenesis during endurance training overload. The Journal of Physiology, 601(12), 2345&#x2013;2358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prommer, N., Sottas, P. E., Schoch, C., Schumacher, Y. O., &amp; Schmidt, W. (2008). Total haemoglobin mass&#x2010;A new parameter to detect blood doping. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 40(12), 2112&#x2013;2118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robach, P., Gammella, E., Recalcati, S., Girelli, D., Castagna, A., Roustit, M., Lundby, C., Lundby, A. K., Bouzat, P., Verg&#xe8;s, S., S&#xe9;chaud, G., Banco, P., Uhr, M., Cornu, C., Sallet, P., &amp; Cairo, G. (2021). Induction of erythroferrone in healthy humans by micro&#x2010;dose recombinant erythropoietin or high&#x2010;altitude exposure. Haematologica, 106(2), 384&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robach, P., Hansen, J., Pichon, A., Meinild Lundby, A. K., Dandanell, S., Slettalokken Falch, G., Hammarstrom, D., Pesta, D. H., Siebenmann, C., Keiser, S., Kerivel, P., Whist, J. E., Ronnestad, B. R., &amp; Lundby, C. (2018). Hypobaric live high&#x2010;train low does not improve aerobic performance more than live low&#x2010;train low in cross&#x2010;country skiers. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 28(6), 1636&#x2013;1652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robach, P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2012). Is live high&#x2010;train low altitude training relevant for elite athletes with already high total haemoglobin mass? Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 22(3), 303&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robach, P., Thoolen, S., Rommel, S., Recalcati, S., Correnti, M., Girelli, D., Castagna, A., Manceau, M., Meinild Lundby, A. K., Hillig, T., Prchal, J. T., Song, J., Stauffer, E., Connes, P., Goetze, J. P., Verg&#xe8;s, S., Mulder, E., Ulliel&#x2010;Roche, M., Chabridon, L., &#x2026; Lundby, C. (2025). Does one year of continuous hypoxia necessarily increase total haemoglobin mass ? (abstract) 23rd International Hypoxia Symposium, Lake Louise, Canada, 112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson, E. Y., Saunders, P. U., Pyne, D. B., Aughey, R. J., Anson, J. M., &amp; Gore, C. J. (2010). Reproducibility of performance changes to simulated live high/train low altitude. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 42(2), 394&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez, F. A., Iglesias, X., Feriche, B., Calderon&#x2010;Soto, C., Chaverri, D., Wachsmuth, N. B., Schmidt, W., &amp; Levine, B. D. (2015). Altitude training in elite swimmers for sea level performance (Altitude Project). Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 47(9), 1965&#x2013;1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, B. J., Goodrich, J. A., Schmidt, W., Kane, L. A., &amp; Byrnes, W. C. (2016). Ten days of intermittent, low&#x2010;dose carbon monoxide inhalation does not significantly alter haemoglobin mass, aerobic performance predictors, or peak&#x2010;power exercise tolerance. International Journal of Sports Medicine, 37(11), 884&#x2013;889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad, B. R., Hamarsland, H., Hansen, J., Holen, E., Montero, D., Whist, J. E., &amp; Lundby, C. (2021). Five weeks of heat training increases haemoglobin mass in elite cyclists. Experimental Physiology, 106(1), 316&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad, B. R., Hansen, J., Bonne, T. C., &amp; Lundby, C. (2022a). Case report: Heat suit training may increase haemoglobin mass in elite athletes. International Journal of Sports Physiology and Performance, 17(1), 115&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad, B. R., Lid, O. M., Hansen, J., Hamarsland, H., M&#xf8;lmen, K. S., Nygaard, H., Ellefsen, S., Hammarstr&#xf6;m, D., &amp; Lundby, C. (2022b). Heat suit training increases haemoglobin mass in elite cross&#x2010;country skiers. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 32(7), 1089&#x2013;1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad, B. R., Odden, I., Urianstad, T., Hansen, J., M&#xf8;lmen, K. S., &amp; Cardinale, D. A. (2025). Heat suit training preserves the increased haemoglobin mass after altitude camp in elite cyclists. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 57(1), 81&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad, B. R., Urianstad, T., Hamarsland, H., Hansen, J., Nygaard, H., Ellefsen, S., Hammarstr&#xf6;m, D., &amp; Lundby, C. (2022c). Heat training efficiently increases and maintains haemoglobin mass and temperate endurance performance in elite cyclists. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 54(9), 1515&#x2013;1526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, W. F. J., Hoffmeister, T., Haupt, S., Schwenke, D., Wachsmuth, N. B., &amp; Byrnes, W. C. (2020). Chronic exposure to low&#x2010;dose carbon monoxide alters haemoglobin mass and V&#x2d9;O2max. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise, 52(9), 1879&#x2013;1887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt, L., Willis, S. J., Fardel, A., Coulmy, N., &amp; Millet, G. P. (2018). Live high&#x2010;train low guided by daily heart rate variability in elite Nordic&#x2010;skiers. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 118(2), 419&#x2013;428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, A. P., Saunders, P. U., Garvican&#x2010;Lewis, L. A., Periard, J. D., Clark, B., Gore, C. J., Raysmith, B. P., Stanley, J., Robertson, E. Y., &amp; Thompson, K. G. (2018). Training quantification and periodization during live high train high at 2100 M in elite runners: An observational cohort case study. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine, 17(4), 607&#x2013;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann, C., Cathomen, A., Hug, M., Keiser, S., Lundby, A. K., Hilty, M. P., Goetze, J. P., Rasmussen, P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2015). Hemoglobin mass and intravascular volume kinetics during and after exposure to 3,454&#x2010;m altitude. Journal of Applied Physiology, 119(10), 1194&#x2013;1201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann, C., Keiser, S., Robach, P., &amp; Lundby, C. (2017). CORP: Determinantion of blood volumes in man. Journal of Applied Physiology, 123(3), 645&#x2013;654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sitkowski, D., Szygula, Z., Surala, O., Orysiak, J., Zdanowicz, R., Pokrywka, A., Starczewski, M., &amp; Malczewska&#x2010;Lenczowska, J. (2019). Hematological status and endurance performance predictors after low altitude training supported by normobaric hypoxia: A double&#x2010;blind, placebo controlled study. Biology of Sport, 36(4), 341&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skattebo, O., &amp; Hallen, J. (2022). Individual variations in pre&#x2010;altitude haemoglobin mass influence haemoglobin mass responses to repeated altitude sojourns. Scandinavian journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 32(10), 1493&#x2013;1501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, J., Sundar, K., Gangaraju, R., &amp; Prchal, J. T. (2017). Regulation of erythropoiesis after normoxic return from chronic sustained and intermittent hypoxia. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 123(6), 1671&#x2013;1675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalmans, M., Tominec, D., Lauriks, W., Robberechts, R., Ramaekers, M., Debevec, T., &amp; Poff&#xe9;, C. (2025). Ketone ester ingestion impairs exercise performance without impacting cognitive function or circulating EPO during acute hypoxic exposure. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 138(6), 1309&#x2013;1320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urianstad, T., Villanova, S., Odden, I., Hansen, J., Molmen, K. S., Porcelli, S., Ronnestad, B. R., &amp; Cardinale, D. A. (2024). Carbon monoxide supplementation: Evaluating its potential to enhance altitude training effects and cycling performance in elite athletes. Journal of Applied Physiology, 137(5), 1092&#x2013;1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehrlin, J. P., Marti, B., &amp; Hall&#xe9;n, J. (2016). Hemoglobin mass and aerobic performance at moderate altitude in elite athletes. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology, 903, 357&#x2013;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, B., Ge, X., Yu, J., Hu, Y., &amp; Girard, O. (2021). Hypoxic re&#x2010;exposure retains haematological but not performance adaptations post&#x2010;altitude training. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 121(4), 1049&#x2013;1059.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, L., Wu, J., Yan, B., Wang, Y., Zou, M., Zhang, Y., Li, F., Qiu, J., &amp; Girard, O. (2024). Effects of three weeks base training at moderate simulated altitude with or without hypoxic residence on exercise capacity and physiological adaptations in well&#x2010;trained male runners. PeerJ, 12, e17166.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>