<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41328382</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0974-7052</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical pediatric dentistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Pediatr Dent</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Antimicrobial Efficacy and Cytotoxicity of Phytoextract from <i>Leucas aspera</i> as a Root Canal Irrigant in Primary Tooth: <i>In Vitro</i> Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1378</StartPage><EndPage>1384</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1378-1384</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5005/jp-journals-10005-3308</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM AND BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Root canal irrigation is a critical step in pediatric endodontics, where an ideal irrigant should exhibit potent antimicrobial properties while maintaining biocompatibility. Sodium hypochlorite (NaOCl) is widely used for its strong antimicrobial efficacy, but its cytotoxic effects raise concerns, especially in pediatric patients. <i>Leucas aspera</i> (<i>L. aspera</i>), a medicinal plant known for its antimicrobial properties, is explored as a potential alternative to 1% NaOCl. This study aims to evaluate and compare the antimicrobial efficacy and cytotoxicity of <i>L. aspera</i> extract and 1% NaOCl as root canal irrigants in pediatric dentistry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The antimicrobial efficacy of <i>L. aspera</i> and 1% NaOCl was assessed using the MIC (minimum inhibitory concentration), zone of inhibition (ZOI) test against <i>Enterococcus faecalis</i>, <i>Candida albicans</i>, and <i>Aggregatibacter actinomycetemcomitans</i>. Cytotoxicity was evaluated through the MTT (3-(4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl)-2,5-diphenyltetrazolium bromide) assay on human dental pulp stem cells (hDPSC) to determine cell viability. IC<sub>50</sub> values (half-maximal inhibitory concentration) were calculated for both irrigants to compare their toxicity levels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Antimicrobial efficacy<b>-</b> <i>L. aspera</i> exhibited superior antimicrobial activity compared to 1% NaOCl against tested pathogens, highlighting its potent antibacterial properties. Cytotoxicity analysis<b>-</b>The MTT assay showed that <i>L. aspera</i> demonstrated significantly higher cell viability than NaOCl. However, NaOCl's antimicrobial effectiveness is concentration-dependent, with higher concentrations yielding greater bacterial inhibition but also increased cytotoxicity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">NaOCl's antimicrobial efficacy is concentration-dependent, with higher concentrations providing greater bacterial inhibition but also increasing cytotoxic effects. One percent NaOCl is chosen for pediatric dentistry as it offers a balance between antimicrobial effectiveness and safety. Although <i>L. aspera</i> exhibited superior antimicrobial activity than 1% NaOCl and better cytotoxicity results in the MTT assay, further studies are needed to explore its potential as a clinically viable alternative.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The use of <i>L. aspera</i> as a root canal irrigant in pediatric dentistry could minimize cytotoxic risks while maintaining effective microbial control. This could lead to safer and more biocompatible endodontic treatments in children, reducing potential postoperative complications associated with NaOCl.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HOW TO CITE THIS ARTICLE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Pragadesh G, Srinivasan D, Abishek CB, <i>et al</i>. Evaluation of Antimicrobial Efficacy and Cytotoxicity of Phytoextract from <i>Leucas aspera</i> as a Root Canal Irrigant in Primary Tooth: <i>In Vitro</i> Study. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent 2025;18(11):1378-1384.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025; The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pragadesh</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-7234-5728</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Chettinad Dental College &amp; Research Institute, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srinivasan</LastName><ForeName>Daya</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5453-4380</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Chettinad Dental College &amp; Research Institute, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abishek</LastName><ForeName>C B</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-4014-5906</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Chettinad Dental College &amp; Research Institute, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sujathadevi</LastName><ForeName>B K</ForeName><Initials>BK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-4353-7923</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Dentistry, Sathyabama Dental College, Chengalpattu, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Pediatr Dent</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101585405</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0974-7052</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biocompatibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytotoxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leucas aspera</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric dentistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Root canal irrigation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium hypochlorite</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Source of support: Nil Conflict of interest: NoneConflict of interest: None</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41328382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12658424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5005/jp-journals-10005-3308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hincapi&#xe9; S, Fuks A, Mora I, et al. Teaching and practical guidelines in pulp therapy in primary teeth in Colombia&#x2014;South America. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2014;25(2):87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24650083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo S, Sriram S, Muthu MS, et al. Three-dimensional assessment of root canal morphology of primary dentition using cone beam computed tomography. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2025;35(4):675&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39380320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vora MS, Ramachandra JA, Nihal NK. Root canal irrigants in primary teeth. World J Dent. 2015;6(4):229&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino Ribeiro JR, Da Silveira Bueno CE, Bruno KF, et al. Impact of sodium hypochlorite on organic tissue dissolution in the periapical region of immature permanent teeth: an ex vivo study. J Endod. 2022;48(4):555&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35032539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi Z, Abbott PV. The properties and applications of chlorhexidine in endodontics. Int Endod J. 2009;42(4):288&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19220510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serper A, Calt S. The demineralizing effects of EDTA at different concentrations and pH. J Endod. 2002;28(7):501&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12126374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal V. Pediatric endodontics. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2022;15(Suppl. 1):S1&#x2013;S2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35645490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzanova M, Atanasov V, Yaneva Z, et al. Selectivity of current extraction techniques for flavonoids from plant materials. Processes. 2020;8(10):1222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaves JO, Da Silva LC, Machado APDF, et al. Extraction of flavonoids from natural sources using modern techniques. Front Chem. 2020;8(Pt A):507887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7546908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33102442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani V, Kannasandra Ramaiah M. Assessment of antioxidant and antimicrobial activity of Leucas aspera and its application in neuroprotection. J Neonat Surg. 2025;14(5S):388&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zehnder M. Root canal irrigants. J Endod. 2006;32(5):389&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16631834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes BP, Ferraz CC, Vianna ME, et al. In vitro antimicrobial activity of several irrigants against Enterococcus faecalis. Int Endod J. 2013;34(3):424&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vianna ME, Gomes BP, Berber VB, et al. In vitro evaluation of the antimicrobial activity of chlorhexidine and sodium hypochlorite. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod. 2004;97(1):79&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14716261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath A, John J, Nagappan N. Comparison of antimicrobial efficacy of neem, propolis, and sodium hypochlorite against Enterococcus faecalis and Candida albicans: an in vitro study. J Conserv Dent. 2018;21(2):138&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhakar AR, Hadakar SG, Raju OS, et al. Evaluation of antimicrobial efficacy of Triphala (an Indian Ayurvedic herb) against Enterococcus faecalis compared with sodium hypochlorite. J Endod. 2010;36(1):83&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20003940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathyanarayanan MB, Abirami A, Harikrishnan S. Antibacterial and anti-inflammatory properties of Leucas aspera: a potential alternative for synthetic drugs. Indian J Med Plants Res. 2020;10(3):45&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollashahi NF, Saberi E, Karkehabadi H. Evaluation of cytotoxic effects of various endodontic irrigation solutions on the survival of stem cell of human apical papilla. Iran Endod J. 2016;11(4):293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5069905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27790258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simbula G, Dettori C, Camboni T, et al. Comparison of tetraacetylethylendiamine + sodium perborate and sodium hypochlorite cytotoxicity on L929 fibroblasts. J Endod. 2010;36(9):1516&#x2013;1520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20728719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Tian J, Yu K, et al. A ROS-responsive hydrogel incorporated with dental follicle stem cell-derived small extracellular vesicles promotes dental pulp repair by ameliorating oxidative stress. Bioact Mater. 2024;36:524&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11279300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39072284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y, Hu X, Cai Z, et al. Photodynamic and nitric oxide therapy-based synergistic antimicrobial nanoplatform: an advanced root canal irrigation system for endodontic bacterial infections. J Nanobiotechnol. 2024;22(1):213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11059741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38689259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil SJ. Antioxidant studies, in vitro cytotoxic and cell viability assay of flavonoids and alkaloids of Leucas aspera (Wild.) Linn leaves. Asian J Biol Life Sci. 2021;10(1):165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman MA, Islam MS. Antioxidant, antibacterial and cytotoxic effects of the phytochemicals of whole Leucas aspera extract. Asian Pac J Trop Biomed. 2013;3(4):273&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3634923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23620850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukundan D, Sruthi MA. Cytotoxic effect of 1% and 3% sodium hypochlorite as irrigation agent in primary teeth on human red blood cells: an in vitro study. Rom J Stomatol. 2024;70(2):131&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baruah H, Sarma J, Mohan P, et al. Evaluation of cytotoxicity of Azadirachta indica A. Juss., Curcuma longa L. and Ocimum sanctum L. in BHK-21 cell line. Ann Phytomed. 2021;10(2):182&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>