<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41293125</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>53</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Deep eutectic solvent-assisted chemosensing of Fe(iii), V(iii), C(ii), and P(ii) ions using a paper-based micro-array decorated by silver nanoparticles.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>45822</StartPage><EndPage>45839</EndPage><MedlinePgn>45822-45839</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5ra07032e</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Heavy metal pollution has become one of the most serious environmental and industrial challenges today. This is because of their toxicity, tendency to bioaccumulate in living organisms, and persistence in the environment. In recent years, various techniques have been developed to detect and quantify heavy metal contaminants. In this study, an innovative paper-based chemosensor (PCS) was constructed for the specific colorimetric recognition of Fe(iii), V(iii), Co(ii), and Pd(ii) ions in the presence of deep eutectic solvent (DES). This micro-array of PCS, mounted on fiberglass with a diameter of 5 mm for each zone of reaction. Thus, a miniaturized ion sensing substrate was proposed for low-cost, rapid, sensitive, and selective ion detection in real samples using a smartphone, with silver nanoparticles (AgNPrs) with a prism structure that serves as an optical probe. The DES-PCS combined with silver nanoparticles showed excellent performance in both semi-quantitative and quantitative analysis of Fe(iii), V(iii), Co(ii), and Pd(ii). Furthermore, an RGB-based absorbance method was used to estimate ion concentrations through digital image analysis with a color-picker app installed on a Samsung Galaxy A54 smartphone. High linearity was achieved for all analytes (<i>R</i> <sup>2</sup> &gt; 0.975), with a low limit of quantification (LLOQ) ranging from 50 ng ml<sup>-1</sup> to 1 &#xb5;g ml<sup>-1</sup>. The use of the developed DES-PCS confirmed that it is easy to detect Fe(iii), V(iii), Co(ii), and Pd(ii) in human biofluids, with results aligning well with those from standard solutions. Additionally, the DES-PCS demonstrated selective, sensitive, and stable responses without needing sample manipulation, making it suitable for on-site monitoring of ions in both occupational and environmental contexts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tayefeh-Rahimian</LastName><ForeName>Raana</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Health Department, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences Isfahan Iran rismanchian@hlth.mui.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Analysis Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences Tabriz Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Student Research Committee, Occupational Health Department, Isfahan University of Medicals Sciences Isfahan Iran hassanzadem@tbzmed.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rismanchian</LastName><ForeName>Masoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Health Department, Isfahan University of Medical Sciences Isfahan Iran rismanchian@hlth.mui.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasanzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4918-1239</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Analysis Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences Tabriz Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saadati</LastName><ForeName>Arezoo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Research Center, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences Tabriz Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41293125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12641252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ra07032e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5ra07032e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Paithankar J. G. Saini S. Dwivedi S. Sharma A. Chowdhuri D. K. Heavy metal associated health hazards: An interplay of oxidative stress and signal transduction. Chemosphere. 2021;262:128350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33182141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamora-Ledezma C. Negrete-Bolagay D. Figueroa F. Zamora-Ledezma E. Ni M. Alexis F. et al., Heavy metal water pollution: A fresh look about hazards, novel and conventional remediation methods. Environ. Technol. Innovation. 2021;22:101504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra S. Chakraborty A. J. Tareq A. M. Emran T. B. Nainu F. Khusro A. et al., Impact of heavy metals on the environment and human health: Novel therapeutic insights to counter the toxicity. J. King Saud Univ., Sci. 2022;34(3):101865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik S. Singh J. Umar A. Ibrahim A. A. Baskoutas S. Smartphone-integrated paper sensor strips for rapid and on-site detection of heavy metal ions in environmental water samples. J. Photochem. Photobiol., A. 2025:116675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khayatian G. Moradi M. Hassanpoor S. MnO2/3MgO nanocomposite for preconcentration and determination of trace copper and lead in food and water by flame atomic absorption spectrometry. J. Anal. Chem. 2018;73(5):470&#x2013;478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourya A. Mazumdar B. Sinha S. K. Determination and quantification of heavy metal ion by electrochemical method. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2019;7(6):103459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding R., Cheong Y. H., Ahamed A. and Lisak G., in. Heavy Metals Detection with Paper-Based Electrochemical Sensors, ACS Publications, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33430590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S. R. Sharma B. Chawla P. A. Bhatia R. Inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectrometry (ICP-OES): a powerful analytical technique for elemental analysis. Food Anal. Methods. 2022;15(3):666&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limchoowong N. Sricharoen P. Techawongstien S. Chanthai S. Using bio-dispersive solution of chitosan for green dispersive liquid&#x2013;liquid microextraction of trace amounts of Cu (II) in edible oils prior to analysis by ICP&#x2013;OES. Food Chem. 2017;230:398&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28407927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W. Yang Y. Fu K. Zhang D. Wang Z. Progress in ICP-MS analysis of minerals and heavy metals in traditional medicine. Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13:891273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9274010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35837276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echioda S. Ogunieye A. O. Salisu S. Abdulrasheed A. A. Chindo I. Kolo A. UV-Vis spectrophotometric determination of selected heavy metals (Pb, Cr, Cd and As) in environmental, water and biological samples with synthesized glutaraldehyde phenyl hydrazone as the chromogenic reagent. Eur. J. Adv. Chem. 2021;2(3):1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yetisen A. K. Akram M. S. Lowe C. R. based microfluidic point-of-care diagnostic devices. Lab Chip. 2013;13(12):2210&#x2013;2251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23652632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akyazi T. Basabe-Desmonts L. Benito-Lopez F. Review on microfluidic paper-based analytical devices towards commercialisation. Anal. Chim. Acta. 2018;1001:1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29291790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryal P. Henry C. S. Advancements and challenges in microfluidic paper-based analytical devices: design, manufacturing, sustainability, and field applications. Front. Lab Chip Technol. 2024;3:1467423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devadhasan J. P. Kim J. A chemically functionalized paper-based microfluidic platform for multiplex heavy metal detection. Sens. Actuators, B. 2018;273:18&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi H. Tashkhourian J. Hemmateenejad B. Identification and determination of multiple heavy metal ions using a miniaturized paper-based optical device. Sens. Actuators, B. 2022;359:131551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Neto H. A. Arantes I. V. Ferreira A. L. do Nascimento G. H. Meloni G. N. de Araujo W. R. et al., Recent advances on paper-based microfluidic devices for bioanalysis. TrAC, Trends Anal. Chem. 2023;158:116893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinheiro T. Cardoso A. R. Sousa C. E. Marques A. C. Tavares A. P. Matos A. M. et al., based biosensors for COVID-19: a review of innovative tools for controlling the pandemic. ACS Omega. 2021;6(44):29268&#x2013;29290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34778604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryal P. Hefner C. Martinez B. Henry C. S. Microfluidics in environmental analysis: advancements, challenges, and future prospects for rapid and efficient monitoring. Lab Chip. 2024;24(5):1175&#x2013;1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38165815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du A. Lu Z. Hua L. Decentralized food safety and authentication on cellulose paper-based analytical platform: A review. Compr. Rev. Food Sci. Food Saf. 2024;23(5):e13421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39136976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ameku W. A. de Araujo W. R. Rangel C. J. Ando R. A. Paixao T. R. Gold nanoparticle paper-based dual-detection device for forensics applications. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 2019;2(9):5460&#x2013;5468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S. Korvink J. G. Mager D. Land K. The potential of paper-based diagnostics to meet the ASSURED criteria. RSC Adv. 2018;8(59):34012&#x2013;34034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9086909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35548839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada K. Shibata H. Suzuki K. Citterio D. Toward practical application of paper-based microfluidics for medical diagnostics: state-of-the-art and challenges. Lab Chip. 2017;17(7):1206&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morbioli G. G. Mazzu-Nascimento T. Stockton A. M. Carrilho E. Technical aspects and challenges of colorimetric detection with microfluidic paper-based analytical devices (&#xb5;PADs)-A review. Anal. Chim. Acta. 2017;970:1&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28433054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan W. Zhang L. Jarujamrus P. Doery J. C. Shen W. Improvement strategies on colorimetric performance and practical applications of Paper-based analytical devices. Microchem. J. 2022;180:107562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wi J.-S. Kim J. D. Lee W. Choi H. Kwak M. Song J. et al., Inkjet-printable nanoporous Ag disk arrays enabling coffee- ring effect-driven analyte enrichment towards practical SERS Applications. Int. J. Precis. Eng. Manuf.&#x2013;Green Technol. 2022;9(2):421&#x2013;429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grazioli C. Faura G. Dossi N. Toniolo R. Tubaro F. Terzi F. et al., A colorimetric paper-based smart label soaked with a deep-eutectic solvent for the detection of malondialdehyde. Sens. Actuators, B. 2021;329:129174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi H. Tashkhourian J. Hemmateenejad B. A 3D origami paper-based analytical device combined with PVC membrane for colorimetric assay of heavy metal ions: Application to determination of Cu (II) in water samples. Anal. Chim. Acta. 2020;1126:114&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32736715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galpothdeniya W. I. S. McCarter K. S. De Rooy S. L. Regmi B. P. Das S. Hasan F. et al., Ionic liquid-based optoelectronic sensor arrays for chemical detection. RSC Adv. 2014;4(14):7225&#x2013;7234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S. Dong Y. Sun J. Gu P. Wang J. Zhang S. Ionic liquids membranes for liquid separation: status and challenges. Green Chem. 2023;25(15):5813&#x2013;5835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florindo C. Lima F. Ribeiro B. D. Marrucho I. M. Deep eutectic solvents: overcoming 21st century challenges. Curr. Opin. Green Sustainable Chem. 2019;18:31&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhune A. Dey R. Green and sustainable solvents of the future: Deep eutectic solvents. J. Mol. Liq. 2023;379:121676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith E. L. Abbott A. P. Ryder K. S. Deep eutectic solvents (DESs) and their applications. Chem. Rev. 2014;114(21):11060&#x2013;11082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25300631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Vigier K. Garc&#xed;a-&#xc1;lvarez J. Deep eutectic and low-melting mixtures. Bio-Based Solvents. 2017;93(14):83&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#x142;otka-Wasylka J. De la Guardia M. Andruch V. Vilkov&#xe1; M. Deep eutectic solvents vs. ionic liquids: Similarities and differences. Microchem. J. 2020;159:105539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janicka P. Kaykhaii M. P&#x142;otka-Wasylka J. G&#x119;bicki J. Supramolecular deep eutectic solvents and their applications. Green Chem. 2022;24(13):5035&#x2013;5045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen B. B. Spittle S. Chen B. Poe D. Zhang Y. Klein J. M. et al., Deep eutectic solvents: a review of fundamentals and applications. Chem. Rev. 2020;121(3):1232&#x2013;1285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mr M. B. S. Mr V. S. K. Chaudhary M. Singh P. A mini review on synthesis, properties and applications of deep eutectic solvents. J. Indian Chem. Soc. 2021;98(11):100210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Achkar T. Greige-Gerges H. Fourmentin S. Basics and properties of deep eutectic solvents: a review. Environ. Chem. Lett. 2021;19(4):3397&#x2013;3408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alahmad W. Sahragard A. Varanusupakul P. An overview of the recent developments of microfluidic paper-based analytical devices for the detection of chromium species. Microchem. J. 2021;170:106699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J. Wang G. Zou J. Lei Z. Chitosan modified cuprous oxide nanoparticles with specific oxidoreductase-like activity for rapid and sensitive colorimetric detection of Cr (VI) Colloids Surf., A. 2024;686:133356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivas K. Sahu B. Deb M. K. Thakur S. S. Sahu S. Kurrey R. et al., Colorimetric and paper-based detection of lead using PVA capped silver nanoparticles: experimental and theoretical approach. Microchem. J. 2019;150:104156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q. Lin Y. Xiong J. Wu L. Hou X. Xu K. et al., Disposable paper-based analytical device for visual speciation analysis of Ag(i) and silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) Anal. Chem. 2019;91(5):3359&#x2013;3366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khachornsakkul K. Phuengkasem D. Palkuntod K. Sangkharoek W. Jamjumrus O. Dungchai W. A simple counting-based measurement for paper analytical devices and their application. ACS Sens. 2022;7(7):2093&#x2013;2101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35736786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar D. Kaur N. Rigid anthraquinone based sensor for dual and differential colorimetric detection of Cu2+ and Ni2+ ions: mimicking different molecular logic systems. Results Chem. 2022;4:100563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Maghrabey M. Seino S. Kishikawa N. Kuroda N. The Development of a Selective Colorimetric Sensor for Cu2+ and Zn2+ in Mineral Supplement with Application of a Smartphone Paper-Based Assay of Cu2+ in Water Samples. Sensors. 2024;24(23):7844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11645015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39686381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad-Aree S. Teepoo S. On-site detection of heavy metals in wastewater using a single paper strip integrated with a smartphone. Anal. Bioanal. Chem. 2020;412(6):1395&#x2013;1405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31919608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idros N. Chu D. Triple-indicator-based multidimensional colorimetric sensing platform for heavy metal ion detections. ACS Sens. 2018;3(9):1756&#x2013;1764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30193067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong X. Zhang J. Wang Z. Liu C. Xiao W. Han J. et al., Simultaneous multiplexed detection of protein and metal ions by a colorimetric microfluidic paper-based analytical device. BioChip J. 2020;14(4):429&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7594977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue J. Lv Q. Wang W. Zhang Q. Quantum-dot-functionalized paper-based device for simultaneous visual detection of Cu (II), Mn (II), and Hg (II) Talanta. 2022;5:100099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayefeh-Rahimian R. Rismanchian M. Hasanzadeh M. Plasmonic chemosensing of W(VI), Pd(II), Cr(III), and Cs(I) in deep eutectic solvent using silver nanoparticles: green solvent toward optical point-of-use quality testing. RSC Adv. 2025;15:28021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12327382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40772006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saadati A. Farshchi F. Hasanzadeh M. Liu Y. Seidi F. Colorimetric and naked-eye detection of arsenic(iii) using a paper-based microfluidic device decorated with silver nanoparticles. RSC Adv. 2022;12:21836&#x2013;21850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9358409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36091189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuntzleman T. S. Jacobson E. C. Teaching Beer's law and absorption spectrophotometry with a smart phone: a substantially simplified protocol. J. Chem. Educ. 2016;93(7):1249&#x2013;1252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans E. Gabriel E. F. M. Coltro W. K. T. Garcia C. D. Rational selection of substrates to improve color intensity and uniformity on microfluidic paper-based analytical devices. Analyst. 2014;139(9):2127&#x2013;2132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24618915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma N. Barstis T. Giri B. Advances in paper-analytical methods for pharmaceutical analysis. Eur. J. Pharmacol. 2018;111:46&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28943443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>