<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41589156</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of the Cariogenic Potential of Two Sweeteners, Stevia and Aspartame, Based on Bacterial Inhibition and pH Reduction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e100100</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e100100</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e100100</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.100100</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background and aim Complete elimination of dietary sugars is impractical, especially for children. Restricting sugar intake and substituting sucrose with less cariogenic alternatives are plausible solutions. This in vitro study aimed to compare the cariogenic potential of two sweeteners, aspartame and stevia, by evaluating their bacterial inhibition capacity and the salivary pH changes produced at fixed time intervals. Methods To measure antibacterial activity, Petri plates containing 20 mL of Mueller-Hinton agar were seeded with a <i>Streptococcus mutans</i> culture adjusted to 0.5% McFarland Standard. Wells of approximately 10 mm diameter were bored using a well cutter, and different concentrations of the sweeteners (0.5%, 2.5%, 5.0%, and 10%) were added. Plates were incubated at 37&#xb0;C for 24 hours, after which the zones of bacterial inhibition were measured. To measure pH changes, a test medium prepared by mixing artificial saliva (5 mL) with brain heart infusion medium (5 mL) was inoculated with <i>S. mutans</i> (50 &#xb5;L). Samples were divided into two groups: stevia extract and aspartame. Increasing concentrations of both sweeteners were tested, and pH was recorded at regular intervals. Uninoculated test medium served as the control. Results Preliminary experiments were performed in single trials, followed by subsequent experiments carried out in triplicate&#xa0;to determine both pH changes and antibacterial activity of stevia and aspartame. The arithmetic mean of the observed values was used for statistical analysis.&#xa0;The zone of bacterial inhibition measured in millimeters and the pH change measured at varying concentrations of the two samples&#xa0;were&#xa0;compared using one-way ANOVA. The change in pH of various concentrations of stevia extract and aspartame recorded at different time intervals was compared using a paired t-test. The mean zone of bacterial inhibition was greater for stevia, and the area of inhibition increased with increasing concentration in both groups. No significant difference in pH change with increasing concentrations or time was observed between the aspartame and stevia groups. Conclusions Significant antimicrobial activity was&#xa0;exhibited by both aspartame and stevia against the cariogenic bacteria,&#xa0;<i>S. mutans</i>. The pH drop produced by both sweeteners over time also did not show significant differences under in vitro&#xa0;conditions. Hence, the&#xa0;findings suggest that aspartame and stevia possess comparable anticariogenic properties. Considering the calorific value and&#xa0;potential adverse effects of aspartame on human health, the natural sweetener stevia may be regarded as a better alternative.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, J et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>J</LastName><ForeName>Reshmi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Preventive Dentistry, Government Dental College, Thiruvananthapuram, Thiruvananthapuram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sain</LastName><ForeName>Shaniya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Preventive Dentistry, PMS College of Dental Science and Research, Thiruvananthapuram, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aspartame</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrogen-ion concentration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stevia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sweetening agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">&#xa0;dental caries</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41589156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12831961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.100100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Biology, immunology, and cariogenicity of Streptococcus mutans. Hamada S, Slade HD. Microbiol Rev. 1980;44:331&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC373181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6446023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbal remedies for oral and dental health: a comprehensive review of their multifaceted mechanisms including antimicrobial, anti-inflammatory, and antioxidant pathways. Anwar MA, Sayed GA, Hal DM, et al. Inflammopharmacology. 2025;33:1085&#x2013;1160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39907951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The science and practice of caries prevention. Featherstone JD. J Am Dent Assoc. 2000;131:887&#x2013;899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10916327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Children's dental health and medicines that contain sugar. Mackie IC. BMJ. 1995;311:141&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2550215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7613414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A qualitative investigation into general practitioners' views on prescribing sugar-free medicines for children prior to a dental health education campaign. Bentley EM, Mackie IC. http://www.jstor.org/stable/45109634 Health Educ Res. 1993;8:519&#x2013;524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aspartame hazard and risk assessment results released.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2023. https://www.who.int/news/item/14-07-2023-aspartame-hazard-and-risk-assessment-results-released? https://www.who.int/news/item/14-07-2023-aspartame-hazard-and-risk-assessment-results-released?</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevia rebaudiana Bertoni: a natural alternative for treating diseases associated with metabolic syndrome. Carrera-Lanestosa A, Moguel-Ord&#xf3;&#xf1;ez Y, Segura-Campos M. J Med Food. 2017;20:933&#x2013;943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5651958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28792778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role of sugar and sugar substitutes in dental caries: a review. Gupta P, Gupta N, Pawar AP, Birajdar SS, Natt AS, Singh HP. ISRN Dent. 2013;2013:519421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3893787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24490079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of artificial sweeteners on human health and cancer association: a comprehensive clinical review. Ghusn W, Naik R, Yibirin M. Cureus. 2023;15:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10822749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consumption of low-calorie sweeteners among children and adults in the United States. Sylvetsky AC, Jin Y, Clark EJ, Welsh JA, Rother KI, Talegawkar SA. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2017;117:441&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6176710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28087414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial sweeteners and absence of bladder cancer risk in Copenhagen. M&#xf8;ller-Jensen O, Knudsen JB, S&#xf8;rensen BL, Clemmesen J. http://] Int J Cancer. 1983;32:577&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6642755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The relationship between the use of artificial sweeteners and cancer: a meta-analysis of case-control studies. Liu L, Zhang P, Wang Y, Cui W, Li D. Food Sci Nutr. 2021;9:4589&#x2013;4597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8358351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34401106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial sweeteners and human bladder cancer. Howe GR, Burch JD, Miller AB, et al. Lancet. 1977;310:578&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">71398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of epidemiological studies on artificial sweeteners and bladder cancer. Morgan RW, Wong O. Food Chem Toxicol. 1985;23:529&#x2013;533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3891558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial sweeteners and bladder cancer in Manchester, U.K., and Nagoya, Japan. Morrison AS, Verhoek WG, Leck I, Aoki K, Ohno Y, Obata K. Br J Cancer. 1982;45:332&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2010924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7073930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of artificially sweetened beverage consumption and urinary tract cancers in the women's health initiative observational study. Ringel NE, Hovey KM, Andrews CA, et al. Eur Urol Open Sci. 2023;47:80&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9806707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36601047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can artificial sweeteners increase the risk of cancer incidence and mortality: evidence from prospective studies. Yan S, Yan F, Liu L, Li B, Liu S, Cui W. Nutrients. 2022;14:3742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9506029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36145117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aspartame administered in feed, beginning prenatally through life span, induces cancers of the liver and lung in male Swiss mice. Soffritti M, Belpoggi F, Manservigi M, Tibaldi E, Lauriola M, Falcioni L, Bua L. Am J Ind Med. 2010;53:1197&#x2013;1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20886530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deviyanti S. Nusantara Science and Technology Proceedings. 2022. Cariogenic antibacterial potential of Stevia rebaudiana Bertoni leaves extract against Lactobacillus acidophilus; pp. 96&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anticariogenic properties and effects on periodontal structures of Stevia rebaudiana Bertoni. Narrative review. Contreras M. J Oral Res. 2013;2:158&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutritional value, cytotoxic and antimicrobial activities of Stevia rebaudiana leaf extracts. Ibrahem ES, Ragheb EM, Yousef FM, Abdel-Aziz MF, Alghamdi BA. https://share.google/Ykl9BtX4q3rxg8X06  J Biochem Tech. 2020;11:108&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phytochemical screening and comparative antimicrobial potential of different extracts of Stevia rebaudiana Bertoni leaves. Siddique AB, Rahman&#x202f;SM Rahman&#x202f;SM, Hossain&#x202f;MA Hossain&#x202f;MA, Hossain&#x202f;MA Hossain&#x202f;MA, Rashid&#x202f;MA Rashid&#x202f;MA. Asian Pac J Trop Dis. 2014;4:275&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevia polyphenols, their antimicrobial and anti-inflammatory properties, and inhibitory effect on digestive enzymes. Myint KZ, Zhou Z, Shi Q, Chen J, Dong X, Xia Y. Molecules. 2023;28:7572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10673113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38005293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anti-cancer properties of Stevia rebaudiana; more than a sweetener. Iatridis N, Kougioumtzi A, Vlataki K, Papadaki S, Magklara A. Molecules. 2022;27:1362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8874712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35209150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steviol glycosides from stevia rebaudiana: an updated overview of their sweetening activity, pharmacological properties, and safety aspects. Orellana-Paucar AM. Molecules. 2023;28:1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9920402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36770924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>