<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41890470</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Zone 3 Aggressive Retinopathy of Prematurity in a Near-Term Delivered Big Baby With a Birth Weight of 3,200 g.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e104121</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e104121</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e104121</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.104121</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aggressive retinopathy of prematurity (A-ROP) represents a severe, rapidly progressive variant of retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) that is most observed in extremely premature, low-birth-weight infants and usually involves the posterior zones. Its occurrence in near-term infants with normal birth weight, involving Zone 3, is rare. This report dwells upon such a rare occurrence. This is a case of a male baby born at 37 weeks' gestation with a birth weight of 3,200 g. The baby required a neonatal ICU (NICU) admission for 13 days for respiratory distress and seizures. At a postmenstrual age of 40 weeks, fundus examination revealed A-ROP in both eyes in Zone 3. After parental counseling, bilateral intravitreal anti-vascular endothelial growth factor (anti-VEGF) therapy with bevacizumab (one-third adult dose, 0.4 mg/0.015 mL) was administered. The infant showed rapid regression of plus disease and hemorrhages. Subsequent follow-ups demonstrated continued improvement, with complete retinal maturation by six months. At the final follow-up, the child had a mature retina, an unremarkable anterior segment, and a refraction of +0.50 DS/-2.00 DC &#xd7; 180&#xb0; in both eyes. This case highlights a rare presentation of A-ROP involving Zone 3 in a near-term, normal birth-weight infant. The potential role of postnatal factors, including respiratory distress management, in the development of A-ROP outside traditional risk profiles. The prognosis is good if the condition is treated promptly and there is no further systemic deterioration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Jain et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>K Shreeya</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vitreoretina, Srimati Kanuri Santhamma Centre for Vitreo-Retinal Diseases, Anant Bajaj Retina Institute, Kallam Anji Reddy Campus, LV Prasad Eye Institute, Hyderabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takkar</LastName><ForeName>Brijesh</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vitreoretina, Srimati Kanuri Santhamma Centre for Vitreo-Retinal Diseases, Anant Bajaj Retina Institute, Kallam Anji Reddy Campus, LV Prasad Eye Institute, Hyderabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belenje</LastName><ForeName>Akash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vitreoretina, Srimati Kanuri Santhamma Centre for Vitreo-Retinal Diseases, Anant Bajaj Retina Institute, Kallam Anji Reddy Campus, LV Prasad Eye Institute, Hyderabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">a-rop</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aggressive retinopathy of prematurity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">big baby a-rop</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">near-term baby a-rop</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neonatal intensive care unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zone 3 a-rop</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41890470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13016036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.104121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity: a global perspective of the epidemics, population of babies at risk and implications for control. Gilbert C. Early Hum Dev. 2008;84:77&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18234457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International classification of retinopathy of prematurity, third edition. Chiang MF, Quinn GE, Fielder AR, et al. Ophthalmology. 2021;128:0&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10979521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34247850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The International Classification of Retinopathy of Prematurity revisited. Classification of Retinopathy of Prematurity. Arch Ophthalmol. 2005;123:991&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16009843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity: two distinct mechanisms that underlie zone 1 and zone 2 disease. Flynn JT, Chan-Ling T. Am J Ophthalmol. 2006;142:46&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16815250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggressive posterior retinopathy of prematurity: a review on current understanding. Kumawat D, Sachan A, Shah P, Chawla R, Chandra P. Eye (Lond) 2021;35:1140&#x2013;1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8115681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33514899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Survey on retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) in Italy. Borroni C, Carlevaro C, Morzenti S, et al. Ital J Pediatr. 2013;39:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3716628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23837411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggressive posterior retinopathy of prematurity in infants &#x2265; 1500 g birth weight. Sanghi G, Dogra MR, Katoch D, Gupta A. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2014;62:254&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4005248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24618495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggressive posterior retinopathy of prematurity in large preterm babies in South India. Shah PK, Narendran V, Kalpana N. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2012;97:0&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22611114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>India to gear up to the challenge of "third epidemic" of retinopathy of prematurity in the world. Sai Kiranmayee P, Kalluri V. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2019;67:726&#x2013;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6552629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31124480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retinopathy of prematurity in Asian Indian babies weighing greater than 1250 grams at birth: ten year data from a tertiary care center in a developing country. Vinekar A, Dogra MR, Sangtam T, Narang A, Gupta A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17699940/ Indian J Ophthalmol. 2007;55:331&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2636032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17699940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update on blindness due to retinopathy of prematurity globally and in India. Blencowe H, Moxon S, Gilbert C. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27915313/ Indian Pediatr. 2016;53:0&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27915313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of the day-30 screening strategy on the disease presentation and outcome of retinopathy of prematurity. The Indian twin cities retinopathy of prematurity report number 3. Jalali S, Anand R, Rani PK, Balakrishnan D. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2014;62:610&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4065515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24088643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>