<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41220049</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-4798</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cornea</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cornea</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Corneal Densitometry for Early and Long-Term Evaluation of Surgical Outcomes After Phototherapeutic Keratectomy for Granular, Macular, and Lattice Corneal Dystrophy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ICO.0000000000004039</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate early and long-term outcomes of phototherapeutic keratectomy (PTK) in granular (GCD), macular (MCD), and lattice corneal dystrophy (LCD) using corneal densitometry as an objective marker for surgical efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this retrospective study, 51 eyes from 31 patients (GCD: n = 27; MCD: n = 13; LCD: n = 11) undergoing PTK were analyzed. Corneal tomography and densitometry were assessed preoperatively and at intervals up to over 5 years. Mixed-model analysis was used for statistical evaluation (P &#x2264; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In GCD, best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) improved from 0.4 &#xb1; 0.3 to 0.2 &#xb1; 0.1 logMAR after 6 to 12 months, with sustained reductions in anterior densitometry (0-2 mm and 2-6 mm zones) for up to 1 year. LCD eyes showed a short-term densitometry decrease in the 2 to 6 mm anterior zone at 6 weeks, but no significant BCVA improvement. MCD eyes demonstrated improved BCVA at 6 to 12 months, despite increased densitometry in anterior and central layers at 6 weeks. After 2 years, densitometry of the anterior and central layer as well as the total corneal thickness in all diameters were not statistically different to the preoperative values in all 3 groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PTK effectively improves BCVA and corneal transparency in GCD, where densitometry provides a useful objective measure. In LCD, densitometry changes are transient and do not clearly reflect functional benefit. In MCD, densitometry has limited value due to diffuse stromal involvement and does not correlate with visual improvement. Overall, corneal densitometry may support preoperative planning and postoperative follow-up in selected dystrophies, with its strongest applicability in GCD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2307-2237</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Saarland University Medical Center, Homburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seitz</LastName><ForeName>Berthold</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flockerzi</LastName><ForeName>Elias</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sneyers</LastName><ForeName>Alb&#xe9;ric</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suffo</LastName><ForeName>Shady</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daas</LastName><ForeName>Loay</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cornea</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8216186</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-3740</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IC3D</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scheimpflug tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneal densitometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneal opacity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneal surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41220049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ICO.0000000000004039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00003226-990000000-01028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Weiss JS, Lisch W, et al. [The latest IC3D classification of corneal dystrophies&#x2014;Overview and changes of the 3rd edition]. Ophthalmologie. 2024;121:714&#x2013;725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss JS, Rapuano CJ, Seitz B, et al. IC3D classification of corneal dystrophies&#x2014;edition 3. Cornea. 2024;43:466&#x2013;527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha-de-Lossada C, Rachwani-Anil R, Colmenero-Reina E, et al. Laser refractive surgery in corneal dystrophies. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2021;47:662&#x2013;670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otri AM, Fares U, Al-Aqaba MA, et al. Corneal densitometry as an indicator of corneal health. Ophthalmology. 2012;119:501&#x2013;508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhubhghaill SN, Rozema JJ, Jongenelen S, et al. Normative values for corneal densitometry analysis by Scheimpflug optical assessment. Invest Opthalmol Vis Sci. 2014;55:162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Ju G, He Y. Corneal densitometry: a new evaluation indicator for corneal diseases. Surv Ophthalmol. 2025;70:132&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borroni D, Bonzano C, Hristova R, et al. A new surgical technique to deliver riboflavin beneath corneal epithelium: the corneal cross-linking epi-pocket. Asia Pac J Ophthalmol (Phila). 2021;10:495&#x2013;498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayres BD, Rapuano CJ. Excimer laser phototherapeutic keratectomy. Ocul Surf. 2006;4:196&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz B, Langenbucher A. Phototherapeutic keratectomy in corneal dystrophies. In: Essentials in Ophthalmology. Vol 11. Berlin: Springer; 2019:55&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herber R, Kaiser A, Gr&#xe4;hlert X, et al. [Statistical analysis of correlated measurement data in ophthalmology: tutorial for the application of the linear mixed model in SPSS and R using corneal biomechanical parameters]. Ophthalmologe. 2020;117:27&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cnaan A, Laird NM, Slasor P. Mixed models: using the general linear mixed model to analyse unbalanced repeated measures and longitudinal data. Tutorials Biostat. 2005;2:127&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapuano CJ. Excimer laser phototherapeutic keratectomy: long-term results and practical considerations. Cornea. 1997;16:151&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinh R, Rapuano CJ, Cohen EJ, et al. Recurrence of corneal dystrophy after excimer laser phototherapeutic keratectomy. Ophthalmology. 1999;106:1490&#x2013;1497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz B, Behrens A, Fischer M, et al. Morphometric analysis of deposits in granular and lattice corneal dystrophy: histopathologic implications for phototherapeutic keratectomy. Cornea. 2004;23:380&#x2013;385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauvageot P, Julio G, Bola&#xf1;os JV, et al. Recurrence and visual outcomes of phototherapeutic keratectomy in lattice corneal dystrophy: a cohort study. J Refract Surg. 2022;38:43&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S, Langenbucher A, Seitz B. Excimer laser phototherapeutic keratectomy for granular and lattice corneal dystrophy: a comparative study. J Refract Surg. 2005;21:727&#x2013;731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Xie L. Features of recurrence after excimer laser phototherapeutic keratectomy for anterior corneal pathologies in North China. Ophthalmology. 2013;120:1179&#x2013;1185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Flockerzi E, Daas L, et al. Comparison of Scheimpflug imaging (Pentacam HR) and swept-source optical coherence tomography (CASIA2) in eyes with macular corneal dystrophy. Cornea. 2024;44:732&#x2013;739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudakova L, Palos M, Svobodova M, et al. Macular corneal dystrophy and associated corneal thinning. Eye. 2014;28:1201&#x2013;1205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafner A, Langenbucher A, Seitz B. Long-term results of phototherapeutic keratectomy with 193-nm excimer laser for macular corneal dystrophy. Am J Ophthalmol. 2005;140:392&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemer Atik B, Yildirim Y, Sonmez O, et al. Phototherapeutic keratectomy in macular and granular dystrophy: two-year results. Semin Ophthalmol. 2020;35:182&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha BJ, Kim T, Choi S, et al. Mitomycin C does not inhibit exacerbation of granular corneal dystrophy type II induced by refractive surface ablation. Cornea. 2010;29:490&#x2013;496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller A, Solomon R, Bloom A, et al. Prevention of recurrent Reis-B&#xfc;cklers dystrophy following excimer laser phototherapeutic keratectomy with topical mitomycin C. Cornea. 2004;23:732&#x2013;735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayres BD, Hammersmith KM, Laibson PR, et al. Phototherapeutic keratectomy with intraoperative mitomycin C to prevent recurrent anterior corneal pathology. Am J Ophthalmol. 2006;142:490&#x2013;492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T, Pak JH, Chae J, et al. Mitomycin C inhibits recurrent Avellino dystrophy after phototherapeutic keratectomy. Cornea. 2006;25:220&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah K, Eghrari AO, Vanner EA, et al. Scheimpflug corneal densitometry values and severity of guttae in relation to visual acuity in Fuchs endothelial corneal dystrophy. Cornea. 2022;41:692&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kai C, Oie Y, Nishida N, et al. Associations between visual functions and severity gradings, corneal scatter, or higher-order aberrations in Fuchs endothelial corneal dystrophy. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2024;65:15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaub F, Gerber F, Adler W, et al. Corneal densitometry as a predictive diagnostic tool for visual acuity results after Descemet membrane endothelial keratoplasty. Am J Ophthalmol. 2019;198:124&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz B, Lisch W. Stage-related therapy of corneal dystrophies. Dev Ophthalmol. 2011;48:116&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>