<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41198134</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-2864</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Retina (Philadelphia, Pa.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Retina</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>EXUDATIVE MACULAR NEOVASCULARIZATION BEFORE VISIBLE PIGMENTATION IN MACULAR TELANGIECTASIA TYPE-2 (MacTel).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>318</StartPage><EndPage>330</EndPage><MedlinePgn>318-330</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/IAE.0000000000004716</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">To examine multimodal imaging findings in eyes before and after the onset of exudative macular neovascularization (ExMNV) bypassing the stage of pigmentation in Macular Telangiectasia Type-2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">From a total of 798 patients, Macular Telangiectasia Type-2 eyes with ExMNV that exhibited no signs of focal hyperpigmentation on color fundus photograph, fundus autofluorescence, and spectral-domain optical coherence tomography were retrospectively evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">There were 16 eyes of 16 patients (2%) with a mean age of 50.60 &#xb1; 9.82 years. Among them, 11 eyes had ExMNV at the time of examination, whereas the remaining five eyes developed ExMNV during the follow-up period, all lacking pigment when it occurred. The average time for ExMNV development in the five eyes was 27.6 months (range: 11-46 months). Preceding signs of ExMNV included right-angled vessels and telangiectatic leaks causing the following optical coherence tomography changes-temporal parafoveal thickening in three eyes, minimal intraretinal fluid pockets in three eyes, convex hyporeflective subretinal space in two eyes, and subretinal fluid in two eyes. With further declension/descent of inner into outer retina, progression of ellipsoid zone loss was seen and outer retinal hyperreflectivity formed in areas with preexisting ellipsoid zone loss with visual acuity decline. Multiple retinal vessels formed an anastomosis with each other and extended into the center of the subretinal neovascular lesion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Patients with early Macular Telangiectasia Type-2 can proceed directly to ExMNV without pigmentation. Recognizing the signs before ExMNV develop will allow for closer follow-up and earlier treatment of these patients to prevent irreversible visual loss.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandran</LastName><ForeName>Kiran</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Vitreoretinal Services, Giridhar Eye Institute, Cochin, Kerala, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SSM Eye Research Foundation, Giridhar Eye Institute, Cochin, Kerala, India ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giridhar</LastName><ForeName>Anantharaman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7126-4885</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Vitreoretinal Services, Giridhar Eye Institute, Cochin, Kerala, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SSM Eye Research Foundation, Giridhar Eye Institute, Cochin, Kerala, India ; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vyas</LastName><ForeName>Jyoti Prakash</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Vitreoretinal Services, Giridhar Eye Institute, Cochin, Kerala, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gopalakrishnan</LastName><ForeName>Mahesh</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Vitreoretinal Services, Giridhar Eye Institute, Cochin, Kerala, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sivaprasad</LastName><ForeName>Sobha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Biomedical Research Centre, Moorfields Eye Hospital, NHS Foundation Trust, London, United Kingdom .</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/P027881/1</GrantID><Agency>UKRI Global Challenge Research Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Retina</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8309919</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0275-004X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D041623" MajorTopicYN="N">Tomography, Optical Coherence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005451" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescein Angiography</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058456" MajorTopicYN="Y">Retinal Telangiectasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014792" MajorTopicYN="N">Visual Acuity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008266" MajorTopicYN="Y">Macula Lutea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015861" MajorTopicYN="Y">Retinal Neovascularization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005654" MajorTopicYN="N">Fundus Oculi</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064847" MajorTopicYN="N">Multimodal Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005122" MajorTopicYN="N">Exudates and Transudates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">declension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exudation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exudative macular neovascularization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macular telangiectasia Type-2 (MacTel)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pigmentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">right-angled vessels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telangiectasia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41198134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/IAE.0000000000004716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006982-990000000-01241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title/><Reference><Citation>Charbel Issa P, Gillies MC, Chew EY, et al. Macular telangiectasia type 2. Prog Retin Eye Res 2013;34:49&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gass JD, Blodi BA. Idiopathic juxtafoveolar retinal telangiectasis. Update of classification and follow-up study. Ophthalmology 1993;100:1536&#x2013;1546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzaridis S, Heeren T, Mai C, et al. Right-angled vessels in macular telangiectasia type 2. Br J Ophthalmol 2021;105:1289&#x2013;1296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaide RF. New proposal for the pathophysiology of type 3 neovascularization as based on multimodal imaging findings. Retina 2019;39:1451&#x2013;1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Wang RK, Chen CL, et al. Swept source optical coherence tomography angiography of neovascular macular telangiectasia type 2. Retina 2015;35:2285&#x2013;2299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaide RF, Klancnik JM Jr, Cooney MJ. Retinal vascular layers in macular telangiectasia type 2 imaged by optical coherence tomographic angiography. JAMA Ophthalmol 2015;133:66&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudric A, Krivosic V, Tadayoni R. Outer retina capillary invasion and ellipsoid zone loss in macular telangiectasia type 2 imaged by optical coherence tomography angiography. Retina 2015;35:2300&#x2013;2306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toto L, Di Antonio L, Mastropasqua R, et al. Multimodal imaging of macular telangiectasia type 2: focus on vascular changes using optical coherence tomography angiography. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2016;57:268&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peto T, Heeren TFC, Clemons TE, et al. Correlation of clinical and structural progression with visual acuity loss in macular telangiectasia type 2: Mactel project report no. 6-The MacTel Research Group. Retina 2018;38:S8&#x2013;S13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heeren TFC, Chew EY, Clemons T, et al. Macular telangiectasia type 2: visual acuity, disease end stage, and the MacTel area MacTel project report number 8. Ophthalmology 2020;127:1539&#x2013;1548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew EY, Peto T, Clemons TE, et al. Macular telangiectasia type 2: a classification system using MultiModal imaging MacTel project report number 10. Ophthalmol Sci 2023;3:100261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung I, Sallo FB, Bonelli R, et al. Characteristics of pigmented lesions in type 2 idiopathic macular telangiectasia. Retina 2018;38:S43&#x2013;S50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yannuzzi LA, Bardal AM, Freund KB, et al. Idiopathic macular telangiectasia. Arch Ophthalmol 2006;124:450&#x2013;460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surguch V, Gamulescu MA, Gabel VP. Optical coherence tomography findings in idiopathic juxtafoveal retinal telangiectasis. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol 2007;245:783&#x2013;788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meleth AD, Toy BC, Nigam D, et al. Prevalence and progression of pigment clumping associated with idiopathic macular telangiectasia type 2. Retina 2013;33:762&#x2013;770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzaridis S, Aguilar E, Dorrell MI, et al. Retinal pigment epithelial cells reduce vascular leak and proliferation in retinal neovessels. Angiogenesis 2024;28:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelbrecht NE, Aaberg TM Jr, Sung J, Lewis ML. Neovascular membranes associated with idiopathic juxtafoveolar telangiectasis. Arch Ophthalmol 2002;120:320&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manayath GJ, Ninan RS, Verghese S, Narendran V. Intraretinal and subretinal fluid in exudative nonproliferative macular telangiectasia type 2. Oman J Ophthalmol 2022;15:393&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess K, Charbel Issa P, Holz FG, Tzaridis S. Morphological characteristics preceding exudative neovascularisation secondary to macular telangiectasia type 2. Br J Ophthalmol 2022;106:1736&#x2013;1741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivosic V, Zureik A, Tadayoni R, Gaudric A. From outer retinal neovascularization to exudative subretinal neovascularization in macular telangiectasia type-2. Retina 2024;44:1217&#x2013;1223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashani AH, Chen CL, Gahm JK, et al. Optical coherence tomography angiography: a comprehensive review of current methods and clinical applications. Prog Retin Eye Res 2017;60:66&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauleikhoff D, Bonelli R, Dubis AM, et al. Progression characteristics of ellipsoid zone loss in macular telangiectasia type 2. Acta Ophthalmol 2019;97:e998&#x2013;e1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breazzano MP, Yannuzzi LA, Spaide RF. Characterizing retinal-choroidal anastomosis in macular telangiectasia type 2 with optical coherence tomography angiography. Retina 2020;40:92&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zbek M, Artunay &#xd6;, Ko&#xe7;ak R, et al. Macular telangiectasia type 2: long-term disease progression and management of complications. Turk J Ophthalmol 2025;55:193&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsonia K, Kiran Chandra K, Ali MH, et al. Long-term follow-up of visual acuity and incidence of subretinal neovascularization in Mactel type 2 in 82 eyes. Semin Ophthalmol 2022;37:136&#x2013;141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller S, Gunnemann F, Rothaus K, et al. Incidence and phenotypical variation of outer retina-associated hyperreflectivity in macular telangiectasia type 2. Br J Ophthalmol 2021;105:573&#x2013;576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chidambara L, Gadde SG, Yadav NK, et al. Characteristics and quantification of vascular changes in macular telangiectasia type 2 on optical coherence tomography angiography. Br J Ophthalmol 2016;100:1482&#x2013;1488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaide RF, Yannuzzi LA, Maloca PM. Retinal-choroidal anastomosis in macular telangiectasia type 2. Retina 2018;38:1920&#x2013;1929.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coscas G, Coscas F, Zucchiatti I, et al. SD-OCT stages of progression of type 2 macular telangiectasia in a patient followed for 3 years. Eur J Ophthalmol 2013;23:917&#x2013;921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew EY, Clemons TE, Peto T, et al. Ciliary neurotrophic factor for macular telangiectasia type 2: results from a phase 1 safety trial. Am J Ophthalmol 2015;159:659&#x2013;666.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heeren TFC, Kitka D, Florea D, et al. Longitudinal correlation of ellipsoid zone loss and functional loss in macular telangiectasia type 2. Retina 2018;38:S20&#x2013;S26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew EY, Clemons TE, Jaffe GJ, et al. Effect of ciliary neurotrophic factor on retinal neurodegeneration in patients with macular telangiectasia type 2: a randomized clinical trial. Ophthalmology 2019;126:540&#x2013;549.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>