<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41752397</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1420-3049</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecules (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Molecules</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>CO<sub>2</sub>-Binder Reaction Mechanisms in Geopolymer Wellbore Cements: Alternatives to API Class G Cement in CO<sub>2</sub>-Rich Environments (CCS).</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">620</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/molecules31040620</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>API Classes of cement are susceptible to three major problems: carbonation, decalcification, and increased porosity of cement sheaths in CO<sub>2</sub>-rich environments. These degradation pathways in American petroleum institute (API) Class/ordinary Portland cement (OPC) systems are well documented in laboratory and field observations for CO<sub>2</sub>-rich wellbore service. In contrast, while geopolymer/alkali-activated binders have been increasingly studied as alternatives, the evidence remains distributed across different precursor chemistries, exposure conditions, and test protocols, and a consolidated, mechanism-based synthesis specific to CO<sub>2</sub> sequestration wells is still limited. Accordingly, this article presents a critical, narrative (non-systematic) review that synthesizes published laboratory and field studies on geopolymer/alkali-activated binders for CO<sub>2</sub> sequestration wells, with emphasis on permeability, strength retention, and microstructural stability under CO<sub>2</sub>-rich exposure. The main outcome of this review is a mechanism-based synthesis that links CO<sub>2</sub>-binder reaction pathways (gel chemistry/phase evolution) to pore-network and transport changes, and consolidates quantitative performance benchmarks (permeability and strength retention) relative to API Class G/OPC, while defining the key validation gaps for qualification (HPHT, cyclic/tensile integrity, mixed fluids, and long-term monitoring). Laboratory tests have already demonstrated that geopolymer samples have ultralow permeability and preserve 90% of their strength after being treated with supercritical CO<sub>2</sub> concentrations, while OPC loses its strength and produces macropores causing substantial growth of cement sheath porosity. Microstructural studies have shown that geopolymers do not contain portlandite but only N-A-S-H/C-A-S-H gels with low Ca content in concentrations high enough to create N-A-S-H/C-A-S-H gels, but do not suffer from multi-zone carbonation, as occurs for OPC concrete. Key challenges being tackled include slurry rheology, setting control and variability of precursors by designed admixture use and new performance specifications for higher-quality geopolymers. On the whole, geopolymers emerge as a sustainable and reliable alternative to traditional well cementing techniques for their sustainability well integrity.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bakri</LastName><ForeName>Omer Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>OM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-4096-9486</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Petroleum Engineering, King Fahd University of Petroleum &amp; Minerals, Dhahran 31261, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoud</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed Abdulhamid</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Petroleum Engineering, King Fahd University of Petroleum &amp; Minerals, Dhahran 31261, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Integrative Petroleum Research, King Fahd University of Petroleum &amp; Minerals, Dhahran 31261, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Molecules</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100964009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1420-3049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">API class G cement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CO2-induced degradation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alkali activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbon capture and storage (CCS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">geopolymer cement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">permeability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supercritical CO2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wellbore sealing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zonal isolation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41752397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12943332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules31040620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">molecules31040620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ghannam Z., Osman M., Bakri O.M., Mahmoud M., Kamal M.S., Gajbhiye R., Mahmoud A.A. Hybrid Monitoring Framework for Geological CO2 Storage: Comparative Insights from Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) and Conventional Techniques. Carbon Capture Sci. Technol. 2026;18:100561. doi: 10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavez Panduro E.A., Cordonnier B., Gawel K., B&#xf8;rve I., Iyer J., Carroll S.A., Michels L., Rogowska M., McBeck J.A., S&#xf8;rensen H.O., et al. Real Time 3D Observations of Portland Cement Carbonation at CO2 Storage Conditions. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2020;54:8323&#x2013;8332. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.0c00578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.0c00578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7467647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32525672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah V., Scrivener K., Bhattacharjee B., Bishnoi S. Changes in Microstructure Characteristics of Cement Paste on Carbonation. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;109:184&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.04.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.04.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y., Yao C., Guo X., Zhou Y., Jia Z., Chen S. Proceedings of the 2025 Unconventional Resources Technology Conference. American Association of Petroleum Geologists; Tulsa, OK, USA: 2025. Investigation on the Variation Pattern of Carbonation Damage in Oil Well Cement under CO2 Sequestration Conditions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai M., Sun J., Song K., Li L., Qiao Z. Well Completion and Integrity Evaluation for CO2 Injection Wells. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2015;45:556&#x2013;564. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2015.02.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2015.02.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck J., Feng R., Hall D.M., Buyuksagis A., Ziomek-Moroz M., Lvov S.N. Effects of H2S and CO2 on Cement/Casing Interface Corrosion Integrity for Cold Climate Oil and Gas Well Applications. ECS Meet. Abstr. 2016;MA2016-01:946. doi: 10.1149/MA2016-01/15/946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/MA2016-01/15/946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakri O.M., Mahmoud A.A. Proceedings of the Middle East Oil, Gas and Geosciences Show (MEOS GEO) SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2025. Review of the Behavior of Geopolymer Cement Exposed to Acidic Environment Under CO2 Sequestration Conditions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasvi M.C.M., Ranjith P.G., Sanjayan J. Effect of Different Mix Compositions on Apparent Carbon Dioxide (CO2) Permeability of Geopolymer: Suitability as Well Cement for CO2 Sequestration Wells. Appl. Energy. 2014;114:939&#x2013;948. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.05.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.05.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridha S., Dzulkarnain I., Abdurrahman M., Ilyas S.U., Bataee M. Microstructural Properties and Compressive Strength of Fly Ash-Based Geopolymer Cement Immersed in CO2-Saturated Brine at Elevated Temperatures. Int. J. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2022;19:7589&#x2013;7598. doi: 10.1007/s13762-021-03665-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13762-021-03665-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathsarani H.B.S., Sampath K.H.S.M., Ranathunga A.S. Utilization of Fly Ash-Based Geopolymer for Well Cement during CO2 Sequestration: A Comprehensive Review and a Meta-Analysis. Gas Sci. Eng. 2023;113:204974. doi: 10.1016/j.jgsce.2023.204974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgsce.2023.204974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter C. Geopolymer Implemented in Primary Casing Cementing. J. Pet. Technol. 2024;76:105&#x2013;108. doi: 10.2118/0524-0105-JPT.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/0524-0105-JPT</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meade M., Nenjerama Y., Parton C., Richter McDonald V., Fischer N., Kapoor S., Yakovlev A., Lafitte V., Smith W., Landry G., et al. First Global Implementation of Geopolymer in Primary Casing Cementing; Proceedings of the Offshore Technology Conference; Houston, TX, USA. 1&#x2013;4 May 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riyanto L., Kumar A.K., Shahril M.A., Lau C.H., Sazali Y.A., Amir M.S.E., Jain B., Kapoor S., Yakovlev A., Duong A.T. Proceedings of the SPE Asia Pacific Oil and Gas Conference and Exhibition. SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2023. Environmentally Friendly CO2 Resistance Cement for Carbon Capture Storage Project: First Deployment in Offshore Malaysia; p. D031S022R001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidovits J. Geopolymers. J. Therm. Anal. 1991;37:1633&#x2013;1656. doi: 10.1007/BF01912193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01912193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provis J.L. Alkali-Activated Materials. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;114:40&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.02.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korniejenko K., Miku&#x142;a J., Brudny K., Aruova L., Zhakanov A., Jexembayeva A., Zhaksylykova L. A Review of Industrial By-Product Utilization and Future Pathways of Circular Economy: Geopolymers as Modern Materials for Sustainable Building. Sustainability. 2025;17:4536. doi: 10.3390/su17104536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17104536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siyal A.A., Mohamed R.M.S.R., Shamsuddin R., Ridzuan M.B. A Comprehensive Review of Synthesis Kinetics and Formation Mechanism of Geopolymers. RSC Adv. 2024;14:446&#x2013;462. doi: 10.1039/D3RA06205H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3RA06205H</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10759171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38173565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalifeh M., Saasen A., Hodne H., Motra H.B. Laboratory Evaluation of Rock-Based Geopolymers for Zonal Isolation and Permanent P&amp;A Applications. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2019;175:352&#x2013;362. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2018.12.065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2018.12.065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto S., Machino T., Ando K., Daiko Y., Honda S., Iwamoto Y. Hot Sulfuric Acid-Resistance of Fly-Ash-Based Geopolymer Paste Product Due to the Precipitation of Natroalunite Crystals. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;151:714&#x2013;719. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.06.089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.06.089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud A.A., Abdelaal A., Elkatatny S., Shehri D. Proceedings of the GOTECH. SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2024. Al Red Mud-Based Geopolymer Cement for Sustainable Oil Well Construction: Opportunities and Challenges.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasyunina N.V., Dubova I.V., Druzhinin K.E., Gilmanshina T.R. Pyrometallurgical Processing of Red Mud. Metallurgist. 2024;68:631&#x2013;639. doi: 10.1007/s11015-024-01767-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11015-024-01767-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiabadi S.H., Khalifeh M., van Noort R. Proceedings of the SPE/IADC International Drilling Conference and Exhibition. SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2025. Hydro-Mechanical Behavior of a Granite-Based Geopolymer Sealant Exposed to MgCl2-Brine: Implications for CO2 Geosequestration.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanqari K., Al-Yami A., Wagle V. Proceedings of the International Petroleum Technology Conference. IPTC; London, UK: 2022. Preparation of a Synthetic Geopolymer Cement Utilizing Saudi Arabian Volcanic Ash for a Sustainable Development: Method, Preparation and Applications; p. D021S050R001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardjito D., Wallah S.E., Sumajouw D.M.J., Rangan B. V Fly Ash-Based Geopolymer Concrete. Aust. J. Struct. Eng. 2005;6:77&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1080/13287982.2005.11464946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13287982.2005.11464946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesanya E., Ohenoja K., Luukkonen T., Kinnunen P., Illikainen M. One-Part Geopolymer Cement from Slag and Pretreated Paper Sludge. J. Clean. Prod. 2018;185:168&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.03.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omran M., Khalifeh M. Development of One-Part Rock-Based Geopolymers for Downhole Cementing Applications. J. Energy Resour. Technol. 2023;145:103201. doi: 10.1115/1.4062250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4062250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelaal A., Elkatatny S., Abdel Fattah A. Proceedings of the Middle East Oil, Gas and Geosciences Show. SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2023. A Geopolymer System for High Pressure Oil and Gas Well Cementing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelaal A.E., Elkatatny S.M. High Density Geopolymers: A Step Forward Towards Low Carbon Footprint Cementing Operations; Proceedings of the Offshore Technology Conference; Houston, TX, USA. 1&#x2013;4 May 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjei S., Elkatatny S., Aggrey W.N., Abdelraouf Y. Geopolymer as the Future Oil-Well Cement: A Review. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2022;208:109485. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2021.109485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2021.109485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najeeb Z., Mosaberpanah M.A. Mechanical and Durability Properties of Modified High-Performance Mortar by Using Cenospheres and Nano-Silica. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;362:129782. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud A.A., Elkatatny S. Improving Class G Cement Carbonation Resistance for Applications of Geologic Carbon Sequestration Using Synthetic Polypropylene Fiber. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2020;76:103184. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habarudin M.F., Shafiq N., Zulkarnain N.N., Md Yusof M.A., Razak A.A.A., Sazali Y.A., Rahman S.H.A., Riyanto L., Abd Hamid A.I. Unlocking the Potential of Graphene Oxide as an Early Strength Enhancer for Geopolymer Well Cement in Extreme Downhole Environment. Cogent Eng. 2024;11:2380021. doi: 10.1080/23311916.2024.2380021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311916.2024.2380021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasvi M.C.M., Rathnaweera T.D., Padmanabhan E. Geopolymer as Well Cement and Its Mechanical Integrity under Deep Down-Hole Stress Conditions: Application for Carbon Capture and Storage Wells. Geomech. Geophys. Geo-Energy Geo-Resour. 2016;2:245&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1007/s40948-016-0034-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40948-016-0034-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahdaya M., Imqam A. Fly Ash Class C Based Geopolymer for Oil Well Cementing. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2019;179:750&#x2013;757. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2019.04.106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2019.04.106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helmy Y., Fakher S. Evaluating the Performance of Class F Fly Ash Compared to Class G Cement for Hydrocarbon Wells Cementing: An Experimental Investigation. Materials. 2024;17:2710. doi: 10.3390/ma17112710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17112710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11174082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38893976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiapei D., Yuhuan B., Xuechao C., Zhonghou S., Baojiang S. Utilization of Alkali-Activated Slag Based Composite in Deepwater Oil Well Cementing. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;186:114&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.07.068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.07.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu Y., Ma R., Du J., Guo S., Liu H., Zhao L. Utilization of Metakaolin-Based Geopolymer as a Mud-Cake Solidification Agent to Enhance the Bonding Strength of Oil Well Cement&#x2013;Formation Interface. R. Soc. Open Sci. 2020;7:191230. doi: 10.1098/rsos.191230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsos.191230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7062085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32257308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiabadi S.H., Khalifeh M., Van Noort R. Multiscale Insights into Mechanical Performance of a Granite-Based Geopolymer: Unveiling the Micro to Macro Behavior. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 2023;231:212375. doi: 10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanqari K., Al-Yami A., Wagle V. Proceedings of the Abu Dhabi International Petroleum Exhibition and Conference. SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2022. Synthesis of Epoxy Resin Based Geopolymer Utilizing Saudi Arabian Volcanic Ash for Primary Well Cementing Applications; p. D042S198R003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelaal A., Elkatatny S., Abd El Fattah A.M. Development of Heavy-Weight Hematite-Based Geopolymers for Oil and Gas Well Cementing. ACS Omega. 2023;8:14025&#x2013;14033. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c00590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c00590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10116515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37091391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjei S., Elkatatny S. Overview of the Lightweight Oil-Well Cement Mechanical Properties for Shallow Wells. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2021;198:108201. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2020.108201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2020.108201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelaal A., Elkatatny S. Mixed Micromax and Hematite-Based Fly Ash Geopolymer for Heavy-Weight Well Cementing. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:8669. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-36010-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-36010-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10226979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta M., Hajiabadi S.H., Aghabeyk F., Chen Y., van Noort R., Khalifeh M., Ye G. Understanding Microstructural Changes of a One-Part Geopolymer Exposed to CO2 for Geological Carbon Storage Application&#x2014;An Experimental and Numerical Investigation. Carbon Capture Sci. Technol. 2025;16:100466. doi: 10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccst.2025.100466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mammadov O., Mahmoud A.A., Al-Yaseri A., Al Ramadan M. A Comprehensive Review of Cement Degradation Analysis under Downhole Conditions: CCS/CCUS/CO2-EOR Applications. ACS Omega. 2025;10:28515&#x2013;28533. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c11295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c11295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12268432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40687035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pernites R., Kapoor S., Meade M., Yakovlev A., Smith W., Le V., Wang J., Obonna O., Urbano G., Abad C., et al. First Global Application of Corrosion-Resistant Cement-Free System: A Breakthrough Innovation to Decarbonize Well Cementing; Proceedings of the SPE EOR Conference at Oil and Gas West Asia; Muscat, Oman. 22&#x2013;24 April 2024;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/218822-ms</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakovlev A., Lafitte V., Kapoor S., Meade M., Smith W., Fischer N., Parton C., Richter McDonald V., Nenjerama Y., Wei X. Proceedings of the SPE International Conference on Oilfield Chemistry. SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2023. An Innovative and Sustainable Portland Cement Alternative for Oil and Gas Wells; p. D011S006R001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruszewski M., Glissner M., Hahn S., Wittig V. Alkali-Activated Aluminosilicate Sealing System for Deep High-Temperature Well Applications. Geothermics. 2021;89:101935. doi: 10.1016/j.geothermics.2020.101935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geothermics.2020.101935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burciaga-D&#xed;az O., Betancourt-Castillo I.E., Escalante-Garc&#xed;a J.I. Limestone and Class C Fly Ash Blends Activated with Binary Alkalis of Na2CO3&#x2013;NaOH and MgO&#x2013;NaOH: Reaction Products and Environmental Impact. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2023;137:104949. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.104949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.104949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Ma Z., Zhang B., Gong F. Mitigation of Autogenous Shrinkage in Alkali-activated Slag (AAS) Using Doped Diatomaceous Earth (DE) J. Am. Ceram. Soc. 2025;108:e20704. doi: 10.1111/jace.20704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jace.20704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peknikova A., Jerabek J., Gandel R., Gabor R., Bilek V., Sucharda O. Physical&#x2013;Mechanical Behavior of High-Performance Concrete and Ordinary Concrete with Portland Cement Mixtures After Exposure to Selected Durability Tests Including High Thermal Stress. Buildings. 2025;15:1029. doi: 10.3390/buildings15071029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15071029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Chen X., Peng Z., Zhou Y., Li Y., Jian W., Fan Z., Chen Y. Cleaner Geopolymer Prepared by Co-Activation of Gasification Coal Fly Ash and Steel Slag: Durability Properties and Economic Assessment. Front. Environ. Sci. Eng. 2023;17:150. doi: 10.1007/s11783-023-1750-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11783-023-1750-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y., Wang Y., Zhang Z., Ma Y., Wang H. Thermal Stability of Limestone Calcined Clay Cement (LC3) at Moderate Temperatures 100&#x2013;400 &#xb0;C. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2023;135:104832. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H., Kim K., Kim T., Kim G.-W. Permeability and Strength of Cements Exposed to Supercritical CO2 for Varying Periods. J. Eng. Geol. 2016;26:117&#x2013;128. doi: 10.9720/kseg.2016.1.117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9720/kseg.2016.1.117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu B., He P., Liu J., Peng Z., Song B., Hu X. Microstructure of Portland Cement Paste Subjected to Different CO2 Concentrations and Further Water Curing. J. CO2 Util. 2021;53:101714. doi: 10.1016/j.jcou.2021.101714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcou.2021.101714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou H., Dong X., Duan Z., Ma Y., Gao D. Cement Integrity Loss Due to Interfacial Debonding and Radial Cracking during CO2 Injection. Energies. 2020;13:4589. doi: 10.3390/en13174589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en13174589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anya A., Khalifeh M., Kamali M., Haddad Y., Joppe L.C. Proceedings of the SPE/IADC Drilling Conference and Exhibition. SPE; Richardson, TX, USA: 2024. Replacing Portland Cement with Granite-Based Geopolymers for Oil Well Applications; Conventional Two-Part System; p. D011S009R004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moein M.M., Moein A.M., Saradar A., Rigby S., Tazari H., Karakouzian M. Mechanical Properties of Portland Cement Concrete Mixed with Different Doses of Recycled Brick Powder and Steel Fiber. Heliyon. 2025;11:e41900. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2025.e41900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2025.e41900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11786684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39897841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel H., Johnson K., Martinez R. Triazine Polymers for Improving Elastic Properties in Oil Well Cements; Proceedings of the SPE International Conference on Oilfield Chemistry; The Woodlands, TX, USA. 6&#x2013;7 December 2021;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/204333-ms</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakharev T. Resistance of Geopolymer Materials to Acid Attack. Cem. Concr. Res. 2005;35:658&#x2013;670. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.06.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.06.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saillio M., Baroghel-Bouny V., Pradelle S., Bertin M., Vincent J., de Lacaillerie J.-B. d&#x2019;Espinose Effect of Supplementary Cementitious Materials on Carbonation of Cement Pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;142:106358. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adewuyi A.P., Mojakgesa K.T. Influence of Slag and Fly Ash as Supplementary Cementitious Materials on Properties of Concrete. J. Multidiscip. Eng. Sci. Stud. 2020;6:3656&#x2013;3662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiabadi S.H., Khalifeh M., van Noort R., Silva Santos Moreira P.H. Review on Geopolymers as Wellbore Sealants: State of the Art Optimization for CO2 Exposure and Perspectives. ACS Omega. 2023;8:23320&#x2013;23345. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c01777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c01777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10323953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37426265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barr&#xed;a J., Bagheri M., Manzanal D., Shariatipour S., Pereira J.-M. Poromechanical Analysis of Oil Well Cements in CO2-Rich Environments. Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control. 2022;119:103734. doi: 10.1016/j.ijggc.2022.103734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijggc.2022.103734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutisya S.M., Kalinichev A.G. Carbonation Reaction Mechanisms of Portlandite Predicted from Enhanced Ab Initio Molecular Dynamics Simulations. Minerals. 2021;11:509. doi: 10.3390/min11050509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min11050509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannoukos K., Rigby S.P., Rochelle C.A., Milodowski A.E., Hall M.R. Carbonation Rate and Microstructural Alterations of Class G Cement under Geological Storage Conditions. Appl. Geochem. 2021;131:105007. doi: 10.1016/j.apgeochem.2021.105007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apgeochem.2021.105007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamaa G., Duarte A.P.C., Silva R.V., de Brito J. Carbonation of Alkali-Activated Materials: A Review. Materials. 2023;16:3086. doi: 10.3390/ma16083086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16083086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10140813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37109923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han W., Lv Y., Wang S., Qiao J., Zou C., Su M., Peng H. Effects of Al/Na and Si/Na Molar Ratios on the Alkalinity of Metakaolin-Based Geopolymer Pore Solutions. Materials. 2023;16:1929. doi: 10.3390/ma16051929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16051929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10003817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36903044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakkor O. Durability and Microstructural Evaluation of Geopolymer Mortars Exposed to Sulphuric Acid Using Industrial By-Product Fillers. Polymers. 2025;17:2310. doi: 10.3390/polym17172310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym17172310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12431282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40942228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim M.U., Moro C. Microstructural Insights of Geopolymer Mortar Containing Cenosphere: Effects on Fresh Properties and Durability. Mater. Struct. 2025;58:101. doi: 10.1617/s11527-025-02636-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-025-02636-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen T.N., Phung Q.T., Frederickx L., Jacques D., Dauzeres A., Elsen J., Pontikes Y. Microstructural Evolution and Its Impact on the Mechanical Strength of Typical Alkali-Activated Slag Subjected to Accelerated Carbonation. Dev. Built Environ. 2024;19:100519. doi: 10.1016/j.dibe.2024.100519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dibe.2024.100519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Rojo L., Soler J.M., D&#xe1;vila G., Chaparro M.C., Queralt I., Cama J. Flow and Reaction along the Interface between Hydrated Portland Cement and Calcareous Rocks during CO2 Injection. Laboratory Experiments and Modeling. Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control. 2021;108:103331. doi: 10.1016/j.ijggc.2021.103331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijggc.2021.103331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhino K., Iyer J., Walsh S., Smith M. Impact of Mechanical and Chemical Alteration on CO2 Leakage at the Cement-Casing Interface; Proceedings of the Goldschmidt2021 Conference; Online. 4&#x2013;9 July 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habarudin M., Shafiq N., Izwan A., Hamid A., Zulkarnain N., Amirhilmi A., Razak A., Humairah S., Rahman A. Optimization of Graphene-Enhanced Geopolymer Cement for Oil Well Applications. J. Hunan Univ. Nat. Sci. 2024;51:6. doi: 10.55463/issn.1674-2974.51.6.32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55463/issn.1674-2974.51.6.32</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Y., Qiao J., Han W., Pan B., Jin X., Peng H. Modification Effect of Ca(OH)2 on the Carbonation Resistance of Fly Ash-Metakaolin-Based Geopolymer. Materials. 2023;16:2305. doi: 10.3390/ma16062305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16062305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10056939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36984186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benli A., Dheyaaldin M.H., &#xd6;z A., Kara &#x130;.B., Kaplan G., Ayd&#x131;n A.C. Sustainable Single and Hybrid Fiber Reinforcement of Ternary Geopolymer Composites with Waste Marble Powder: Synergistic Effects of Micro Steel, Basalt, and Carbon Fibers. Struct. Concr. 2025 doi: 10.1002/suco.70173. early view .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.70173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang T., Huang B.-Y., Zhan Z.-F., Huang Y.-W., Wang L., Li M., Xie Z.-H., Li J.-F., Su J.-Y. Fracture Properties of High-Performance High-Ductility Alkali-Activated Concrete Under Thermo-Mechanical Coupling: Effect of Fiber Hybrid Ratio. Polymers. 2025;17:2568. doi: 10.3390/polym17192568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym17192568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12526869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41096214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gailitis R., Sprince A., &#x141;ach M., Gavrilovs P., Pakrastins L. Cyclic Load Impact Assessment of Long-Term Properties in Compression to Steel and Polyvinyl Alcohol Fibre-Reinforced Geopolymer Composites. Materials. 2023;16:6128. doi: 10.3390/ma16186128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16186128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10532526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37763405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samal S., Blanco I. An Application Review of Fiber-Reinforced Geopolymer Composite. Fibers. 2021;9:23. doi: 10.3390/fib9040023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fib9040023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin L., Yan J., Zhou M., Liu H., Wang A., Zhang W., Duan P., Zhang Z. Mechanical Properties and Durability of Fiber Reinforced Geopolymer Composites: A Review on Recent Progress. Eng. Rep. 2023;5:e12708. doi: 10.1002/eng2.12708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eng2.12708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv C., Liu J. Alkaline Degradation of Plant Fiber Reinforcements in Geopolymer: A Review. Molecules. 2023;28:1868. doi: 10.3390/molecules28041868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules28041868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36838855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyebisi S., Ede A., Olutoge F., Ogbiye S. Evaluation of Reactivity Indexes and Durability Properties of Slag-Based Geopolymer Concrete Incorporating Corn Cob Ash. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;258:119604. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo L.B.R., Targino D.L.L., Babadopulos L.F.A.L., Costa H.N., Cabral A.E.B., Bastos J.B.S. Microstructural, Mechanical and Fresh-State Performance of BOF Steel Slag in Alkali-Activated Binders: Experimental Characterization and Parametric Mix Design Method. Buildings. 2025;15:2056. doi: 10.3390/buildings15122056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15122056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naresh T., Mallik M., Venkateswara Rao S., Dubey S. Performance and Microstructural Optimization of Sustainable Geopolymer Mortars Using Fly Ash, Ground Granulated Blast Furnace Slag, and Rice Husk Ash. Struct. Concr. 2025;26:7863&#x2013;7889. doi: 10.1002/suco.70192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.70192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldawsari S., Kampmann R., Harnisch J., Rohde C. Setting Time, Microstructure, and Durability Properties of Low Calcium Fly Ash/Slag Geopolymer: A Review. Materials. 2022;15:876. doi: 10.3390/ma15030876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15030876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8838795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35160820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasyunina N., Dubova I., Druzhinin K., Alekseev A., Gilmanshina T., Rudnitsky E. Methods for Extracting Valuable Elements (Fe, Al, Na, Ti) from Red Mud. Ecol. Ind. Russ. 2020;24:32&#x2013;38. doi: 10.18412/1816-0395-2020-9-32-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18412/1816-0395-2020-9-32-38</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves A.V., Lima V.N., Lima I.N., Letichevsky S., de Avillez R.R., de Andrade Silva F. The Influence of H2S and CO2 on the Triaxial Behavior of Class G Cement Paste under Elevated Temperature and Pressure. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 2024;240:213084. doi: 10.1016/j.geoen.2024.213084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoen.2024.213084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahsin A., Borno I.B., Ahmed N., Nair N., Ashraf W., Hollenbeck C. Evaluation of Low-Carbon Cementitious Composites in Marine Environment for Coastal Protection and Artificial Reef Substrate. npj Mater. Degrad. 2025;9:116. doi: 10.1038/s41529-025-00652-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41529-025-00652-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain S.S., Akhtar F. Recent Progress of Geopolymers for Carbon Dioxide Capture, Storage and Conversion. J. CO2 Util. 2023;78:102631. doi: 10.1016/j.jcou.2023.102631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcou.2023.102631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lingyu T., Dongpo H., Jianing Z., Hongguang W. Durability of Geopolymers and Geopolymer Concretes: A Review. Rev. Adv. Mater. Sci. 2021;60:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1515/rams-2021-0002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/rams-2021-0002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akturk B., Abolfathi M., Ulukaya S., Kizilkanat A.B., Hooper T.J.N., Gu L., Yang E.-H., Unluer C. Hydration Kinetics and Performance of Sodium Carbonate-Activated Slag-Based Systems Containing Reactive MgO and Metakaolin under Carbonation. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;132:104617. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojedokun O.O., Mangat P.S. Chemical Composition and Physico-Mechanical Properties of Carbonated Alkali Activated Concrete and Mortar. J. Build. Eng. 2023;71:106480. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricciotti L., Frettoloso C., Franchino R., Pisacane N., Aversa R. Geopolymer Materials: Cutting-Edge Solutions for Sustainable Design Building. Sustainability. 2025;17:7483. doi: 10.3390/su17167483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su17167483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madirisha M.M., Ikotun B.D. The Future of Geothermal Wellbore Integrity: Geopolymer Cements for Enhanced Stability and Hydrogen Coproduction. Int. J. Energy Res. 2025;2025:6641119. doi: 10.1155/er/6641119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/er/6641119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki T., Soga K., Abuhaikal M. Water Absorption and Shrinkage Behaviour of Early-Age Cement in Wellbore Annulus. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2018;169:205&#x2013;219. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2018.05.065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2018.05.065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson E.B. Well Cementing. Newnes; London, UK: 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khasawneh M.A. Geopolymer Concrete in Construction Projects: A Review. Discov. Civ. Eng. 2025;2:124. doi: 10.1007/s44290-025-00281-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44290-025-00281-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Noaimat Y.A., Ghaffar S.H., Chougan M., Al-Kheetan M.J. A Review of 3D Printing Low-Carbon Concrete with One-Part Geopolymer: Engineering, Environmental and Economic Feasibility. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e01818. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adnan, Anas M. Geopolymer Concrete as a Sustainable Alternative to OPC. J. Umm Al-Qura Univ. Eng. Archit. 2025;16:1223&#x2013;1245. doi: 10.1007/s43995-025-00155-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43995-025-00155-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barve P., Bahrami A., Shah S. A Comprehensive Review on Effects of Material Composition, Mix Design, and Mixing Regimes on Rheology of 3D-Printed Geopolymer Concrete. Open Constr. Build. Technol. J. 2024;18:e18748368292859. doi: 10.2174/0118748368292859240313061706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/0118748368292859240313061706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>