<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41723345</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mortality and its predictors among adolescents and adults on antiretroviral therapy in the era of test-and-treat, Ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">655</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-12919-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">HIV/AIDS remains a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in resource-limited settings. Although several studies have assessed mortality among patients on antiretroviral therapy (ART), evidence from Ethiopia during the test-and-treat era, where all diagnosed individuals start ART immediately regardless of clinical stage or CD4 count, is limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective cohort study was conducted at public hospitals in the West Arsi Zone, involving 446 adolescents and adults on ART between August 2016 and June 2019. Participants were selected by stratified random sampling at three randomly selected hospitals. Data were extracted from the patient cards and electronic databases. Cox proportional hazard regression was fitted to identify predictors of mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among 446 patients followed for 13,860 person-months, early mortality predominated, with 28 (59.57%) deaths occurring within the first 6 months of ART initiation. Overall, 47 (10.54%) patients died, yielding an all-cause mortality rate of 4.07 (95% CI: 3.14&#x2013;5.19) per 100 person-years. The cumulative survival at the end of follow-up was 87.37% (95% CI: 83.46&#x2013;90.41). The predictors of mortality were age group&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;35 (AHR 2.51, 95% CI: 1.17&#x2013;5.37), rural residence (AHR 1.77, 95% CI: 1.09&#x2013;2.89), WHO clinical stage 3 or 4 (AHR 4.16, 95% CI: 1.89&#x2013;9.16), bedridden functional status (AHR 8.48, 95% CI: 3.19&#x2013;22.52), TB coinfection (AHR 3.69, 95% CI: 1.95&#x2013;6.98), moderate or severe anemia (AHR 4.15, 95% CI: 2.16&#x2013;7.97), and non-disclosure of HIV status (AHR 3.86, 95% CI: 1.93&#x2013;7.72).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study highlights substantial early mortality among patients receiving ART and identified key clinical and demographic predictors of mortality. These findings underscore the need for targeted interventions to improve survival outcomes. Policy makers and program managers should prioritize early diagnosis and treatment initiation, strengthen tuberculosis screening programs and disclosure counseling, and ensure close monitoring of patients with advanced disease, anemia, and those residing in rural areas.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">Clinical trial number: Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12879-026-12919-1.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jarso</LastName><ForeName>Habtemu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, School of Health Science, Madda Walabu University Shashemene Campus, P.O. Box 238, Shashemene, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jilo</LastName><ForeName>Jemal</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shashemene Comprehensive Specialized Hospital, Shashemene, Ethiopia. jilojemal1@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Negawo</LastName><ForeName>Shumi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, School of Health Science, Madda Walabu University Shashemene Campus, P.O. Box 238, Shashemene, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geda</LastName><ForeName>Biftu</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, School of Health Science, Madda Walabu University Shashemene Campus, P.O. Box 238, Shashemene, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Kemal</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, School of Health Science, Madda Walabu University Shashemene Campus, P.O. Box 238, Shashemene, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rullo</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuele Venanzi</ForeName><Initials>EV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical and Experimental Medicine, Unit of Infectious Diseases, University of Messina, Policlinico Universitario "G. Martino", Messina, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spigt</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, School CAPHRI, Care and Public Health Research Institute, Maastricht University, P.O. Box 616, Maastricht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antiretroviral</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Death</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Test-and-treat</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in according with the Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical clearance was obtained from the Ethical Review Committee of Madda Walabu University Shashemene Campus. Confidentiality of the information was maintained by omitting the names and identities of patients and storing filled checklists in secured areas. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41723345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13032719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-12919-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-12919-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Melhuish A, Lewthwaite P. Natural history of HIV and AIDS. Medicine. 2018;46(6):356&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mpmed.2018.03.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS). Fact sheet 2025 &#x2013; Global HIV &amp; AIDS statistics. Geneva: UNAIDS; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian Public Health Institute (EPHI). HIV Related Estimates and Projections in Ethiopia for the Year 2023&#x2013;2024. Addis Ababa: EPHI; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinkels H, Nguyen A, Gulick P. HIV and AIDS. StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. [updated 2024 Jul 27].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Indunil K, Asoka J, Vidanagama U, Fernando C, Ekanayake U, Hapuarachchi T, et al. Advancements in HIV treatment from ART to cure strategies. Uva Clin Anaesth Intensive Care; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Guidelines for managing advanced HIV disease and rapid initiation of antiretroviral therapy. Geneva: WHO; 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29341560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bantie B, Kassaw Yirga G, Abate MW, Amare AT, Nigat AB, Tigabu A, et al. Delayed ART initiation in Test and Treat era and its associated factors among adults receiving antiretroviral therapy at public health institutions in Northwest Ethiopia: A multicenter cross-sectional study. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(7):e0271127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0271127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9312408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35877661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed I, Demissie M, Worku A, Gugsa S, Berhane Y. Effectiveness of same-day antiretroviral therapy initiation in retention outcomes among people living with human immunodeficiency virus in Ethiopia: empirical evidence. BMC Public Health. 2020;20:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-09887-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekele A, Hrapcak S, Mohammed JA, Yimam JA, Tilahun T, Antefe T, et al. Rates of confirmatory HIV testing, linkage to HIV services, and rapid initiation of antiretroviral treatment among newly diagnosed children living with HIV in Ethiopia: perspectives from caregivers and healthcare workers. BMC Pediatr. 2022;22(1):736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-022-03784-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9791729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36572846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Consolidated guidelines on the use of antiretroviral drugs for treating and preventing HIV infection: recommendations for a public health approach. 2nd ed. Geneva: WHO; 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27466667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girum T, Yasin F, Wasie A, Shumbej T, Bekele F, Zeleke B. The effect of universal test and treat program on HIV treatment outcomes and patient survival among a cohort of adults taking antiretroviral treatment (ART) in low income settings of Gurage zone, South Ethiopia. AIDS Res Ther. 2020;17:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12981-020-00274-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32423457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayisa L, Abera T, Mulisa D, Mosisa G, Mosisa A, Tolosa T, et al. Time to antiretroviral therapy initiation and its predictors among newly diagnosed HIV-Positive people in Nekemte Town, Western Ethiopia: claim of universal test and treat. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2021;13:959&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8519411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34675687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishi M. Care during ART scale-up: surviving the HIV epidemic in Ethiopia. Biosocieties. 2022;1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9527715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian Federal Minister of Health (FMOH). National Comprehensive HIV Prevention, Care and Treatment Training Participant Manual. Addis Ababa: FMOH; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian Federal Minister of Health (FMOH). National Consolidated Guidelines for Comprehensive HIV Prevention, Care and Treatment: Pocket Guide. Addis Ababa: FMOH; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merid F, Guyo TG, Wagaye S, Mekuria M, Anbesie A, Toma TM. Uptake and associated factors of six multi-month scripting/appointment spacing differentiated service delivery model of care among stable clients on antiretroviral therapy in Southern Ethiopia. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11392334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39264931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Ministry of Health Ethiopia (FMOH). Implementation guide for community-based differentiated ART service delivery models in Ethiopia. Addis Ababa: FMOH; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayalew MB. Mortality and its predictors among HIV infected patients taking antiretroviral treatment in Ethiopia: a systematic review. AIDS Res Treat. 2017;2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5682904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29214077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tekelehaimanot AN, Belachew T, Gudina EK, Getnet M, Amdisa D, Dadi LS. Predictors of mortality among adult people living with HIV and its implications for appointment spacing model approach care. Ethiop J Health Sci. 2021;31(5):925&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8843146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35221608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argaw GS, Gelaye KA, Lakew AM, Aragaw FM, Chekol YM, Tesfie TK, et al. Survival and predictors of mortality among HIV-infected adults after initiation of antiretroviral therapy in Eastern Ethiopia governmental hospitals, from January 2015 to December 2021 (multi-center retrospective follow-up study). BMC Infect Dis. 2024;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11600927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39592986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birhanu A, Dingeta T, Tolera M. Predictors of mortality among adult HIV-infected patients taking antiretroviral therapy (ART) in Harari hospitals, Ethiopia. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2021;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8259829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34239331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barata TY, Abiso G, Israel E, Molla S, Wolka E. Incidence of mortality and its predictors among adult human immune virus infected patients on antiretroviral therapy in Wolaita Sodo University Comprehensive Specialized Hospital, Southern Ethiopia: a retrospective follow-up study. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2023;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10289094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37359271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfayohannes S, Shine S. Mortality and its predictors among adult human immune-deficiency virus-infected patients attending their antiretroviral treatment at health centers, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: multicenter retrospective cohort study. AIDS Res Treat. 2022;2022:6128718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9512605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36172060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuto W, Abera A. Survival and predictors of mortality among HIV positive adult patients on highly active antiretroviral therapy in public hospitals of Kambata Tambaro Zone, Southern Ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2021;13:271&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7966412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33737838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigussie F, Alamer A. Survival and predictors of mortality among adult HIV/AIDS patients initiating highly active antiretroviral therapy in Debre-Berhan Referral Hospital, Amhara, Ethiopia: a retrospective study. HIV AIDS (Auckl). 2020;12:757&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7680687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye B, Ermias D, Moges S, Astatk A. Effect of the test and treat strategy on mortality among HIV-positive adult clients on antiretroviral treatment in public hospitals of Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. HIV AIDS (Auckl; 2021. p. 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8020807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morka B, Belay Keno F, Gebre DS, Fikadu W, Tiruneh G, Golja EA, et al. Time to death and its predictors among HIV patients on antiretroviral therapy in public health facilities of Horro Guduru Wallaga zone, Ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study. Front Public Health. 2025;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12040889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40308933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS). Global HIV Target Setting for 2030: Global Task Team on 2030 Targets Recommendations. Geneva: UNAIDS; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS). Global AIDS Strategy 2021&#x2013;2026 &#x2013; End Inequalities. End AIDS. Geneva: UNAIDS; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teka Z, Mohammed K, Workneh G, Gizaw Z. Survival of HIV/AIDS patients treated under ART follow-up at the University Hospital, northwest Ethiopia. Environ Health Prev Med. 2021;26(52).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8091691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33941074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadege M. Time to death predictors of HIV/AIDS infected patients on antiretroviral therapy in Ethiopia. BMC Res Notes. 2018;11(1):761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-018-3863-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6202867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30359289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse K, Haile F, Hiruy N. Predictors of mortality among patients enrolled on antiretroviral therapy in Aksum Hospital, northern Ethiopia: a retrospective cohort study. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(1):e87392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0087392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3909114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24498093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz MH. Multivariable analysis: a practical guide for clinicians and public health researchers. 3rd ed. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Consolidated guidelines on person-centred HIV strategic information: strengthening routine data for impact. Geneva: WHO; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopian Federal Minister of Health (FMOH). National adolescents and youth health strategy (2021&#x2013;2025). Addis Ababa: FMOH; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Guideline on haemoglobin cutoffs to define anaemia in individuals and populations. Geneva: WHO; 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38530913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebede A, Tessema F, Bekele G, Kura Z, Merga H. Epidemiology of survival pattern and its predictors among HIV positive patients on highly active antiretroviral therapy in Southern Ethiopia public health facilities: a retrospective cohort study. AIDS Res Ther. 2020;17(1):49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12981-020-00307-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32758247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldegeorgis BZ, Asgedom YS, Habte A, Kassie GA, Badacho AS. Highly active antiretroviral therapy is necessary but not sufficient. a systematic review and meta-analysis of mortality incidence rates and predictors among HIV-infected adults receiving treatment in Ethiopia, a surrogate study for resource-poor settings. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):1735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-19268-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11214252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38943123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aemro A, Wassie M, Chekol B. Incidence and predictors of mortality within the first year of antiretroviral therapy initiation at Debre-Markos Referral Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia: a retrospective follow up study. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(5):e0251648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0251648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8121335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33989330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nura GJ, Wario KS, Erango MA. Determinants of survival time for HIV/AIDS patients in the pastoralist region of Borena: a study at Yabelo General Hospital, South East Ethiopia. AIDS Res Ther. 2024;21(1):58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12981-024-00644-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11360864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39198844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>