<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41507903</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1742-4755</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reproductive health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Reprod Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors associated with married adolescent girls' and young women's participation in decision-making regarding sexual and reproductive health in Tanzania: a nationwide cross-sectional survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>38</StartPage><MedlinePgn>38</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">38</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12978-025-02264-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Married adolescent girls and young women's (AGYW) participation in sexual and reproductive health (SRH) decision-making is a critical factor for their overall health and well-being. High adolescent fertility rates and disparities in healthcare decision-making participation highlight a significant gap in understanding the dynamics that influence AGYW's involvement in SRH decisions. Therefore, this study aimed to address this gap by examining the factors associated with married AGYW's participation in decision-making regarding SRH in Tanzania.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study design was employed. This study analyzed secondary data from the 2022 Tanzania Demographic and Health Survey and Malaria Indicator Survey (TDHS-MIS), focusing on a weighted sample of 2,178 married AGYW. The data were weighted using the individual weight for women (v005/1,000,000). Multivariable modified Poisson regression was used to identify factors significantly associated with married AGYW's participation in decision-making regarding SRH. Statistical significance was determined at the 5% level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study found that the participation of married AGYW in SRH decision-making was 41% (95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;37.4, 44.0). Participation decision-making varied across zones, with the highest in the Southern highlands (72.3%) and the lowest in the Western zone (15.4%). The study found that having primary education (APR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.31, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.05, 1.64), secondary education/higher (APR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.87, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.45, 2.42), being employed (APR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.28, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.12, 1.47), listening to radio (APR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.34, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.15, 1.56), covered by health insurance (APR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.30, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.04, 1.62), husband /partner with primary education (APR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.32, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.02, 1.72) and secondary/higher education (APR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.35, 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.02, 1.80) had significantly associated with participation in decision-making regarding SRH among AGYW.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results indicate that AGYW participation in SRH decision-making remains low. To enhance the involvement of married AGYW in these decisions, it is essential to implement targeted educational programs that include workshops and community-based education, especially for those with limited educational backgrounds. Furthermore, empowering women through various economic activities is crucial. Stakeholders should intensify their efforts to achieve universal health coverage for AGYW, ensuring equitable access to SRH services.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Jovinary</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. adamjovinary3@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zablon</LastName><ForeName>Tunu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abihudi</LastName><ForeName>Siri</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Traditional Medicine, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, P. O. Box 65001, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luoga</LastName><ForeName>Pankras</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mbise</LastName><ForeName>Furahini</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Medical Research, Muhimbili Center, Box 3436, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nyamhanga</LastName><ForeName>Tumaini</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Development Studies, School of Public Health and Social Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Reprod Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101224380</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1742-4755</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003657" MajorTopicYN="Y">Decision Making</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013636" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Tanzania</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060728" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reproductive Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074384" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sexual Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008393" MajorTopicYN="Y">Marriage</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012725" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sexual Behavior</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent girls</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Decision-making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Participation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sexual and reproductive health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Young women</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study used secondary data which are freely available to the public upon request to The DHS program website ( https://dhsprogram.com ). In this case, we were granted approval to access the data after submitting our concept note to the DHS custodian. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41507903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12882248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-025-02264-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12978-025-02264-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>United Nations Children&#x2019;s Fund (UNICEF). Is an end to child marriage within reach? Is an end to within reach child marriage latest trends futur prospect 2023. Updat. 2023;1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNFPA-UNICEF. Cost of Ending ChildMarriage. Transform Result End Gender-Based Violence All Harmful Pract. 2020;28&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNICEF. Child marriage interventions and research from 2020 to 2022. United Nations Child Fund. 2023;(January):1&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kagoye SA, Jahanpour O, Ngoda OA, Obure J, Mahande MJ, Renju J. Trends and determinants of unmet need for modern contraception among adolescent girls and young women in Tanzania, 2004&#x2013;2016. Austin N, editor. PLOS Glob Public Heal. 2024;4(1):e0000695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0000695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38170707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soeiro RE, de Siqueira Guida JP, Da-Costa-Santos J, Costa ML. Sexual and reproductive health (SRH) needs for forcibly displaced adolescent girls and young women (10&#x2013;24 years old) in humanitarian settings: a mixed-methods systematic review. Reprod Health. 2023;20(1):174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-023-01715-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10668438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37996929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OECD. Social institutions and gender Index - Country report for Tanzania. OECD; 2022. p. 182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakubu I, Salisu WJ. Determinants of adolescent pregnancy in sub-Saharan africa: a systematic review. Reprod Health. 2018;15(1):15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-018-0460-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5787272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29374479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaya S, Odusina EK, Bishwajit G. Prevalence of child marriage and its impact on fertility outcomes in 34 sub-Saharan African countries. BMC Int Health Hum Rights. 2019;19(1):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12914-019-0219-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6924035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31856810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonen EG. Pooled prevalence and associated factors of teenage pregnancy among women aged 15 to 19 years in sub-Saharan africa: evidence from 2019 to 2022 demographic and health survey data. Contracept Reprod Med. 2024;9(1):26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40834-024-00289-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11112827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38778418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahinkorah BO, Kang M, Perry L, Brooks F, Hayen A. Prevalence of first adolescent pregnancy and its associated factors in sub-Saharan Africa: A multi-country analysis. Ortega JA, editor. PLoS One. 2021;16(2):e0246308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7861528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33539394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santhya KG, Ram U, Acharya R, Jejeebhoy SJ, Ram F, Singh A. Associations between early marriage and young women&#x2019;s marital and reproductive health outcomes: evidence from India. Int Fam Plan Perspect. 2010;36(3):132&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1363/3613210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20880798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNAIDS. We&#x2019;ve got the power &#x2014; Women, adolescent girls and the HIV response. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lami M, Negash A, Eyeberu A, Birhanu A, Debella A, Getachew T et al. Prevalence of child marriage and associated factors among reproductive age women in Harari regional state, eastern Ethiopia, 2022: a community-based study. BMC Womens Health. 2023;23(1):267. Available from: 10.1186/s12905-023-02409-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37194015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadele A, Tesfay A, Kebede A. Factors influencing decision-making power regarding reproductive health and rights among married women in Mettu rural district, south-west, Ethiopia. Reprod Health. 2019;16(1):155. Available from: 10.1186/s12978-019-0813-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6819561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31665037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matovu KBJ, Amongin D, Akulume M, Tuhebwe D, Murungi I, Wanyenze RK. Contraception decision-making autonomy among adolescent girls and young women in Uganda. npj Women&#x2019;s Heal. 2025;3(1):14. Available from: 10.1038/s44294-025-00066-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uganda Bureau of Statistics. Uganda demographic and health survey 2022. Volume 1. Kampala, Uganda: UBOS; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TDHS. Demographic and Health Survey and Malaria Indicator Survey. Pap Knowl Towar a Media Hist Doc. 2022;1&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNFPA. Fact Sheet: Family Planning. 2018;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temba A, Ngoye E, George R, Agarwal A. Leaving No Young Person Behind: Addressing the Contraception Needs of Young People in Tanzania. 2021;1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessy IP, Eliufoo E, Godfrey V, Bago M, Nyundo A, Mtoro MJ. Predictors of modern contraceptive use among adolescent girls and young women in Tanzania: Insights from a nationwide survey. Discov Public Heal. 2025;22(1):225. Available from: 10.1186/s12982-025-00615-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations. Department of Economic and Social Affairs PD. Family Planning and the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. Creative Commons license (CC BY 3.0 IGO 2019. (ST/ESA/ SER.A/429).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Republic of Tanzania, MOHCDGEC. National accelerated action and investment agenda for adolescent health and wellbeing (NAIA-AHW) 2021/22&#x2013;2024/25. Dodoma: United Republic of Tanzania; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Republic of Tanzania, MOHCDGEC. National adolescent health and development strategy 2018&#x2013;2022. Dodoma: United Republic of Tanzania; 2018. pp. 1&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kihwele G, Mbele MN, Millanzi WC. Evaluating the implementation fidelity of National standards for adolescent- and youth-friendly sexual and reproductive health services in Tanzania: a descriptive cross-sectional survey. Reprod Heal. 2025;22(1):2-14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12486639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41029823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MoH. National adolescent reproductive health strategy 2011&#x2013;2015. Ministry of Health and Social Welfare . 2015;(February 2011):1-45</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health (MoH) [Tanzania Mainland], Ministry of Health (MoH). [Zanzibar], National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) O of the CGS (OCGS). Demographic and Health Survey and Malaria Indicator Survey (TDHS-MIS) 2022 Final Report. Demographic and Health Survey and Malaria Indicator Survey (TDHS-MIS) 2022. Dodoma, Tanzania, and Rockville, Maryland, USA: MoH, NBS, OCGS, and ICF; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demissie GD, Akalu Y, Gelagay AA, Alemnew W, Yeshaw Y. Factors associated with decision-making power of married women to use family planning in sub-Saharan Africa: a multilevel analysis of demographic health surveys. BMC Public Health. 2022;22(1):837. Available from: 10.1186/s12889-022-13251-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35473613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negasa YT, Teferi E, Darega J, Solbana LK. Married women&#x2019;s Decision-Making power on family planning utilization and associated factors among married women in Jeldu District, ethiopia: an implication for women empowerment. Heal Sci Rep. 2025;8(7):e71003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.71003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12239032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40636525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokharel A, Pokharel SD. Women&#x2019;s involvement in decision-making and receiving husbands&#x2019; support for their reproductive healthcare: a cross-sectional study in Lalitpur, Nepal. Int Health. 2023;15(1):67&#x2013;76. Available from: 10.1093/inthealth/ihac034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9808508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35639520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mtae G. Decision-Making power and family planning use: A case of married women in Kishapu District, Tanzania. East Afr J Educ Soc Sci. 2021;2(Issue 4):136&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuler SR, Rottach E, Mukiri P. Gender norms and family planning decision-making in tanzania: a qualitative study. J Public Health Afr. 2011;2(2):e25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/jphia.2011.e25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5345498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28299066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HER Voice Fund. Tanzania Country Profile. Dar es Salaam: HER Voice Fund. 2024. pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghana Statistical Service (GSS), ICF. Ghana demographic and health survey 2022. Accra, Ghana, and Rockville. Maryland, USA: GSS and ICF; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KNBS ICF, Kenya Demographic. and Health Survey 2022: Volume 1. Nairobi, Kenya, and Rockville, Maryland, USA: KNBS and ICF.; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamangu AA, Mbago MCY. Provision of sexual health education in secondary schools: A multidisciplinary lens of stakeholders in southern highlands, Tanzania. Heliyon. 2024;10(9):e30846. Available from: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e30846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11101840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38765094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamangu A, Mbago M. Implementation of school-Based sexual health curriculum in tanzania: perspectives of secondary school adolescents in Southern highlands. Ghana J Geogr. 2024;16(2):22&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/gjg.v16i2.3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zulfiqar H, Aziz T, Syed R. Interplay of education in the lives of financially independent women: A qualitative analysis. Adv Soc Sci Arch J. 2025;03(01):325&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belay AD, Mengesha ZB, Woldegebriel MK, Gelaw YA. Married women&#x2019;s decision making power on family planning use and associated factors in Mizan-Aman, South ethiopia: A cross sectional study. BMC Womens Health. 2016;16(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-016-0290-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4782567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26952021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haruna TS, Duah HO, Lee R. Factors associated with health decision-making autonomy on own healthcare among Tanzanian women: A 2022&#x2013;2023 demographic health survey study. PLoS ONE. 2025;20(5 May):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12101699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40408344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onarheim KH, Iversen JH, Bloom DE. Economic benefits of investing in women&#x2019;s health: A systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(3):e0150120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0150120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4814064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27028199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nepal A, Dangol SK, Karki S, Shrestha N. Factors that determine women&#x2019;s autonomy to make decisions about sexual and reproductive health and rights in nepal: A cross-sectional study. PLOS Glob Public Heal. 2023;3(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10022137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belachew TB, Asmamaw DB, Belachew AB, Bayafers MW, Negash WD. Married women&#x2019;s decision-making autonomy on modern contraceptive use and its associated factors in high fertile sub-Saharan Africa countries: a multi-level analysis of demographic and health surveys. Arch Public Heal. 2023;81(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10642072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37953331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassahun A, Zewdie A. Decision-making autonomy in maternal health service use and associated factors among women in Mettu District, Southwest ethiopia: a community-based cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2022;12(5):e059307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-059307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9062806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35501088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haile A, Lonsako AA, Kebede FA, Adisu A, Elias A, Kasse T. Women autonomy in health care decision making and associated factors among postpartum women in Southern ethiopia: A Cross-Sectional study. Heal Sci Rep. 2024;7(12):e70245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.70245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11628633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39659820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zegeye B, Idriss-Wheeler D, Ahinkorah BO, Ameyaw EK, Seidu AA, Adjei NK, et al. Association between women&#x2019;s household decision-making autonomy and health insurance enrollment in sub-saharan Africa. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-15434-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10064715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36997885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sougou NM, Sougou AS, Bassoum O, L&#xe8;ye MMM, Faye A, Seck I. Actors associated with women&#x2019;s decision-making autonomy for their health in Senegal. Sante Publique. 2020;32(4):381&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3917/spub.204.0381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33512105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speizer IS, Story WT, Singh K. Factors associated with institutional delivery in ghana: the role of decision-making autonomy and community norms. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2014;14:398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12884-014-0398-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4247879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25427853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idris IB, Hamis AA, Bukhori ABM, Hoong DCC, Yusop H, Shaharuddin MAA, et al. Women&#x2019;s autonomy in healthcare decision making: a systematic review. BMC Womens Health. 2023;23(1):643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-023-02792-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10693143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38042837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey SE, Gallagher MC, Kakesa J, Kalyanpur A, Muselemu JB, Rafanoharana RV, et al. Contraceptive use among adolescent and young women in North and South Kivu, Democratic Republic of the congo: A cross-sectional population-based survey. PLoS Med. 2020;17(3):e1003086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7108687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32231356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ollomy F, Msuya SE, Todd J, Meku S, Samwel EL, Lutobeka J, et al. Trends and factors associated with modern contraceptive use among sexually active female youths in Tanzania, 2004&#x2013;2022. BMJ Open. 2025;15(10):e096878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2024-096878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12542531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41120150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury S, Haque MA. Understanding the issues of women&#x2019;s empowerment and fertility in Bangladesh. Reprod Health. 2025;22(1):185. Available from: 10.1186/s12978-025-02065-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12502350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41053805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sougou NM, Bassoum O, Faye A, Leye MMM. Women&#x2019;s autonomy in health decision-making and its effect on access to family planning services in Senegal in 2017: a propensity score analysis. BMC Public Health. 2020;20(1):872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-09003-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>