<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41446768</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2833-8278</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environment &amp; health (Washington, D.C.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Health (Wash)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>First Report on the Tissue Distributions and Habitat Differences of PFMOAA and Other PFAS in Veined Rapa Whelk (<i>Rapana venosa</i>).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1544</StartPage><EndPage>1553</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1544-1553</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/envhealth.5c00149</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Veined rapa whelks (<i>Rapana venosa</i>) are predatory marine snails that are widely distributed in the coastal water worldwide. In our previous studies, perfluoro-2-methoxy acetic acid (PFMOAA) has been found at extremely high levels in this species than in other benthos and fishes in estuaries and coastal waters. However, there is a knowledge gap regarding geographical bioaccumulative characteristics and tissue distribution patterns of PFMOAA in veined rapa whelk. This is the first study to investigate the tissue distributions of 17 legacy per- and polyfluoroalkyl substance (PFAS), 6 emerging polyfluoroether sulfonic acids (PFESAs), and 14 emerging perfluoroalkyl ether carboxylic acids (PFECAs) including PFMOAA in the kidney, liver, gill, foot, adductor muscle, Lebrin's gland, gonad, digestive tract, and mixed tissues of the veined rapa whelk (<i>R. venosa</i>) from five regions around the Bohai Sea. Overall, PFMOAA was consistently the predominant PFAS (20.7-93.7%) in all tissues. The kidney presented the highest PFAS concentration, followed by the gill, Lebrin's gland, digestive tract, and liver. Whelks from the Xiaoqing River Estuary showed the highest kidney &#x2211;PFAS level (mean 629.2 ng/g dw) compared to those from other regions (119.9 ng/g dw). For PFMOAA, the contributions of the foot and mixed tissues to the whole-body levels were relatively high despite their low concentrations in these tissues. PFOA and PFOS showed the highest concentrations and the largest contributions in terms of whole-body concentrations in Lebrin's glands and the livers, respectively. Further research on the toxicity of PFMOAA and its associated risks to the ecosystem and human beings are urgently needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Co-published by Research Center for Eco-Environmental Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Environmental Processes, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai 264003, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12381</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Yitao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6496-8174</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Environmental Health Impact Assessment of Emerging Contaminants, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200240, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12474</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yanan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Environmental Processes, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai 264003, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12381</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Environment, Taiyuan University of Science and Technology, Taiyuan 030024, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117763</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Fengfeng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Environmental Health Impact Assessment of Emerging Contaminants, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200240, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12474</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Zhenglin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Environmental Processes, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai 264003, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12381</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Jiayin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4908-5597</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Environmental Health Impact Assessment of Emerging Contaminants, School of Environmental Science and Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai 200240, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12474</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Jianhui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9006-263X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Coastal Environmental Processes, Yantai Institute of Coastal Zone Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yantai 264003, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12381</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pinglu Canal and Beibu Gulf Coastal Ecosystem Observation and Research Station of Guangxi, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Marine Environmental Change and Disaster in Beibu Gulf, College of Marine Sciences, Beibu Gulf University, Qinzhou 535011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Health (Wash)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918646069906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2833-8278</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Xiaoqing River Estuary</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emerging perfluoroalkyl ether carboxylic acids (PFECAs)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">geographical differences</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perfluoro-2-methoxy acetic acid (PFMOAA)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tissue distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">veined rapa whelk (Rapana venosa)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41446768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12723532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/envhealth.5c00149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Buck R. C., Franklin J., Berger U., Conder J. M., Cousins I. T., de Voogt P., Jensen A. A., Kannan K., Mabury S. A., van Leeuwen S. P. J.. Perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances in the environment: terminology, classification, and origins. Integr Environ. Assess Manag. 2011;7:513&#x2013;541. doi: 10.1002/ieam.258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ieam.258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3214619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21793199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kissa, E. Fluorinated Surfactants and Repellents. 2nd ed.; Marcel Dekker Inc.: New York, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T., Wang Y. W., Liao C. Y., Cai Y. Q., Jiang G. B.. Perspectives on the Inclusion of Perfluorooctane Sulfonate into the Stockholm Convention on Persistent Organic Pollutants. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2009;43(14):5171&#x2013;5175. doi: 10.1021/es900464a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es900464a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19708337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gl&#xfc;ge J., Scheringer M., Cousins I. T., DeWitt J. C., Goldenman G., Herzke D., Lohmann R., Ng C. A., Trier X., Wang Z. Y.. An overview of the uses of per-and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) Environ. Sci.: Processes Impacts. 2020;22(12):2345&#x2013;2373. doi: 10.1039/D0EM00291G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0EM00291G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7784712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33125022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson J. H., Salter M. E., Acosta Navarro J. C., Leck C., Nilsson E. D., Cousins I. T.. Global transport of perfluoroalkyl acids via sea spray aerosol. Environ. Sci.: Processes Impacts. 2019;21(4):635&#x2013;649. doi: 10.1039/C8EM00525G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C8EM00525G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30888351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindstrom A. B., Strynar M. J., Libelo E. L.. Polyfluorinated compounds: Past, present, and future. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2011;45(19):7954&#x2013;7961. doi: 10.1021/es2011622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es2011622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21866930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul A. G., Jones K. C., Sweetman A. J.. A first global production, emission, and environmental inventory for perfluorooctane sulfonate. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2009;43:386&#x2013;392. doi: 10.1021/es802216n.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es802216n</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19238969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z. Y., Cousins I. T., Scheringer M., Hungerbuehler K.. Hazard assessment of fluorinated alternatives to long-chain perfluoroalkyl acids (PFAAs) and their precursors: Status quo, ongoing challenges and possible solutions. Environ. Int. 2015;75:172&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1016/j.envint.2014.11.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2014.11.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan T., Lin Y. F., Wang T., Liu R. Z., Jiang G. B.. Identification of novel polyfluorinated ether sulfonates as PFOS alternatives in municipal sewage sludge in China. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2015;49(11):6519&#x2013;6527. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5b01010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5b01010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25961764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y. T., Zhang H. X., Cui Q. Q., Sheng N., Yeung L. W. Y., Sun Y., Guo Y., Dai J. Y.. Worldwide Distribution of Novel Perfluoroether Carboxylic and Sulfonic Acids in Surface Water. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2018;52(14):7621&#x2013;7629. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.8b00829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.8b00829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29749740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strynar M., Dagnino S., McMahen R., Liang S., Lindstrom A., Andersen E., McMillan L., Thurman M., Ferrer I., Ball C.. Identification of novel perfluoroalkyl ether carboxylic acids (PFECAs) and sulfonic acids (PFESAs) in natural waters using accurate mass Time-of-Flight Mass Spectrometry (TOFMS) Environ. Sci. Technol. 2015;759(49):11622&#x2013;11630. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5b01215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5b01215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26392038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Cousins I. T., Scheringer M., Hungerbuhler K.. Fluorinated alternatives to long-chain perfluoroalkyl carboxylic acids (PFCAs), perfluoroalkane sulfonic acids (PFSAs) and their potential precursors. Environ. Int. 2013;60:242&#x2013;248. doi: 10.1016/j.envint.2013.08.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2013.08.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24660230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joerss H., Menger F., Tang J. H., Ebinghaus R., Ahrens L.. Beyond the tip of the iceberg: suspect screening reveals point source-specific patterns of emerging and novel per-and polyfluoroalkyl substances in German and Chinese rivers. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2022;56(9):5456&#x2013;5465. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.1c07987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.1c07987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35446578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petre M. A., Genereux D. P., Koropeckyj-Cox L., Knappe D. R. U., Duboscq S., Gilmore T. E., Hopkins Z. R.. Per- and polyfluoroalkyl substance (PFAS) transport from groundwater to streams near a PFAS manufacturing facility in North Carolina, USA. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2021;55:5848&#x2013;5856. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.0c07978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.0c07978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33797238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y. N., Yao J. Z., Zhang J., Pan Y. T., Dai J. Y., Ji C. L., Tang J. H.. First report on the bioaccumulation and trophic transfer of perfluoroalkyl ether carboxylic acids in estuarine food web. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2022;56:6046&#x2013;6055. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.1c00965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.1c00965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34296857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y. T., Zhang H. X., Cui Q. Q., Sheng N., Yeung L. W. Y., Guo Y., Sun Y., Dai J. Y.. First report on the occurrence and bioaccumulation of hexafluoropropylene oxide trimer acid: an emerging concern. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2017;51:9553&#x2013;9560. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.7b02259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.7b02259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28780851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao J. Z., Pan Y. T., Sheng N., Su Z. B., Guo Y., Wang J. S., Dai J. Y.. Novel perfluoroalkyl ether carboxylic acids (PFECAs) and sulfonic acids (PFESAs): occurrence and association with serum biochemical parameters in residents living near a fluorochemical plant in China. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2020;54:13389&#x2013;13398. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.0c02888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.0c02888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33047597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evich M. G., Davis M. J. B., McCord J. P., Acrey B., Awkerman J. A., Knappe D. R. U., Lindstrom A. B., Speth T. F., Tebes-Stevens C., Strynar M. J., Wang Z., Weber E. J., Henderson W. M., Washington J. W.. Per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances in the environment. Science. 2022;375:eabg9065. doi: 10.1126/science.abg9065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abg9065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8902460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35113710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y. N., Yao J. Z., Pan Y. T., Dai J. Y., Tang J. H.. Trophic behaviors of PFOA and its alternatives perfluoroalkyl ether carboxylic acids (PFECAs) in a coastal food web. J. Hazard Mater. 2023;452:131353. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.131353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.131353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37030227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao J., Dong Z., Jiang L., Pan Y., Zhao M., Bai X., Dai J.. Emerging and legacy perfluoroalkyl substances in breastfed Chinese infants: renal clearance, body burden, and implications. Environ. Health Perspect. 2023;131(3):037003. doi: 10.1289/EHP11403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/EHP11403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9980344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36862174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen K. Y., Raymond M., Blackowicz M., Liu Y. Y., Thompson B. A., Anderson H., Turyk M.. Perfluoroalkyl substances and fish consumption. Environ. Res. 2017;154(Apr):145&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2016.12.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2016.12.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28073048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gewurtz S. B., Bhavsar S. P., Petro S., Mahon C. G., Zhao X. M., Morse D., Reiner E. J., Tittlemier S. A., Braekevelt E., Drouillard K.. High levels of perfluoroalkyl acids in sport fish species downstream of a firefighting training facility at Hamilton International Airport, Ontario. Canada. Environ. Int. 2014;67:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.envint.2014.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2014.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24632327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X. C., Dassuncao C., Zhang X., Grandjean P., Weihe P., Webster G. M., Nielsen F., Sunderland E. M.. Can profiles of poly- and Perfluoroalkyl substances (PFASs) in human serum provide information on major exposure sources? Environ. Health. 2018;17(1):11. doi: 10.1186/s12940-018-0355-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12940-018-0355-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5796515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29391068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H., Wei Q. W., Wan Y., Giesy J. P., Li L. X., Hu J. Y.. Tissue distribution and maternal transfer of poly- and perfluorinated compounds in Chinese sturgeon (Acipenser sinensis): Implications for reproductive risk. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2010;44(5):1868&#x2013;1874. doi: 10.1021/es903248d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es903248d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20143820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin J. W., Mabury S. A., Solomon K. R., Muir D. C. G.. Bioconcentration and tissue distribution of perfluorinated acids in rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) Environ. Toxicol. Chem. 2003;22(1):196&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1002/etc.5620220126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/etc.5620220126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12503765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dassuncao C., Pickard H., Pfohl M., Tokranov A. K., Li M., Mikkelsen B., Slitt A., Sunderland E. M.. Phospholipid levels predict the tissue distribution of poly-and perfluoroalkyl substances in a marine mammal. Environ. Sci. Technol. Lett. 2019;6(3):119&#x2013;125. doi: 10.1021/acs.estlett.9b00031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.estlett.9b00031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7713714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33283018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzke D., Nygard T., Berger U., Huber S., Rov N.. Perfluorinated and other persistent halogenated organic compounds in European shag (Phalacrocorax aristotelis) and common eider (Somateria mollissima) from Norway: A suburban to remote pollutant gradient. Sci. Total Environ. 2009;408(2):340&#x2013;348. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2009.08.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2009.08.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19836057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Q. Q., Pan Y. T., Zhang H. X., Sheng N., Wang J. S., Guo Y., Dai J. Y.. Occurrence and Tissue Distribution of Novel Perfluoroether Carboxylic and Sulfonic Acids and Legacy Per/Polyfluoroalkyl Substances in Black-Spotted Frog (Pelophylax nigromaculatus) Environ. Sci. Technol. 2018;52(3):982&#x2013;990. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.7b03662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.7b03662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M. M., Wuwilliams A., Whittemore A. S., Zheng S., Gallagher R., Teh C. Z., Zhou L., Wang X. H., Chen K., Ling C. D., Jiao D. A., Jung D., Paffenbarger R. S.. Comparison of dietary habits, physical-activity and body-size among Chinese in North-America and China. Int. J. Epidemiol. 1994;23:984&#x2013;990. doi: 10.1093/ije/23.5.984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/23.5.984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7860179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry; US Department of Health and Human Services; 2018. ToxGuide for perfluoroalkyls.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
United States Enviromental
Protection Agency . Fact Sheet:Human
health toxicity assessment for GenX chemicals
2021. 
https://www.epa.gov/chemical-research/human-health-toxicity-assessments-genx-chemicals (accessed August 21, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bil W., Zeilmaker M., Fragki S., Lijzen J., Verbruggen E., Bokkers B.. Risk assessment of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substance mixtures: a relative potency factor approach. Environ. Toxicol. Chem. 2020;40:859&#x2013;870. doi: 10.1002/etc.4835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/etc.4835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32729940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M. M., Wu F., Geng Q. Q., Wu H. Y., Song Z. L., Zheng G. C., Peng J. X., Zhao X. N., Tan Z. J.. Perfluoroalkyl substances (PFASs) in aquatic products from the Yellow-Bohai Sea coasts, China: Concentrations and profiles across species and regions. Environ. Pollut. 2023;327:121514. doi: 10.1016/j.envpol.2023.121514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2023.121514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36990342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Cheng X. H., Hua X., Jiang B., Tian C. G., Tang J. H., Li Q. L., Sun H. W., Lin T., Liao Y. H., Zhang G.. Emerging and legacy per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances in water, sediment, and air of the Bohai sea and its surrounding rivers. Environ. Pollut. 2020;263:114391. doi: 10.1016/j.envpol.2020.114391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2020.114391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32213363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Feng X. M., Zhou J., Zhu L. Y.. Occurrence and source apportionment of novel and legacy poly/perfluoroalkyl substances in Hai River basin in China using receptor models and isomeric fingerprints. Water Res. 2020;168:115145. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2019.115145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2019.115145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31614237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi J. D., Ryu D. K.. Age and growth of purple whelk, rapana venosa (gastropoda: muricidae) in the west sea of korea. Btrge Zur Pathologischen Anatomie Und Zur Allgemnen Pathologie. 2009;25(3):242&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller J. M., Kannan K., Taniyasu S., Yamashita N., Day R. D., Arendt M. D., Segars A. L., Kucklick J. R.. Perfluorinated compounds in the plasma of loggerhead and Kemp&#x2019;s Ridley sea turtles from the southeastern coast of the United States. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2005;39(23):9101&#x2013;9108. doi: 10.1021/es050690c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es050690c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16382930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houde M., Wells R. S., Fair P. A., Bossart G. D., Hohn A. A., Rowles T. K., Sweeney J. C., Solomon K. R., Muir D. C. G.. Polyfluoroalkyl compounds in free-ranging bottlenose dolphins (Tursiops truncatus) from the gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic Ocean. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2005;39(17):6591&#x2013;6598. doi: 10.1021/es0506556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es0506556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16190216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishibashi H., Iwata H., Kim E.-Y., Tao L., Kannan K., Amano M., Miyazaki N., Tanabe S., Batoev V. B., Petrov E. A.. Contamination and effects of perfluorochemicals in Baikal seal (Pusa sibirica). 1. Residue level, tissue distribution, and temporal trend. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2008;42(7):2295&#x2013;2301. doi: 10.1021/es072054f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es072054f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18504956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian L., Lang Y. Y., Wang Q. Y.. Anatomic Study of Circulatory System of Rapana Venosa. Prog. Anat. Sci. 2001;7(4):319&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Chen Y., Chen H. J., Zhang Y. F., Yang L. P., Zhong W. J., Zhu L. Y.. Direct evidence of the important role of proteins in bioconcentration and biomagnification of PFASs in benthic organisms based on comparison with OPEs. Sci. Total Environ. 2023;863:161012. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.161012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.161012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36549529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knutsen H. K., Alexander J., Barreg&#xe5;rd L., Bignami M., Br&#xfc;schweiler B., Ceccatelli S., Cottrill B., Dinovi M., Edler L., Grasl-Kraupp B., Hogstrand C., Hoogenboom L., Nebbia C. S., Oswald I. P., Petersen A., Rose M., Roudot A., Vleminckx C., Vollmer G., Wallace H., Bodin L., Cravedi J., Halldorsson T. I., Haug L. S., Johansson N., van Loveren H., Gergelova P., Mackay K., Levorato S., van Manen M., Schwerdtle T.. Risk to human health related to the presence of perfluorooctane sulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid in food. Efsa J. 2018;16:5194. doi: 10.2903/j.efsa.2018.5194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2018.5194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7009575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32625773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Ruan Y. F., Jin L. J., Lu G. Y., Ma L., Yeung L. W.Y., Wang W. X., Lam P K.S.. Oysters for legacy and emerging per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFASs) monitoring in estuarine and coastal waters: Phase distribution and bioconcentration profile. Sci. Total Environ. 2022;846:157453. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.157453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.157453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35863582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>