<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41723258</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Numerical simulation study on the cooperative movement of overburden and fracture healing mechanisms in shallow-buried coal seams.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10131</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40465-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>During the mining of shallow-buried coal seams, overburden movement leads to the formation of water-conducting pathways, resulting in surface subsidence and ground fissures, which in turn pose serious threats to shallow water systems and surface ecological environments. The development and stage-wise healing behavior of fractures in thick loose layers play a significant regulatory role in the transmission of mining-induced damage, yet these processes are challenging to quantitatively characterize due to their concealed nature. To address this, this study takes the 12,403 working face of the Ulanmulun Coal Mine in the Shendong Mining Area as its engineering background. A numerical simulation model for the mining process was established and validated through field measurements. By extracting key characteristic data such as the area of the plastic zone and fracture density, the evolution of mining-induced damage in both the bedrock layer and the loose layer was quantitatively analyzed, revealing the fracture healing mechanism in the loose layer and the interactive response pattern among the bedrock layer, loose layer, and surface. The research demonstrates that: (1) The area of the plastic failure zone in the overburden increases nonlinearly with working face advance, which can be divided into three stages: slow growth, rapid expansion, and stable linear development. The overall failure mode is dominated by shear failure, while tensile and tensile-shear failures are primarily concentrated at lithological interfaces and the soil&#x2013;rock contact zone. (2) There are significant differences in fracture development behavior between the bedrock layer and the loose layer. Under the combined influence of fracture propagation and compaction-induced healing, the fracture density in the bedrock layer first increases, then decreases, and eventually stabilizes. In contrast, the fracture density in the loose layer exhibits logarithmic growth accompanied by periodic fluctuations. (3) Following the collapse of the key stratum, a temporary load-bearing fracture arch structure forms within the loose layer, delaying surface subsidence. As mining-induced damage accumulates and goaf compaction progresses, the fracture arch gradually destabilizes and closes, leading to accelerated surface subsidence and the development of tensile ground fissures at the edges of the subsidence basin. These findings deepen the understanding of cooperative deformation and fracture healing mechanisms in the overburden of shallow-buried coal seams, providing a theoretical basis for predicting surface damage and protecting shallow water resources.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pang</LastName><ForeName>Changqing</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHN Shendong Coal Group Co., Ltd., Shaanxi, 719315, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Water Resource Protection and Utilization in Coal Mining, Beijing, 102209, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Zheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Water Resource Protection and Utilization in Coal Mining, Beijing, 102209, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Clean and Low Carbon Energy, Beijing, 102209, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Water Resource Protection and Utilization in Coal Mining, Beijing, 102209, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Clean and Low Carbon Energy, Beijing, 102209, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Zhuhe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Water Resource Protection and Utilization in Coal Mining, Beijing, 102209, China. 1252747312@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute of Clean and Low Carbon Energy, Beijing, 102209, China. 1252747312@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>GJNY-25-98</GrantID><Agency>State Key Laboratory of Water Resource Protection and Utilization in Coal Mining</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>NICE_RD_2024_303</GrantID><Agency>State Key Laboratory of Water Resource Protection and Utilization in Coal Mining</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cooperative movement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fracture healing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Numerical simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shallow-Buried coal seam</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thick loose layer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41723258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13022414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40465-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40465-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Quansheng, L. I., Xiaobin, L. I., Jialin, X. U., Zhuhe, X. U. &amp; Cun, Z. Research advances in mining fractures evolution law of rock strata and ecological treatment technology. <i>Coal Sci. Technol.</i>, <b>50</b>(1), 28&#x2013;47 (2022)..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, L. et al. Effect of dominant fractures on triaxial behavior of 3D-printed rock analogs with internal fracture networks. <i>J. Rock Mech. Geotech. Eng.</i><b>18</b> (2026), 1390&#x2013;1412 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrmge.2025.06.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, X. et al. Hybrid strengthening method and mechanism of sand powder 3D printed rock analog. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng</i>.10.1007/s00603-026-05310-8 (2026). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, T. et al. A novel probability integral method segmental modified model for subsidence prediction applicable to thick loose layer mining areas. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res.</i><b>30</b> (18), 52049&#x2013;52061 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-023-26021-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36826765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linming, D. O. U. &amp; T Present situation and problems of coal mine rock burst prevention and control in China. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>47</b> (1), 152&#x2013;171 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, X. P. et al. Study on development law of water-conducting fractures in overlying strata of three soft coal seam mining under thick loose layers. <i>Chin. J. Rock. Mech. Eng.</i><b>40</b> (09), 1739&#x2013;1750 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Study on overburden structure and support load characteristics under concentrated load in shallow coal seam mining across-coal pillar. <i>Results Eng.</i> 106532 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng, T., Xu, Z. &amp; Wang, Y. Overburden damage in high-intensity mining: Effects of lithology and formation structure. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>15</b> (19), 10518 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app151910518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, M., Miao, X. &amp; He, F. Key block analysis of the Voussoir beam structure in a stope. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>19</b> (6), 557&#x2013;563 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, M., Miao, X. &amp; Xu, J. Theoretical study of key stratum in ground control. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>21</b> (3), 225&#x2013;230 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y., Zhang, J., Liu, H., Yang, T. &amp; Sun, J. Study on activation and restructuring of key strata in shallowly buried coal seam bearing structure and load characteristics. <i>Processes</i><b>12</b> (6), 1257 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr12061257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Rui, Q., Yang, Y., Chen, J., Shen, W., Yuan, Y. &amp; Liu, W. Roof movement and instability fracture characteristics in shallow-buried thin coal seam conventional mining faces. <i>Geomech.Geophys. Geo-Energy Geo-Resour</i>. <b>10</b>(1), 27 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Zhou, D., Zhang, J. &amp; Liang, B. Research on the dynamic evolution law of fissures in shallow-buried and short-distance coal seam mining in Lijiahao coal mine. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b> (1), 5625 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-32849-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10079860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37024549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, J., Su, H., Wang, C. &amp; Li, J. Research on the evolution and height prediction of WCFZ in shallow close coal seams mining. <i>Geomech. Geophys. Geo-Energy Geo-Resources</i>. <b>9</b> (1), 128 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40948-023-00662-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., Kong, D., Liu, Q., Cai, H. &amp; Chen, L. Study on law and prediction of surface movement and deformation in mountain area under repeated mining of shallow coal seam. <i>Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ.</i><b>82</b> (3), 76 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-023-03105-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. A study on the subsidence movement and stress evolution characteristics of unequally thick bedrock overburden under the extremely thick loose layer. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>518</b>, 145779 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, F., Xu, J. &amp; Xie, J. Effects of arch structure in unconsolidated layers on fracture and failure of overlying strata. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>114</b>, 141&#x2013;152 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2018.12.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, J., Huang, Q. &amp; Guo, L. Subsidence prediction of overburden strata and ground surface in shallow coal seam mining. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>11</b> (1), 18972 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-98520-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8460826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34556745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, W., Chen, J., Tan, Y., Zhang, W. &amp; Cai, L. Theoretical analysis of mining induced overburden subsidence boundary with the horizontal coal seam mining. <i>Adv. Civil Eng.</i><b>2021</b> (1), 6657738 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/6657738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo, H. et al. Study on surface subsidence prediction method of shallow coal seam backfill-strip mining under the hard roof. <i>Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ.</i><b>82</b> (7), 281 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-023-03284-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y., Zuo, J., Karakus, M. &amp; Wang, J. Investigation of movement and damage of integral overburden during shallow coal seam mining. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>117</b>, 63&#x2013;75 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2019.03.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y., Zuo, J., Karakus, M. &amp; Wen, J. A novel method for predicting movement and damage of overburden caused by shallow coal mining. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>53</b> (4), 1545&#x2013;1563 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-019-01988-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>YANG, S. et al. Surface subsidence and its prediction method ofmining deep-buried seam with thick alluvial layer and thin bedrock. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>48</b> (2), 523&#x2013;537 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Q. et al. Quantitative and dynamic predictive model for mining-induced movement and deformation of overlying strata. <i>Eng. Geol.</i><b>311</b>, 106876 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2022.106876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, J., Li, Y., Meng, X., Guo, Q. &amp; Zhao, G. Influence of coupling mechanism of loose layer and fault on multi-physical fields in mining areas. <i>Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>10</b> (1), 86 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-023-00640-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Z., Chen, C., Xiao, W., Wang, X. &amp; Gao, M. Surface movement and deformation characteristics due to high-intensive coal mining in the windy and sandy region. <i>Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>3</b> (3), 339&#x2013;348 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-016-0144-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., Wu, K., Bai, Z. &amp; Hu, Z. Theoretical analysis of the secondary development of mining-induced surface cracks in the Ordos region. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>76</b> (20), 703 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-017-7050-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. &amp; Einstein, H. H. Using RQD to estimate the deformation modulus of rock masses. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>41</b> (2), 337&#x2013;341 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1365-1609(03)00100-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q., Huang, X., Zhu, H. &amp; Li, J. Quantitative assessments of the correlations between rock mass rating (RMR) and geological strength index (GSI). <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i><b>83</b>, 73&#x2013;81 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2018.09.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Z., Zhang, C., Wang, Y., Yang, S. &amp; Li, Q. Collaborative movement characteristics of overlying rock and loose layer based on block-particle discrete-element simulation method. <i>Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>12</b> (1), 17 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-025-00762-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad, N., Reddish, D. J. &amp; Stace, L. R. The relation between in situ and laboratory rock properties used in numerical modelling. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>34</b> (2), 289&#x2013;297 (1997).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0148-9062(96)00060-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. X., Mao, D. B. &amp; Qi, Q. X. Study on determining of the mechanical parameters of rock mass used in numerical simulation. <i>J. China Coal Soc.</i><b>28</b> (6), 594&#x2013;597 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, D. M., Guo, W. B., Yu, Q. G., Tan, Y. &amp; Deng, W. Structural characteristics and evolution mechanism of overlying strata pressure arch in shallow and flat seams. <i>J. Min. Saf. Eng.</i><b>36</b> (2), 323&#x2013;330 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. &amp; Zeng, Q. Evolutionary laws and response mechanisms of stress-fracture-seepage in mining-induced overburden of coal seams: A case study in Dajing mining area, Xinjiang, China. <i>Geomech. Geophys. Geo-Energy Geo-Resour</i>. (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>