<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41311068</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-9613</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of ultrasound in medicine : official journal of the American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Ultrasound Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of the Morphological Uterus Sonographic Assessment (MUSA) Consensus for Adenomyosis Diagnosis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jum.70141</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the diagnostic value of the nine Morphological Uterus Sonographic Assessment (MUSA)-defined ultrasonographic features for adenomyosis and develop an ultrasound scoring system to improve diagnostic accuracy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective study analyzed ultrasound images from patients who underwent total hysterectomy between May 2023 and December 2024, in accordance with the MUSA consensus. The cohort was split into training and testing sets. Ridge regression was applied to the training set to develop an ultrasound scoring system based on the regression coefficients of each sign, which was subsequently validated in the test set. Correlations between the ultrasound score and preoperative hemoglobin, dysmenorrhea were evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Interrupted junctional zone and myometrial cysts showed highest specificity (89.0%, 88.5%), hyperechoic islands highest sensitivity (69.2%). In the training set, the scoring system achieved an area under the curve (AUC)&#xa0;of 0.948 (95% CI 0.901-0.990), sensitivity 86.3%, specificity 87.3%, accuracy 86.8%. In the testing set, AUC was 0.894 (95% CI 0.856-0.931), sensitivity 79.4%, specificity 83.9%, accuracy 81.7%. No significant correlation existed between ultrasound score and hemoglobin (&#x3c1;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.017, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.824), but a weak positive correlation was found with Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) scores (&#x3c1;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.178, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.016).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">All nine MUSA features contribute to adenomyosis diagnosis, but no single sign is sufficiently accurate alone. The ultrasound scoring system significantly enhances transvaginal ultrasound diagnostic performance and shows strong clinical potential. Higher scores correlate modestly with greater dysmenorrhea severity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yixuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-0255-1742</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Abdominal Ultrasound, Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yushan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Jimo District People's Hospital of Qingdao, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Lingzhi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Obstetrics and Gynecology Ultrasound Department, Qingdao Women and Children's Hospital, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Jinzhen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Abdominal Ultrasound, Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Zongli</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Abdominal Ultrasound, Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZR2022QH310</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Shandong Province Youth Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Ultrasound Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8211547</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0278-4297</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MUSA criteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adenomyosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasound</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41311068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jum.70141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Selntigia A, Molinaro P, Tartaglia S, et al. Adenomyosis: An update concerning diagnosis, treatment, and fertility. J Clin Med 2024; 13:5224. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13175224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etrusco A, Barra F, Chiantera V, et al. Current medical therapy for adenomyosis: from bench to bedside. Drugs 2023; 83:1595&#x2013;1611. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40265-023-01957-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dessouky R, Gamil SA, Nada MG, et al. Management of uterine adenomyosis: current trends and uterine artery embolization as a potential alternative to hysterectomy. Insights Imaging 2019; 10:48. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13244-019-0732-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tellum T, Nygaard S, Lieng M. Noninvasive diagnosis of adenomyosis: a structured review and meta&#x2010;analysis of diagnostic accuracy in imaging. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2020; 27:408&#x2013;418. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmig.2019.11.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bosch T, Dueholm M, Leone FP, et al. Terms, definitions and measurements to describe sonographic features of myometrium and uterine masses: a consensus opinion from the morphological uterus sonographic assessment (MUSA) group. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol 2015; 46:284&#x2013;298. https://doi.org/10.1002/uog.14806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmsen MJ, Van den Bosch T, de Leeuw RA, et al. Consensus on revised definitions of morphological uterus sonographic assessment (MUSA) features of adenomyosis: results of modified Delphi procedure. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol 2022; 60:118&#x2013;131. https://doi.org/10.1002/uog.24786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feferkorn I, Tulandi T. Sonographic diagnosis of adenomyosis&#x2010;ultrasound that cried wolf? Fertil Steril 2023; 119:490&#x2013;491. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fertnstert.2022.12.043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landis JR, Koch GG. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. Biometrics 1977; 33:159&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krentel H, Keckstein J, F&#xfc;ger T, et al. Accuracy of ultrasound signs on two&#x2010;dimensional transvaginal ultrasound in prediction of adenomyosis: prospective multicenter study. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol 2023; 62:739&#x2013;746.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Li W, Leonardi M, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of transvaginal ultrasound and magnetic resonance imaging for adenomyosis: systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis and review of sonographic diagnostic criteria. J Ultrasound Med 2021; 40:2289&#x2013;2306. https://doi.org/10.1002/jum.15635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadam N, Khalid S, Jayaprakasan K. How reproducible are the ultrasound features of adenomyosis defined by the revised MUSA consensus? J Clin Med 2025; 14:456. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm14020456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dosunmu SD, Sarno A, Lee E, et al. Validation of the revised MUSA criteria for sonographic detection of adenomyosis. Abdom Radiol (NY), Published online, June 14, 2025. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00261-025-05039-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen CK, Hansen ES, Ernst E, et al. Two&#x2010; and three&#x2010;dimensional transvaginal ultrasonography for diagnosis of adenomyosis of the inner myometrium. Reprod Biomed Online 2019; 38:750&#x2013;760. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rbmo.2018.12.033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naftalin J, Hoo W, Nunes N, et al. Association between ultrasound features of adenomyosis and severity of menstrual pain. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol 2016; 47:779&#x2013;783. https://doi.org/10.1002/uog.15798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavuz O, Akd&#xf6;ner A, &#xd6;zgozen ME, et al. Prediction of adenomyosis according to revised definitions of morphological uterus sonographic assessment features. Front Med (Lausanne) 2024; 11:1387515. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2024.1387515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sam M, Raubenheimer M, Manolea F, et al. Accuracy of findings in the diagnosis of uterine adenomyosis on ultrasound. Abdom Radiol (NY) 2020; 45:842&#x2013;850. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00261-019-02231-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmsen MJ, Trommelen LM, de Leeuw RA, et al. Uterine junctional zone and adenomyosis: comparison of MRI, transvaginal ultrasound and histology. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol 2023; 62:42&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1002/uog.26117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Gupta R, Picard MM, et al. Use of three&#x2010;dimensional US for troubleshooting in gynecologic imaging. Radiographics 2025; 45:e240160. https://doi.org/10.1148/rg.240160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martire FG, Costantini E, D'Abate C, et al. Endometriosis and adenomyosis: from pathogenesis to follow&#x2010;up. Curr Issues Mol Biol 2025; 47:298. https://doi.org/10.3390/cimb47050298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An XL, Zhang J, Yun XC, et al. Perspectives in transvaginal sonography for the diagnosis of adenomyosis. Front Med (Lausanne) 2025; 12:1533648. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmed.2025.1533648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exacoustos C, Morosetti G, Conway F, et al. New sonographic classification of adenomyosis: do type and degree of adenomyosis correlate to severity of symptoms? J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2020; 27:1308&#x2013;1315. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmig.2019.09.788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vald&#xe9;s&#x2010;Bango M, Ros C, Daza M, et al. Internal and external adenomyosis phenotypes: ultrasound features and association with clinical outcomes. Hum Reprod 2024; 39:1471&#x2013;1480. https://doi.org/10.1093/humrep/deae105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnay JL, O'Brien S, Gerlinger C, et al. Pictorial methods to assess heavy menstrual bleeding in research and clinical practice: a systematic literature review. BMC Womens Health 2020; 20:24. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-020-0887-y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldutyt&#x117; G, Opolskien&#x117; G, Rudaitis V, et al. The association between sonographic features and clinical symptoms of adenomyosis. J Clin Ultrasound 2024; 52:846&#x2013;850. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcu.23712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tellum T, Matic GV, Dormagen JB, et al. Diagnosing adenomyosis with MRI: a prospective study revisiting the junctional zone thickness cutoff of 12&#x2009;mm as a diagnostic marker. Eur Radiol 2019; 29:6971&#x2013;6981. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00330-019-06308-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matot R, Blickstein O, Leibner G, et al. Differences in the sonographic features of adenomyosis and concurrent endometriosis compared to isolated adenomyosis: a MUSA criteria analysis. J Ultrasound Med 2025; 44:1077&#x2013;1084. https://doi.org/10.1002/jum.16667.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>