<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41601846</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2473-0114</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Foot &amp; ankle orthopaedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Foot Ankle Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association of Preoperative Coronal Plane Deformity With Postoperative Tibial Bone-Prosthesis Interface Lucency in the Cadence Total Ankle.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>24730114251413240</StartPage><MedlinePgn>24730114251413240</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">24730114251413240</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/24730114251413240</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Minimal resection total ankle arthroplasty (TAA) has been linked to an increased incidence of tibial component lucency in large preoperative coronal plane deformity. Lucency has been linked to implant loosening. Because radiographic lucency may reflect implant micromotion, lack of bony ingrowth and/or early component loosening, we analyzed a series of TAA cases with varying degrees of preoperative coronal deformity. Our primary aim was to determine if larger preoperative tibiotalar angles were associated with increased postoperative tibial component lucency in the Cadence TAA system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A retrospective review of a single surgeon's TAA procedures using the Cadence prosthesis was conducted. Patients aged &#x2265;18&#x2009;years who underwent Cadence TAA from January 1, 2018, to December 31, 2023, were included; those with &lt;12&#x2009;months' follow-up or poor-quality radiographs were excluded. Lucency was defined as a radiolucent line at the interface between the tibia and the tibial component that was greater than 0.5&#x2009;mm at any point. The patient's final follow-up radiograph was used for this analysis. Pre- and postoperative tibiotalar alignment was recorded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fifty-five ankles were examined. The average follow-up duration was 29.8&#x2009;months. Sixteen patients (29%) had no deformity. Twenty-seven patients (49%) had less than 15 degrees of angulation and 12 patients (22%) had more than 15 degrees of angulation. Postoperatively, all ankles were corrected to within 3.7 degrees of a coronal tibiotalar angle of 90 degrees. Comparisons among the 3 groups with &#x3c7;<sup>2</sup> tests and analyses of variance revealed no significant differences in tibial interface lucency across any zone (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Aseptic loosening in TAAs, indicated by peri-implant lucency, is a recognized mode of failure. Recent studies suggest that preoperative coronal tibiotalar angles greater than 15 degrees increase the risk of failure when using minimal resection TAA. In this short-term, single-surgeon cohort, there were no differences in peri-implant lucency between groups. Findings should be interpreted cautiously, given the limited follow-up and statistical power.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Level IV, retrospective analysis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coale</LastName><ForeName>Max</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4746-1931</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mercy Medical Center, Institute for Foot and Ankle Reconstruction, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maloney</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mercy Medical Center, Institute for Foot and Ankle Reconstruction, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fogel</LastName><ForeName>Jessa</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Maryland Medical Center, Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeng</LastName><ForeName>Clifford</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3751-8757</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mercy Medical Center, Institute for Foot and Ankle Reconstruction, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Foot Ankle Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101752333</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2473-0114</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ankle arthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aseptic loosening</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peri-implant lucency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total ankle arthroplasty</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total ankle failure</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: Clifford Jeng, MD, reports disclosures relevant to manuscript of Smith and Nephew, consulting fees, $13,000. Disclosure forms for all authors are available online.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41601846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12833150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/24730114251413240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_24730114251413240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Malherbe C, Deleu PA, Devos Bevernage B, et al. Early-term results of the cadence total ankle prosthesis: an European noninventor study. Foot Ankle Int. 2023;44(1):1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36609177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushing CJ, Law R, Hyer CF. Early experience with the CADENCE total ankle prosthesis. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2021;60(1):67-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33129676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cody EA, Henry JK, Shaffrey I, et al. Early periprosthetic tibial lucency following low-profile total ankle arthroplasty. Foot Ankle Int. 2025;46(6):608-616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40100001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffrey I, O&#x2019;Malley E, Henry JK, et al. Midterm clinical outcomes, radiographic outcomes, and survivorship of the infinity total ankle arthroplasty. Foot Ankle Int. 2023;44(12):1247-1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37964445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cody EA, Taylor MA, Nunley JA, 2nd, Parekh SG, DeOrio JK. Increased early revision rate with the INFINITY total ankle prosthesis. Foot Ankle Int. 2019;40(1):9-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30175612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry JK, Shaffrey I, Wishman M, et al. Early outcomes of the Exactech vantage fixed-bearing total ankle replacement. Bone Joint J. 2023;105-B(10):1099-1107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37777206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry JK, Shaffrey I, Cororaton AD, et al. Implant choice may reduce the risk of early mechanical failure in total ankle replacement. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2024;106(9):767-775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38442190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell A, Mann RA. Ankle arthroplasty with preoperative coronal plane deformity: short-term results. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2004;424:98-103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15241149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood PL, Deakin S. Total ankle replacement. The results in 200 ankles. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2003;85(3):334-341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12729104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood PL, Sutton C, Mishra V, Suneja R. A randomised, controlled trial of two mobile-bearing total ankle replacements. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2009;91(1):69-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cody EA, Bejarano-Pineda L, Lachman JR, et al. Risk factors for failure of total ankle arthroplasty with a minimum five years of follow-up. Foot Ankle Int. 2019;40(3):249-258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30345818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piga C, Maccario C, D&#x2019;Ambrosi R, Romano F, Usuelli FG. Total ankle arthroplasty with valgus deformity. Foot Ankle Int. 2021;42(7):867-876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33517787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy SC, Mann JA, Mann RA, Mangold DR. Correction of moderate to severe coronal plane deformity with the STAR&#x2122; ankle prosthesis. Foot Ankle Int. 2011;32(7):659-664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21972759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cody E, Demetracopoulos C, Adams S, DeOrio J, Nunley J, Easley M. Outcomes of total ankle arthroplasty in moderate and severe valgus deformity. Foot Ankle Orthop. 2018;3(3):2473011418S00035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trajkovski T, Pinsker E, Cadden A, Daniels T. Outcomes of ankle arthroplasty with preoperative coronal-plane varus deformity of 10&#xb0; or greater. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2013;95(15):1382-1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23925742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BS, Choi WJ, Kim YS, Lee JW. Total ankle replacement in moderate to severe varus deformity of the ankle. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2009;91-B(9):1183-1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19721044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shock RP, Christensen JC, Schuberth JM. Total ankle replacement in the varus ankle. J Foot Ankle Surg. 2011;50(1):5-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21172638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee GW, Wang SH, Lee KB. Comparison of intermediate to long-term outcomes of total ankle arthroplasty in ankles with preoperative varus, valgus, and neutral alignment. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2018;100(10):835-842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29762278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvarda P, Mills A, Shepherd D, Schneider T. Lack of consensus on the definition of aseptic loosening in total ankle replacement: a narrative systematic review. J Clin Med. 2024;13(3):786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10856361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooner S, Kayum S, Pinsker EB, et al. Two-year outcomes after total ankle replacement with a novel fixed-bearing implant. Foot Ankle Int. 2021;42(8):1002-1010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo S-D, Lee K-B. Comparison of the outcome of total ankle arthroplasty for osteoarthritis with moderate and severe varus malalignment and that with neutral alignment. Bone Joint J. 2017;99-B(10):1335-1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28963155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Queen RM, Adams SB, Jr, Viens NA, et al. Differences in outcomes following total ankle replacement in patients with neutral alignment compared with tibiotalar joint malalignment. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2013;95(21):1927-1934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24196462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung KS, Ahn J, Lee KH, Chun TH. Short-term results of total ankle arthroplasty for end-stage ankle arthritis with severe varus deformity. Foot Ankle Int. 2014;35(3):225-231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24346769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>