<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41637417</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spatiotemporal evolution of the thermal environment and influencing factors in Kashgar City's Urban Expansion.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0341615</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0341615</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0341615</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0341615</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Under the dual pressures of global warming and rapid urbanization, the mechanisms governing the evolution of high-temperature environments in arid-zone cities demand systematic analysis. This study investigates the spatiotemporal evolution characteristics and multidimensional influencing factors of urban expansion and thermal environments in the Kashgar region. As a representative city in China's arid western region, the analysis utilizes multi-source remote sensing data and socioeconomic statistics from 2010 to 2024. Methods including urban expansion indices, surface temperature inversion, and geographic detector models were employed to reveal spatiotemporal patterns linking urban form changes and thermal environments. The findings indicate: (1) Kashgar's urban expansion exhibits significant spatial heterogeneity, with construction land expansion characterized by stable central areas and rapid peripheral growth. Marginal expansion dominates the thermal environment, where the township-Mulatibag urban-rural fringe has emerged as a new growth pole for thermal expansion. (2) Kashgar's thermal environment continues to deteriorate, with the area affected by high temperatures increasing by an average of 19.55% annually. The spatial pattern has undergone a three-stage evolution: punctual breakthroughs, cluster aggregation, and contiguous spread. The low-temperature ecological corridor system has systematically shrunk, and the city's thermal environment regulation capacity shows a significant downward trend. (3) A strong positive correlation exists between Kashgar's urban expansion and its thermal environment. This correlation exhibited a trend of "initial strengthening followed by weakening" over the fifteen-year period. (4) Factors influencing high temperatures exhibit multidimensional interactions. Among anthropogenic factors, impervious surfaces and population density jointly intensify high-temperature severity through a dual-factor amplification effect. Conversely, natural factors such as vegetation and water bodies exert a negative mitigating influence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Yan et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Jiaxing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, Shihezi University, Shihezi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Wenli</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7353-5637</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, Shihezi University, Shihezi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Architecture and Urban Planning, Chongqing University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Chunlan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Architecture and Urban Planning, Chongqing University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xutong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, Shihezi University, Shihezi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheng</LastName><ForeName>Xinyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, Shihezi University, Shihezi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014507" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urbanization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="N">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N">Cities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062211" MajorTopicYN="N">Spatio-Temporal Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013696" MajorTopicYN="N">Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057232" MajorTopicYN="N">Global Warming</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41637417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12872019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0341615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-39327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>United Nations. World urbanization prospects report 2024. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Z, Tian GJ, Zhang LX, Xu XL. Influences of urban expansion on urban heat Island in Beijing during 1989&#x2013;2010. Adv Meteorol. 2014;2014:187169. doi: 10.1155/2014/187169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/187169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo WY, Ren ZG, Shan XF, Zhou Z, Deng QL. Analysis of urban heat Island effect in Wuhan urban area based on prediction of urban underlying surface coverage type change. Adv Meteorol. 2024:4509221. doi: 10.1155/2024/4509221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2024/4509221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X, Peng S. Assessing the quantitative relationships between the impervious surface area and surface heat island effect during urban expansion. Peer J. 2021;9:e11854. doi: 10.7717/peerj.11854</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.11854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8312497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34386305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Zhou Y, Hu M, Zhou Y. Influence of urban scale and urban expansion on the urban heat Island effect in metropolitan areas: Case study of beijing&#x2013;tianjin&#x2013;hebei urban agglomeration. Remote Sens. 2020;12(21):3491. doi: 10.3390/rs12213491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12213491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah N, Siddique MA, Ding M, Grigoryan S, Khan IA, Kang Z, et al. The impact of urbanization on urban heat Island: Predictive Approach Using Google Earth Engine and CA-Markov Modelling (2005-2050) of Tianjin City, China. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(3):2642. doi: 10.3390/ijerph20032642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20032642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9916317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36768019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Liu S, Ma Q, Cao W, Zhang H, Wang Z. Impacts of spatial explanatory variables on surface urban heat island intensity between urban and suburban regions in China. Int J Digit Earth. 2024;17(1). doi: 10.1080/17538947.2024.2304074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17538947.2024.2304074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zhang N. Urban heat island mitigation effectiveness under extreme heat conditions in the Suzhou&#x2013;Wuxi&#x2013;Changzhou metropolitan area, China. J Appl Meteor. 2018;57:235&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1175/jamc-d-17-0101.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1175/jamc-d-17-0101.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritipadmaja Garg RD, Sharma AK. Assessing the cooling effect of blue-green spaces: implications for urban heat Island Mitigation. Water. 2023;15(16):2983. doi: 10.3390/w15162983</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w15162983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Dong S, Cheng H, Li F. Spatio-temporal evolution of urban thermal environment and its driving factors: Case study of Nanjing, China. PLoS One. 2021;16(5):e0246011. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0246011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0246011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8096077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33945549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiaxing Z, Lin L, Hang L, Dongmei P. Evaluation and analysis on suitability of human settlement environment in Qingdao. PLoS One. 2021;16(9):e0256502. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0256502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0256502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8476008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34570789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li G, Yu H, Gao G, Lou Z. Remote sensing monitoring and multidimensional impact factor analysis of urban heat Island Effect in Zhengzhou city. Atmosphere. 2024;15(9):1097. doi: 10.3390/atmos15091097</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/atmos15091097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Zhang Y. Quantitative identification of temporal-spatial variations of Urban Heat Island (UHI) effects in Changchun, China. IEEE J Sel Top Appl Earth Observations Remote Sensing. 2022;15:3052&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1109/jstars.2022.3167831</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/jstars.2022.3167831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koomen E, Diogo V. Assessing potential future urban heat island patterns following climate scenarios, socio-economic developments and spatial planning strategies. Mitig Adapt Strateg Glob Chang. 2017;22(2):287&#x2013;306. doi: 10.1007/s11027-015-9646-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11027-015-9646-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6108038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30197566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Z, Tian D, Zhu Y. Research on spatial and temporal patterns of heat island variability and influencing factors in urban center areas: A case study of Beijing&#x2019;s central area. Buildings. 2023;13(8):1887. doi: 10.3390/buildings13081887</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13081887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourfi A, Ta&#xef;bi AN, Salhi S, Hannani ME, Boujrouf S. The Surface Urban Heat Island and Key Mitigation Factors in Arid Climate Cities, Case of Marrakesh, Morocco. Remote Sens. 2022;14(16):3935. doi: 10.3390/rs14163935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14163935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed A, Khan A, Santamouris M. Numerical evaluation of enhanced green infrastructures for mitigating urban heat in a desert urban setting. Build Simul. 2023;16:1691&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1007/s12273-022-0940-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12273-022-0940-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azmeer A, Tahir F, Al-Ghamdi SG. Progress on green infrastructure for urban cooling: Evaluating techniques, design strategies, and benefits. Urban Climate. 2024;56:102077. doi: 10.1016/j.uclim.2024.102077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.uclim.2024.102077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battista G, Evangelisti L, Guattari C, De Lieto Vollaro E, De Lieto Vollaro R, Asdrubali F. Urban Heat Island Mitigation Strategies: Experimental and Numerical Analysis of a University Campus in Rome (Italy). Sustainability. 2020;12(19):7971. doi: 10.3390/su12197971</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12197971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y, Chakraborty TC, Li J, Li D, He C, Sarangi C, et al. Urbanization impact on regional climate and extreme weather: Current understanding, uncertainties, and future research directions. Adv Atmos Sci. 2022;39(6):819&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1007/s00376-021-1371-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00376-021-1371-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8786627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35095158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassandro P, Zaccaro SA, Di Turi S. Mitigation and adaptation strategies for different urban fabrics to face increasingly hot summer days due to climate change. Sustainability. 2024;16(5):2210. doi: 10.3390/su16052210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16052210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes HS, Vidal DG, Cherif N, Silva L, Remoaldo PC. Green infrastructure and its influence on urban heat island, heat risk, and air pollution: A case study of Porto (Portugal). J Environ Manage. 2025;376:124446. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124446</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39921953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marando F, Heris MP, Zulian G, Ud&#xed;as A, Mentaschi L, Chrysoulakis N, et al. Urban heat island mitigation by green infrastructure in European Functional Urban Areas. Sustain Cities Soc. 2022;77:103564. doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2021.103564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2021.103564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito A, Pappaccogli G, Donateo A, Salizzoni P, Maffeis G, Semeraro T, et al. Urban morphology and surface urban heat island relationship during heat waves: A study of milan and lecce (Italy). Remote Sens. 2024;16(23):4496. doi: 10.3390/rs16234496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs16234496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker T, Fan P, Messina JP, Mujahid N, Aldrian E, Chen J. Impact of Urban built-up volume on Urban environment: A case of Jakarta. Sustain Cities Soc. 2024;105:105346. doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2024.105346</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2024.105346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han S, Li W, Kwan M-P, Miao C, Sun B. Do polycentric structures reduce surface urban heat island intensity?. Appl Geography. 2022;146:102766. doi: 10.1016/j.apgeog.2022.102766</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apgeog.2022.102766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Li YQ, Zheng CG, Zhu YB. Surface urban heat island effect and its driving factors for all the cities in China: Based on a new batch processing method. Ecol Indic. 2023;146:109818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araque K, Palacios P, Mora D, Chen Austin M. Biomimicry-based strategies for urban heat island mitigation: A numerical case study under tropical climate. Biomimetics (Basel). 2021;6(3):48. doi: 10.3390/biomimetics6030048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomimetics6030048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8293213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34287246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C, Tang Y, Wu Y, Tao Y, Xu M, Xu N, et al. Assessing long-term thermal environment change with landsat time-series data in a rapidly Urbanizing city in China. Land. 2024;13(2):177. doi: 10.3390/land13020177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land13020177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeren Cetin I, Varol T, Ozel HB. A geographic information systems and remote sensing-based approach to assess urban micro-climate change and its impact on human health in Bartin, Turkey. Environ Monit Assess. 2023;195(5):540. doi: 10.1007/s10661-023-11105-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-023-11105-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37017749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamry SF, Al-Jashaami SHK. Urban governance and renewable energy for sustainable city planning and management. J Hum Earth Future. 2024;5(4):591&#x2013;602. doi: 10.28991/hef-2024-05-04-04</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.28991/hef-2024-05-04-04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen D, Wang L, Cao Q, Hong M, Wang H, Bian G. A comparative study of the effects of urban morphology on land surface temperature in Chengdu and Chongqing, China. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):25130. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-77036-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-77036-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11502834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39448693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moazzam MFU, Doh YH, Lee BG. Impact of urbanization on land surface temperature and surface urban heat Island using optical remote sensing data: A case study of Jeju Island, Republic of Korea. Building and Environment. 2022;222:109368. doi: 10.1016/j.buildenv.2022.109368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2022.109368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irfeey AMM, Chau H-W, Sumaiya MMF, Wai CY, Muttil N, Jamei E. Sustainable mitigation strategies for urban heat island effects in urban areas. Sustainability. 2023;15(14):10767. doi: 10.3390/su151410767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151410767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwaab J, Meier R, Mussetti G, Seneviratne S, B&#xfc;rgi C, Davin EL. The role of urban trees in reducing land surface temperatures in European cities. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):6763. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-26768-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26768-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8611034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34815395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng WL, Saleem A, Sadr R. Recent warming trend in the coastal region of Qatar. Theor Appl Climatol. 2017;128:193&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1007/s00704-015-1693-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00704-015-1693-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takebayashi H, Senoo M. Analysis of the relationship between urban size and heat island intensity using WRF model. Urban Climate. 2018;24:287&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1016/j.uclim.2016.12.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.uclim.2016.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousta I, Sarif MO, Gupta RD, Olafsson H, Ranagalage M, Murayama Y, et al. Spatiotemporal analysis of land use/land cover and its effects on surface urban heat island using Landsat data: A case study of metropolitan city Tehran (1988&#x2013;2018). Sustainability. 2018;10(12):4433. doi: 10.3390/su10124433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su10124433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baqa MF, Lu L, Chen F, Nawaz-ul-Huda S, Pan L, Tariq A, et al. Characterizing spatiotemporal variations in the urban thermal environment related to land cover changes in Karachi, Pakistan, from 2000 to 2020. Remote Sens. 2022;14(9):2164. doi: 10.3390/rs14092164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14092164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said ZM, Dindar S. Key Challenges and strategies in the evaluation of sustainable urban regeneration projects: Insights from a systematic literature review. Sustainability. 2024;16(22):9903. doi: 10.3390/su16229903</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su16229903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dindar S. A systematic review of urban regeneration&#x2019;s impact on sustainable transport: Traffic dynamics, policy responses, and environmental implications. Sustain Deve. 2025;2025(0):1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhao H, Long Y. CMAB: A multi-attribute building dataset of China. Sci Data. 2025;12(1):430. doi: 10.1038/s41597-025-04730-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-025-04730-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11903664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40075090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How Jin Aik D, Ismail MH, Muharam FM, Alias MA. Evaluating the impacts of land use/land cover changes across topography against land surface temperature in Cameron Highlands. PLoS One. 2021;16(5):e0252111. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0252111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0252111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34019599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Sun A, Niu R. Effect of land cover fractions on changes in surface urban heat islands using landsat time-series images. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(6):971. doi: 10.3390/ijerph16060971</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16060971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6466230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30889877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seletkovi&#x107; A, Ki&#x10d;i&#x107; M, An&#x10d;i&#x107; M, Koli&#x107; J, Pernar R. The urban heat island analysis for the city of zagreb in the period 2013&#x2013;2022 utilizing landsat 8 satellite imagery. Sustainability. 2023;15(5):3963. doi: 10.3390/su15053963</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15053963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafzadeh F, Mohammadzadeh A, Ghorbanian A, Jamali S. Spatial and temporal analysis of surface urban heat island and thermal comfort using landsat satellite images between 1989 and 2019: A case study in tehran. Remote Sens. 2021;13(21):4469. doi: 10.3390/rs13214469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13214469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan H, Chen Y, Zhang Y, Ming L, Xie Y. Urban sprawl and thermal response in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, 2000&#x2013;2020. Environ Res Commun. 2024;6:085023. doi: 10.1088/2515-7620/ad6cab</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2515-7620/ad6cab</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez FA, Vega-De-Lille M, Castillo-Atoche AA, L&#xf3;pez-Maldonado JT, Cruz-Fernandez M, Camacho-P&#xe9;rez E, et al. Geo-sensing-based analysis of urban heat island in the metropolitan area of Merida, Mexico. Sensors (Basel). 2024;24(19):6289. doi: 10.3390/s24196289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24196289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11479025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39409328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi Y, Shan L, Ke LN, Yang RX. Analysis of land surface temperature driving factors and spatial heterogeneity research based on geographically weighted regression model. Complexity. 2020;2020:2862917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Wang M, Zhang Z, Hu T, Xing J, He Z, et al. Geographical Detection of Urban Thermal Environment Based on the Local Climate Zones: A case study in Wuhan, China. Remote Sens. 2022;14(5):1067. doi: 10.3390/rs140510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs140510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Z, Liu Z, Liu X, Zheng W, Yin L. Urban heat islands and their effects on thermal comfort in the US: New York and New Jersey. Ecological Indicators. 2023;154:110765. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgescu M, Broadbent AM, Krayenhoff ES. Quantifying the decrease in heat exposure through adaptation and mitigation in twenty-first-century US cities. Nat Cities. 2023;1(1):42&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1038/s44284-023-00001-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44284-023-00001-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>