<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41073485</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>EECH HEED an adaptive hybrid clustering protocol for energy efficient soil monitoring in heterogeneous wireless sensor networks.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>35548</StartPage><MedlinePgn>35548</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">35548</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-19480-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Wireless Sensor Networks (WSNs) play a pivotal role in precision agriculture, especially for real-time soil health monitoring. However, the limited energy capacity of sensor nodes poses a significant challenge to achieving prolonged network lifetime and consistent data transmission. Existing clustering protocols often struggle with inefficient cluster head (CH) selection, limited adaptability to heterogeneous environments, and excessive control overhead. To address these issues, this paper proposes EECH-HEED, a hybrid and energy-efficient clustering model designed for soil monitoring in heterogeneous WSNs. The proposed protocol utilizes a dual-zone architecture: Zone 1, located near the base station, implements a HEED-based CH selection mechanism that considers both residual energy and communication cost for energy-aware clustering. Zone 2, positioned farther from the base station, employs an enhanced EECH-based hierarchical multi-hop clustering strategy, using residual energy and node degree to select primary and secondary CHs. Unlike the threshold-based hybrid clustering approach which, despite reducing redundant transmissions, relies on static thresholds-EECH-HEED introduces a dynamic threshold-based sensing mechanism. Here, hard and soft thresholds are continuously adjusted in real-time based on environmental change rates and node energy levels. This adaptive strategy significantly reduces energy consumption and extends the operational lifespan of sensor nodes. The model was rigorously tested using MATLAB simulations over 5000 rounds on a heterogeneous WSN setup inspired by real agricultural scenarios. Performance was benchmarked against leading protocols including LEACH, HEED, EECH, TCO, FPA, MIMO-HC, HTCCR, EEHP, and the HCRT model. EECH-HEED demonstrated marked improvements across multiple performance metrics-achieving a 33% reduction in Total Energy Consumption (TEC), a 15% increase in Packet Delivery Ratio (PDR), and a nearly 50% reduction in control overhead. It also recorded the lowest End-to-End Delay (190&#xa0;ms) and the highest number of alive nodes by the end of the simulation. With its zone-based design, adaptive thresholding, and hierarchical energy-aware clustering, EECH-HEED presents a scalable and low-overhead solution for sustainable soil health monitoring. Future work includes its integration with UAV-based data collection systems and IoT platforms to support intelligent farming infrastructures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaur</LastName><ForeName>Shinder</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering and Technology, Guru Nanak Dev University, Amritsar, 143005, India. shinderk1995@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Science and Information Technology, Swami Swatantranand Memorial College, Dinanagar, 143531, India. shinderk1995@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kour</LastName><ForeName>Satveer</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Computer Engineering and Technology, Guru Nanak Dev University, Amritsar, 143005, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Manjit</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering and Technology, Guru Nanak Dev University Regional Campus, Jalandhar, 44009, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clustering</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EECH</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HEED</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network Lifetime</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Agriculture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil Monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wireless Sensor Networks</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41073485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12514238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-19480-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-19480-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aslam, N., Xia, K., Haider, M. T. &amp; Hadi, M. U. Energy-aware adaptive weighted grid clustering algorithm for renewable wireless sensor networks. <i>Future Internet.</i><b>9</b>(4), 54. 10.3390/fi9040054 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fi9040054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilal, M., Munir, E. U. &amp; Alarfaj, F. K. Hybrid clustering and routing algorithm with threshold-based data collection for heterogeneous wireless sensor networks. <i>sensors</i><b>22</b>(15), 5471 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22155471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9331321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35897974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kour, S., Kaur, E. S., &amp; Kaur, S. (2022). MANETS, Routing Protocols and Mobility Models.&#xa0;Chief Editor, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satveer, S. K., Ubhi, J. S. &amp; Singh, M. QoS improvement using enhanced manhattan mobility model on proposed ant colony optimization technique in MANETs: ACO optimization in mobility efficient MANETS. <i>J. Sci. Ind. Res. (JSIR)</i><b>82</b>(06), 616&#x2013;628 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslam, N., Xia, K. &amp; Hadi, M. U. Optimal wireless charging inclusive of intellectual routing based on SARSA learning in renewable wireless sensor networks. <i>IEEE Sens. J.</i><b>19</b>(18), 8340&#x2013;8351. 10.1109/JSEN.2019.2918865 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JSEN.2019.2918865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslam, N., Wang, H., Aslam, M. F., Aamir, M. &amp; Hadi, M. U. Intelligent wireless charging path optimization for critical nodes in internet of things-integrated renewable sensor networks. <i>Sensors.</i><b>24</b>(22), 7294. 10.3390/s24227294 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s24227294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11597955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39599071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, T., Kundroo, M. &amp; Kim, T. WSN-driven advances in soil moisture estimation: A machine learning approach. <i>Electronics</i><b>13</b>(8), 1590 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics13081590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alrubaye, A. Q. &amp; Myderrizi, I. Improvement of cluster head selection in LEACH for reducing energy consumption in wireless sensor networks. <i>Int. J. Eng. Technol. IJET.</i><b>8</b>(1), 49&#x2013;57 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon, C., Cho, S. &amp; Lee, Y. Extending WSN lifetime with enhanced LEACH protocol in autonomous vehicle using improved K-means and advanced cluster configuration algorithms. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>14</b>(24), 11720 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app142411720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muosa, A. H. An improvement routing algorithm based on LEACH protocol. <i>Int J Tech Phys Probl Eng (IJTPE).</i><b>14</b>(3), 66&#x2013;72 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, P., Mahato, D., Sinha, A. &amp; Singh, S. An efficient LEACH clustering protocol to enhance the QoS of WSN. <i>Indian J. Artif. Intell. Neural Netw. (IJAINN)</i><b>3</b>(3), 1&#x2013;8 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M. K. et al. Hierarchical routing protocols for wireless sensor networks: Functional and performance analysis. <i>J. Sens.</i><b>2021</b>(1), 7459368 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/7459368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbar, M. S., Issa, S. S. &amp; Ali, A. H. Improving WSNs execution using energy-efficient clustering algorithms with consumed energy and lifetime maximization. <i>Indonesian J. Electr. Eng. Comput. Sci.</i><b>29</b>(2), 1122&#x2013;1131 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11591/ijeecs.v29.i2.pp1122-1131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudhiafi, W., Ezzedine, T. (2021). Optimization of multi-level HEED protocol in wireless sensor networks. In: <i>Applied Informatics: Fourth International Conference, ICAI 2021, Buenos Aires, Argentina</i>, October 28&#x2013;30, 2021, Proceedings 4&#xa0;(pp. 407&#x2013;418). Springer International Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pande, S. D. &amp; Ahammad, S. H. Improved clustering-based energy optimization with routing protocol in wireless sensor networks. <i>Res J Comput. Syst. Eng.</i><b>2</b>(1), 33&#x2013;39 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jubair, A. M. et al. Optimization of clustering in wireless sensor networks: techniques and protocols. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>11</b>(23), 11448 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app112311448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meenakshi, N. et al. Efficient communication in wireless sensor networks using optimized energy efficient engroove leach clustering protocol. <i>Tsinghua Sci. Technol.</i><b>29</b>(4), 985&#x2013;1001 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26599/TST.2023.9010056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adumbabu, I. &amp; Selvakumar, K. Energy efficient routing and dynamic cluster head selection using enhanced optimization algorithms for wireless sensor networks. <i>Energies</i><b>15</b>(21), 8016 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15218016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedham WB, Al-Qurabat AKM. An improved energy-efficient clustering protocol for wireless sensor networks. In: <i>2022 International Conference for Natural and Applied Sciences (ICNAS)</i>; 2022:23&#x2013;28. IEEE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattatraya, K. N. &amp; Rao, K. R. Hybrid based cluster head selection for maximizing network lifetime and energy efficiency in WSN. <i>J. King Saud Univ. Comput. Inf. Sci.</i><b>34</b>(3), 716&#x2013;726 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksuci.2019.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasim, A. A. et al. Energy-efficient wireless sensor network with an unequal clustering protocol based on a balanced energy method (EEUCB). <i>Sensors</i><b>21</b>(3), 784 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21030784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7866149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33503903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarajan, L. &amp; Thangavelu, S. Hybrid grey wolf sunflower optimisation algorithm for energy-efficient cluster head selection in wireless sensor networks for lifetime enhancement. <i>IET Commun.</i><b>15</b>(3), 384&#x2013;396 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/cmu2.12072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao, W., Tang, R. &amp; Xu, Y. A coverage optimization algorithm for the wireless sensor network with random deployment by using an improved flower pollination algorithm. <i>Forests</i><b>13</b>(10), 1690 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f13101690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, K. J. et al. Adaptive flower pollination algorithm-based energy efficient routing protocol for multi-robot systems. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 82417&#x2013;82434 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3086628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, J., Yuan, T., Xie, W., Yang, Z. &amp; Yu, D. An enhanced flower pollination algorithm with Gaussian perturbation for node location of a WSN. <i>Sensors.</i><b>23</b>(14), 6463 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s23146463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10385948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37514758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raslan, A. F., Ali, A. F., Darwish, A. &amp; El-Sherbiny, H. M. An improved sunflower optimization algorithm for cluster head selection in the internet of things. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 156171&#x2013;156186 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3126537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elfarra, B. K., Salha, M. A., Rasheed, R. S., Aldahdooh, J. &amp; Abusamra, A. A. Enhancing the lifetime of WSN using a modified ant colony optimization algorithm. <i>J. Wirel. Mobile Netw. Ubiquitous Comput. Depend. Appl.</i><b>14</b>(3), 143&#x2013;155 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasir, H. J. A., Ku-Mahamud, K. R. &amp; Kamioka, E. Energy efficient ant colony system for packet routing in wireless sensor network. <i>J. Phys. Conf. Ser.</i><b>2312</b>(1), 012003 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/2312/1/012003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaraj, M., Srinath, R. (2021). Hybrid Ant Colony Optimization for Sinkhole Detection in WSN.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, S., Kour, S. &amp; Singh, M. Energy efficiency in wireless sensor networks: comparing traditional and advanced clustering protocols. <i>Eng. Res. Express.</i><b>7</b>(1), 015258 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-8695/adb37b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal, N. &amp; Tripathi, R. Energy-efficient routing protocol for an IoT-based WSN system to monitor soil parameters in precision agriculture. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>12</b>(5), 3026. 10.3390/app12053026 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app12053026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh, S. &amp; Misra, S. Energy-efficient clustering and routing algorithms for wireless sensor networks: Comparative analysis and performance evaluation. <i>Wirel. Pers. Commun.</i><b>124</b>(3), 2301&#x2013;2321. 10.1007/s11277-022-09490-6 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11277-022-09490-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., Wang, G. &amp; Zhang, J. A fuzzy logic-based clustering protocol for wireless sensor networks. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 123456&#x2013;123467. 10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3101234 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3101234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai, X. M., Yang, L. &amp; Yang, L. Research and improvement of LEACH routing protocol. <i>Appl. Mech. Mater.</i><b>713</b>, 2296&#x2013;2299 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMM.713-715.2296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merabtine, N., Djenouri, D. &amp; Zegour, D. E. Towards energy efficient clustering in wireless sensor networks: A comprehensive review. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>9</b>, 92688&#x2013;92705 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2021.3092509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Gburi, K. H. A. (2022). Performance comparison of PEGASIS, HEED, and LEACH protocols in wireless sensor networks.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, S., Kour, S. &amp; Singh, M. Energy efficiency in wireless sensor networks: Comparing traditional and advanced clustering protocols. <i>Eng. Res. Express</i><b>7</b>(1), 015258 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-8695/adb37b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baniata, M., Reda, H. T., Chilamkurti, N. &amp; Abuadbba, A. Energy-efficient hybrid routing protocol for IoT communication systems in 5G and beyond. <i>Sensors</i><b>21</b>(2), 537 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21020537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7828529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33451047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhukya, S. N. &amp; Annavarapu, C. S. R. Hybrid reliable clustering algorithm with heterogeneous traffic routing for wireless sensor networks. <i>Sensors</i><b>25</b>(3), 864 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s25030864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11820824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39943503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J. et al. Wireless sensor network (WSN) configuration method to increase node energy efficiency through clustering and location information. <i>Symmetry</i><b>13</b>(3), 390 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sym13030390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>