<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41634222</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Friction stir welding parameter optimization for dissimilar AA2014 and AA5052 aluminium alloys.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7138</StartPage><MedlinePgn>7138</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7138</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-37562-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This scientific research has optimized the parameters of Friction Stir Welding (FSW) for dissimilar aluminium alloys of AA2014 and AA5052 by using Response Surface Methodology (RSM) with a Box-Behnken Design (BBD). Four critical processing variables, i.e., tool rotating speed (1500-2100&#xa0;rpm), pin geometry (triangle, circular, square), axial load (7-10 kN), and welding speed (10-20&#xa0;mm/min), were systematically varied to assess their influence on ultimate tensile strength (UTS), yield strength (YS), elongation (E), and microhardness (H). Multi-response optimization using the desirability function revealed a set of favourable conditions: 1879.95&#xa0;rpm, square pin, 10 kN axial load, and 17.62&#xa0;mm/min welding speed. Under these conditions the mechanical performance of the weld showed a balance of UTS&#x2009;=&#x2009;257.76&#xa0;MPa, YS&#x2009;=&#x2009;196.96&#xa0;MPa, E&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.41%, and H&#x2009;=&#x2009;100.96 Hv with a combined desirability of 0.880. Subsequent validation experiments proved the model to be reliable, with errors in the prediction of UTS and YS less than 1.5%. Microstructural examination showed that the optimized weld had a fine equiaxed grain structure and a homogeneous distribution of Al<sub>2</sub>CuMg precipitates in the stir zone that is due to complete dynamic recrystallization and thorough material mixing. On the contrary, coarse grains, clusters of precipitates, and tunnel defects were produced by sub-optimal parameters, which correlated with inferior mechanical properties. In this research, the integrated approach of RSM-BBD-desirability approach has been shown to be effective in the optimization of FSW of this dissimilar pair of alloys to produce defect-free joints with an improved strength-hardness balance suitable for lightweight structural applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soundararjan</LastName><ForeName>Seenivasan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Rathinam Technical Campus, Coimbatore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeevakarunya</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering, Rathinam Technical Campus, Coimbatore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raj Kumar</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Robotics and Automation, Dhaanish Ahmed Institute of Technology, Coimbatore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandraprakash</LastName><ForeName>R</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Robotics and Automation, Dhaanish Ahmed Institute of Technology, Coimbatore, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kannan</LastName><ForeName>Sathish</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, School of Engineering Architecture and Interior Design, Amity University Dubai, Dubai, UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saiyathibrahim</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Saveetha School of Engineering, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, SIMATS, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 602105, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson Santhosh</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, Jimma Institute of Technology, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia. johnsonsanthosh@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dissimilar aluminium alloys</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Friction stir welding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microhardness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Productivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Response surface methodology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tensile properties</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper. Ethical approval: The content studied in this article belongs to the field of metal processing, does not involve humans and animals. This article strictly follows the accepted principles of ethical and professional conduct. Consent to participate: All the authors consent to participate this work. Consent for publication: All the authors in this work have consented to publish this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41634222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12920769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-37562-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-37562-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ganesan, C., Manivannan, A., Seenivasan, S. &amp; Keerthi vasan, T. Experimental research on the wear properties of friction stir welded Al&#x2013;Li/Al&#x2013;Mg improved heterogeneous material joints. <i>Trans. Indian Inst. Metals</i><b>77</b>(6), 1711&#x2013;1718. 10.1007/s12666-024-03278-z (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12666-024-03278-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasikala, P. &amp; Madhusudhan, R. Performance assessment of different pin profiles in friction stir welding of AA2014 aluminum alloy: A microstructural and mechanical analysis. <i>J. Inst. Eng. (India): Ser. D</i><b>105</b>(3), 1781&#x2013;1791. 10.1007/s40033-023-00581-9 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40033-023-00581-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan, R. &amp; Pothur, H. A novel approach for the weld defect analysis of friction stir welded AA 6061&#x2013;T6-AA 5052&#x2013;H32 dissimilar aluminum alloy joints. <i>Weld. Int.</i>10.1080/09507116.2025.2472704 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09507116.2025.2472704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zondi, M. C. Factors that affect welding-induced residual stress and distortions in pressure vessel steels and their mitigation techniques: A review. <i>J. Press. Vessel Technol.</i><b>136</b>(4), 040801. 10.1115/1.4026564 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4026564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soundararjan, S. et al. Experimental study on wear performance of dissimilar aluminium alloy FSW joints optimized by RSM and desirability approach. <i>Eng. Rep.</i><b>7</b>(9), e70402. 10.1002/eng2.70402 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eng2.70402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathish, T. et al. Experimental investigation of the friction stir weldability of AA8006 with zirconia particle reinforcement and optimized process parameters. <i>Materials</i><b>14</b>(11), 2782. 10.3390/ma14112782 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14112782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8197271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34073828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kah, P., Rajan, R., Martikainen, J. &amp; Suoranta, R. Investigation of weld defects in friction-stir welding and fusion welding of aluminium alloys. <i>Int. J. Mech. Mater. Eng.</i><b>10</b>, 1&#x2013;10. 10.1186/s40712-015-0053-8 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40712-015-0053-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugender, S. Influence of tool pin profile and rotational speed on the formation of friction stir welding zone in AZ31 magnesium alloy. <i>J. Magnes. Alloy.</i><b>6</b>(2), 205&#x2013;213. 10.1016/j.jma.2018.05.001 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jma.2018.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulahem, K., Salem, S. B., Shiri, S. &amp; Bessrour, J. Experimental modeling and multi-response optimization in friction stir welding process parameters of AA2024-T3 using response surface methodology and desirability approach. <i>Exp. Tech.</i><b>48</b>(5), 833&#x2013;849. 10.1007/s40799-023-00691-9 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40799-023-00691-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feizollahi, V. et al. Effect of shoulder diameter, tool rotation speed, and arrangement of plates on mechanical and metallurgical properties of dissimilar aluminum 2024&#x2013;T3 and 7075&#x2013;T6 friction stir spot welding (FSSW). <i>Eng. Fail. Anal.</i><b>163</b>, 108548. 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108548 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safeen, W. et al. Predicting the tensile strength, impact toughness, and hardness of friction stir-welded AA6061-T6 using response surface methodology. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol.</i><b>87</b>, 1765&#x2013;1781. 10.1007/s00170-016-8565-9 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-016-8565-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzbanrad, J., Akbari, M., Asadi, P. &amp; Safaee, S. Characterization of the influence of tool pin profile on microstructural and mechanical properties of friction stir welding. <i>Metall. Mater. Trans. B.</i><b>45</b>, 1887&#x2013;1894. 10.1007/s11663-014-0089-9 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11663-014-0089-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C., Wang, J., Wang, Q., Xia, P. &amp; Li, D. 7075 aluminum alloy Friction Stir Welding (FSW): Quality analysis and mechanical properties with WC-Co tool. <i>Mater. Today Commun.</i><b>38</b>, 108203. 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108203 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.108203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramamurthy, M., Balasubramanian, P., Senthilkumar, N. &amp; Anbuchezhiyan, G. Influence of process parameters on the microstructure and mechanical properties of friction stir welds of AA2014 and AA6063 aluminium alloys using response surface methodology. <i>Mater. Res. Express</i><b>9</b>(2), 026528. 10.1088/2053-1591/ac5777 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/ac5777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, N. &amp; Gupta, M. Optimizing friction stir welding of AA7075 and AA8090 aluminum alloys: A desirability-driven investigation into mechanical and microstructural enhancement. <i>Eng. Res. Express</i><b>6</b>(2), 025573. 10.1088/2631-8695/ad58a1 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2631-8695/ad58a1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, S. &amp; Kumar, V. Optimization of friction stir welding parameters of dissimilar aluminium alloys 6061 and 5083 by using response surface methodology. <i>Proc. Inst. Mech. Eng. C J. Mech. Eng. Sci.</i><b>235</b>(23), 7009&#x2013;7020. 10.1177/09544062211005804 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09544062211005804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logesh, K. et al. Optimization of dissimilar AA5052 and AA2219 alloy joints in friction stir welding using Taguchi grey relational analysis. <i>J. Inorg. Organomet. Polym. Mater.</i>10.1007/s10904-024-03287-x (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10904-024-03287-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendran, C. et al. Mathematical modeling, optimization and prediction of friction stir spot welding parameters for dissimilar joining AA2024-T6 aluminium and AZ31B magnesium alloy in lap weld configuration. <i>Int. J. Interact. Des. Manuf. (IJIDeM)</i><b>19</b>(1), 275&#x2013;289. 10.1007/s12008-023-01669-y (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-023-01669-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arunkumar, D. &amp; Sekar, K. V. Influence of scandium interlayer on the mechanical and metallurgical characteristics of friction stir welded AA1200-H14/Sc/AA6061-T6. <i>Mater. Res. Express</i><b>11</b>(1), 016507. 10.1088/2053-1591/ad19b0 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/ad19b0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhuraj, P., Rajakumar, S., Sonar, T., Ivanov, M. &amp; Nathan, S. R. Mathematical modelling and development of response surfaces to predict and analyze the salt fog corrosion resistance of friction stir welded AA7075-T651 alloy joints: Effect of retrogression and reaging. <i>Int. J. Interact. Des. Manuf. (IJIDeM)</i><b>19</b>(1), 347&#x2013;363. 10.1007/s12008-024-01776-4 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-024-01776-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feizollahi, V. et al. The effect of pin diameter, tool penetration depth and plate arrangement on mechanical and metallurgical properties of 6061&#x2013;T6 and 5052&#x2013;T32 aluminum dissimilar joints in friction stir spot welding (FSSW). <i>Heliyon</i>10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e36962 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e36962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11407978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39296068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider, F., Hanif, M. W. &amp; Jahanzaib, M. Investigating the effects of novel cylindrical pins geometries and aging on the mechanical characteristics of friction stir welded Al-2024/Al-5754 joints. <i>Int. J. Interact. Des. Manuf. (IJIDeM)</i>10.1007/s12008-024-02105-5 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-024-02105-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, J., Kumar, G., Mehdi, H. &amp; Kumar, M. Optimization of FSW parameters on mechanical properties of different aluminum alloys of AA6082 and AA7050 by response surface methodology. <i>Int. J. Interact. Des. Manuf. (IJIDeM)</i><b>18</b>(3), 1359&#x2013;1371. 10.1007/s12008-023-01425-2 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-023-01425-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdi, H. &amp; Mishra, R. S. An experimental analysis and optimization of process parameters of AA6061 and AA7075 welded joint by TIG+ FSP welding using RSM. <i>Adv. Mater. Process. Technol.</i><b>8</b>(1), 598&#x2013;620. 10.1080/2374068X.2020.1829952 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2374068X.2020.1829952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salah, A. N. et al. Optimization of process parameters of friction stir welded joints of dissimilar aluminum alloys AA3003 and AA6061 by RSM. <i>Mater. Today: Proc.</i><b>56</b>, 1675&#x2013;1683. 10.1016/j.matpr.2021.10.288 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2021.10.288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdi, H. et al. Optimization of process parameters on the mechanical properties of AA6061/Al2O3 nanocomposites fabricated by multi-pass friction stir processing. <i>Mater. Today: Proc.</i><b>56</b>, 1995&#x2013;2003. 10.1016/j.matpr.2021.11.333 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2021.11.333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, S., Mishra, R. S., Mehdi, H., Gupta, R. &amp; Dubey, A. K. Optimization of processing variables of friction stir welded dissimilar composite joints of AA6061 and AA7075 using response surface methodology. <i>J. Adhes. Sci. Technol.</i><b>38</b>(6), 949&#x2013;968. 10.1080/01694243.2023.2243682 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01694243.2023.2243682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozkurt, Y. &amp; Bilici, M. K. Application of Taguchi approach to optimize of FSSW parameters on joint properties of dissimilar AA2024-T3 and AA5754-H22 aluminum alloys. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>51</b>, 513&#x2013;521. 10.1016/j.matdes.2013.04.074 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2013.04.074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghangas, G. &amp; Singhal, S. Effect of tool pin profile and dimensions on mechanical properties and microstructure of friction stir welded armor alloy. <i>Mater. Res. Express</i><b>5</b>(6), 066555. 10.1088/2053-1591/aacdb1 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/aacdb1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, X., Kalya, P., Landers, R. G., &amp; Krishnamurthy, K. Design and implementation of a nonlinear axial force controller for friction stir welding processes. In <i>2007 American Control Conference</i> 5553&#x2013;5558. (IEEE, 2007) 10.1109/ACC.2007.4282731</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal Babu, K. et al. Parameter optimization of friction stir welding of cryorolled AA2219 alloy using artificial neural network modeling with genetic algorithm. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol.</i><b>94</b>(9), 3117&#x2013;3129. 10.1007/s00170-017-0897-6 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-017-0897-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Bella, G., Favaloro, F. &amp; Borsellino, C. Effect of process parameters on friction stir welded joints between dissimilar aluminum alloys: A review. <i>Metals</i><b>13</b>(7), 1176. 10.3390/met13071176 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met13071176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, M. M. et al. Heat input and mechanical properties investigation of friction stir welded AA5083/AA5754 and AA5083/AA7020. <i>Metals</i><b>11</b>(1), 68. 10.3390/met11010068 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met11010068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. et al. High rotation speed friction stir welding for 2014 aluminum alloy thin sheets. <i>J. Mater. Eng. Perform.</i><b>26</b>(3), 1337&#x2013;1345. 10.1007/s11665-017-2524-y (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-017-2524-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, Q., Zhao, M. &amp; Zhang, Z. The Effect of high-temperature deformation on the mechanical properties and corrosion resistance of the 2024 aluminum alloy joint after friction stir welding. <i>Materials</i><b>17</b>(12), 2969. 10.3390/ma17122969 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17122969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38930338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdi, H., Batra, L., Singh, A. P. &amp; Malla, C. Multi-response optimization of FSW process parameters of dissimilar aluminum alloys of AA2014 and AA6061 by response surface methodology (RSM). <i>Int. J. Interact. Des. Manuf. (IJIDeM)</i><b>18</b>(3), 1507&#x2013;1522. 10.1007/s12008-023-01409-2 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12008-023-01409-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thangagiri, B., Sakthivel, A., Jeyasubramanian, K., Seenivasan, S. &amp; Raja, J. D. Modeling and optimization of removal of Pb (II) in aqueous solutions by biochar derived from neem leaves using central composite design of response surface methodology. <i>Biomass Convers. Biorefinery</i><b>14</b>(14), 16019&#x2013;16034. 10.1007/s13399-023-03904-8 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13399-023-03904-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamoli, S. ANN and RSM approach for modeling and optimization of designing parameters for a V down perforated baffle roughened rectangular channel. <i>Alex. Eng. J.</i><b>54</b>(3), 429&#x2013;446. 10.1016/j.aej.2015.03.018 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2015.03.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, W., Yang, P. &amp; Liu, Y. Multi-objective thermodynamic optimization of a free piston Stirling engine using response surface methodology. <i>Energy Convers. Manage.</i><b>176</b>, 147&#x2013;163. 10.1016/j.enconman.2018.09.011 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2018.09.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. Q. &amp; Liu, H. J. Effects of tool rotation speed on microstructures and mechanical properties of AA2219-T6 welded by the external non-rotational shoulder assisted friction stir welding. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>43</b>, 299&#x2013;306. 10.1016/j.matdes.2012.07.011 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2012.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar, A., Singh, K. &amp; Kumar, L. Effect of tool rotational speed and mechanisms associated with microstructure evolution and intermetallics formation in friction stir welding of aluminum alloy to titanium alloy. <i>J. Mater. Eng. Perform.</i><b>33</b>(13), 6748&#x2013;6759. 10.1007/s11665-023-08407-1 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-023-08407-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salih, O. S., Ou, H. &amp; Sun, W. Heat generation, plastic deformation and residual stresses in friction stir welding of aluminium alloy. <i>Int. J. Mech. Sci.</i><b>238</b>, 107827. 10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2022.107827 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2022.107827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdi, H. &amp; Mishra, R. S. Analysis of material flow and heat transfer in reverse dual rotation friction stir welding: A review. <i>Int. J. Steel Struct.</i><b>19</b>, 422&#x2013;434. 10.1007/s13296-018-0131-x (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13296-018-0131-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sayed, M. M., Shash, A. Y., Abd-Rabou, M. &amp; ElSherbiny, M. G. Welding and processing of metallic materials by using friction stir technique: A review. <i>J. Adv. Join. Process.</i><b>3</b>, 100059. 10.1016/j.jajp.2021.100059 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jajp.2021.100059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda, B., Garg, A., Jian, Z., Heidarzadeh, A. &amp; Gao, L. Characterization of the tensile properties of friction stir welded aluminum alloy joints based on axial force, traverse speed, and rotational speed. <i>Front. Mech. Eng.</i><b>11</b>, 289&#x2013;298. 10.1007/s11465-016-0393-y (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11465-016-0393-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elangovan, K., Balasubramanian, V. &amp; Valliappan, M. Effect of tool pin profile and tool rotational speed on mechanical properties of friction stir welded AA6061 aluminium alloy. <i>Mater. Manuf. Process.</i><b>23</b>(3), 251&#x2013;260. 10.1080/10426910701860723 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10426910701860723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, Z. et al. Effect of tool offset and tool rotational speed on enhancing mechanical property of Al/Mg dissimilar FSW joints. <i>Metall. Mater. Trans. A.</i><b>44</b>, 3721&#x2013;3731. 10.1007/s11661-013-1700-4 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11661-013-1700-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R. S., Vinodh, S., Satishkumar, P. &amp; Seenivasan, S. Evaluation of machinability performance of T51603 using response surface methodology and grey relational analysis. <i>Mat&#xe9;ria (Rio de Janeiro)</i><b>29</b>(1), e20230322. 10.1590/1517-7076-RMAT-2023-0322 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-7076-RMAT-2023-0322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg, A., Raturi, M. &amp; Bhattacharya, A. Strength, failure and microstructure development for friction stir welded AA6061-T6 joints with different tool pin profiles. <i>CIRP J. Manuf. Sci. Technol.</i><b>29</b>, 99&#x2013;114. 10.1016/j.cirpj.2020.03.001 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cirpj.2020.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubit, A., Trzepieci&#x144;ski, T., Kluz, R., Ocha&#x142;ek, K. &amp; Slota, J. Multi-criteria optimisation of friction stir welding parameters for EN AW-2024-T3 aluminium alloy joints. <i>Materials</i><b>15</b>(15), 5428. 10.3390/ma15155428 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15155428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35955362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anas, N. M., Dhindaw, B. K., Zuhailawati, H., Abdullah, T. K. &amp; Anasyida, A. S. Effect of initial microstructure on properties of cryorolled Al 5052 alloy subjected to different annealing treatment temperatures. <i>J. Mater. Eng. Perform.</i><b>27</b>(11), 6206&#x2013;6217. 10.1007/s11665-018-3645-7 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-018-3645-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navya, G. et al. Experimental and numerical simulation of mechanical behaviour of ultrafine grained AA 2014 Al alloy. <i>Mech. Solids</i><b>57</b>(3), 590&#x2013;596. 10.3103/S0025654422030177 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3103/S0025654422030177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, Z. Y., Feng, A. H., Chen, D. L. &amp; Shen, J. Recent advances in friction stir welding/processing of aluminum alloys: Microstructural evolution and mechanical properties. <i>Crit. Rev. Solid State Mater. Sci.</i><b>43</b>(4), 269&#x2013;333. 10.1080/10408436.2017.1358145 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408436.2017.1358145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, P., Wu, C. &amp; Shi, L. Analysis and characterization of dynamic recrystallization and grain structure evolution in friction stir welding of aluminum plates. <i>Acta Mater.</i><b>207</b>, 116692. 10.1016/j.actamat.2021.116692 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2021.116692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazi, N., Ifires, M., Mehala, S. &amp; Chopart, J. P. Corrosion behavior on the different zones of AA2014 welded aluminum alloy by AA5554 filler aluminum alloy with TIG process: Before and after solution heat treatments followed by ageing. <i>Russ. J. Non-Ferr. Metals</i><b>58</b>, 516&#x2013;524. 10.3103/S1067821217050169 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3103/S1067821217050169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh, K. S. &amp; Tripati, K. Microstructural characterization and electrochemical behavior of AA2014 Al-Cu-Mg-Si alloy of various tempers. <i>J. Mater. Eng. Perform.</i><b>27</b>(11), 5926&#x2013;5937. 10.1007/s11665-018-3694-y (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-018-3694-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, K. et al. Mechanical behavior and strengthening mechanisms in ultrafine grain precipitation-strengthened aluminum alloy. <i>Acta Mater.</i><b>62</b>, 141&#x2013;155. 10.1016/j.actamat.2013.09.042 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actamat.2013.09.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Y. et al. Vacancy-induced &#x3b8;&#x2032; precipitation during ultrasonic-affected friction stir welding of Al&#x2013;Cu alloy. <i>J. Mater. Sci.</i><b>55</b>(29), 14626&#x2013;14641. 10.1016/j.msea.2022.142751 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2022.142751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attallah, M. M., Davis, C. L. &amp; Strangwood, M. Influence of base metal microstructure on microstructural development in aluminium based alloy friction stir welds. <i>Sci. Technol. Weld. Joining</i><b>12</b>(4), 361&#x2013;369. 10.1179/174329307X164238 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/174329307X164238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izadi, H., Sandstrom, R. &amp; Gerlich, A. P. Grain growth behavior and Hall-Petch strengthening in friction stir processed Al 5059. <i>Metall. Mater. Trans. A.</i><b>45</b>, 5635&#x2013;5644. 10.1007/s11661-014-2492-x (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11661-014-2492-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K., Naumov, A., Panchenko, E. &amp; Panchenko, O. A review on friction stir welding of high-strength Al-Zn-Mg Alloy: Insights on second-phase particles. <i>Materials</i><b>17</b>(20), 5107. 10.3390/ma17205107 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17205107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11509272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39459812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y., Paramatmuni, C. &amp; Avcu, E. Void nucleation and growth from heterophases and the exploitation of new toughening mechanisms in metals. <i>Crystals</i><b>13</b>(6), 860. 10.3390/cryst13060860 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst13060860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanikodi, S., Giri, J., Ramesh, P. T., Jagadeesan, A. K. &amp; Saravanan, R. Optimization of friction stir processing to improve the mechanical properties of bone fixation plate inputs made of ZK60 magnesium alloy. <i>Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol.</i><b>136</b>(1), 297&#x2013;314. 10.1007/s00170-024-14002-y (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-024-14002-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar, A., Suwas, S. &amp; Kailas, S. V. Two-pass friction stir welding of aluminum alloy to titanium alloy: A simultaneous improvement in mechanical properties. <i>Mater. Sci. Eng., A</i><b>733</b>, 199&#x2013;210. 10.1016/j.msea.2018.07.057 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2018.07.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murr, L. E. A review of FSW research on dissimilar metal and alloy systems. <i>J. Mater. Eng. Perform.</i><b>19</b>(8), 1071&#x2013;1089. 10.1007/s11665-010-9598-0 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11665-010-9598-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghate, N. D., Sood, A., Srivastava, A. &amp; Shrivastava, A. Ductile fracture based joint formation mechanism during friction stir welding. <i>Int. J. Mech. Sci.</i><b>168</b>, 105293. 10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2019.105293 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2019.105293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>