<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41864881</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Multi-trait stability selection drives genetic gains in cowpea [Vigna unguiculata (L.) Walp.] under high-temperature stress.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">519</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-026-08597-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Cowpea (<i>Vigna unguiculata</i> (L.) Walp.) is a crucial food and fodder crop in regions characterised by high temperatures. However, its reproductive stages are particularly sensitive to heat stress, leading to reduced pollen viability, pod set, and yield. Therefore, developing and deploying high-temperature-tolerant cultivars is crucial for maintaining productivity under changing climatic conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 250 diverse cowpea accessions, along with five checks, were evaluated at Baramati and Jodhpur during the 2022&#x2013;2023 growing season under both normal and late sowing conditions to simulate high-temperature stress. Growth, yield, and physiological traits, including canopy temperature, were measured. Multi-trait stability indices, including the multi-trait genotype-ideotype distance index (MGIDI), the multi-trait stability index (MTSI), the multi-trait mean performance and stability index (MTMPS), Mean Performance and Stability (MPS) analysis and the factor analysis-based BLUP index (FAI-BLUP), were utilised to identify superior genotypes. Further, genetic parameters were also estimated using mixed linear models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Late sowing exposed genotypes to temperatures exceeding 35&#xa0;&#xb0;C during flowering, inducing severe reproductive stress; only 147 of 250 accessions successfully flowered and set seeds. Traits such as seed yield, pods per plant, and seeds per pod showed high heritability (&#x2265;&#x2009;60%) and considerable genetic variation, while canopy temperature exhibited lower variability. Grain yield was positively correlated with pods per plant (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.40) and grains per pod (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.36), and negatively correlated with canopy temperature (<i>r</i> = &#x2212;&#x2009;0.35). Multi-trait indices identified 29 superior genotypes, with six [G044 (IC488270), G078 (EC240920), G080 (IC488085), G112 (EC240868), G114 (EC243927), G142 (IC402161)] consistently selected across all models. Predicted selection gains were high for grain yield (+&#x2009;18.7%), pods per plant (+&#x2009;11.2%), and grains per pod (+&#x2009;8.5%). Several genotypes [G066 (EC240878), G080 (IC488085), G112 (EC240868)] demonstrated both high yield and stability across environments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study reveals substantial genetic variation for high-temperature tolerance in cowpea, highlighting the value of integrating multi-environment phenotyping with multi-trait stability indices for robust selection. The identified genotypes provide immediate candidates for cultivar release and represent valuable genetic resources for breeding programs aiming to develop heat-resilient cowpea varieties.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12870-026-08597-5.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ps</LastName><ForeName>Basavaraj</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Abiotic Stress Management, Baramati, 413115, India. bassuptl@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biradar</LastName><ForeName>Mallikarjun</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Bureau of Plant Genetic Resources, New Delhi, 110012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meena</LastName><ForeName>Vijay Singh</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR- Central Arid Zone Research Institute, Jodhpur, 342003, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tripathi</LastName><ForeName>Kuldeep</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Bureau of Plant Genetic Resources, New Delhi, 110012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Babar</LastName><ForeName>Rohit</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Abiotic Stress Management, Baramati, 413115, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sreekanth</LastName><ForeName>Dasari</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-Directorate of Weed Research, Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh, 482010, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Km</LastName><ForeName>Boraiah</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Abiotic Stress Management, Baramati, 413115, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cb</LastName><ForeName>Harisha</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Abiotic Stress Management, Baramati, 413115, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halli</LastName><ForeName>Hanamant M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Abiotic Stress Management, Baramati, 413115, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>C</LastName><ForeName>Anil Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-Central Rice Research Institute, Cuttack, 753006, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hb</LastName><ForeName>Santosh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-Central Research Institute for Dryland Agriculture, Santosh Nagar, Hyderabad, 500059, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sultana</LastName><ForeName>Rafat</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Abiotic Stress Management, Baramati, 413115, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K</LastName><ForeName>Sammi Reddy</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICAR-National Institute of Abiotic Stress Management, Baramati, 413115, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>OXX01737</GrantID><Agency>ICAR-NICRA under the project "Phenotyping of Pulses for Enhanced Tolerance to Drought and Heat</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="eng"><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Screened 250 cowpea accessions; 147 reproduced under &gt;&#x2009;35&#xa0;&#xb0;C field heat stress. Grain yield showed high heritability (71.4%) and a wide range (1.0&#x2013;52.5&#xa0;g/plant). Multi-trait indices identified 29 superior heat-resilient genotypes. Six genotypes [G044 (IC488270), G078 (EC240920), G080 (IC488085), G112 (EC240868), G114 (EC243927), G142 (IC402161)] were selected across all models owing to multi-trait superiority (high grain yield, 3-4&#xa0;&#xb0;C lower canopy temperature under stress). Predicted selection gains: yield&#x2009;+&#x2009;18.7%, pods&#x2009;+&#x2009;11.2%, grains per pod&#x2009;+&#x2009;8.5%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12870-026-08597-5.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breeding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cowpea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Germplasm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heat stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heritability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yield</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41864881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13005303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-026-08597-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-026-08597-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Boukar O, Fatokun C, Huynh BL, Roberts PA, Close TJ. Genomic tools in cowpea breeding programs: status and perspectives. Front Plant Sci. 2018;9:1346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4891349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27375632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed SB, Ongom PO, Togola A, Boukar O. Enhancing cowpea tolerance to elevated temperature: achievements, challenges and future directions. Agronomy. 2024;14:513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14030513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Kakani V, Surabhi G, Reddy K. Cowpea (<i>Vigna unguiculata</i> [L.] Walp.) genotypes response to multiple abiotic stresses. J Photochem Photobiol B. 2010;100:135&#x2013;46.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jphotobiol.2010.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20605100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall AE. Breeding cowpea for future climates. Crop Adaptation to Climate Change. Hoboken, NJ, USA: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2011. pp. 340&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed FE, Hall AE, DeMason DA. Heat injury during floral development in cowpea (<i>Vigna unguiculata</i>, Fabaceae). Am J Bot. 1992;79:784&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.1537-2197.1992.tb13655.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barros JRA, Guimaraes MJM, Silva RME, Rego MTC, de Melo NF, de Melo Chaves AR, Angelotti F. Selection of cowpea cultivars for high temperature tolerance: physiological, biochemical and yield aspects. Physiol Mol Biol Plants. 2021;27:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12298-020-00919-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33627960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrag MOA, Hall AE. Reproductive responses of cowpea to heat stress: genotypic differences in tolerance to heat at flowering. Crop Sci. 1983;23:1088&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2135/cropsci1983.0011183X002300060016x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrag MOA, Hall AE. Reproductive responses of cowpea (<i>Vigna unguiculata</i> (L.)Walp.) to heat stress. II. Responses to night air temperature. Field Crops Res. 1984;8:17&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-4290(84)90049-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes LRDL, Pinheiro PR, Pinheiro CL, Lima KAP, Dutra AS. Germination and vigour in seeds of the cowpea in response to salt and heat stress. Rev Caatinga. 2019;32:143&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1983-21252019v32n115rc</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandalinas SI, Mittler R, Balfagon D, Arbona V, Gomez-Cadenas A. Plant adaptations to the combination of drought and high temperatures. Physiol Plant. 2018;162:2&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ppl.12540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28042678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen CL, Hall AE. Responses of cowpea (<i>Vigna unguiculata</i> (L.)Walp.) in the field to high night air temperature during flowering. II. Plant responses. Field Crops Res. 1985;10:181&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-4290(85)90025-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall AE. Sustainable productivity, heat tolerance. Encyclopedia of Sustainability Science and Technology. New York, NY, USA: Springer; 2013. pp. 599&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva JdA, Barros JRA, Silva EG. Rocha MdM, Angelotti F. Cowpea: prospecting for heat-tolerant genotypes. Agronomy. 2024;14:1969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14091969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan W, Kang MS. GGE biplot analysis: a graphical tool for breeders, geneticists, and agronomists. Boca Raton, FL: CRC; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaezi B, Pour-Aboughadareh A, Mohammadi R, Mehraban A, Hossein-Pour T, Koohkan E, et al. Integrating different stability models to investigate genotype x environment interactions and identify stable and high-yielding barley genotypes. Euphytica. 2019;215:63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10681-019-2386-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quintero A, Molero G, Reynolds MP, Calderini DF. Trade-off between grain weight and grain number in wheat depends on GxE interaction: a case study of an elite CIMMYT panel (CIMCOG). Eur J Agron. 2018;92:17&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eja.2017.09.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay KW, Wilkinson GN. The analysis of adaptation in a plant breeding programme. Aust J Agric. 1963;14:742&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/AR9630742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberhart SA, Russell WA. Stability parameters for comparing varieties. Crop Sci. 1966;6:36&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2135/cropsci1966.0011183X000600010011x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendal E. GGE biplot analysis of multi-environment yield trials in barley (<i>Hordeum vulgare</i> L.) cultivars. Ekin J Crop Breed Gen. 2016;2:90&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singamsetti A, Zaidi PH, Seetharam K, Vinayan MT, Olivoto T, Mahato A, et al. Genetic gains in tropical maize hybrids across moisture regimes with multi-trait-based index selection. Front Plant Sci. 2023;14:1147424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2023.1147424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10020505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36938016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith H. A discriminant function for plant selection. Ann Eugenics. 1936;7:240&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-1809.1936.tb02143.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazel LN. The genetic basis for constructing selection indexes. Genetics. 1943;28:476&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/genetics/28.6.476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1209225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17247099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha JRDSAC, MaChado JC, Carneiro PCS. Multitrait index based on factor analysis and ideotype-design: proposal and application on elephant grass breeding for bioenergy. GCB Bioenergy. 2018;10:52&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcbb.12443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivoto T, Lucio ADC, da Silva JAG, Sari BG, Diel MI. Mean performance and stability in multi-environment trials II: selection based on multiple traits. Agron J. 2019b;111:2961&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2134/agronj2019.03.0221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuffo AM, Steiner F, Aguilera JG, Teodoro PE, Teodoro LPR, Busch A, et al. Multi-trait stability index: a tool for simultaneous selection of soya bean genotypes in drought and saline stress. J Agron Crop Sci. 2020;206:815&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jac.12409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivoto T, Nardino M. MGIDI: toward an effective multivariate selection in biological experiments. Bioinformatics. 2021;37:1383&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btaa981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33226063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivoto T, Lucio ADC. Metan: an R package for multi-environment trial analysis. Methods Ecol Evol. 2021;11:783&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.13384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivoto T, Lucio ADC, da Silva JAG, Marchioro VS. Mean performance and stability in multi-environment trials I: combining features of AMMI and BLUP techniques. Agron J. 2019a;111:2949&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2134/agronj2019.03.0220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar P, Navathe S, Yashavanthakumar KJ, Kumari J, Kumar S, Basavaraj PS, Singh SK, Singh GP, Oak M. Effective selection criteria for high-throughput wheat drought tolerance screening using integrated physiological and statistical approaches. Plant Physiol Rep. 2025;40:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall AE. Breeding for adaptation to drought and heat in cowpea. Eur J Agron. 2004;21:447&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eja.2004.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biradar M, Tripathi K, Meena VS, Basavaraj PS, Kumari J, Reddappa SB, Wankhede D, Jacob SR, Archak S. Morpho-physiological traits underpinning high-temperature stress tolerance in cowpea (<i>Vigna unguiculata</i> L. Walp). Genet Resour Crop Evol. 2025;1:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basavaraj PS, Rane JA. Avenues to realize potential of phenomics to accelerate crop breeding for heat tolerance. Plant Physiol Rep. 2020;25:594&#x2013;610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40502-020-00552-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail AM, Hall A. Cowpea adaptation to drought: leaf morphology and physiology in relation to water use efficiency. Field Crops Res. 1998;60:209&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B Lepekhov S. Canopy temperature depression for drought- and heat stress tolerance in wheat breeding. Vavilovskii zhurnal genetiki i selektsii. 2022;26(2):196&#x2013;201. 10.18699/VJGB-22-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18699/VJGB-22-24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8983952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue H, Olivoto T, Bu J, Li J, Wei J, Xie J, Chen S, Peng H, Nardino M, Jiang X. Multi-trait selection for mean performance and stability of maize hybrids in mega-environments delineated using envirotyping techniques. Front Plant Sci. 2022;13:1030521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2022.1030521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9702090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36452111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fellahi ZEA, Hannachi A, Bouzerzour H. Expected genetic gains from mono-trait and index-based selection in advanced bread wheat (<i>Triticum aestivum</i> L.) populations. Revista Facultad Nacional de Agronom&#xed;a Medell&#xed;n. 2020;73:9131&#x2013;41. 10.15446/rfnam.v73n2.77806</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>