<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41723277</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spatiotemporal imbalance of regional water shortage risk based on copulas and concentration index.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10078</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-41016-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Water resources are essential for human survival and development. Ensuring sufficient water supply to meet living, production, and ecological demands has emerged as a critical challenge for regions facing water scarcity. In response to the increasingly severe water shortage in Central Yunnan, the Chinese government has invested over 100&#xa0;billion yuan in implementing the Central Yunnan Water Diversion Project (CYWDP). Accurately assessing and predicting the project&#x2019;s impact on water shortage risk and its spatiotemporal imbalance in the receiving regions is crucial for fostering sustainable and high-quality regional development. In this study, we propose an integrated methodological framework that combines Copula functions with a concentration index to evaluate the effects of the CYWDP on water shortage risk and its spatiotemporal imbalance in the Yuxi water-receiving area. First, based on risk theory, we develop a water shortage risk assessment model by integrating Kernel Density Estimation (KDE) with Copula functions to evaluate water shortage risk under various scenarios. This model accounts for the heterogeneous importance of domestic, industrial, agricultural, and ecological water uses. Second, a simplified concentration index is introduced to quantify the spatiotemporal imbalance of water shortage risk. The results reveal that: (1) Water shortage risk in the Yuxi water-receiving area exhibits strong seasonality, with spring being the highest-risk period, in approximately 80% of years falling into moderate-risk zones. Interannual variability in risk is high and strongly negatively correlated with precipitation, and only in wet years can water supply security be effectively ensured. (2) Due to differences in precipitation, groundwater availability, and the number of water storage projects, sub-regions display heterogeneous distributions of water shortage risk, with significant spatial imbalance. Intra annual variations are also evident, and more pronounced in dry years compared with wet years. (3) Without considering the supplemental supply from the CYWDP, the receiving area is projected to enter a high-risk zone by 2030 and 2040. However, with the CYWDP, the overall risk is expected to decrease to a moderate level by 2030, and by 2040, increased water transfers could alleviate risks and mitigate spatial imbalances. This study provides critical insights for evaluating the socio-economic benefits of the CYWDP and offers guidance for water resource allocation strategies. Moreover, the proposed framework serves as a methodological reference for analogous studies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Tanghui</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Geography, Yunnan Normal University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surveying and Mapping Engineering Institute of Yunnan Province, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Dingjie</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surveying and Mapping Engineering Institute of Yunnan Province, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Zhihua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Citic Zhengye Investment Co., Ltd, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Map Institute of Yunnan Province, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xi</LastName><ForeName>Wenfei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Geography, Yunnan Normal University, Kunming, China. xiwenfei911@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Shixiang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Institute of Water &amp; Hydropower Engineering Investigation, Design and Research, Kunming, China. 13078773756@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jinming</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yunnan Institute of Water &amp; Hydropower Engineering Investigation, Design and Research, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiankai</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kunming Engineering Corporation Limited, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhike</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dali Branch of Yunnan Hydrology and Water Resources Bureau, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Geography, Yunnan Normal University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>89-Y50G31-9001-22/23-05</GrantID><Agency>Demonstration project of comprehensive government management and large-scale industrial application of the major special project of CHEOS</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KLMHER-K25</GrantID><Agency>Open Funds of the Key Laboratory of Mountain Hazards and Engineering Resilience, Chinese Academy of Sciences</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Assessment framework</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Central Yunnan Water Diversion Project</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Concentration index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Copula</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatiotemporal Imbalance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water shortage risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yuxi Water-Receiving area</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics approval: This is an original article that did not use other information, which requires ethical approval. Consent to participate: All authors participated in this article. Consent for publication: All authors have given consent for publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41723277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13022236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-41016-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-41016-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>IPCC. : Summary for Policymakers. In: Climate Change 2023: Synthesis Report. Contribution of Working Groups I, II and III to the Sixth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change [R]. Geneva, Switzerland: IPCC, 2023. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min, S.-K. et al. Human contribution to more-intense precipitation extremes. <i>Nature</i><b>470</b>, 378&#x2013;81 (2011).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature09763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21331039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudmundsson, L. et al. Globally observed trends in mean and extreme river flow attributed to climate change. <i>Science</i><b>371</b>, 1159&#x2013;62 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aba3996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33707264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, D., Zou, L. &amp; Zhou, T. Extreme climate event changes in China in the 1.5 and 2&#xb0;C warmer climates: Results from statistical and dynamical downscaling [J]. <i>J. Geophys. Res. Atmos.</i><b>123</b>(18), 10,215-10,30 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2018JD028835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, D. &amp; Wang, N. Water cycle changes: Interpretation of IPCC AR6. <i>Climate Change Research</i><b>17</b>(06), 699&#x2013;704 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J., Chen, H. &amp; Tian, Z. Interpretation of IPCC AR6: Climate change and water security. <i>Climate Change Research</i><b>18</b>(04), 405&#x2013;13 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuannukul, W., Phumiphan, A. &amp; Kangrang, A. Cross-drainage culvert design under global climate and land use changes. <i>ARPN J. Eng. Appl. Sci.</i><b>16</b>(10), 1036&#x2013;44 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suwannachai, L. et al. Integrating hydrological models for improved flash flood risk assessment and mitigation strategies in Northeastern Thailand. <i>Water</i><b>17</b>(3), 345 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w17030345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brauman, K. A. et al. Water depletion: An improved metric for incorporating seasonal and dry-year water scarcity into water risk assessments. <i>Elementa: Science of the Anthropocene</i><b>4</b>, 000083 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. R, B. et al. Alleviating water scarcity by optimizing crop mixes. <i>Nat. Water</i><b>1</b>(12), 1035&#x2013;47 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44221-023-00155-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonnen, M. M. &amp; Hoekstra, A. Y. Four billion people facing severe water scarcity. <i>Sci. Adv.</i><b>2</b>(2), e1500323 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.1500323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4758739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26933676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi, M. Global water shortage and potable water safety; Today&#x2019;s concern and tomorrow&#x2019;s crisis. <i>Environ. Int.</i><b>158</b>, 106936 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2021.106936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34655888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, L. et al. Characteristics and origins of drought disasters in Southwest China in nearly 60 years [J]. <i>Acta Geogr. Sin.</i><b>69</b> (05), 632&#x2013;639 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, S., Fang, C. &amp; Lv, J. Spatial inequality of water footprint in China: A detailed decomposition of inequality from water use types and drivers. <i>J. Hydrol.</i><b>553</b>, 398&#x2013;407 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2017.08.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, Y. China&#x2019;s water security: Current status, emerging challenges and future prospects. <i>Environ. Sci. Policy</i><b>54</b>, 106&#x2013;25 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envsci.2015.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. The most representative National Key Water Conservancy Project under construction: Central Yunnan Water Diversion Project. <i>Tunnel Construction</i><b>39</b>(3), 511&#x2013;22 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di, L. et al. South-to-North water diversion stabilizing Beijing&#x2019;s groundwater levels. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>11</b>(1), 3665 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-17428-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7374106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32694568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. et al. Continuing severe water shortage in the water-receiving area of the South-To-North Water Diversion Eastern Route Project from 2002 to 2020. <i>Water Resour. Res.</i>10.1029/2022WR034365 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2022WR034365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, X. <i>Evaluation of water scarcity in China considering inter-basin water transfer [D]</i> (Dalian University of Technology, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, W., Shao, D. &amp; Jiang, Y. Risk evaluation of water shortage in source area of Middle Route Project for South-to-North Water Transfer in China. <i>Water Resour. Manage.</i><b>26</b>(12), 3479&#x2013;93 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11269-012-0086-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao, Q., Zhang, S. &amp; Chen, J. Risk assessment and prediction of water shortages in Beijing. <i>Resour. Sci.</i><b>35</b>(1), 140&#x2013;7 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenting, Y. &amp; Di, L. R. S B, et al. Human intervention will stabilize groundwater storage across the north China plain [J]. <i>Water Resour. Research</i>, <b>58</b>(2). (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Study on Water Resources Risk in Beijing after South-North Water Transfer Project [J]. <i>J. China Hydrology</i>. <b>35</b> (04), 55&#x2013;61 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Su, S. &amp; Zuo, Q. Risk analysis of water resource shortage in Baiyangdian District before and after cross basin water transfer [J]. <i>Journal of North China university of water resources and electric power (natural science edition)</i><b>1</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, S. et al. Unraveling the effect of inter-basin water transfer on reducing water scarcity and its inequality in China. <i>Water Res.</i><b>194</b>, 116931 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2021.116931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33636664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, T. et al. Pollution exacerbates China&#x2019;s water scarcity and its regional inequality. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>11</b>(1), 650 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-14532-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6994511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32005847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. The effectiveness of the South-to&#x2010;North Water Diversion Middle Route Project on water delivery and groundwater recovery in North China Plain [J]. <i>Water Resour. Res.</i><b>56</b>(10), e2019WR026759 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2019WR026759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, L. et al. Risk loss model of water supply and water demand based on copula function and its applications [J]. <i>Syst. Engineering-Theory Pract.</i><b>36</b> (02), 517&#x2013;527 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, S. et al. Daily reference evapotranspiration and meteorological drought forecast using high-dimensional Copula joint distribution model [J]. <i>Trans. Chin. Soc. Agricultural Eng.</i><b>36</b> (09), 143&#x2013;151 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. et al. Development of a multi-GCMs Bayesian copula method for assessing multivariate drought risk under climate change: A case study of the Aral Sea basin [J]. <i>Catena</i>10.1016/j.catena.2022.106048 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2022.106048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Gu, S. &amp; Zhang, T. Synchronous-asynchronous encounter probability analysis of high-low runoff for Jinsha River, China, using Copulas* [J]. <i>MATEC Web Conf.</i><b>246</b>, 01094 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/matecconf/201824601094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, T. et al. A water shortage risk assessment model based on kernel density estimation and copulas. <i>Water</i><b>16</b>(11), 1465 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w16111465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, L. et al. A new multiple integral model for water shortage risk assessment and its application in Beijing, China. <i>Nat. Hazards</i><b>80</b>(1), 43&#x2013;67 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-015-1955-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, L. et al. Monthly risk assesment model of water supply and demand based on logistic regression DEA and its application [J]. <i>J. Nat. Resour.</i><b>31</b> (01), 177&#x2013;186 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian, L. et al. Model for water shortage risk econimic losses based on M-Copula and its application [J]. <i>J. Appl. Basic. Eng. Sci.</i><b>30</b> (04), 907&#x2013;917 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongarmart, P. et al. Improving Reservoir Operation Efficiency Using Electric Eel Foraging Optimization and Transit Search Algorithms with Standard Operating Policy: Nong Han-Kumphawapi Case Study [J]. <i>ARPN J. Eng. Appl. Sci.</i><b>20</b> (6), 300&#x2013;313 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. Inequality Indexes for Measuring Between-Groups Mean Difference of Size and Spatial Distributions [J]. <i>Acta Sci. Nat. Univ. Pekin.</i><b>55</b>(06), 1097&#x2013;1102 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Theory and assessment method of water resources risk [J]. <i>J. Hydraul. Eng.</i><b>50</b> (08), 980&#x2013;989 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, P. et al. Risk assessment of water resource shortages in the Aksu River basin of northwest China under climate change [J]. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>305</b>, 114394 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2021.114394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34995939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allan, C., Xia, J. &amp; Pahl-Wostl, C. Climate change and water security: Challenges for adaptive water management [J]. <i>Curr. Opin. Environ. Sustain.</i><b>5</b>(6), 625&#x2013;632 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cosust.2013.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, Y. et al. Studies on Distribution Characteristics and Variation Trend of the Regional Drought Events over Yunnan in Recent 55 Years [J]. <i>Meteorological Monthly</i>. <b>44</b> (9), 1169&#x2013;1178 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C. et al. Water resource vulnerability assessment methods and applications [J]. <i>South-to-North Water Transfers Water Sci. Technol.</i><b>23</b> (01), 99&#x2013;109 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan, B. et al. Fuzzy comprehensive assessment of water shortage risk [J]. <i>Journal Hydraulic Engineering</i>, (08): 906&#x2013;912. (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejda, G. E. &amp; McNamara, M. J. <i>Principles of risk management and insurance [M]</i> (Cengage Learning, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ningpeng, D., Wenhai, G. &amp; Jixue, C. A hybrid hydrologic modelling framework with data-driven and conceptual reservoir operation schemes for reservoir impact assessment and predictions. <i>J. Hydrol.</i>10.1016/j.jhydrol.2023.129246 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2023.129246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B. et al. Research on the Social Stability Risk Assessment and Empirical Analysis of Hydraulic Engineering Construction [J]. <i>China Popul. Resour. Environ.</i><b>25</b> (04), 149&#x2013;154 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junguo, L. et al. Water scarcity assessments in the past, present and future. <i>Earth&#x2019;s Future</i><b>5</b>(6), 545&#x2013;59 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2016EF000518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6204262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30377623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, J. et al. Analysis on the spatial distribution characteristics of Chinese traditional villages [J]. <i>Process. Geogr.</i><b>35</b> (7), 839&#x2013;850 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. et al. Spatial Distribution and Influencing Factors of Traditional Villages: A Case of Wuyue Culture Region [J]. <i>Resour. Environ. Yangtze Basin</i>. <b>27</b> (08), 1693&#x2013;1702 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverman, B. W. <i>Density Estimation for Statistics and Data Analysis [M]</i> (Routledge, 1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, H. et al. Research on the Spatiotemporal Differentiation and Prediction of Water Resource Scarcity Risks in Yuxi City [J]. <i>Water Sav. Irrigation</i>, (01): 57&#x2013;60. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Zhang, T. &amp; Gu, S. Study on encounter of runoff abundance and scarcity between source area and receiving area of the Central Yunnan Irrigation Proiect and the hydrological drought. <i>Water Resour. Power</i><b>42</b>(06), 23&#x2013;7 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willmott, C. J. &amp; Matsuura, K. Advantages of the mean absolute error (MAE) over the root mean square error (RMSE) in assessing average model performance. <i>Clim. Res.</i><b>30</b>(1), 79&#x2013;82 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/cr030079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianzhou, W., Xiaoling, S. &amp; Te, Z. Challenges of typical inter-basin water transfer projects in China: Anticipated impacts of climate change on streamflow and hydrological drought under CMIP6 [J]. <i>Journal Hydrology</i>, (2023). 627(PA).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuiping, Q., Zhongrui, N. &amp; Yan, W. Impact of climate change on water availability in water source areas of the South-to-North Water Diversion Project in China. <i>Front. Earth Sci.</i>10.3389/feart.2021.747429 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2021.747429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, J. et al. Risk assessment of regional water resources and forewarning model at different time scales. <i>J. Hydrol. Eng.</i><b>18</b>(9), 1114&#x2013;1121 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)HE.1943-5584.0000490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmivaara, A. et al. Exploring the modifiable areal unit problem in spatial water assessments: A case of water shortage in Monsoon Asia. <i>Water</i><b>7</b>(3), 898&#x2013;917 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w7030898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veldkamp, T. I. E. et al. Towards a global water scarcity risk assessment framework: Incorporation of probability distributions and hydro-climatic variability. <i>Environ. Res. Lett.</i><b>11</b>(2), 024006 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/11/2/024006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosasaeng, S. et al. Hybrid Modeling for Future Inflow Prediction of Huai Luang Reservoir Under Climate Change [J]. <i>Int. J. GEOMATE</i>. <b>29</b> (132), 98&#x2013;109 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21660/2025.132.4978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph, J., Valentina, R. &amp; Ali, A. Assessment of Future Risks of Seasonal Municipal Water Shortages Across North America [J]. <i>Frontiers Earth Science</i>, 9. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xianneng, Z., Huaiwei, S. &amp; Hao, J. Coupling Bayesian network and copula theory for water shortage assessment: A case study in source area of the South-to-North Water Division Project (SNWDP). <i>J. Hydrol.</i>10.1016/j.jhydrol.2023.129434 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2023.129434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>