<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41490133</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1935-2735</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLoS neglected tropical diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Community knowledge, attitudes, and practices toward cutaneous leishmaniasis in central Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0013838</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0013838</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0013838</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pntd.0013838</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cutaneous leishmaniasis is the most prevalent clinical form of leishmaniasis and remains a significant public health problem, particularly in low- and middle-income countries where it disproportionately affects disadvantaged populations. The disease causes a far-reaching impact to the community where community-level awareness of its transmission, prevention, and treatment often remains low and less studied. Therefore, the present study aimed to assess community knowledge, attitudes, and practices related to CL in the Kambata Zone of Central Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ethics statement: Ethical approval was granted by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of Jimma University with the reference number JUIH/IRB/684/23. Authorization was also obtained from the Kambata zone Health Bureau to proceed with the study. All participants provided written informed consent in accordance with the principles outlined in the Helsinki Declaration. To uphold confidentiality, participant identities were anonymized, and data was securely stored in a separate location at the Principal Investigator's office. Community-based cross-sectional study design was employed from February 2024 to August 2024 in Kambata zone to assess knowledge, attitude, and practice of community toward cutaneous leishmaniasis. Systematic sampling technique was used to select individuals. A pretested structured questionnaire was used to collect data from the household head. Bivariate and multivariate logistic regression analyses were performed to determine the relationship between the participants' knowledge, attitude, and practice toward cutaneous leishmaniasis and socio demographic characteristics. The association between the independent and outcome variables was presented in the form of a table showing the adjusted odds ratio (AOR) along with their 95% confidence interval (CI). The level of statistical significance was declared at P-value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Out of 387 participants, 72.9% were male and 66.1% resided in rural areas. Only 18.1% had good knowledge, 13.2% a positive attitude, and 11.6% good practices toward cutaneous leishmaniasis. Good knowledge of cutaneous leishmaniasis was significantly associated with age 18-40 years (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.47; 95% CI: 2.07-9.67), male sex (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.25; 95% CI: 0.11-0.56), formal education (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.7; 95% CI: 2.18-8.75), family history of CL (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.22; 95% CI: 0.11-0.44), and crack-filling habits (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.20; 95% CI: 0.10-0.42). Positive attitude was associated with age 18-40 years (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.43; 95% CI: 1.14-5.16), formal education (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.67; 95% CI: 0.33-1.36), absence of open defecation (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.12; 95% CI: 0.06-0.23), and crack-filling habits (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02; 95% CI: 0.01-0.05).Good practices were associated with age 18-40 years (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.30; 95% CI: 1.64-11.10), formal education (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.34; 95% CI: 1.31-6.70.), family history of CL (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.17; 95% CI: 0.09-0.32), and crack-filling (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.14; 95% CI: 0.74-0.28).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The level of knowledge, attitude and practices towards CL in the study area is very low. Good knowledge, positive attitude and good practice were associated with younger age, formal education, absence of open defecation, and crack-filling behavior. Poor knowledge, attitude and practice of the study communities in the study area emphasize the need to initiate health education and awareness campaigns to reduce cutaneous leishmaniasis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Yohannes et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yohannes</LastName><ForeName>Tagesech</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-0105-2374</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science, School of Medical Laboratory Sciences, Institute of Health, Wolaita Sodo University, Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beyene</LastName><ForeName>Getenet</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geltore</LastName><ForeName>Teketel Ermias</ForeName><Initials>TE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, College of Medicine and Health Science, Wachamo University, Durame Campus, Durame, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geleta</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Faculty of Public Health, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mekonnen</LastName><ForeName>Zeleke</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101291488</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1935-2727</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016773" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leishmaniasis, Cutaneous</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41490133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12844503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0013838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PNTD-D-25-01161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>de Vries HJC, Schallig HD. Cutaneous Leishmaniasis: a 2022 updated narrative review into diagnosis and management developments. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2022;23(6):823&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1007/s40257-022-00726-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-022-00726-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9472198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36103050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisetegn H, Zeleke AJ, Gadisa E, Shumie G, Damte D, Fenta T, et al. Clinical, parasitological and molecular profiles of Cutaneous Leishmaniasis and its associated factors among clinically suspected patients attending Borumeda Hospital, North-East Ethiopia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2020;14(8):e0008507. doi: 10.1371/journal.pntd.0008507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0008507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7473553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32841279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed AB, Mohammed FS, Zewdu FT, et al. Protocol for a prospective observational cohort study of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Ethiopia. NIHR Open Res. 2025;49:1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11748424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39839605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kian M. A retrospective analysis of human cutaneous leishmaniasis epidemiology during 2016 - 2021 in Hoveyzeh County, Khuzestan. Jundishapur J Heal Sci. 2024;16:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adegboye OA, Al-Saghir M, Leung DHY. Joint spatial time-series epidemiological analysis of malaria and cutaneous leishmaniasis infection. Epidemiol Infect. 2017;145(4):685&#x2013;700. doi: 10.1017/S0950268816002764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0950268816002764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9507751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27903308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfay K, Mardu F, Berhe B. Household knowledge, practice and treatment seeking behaviors towards cutaneous leishmaniasis in the endemic rural communities of Ganta- afeshum district, Tigrai, northern Ethiopia, 2019: a cross-sectional study. Trop Dis Travel Med Vaccines. 2021;4:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8204582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal W, Iram U, Nisar S, Musa N, Alam A, Khan MR, et al. Epidemiology and clinical features of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan. Braz J Biol. 2022;84:e249124. doi: 10.1590/1519-6984.249124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1519-6984.249124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35946727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshetu B, Mamo H. Cutaneous leishmaniasis in north-central Ethiopia: trend, clinical forms, geographic distribution, and determinants. Trop Med Health. 2020;48:39. doi: 10.1186/s41182-020-00231-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-020-00231-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32518497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shita EY, Nibret E, Munshea A. Burden and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Dermatol. 2022;63:1&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35569096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merdekios B, Kote M, Pareyn M, Van Geertruyden J-P, van Griensven J. Prevalence and risk factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis in a newly identified endemic site in South-Ethiopia. PLoS One. 2024;19(12):e0311917. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0311917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0311917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11684615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39775255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed AB, Mohammed FS, Zewdu FT. Protocol for a prospective observational cohort study of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Ethiopia. NIHR Open Res. 2025;3:1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11748424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39839605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamiru HF. Cutaneous Leishmaniasis A Neglected Tropical Disease: Community Knowledge, Attitude And Practices In An Endemic Area, Northwest Ethiopia. 2019. pp. 1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6796443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31619180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bantie B, Kassaw G, Demelash AT. Magnitude and associated factors of cutaneous leishmaniasis among patients visiting Nefas Mewcha primary hospital, Northern Ethiopia, 2022: An institution- based cross- sectional study. BMJ Open. 2024;14:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10773395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38176880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengeot L, Yombi J-C, Baeck M. Cutaneous leishmaniasis due to Leishmania aethiopica: a therapeutic challenge. JAAD Case Rep. 2021;20:72&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.jdcr.2021.12.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdcr.2021.12.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8807949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan W, Khan I, Ullah H. Cutaneous leishmaniasis &#x2013; awareness, knowledge and practices among general population in rural and urban areas in Malakand region, Pakistan. Brazilian J Biol. 2022;82:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33825759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punjab S. Indigenous knowledge, attitude and practices (KAP) of people about leishmaniasis and its vector sand fly (Phlebotominae: Psychodidae: Diptera) living in an urban. J Gynecol Oncol. 2022;5:3&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi T, Sharifi I, Aflatoonian MR, Aflatoonian B, Mohammadi MA, Salarkia E, et al. A long-lasting emerging epidemic of anthroponotic cutaneous leishmaniasis in southeastern Iran: population movement and peri-urban settlements as a major risk factor. Parasit Vectors. 2021;14(1):122. doi: 10.1186/s13071-021-04619-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-021-04619-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33627184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh I, Gorouhi MA, Sharifi I. Risk factors of anthroponotic Cutaneous Leishmaniasis among residents in endemic communities in southeast of Iran in 2019. J Environ Heal Sustain Dev. 2021;6:1219&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doe ED, Egyir-yawson A, Kwakye-nuako G. Knowledge, attitude and practices related to Cutaneous Leishmaniasis in endemic communities in the volta region of Ghana. Int J Healthc Sci. 2019;7:33&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafiei R, Reza H, Mahmoodi M. Community health of knowledge and attitude towards cutaneous leishmaniasis among rural residents in Esfarayen county, North Khorasan province of Iran. Clin Epidemiol Glob Heal. 2025;33:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmahallawy EK, Sampedro Martinez A, Rodriguez-Granger J, Hoyos-Mallecot Y, Agil A, Navarro Mari JM, et al. Diagnosis of leishmaniasis. J Infect Dev Ctries. 2014;8(8):961&#x2013;72. doi: 10.3855/jidc.4310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3855/jidc.4310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25116660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koohsar F, Hajjaran H, Heidari S, Darabi E, Fathi S, Borhani M, et al. Molecular identification of Leishmania species isolated from patients with cutaneous leishmaniosis in gonbad Kavoos, northeastern of Iran using hSP70 and ITS-based PCR-RFlP. Ann Parasitol. 2020;66(3):339&#x2013;46. doi: 10.17420/ap6603.272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17420/ap6603.272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33128516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambata Agricultural Office. Kambata Zone. 2022. pp. 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebrewold-tochalo B. The Impact of the Socio-Cultural Structures of the Kambata/Ethiopia on their Economic Development. &#xd6;sterreichische Forschungsstiftung f&#xfc;r Entwicklungshilfe; 2001. pp. 3&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemayehu B, Kelbore AG, Alemayehu M, Adugna C, Bibo T, Megaze A, et al. Knowledge, attitude, and practice of the rural community about cutaneous leishmaniasis in Wolaita zone, southern Ethiopia. PLoS One. 2023;18(3):e0283582. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0283582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0283582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10047512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36976758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemayehu M, Paintain L, Adera C, Berhe R, Gebeyehu A, Gizaw Z, et al. Impact of education on knowledge and practice of Kala Azar preventive measures among seasonal and migrant agricultural workers in Northwest Ethiopia. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020;102(4):758&#x2013;67. doi: 10.4269/ajtmh.19-0079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.19-0079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7124897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32043439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikari RC, Shah M. Cutaneous leishmaniasis. J Pathol Nep. 2017;7(2):1212&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3126/jpn.v7i2.18031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/jpn.v7i2.18031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dires A, Kumar P, Gedamu S, Yimam W, Ademe S. Knowledge, attitude and prevention measures of students towards cutaneous leishmaniasis in Delanta district, Northeast Ethiopia. Parasite Epidemiol Control. 2022;17:e00241. doi: 10.1016/j.parepi.2022.e00241</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parepi.2022.e00241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8818578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35146141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alatawi AM, Alanazi AMM, Albalawi IAS, Abujaser NSM, Alblowi YH, Alfuhaymani AMM, et al. Knowledge and attitude regarding Cutaneous Leishmaniasis among adult population in Tabuk, Saudi Arabia. Cureus. 2024;16(1):e52614. doi: 10.7759/cureus.52614</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.52614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10875712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38374837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassa AG, Malede A, Lingerew M. Knowledge, attitude, prevention practice and lived experience towards cutaneous leishmaniasis and associated factors among residents of Kutaber district, Northeast Ethiopia, 2022: A mixed method study. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2024;21:1&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11373811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39173077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebremichael D. Zoonotic impact and epidemiological changes of leishmaniasis in Ethiopia. Open Vet J. 2018;8(4):432&#x2013;40. doi: 10.4314/ovj.v8i4.13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ovj.v8i4.13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6258520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30538935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alharazi TH, Haouas N, Al-Mekhlafi HM. Knowledge and attitude towards cutaneous leishmaniasis among rural endemic communities in Shara&#x2019;b district, Taiz, southwestern Yemen. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):269. doi: 10.1186/s12879-021-05965-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-021-05965-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7968254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33731042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamiru HF, Mashalla YJ, Mohammed R, Tshweneagae GT. Cutaneous leishmaniasis a neglected tropical disease: community knowledge, attitude and practices in an endemic area, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Infect Dis. 2019;19(1):855. doi: 10.1186/s12879-019-4506-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-019-4506-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6796443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31619180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alizadeh I, Gorouhi MA, Afshar AA. Anthroponotic cutaneous leishmaniasis: knowledge, attitudes, practices, and risk factors among residents in endemic communities in Kerman City in the Southeast of Iran. J Infect Dis. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewasurendra R, Silva H, Samaranayake N, Manamperi N, Silva N de, Karunanayake P, et al. Assessment of knowledge and perceptions on leishmaniasis: An island-wide study in Sri Lanka. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2022;16(10):e0010821. doi: 10.1371/journal.pntd.0010821</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0010821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9560589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36228029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadele G, Samuel A, Fite MB. Prevalence and knowledge of cutaneous leishmaniasis in Aleku area of Sayo district, Western Ethiopia: community-based cross-sectional study. J Med Public Heal. 2024;5:97&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>