<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41822314</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2753-6351</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in rehabilitation science and practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Rehabil Sci Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Medication Adherence and Its Determinants Among Adults With Heart Failure: A Study in Selected Hospitals of North Shewa Zone, Oromia, Ethiopia (2024)-A Multicenter Institutional-Based Cross-Sectional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>27536351251391632</StartPage><MedlinePgn>27536351251391632</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">27536351251391632</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/27536351251391632</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Effective management of heart failure (HF) critically relies on adherence to evidence-based pharmacotherapy. However, adherence remains suboptimal, contributing to preventable hospital readmissions, disease progression, and increased healthcare costs. This study assessed medication adherence and associated factors among adult HF patients in selected hospitals of North Shewa Zone, Oromia, Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">An institutional-based cross-sectional study was conducted among 327 adult HF patients selected via simple random sampling. The sample size was calculated using a single population proportion formula (<i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.738, 95% confidence interval [CI], 5% margin of error) and adjusted for a 10% non-response rate. Medication adherence was measured using the Amharic version of the Morisky Medication Adherence Scale (MMAS-8). Data were entered and analyzed using SPSS version 26. Logistic regression identified factors associated with adherence, with statistical significance set at <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Out of 327 participants, 165 (50.5%) were female, with a mean age of 43&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;17.6&#x2009;years. Good medication adherence was observed in 146 participants (44.65%). Independent predictors of adherence included higher HF knowledge (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.03; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.13-3.66; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.018), access to free medications (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.78; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.04-3.03; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.034), and receiving education on medication adherence (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.20; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.22-3.97; <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;.009).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION AND RECOMMENDATIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Less than half of HF patients demonstrated good medication adherence. Structured patient education, reliable access to medications, and improved HF knowledge were key determinants of adherence. Interventions targeting these factors are strongly recommended to enhance medication adherence and improve clinical outcomes among HF patients in North Shewa Zone.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammed</LastName><ForeName>Abdurehman Seid</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-2335-1508</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Kidus Petros Specialized Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kemal</LastName><ForeName>Wubanchi Seid</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Advanced Adult Health Nursing, Ras Desta Damtew Memory Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kolbay</LastName><ForeName>Ali Seid</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Advanced Adult Health Nursing, Kidus Petros Specialized Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yesuf</LastName><ForeName>Mustofa Hassen</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-6191-4102</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Kidus Petros Specialized Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abebe</LastName><ForeName>Selam Seyoum</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Kidus Petros Specialized Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Bisrat</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Trials, Kidus Petros Specialized Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deress</LastName><ForeName>Getachew Mekete</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-1463-3222</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, College of Health Sciences, School of Medicine, Debre Tabor University, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Rehabil Sci Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918540788406676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2753-6351</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">North Shewa Zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oromia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">associated factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">determinants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medication adherence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41822314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12976411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/27536351251391632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_27536351251391632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Knafl GJ, Moser DK, Wu JR, Riegel B. Effects of medication adherence on clinical outcomes in heart failure: a systematic review. J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2019;34(1):20-29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickson VV, Knafl GJ, Riegel B. Predictors of medication nonadherence in adults with heart failure. Heart Lung. 2015;44(1):19-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambardekar AV, Fonarow GC, Hernandez AF, et al. Characteristics and in-hospital outcomes for nonadherent patients with heart failure: findings from the Get With The Guidelines&#x2013;Heart Failure Program. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53(18):1699-1706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19781426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Adherence to Long-Term Therapies: Evidence for Action. WHO; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lines LM, Suleman S. Medication adherence and its impact on health outcomes: a global perspective. J Patient Rep Outcomes. 2017;1(1):23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muriuki M, Obare F, Ayieko J, Matanda D, Sisimwo K, Mdawida B. Determinants of adherence to cardiovascular medicines in sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2017;17(1):202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. Cardiovascular Diseases (CVDs). WHO; 2023. Accessed March 15, 2024. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/cardiovascular-diseases-(cvds)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzudie A, Ojji D, Anisiuba BC, et al. Outcomes in patients with heart failure in sub-Saharan Africa: results from the THESUS-HF registry. Cardiovasc J Afr. 2021;32(3):133-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallangyo P, Nicholls SJ, Breathett K, et al. Heart failure in sub-Saharan Africa: a contemporary review. ESC Heart Fail. 2020;7(6):3717-3728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguntade AS, Ajayi SO. Hypertension and heart failure in sub-Saharan Africa: epidemiology and management challenges. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2021;23(6):30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birhanu B, Gizaw M, Teshome A, Boche T, Gudeta T. Spectrum of cardiovascular diseases and outcomes in Ethiopian hospitals: a multicenter review. Ethiop J Health Sci. 2022;32(3):587-596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gizaw M, Bogale B, Gudeta T. Determinants of medication adherence among patients with chronic heart failure in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2021;21(1):541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke RM, Colburn J, Rami T, et al. Heart failure epidemiology and outcomes in low-income countries: the case of Ethiopia. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2019;25:100418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdinand KC, Senatore FF, Clayton-Jeter H, et al. Polypharmacy and medication adherence in heart failure patients: recent evidence. J Clin Med. 2020;9(4):1054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad A, Osman E, Altayib H. Polypharmacy as a predictor of non-adherence in Sudanese heart failure patients. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2021;21:302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein MK, Gathright EC, Dolansky MA, et al. Depression and medication adherence in heart failure patients: a cohort study. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2021;33:100747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seid A, Gebremariam GT, Asfaw M. Psychological comorbidities and their effect on heart failure adherence in Ethiopia. Heart Views. 2022;23(1):12-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alosco ML, Spitznagel MB, Cohen R, et al. Cognitive impairment and heart failure: implications for medication adherence. Heart Fail Rev. 2020;25:899-910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruf V, Stewart S, Carrington MJ, et al. Cognitive function and adherence in older adults with chronic heart failure: a systematic review. J Geriatr Cardiol. 2022;19(2):111-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobretti MR, Page RL, Kliethermes MA, et al. Medication-related barriers to adherence in heart failure: a meta-analysis. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2020;14:245-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meraz M, McNaul E, Tanner N, et al. Polypharmacy, adherence, and quality of life among older heart failure patients. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2021;46(2):410-419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raffaa H, Al-Saadi R, Al-Harbi T. et al. Medication adherence among patients with heart failure in Saudi Arabia: a cross-sectional study. Saudi Pharm J. 2020;28(7):888-894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetensa G, Negera G, Tsegaye B. Medication adherence and associated factors among heart failure patients in Western Ethiopia. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2019;19:220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seid MA, Engidawork E, Alebachew M, Mekonnen N, Berha AB. Adherence to pharmacotherapy and associated factors among heart failure patients at Tikur Anbessa Specialized Hospital, Ethiopia. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2020;14:1619-1629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallangyo P, Nicholaus P, Kisenge P, et al. Medication adherence and associated factors among patients with heart failure in Tanzania. Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2020;29:100557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santra G. Assessment of medication adherence in heart failure patients in India. Indian Heart J. 2015;67(5):448-454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguntade AS, Ajayi IO. Determinants of medication adherence among heart failure patients in sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review. Cardiovasc J Afr. 2021;32(4):1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaarsma T, Str&#xf6;mberg A, M&#xe5;rtensson J, Dracup K. Development and testing of the European Heart Failure Self-Care Behaviour Scale. Eur J Heart Fail. 2003;5(3):363-370. doi:10.1016/S1388-9842(02)00253-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12798836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisky DE, Ang A, Krousel-Wood M, Ward HJ. Predictive validity of a medication adherence measure in an outpatient setting. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich). 2008;10(5):348-354. doi:10.1111/j.1751-7176.2008.07572.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2562622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18453793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatib R, Marshall K, Silcock J, Hall A, Khan K. Adherence interventions and peer-support programs for patients with chronic conditions: implications for heart failure management. Patient Educ Couns. 2020;103(6):1216-1223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad AI, Osman NM, Altayeb IA. Medication adherence among heart failure patients in Sudan: barriers and facilitators. Pharm Pract. 2017;15(1):873.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>