<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41456014</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Autoregulated macro-microcycle training enhances physiological reserve and adaptability in competitive speed skaters.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>47</StartPage><MedlinePgn>47</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">47</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-025-01495-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The personalization of training is one of the main pillars of performance science, but multidomain reserve modelling based on aerobic, neuromuscular, and autonomic systems remains under-researched. Unlike fixed-load models, the approach uses real-time heart rate variability (HRV) and performance load ratio (PLR) feedback to tune training and recovery, offering a new, evidence-based approach to maintaining the adaptive potential of speed skating. This study tested whether an autoregulated macro&#x2013;microcycle using readiness signals improves physiological reserve versus volume-matched conventional programming.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Eighteen intercollegiate athletes underwent 24 weeks of closely supervised training with the same volume but different load-modulation guidelines. The intervention arm maintained daily intensity using HRV-based readiness thresholds and session-RPE feedback, whereas the control group followed preset linear periodization. Outcomes included maximal oxygen uptake (VO&#x2082;max), lactate threshold (LT), Wingate anaerobic peak power, countermovement jump (CMJ), heart rate recovery at 1&#xa0;min (HRR-1), root mean square of successive differences (RMSSD), the low-frequency to high-frequency ratio (LF/HF), and a composite Performance Reserve Index (PRI). Linear mixed model analysis, subgroup contrast, correlation matrices, and cluster segmentation analyses were done.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with conventional programming, larger gains were observed for VO&#x2082;max (+&#x2009;3.9 mL/kg/min, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.010, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.92), lactate threshold (+&#x2009;0.57 mmol/L, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.04), Wingate peak power (+&#x2009;67&#xa0;W, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.00), CMJ height (+&#x2009;4.2&#xa0;cm, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.021, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.83), HRR-1 (+&#x2009;8.3&#xa0;bpm, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.009, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.93), RMSSD (to 47.6 ms, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.007, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.96), and PRI (0.62&#x2192;0.85, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, d&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.41). The coordinated aerobic, neuromuscular, and autonomic pattern indicates tighter stimulus&#x2013;recovery coupling under autoregulation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The autoregulated macro-microcycle training resulted in combined advantages in aerobic capacity, neuromuscular power, and autonomic balance, demonstrating the effectiveness of individualized feedback control as the next-generation paradigm for maximizing long-term adaptation in competitive speed skating. Coaches can apply simple HRV thresholds and sRPE bounds to cap or extend sessions and use PLR bands to schedule deloads and Zone-2 extensions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">The study was retrospectively registered with the UK ISRCTN registry (ISRCTN16362421) on 04 September 2025.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s13102-025-01495-7.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tianjin Institute of Physical Education, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hebei Institute of Physical Education, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hongye</LastName><ForeName>Lian</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hebei Institute of Physical Education, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donglin</LastName><ForeName>Shi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hebei Institute of Physical Education, Shijiazhuang, Hebei, China. shidonglin1ok@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen consumption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Tianjin University of Sport (Approval No. TJUS 2025-093). Written informed consent to participate was obtained from all participants before data collection. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41456014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12859854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-025-01495-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-025-01495-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li T, Shao J, An N, Chang Y, Xia Y, Han Q, et al. Combined proteomics and metabolomics analysis reveal the effect of a training course on the immune function of Chinese elite short-track speed skaters. Immun Inflamm Dis. 2024;12(10). 10.1002/IID3.70030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11443606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39352112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gisbert-Orozco JF, Moras G, Toro-Rom&#xe1;n V, Illera-Dom&#xed;nguez V, P&#xe9;rez-Chirinos Buxad&#xe9; C, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Vald&#xe9;s B. Effects of mechanical vibration during an incremental slide board skating test on physiological and movement variability parameters. Appl Sci (Switzerland). 2024;14(4). 10.3390/APP14041342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebisz R, Hebisz P. Greater improvement in aerobic capacity after a polarized training program, including cycling interval training at low Cadence (50&#x2013;70 RPM) than freely chosen Cadence (above 80 RPM). PLoS ONE. 2024;19(11). 10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0311833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11559993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39536034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowley N, Nicholson V, Timmins R, Munteanu G, Wood T, Garca-Ramos A, et al. The effects of Percentage-Based, rating of perceived Exertion, repetitions in Reserve, and Velocity-Based training on performance and fatigue responses. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2025;39(4):e516&#x2013;29. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000005026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39787033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calaway C, Walls K, Levitt H, Caplan J, Mann B, Martinez K, et al. Velocity-Based-Training frequency impacts changes in muscle Morphology, neuromuscular Performance, and functional capability in persons with parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2025;39(1):99&#x2013;106. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39316787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savolainen EHJ, Ihalainen JK, V&#xe4;nttinen T, Walker S. Changes in female football players&#x2019; in-season training load, intensity, and physical performance: training progression matters more than accumulated load. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6. 10.3389/FSPOR.2024.1454519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11540696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39512665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Konrad A, Nakamura M, Alizadeh S, Culleton R, Anvar SH, et al. A narrative review of velocity-based training best practice: the importance of contraction intent versus movement speed. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2025;50. 10.1139/APNM-2024-0136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39366003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManaman C, Novak B, Paul L, Rooney S. Changes in walking speed following resistance training in people with multiple sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PM R. 2025;17(2):222&#x2013;37. 10.1002/PMRJ.13255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/PMRJ.13255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11826970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39311403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gismondi A, Iellamo F, Caminiti G, Sposato B, Gregorace E, D&#x2019;Antoni V, et al. Rate of perceived exertion based on repetitions in reserve versus percentage of One-Repetition maximum for resistance training prescription in cardiac rehabilitation: A pilot study. J Cardiovasc Dev Disease. 2025;12(1). 10.3390/JCDD12010008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11766398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39852286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian T. Wearable sensor-based real-time monitoring system for physical education teaching and training. MCB Mol Cell Biomech. 2025;22(1). 10.62617/MCB1027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun B. Comprehensive evaluation of physical education based on personalized training plan generation algorithm and biomechanics. MCB Mol Cell Biomech. 2025;22(1). 10.62617/MCB477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski T, R&#x119;bi&#x15b; K, Malczewska-Lenczowska J, Klusiewicz A, Starczewski M, Klich S, et al. Optimizing recovery strategies in elite speedskating: A comparative analysis of different modalities. J Funct Morphology Kinesiol. 2025;10(1). 10.3390/JFMK10010034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11755552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39846675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto BB, Moreno-Parro I, Sufrate-Vergara B, Fabre-Estremera B, Soto AB, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Calle P, et al. Biological variation of cardiac biomarkers in athletes during an entire sport season. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2025;63(5):987&#x2013;94. 10.1515/CCLM-2024-1203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/CCLM-2024-1203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39865503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-L&#xf3;pez J, P&#xe9;rez-L&#xf3;pez A, Varillas-Delgado D, L&#xf3;pez-Samanes &#xc1;. Influence of time-of-day on neuromuscular performance in team sport athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6. 10.3389/FSPOR.2024.1466050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11782285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39896341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Fu X, Xu H, Guo Q, Wang X. The effect of instability resistance training on balance ability among athletes: a systematic review. Front Physiol. 2024;15. 10.3389/FPHYS.2024.1434918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11746901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39839523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerrie JM, Valovich Mcleod TC. Resting metabolic rate and recovery from Sport-Related concussion: A critically appraised topic. J Sport Rehabilitation. 2025;34(5):577&#x2013;80. 10.1123/JSR.2024-0020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/JSR.2024-0020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39832506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biesiada W, Kopczy&#x144;ska E, Kulej P, Wo&#x17a;niak J, Kmie&#x107; JW, Chernysh A-M, et al. Tirzepatide in sport: A comprehensive review of its metabolic impacts and potential applications for athletes. Qual Sport. 2025;37:57025&#x2013;57025. 10.12775/QS.2025.37.57025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12775/QS.2025.37.57025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D. Effect analysis of functional physical fitness training based on improved genetic algorithm under functional analysis. Mol Cell Biomech. 2025;22(2):1044&#x2013;1044. 10.62617/MCB1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62617/MCB1044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menting SGP, Huijgen BC, Konings MJ, Hettinga FJ, Elferink-Gemser MT. Pacing behavior development of youth Short-Track speed skaters: A longitudinal study. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52(5):1099&#x2013;108. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31815834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zukowski M, Herzog W, Jordan MJ. Velocity-Load jump testing predicts acceleration performance in elite speed skaters: but does movement specificity matter? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2024;19(8):757&#x2013;64. 10.1123/IJSPP.2023-0373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/IJSPP.2023-0373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38823795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roete AJ, Stoter IK, Lamberts RP, Elferink-Gemser MT, Otter RTA. Introducing a method to quantify the specificity of training for races in speed skating. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2022;36(7):1998&#x2013;2004. 10.1519/JSC.0000000000004271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35544349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber JG, Ortigas-V&#xe1;squez A, Sauer A, Dupraz I, Utz M, Maas A, et al. Comparison of IMU-Based knee kinematics with and without Harness fixation against an optical Marker-Based system. Bioengineering. 2024;11(10). 10.3390/BIOENGINEERING11100976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11505205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39451352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Ding M, Zhang M, Yu B, Liu H. Effects of technique asymmetry on 500 m speed skating performance. Bioengineering. 2024;11(9). 10.3390/BIOENGINEERING11090899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39329641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz JP, Vriner M, Mangum LC, Slater L. Longitudinal changes in athletic performance in competitive figure skaters. J Sci Sport Exerc. 2021;3(4):332&#x2013;9. 10.1007/S42978-021-00124-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S42978-021-00124-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helbok OVZ, Sousa LVA, Herdy AH, Laporta GZ, Raimundo RD. Comparative electrocardiographic analysis between physical exercise practitioners and athletes: A Cross-Sectional study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2025;22(1). 10.3390/IJERPH22010078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11765152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39857533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#xe9;cart C, Bouten J, Giroux C, Morales-Artacho A, Rousseau Q, Rabita G, et al. Individual sex-based variability to altitude training in elite badminton players. J Sports Sci. 2024;42(24):2535&#x2013;40. 10.1080/02640414.2024.2448358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2448358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39742425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cano-Montoya J, Hurtado N, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez Vergara C, B&#xe1;ez Vargas S, Rojas-Vargas M, Mart&#xed;nez-Huenchull&#xe1;n S, et al. Interindividual variability response to resistance and High-Intensity interval training on blood pressure reduction in hypertensive older adults. J Cardiovasc Dev Disease. 2025;12(1). 10.3390/JCDD12010030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11765815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39852308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decoux BE, Wilburn CM, Aldahir P, Gordon MA, Weimar WH. Inter-segmental coordination variability during hopping and running on natural and synthetic turf surfaces. Sports Biomech. 2025;24(8):2247&#x2013;67. 10.1080/14763141.2025.2450656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14763141.2025.2450656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39803751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahal P, Rauhala OJ, Khodagholy D, Gelinas JN. Hippocampal&#x2013;cortical coupling differentiates long-term memory processes. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2023;120(7). 10.1073/PNAS.2207909120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36749719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prima O, Golovin M, Subotyalov M. Autonomic regulation and reactivity of the cardiovascular system of adolescent hockey players depending on the game role. Sci Notes V I Vernadsky Crime Fed Univ Biology Chem. 2024;10(3):155&#x2013;61. 10.29039/2413-1725-2024-10-3-155-161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29039/2413-1725-2024-10-3-155-161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongiorno G, Sisti G, Biancuzzi H, Dal Mas F, Minisini FG, Miceli L. Training in roller speed skating: proposal of surface electromyography and kinematics data for educational purposes in junior and senior athletes. Sensors. 2024;24(23). 10.3390/S24237617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11645072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39686154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa MJ, Marinho DA, Reis JF, Espada MC, Santos CC. Monitoring In-Water and dryland interlimb asymmetry of young competitive swimmers: insights across a training macrocycle. Appl Sci (Switzerland). 2024;14(24). 10.3390/APP142411858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner MJ. Training elite athletes: 50 years of thinking about practice and research for endurance sports. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2025;35(1). 10.1111/SMS.70013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39776013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dausin C, Tironi RM, Cornelissen V, Hespel P, Willems R, Haykowsky M, et al. Your heart can&#x2019;t see what sneakers you are wearing: exercise training load in endurance athletes is inadequately quantified in sports cardiology. Can J Cardiol. 2025;41(3):354&#x2013;63. 10.1016/J.CJCA.2024.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CJCA.2024.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39672298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SR, Bruinvels G, Smith-Ryan AE. Menstrual cycle Phase-Based strength and conditioning training for elite team sport female athletes. Strength Conditioning J. 2025;47(3):340&#x2013;52. 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Reyes P, van den Tillaar R, Casta&#xf1;o-Zambudio A, Gleadhill S, Nagahara R. Understanding sprint phase-specific training stimuli: a cluster analysis approach to overload conditions. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6. 10.3389/FSPOR.2024.1510379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11669057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39722738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banister EW, Calvert TW, Savage MV, Bach T. A systems model of training for athletic performance. Aust J Sports Med. 1975;7(3):57&#x2013;61. 10.1109/TSMC.1976.5409179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TSMC.1976.5409179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busso T. Variable dose-response relationship between exercise training and performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(7):1188&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000074465.13621.37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12840641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanch P, Gabbett TJ. Has the athlete trained enough to return to play safely? The acute: chronic workload ratio permits clinicians to quantify a player&#x2019;s risk of subsequent injury. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(8):471&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26701923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulin BT, Gabbett TJ, Lawson DW, Caputi P, Sampson JA. The acute: chronic workload ratio predicts injury: high chronic workload May decrease injury risk in elite rugby league players. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(4):231&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-094817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26511006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton R. Modelling training and overtraining. J Sports Sci. 1997;15(3):335&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404197367344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9232559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Florhaug JA, Franklin J, Gottschall L, Hrovatin LA, Parker S, et al. A new approach to monitoring exercise training. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2001;15(1):109&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impellizzeri FM, Rampinini E, Marcora SM. Physiological assessment of aerobic training in soccer. J Sports Sci. 2005;23(6):583&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410400021278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16195007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB. New horizons for the methodology and physiology of training periodization. Sports Med. 2010;40(3):189&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11319770-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20199119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bompa TO, Buzzichelli C. Periodization-: theory and methodology of training. Human kinetics; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issurin VB. Benefits and limitations of block periodized training approaches to athletes&#x2019; preparation: A review. Sports Med. 2016;46(3):329&#x2013;38. 10.1007/s40279-015-0425-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0425-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laursen PB, Jenkins DG. The scientific basis for high-intensity interval training. Sports Med. 2002;32(1):53&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200232010-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11772161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiler S. What is best practice for training intensity and duration distribution in endurance athletes? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(3):276&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.5.3.276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20861519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Scientific bases for precompetition tapering strategies. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(7):1182&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000074448.73931.11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12840640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howley ET, Bassett DR Jr., Welch HG. Criteria for maximal oxygen uptake: review and commentary. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1995;27(9):1292&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00005768-199509000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8531628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg G. Borg&#x2019;s perceived exertion and pain scales. Human kinetics; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Coutts AJ, Kelly V, McGuigan MR, Cormack SJ. Neuromuscular, endocrine, and perceptual fatigue responses during different length between-match microcycles in professional rugby league players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(3):367&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.5.3.367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20861526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloszy JO, Booth FW. Biochemical adaptations to endurance exercise in muscle. Annu Rev Physiol. 1976;38:273&#x2013;91. 10.1146/annurev.ph.38.030176.001421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.ph.38.030176.001421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">130825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plews DJ, Laursen PB, Stanley J, Kilding AE, Buchheit M. Training adaptation and heart rate variability in elite endurance athletes: opening the door to effective monitoring. Sports Med. 2013;43(9):773&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0071-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23852425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>