<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41179714</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1948-5182</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Gray zone and the need for expansion in chronic hepatitis B: From theory to clinical practice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107735</StartPage><MedlinePgn>107735</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">107735</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4254/wjh.v17.i10.107735</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic hepatitis B (CHB) remains a significant global health challenge. The natural course of CHB is traditionally divided into four phases: (1) Immune tolerance; (2) Immune activation; (3) Immune control; and (4) Immune escape. However, approximately 20%-30% of patients referred to as the "gray zone" (GZ) do not fit neatly into these categories. These patients often exhibit elevated hepatitis B virus DNA levels alongside normal or mildly elevated alanine aminotransferase levels, placing them at significant risk for liver fibrosis, cirrhosis, and hepatocellular carcinoma. However, current clinical guidelines generally do not recommend antiviral therapy for GZ patients, increasing their vulnerability to adverse outcomes. This mini-review explores the challenges and gaps in CHB management, focusing on GZ patients. It also highlights recent advancements in therapeutic strategies and updates in clinical guidelines, emphasizing the need for a more inclusive, risk-adapted approach to treatment. By leveraging novel biomarkers, noninvasive fibrosis assessment tools, and artificial intelligence-driven predictive models, this article advocates for early intervention to mitigate disease progression and improve clinical outcomes in this overlooked population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Viet Luong</LastName><ForeName>Thang</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Hue University, Hue 530000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phan Hong Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Ngoc</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Hue University, Hue 530000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Tri Van</ForeName><Initials>TV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, International Medical Center, Hue Central Hospital, Hue 530000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Duong Hung</ForeName><Initials>DH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Hue University, Hue 530000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dinh Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Thien</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Hue Central Hospital, Hue 530000, Viet Nam. nguyendinhthien232@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen Ngoc Dang</LastName><ForeName>Hai</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Duy Tan University, Da Nang 550000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532469</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic hepatitis B</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gray zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liver fibrosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk stratification</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41179714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12576699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4254/wjh.v17.i10.107735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver. EASL 2017 Clinical Practice Guidelines on the management of hepatitis B virus infection. J Hepatol. 2017;67:370&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28427875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan P, Li LQ, Chen EQ. The urgency to expand the antiviral indications of general chronic hepatitis B patients. Front Med (Lausanne) 2023;10:1165891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10235492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37275355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Lee Y, Bang SM, Bak H, Yim SY, Lee YS, Yoo YJ, Jung YK, Kim JH, Seo YS, Yim HJ, Um SH, Byun KS, Yeon JE. Early Normalization of Alanine Aminotransferase during Antiviral Therapy Reduces Risk of Hepatocellular Carcinoma in HBV Patients. J Clin Med. 2021;10:1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33922708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarin SK, Kumar M, Lau GK, Abbas Z, Chan HL, Chen CJ, Chen DS, Chen HL, Chen PJ, Chien RN, Dokmeci AK, Gane E, Hou JL, Jafri W, Jia J, Kim JH, Lai CL, Lee HC, Lim SG, Liu CJ, Locarnini S, Al Mahtab M, Mohamed R, Omata M, Park J, Piratvisuth T, Sharma BC, Sollano J, Wang FS, Wei L, Yuen MF, Zheng SS, Kao JH. Asian-Pacific clinical practice guidelines on the management of hepatitis B: a 2015 update. Hepatol Int. 2016;10:1&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4722087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26563120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terrault NA, Lok ASF, McMahon BJ, Chang KM, Hwang JP, Jonas MM, Brown RS Jr, Bzowej NH, Wong JB. Update on prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of chronic hepatitis B: AASLD 2018 hepatitis B guidance. Hepatology. 2018;67:1560&#x2013;1599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5975958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim YS. Gray zone of hepatitis B virus infection. Saudi J Gastroenterol. 2024;30:76&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10980295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37843134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang W, Peng Y, Kang L. Advancements of non-invasive imaging technologies for the diagnosis and staging of liver fibrosis: Present and future. VIEW. 2024;5:20240010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim YS. New biomarkers of hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection: HBV RNA and HBV core-related antigen, new kids on the block? Clin Mol Hepatol. 2023;29:118&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36443925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida N. Advancements in Artificial Intelligence-Enhanced Imaging Diagnostics for the Management of Liver Disease-Applications and Challenges in Personalized Care. Bioengineering (Basel) 2024;11:1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11673237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39768061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim YS, Kim WR, Dieterich D, Kao JH, Flaherty JF, Yee LJ, Roberts LR, Razavi H, Kennedy PTF. Evidence for Benefits of Early Treatment Initiation for Chronic Hepatitis B. Viruses. 2023;15:997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10142077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37112976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang HC. Revisiting the natural history of chronic hepatitis B infection. Clin Liver Dis (Hoboken) 2024;23:e0195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11168840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38872766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spradling PR, Xing J, Rupp LB, Moorman AC, Gordon SC, Teshale ET, Lu M, Boscarino JA, Schmidt MA, Trinacty CM, Holmberg SD Chronic Hepatitis Cohort Study Investigators. Distribution of disease phase, treatment prescription and severe liver disease among 1598 patients with chronic hepatitis B in the Chronic Hepatitis Cohort Study, 2006-2013. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2016;44:1080&#x2013;1089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27640985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao K, Liu J, Wang J, Yan X, Xia J, Yang Y, Wu W, Liu Y, Chen Y, Zhang Z, Li J, Huang R, Wu C. Distribution and clinical characteristics of patients with chronic hepatitis B virus infection in the grey zone. J Viral Hepat. 2021;28:1025&#x2013;1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33797145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Yu S, Zhu K, Li S, Huang Y. Probability analysis of hepatocellular carcinoma in hepatitis patients in the gray zone. Front Med (Lausanne) 2024;11:1464981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11703914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39776842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaw YF, Tai DI, Chu CM, Chen TJ. The development of cirrhosis in patients with chronic type B hepatitis: a prospective study. Hepatology. 1988;8:493&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3371868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng MD, Lu LG, Mao YM, Qiu DK, Li JQ, Wan MB, Chen CW, Wang JY, Cai X, Gao CF, Zhou XQ. Prediction of significant fibrosis in HBeAg-positive patients with chronic hepatitis B by a noninvasive model. Hepatology. 2005;42:1437&#x2013;1445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16317674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim WR, Flamm SL, Di Bisceglie AM, Bodenheimer HC Public Policy Committee of the American Association for the Study of Liver Disease. Serum activity of alanine aminotransferase (ALT) as an indicator of health and disease. Hepatology. 2008;47:1363&#x2013;1370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18366115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang DQ, Li X, Le MH, Le AK, Yeo YH, Trinh HN, Zhang J, Li J, Wong C, Wong C, Cheung RC, Yang HI, Nguyen MH. Natural History and Hepatocellular Carcinoma Risk in Untreated Chronic Hepatitis B Patients With Indeterminate Phase. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;20:1803&#x2013;1812.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33465482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Yan X, Zhu L, Liu J, Qiu Y, Li Y, Liu Y, Xue R, Zhan J, Jiang S, Geng Y, Wan Y, Li M, Mao M, Gao D, Yin S, Tong X, Xia J, Ding W, Chen Y, Li J, Zhu C, Huang R, Wu C. Significant histological disease of patients with chronic hepatitis B virus infection in the grey zone. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2023;57:464&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36324235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu HS, Jiang H, Li MK, Yang BL, Smayi A, Chen JN, Wu B, Yang YD. Lowering the threshold of alanine aminotransferase for enhanced identification of significant hepatic injury in chronic hepatitis B patients. World J Gastroenterol. 2023;29:5166&#x2013;5177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10514758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37744292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CJ, Iloeje UH, Yang HI. Long-term outcomes in hepatitis B: the REVEAL-HBV study. Clin Liver Dis. 2007;11:797&#x2013;816, viii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17981229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SK, Kwon JH. HBeAg-positive grey-zone patients: Treatment beyond guideline recommendations? Clin Mol Hepatol. 2023;29:825&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10366786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37254484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Wang FD, Li LQ, Li YJ, Wang SY, Chen EQ. Antiviral Therapy Favors a Lower Risk of Liver Cirrhosis in HBeAg-negative Chronic Hepatitis B with Normal Alanine Transaminase and HBV DNA Positivity. J Clin Transl Hepatol. 2023;11:1465&#x2013;1475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10752813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Yu S, Zhu K, Li S, Huang Y. Necessity of antiviral treatment for patients with chronic hepatitis B in the grey zone based on liver pathology analysis. Ann Med. 2024;56:2399757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11407419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39283046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai JC, Wong GL, Tse YK, Hui VW, Lai MS, Chan HL, Wong VW, Yip TC. Histological severity, clinical outcomes and impact of antiviral treatment in indeterminate phase of chronic hepatitis B: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Hepatol. 2025;82:992&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39577468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You H, Wang F, Li T, Xu X, Sun Y, Nan Y, Wang G, Hou J, Duan Z, Wei L, Jia J, Zhuang H Chinese Society of Hepatology, Chinese Medical Association; Chinese Society of Infectious Diseases, Chinese Medical Association. Guidelines for the Prevention and Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis B (version 2022) J Clin Transl Hepatol. 2023;11:1425&#x2013;1442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10500285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37719965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Kong Y, Xu X, Sun Y, Jia J, You H. "Treat-all" Strategy for Patients with Chronic Hepatitis B Virus Infection in China: Are We There Yet? J Clin Transl Hepatol. 2024;12:589&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11224901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38974957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong GL, Lemoine M. The 2024 updated WHO guidelines for the prevention and management of chronic hepatitis B: Main changes and potential implications for the next major liver society clinical practice guidelines. J Hepatol. 2025;82:918&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39647534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver. EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines on the management of hepatitis B virus infection. J Hepatol. 2025;83:502&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40348683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bera C, Hamdan-Perez N, Patel K. Non-Invasive Assessment of Liver Fibrosis in Hepatitis B Patients. J Clin Med. 2024;13:1046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10889471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38398358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Wang H, Shan S, Sun Y, Xu X, You H, Jia J, Zhuang H, Kong Y On Behalf Of The China Registry Of Hepatitis B Cr-HepB Group. The Impact of the Definitions of Clinical Phases on the Profiles of Grey-Zone Patients with Chronic Hepatitis B Virus Infection. Viruses. 2023;15:1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10222301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37243297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park CC, Nguyen P, Hernandez C, Bettencourt R, Ramirez K, Fortney L, Hooker J, Sy E, Savides MT, Alquiraish MH, Valasek MA, Rizo E, Richards L, Brenner D, Sirlin CB, Loomba R. Magnetic Resonance Elastography vs Transient Elastography in Detection of Fibrosis and Noninvasive Measurement of Steatosis in Patients With Biopsy-Proven Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease. Gastroenterology. 2017;152:598&#x2013;607.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5285304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27911262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan Q, Huang Y, Zhu C, Zhao S, Fu H, Cai M, Wang J, Zhang C, Guo S, Cao Z, Xie Q. qHBsAg for the Identification of Liver Histological Abnormalities in HBeAg-Negative Chronic Hepatitis B Patients with Normal and Mildly Elevated ALT Levels. Can J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;2022:8695196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9303505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35875362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;ld&#x131;z Kaya S, Mete B, Kaya A, Balkan II, Saltoglu N, Tabak &#xd6;F. The role of quantitative HBsAg in patients with HBV DNA between 2000-20,000 IU/ml. Wien Klin Wochenschr. 2021;133:647&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33914152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue T, Tanaka Y. The Role of Hepatitis B Core-Related Antigen. Genes (Basel) 2019;10:357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6562807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31075974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Zhou B, Valdes JD, Sun J, Guo H. Serum Hepatitis B Virus RNA: A New Potential Biomarker for Chronic Hepatitis B Virus Infection. Hepatology. 2019;69:1816&#x2013;1827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6438723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30362148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Y, Yan J, Shi K, Liu X, Gao F, Wu T, Meng P, Zhang M, Jiang Y, Wang X. Development and Validation of a Machine Learning-Based Model Used for Predicting Hepatocellular Carcinoma Risk in Patients with Hepatitis B-Related Cirrhosis: A Retrospective Study. Onco Targets Ther. 2024;17:215&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10972695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38550662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su TH, Kao JH. Role of artificial intelligence in the management of chronic hepatitis B infection. Clin Liver Dis (Hoboken) 2024;23:e0164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11068129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38707242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C, Shu Z, Chen S, Peng J, Zhao Y, Dai X, Li J, Zou X, Hu J, Huang H. A machine learning-based model analysis for serum markers of liver fibrosis in chronic hepatitis B patients. Sci Rep. 2024;14:12081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11130122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38802526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HY, Lampertico P, Nam JY, Lee HC, Kim SU, Sinn DH, Seo YS, Lee HA, Park SY, Lim YS, Jang ES, Yoon EL, Kim HS, Kim SE, Ahn SB, Shim JJ, Jeong SW, Jung YJ, Sohn JH, Cho YK, Jun DW, Dalekos GN, Idilman R, Sypsa V, Berg T, Buti M, Calleja JL, Goulis J, Manolakopoulos S, Janssen HLA, Jang MJ, Lee YB, Kim YJ, Yoon JH, Papatheodoridis GV, Lee JH. An artificial intelligence model to predict hepatocellular carcinoma risk in Korean and Caucasian patients with chronic hepatitis B. J Hepatol. 2022;76:311&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34606915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui F, Yeo YH, Xu L, Zheng Q, Xu X, Ni W, Tan Y, Zeng QL, He Z, Tian X, Xue Q, Qiu Y, Zhu C, Ding W, Wang J, Huang R, Xu Y, Chen Y, Fan J, Fan Z, Qi X, Huang DQ, Xie Q, Shi J, Wu C, Li J. Development of a machine learning-based model to predict hepatic inflammation in chronic hepatitis B patients with concurrent hepatic steatosis: a cohort study. EClinicalMedicine. 2024;68:102419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10827491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38292041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang H, Hu Y, Guo H, Lai R, Fu Y, Xu S, Zeng Y, Xun Z, Liu C, Wu W, Guo J, Ou Q, Chen T. Using machine learning models to predict HBeAg seroconversion in CHB patients receiving pegylated interferon-&#x3b1; monotherapy. J Clin Lab Anal. 2022;36:e24667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9701889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36181316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang XY, Li XD, Wu BY, Yang Q, Zheng YB, Zheng MH, Wu YP, Ma HY, Zuo J, Jia RX, Yu Y, Xu LY, Tian YX, An Q, Zhang T, He YL, Shi Y, Fan YC. A Model to Identify Gray Zone Patients With Chronic Hepatitis B Requiring Antiviral Therapy: A Multicenter Retrospective Study. J Infect Dis. 2025;232:485&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39960318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau G, Yu ML, Wong G, Thompson A, Ghazinian H, Hou JL, Piratvisuth T, Jia JD, Mizokami M, Cheng G, Chen GF, Liu ZW, Baatarkhuu O, Cheng AL, Ng WL, Lau P, Mok T, Chang JM, Hamid S, Dokmeci AK, Gani RA, Payawal DA, Chow P, Park JW, Strasser SI, Mohamed R, Win KM, Tawesak T, Sarin SK, Omata M. APASL clinical practice guideline on hepatitis B reactivation related to the use of immunosuppressive therapy. Hepatol Int. 2021;15:1031&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8382940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34427860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>