<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41476556</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>50</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on the Feasibility of Enhancing Gas Extraction Efficiency Based on Hydraulic Flushing Combined with Gas Injection Displacement (HF-GID): Model Development and Numerical Simulation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>62322</StartPage><EndPage>62335</EndPage><MedlinePgn>62322-62335</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c10576</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As an effective coal seam permeability enhancement technology, hydraulic flushing (HF) has been applied on a large scale in some Chinese mining areas. However, with mining depth extension and increasingly complex coal seam geology, some coal seams still enter the extraction depletion period after HF. Realizing secondary enhanced extraction of low-permeability coal seams is urgent. Thus, this study investigates feasibility based on hydraulic flushing combined with gas injection displacement (HF-GID) synergistic extraction, focusing on feasibility in the No. 3 coal seam of Shanxi's Qinshui Coalfield via numerical simulation. First, a multifield coupling GID model (covering coal deformation, CH<sub>4</sub>/N<sub>2</sub> migration, and permeability evolution) and an HF model (based on dual-porosity media effective stress and high-pressure water jet coal-breaking) were established. Then, four working conditions (OD, HF, GID, and HF-GID) were simulated, leveraging No. 3 coal seam properties and drilling layouts. Temporal permeability evolution, stress mechanisms of HF/HF-GID, and impacts on gas extraction (especially content reduction) were analyzed. Results show HF-GID achieved significant permeability enhancement. An elliptical high-permeability zone (with permeability reaching a maximum of 250 times the initial value) forms around the boreholes, characterized by slower growth in the early stage and accelerated growth in the mid-to-late stage and outperforming single technologies. GID alleviates the HF-induced peripheral stress concentration via injection pressure, improving gas migration. HF-GID reached the safety threshold (8 m<sup>3</sup>/t) in 75 d, outperforming HF (125 d) and GID (93 d) . A synergistic gain factor &#x3b7; was proposed. Under basic conditions, &#x3b7; ranges 0.08-0.42; optimized parameters increase it to 0.33-1.19. &#x3b7; positively correlates with the hydraulic cavitation radius <i>R</i> <sub>hyd</sub>. At 1.4 MPa injection pressure <i>P</i> <sub>inj</sub>, &#x3b7; peaks, boosting extraction efficiency by 33% compared with other single technologies. HF-GID overcomes the limitations of single technologies through the mechanisms of pressure relief-flow promotion, copermeability enhancement, and accelerated replacement, providing theoretical/technical support for low-permeability coal seam extraction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Macro-Safety Science, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12507</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qingcheng</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-8519-4679</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Mine Safety, North China Institute of Science and Technology, Langfang, Hebei 065201, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71039</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Feiyan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Macro-Safety Science, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12507</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Yunfei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Emergency Management and Safety Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology (Beijing), Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">154610</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yiyang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Emergency Management and Safety Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology (Beijing), Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">154610</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Jiayao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Emergency Management and Safety Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology (Beijing), Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">154610</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Emergency Management and Safety Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology (Beijing), Beijing 100083, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">154610</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41476556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12750234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c10576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Flores R. M.. Coalbed methane: From hazard to resource. Int. J. Coal Geol. 1998;35(1&#x2013;4):3&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1016/S0166-5162(97)00043-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0166-5162(97)00043-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karacan C. Z., Ruiz F. A., Cot&#xe8; M., Phipps S.. Coal mine methane: A review of capture and utilization practices with benefits to mining safety and to greenhouse gas reduction. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2011;86(2&#x2013;3):121&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2011.02.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2011.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu T., Tang C. A., Yang T. H., Zhu W. C., Liu J.. Numerical investigation of coal and gas outbursts in underground collieries. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2006;43(6):905&#x2013;919. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2006.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2006.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z. B., Wei G. M., Liang R., Shi P. P., Wen H., Zhou W. H.. LCO2-ECBM technology for preventing coal and gas outburst: Integrated effect of permeability improvement and gas displacement. Fuel. 2021;285:119219. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2020.119219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2020.119219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao D., Liu J., Pan J. T.. Study on gas seepage from coal seams in the distance between boreholes for gas extraction. J. Loss Prev. Process Ind. 2018;54:266&#x2013;272. doi: 10.1016/j.jlp.2018.04.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jlp.2018.04.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Guanhua N., Lulu S., Qian S., Shang L., Kai D., Jingna X., Gang W.. Effect of ionic liquid treatment on pore structure and fractal characteristics of low rank coal. Fuel. 2020;262:116513. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Zhang H., Guo H.. A case study of gas drainage to low permeability coal seam. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 2017;27(4):687&#x2013;692. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2017.05.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2017.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y., Liu J., Zhang S., Zhang W., Wang H.. Contrast test of different permeability improvement technologies for gas-rich low-permeability coal seams. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2016;33:1282&#x2013;1290. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2016.06.066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2016.06.066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Li X., Bai G., Chai L., Wang Y., Xiao M., Xia S.. Shiyang. Research method of pressure relief and permeability enhancement in low permeability coal seam: A review. AIP Adv. 2022;12(1):010702. doi: 10.1063/5.0078373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0078373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Barboza B. R., Sun Y., Bai J., Thomas H. R., Dutko M., Cottrell M., Li C.. A Review of Hydraulic Fracturing Simulation. Arch. Comput. Methods Eng. 2022;29(4):1&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1007/s11831-021-09653-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11831-021-09653-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei G., Wen H., Deng J., Li Z., Fan S., Lei C., Liu M., Ren L.. Enhanced coalbed permeability and methane recovery via hydraulic slotting combined with liquid CO2 injection. Process Saf. Environ. Prot. 2020;147:234&#x2013;244. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2020.08.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2020.08.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Huang B., Li H., Chen S.. Field investigation of multi-stage pulse hydraulic fracturing for improving permeability of coal seam in directional long borehole in underground coal mines. Environ. Earth Sci. 2023;82(21):519. doi: 10.1007/s12665-023-11212-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-023-11212-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Zhang X., Liu X., Wang L., Zhang J.. Comparative Analysis of the Drainage Effect Based on Improved Hydraulic Flushing Technology. ACS Omega. 2022;7(48):44310&#x2013;44321. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.2c05882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.2c05882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9730496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36506118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei C. F., Li B., Li H. M., Wang F. Z.. A Study on the Pressure Relief Scope and the Stress Variation of Hydraulic Flushing Borehole. J. Eng. Sci. Technol. Rev. 2014;7(1):103&#x2013;108. doi: 10.25103/jestr.071.17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25103/jestr.071.17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu L. M., Song D. Z., Wang E. Y., Liu Z. T., Shen R. X., Li D. X., Jia H. S., Hong S.. Determination of hydraulic flushing impact range by DC resistivity test method. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2018;107:127&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2018.04.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2018.04.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen R., Qiu L., Lv G., Wang E., Li H., Han X., Zhang X., Hou Z.. An effect evaluation method of coal seam hydraulic flushing by EMR. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2018;54:154&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2018.03.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2018.03.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y. B., Lin B. Q., Yang W., Li Z. W., Pang Y., Li H.. Drilling large diameter cross-measure boreholes to improve gas drainage in highly gassy soft coal seams. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2015;26:193&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2015.05.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2015.05.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou Q., Lin B., Zheng C., Hao Z., Zhai C., Liu T., Liang J., Yan F., Yang W., Zhu C.. Novel integrated techniques of drilling&#x2013;slotting&#x2013;separation-sealing for enhanced coal bed methane recovery in underground coal mines. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2015;26:960&#x2013;973. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2015.07.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2015.07.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Liu Y., Li X., Kang Y.. A new method of drilling long boreholes in low permeability coal by improving its permeability. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2010;84(2):94&#x2013;102. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2010.08.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2010.08.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan F., Lin B., Zhu C., Shen C., Zou Q., Guo C., Liu T.. A novel ECBM extraction technology based on the integration of hydraulic slotting and hydraulic fracturing. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2015;22:571&#x2013;579. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2015.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2015.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Lin B., Liu T., Zhao Y., Hao Z.. Synergistic ECBM extraction technology and engineering application based on hydraulic flushing combing gas injection displacement in low permeability coal seams. Fuel. 2022;318:123688. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2022.123688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2022.123688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H., Ji P., Kong X., Li S., Bai Y., Long H., Li B., Di H.. Progress and prospect of gas extraction technology by underground gas injection displacement for increasing flow in low-permeability coal seam in China. J. China Coal Soc. 2023;48(2):730&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong H., Wang K., Wang G., Yang X., Du F.. Underground coal seam gas displacement by injecting nitrogen: Field test and effect prediction. Fuel. 2021;306:121646. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2021.121646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2021.121646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J., Ren T., Cheng Y., Nemcik J., Wang G.. Cyclic N2 injection for enhanced coal seam gas recovery: A laboratory study. Energy. 2019;188:116115. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2019.116115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2019.116115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X., Wang G., Du F., Jin L., Gong H.. N2 injection to enhance coal seam gas drainage (N2-ECGD): Insights from underground field trial investigation. Energy. 2022;239:122247. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2021.122247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2021.122247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X., Wang G. D., Ni M. Q., Shu L. Y., Gong H. R., Wang Z. E.. Investigation on Key Parameters of N2 Injection to Enhance Coal Seam Gas Drainage (N2-ECGD) Energies. 2022;15(14):5064. doi: 10.3390/en15145064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15145064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang A., Fan Z., Zhao L.. An investigation on phase behaviors and displacement mechanisms of gas injection in gas condensate reservoir. Fuel. 2020;268:117373. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2020.117373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2020.117373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X., He L., Lu T., Liu Y., Li X., Cao J., Luo G., Yang H.. Optimization and field application of water jet for coal bed methane stimulation. Energy Sci. Eng. 2019;7(6):3186&#x2013;3203. doi: 10.1002/ese3.490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ese3.490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Hu B., Nie B., Liu X., Zhao D., Li H., Deng C., Duan Z.. Experimental study and field application of hydraulic flushing technology in soft coal seam. Sci. Rep. 2025;15(1):3304. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-87683-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-87683-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11770141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39865133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connell L. D.. Coupled flow and geomechanical processes during gas production from coal seams. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2009;79(1&#x2013;2):18&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2009.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2009.03.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui X., Bustin R. M.. Volumetric strain associated with methane desorption and its impact on coalbed gas production from deep coal seams. AAPG Bull. 2005;89(9):1181&#x2013;1202. doi: 10.1306/05110504114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1306/05110504114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora C. A., Wattenbarger R. A.. Analysis and Verification of Dual Porosity and CBM Shape Factors. J. Can. Pet. Technol. 2009;48(2):17&#x2013;21. doi: 10.2118/09-02-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/09-02-17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J. Q., Durucan S.. A Model for Changes in Coalbed Permeability During Primary and Enhanced Methane Recovery. SPE Reservoir Eval. Eng. 2005;8(4):291&#x2013;299. doi: 10.2118/87230-PA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/87230-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J. G., Kabir A., Liu J. S., Chen Z. W.. Effects of non-Darcy flow on the performance of coal seam gas wells. Int. J. Coal Geol. 2012;93:62&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1016/j.coal.2012.01.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2012.01.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hungerford F., Ren T., Aziz N.. Evolution and application of in-seam drilling for gas drainage. Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol. 2013;23(4):543&#x2013;553. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmst.2013.07.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2013.07.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren T., Wang G., Cheng Y., Qi Q.. Model development and simulation study of the feasibility of enhancing gas drainage efficiency through nitrogen injection. Fuel. 2017;194(194):406&#x2013;422. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2017.01.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2017.01.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean D. E., Stiel L. I.. The viscosity of nonpolar gas mixtures at moderate and high pressures. AIChE J. 1965;11(3):526&#x2013;532. doi: 10.1002/aic.690110330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aic.690110330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H. J., Tang H. L., Wu Y. C., Wang K., Xu C.. Gas seepage in underground coal seams: Application of the equivalent scale of coal matrix-fracture structures in coal permeability measurements. Fuel. 2021;288:119641. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2020.119641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2020.119641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T., Lin B., Yang W.. Impact of matrix&#x2013;fracture interactions on coal permeability: Model development and analysis. Fuel. 2017;207:522&#x2013;532. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2017.06.125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2017.06.125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Fan C., Han J., Luo M., Yang Z., Bi H.. A fully coupled thermal-hydraulic-mechanical model with two-phase flow for coalbed methane extraction. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2016;33:324&#x2013;336. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2016.05.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2016.05.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng T., Xue Y., Zhang C.. Modeling and simulation on heat-injection enhanced coal seam gas recovery with experimentally validated non-Darcy gas flow. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2019;177:734&#x2013;744. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2019.02.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2019.02.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S. Q., Cheng Y. P., Li W.. Model development and analysis of the evolution of coal permeability under different boundary conditions. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2016;31:129&#x2013;138. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2016.02.049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2016.02.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiabdolmajid V., Kaiser P.. Brittleness of rock and stability assessment in hard rock tunneling. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2003;18(1):35&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/S0886-7798(02)00100-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0886-7798(02)00100-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown E. T., Hoek E.. Trends in relationships between measured in-situ stresses and depth. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. Geomech. Abstr. 1978;15(4):211&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1016/0148-9062(78)91227-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0148-9062(78)91227-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si L., Li Z., Yang Y.. Evolution Characteristics of Gas Permeability Under Multiple Factors. Transp. Porous Media. 2018;127(2):415&#x2013;432. doi: 10.1007/s11242-018-1199-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11242-018-1199-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Huang S., Ge Z., Zhou Z., Liu W., Guan Y.. Research progress and strategic thinking of coal mine water jet technology to enhance coal permeability in China. J. China Coal Soc. 2022;47(9):3189&#x2013;3211. doi: 10.13225/j.cnki.jccs.SS22.0602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13225/j.cnki.jccs.SS22.0602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y., Shu L., Huo Z., Hao J., Li Y.. Numerical simulation of sectional hydraulic reaming for methane extraction from coal seams. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2021;95:104180. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Li Z., Wang H., Chen M., Xian L.. Numerical Simulation Investigation of N2 Injection for Enhanced Coalbed Methane Recovery. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. 2025;50(7):4661&#x2013;4672. doi: 10.1007/s13369-024-09123-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-024-09123-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B. X., Deng Z., Fu X. H., Yu K., Zeng F. H.. An experimental study on the effects of acidization on coal permeability: Implications for the enhancement of coalbed methane production. Energy. 2023;280:128145. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.128145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.128145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R., Hu S., Zhang X., Ren X., Zhang J., Fan W.. Experimental study on the alteration properties of acidified clay particles in coalbed methane wells. Powder Technol. 2024;447:120152. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2024.120152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2024.120152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>