<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41870601</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-2783</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the International Society of Sports Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The emerging and evolving evidence supporting creatine as an ergogenic aid: history and applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2646627</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2646627</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2646627</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/15502783.2026.2646627</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Creatine is one of the most extensively studied ergogenic aids, with over three decades of research supporting its role in exercise performance, recovery, and health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This narrative review summarizes the historical development of creatine supplementation and evaluates evidence regarding its mechanisms, efficacy across active, athletic populations (e.g. strength, endurance, team-sport), and tactical (e.g. military, law enforcement) populations, and its safety profile.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The evidence suggests that creatine enhances phosphocreatine resynthesis and cellular energy availability, resulting in consistent improvements in high-intensity exercise performance, training adaptations, lean body mass, strength, and power. Additional findings indicate that creatine may attenuate exercise-induced muscle damage and inflammation, support recovery, and improve functional outcomes following strenuous activity. Emerging research suggests benefits for endurance and team-sport athletes through enhanced glycogen resynthesis, calcium handling, oxidative stress mitigation, and repeated-sprint performance. In tactical populations, creatine may support occupational readiness by improving strength, hydration status, thermoregulation, cognition, sleep quality, and recovery, with possible neuroprotective and cardiometabolic implications. Soccer-specific evidence demonstrates improvements in repeated-sprint ability and tolerance to high training loads, with preliminary data suggesting protective effects against neurotrauma and gut barrier disruption. Importantly, pooled analyses from hundreds of clinical trials report no greater incidence of adverse events compared with placebo, reinforcing creatine's established safety profile.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Overall, the evidence suggests that creatine is a versatile supplement with strong evidence to enhance performance and recovery across diverse populations. Future research should prioritize individualized dosing strategies, long-term outcomes in underrepresented groups, and exploration of novel therapeutic applications in health and disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerksick</LastName><ForeName>Chad</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0458-7294</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Performance Nutrition Laboratory, Lindenwood University, St. Charles, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez</LastName><ForeName>Drew</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sport Nutrition Lab, Department of Kinesiology and Sports Management, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational, Performance, and Nutrition Lab, Department of Kinesiology, Sam Houston State University, Huntsville, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stout</LastName><ForeName>Jeffery</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6114-1649</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forbes</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6896-5552</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education Studies, Brandon University, Brandon, MB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Candow</LastName><ForeName>Darren</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6655-4482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology and Health Studies, University of Regina, Regina, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziegenfuss</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Center for Applied Health Sciences, Canfield, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AFC Bournemouth, Department of Performance and Medicine, Bournemouth, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic and Trauma Surgery, Martin-Luther-University Halle-Wittenberg, University Medicine, Halle, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwesig</LastName><ForeName>Ren&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic and Trauma Surgery, Martin-Luther-University Halle-Wittenberg, University Medicine, Halle, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreider</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3906-1658</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise &amp; Sport Nutrition Lab, Department of Kinesiology and Sports Management, Texas A&amp;M University, College Station, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Int Soc Sports Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234168</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1550-2783</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>MU72812GK0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003401">Creatine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003401" MajorTopicYN="Y">Creatine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064133" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports Nutritional Physiological Phenomena</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endurance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tactical athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">team sports</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CMK has received grants, honoraria, and consulting fees from companies who do business in areas related to exercise and nutrition. He currently serves as a scientific advisor to multiple companies who do business in exercise and nutrition, and he currently serves as a Scientific Affiliate for Alzchem and on a Scientific Advisory Board for NNB Nutrition, companies that manufacture creatine. DG conducted industry-sponsored research involving creatine supplementation and received creatine donations for scientific studies and travel support for presentations involving creatine supplementation at scientific conferences and serves on the Scientific Advisory Board for Alzchem, Create and Iovate (companies that manufacture creatine products). RBK has conducted industry-sponsored research on creatine through grants awarded to the universities he has been affiliated, received financial support for presenting invited lectures at conferences about sports nutrition and creatine. Additionally, he serves as Chair of the Scientific Advisory Board for AlzChem (a company that makes creatine monohydrate). He does not own any patents, receive royalties for the sale of creatine or any dietary supplement, or have any ownership in a company that sells creatine or any dietary supplements. TNZ has conducted industry sponsored research involving creatine supplementation and has received research funding from industry sponsors related to sports nutrition products and ingredients. JRS has received grants and contracts to research dietary supplements, has served as a paid consultant for industry, and received honoraria for speaking at conferences and writing lay articles about sports nutrition. He is a Chair of the Scientific Advisory Board for Alzchem. SF is a scientific advisor for Bear Balanced&#xae; and has received creatine donations from Creapure&#xae; for research purposes. PM and RS declare that no commercial or financial relationships exist that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41870601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13011109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2026.2646627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Kalman DS, Antonio J, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: safety and efficacy of creatine supplementation in exercise, sport, and Medicine. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:18. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0173-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0173-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Jager R, Purpura M. Bioavailability, efficacy, safety, and regulatory status of creatine and related compounds: a critical review. Nutrients. 2022;14(5). doi: 10.3390/nu14051035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14051035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8912867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35268011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farshidfar F, Pinder MA, Myrie SB. Creatine supplementation and skeletal muscle metabolism for building muscle Mass- review of the potential mechanisms of action. Curr Protein Pept Sci. 2017;18(12):1273&#x2013;1287. doi: 10.2174/1389203718666170606105108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1389203718666170606105108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28595527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Nevill M, Harris DB, et al. Absorption of creatine supplied as a drink, in meat or in solid form. J Sports Sci. 2002;20(2):147&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1080/026404102317200855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/026404102317200855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11811571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persky AM, Brazeau GA, Hochhaus G. Pharmacokinetics of the dietary supplement creatine. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2003;42(6):557&#x2013;574-</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12793840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wax B, Kerksick CM, Jagim AR, et al. Creatine for exercise and sports performance, with recovery considerations for healthy populations. Nutrients. 2021;13(6). doi: 10.3390/nu13061915</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13061915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8228369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB. Effects of creatine supplementation on performance and training adaptations. Mol Cell Biochem. 2003;244(1&#x2013;2):89&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1023/A:1022465203458</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022465203458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12701815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB. Effects of creatine supplementation on body composition, strength, and sprint performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30:73&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199801000-00011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199801000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9475647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS. Creatine supplementation enhances muscular performance during high-intensity resistance exercise. J Am Diet Assoc. 1997;97:765&#x2013;770. doi: 10.1016/s0002-8223(97)00189-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0002-8223(97)00189-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9216554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanhers C. Creatine supplementation and lower limb strength performance: a systematic review and meta-analyses. Sports Med. 2015;45:1285&#x2013;1294. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0337-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0337-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25946994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MH, Branch JD. Creatine supplementation and exercise performance: an update. J Am Coll Nutr. 1998;17(3):216&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1080/07315724.1998.10718751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.1998.10718751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9627907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout JR, Kreider RB, Candow DG, et al. The birth of modern sports nutrition: tracing the path from muscle biopsies to creatine supplementation-A narrative review. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2025;22(Suppl. 1):2463373. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2025.2463373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2025.2463373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11837910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39964101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstrom J. Muscle electrolytes in man determined by neutron activation analysis on needle biopsy specimens. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1962;14(Suppl 68).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E, Bergstrom J, Anderson NM. Breakdown and resynthesis of phosphorylcreatine and adenosine triphosphate in connection with muscular work in man. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1967;19(1):56&#x2013;66. doi: 10.3109/00365516709093481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00365516709093481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6031321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polley HF, Bickel WH. Punch biopsy of synovial membrane. Ann Rheum Dis. 1951;10(3):277&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1136/ard.10.3.277</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.10.3.277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1011693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14878348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Hultman E, Nordesjo LO. Glycogen, glycolytic intermediates and high-energy phosphates determined in biopsy samples of musculus quadriceps femoris of man at rest. Methods and variance of values. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1974;33(2):109&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1080/00365517409082477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00365517409082477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4852173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RC, Soderlund K, Hultman E. Elevation of creatine in resting and exercised muscle of normal subjects by creatine supplementation. Clin Sci (Lond). 1992;83(3):367&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1327657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Bodin K, Soderlund K, et al. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on skeletal muscle phosphocreatine resynthesis. Am J Physiol. 1994;266(5 Pt 1):E725&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.1994.266.5.E725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1994.266.5.E725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8203511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL. Influence of oral creatine supplementation of muscle torque during repeated bouts of maximal voluntary exercise in man. Clin Sci (Lond). 1993;84:565&#x2013;571. doi: 10.1042/cs0840565</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0840565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8504634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey A. Creatine ingestion favorably affects performance and muscle metabolism during maximal exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1996;271:E31&#x2013;E37. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.1996.271.1.E31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1996.271.1.E31</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8760078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke R, Pinero A, Coleman M, et al. The effects of creatine supplementation combined with resistance training on regional measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2023;15(9). doi: 10.3390/nu15092116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15092116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10180745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Forbes SC, Ostojic SM, et al. Heads Up for creatine supplementation and its potential applications for brain health and function. Sports Med. 2023;53(Suppl 1):49&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1007/s40279-023-01870-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01870-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10721691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37368234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Gordon JJ, et al. A 2-yr randomized controlled trial on creatine supplementation during exercise for postmenopausal bone health. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2023;55(10):1750&#x2013;1760. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000003202-</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10487398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37144634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silveira CL, de Souza TS, Batista GR, et al. Is long term creatine and glutamine supplementation effective in enhancing physical performance of military police officers?. J Hum Kinet. 2014;43:131&#x2013;138. doi: 10.2478/hukin-2014-0098-</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/hukin-2014-0098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4332172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elstad K, Malone C, Luedke J, et al. The effects of protein and carbohydrate supplementation, with and without creatine, on occupational performance in firefighters. Nutrients. 2023;15(24). doi: 10.3390/nu15245134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15245134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10745745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38140393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gras D, Lanhers C, Bagheri R, et al. Creatine supplementation and VO(2)max: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2023;63(21):4855&#x2013;4866. doi: 10.1080/10408398.2021.2008864</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2021.2008864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34859731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith-Ryan AE, Cabre HE, Eckerson JM, et al. Creatine supplementation in Women's health: a lifespan perspective. Nutrients. 2021;13(3). doi: 10.3390/nu13030877</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13030877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7998865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper R, Naclerio F, Allgrove J, et al. Creatine supplementation with specific view to exercise/sports performance: an update. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):33. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-9-33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-9-33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22817979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syrotuik DG, Bell GJ. Acute creatine monohydrate supplementation: a descriptive physiological profile of responders vs. Nonresponders. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(3):610&#x2013;617. doi: 10.1519/12392.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/12392.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15320650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobi JM, Rice CL, Curtin SV, et al. Neuromuscular properties and fatigue in older men following acute creatine supplementation. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;84(4):321&#x2013;328. doi: 10.1007/s004210000373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210000373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11374116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihic S, MacDonald JR, McKenzie S, et al. Acute creatine loading increases fat-free mass, but does not affect blood pressure, plasma creatinine, or CK activity in men and women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(2):291&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM. Acute creatine supplementation in older men. Int J Sports Med. 2000;21(1):71&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1055/s-2000-8859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2000-8859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10683103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanez-Silva A, Buzzachera CF, Picarro IDC, et al. Effect of low dose, short-term creatine supplementation on muscle power output in elite youth soccer players. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:5. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0162-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0162-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28190980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox G, Mujika I, Tumilty D, et al. Acute creatine supplementation and performance during a field test simulating match play in elite female soccer players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2002;12(1):33&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.12.1.33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.12.1.33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11993621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Volek JS. Effects of creatine supplementation and resistance training on muscle strength and weightlifting performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(4):822&#x2013;831. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200311000-00031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200311000-00031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14636102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ates O, Keskin B, Bayraktar B. The effect of acute creatine supplementation on fatigue and anaerobic performance. Cent Eur J Sports Sci Med. 2017;19:85&#x2013;92. doi: 10.18276/cej.2017.3-08</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18276/cej.2017.3-08</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares Freitas Sampaio CR, Aidar FJ, Ferreira ARP, et al. Can creatine supplementation interfere with muscle strength and fatigue in Brazilian national level paralympic powerlifting? Nutrients. 2020;12(9): 10.3390/nu12092492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12092492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32824920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birch R, Noble D, Greenhaff PL. The influence of dietary creatine supplementation on performance during repeated bouts of maximal isokinetic cycling in man. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69(3):268&#x2013;276. doi: 10.1007/BF01094800</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01094800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8001541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Duncan ND, Mazzetti SA, et al. Performance and muscle fiber adaptations to creatine supplementation and heavy resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(8):1147&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199908000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10449017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hultman E. Muscle creatine loading in men. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1996;81:232&#x2013;237. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1996.81.1.232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1996.81.1.232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8828669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in college football athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1667&#x2013;1673. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrusch MJ, Chilibeck PD, Chad KE, et al. Creatine supplementation combined with resistance training in older men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(12):2111&#x2013;2117. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200112000-00021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200112000-00021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly VC, Jenkins DG. Effect of oral creatine supplementation on near-maximal strength and repeated sets of high-intensity bench press exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 1998;12(2):109&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syrotuik D, Bell G, Burnham R, et al. Absolute and relative strength performance following creatine monohydrate supplementation combined with periodized resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14:182&#x2013;190. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200005000-00011 05/01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200005000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenberghe K, Goris M, Van Hecke P, et al. Long-term creatine intake is beneficial to muscle performance during resistance training. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1997;83:2055&#x2013;2063. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1997.83.6.2055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1997.83.6.2055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Volek JS. Creatine supplementation. Its role in human performance. Clin Sports Med. 1999;18(3):651&#x2013;666. doi: 10.1016/s0278-5919(05)70174-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0278-5919(05)70174-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10410847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stozer A, Vodopivc P, Krizancic Bombek L. Pathophysiology of exercise-induced muscle damage and its structural, functional, metabolic, and clinical consequences. Physiol Res. 2020;69(4):565&#x2013;598. doi: 10.33549/physiolres.934371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33549/physiolres.934371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8549894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32672048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordingley DM, Cornish SM, Candow DG. Anti-inflammatory and anti-catabolic effects of creatine supplementation: a brief review. Nutrients. 2022;14(3). doi: 10.3390/nu14030544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14030544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8839648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35276903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke MB. Creatine supplementation enhances muscle force recovery after eccentrically-induced muscle damage in healthy individuals. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:13. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-6-13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-6-13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2697134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19490606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northeast B, Clifford T. The effect of creatine supplementation on markers of exercise-induced muscle damage: a systematic review and meta-analysis of human intervention trials. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2021;31(3):276&#x2013;291. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2020-0282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2020-0282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Conti MP, Miles MP. Creatine supplementation does not reduce muscle damage or enhance recovery from resistance exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(4):1208&#x2013;1213. doi: 10.1519/R-21076.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-21076.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Gunn B, Clarkson PM. The effects of creatine supplementation on exercise-induced muscle damage. J Strength Cond Res. 2001;15(2):178&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200105000-00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200105000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11710402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi S, Inami T, Nishioka T, et al. The effects of creatine monohydrate supplementation on recovery from eccentric exercise-induced muscle damage: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial considering sex and age differences. Nutrients. 2025;17(11). doi: 10.3390/nu17111772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17111772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12157024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40507040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu SH, Chen KL, Hsu C, et al. Creatine supplementation for muscle growth: a scoping review of randomized clinical trials from 2012 to 2021. Nutrients. 2022;14(6). doi: 10.3390/nu14061255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14061255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8949037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doma K, Ramachandran AK, Boullosa D, et al. The paradoxical effect of creatine monohydrate on muscle damage markers: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2022;52(7):1623&#x2013;1645. doi: 10.1007/s40279-022-01640-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-022-01640-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9213373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35218552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Neto JHF, et al. Creatine supplementation and endurance performance: surges and sprints to win the race. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2023;20(1):2204071. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2023.2204071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2023.2204071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10132248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37096381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts PA, Fox J, Peirce N, et al. Creatine ingestion augments dietary carbohydrate mediated muscle glycogen supercompensation during the initial 24 h of recovery following prolonged exhaustive exercise in humans. Amino Acids. 2016;48(8):1831&#x2013;1842. doi: 10.1007/s00726-016-2252-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-016-2252-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4974290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27193231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Smith-Ryan AE, et al. Supplements and nutritional interventions to augment high-intensity interval training physiological and performance Adaptations-A narrative review. Nutrients. 2020;12(2). doi: 10.3390/nu12020390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12020390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7071320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassit RA, Curi R, Costa Rosa LF. Creatine supplementation reduces plasma levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines and PGE2 after a half-ironman competition. Amino Acids. 2008;35(2):425&#x2013;431. doi: 10.1007/s00726-007-0582-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-007-0582-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17917696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos RV, Bassit RA, Caperuto EC, et al. The effect of creatine supplementation upon inflammatory and muscle soreness markers after a 30km race. Life Sci. 2004;75(16):1917&#x2013;1924. doi: 10.1016/j.lfs.2003.11.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2003.11.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15306159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss M, Kaddurah-Daouk R. Creatine and creatinine metabolism. Physiol Rev. 2000;80(3):1107&#x2013;1213. doi: 10.1152/physrev.2000.80.3.1107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.2000.80.3.1107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10893433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putman CT, Gallo M, Martins KJ, et al. Creatine loading elevates the intracellular phosphorylation potential and alters adaptive responses of rat fast-twitch muscle to chronic low-frequency stimulation. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2015;40(7):671&#x2013;682. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2014-0300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2014-0300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26039543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pashayee-Khamene F, Heidari Z, Asbaghi O, et al. Creatine supplementation protocols with or without training interventions on body composition: a GRADE-assessed systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2024;21(1):2380058. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2024.2380058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2380058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11268231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39042054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsom PD, Harridge SD, Soderlund K, et al. Creatine supplementation per se does not enhance endurance exercise performance. Acta Physiol Scand. 1993;149(4):521&#x2013;523. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1993.tb09649.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1993.tb09649.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8128901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Landa J, Santibanez-Gutierrez A, Todorovic N, et al. Effects of creatine monohydrate on endurance performance in a trained population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2023;53(5):1017&#x2013;1027. doi: 10.1007/s40279-023-01823-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01823-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36877404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomcik KA, Camera DM, Bone JL, et al. Effects of creatine and carbohydrate loading on cycling time trial performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50(1):141&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28806275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelhardt M, Neumann G, Berbalk A, et al. Creatine supplementation in endurance sports. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30(7):1123&#x2013;1129. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199807000-00016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199807000-00016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9662683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anomasiri W, Sanguanrungsirikul S, Saichandee P. Low dose creatine supplementation enhances sprint phase of 400 meters swimming performance. J Med Assoc Thai. 2004;87 Suppl 2:S228&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16083193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graef JL, Smith AE, Kendall KL, et al. The effects of four weeks of creatine supplementation and high-intensity interval training on cardiorespiratory fitness: a randomized controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:18. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-6-18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-6-18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2780977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19909536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Sletten N, Durrer C, et al. Creatine monohydrate supplementation does not augment fitness, performance, or body composition adaptations in response to four weeks of high-intensity interval training in young females. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2017;27(3):285&#x2013;292. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2016-0129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27768397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg AM, Nilsson E, Werneman J, et al. Muscle composition in relation to age and sex. Clin Sci (Lond). 1991;81(2):249&#x2013;256. doi: 10.1042/cs0810249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0810249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1716189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AN, Moore SR, Patterson ND, et al. The effects of creatine monohydrate loading on exercise recovery in active women throughout the menstrual cycle. Nutrients. 2023;15(16). doi: 10.3390/nu15163567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15163567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10459976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37630756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SR, Gordon AN, Cabre HE, et al. A randomized controlled trial of changes in fluid distribution across menstrual phases with creatine supplementation. Nutrients. 2023;15(2). doi: 10.3390/nu15020429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15020429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9865497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36678300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall KL, Smith AE, Graef JL, et al. Effects of four weeks of high-intensity interval training and creatine supplementation on critical power and anaerobic working capacity in college-aged men. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(6):1663&#x2013;1669. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b1fd1f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b1fd1f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickner RC, Dyck DJ, Sklar J, et al. Effect of 28 days of creatine ingestion on muscle metabolism and performance of a simulated cycling road race. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2010;7:26. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-7-26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-7-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2909923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20609257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez DE, Forbes SC, Zapp A, et al. Fueling the firefighter and tactical athlete with creatine: a narrative review of a key nutrient for public safety. Nutrients. 2024;16(19). doi: 10.3390/nu16193285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16193285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11478539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39408252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez DE, McAllister MJ, Waldman HS, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: tactical athlete nutrition. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2022;19(1):267&#x2013;315. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2022.2086017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2022.2086017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9261739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35813846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar Bonfim Cruz AJ, Brooks SJ, Kleinkopf K, et al. Creatine improves total sleep duration following resistance training days versus non-resistance training days among naturally menstruating females. Nutrients. 2024;16(16). doi: 10.3390/nu16162772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16162772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11357324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainsley Dean PJ, Arikan G, Opitz B, et al. Potential for use of creatine supplementation following mild traumatic brain injury. Concussion. 2017;2(2):CNC34. doi: 10.2217/cnc-2016-0016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cnc-2016-0016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6094347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30202575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dechent P, Pouwels PJ, Wilken B, et al. Increase of total creatine in human brain after oral supplementation of creatine-monohydrate. Am J Physiol. 1999;277(3):R698&#x2013;704. doi: 10.1152/ajpregu.1999.277.3.R698</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.1999.277.3.R698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10484486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan E, Gualano B, Rawson ES. Beyond muscle: the effects of creatine supplementation on brain creatine, cognitive processing, and traumatic brain injury. Eur J Sport Sci. 2019;19(1):1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2018.1500644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2018.1500644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30086660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Cordingley DM, Cornish SM, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on brain function and health. Nutrients. 2022;14(5). doi: 10.3390/nu14050921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14050921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8912287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35267907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohtsuki S, Tachikawa M, Takanaga H, et al. The blood-brain barrier creatine transporter is a major pathway for supplying creatine to the brain. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2002;22(11):1327&#x2013;1335. doi: 10.1097/01.WCB.0000033966.83623.7D</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.WCB.0000033966.83623.7D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12439290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rae C, Digney AL, McEwan SR, et al. Oral creatine monohydrate supplementation improves brain performance: a double-blind, placebo-controlled, cross-over trial. Proc Biol Sci. 2003;270(1529):2147&#x2013;2150. doi: 10.1098/rspb.2003.2492</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rspb.2003.2492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1691485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14561278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke H, Hickner RC, Ormsbee MJ. The potential role of creatine in vascular health. Nutrients. 2021;13(3). doi: 10.3390/nu13030857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13030857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7999364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke H, Kim DH, Meza CA, et al. The evolving applications of creatine supplementation: could creatine improve vascular health?. Nutrients. 2020;12(9). doi: 10.3390/nu12092834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12092834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32947909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke HE, Akhavan NS, Behl TA, et al. Effect of creatine monohydrate supplementation on Macro- and microvascular endothelial function in older adults: a pilot study. Nutrients. 2024;17(1). doi: 10.3390/nu17010058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu17010058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11723049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39796490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Chilibeck PD, Gordon J, et al. Effect of 12 months of creatine supplementation and whole-body resistance training on measures of bone, muscle and strength in older males. Nutr Health. 2021;27(2):151&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1177/0260106020975247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0260106020975247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33234019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Candow DG, Landeryou T, et al. Effects of creatine and resistance training on bone health in postmenopausal women. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(8):1587&#x2013;1595. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilibeck PD, Chrusch MJ, Chad KE, et al. Creatine monohydrate and resistance training increase bone mineral content and density in older men. J Nutr Health Aging. 2005;9(5):352&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16222402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Ostojic SM, Souza-Junior TP, et al. A high dose of creatine combined with resistance training appears to be required to augment indices of bone health in older adults. Ann Nutr Metab. 2022;78(3):183&#x2013;186. doi: 10.1159/000520967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000520967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34788768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenwood M, Kreider RB, Greenwood L, et al. Cramping and injury incidence in collegiate football players are reduced by creatine supplementation. J Athl Train. 2003;38(3):216&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC233174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14608430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenwood M, Kreider RB, Melton C, et al. Creatine supplementation during college football training does not increase the incidence of cramping or injury. Mol Cell Biochem. 2003;244(1-2):83&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1023/A:1022413202549</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022413202549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12701814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilduff LP, Georgiades E, James N, et al. The effects of creatine supplementation on cardiovascular, metabolic, and thermoregulatory responses during exercise in the heat in endurance-trained humans. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2004;14(4):443&#x2013;460. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.14.4.443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.14.4.443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15467102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez RM, Casa DJ, McDermott BP, et al. Does creatine supplementation hinder exercise heat tolerance or hydration status? A systematic review with meta-analyses. J Athl Train. 2009;44(2):215&#x2013;223. doi: 10.4085/1062-6050-44.2.215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4085/1062-6050-44.2.215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19295968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosene JM, Whitman SA, Fogarty TD. A comparison of thermoregulation with creatine supplementation between the sexes in a thermoneutral environment. J Athl Train. 2004;39(1):50&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC385262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15085212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss BA, Powers ME. Creatine supplementation does not impair the thermoregulatory response during a bout of exercise in the heat. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2006;46(4):555&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17119520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendel RW, Blegen M, Cheatham C, et al. Effects of creatine on thermoregulatory responses while exercising in the heat. Nutrition. 2005;21(3):301&#x2013;307. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2004.06.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2004.06.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15797670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiaming Y, Rahimi MH. Creatine supplementation effect on recovery following exercise-induced muscle damage: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Food Biochem. 2021;45(10):e13916. doi: 10.1111/jfbc.13916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfbc.13916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34472118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey SB, Milligan-Saville JS, Paterson HM, et al. The mental health of fire-fighters: an examination of the impact of repeated trauma exposure. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2016;50(7):649&#x2013;658. doi: 10.1177/0004867415615217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004867415615217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26607303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakellaris G, Kotsiou M, Tamiolaki M, et al. Prevention of complications related to traumatic brain injury in children and adolescents with creatine administration: an open label randomized pilot study. J Trauma. 2006;61(2):322&#x2013;329. doi: 10.1097/01.ta.0000230269.46108.d5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.ta.0000230269.46108.d5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16917445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakellaris GS, Partalis NI, Nasis GD, et al. Outcome of traumatic dysarthria and lingual problems of understanding with creatine administration. An open label randomized pilot study. J Trauma Treat. 2012;1.doi: 10.4172/2167-1222.1000120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2167-1222.1000120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett T, Bathalon G, Armstrong D 3rd, et al. Effect of creatine on performance of militarily relevant tasks and soldier health. Mil Med. 2001;166(11):996&#x2013;1002. doi: 10.1093/milmed/166.11.996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/milmed/166.11.996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11725330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warber JP, Tharion WJ, Patton JF, et al. The effect of creatine monohydrate supplementation on obstacle course and multiple bench press performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16(4):500&#x2013;508. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200211000-00003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200211000-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez DE, Lanham SN, Martin SE, et al. Firefighter health: a narrative review of occupational threats and countermeasures. Healthcare (Basel). 2024;12(4). doi: 10.3390/healthcare12040440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare12040440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10888326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38391814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delpino FM, Figueiredo LM, Forbes SC, et al. Influence of age, sex, and type of exercise on the efficacy of creatine supplementation on lean body mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Nutrition. 2022;103-104:111791. doi: 10.1016/j.nut.2022.111791</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2022.111791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35986981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes SC, Candow DG, Ostojic SM, et al. Meta-analysis examining the importance of creatine ingestion strategies on lean tissue mass and strength in older adults. Nutrients. 2021;13(6). doi: 10.3390/nu13061912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13061912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8229907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candow DG, Prokopidis K, Forbes SC, et al. Resistance exercise and creatine supplementation on fat mass in adults. Nutrients. 2023;15(20). doi: 10.3390/nu15204343</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15204343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arciero PJ, Hannibal NS 3rd, Nindl BC, et al. Comparison of creatine ingestion and resistance training on energy expenditure and limb blood flow. Metabolism. 2001;50(12):1429&#x2013;1434. doi: 10.1053/meta.2001.28159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2001.28159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angerer P, Kadlez-Gebhardt S, Delius M, et al. Comparison of cardiocirculatory and thermal strain of Male firefighters during fire suppression to exercise stress test and aerobic exercise testing. Am J Cardiol. 2008;102(11):1551&#x2013;1556. doi: 10.1016/j.amjcard.2008.07.052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2008.07.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn GP, Blevins S, Fernhall B, et al. Core temperature and heart rate response to repeated bouts of firefighting activities. Ergonomics. 2013;56(9):1465&#x2013;1473. doi: 10.1080/00140139.2013.818719</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00140139.2013.818719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23869685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern M, Podewils LJ, Vukovich M, et al. Physiological response to exercise in the heat following creatine supplementation. J Ex Phys Online. 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volek JS, Mazzetti SA, Farquhar WB, et al. Physiological responses to short-term exercise in the heat after creatine loading. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(7):1101&#x2013;1108. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200107000-00006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200107000-00006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Easton C, Turner S, Pitsiladis YP. Creatine and glycerol hyperhydration in trained subjects before exercise in the heat. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2007;17(1):70&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.17.1.70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.17.1.70</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17460334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prokopidis K, Giannos P, Triantafyllidis KK, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on memory in healthy individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Nutr Rev. 2023;81(4):416&#x2013;427. doi: 10.1093/nutrit/nuac064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nutrit/nuac064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9999677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35984306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Mielcarz G, Harris RC, et al. Creatine supplementation and cognitive performance in elderly individuals. Neuropsychol Dev Cogn B Aging Neuropsychol Cogn. 2007;14(5):517&#x2013;528. doi: 10.1080/13825580600788100&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13825580600788100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17828627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMoulin D, Jacobs S, Nam YS, et al. Mental health among firefighters: understanding the mental health risks, treatment barriers, and coping strategies. J Occup Environ Med. 2022;64(11):e714&#x2013;e721. doi: 10.1097/JOM.0000000000002680</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JOM.0000000000002680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo DG, Forrest LN, Shi X, et al. Creatine target engagement with brain bioenergetics: a dose-ranging phosphorus-31 magnetic resonance spectroscopy study of adolescent females with SSRI-resistant depression. Amino Acids. 2016;48(8):1941&#x2013;1954. doi: 10.1007/s00726-016-2194-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-016-2194-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4974294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26907087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roitman S, Green T, Osher Y, et al. Creatine monohydrate in resistant depression: a preliminary study. Bipolar Disord. 2007;9(7):754&#x2013;758. doi: 10.1111/j.1399-5618.2007.00532.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-5618.2007.00532.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17988366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conti F, McCue JJ, DiTuro P, et al. Mitigating traumatic brain injury: a narrative review of supplementation and dietary protocols. Nutrients. 2024;16(15). doi: 10.3390/nu16152430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16152430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11314487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39125311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordji-Nejad A, Matusch A, Kleedorfer S, et al. Single dose creatine improves cognitive performance and induces changes in cerebral high energy phosphates during sleep deprivation. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):4937. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-54249-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54249-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10902318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38418482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangsbo J, Iaia FM, Krustrup P. Metabolic response and fatigue in soccer. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2007;2(2):111&#x2013;127. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2.2.111&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2.2.111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr M, Krustrup P, Bangsbo J. Match performance of high-standard soccer players with special reference to development of fatigue. J Sports Sci. 2003;21(7):519&#x2013;528. doi: 10.1080/0264041031000071182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0264041031000071182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12848386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson DR, Hamby DG, Russel W, et al. Long-term effects of creatine monohydrate on strength and power. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13:187&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Sanborn K, Smith LL, et al. Effects of in-season (5 weeks) creatine and pyruvate supplementation on anaerobic performance and body composition in American football players. Int J Sport Nutr. 1999;9(2):146&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10362452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson-Meyer D, Hunter G, Trowbridge C, et al. The effect of creatine supplementation on muscle strength and body composition during off-season training in female soccer players. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14:434&#x2013;442. doi: 10.1519/00124278-200011000-00011 11/01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00124278-200011000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG, Bemben DA, Loftiss DD, et al. Creatine supplementation during resistance training in college football athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(10):1667&#x2013;1673. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jowko E, Ostaszewski P, Jank M, et al. Creatine and beta-hydroxy-beta-methylbutyrate (HMB) additively increase lean body mass and muscle strength during a weight-training program. Nutrition. 2001;17(7-8):558&#x2013;566. doi: 10.1016/s0899-9007(01)00540-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0899-9007(01)00540-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11448573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peeters BM, Lantz CD, Mayhew JL. Effect of oral creatine monohydrate and creatine phosphate supplementation on maximal strength indices, body composition, and blood pressure. J Strength Cond Res. 1999;13:3&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willoughby DS, Rosene J. Effects of oral creatine and resistance training on myosin heavy chain expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33(10):1674&#x2013;1681. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Snell PG, Rodriguez R, et al. The effect of creatine monohydrate ingestion on anaerobic power indices, muscular strength and body composition. Acta Physiol Scand. 1995;153(2):207&#x2013;209. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.1995.tb09854.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.1995.tb09854.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7778463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noonan D, Berg KE, Latin RW, et al. Effects of varying dosages of oral creatine relative to fat free body mass on strength and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 1998;12:104&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stout J, Eckerson J, Noonan D, et al. Effects of 8 weeks of creatine supplementation on exercise performance and fat-free weight in football players during training. Nutr Res. 1999;19(2):217&#x2013;225. doi: 10.1016/S0271-5317(98)00185-7. 1999/02/01/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0271-5317(98)00185-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner M, Rankin J, Sebolt DON. The effect of creatine supplementation during resistance training in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;05(01):14. doi: 10.1519/1533-4287(2000)014&lt;0207:TEOCSD&gt;2.0.CO;2 &#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/1533-4287(2000)014&lt;0207:TEOCSD&gt;2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S, Ibanez J, et al. Creatine supplementation and sprint performance in soccer players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32(2):518&#x2013;525. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200002000-00039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200002000-00039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10694141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Mez&#xea;ncio B, Amaral S, et al. Creatine monohydrate supplementation on lower-limb muscle power in Brazilian elite soccer players. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014;11:32. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-11-32</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-11-32</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24991195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huerta Ojeda A, Jofr&#xe9;-Sald&#xed;a E, Torres-Banduc M, et al. Effects of a low dose of orally administered creatine monohydrate on post-fatigue muscle power in young soccer players. Nutrients. 2024;16(9). doi: 10.3390/nu16091324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu16091324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11085131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38732571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielgo-Ayuso J, Calleja-Gonzalez J, Marques-Jimenez D, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on athletic performance in soccer players: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2019;11(4). doi: 10.3390/nu11040757</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11040757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30935142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall RP, Droste JN, Giessing J, et al. Role of creatine supplementation in conditions involving mitochondrial dysfunction: a narrative review. Nutrients. 2022;14(3). doi: 10.3390/nu14030529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14030529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8838971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35276888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cisowski M, Bochenek A, Kucewicz E, et al. The use of exogenous creatine phosphate for myocardial protection in patients undergoing coronary artery bypass surgery. J Cardiovasc Surg (Torino). 1996;37(6 Suppl 1):75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10064355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts JJ, Walker JB. Feeding a creatine analogue delays ATP depletion and onset of rigor in ischemic heart. Am J Physiol. 1982;243(6):H911&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1152/ajpheart.1982.243.6.H911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.1982.243.6.H911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7149044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruda M, Samarenko MB, Afonskaya NI, et al. Reduction of ventricular arrhythmias by phosphocreatine (Neoton) in patients with acute myocardial infarction. Am Heart J. 1988;116(2 Pt 1):393&#x2013;397. doi: 10.1016/0002-8703(88)90611-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0002-8703(88)90611-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2456682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharov VG, Saks VA, Kupriyanov VV, et al. Protection of ischemic myocardium by exogenous phosphocreatine. I. Morphologic and phosphorus 31-nuclear magnetic resonance studies. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 1987;94(5):749&#x2013;761. doi: 10.1016/S0022-5223(19)36191-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-5223(19)36191-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3669703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Hove M, Lygate CA, Fischer A, et al. Reduced inotropic reserve and increased susceptibility to cardiac ischemia/reperfusion injury in phosphocreatine-deficient guanidinoacetate-N-methyltransferase-knockout mice. Circulation. 2005;111(19):2477&#x2013;2485. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.0000165147.99592.01</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.0000165147.99592.01</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster I, Du Toit EF, Huisamen B, et al. The effect of creatine supplementation on myocardial function, mitochondrial respiration and susceptibility to ischaemia/reperfusion injury in sedentary and exercised rats. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2012;206(1):6&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1111/j.1748-1716.2012.02463.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.2012.02463.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22741552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordji-Nejad A, Matusch A, Kleed&#xf6;rfer S, et al. Single dose creatine improves cognitive performance and induces changes in cerebral high energy phosphates during sleep deprivation. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):4937. doi: 10.1038/s41598-024-54249-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54249-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10902318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38418482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner CE, Byblow WD, Gant N. Creatine supplementation enhances corticomotor excitability and cognitive performance during oxygen deprivation. J Neurosci. 2015;35(4):1773&#x2013;1780. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3113-14.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3113-14.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6795258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25632150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook CJ, Crewther BT, Kilduff LP, et al. Skill execution and sleep deprivation: effects of acute caffeine or creatine supplementation - a randomized placebo-controlled trial. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2011;8:2. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-8-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-8-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3049131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21324203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallimann T, Hall CHT, Colgan SP, et al. Creatine supplementation for patients with inflammatory bowel diseases: a scientific rationale for a clinical trial. Nutrients. 2021;13(5). doi: 10.3390/nu13051429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13051429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33922654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro FM, Petriz B, Marques G, et al. Is there an exercise-intensity threshold capable of avoiding the leaky gut? Front Nutr. 2021;8:627289. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2021.627289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2021.627289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7982409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33763441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration GRN No. 931 Creatine Monohydrate. Silver Spring (MD): U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jager R, Purpura M, Shao A, et al. Analysis of the efficacy, safety, and regulatory status of novel forms of creatine. Amino Acids. 2011;40(5):1369&#x2013;1383. doi: 10.1007/s00726-011-0874-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-011-0874-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3080578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Stout JR. Creatine in health and disease. Nutrients. 2021;13(2). doi: 10.3390/nu13020447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13020447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7910963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawson ES, Clarkson PM, Tarnopolsky MA. Perspectives on exertional rhabdomyolysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(Suppl 1):33&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0689-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0689-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5371628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28332112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Candow DG, Forbes SC, et al. Common questions and misconceptions about creatine supplementation: what does the scientific evidence really show?. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18(1):13. doi: 10.1186/s12970-021-00412-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-021-00412-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33557850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Brown AF, Candow DG, et al. Part II. Common questions and misconceptions about creatine supplementation: what does the scientific evidence really show? J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2025;22(1):2441760. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2024.2441760</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2024.2441760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11703406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39720835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Gonzalez DE, Hines K, et al. Safety of creatine supplementation: analysis of the prevalence of reported side effects in clinical trials and adverse event reports. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2025;22(sup1):2488937. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2025.2488937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2025.2488937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11983583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40198156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreider RB, Melton C, Rasmussen CJ, et al. Long-term creatine supplementation does not significantly affect clinical markers of health in athletes. Mol Cell Biochem. 2003;244(1-2):95&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1023/A:1022469320296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1022469320296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12701816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenwood M, Farris J, Kreider R, et al. Creatine supplementation patterns and perceived effects in select division I collegiate athletes. Clin J Sport Med. 2000;10(3):191&#x2013;194. doi: 10.1097/00042752-200007000-00007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00042752-200007000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10959929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hile AM, Anderson JM, Fiala KA, et al. Creatine supplementation and anterior compartment pressure during exercise in the heat in dehydrated men. J Athl Train. 2006;41(1):30&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1421498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16619092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson G, Casa DJ, Fiala KA, et al. Creatine use and exercise heat tolerance in dehydrated men. J Athl Train. 2006;41(1):18&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1421496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16619091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalbo VJ, Roberts MD, Stout JR, et al. Putting to rest the myth of creatine supplementation leading to muscle cramps and dehydration. Br J Sports Med. 2008;42(7):567&#x2013;573. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2007.042473 bjsm.2007.042473 [pii]&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;&#x200b;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2007.042473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18184753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosene JM, Matthews TD, McBride KJ, et al. The effects of creatine supplementation on thermoregulation and isokinetic muscular performance following acute (3-day) supplementation. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2015;55(12):1488&#x2013;1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25781214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans JR, Auquier H, Renaut V, et al. Effect of short-term creatine supplementation on renal responses in men. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1997;76(6):566&#x2013;567. doi: 10.1007/s004210050291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004210050291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9404870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson TM, Sewell DA, Casey A, et al. Dietary creatine supplementation does not affect some haematological indices, or indices of muscle damage and hepatic and renal function. Br J Sports Med. 2000;34(4):284&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10953902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groeneveld GJ, Beijer C, Veldink JH, et al. Few adverse effects of long-term creatine supplementation in a placebo-controlled trial. Int J Sports Med. 2005;26(4):307&#x2013;313. doi: 10.1055/s-2004-817917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2004-817917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15795816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Ugrinowitsch C, Novaes RB, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on renal function: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;103(1):33&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1007/s00421-007-0669-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0669-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18188581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lugaresi R, Leme M, de Salles Painelli V, et al. Does long-term creatine supplementation impair kidney function in resistance-trained individuals consuming a high-protein diet?. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2013;10(1):26. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-10-26</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3661339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23680457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farquhar WB, Zambraski EJ. Effects of creatine use on the athlete's kidney. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2002;1(2):103&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12831718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipila I, Rapola J, Simell O, et al. Supplementary creatine as a treatment for gyrate atrophy of the choroid and retina. N Engl J Med. 1981;304(15):867&#x2013;870. doi: 10.1056/NEJM198104093041503</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198104093041503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7207523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroder H, Terrados N, Tramullas A. Risk assessment of the potential side effects of long-term creatine supplementation in team sport athletes. Eur J Nutr. 2005;44(4):255&#x2013;261. doi: 10.1007/s00394-004-0519-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00394-004-0519-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15309421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender A, Samtleben W, Elstner M, et al. Long-term creatine supplementation is safe in aged patients with parkinson disease. Nutr Res. 2008;28(3):172&#x2013;178. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2008.01.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2008.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Januario RS, Junior RP, et al. Long-term creatine supplementation improves muscular performance during resistance training in older women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(4):987&#x2013;996. doi: 10.1007/s00421-012-2514-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-012-2514-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender A, Klopstock T. Creatine for neuroprotection in neurodegenerative disease: end of story?. Amino Acids. 2016;48(8):1929&#x2013;1940. doi: 10.1007/s00726-015-2165-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-015-2165-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26748651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vannas-Sulonen K, Sipila I, Vannas A, et al. Gyrate atrophy of the choroid and retina: a five-year follow-up of creatine supplementation. Ophthalmology. 1985;92(12):1719&#x2013;1727. doi: 10.1016/S0161-6420(85)34098-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0161-6420(85)34098-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4088625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group for the NETiPDI, Kieburtz K, Tilley BC, et al. ,. Effect of creatine monohydrate on clinical progression in patients with parkinson disease: a randomized clinical trial. J Am Med Assoc. 2015;313(6):584&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1001/jama.2015.120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2015.120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4349346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25668262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration 
FDA CFSAN Adverse Event Reporting System (CAERS) [Internet]. Silver Spring (MD): U.S. Food &amp; Drug Administration; 2025. https://www.FDA.gov/food/compliance-enforcement-food/cfsan-adverse-event-reporting-system-caers</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada 
Canada Vigilance Adverse Reaction Online Database [Internet]. Ottawa (ON): Health Canada; 2025. https://cvp-pcv.hc-sc.gc.ca/arq-rei/index-eng.jsp</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutic Goods Administration (AU) 
Database of Adverse Event Notifications (DAEN) &#x2013; medicines. Canberra (AU): Australian Government, Department of Health and Aged Care; 2025. https://daen.tga.gov.au/medicines-search/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>