<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41906260</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1540-8167</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiovascular electrophysiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sinus Rhythm Parameters in the Infarct Border Zone Are Useful to Assess Reentrant Ventricular Tachycardia Inducibility.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jce.70318</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Reentrant ventricular tachycardia (VT) is an important clinical problem, with underlying biophysical mechanisms that remain incompletely understood. Substrate compilation maps were used to detect subtle spatial gradients and for assessing inducibility of sustained VT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD/RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A subepicardial infarct was created via left anterior descending coronary artery (LAD) ligation in canine hearts. After 3-5 days, electrical activity was marked and mapped using a 312-electrode array in 60 postinfarction hearts (30 noninducible for VT, 30 with sustained VT). Compilation maps were constructed by summing the N&#x2009;=&#x2009;30 individual experiment maps of parameters from representative sinus rhythm (SR) and VT cycles. Gradients were determined by averaging multiarray data row-by-row, and by dividing 312-grid sites into LAD-proximate vs. apical-lateral-proximate halves. Prediction of VT induction was done using SR activation statistics. Compilation maps revealed that SR activation times were prolonged in inducible vs. non-inducible experiments (means 21.64 vs. 13.58&#x2009;msec, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). SR activation means and standard deviations per experiment (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;312 sites) were predictive of reentrant VT inducibility (sensitivity&#x2009;=&#x2009;28/30 or 93.3%, specificity&#x2009;=&#x2009;26/30 or 86.7%). SR electrogram duration lengthened in inducible vs. non-inducible VT experiments (36.54 vs. 32.40&#x2009;msec, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). VT electrogram duration averaged 34.70&#x2009;msec, differing from both SR measurements (p&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.003). Isthmus electrogram duration averaged 33.6&#x2009;msec in SR vs. 40.6&#x2009;msec in VT. The SR electrogram duration in VT inducible experiments exhibited a gradient with values increasing away from the LAD (r<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.79, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), perhaps resulting from decreasing blood perfusion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Compilation maps provide insights into profiles of SR spatiotemporal activation, to predict arrhythmia inducibility in reentrant VT substrates.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciaccio</LastName><ForeName>Edward J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Division of Cardiology, Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ElectroCardioMaths Programme, Imperial Centre for Cardiac Engineering, National Heart &amp; Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coromilas</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Division of Cardiovascular Disease and Hypertension, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsia</LastName><ForeName>Henry H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8187-9755</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiac Electrophysiology and Arrhythmia Service. University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talke</LastName><ForeName>Marcus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Division of Cardiology, Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garan</LastName><ForeName>Hasan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Division of Cardiology, Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yarmohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Hirad</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Division of Cardiology, Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biviano</LastName><ForeName>Angelo B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Division of Cardiology, Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peters</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas S</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ElectroCardioMaths Programme, Imperial Centre for Cardiac Engineering, National Heart &amp; Lung Institute, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RG/16/3/32175</GrantID><Acronym>BHF_</Acronym><Agency>British Heart Foundation</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RG/16/3/32175</GrantID><Agency>Rosetrees Trust</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RG/16/3/32175</GrantID><Agency>National Institute for Health and Care Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9010756</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1045-3873</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">activation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bipolar electrode</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sinus rhythm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">substrate mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ventricular tachycardia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41906260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jce.70318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>K. Vlachos, K. P. Letsas, N. T. Srinivasan, et al., &#x201c;The Value of Functional Substrate Mapping in Ventricular Tachycardia Ablation,&#x201d; Heart Rhythm O2 4, no. 2 (November 2023): 134&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Dillon, M. A. Allessie, P. C. Ursell, and A. L. Wit, &#x201c;Influences of Anisotropic Tissue Structure on Reentrant Circuits in the Epicardial Border Zone of Subacute Canine Infarcts,&#x201d; Circulation Research 63 (1988): 182&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Coromilas, A. E. Saltman, B. Waldecker, S. M. Dillon, and A. L. Wit, &#x201c;Electrophysiological Effects of Flecainide on Anisotropic Conduction and Reentry in Infarcted Canine Hearts,&#x201d; Circulation 91 (1995): 2245&#x2013;2263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. L. Wit, M. A. Allessie, F. I. Bonke, W. Lammers, J. Smeets, and J. J. Fenoglio Jr., &#x201c;Electrophysiologic Mapping to Determine the Mechanism of Experimental Ventricular Tachycardia Initiated by Premature Impulses. Experimental Approach and Initial Results Demonstrating Reentrant Excitation,&#x201d; American Journal of Cardiology 49, no. 1 (January 1982): 166&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. S. Peters, J. Coromilas, N. J. Severs, and A. L. Wit, &#x201c;Disturbed connexin43 Gap Junction Distribution Correlates With the Location of Reentrant Circuits in the Epicardial Border Zone of Healing Canine Infarcts That Cause Ventricular Tachycardia,&#x201d; Circulation 95, no. 4 (February 1997): 988&#x2013;996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, H. Ashikaga, R. A. Kaba, et al., &#x201c;Model of Reentrant Ventricular Tachycardia Based on Infarct Border Zone Geometry Predicts Reentrant Circuit Features as Determined by Activation Mapping,&#x201d; Heart Rhythm 4, no. 8 (August 2007): 1034&#x2013;1045.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, N. Cedilnik, H. H. Hsia, A. B. Biviano, H. Garan, and H. Yarmohammadi, &#x201c;Wavefront Curvature Analysis Derived From Preprocedural Imaging Can Identify the Critical Isthmus in Patients With Postinfarcted Ventricular Tachycardia,&#x201d; Heart Rhythm 21, no. 12 (December 2024): 2471&#x2013;2480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. B. Brunckhorst, E. Delacretaz, K. Soejima, W. H. Maisel, P. L. Friedman, and W. G. Stevenson, &#x201c;Identification of the Ventricular Tachycardia Isthmus After Infarction by Pace Mapping,&#x201d; Circulation 110, no. 6 (August 2004): 652&#x2013;659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Ascione, C. Kowalewski, M. Bergonti, et al., &#x201c;Omnipolar Versus Bipolar Mapping to Guide Ventricular Tachycardia Ablation,&#x201d; Heart Rhythm 20, no. 10 (October 2023): 1370&#x2013;1377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Takigawa, J. Relan, R. Martin, et al., &#x201c;Detailed Analysis of the Relation Between Bipolar Electrode Spacing and Far&#x2010; and Near&#x2010;Field Electrograms,&#x201d; JACC: Clinical Electrophysiology 5, no. 1 (January 2019): 66&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Waldecker, J. Coromilas, A. E. Saltman, S. M. Dillon, and A. L. Wit, &#x201c;Overdrive Stimulation of Functional Reentrant Circuits Causing Ventricular Tachycardia in the Infarcted Canine Heart. Resetting and Entrainment,&#x201d; Circulation 87 (1993): 1286&#x2013;1305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, A. E. Saltman, O. M. Hernandez, R. J. Bornholdt, and J. Coromilas, &#x201c;Multichannel Data Acquisition System for Mapping the Electrical Activity of the Heart,&#x201d; Pacing and Clinical Electrophysiology 28, no. 8 (August 2005): 826&#x2013;838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, J. Coromilas, H. H. Hsia, et al., &#x201c;Narrowed Sinus Rhythm Electrograms in the Zone of Uniform Slow Conduction Are Helpful to Identify VT Isthmus Location, Shape, and Orientation,&#x201d; Heart Rhythm S1547&#x2013;5271, no. 25 (June 2025): 02611&#x2013;02616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, C. Costeas, J. Coromilas, and A. L. Wit, &#x201c;Static Relationship of Cycle Length to Reentrant Circuit Geometry,&#x201d; Circulation 104, no. 16 (October 2001): 1946&#x2013;1951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, A. C. Tosti, and M. M. Scheinman, &#x201c;Relationship Between Sinus Rhythm Activation and the Reentrant Ventricular Tachycardia Isthmus,&#x201d; Circulation 104 (2001b): 613&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, A. W. Chow, D. W. Davies, A. L. Wit, and N. S. Peters, &#x201c;Localization of the Isthmus in Reentrant Circuits by Analysis of Electrograms Derived From Clinical Noncontact Mapping During Sinus Rhythm and Ventricular Tachycardia,&#x201d; Journal of Cardiovascular Electrophysiology 15 (2004): 27&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. J. Ciaccio, J. Coromilas, D. S. Saluja, H. H. Hsia, N. S. Peters, and H. Yarmohammadi, &#x201c;Sinus Rhythm Activation Signature Indicates Reentrant Ventricular Tachycardia Inducibility and Approximate Isthmus Location,&#x201d; Heart Rhythm 21, no. 11 (November 2024): 2177&#x2013;2186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Baba, W. Dun, C. Cabo, and P. A. Boyden, &#x201c;Remodeling in Cells From Different Regions of the Reentrant Circuit During Ventricular Tachycardia,&#x201d; Circulation 112, no. 16 (October 2005): 2386&#x2013;2396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Cabo, J. Yao, P. A. Boyden, et al., &#x201c;Heterogeneous Gap Junction Remodeling Stabilizes Reentrant Circuits in the Epicardial Border Zone of the Healing Canine Infarct,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Research 72 (2006): 242&#x2013;249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Spach and P. C. Dolber, &#x201c;Relating Extracellular Potentials and Their Derivatives to Anisotropic Propagation at a Microscopic Level in Human Cardiac Muscle. Evidence for Electrical Uncoupling of Side&#x2010;To&#x2010;Side Fiber Connections With Increasing Age,&#x201d; Circulation Research 58, no. 3 (1986): 356&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Zimarino, A. Ausiello, G. Contegiacomo, et al., &#x201c;Rapid Decline of Collateral Circulation Increases Susceptibility to Myocardial Ischemia,&#x201d; Journal of the American College of Cardiology 48, no. 1 (July 2006): 59&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. T. Vaitkus, J. M. Miller, A. E. Buxton, M. E. Josephson, and W. K. Laskey, &#x201c;Ischemia&#x2010;Induced Changes in Human Endocardial Electrograms During Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty,&#x201d; American Heart Journal 127, no. 6 (June 1994): 1481&#x2013;1490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. E. Josephson and E. Anter, &#x201c;Substrate Mapping for Ventricular Tachycardia,&#x201d; JACC: Clinical Electrophysiology 1, no. 5 (October 2015): 341&#x2013;352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. A. Williams, D. R. Dickenson, and G. N. Beatch, &#x201c;Kinetics of Rate&#x2010;Dependent Shortening of Action Potential Duration in Guinea&#x2010;Pig Ventricle; Effects of IK1 and IKr Blockade,&#x201d; British Journal of Pharmacology 126, no. 6 (March 1999): 1426&#x2013;1436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Jiang, A. D. Beaser, Z. Aziz, G. A. Upadhyay, H. M. Nayak, and R. Tung, &#x201c;High&#x2010;Density Grid Catheter for Detailed Mapping of Sinus Rhythm and Scar&#x2010;Related Ventricular Tachycardia,&#x201d; JACC: Clinical Electrophysiology 6, no. 3 (March 2020): 311&#x2013;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Yalin, B. Ikitimur, A. U. Soysal, et al., &#x201c;Significance of Coherent Mapping in Unveiling Slow Conduction Zones of Ventricular Tachycardia Substrate in Ischemic Cardiomyopathy,&#x201d; supplement, Europace 26, no. S1 (May 2024): euae102.318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Hayashi, E. Muscat, M. Rahimi, et al., &#x201c;Isochronal Late Activation Mapping in Ischemic Scar VT: An Independent Validation Using Intraoperative Mapping,&#x201d; Journal of Interventional Cardiac Electrophysiology, ahead of print, October 14, 2025, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10840-025-02138-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. O. Ly, A. M. Suszko, N. C. Denham, et al., &#x201c;Machine Learning Identifies Arrhythmogenic Features of QRS Fragmentation in Human Cardiomyopathy: Implications for Improving Risk Stratification,&#x201d; Heart Rhythm 22, no. 10 (October 2025): 2457&#x2013;2468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Kabra, S. Israni, B. Vijay, et al., &#x201c;Emerging Role of Artificial Intelligence in Cardiac Electrophysiology,&#x201d; Cardiovascular Digital Health Journal 3, no. 6 (September 2022): 263&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Svennberg, J. K. Han, E. G. Caiani, et al., &#x201c;State of the Art of Artificial Intelligence in Clinical Electrophysiology in 2025: A Scientific Statement of the European Heart Rhythm Association (EHRA) of the ESC, the Heart Rhythm Society (HRS), and the ESC Working Group on E&#x2010;Cardiology,&#x201d; Europace 27, no. 5 (2025): euaf071.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>