<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41846671</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Isolated Cone Dystrophy With Secondary Macular Involvement Mimicking Vascular Insult and Optic Atrophy: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103601</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103601</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103601</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103601</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Isolated cone dystrophy is a rare retinal degenerative disorder characterized by selective dysfunction of cone photoreceptors, with relatively preserved rod function. Clinical presentation can be variable and, in rare cases, may mimic retinal vascular injuries or optic neuropathies, leading to diagnostic uncertainty. We report the case of a 32-year-old male patient with gradual, painless, asymmetric vision loss predominantly affecting the left eye. Fundus examination revealed optic disc pallor, arteriolar narrowing, macular pigmentary changes, and absence of the foveal reflex, raising initial concerns for retinal vascular insufficiency or optic atrophy. Multimodal imaging showed widespread macular thinning, photoreceptor layer disruption, and an enlarged foveal avascular zone, complicating the diagnostic evaluation. Full-field electroretinography demonstrated preserved scotopic responses but markedly reduced photopic responses, confirming selective cone dysfunction and establishing a diagnosis of isolated cone dystrophy with secondary macular involvement. The absence of systemic vascular risk factors, a routine neurological examination, and characteristic electrophysiological findings were pivotal in differentiating this condition from vascular or optic nerve disorders. This case highlights the importance of considering cone dystrophy in the differential diagnosis of painless, progressive vision loss with optic disc pallor and macular changes. It underscores the critical role of electrophysiology and multimodal imaging in accurate diagnosis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Varghese et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varghese</LastName><ForeName>Divya E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sudhakar</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cone dystrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrophysiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">erg</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">full-field electroretinography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macular involvement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multimodal imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optic atrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retinal dystrophy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41846671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12991179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chawla H, Tripathy K, Vohra V. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2024. Retinal dystrophies.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33232049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The cone dysfunction syndromes. Michaelides M, Hunt DM, Moore AT. Br J Ophthalmol. 2004;88:291&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1771989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14736794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Progressive cone and cone-rod dystrophies: clinical features, molecular genetics and prospects for therapy. Gill JS, Georgiou M, Kalitzeos A, Moore AT, Michaelides M. Br J Ophthalmol. 2019;103:711&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6709772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30679166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paracentral acute middle maculopathy (PAMM) in ocular vascular diseases&#x2014;what we know and future perspectives. Fumi D, Ruggeri F, Fasciolo D, Antonello E, Burtini G, Abdolrahimzadeh S. Vision (Basel) 2025;9:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11946784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40137931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macular telangiectasia type 2. Charbel Issa P, Gillies MC, Chew EY, et al. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2013;34:49&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23219692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The electroretinogram in the genomics era: outer retinal disorders. Cornish EE, Vaze A, Jamieson RV, Grigg JR. Eye (Lond) 2021;35:2406&#x2013;2418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34234290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optical coherence tomography angiography and multimodal imaging in the management of coats' disease. Ashkenazy N, Acon D, Kalavar M, Berrocal AM. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep. 2021;23:101177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8332650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34381924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optical coherence tomography angiography in retinal diseases. Chalam KV, Sambhav K. J Ophthalmic Vis Res. 2016;11:84&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4860994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27195091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autosomal recessive cone-rod dystrophy can be caused by mutations in the ATF6 gene. Skorczyk-Werner A, Chiang WC, Wawrocka A, et al. Eur J Hum Genet. 2017;25:1210&#x2013;1216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5643965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28812650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phenotypic heterogeneity in human genetic diseases: ultrasensitivity-mediated threshold effects as a unifying molecular mechanism. Sun YH, Wu YL, Liao BY. J Biomed Sci. 2023;30:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37525275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rod-cone dystrophy is systematically associated to the RTN4IP1 recessive optic atrophy. Meunier I, Bocquet B, Charif M, et al. Retina. 2021;41:1771&#x2013;1779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8297537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cone-rod dystrophy and progressive visual loss as the first manifestation of neuronal ceroid lipofuscinosis type 7: a case report. Hosseini SM, Nejad Shahrokh Abadi R, Babaei M, Eghbal F, Hashemi N. Clin Case Rep. 2024;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11565442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39555201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phenotyping and genotyping inherited retinal diseases: molecular genetics, clinical and imaging features, and therapeutics of macular dystrophies, cone and cone-rod dystrophies, rod-cone dystrophies, Leber congenital amaurosis, and cone dysfunction syndromes. Georgiou M, Robson AG, Fujinami K, et al. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2024;100:101244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38278208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutations in SAMD7 cause autosomal-recessive macular dystrophy with or without cone dysfunction. Bauwens M, Celik E, Zur D, et al. Am J Hum Genet. 2024;111:393&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10870129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38272031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In vivo assessment of cone loss and macular perfusion in children with myopia. Shen Y, Ye X, Zhou X, et al. Sci Rep. 2024;14:26373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11530448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39487258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macular OCT inner retinal changes reflect CNS involvement in m.3243A&amp;gt;G disease. Jouda H, Browning AC, Aftab AM, et al. BMJ Neurol Open. 2025;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12542527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41133266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>