<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41345562</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2261</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cardiovascular disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence and predictors of cardiovascular disease among hypertension patients in, Ethiopia: a retrospective follow-up study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">15</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12872-025-05280-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality among hypertensive patients worldwide including Ethiopia. The World Health Organization (WHO) predicts a rapid rise in CVDs in Sub-Saharan Africa by 2030, though the region has often been overlooked in CVD research. The incidence and predictors of CVD among hypertensive patients in North Shoa, Amhara, Ethiopia, are not well studied. This research aimed to investigate these factors among hypertensive patients attending a medical referral clinic in 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective follow-up study was applied from 2015 to 2023 in the referral medical clinics of North Shoa Zone. Secondary data were collected by using checklists from records of 355 randomly selected hypertensive patients. Data was analyzed by using STATA version 14. The goodness of fitness of the model was checked by using the Cox-Snell residual plot. Finally, Multivariable Cox regression was applied to calculate the adjusted hazard ratios, and variables with a significance level of less than 0.05 were identified as predictors of CVDs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT">The incidence of cardiovascular diseases (CVD) among hypertensive patients was 1.98 cases per 1,000 person-years, with a median survival time of 5 years. Multivariable Cox regression revealed that patients with mental illness had a 2.01 times higher risk of developing CVD (AHR: 2.01, 95% CI: 1.04&#x2013;3.05). Additionally, those with diabetes mellitus (DM) had a 2.5 times higher risk compared to patients without DM (AHR: 2.5, 95% CI: 1.12&#x2013;5.46).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The incidence of cardiovascular disease among hypertensive patients was high, and mental illness and diabetes mellitus were significant predictor of it. Therefore, early identification and integrated care for these high-risk patients are crucial. Targeted cardiovascular screening, mental health support, strict glycemic control, and health education promoting lifestyle modification and treatment adherence can reduce CVD risk.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Getachew</LastName><ForeName>Kagnew</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mengstie</LastName><ForeName>Leweyehu Alemaw</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7314-6535</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia. lewisbrsh@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebreegziabher</LastName><ForeName>Zenebe Abebe</ForeName><Initials>ZA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of public health, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hailemeskel</LastName><ForeName>Solomon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery, Debre Berhan University, Debre Berhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cardiovasc Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968539</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2261</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension patients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predictors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval for this study was obtained from the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of Asrat Woldeyes Health Science Campus, Debre Berhan University. The IRB granted a waiver of informed consent as the study was based on a retrospective review of existing medical records with no direct contact with patients and no collection of identifiable personal information. Following IRB approval, an official cooperation letter was issued by the School of Nursing and midwifery to each selected hospital, and formal permission was secured. Data collection was carried out only after obtaining authorization from the hospitals and respective units, as the study involved a retrospective review of medical records. The research was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki, ensuring strict confidentiality and anonymity of patient data. No personal identifiers were recorded or included in the analysis. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41345562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12781504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-025-05280-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12872-025-05280-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pandey AR, Dhimal M, Shrestha N, Sharma D, Maskey J, Dhungana RR, et al. Burden of cardiovascular diseases in Nepal from 1990 to 2019: the global burden of disease study, 2019. Glob Health. 2023;2023:3700094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10292936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37377984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angaw DA, Ali R, Tadele A, Shumet S. The prevalence of cardiovascular disease in Ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of institutional and community-based studies. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2021;21(1):37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-020-01828-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7814574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33461482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Roeters JE, Tokg&#xf6;zo&#x11f;lu LS, Badimon L, Dumanski SM, Gulati M, Hess CN, et al. Women, lipids, and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: a call to action from the European atherosclerosis society. Eur Heart J. 2023;44(39):4157&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehad472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10576616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37611089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sliwa K, Singh K, Raspail L, Ojji D, Lam CS, Thienemann F, et al. The world heart federation global study on COVID-19 and cardiovascular disease. Glob Heart. 2021. 10.5334/gh.950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/gh.950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8064295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34040935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>organization wh. cardiovascular diseases WHO. 2021 [2024]. Available from: https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/cardiovascular-diseases-(cvds)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soliman EZ, Juma H. Cardiac disease patterns in Northern Malawi: epidemiologic transition perspective. J Epidemiol. 2008;18(5):204&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2188/jea.JE2008006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4771591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18753734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>organization wH. The top 10 causes of death: WHO; 2017 [2024]. Available from: http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs310/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gemechu T, Mahmoud H, Parry EH, Phillips DI, Yacoub MH. Community-based prevalence study of rheumatic heart disease in rural Ethiopia. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2017;24(7):717&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2047487316687104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28071960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de-Graft Aikins A, Kushitor M, Koram K, Gyamfi S, Ogedegbe G. Chronic non-communicable diseases and the challenge of universal health coverage: insights from community-based cardiovascular disease research in urban poor communities in Accra, Ghana. BMC Public Health. 2014;14(Suppl 2):S3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-14-S2-S3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4120153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25082497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu G, Gong X, Xu Y, Sun H, Liu Y, Zhai C, et al. The global burden and trends of four major types of heart disease, 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. Public Health. 2023;220:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.puhe.2023.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37182373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali S, Misganaw A, Worku A, Destaw Z, Negash L, Bekele A, et al. The burden of cardiovascular diseases in Ethiopia from 1990 to 2017: evidence from the global burden of disease study. Int Health. 2021;13(4):318&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/inthealth/ihaa069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8253991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32945840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethiopia CSAo. Demography of north shoa CSA; 2007 [cited 2023]. Available from: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Shewa_Zone_(Amhara).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hospital DC. Partners collaborated to improve hospital services: AIHA; 2018 [updated cited 2023]. Available from: https://www.aiha.com/hivaids-twinning-center/ethiopia/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latouche A, Porcher R, Chevret S. Sample size formula for proportional hazards modelling of competing risks. Stat Med. 2004;23(21):3263&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.1915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15490425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld DA. Sample-size formula for the proportional-hazards regression model. Biometrics. 1983. 10.2307/2531021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2531021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6354290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debele GR, Kefeni BT, Kanfe SG, Ayele TA, Wolde HF, Yenit MK, et al. Incidence and predictors of cardiovascular disease among type 1 and type 2 diabetes mellitus in a tertiary health care setting of ethiopia: 8-Year retrospective Follow-Up study. Risk Manag Healthc Policy. 2021;14:1959&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/RMHP.S307303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8128505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elyamani R, Soulaymani A, Hami H. Epidemiology of cardiovascular diseases in morocco: a systematic review. Rev Diabet Stud. 2021;17(2):57&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1900/RDS.2021.17.57</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9380084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34852896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update AS. Heart disease and stroke statistics&#x2013;2017 update. Circulation. 2017;135:e146&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5408160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendis S, Thygesen K, Kuulasmaa K, Giampaoli S, M&#xe4;h&#xf6;nen M, Ngu Blackett K et al. Writing group on behalf of the participating experts of the WHO consultation for revision of WHO definition of myocardial infarction. World Health Organization definition of myocardial infarction. 2008;9:139&#x2009;&#x2013;&#x2009;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20926369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram RV, Trivedi AV. Behavioral risk factors of coronary artery disease: a paired matched case control study. J Cardiovasc Dis Res. 2012;3(3):212&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0975-3583.98896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3425028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22923939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creager M, Loscalzo J. Arterial diseases of the extremities. Harrison&#x2019;s principles of internal medicine. 19th ed. New York: McGraw Hill Education; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper D, Fauci A, Hauser S, Longo D, Jameson J, Loscalzo J. Harrison&#x2019;s principles of internal medicine, vol. Volume 19e. New York, NY, USA: Mcgraw-hill; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein DJ, Palk AC, Kendler KS. What is a mental disorder? An exemplar-focused approach. Psychol Med. 2021;51(6):894&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291721001185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8161428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33843505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Bak JK, Kim M, Shin H-G, Park K-I, Lee S-P, et al. Long-term cardiovascular events in hypertensive patients: full report of the Korean hypertension cohort. Korean J Intern Med. 2023;38(1):56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3904/kjim.2022.249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9816676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36514267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomorrow AH. OECD Reviews of Public Health: Korea.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Birmeta K, Kim C, Sharma B, Dhaka S, Lee H, et al. Determinants of primary health care utilization in Ethiopia. Inst Poverty Alleviation Int Dev. 2016;25s:269&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18350/ipaid.2016.25s.269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushiro T, Kario K, Saito I, Teramukai S, Sato Y, Okuda Y, et al. Increased cardiovascular risk of treated white coat and masked hypertension in patients with diabetes and chronic kidney disease: the HONEST study. Hypertens Res. 2017;40(1):87&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/hr.2016.87</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5222992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27511054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokubo Y, Kamide K, Okamura T, Watanabe M, Higashiyama A, Kawanishi K, et al. Impact of high-normal blood pressure on the risk of cardiovascular disease in a Japanese urban cohort: the suita study. Hypertension. 2008;52(4):652&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.108.118273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18725580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayele H, Banbeta A, Negash A. Cardiovascular disease risk factors in hypertensive patients: a case study of Jimma university medical center. Health Serv Res Manag Epidemiol. 2022;9:23333928221078601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35187200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correll CU, Solmi M, Veronese N, Bortolato B, Rosson S, Santonastaso P, et al. Prevalence, incidence and mortality from cardiovascular disease in patients with pooled and specific severe mental illness: a large-scale meta&#x2010;analysis of 3,211,768 patients and 113,383,368 controls. World Psychiatry. 2017;16(2):163&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5428179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28498599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manu P, Correll CU, Wampers M, Mitchell AJ, Probst M, Vancampfort D, et al. Markers of inflammation in schizophrenia: association vs. causation. World Psychiatry. 2014;13(2):189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4102292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24890072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Evans JC, Levy D. Hypertension in adults across the age spectrum: current outcomes and control in the community. JAMA. 2005;294(4):466&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.294.4.466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16046653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercuro G, Deidda M, Piras A, Dessalvi CC, Maffei S, Rosano GM. Gender determinants of cardiovascular risk factors and diseases. J Cardiovasc Med (Hagerstown). 2010;11(3):207&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2459/JCM.0b013e32833178ed</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19829128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayatnia M, Asadi Z, Zare-Feyzabadi R, Yaghooti-Khorasani M, Ghazizadeh H, Ghaffarian-Zirak R, et al. Dyslipidemia and cardiovascular disease risk among the MASHAD study population. Lipids Health Dis. 2020;19:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-020-01204-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7075010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32178672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendis S, Puska P, Norrving Be, Organization WH. Global atlas on cardiovascular disease prevention and control. World Health Organization; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallucci G, Tartarone A, Lerose R, Lalinga AV, Capobianco AM. Cardiovascular risk of smoking and benefits of smoking cessation. J Thorac Dis. 2020;12(7):3866&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jtd.2020.02.47</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32802468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>