<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41267127</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-3933</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Movement ecology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mov Ecol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Variability in foraging ranges of snow petrels and implications for breeding distribution and use of stomach-oil deposits as proxies for paleoclimate.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>83</StartPage><MedlinePgn>83</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">83</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40462-025-00609-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Pelagic seabirds forage over vast areas, and their movements and diet provide valuable insights into environmental conditions that are otherwise difficult to observe. Snow petrels Pagodroma nivea forage largely on sea-ice-associated prey, rendering the energy-rich lipids into stomach oil, some of which is spat defensively at nest sites where it accumulates over tens of millennia. These deposits contain chemical signatures of the foraging environment, providing a unique biological archive of sea-ice conditions in the pre-satellite era. Accurate interpretation of these proxies, however, requires detailed knowledge of foraging ranges-how far the petrels travel, the habitats they target, and how these behaviours vary with season, colony location, and sex.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">To estimate foraging ranges at three colonies located 180-200&#x2009;km inland in Dronning Maud Land, we tracked 94 snow petrels (34 with light-based geolocators and 60 with GPS loggers). We tested whether foraging latitude is associated with the latitude of the ice edge, estimated via satellite remote sensing. We then projected potential foraging ranges for all known colonies in the study area to reexamine assumptions made in paleoclimate studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">During most breeding stages, and across breeding seasons, core foraging areas were centred approximately 2&#xb0; south of the outer sea-ice edge and tracked this habitat as it receded during the spring melt. Female snow petrels were approximately 7% lighter than males but foraged at similar distances and in similar areas. Foraging ranges differed little between colonies but substantially between breeding stages. For example, average median range was ~1400&#x2009;km (95% CI 1340-1470&#x2009;km) during the pre-laying exodus vs. ~530 (430-660) km during brood-guard.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Snow petrel stomach-oil deposits potentially integrate environmental conditions over greater and more seasonally variable areas than previously assumed, probably with a bias towards conditions in the marginal ice zone (outer pack ice) during the early summer when stomach oil deposition due to nest competition is likely greatest. Our results are consistent with the hypothesis that snow petrel breeding range in the western Weddell Sea is limited by access to foraging habitat, such as coastal polynyas. Although tracking data from other colonies would be useful to confirm the generality of our foraging range estimates, we hypothesise that as sea ice fluctuated over previous glacial-interglacial cycles, this regulated breeding distribution across the region.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakefield</LastName><ForeName>Ewan D</ForeName><Initials>ED</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, Durham University, Lower Mountjoy, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LE, UK. ewan.wakefield@durham.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McClymont</LastName><ForeName>Erin L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, Durham University, Lower Mountjoy, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LE, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Descamps</LastName><ForeName>S&#xe9;bastien</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norwegian Polar Institute, Fram Centre, Troms&#xf8;, 9296, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grecian</LastName><ForeName>W James</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, Durham University, Lower Mountjoy, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LE, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoelzel</LastName><ForeName>A Rus</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Durham University, Durham, DH1 3LE, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Honan</LastName><ForeName>Eleanor M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, Durham University, Lower Mountjoy, South Road, Durham, DH1 3LE, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rix</LastName><ForeName>Anna S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Durham University, Durham, DH1 3LE, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robert</LastName><ForeName>Henri</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Polar Foundation, Rue des v&#xe9;t&#xe9;rinaires, 42b/1, Brussels, 1070, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Br&#xe5;then</LastName><ForeName>Vegard Sand&#xf8;y</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norwegian Institute for Nature Research, P.O. Box 5685, Torgarden, Trondheim, 7485, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Richard A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Antarctic Survey, Natural Environment Research Council, Cambridge, CB3 0ET, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Mov Ecol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101635009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-3933</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Climate change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Palaeoceanography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resource tracking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sea ice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Seabird tracking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sentinels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sexual segregation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stomach oil</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: Tracking was approved by the Norwegian Animal Research Authority (permits 21,511 and 28,555) and Durham University Animal Welfare and Ethical Review Body. It was carried out under permits issued by the UK Foreign and Commonwealth Development Office (13/2021&#x2013;2022, 08/2022&#x2013;2023, 04/2023&#x2013;2024). Consent for publication: Not applicable Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41267127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12636188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40462-025-00609-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40462-025-00609-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shaffer SA, Costa DP, Weimerskirch H. Foraging effort in relation to the constraints of reproduction in free-ranging albatrosses. Funct Ecol. 2003;17(1):66&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2435.2003.00705.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukas R, Edelstein-Keshet L. The spatial distribution of colonial food provisioners. J Theor Biol. 1998;190(2):121&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jtbi.1997.0530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennycuick CJ, Croxall JP, Prince PA. Scaling of foraging radius and growth-rate in petrels and albatrosses (procellariiformes). Ornis Scandinavica. 1984;15(3):145&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/3675955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainley DG, Hobson KA, Crosta X, Rau GH, Wassenaar LI, Augustinus PC. Holocene variation in the Antarctic coastal food web: linking &#x3b4;D and &#x3b4;13C in snow petrel diet and marine sediments. Mar Ecol Prog Ser. 2006;306:31&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps306031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClymont EL, Bentley MJ, Hodgson DA, Spencer-Jones CL, Wardley T, West MD, et al. Summer sea-ice variability on the Antarctic margin during the last glacial period reconstructed from snow petrel (pagodroma nivea) stomach-oil deposits. Clim Past Discuss. 2022;2022:1&#x2013;39. 10.5194/cp-2021-134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/cp-2021-134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg S, Melles M, Hermichen W-D, McClymont EL, Bentley MJ, Hodgson DA, et al. Evaluation of mumiyo deposits from East Antarctica as archives for the late quaternary environmental and climatic history. Geochem Geophy Geosy. 2019;20(1):260&#x2013;76. 10.1029/2018GC008054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2018GC008054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croxall J, Steele WK, McInnes SJ, Prince PA. Breeding distribution of the snow petrel <i>Pagodroma nivea</i>. Mar Ornith. 1995;23:69&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchant S, Higgins PJ. Handbook of Australian, New Zealand &amp; antarctic birds. Melbourne: Oxford University Press; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zink RM. Observations of seabirds during a cruise from Ross Island to Anvers Island, Antarctica. Wilson J Ornithol. 1981;93:1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainley D, O&#x2019;Connor EF, Boekelheide R. The marine ecology of birds in the Ross Sea, Antarctica. Ornithol Monogr. 1984;32. 10.2307/40166773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbraud C, Delord K, Kato A, Bustamante P, Cherel Y. Sexual segregation in a highly pagophilic and sexually dimorphic marine predator. Peer Community J. 2021;1. 10.24072/pcjournal.75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24072/pcjournal.75</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fijn RC, Van Franeker JA, Trathan PN. Dietary variation in chick-feeding and self-provisioning cape petrel daption capense and snow petrel pagodroma nivea at Signy Island, South Orkney Islands, Antarctica. Mar Ornith. 2015;40:81&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferretti V, Soave GE, Casaux R, Coria NR. Diet of the snow petrel pagodroma nivea at Laurie Island, Antarctica, during the 1997/98 breeding season. Mar Ornith. 2001;29:71&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5038/2074-1235.29.2.500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainley D, Ribic C, Fraser W. Does prey preference affect habitat choice in Antarctic seabirds? Mar Ecol-Prog Ser. Mar Ecol-Prog Ser - MAR Ecol-Progr Ser. 1992;90:207&#x2013;21. 10.3354/meps090207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps090207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Franeker J, Wolff W, Imber MJ, Williams R. Diet and foraging ecology of Southern fulmar Fulmarus glacialoides, antarctic petrel thalassoica antarctica, cape petrel daption capense and snow petrels pagodroma nivea ssp on Ardery Island, Wilkes Land, antarctica. In: Mirrors in ice: fulmarine petrels and Antartic ecosystems. Texel, Netherlands: Alterra; 2001. p. 58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warham J, Watts R, Dainty RJ. Composition, energy content and function of stomach oils of petrels (order, Procellariiformes). J Exp Mar Biol Ecol. 1976;23(1):1&#x2013;13. 10.1016/0022-0981(76)90081-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-0981(76)90081-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warham J. The incidence, functions and ecological significance of petrel stomach oils. Proc New Zealand Ecolo Soc. 1977;24:84&#x2013;93, illust.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbraud C. Subspecies-selective predation of snow petrels by skuas. Oikos. 1999;86(2):275&#x2013;82. 10.2307/3546445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/3546445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiller A, Wand U, K&#xe4;mpf H, Stackebrandt W. Occupation of the Antarctic continent by petrels during the past 35 000 years: inferences from a 14C study of stomach oil deposits. Polar Biol. 1988;9(2):69&#x2013;77. 10.1007/BF00442032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00442032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele W, Hiller A. Radiocarbon dates of snow petrel (Pagodroma nivea) nest sites in central dronning maud land, Antarctica. Polar Rec. 1997;33:29&#x2013;38. 10.1017/S0032247400014145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0032247400014145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thor G, Low M. The persistence of the snow petrel (pagodroma nivea) in Dronning Maud Land (Antarctica) for over 37,000 years. Polar Biol. 2011;34(4):609&#x2013;13. 10.1007/s00300-010-0912-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00300-010-0912-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillenbrand C-D, Bentley MJ, Stolldorf TD, Hein AS, Kuhn G, Graham AGC, et al. Reconstruction of changes in the Weddell Sea sector of the Antarctic ice sheet since the last glacial maximum. Quaternary Sci Rev. 2014;100:111&#x2013;36. 10.1016/j.quascirev.2013.07.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.quascirev.2013.07.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackintosh AN, Verleyen E, O&#x2019;Brien PE, White DA, Jones RS, McKay R, et al. Retreat history of the east antarctic ice sheet since the last glacial maximum. Quaternary Sci Rev. 2014;100:10&#x2013;30. 10.1016/j.quascirev.2013.07.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.quascirev.2013.07.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox-Kemper B, Hewitt HT, Xiao C, A&#xf0;algeirsd&#xf3;ttir G, Drijfhout SS, Edwards TL, Golledge NR, Hemer M, Kopp RE, Krinner G, Am DN, Nowicki S, Nurhati IS, Ruiz L, Sall&#xe9;e J-B, Slangen ABA, Ocean YY. Cryosphere and sea level change. In: Masson-Delmotte V, Zhai P, Pirani A, Connors SL, P&#xe9;an C, Berger S, Caud N, Chen Y, Goldfarb L, Gomis MI, Huang M, Leitzell K, Lonnoy Jbrm E, Maycock TK, Waterfield T, Yelek&#xe7;i O, Yu R, Zhou B, editors. Climate change 2021 - the physical science basis: working group I contribution to the sixth assessment report of the intergovernmental panel on climate change. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2023. p. 1211&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes CR, Bracegirdle TJ, Holland PR. Antarctic sea ice projections constrained by historical ice cover and future global temperature change. Geophys Res Lett. 2022;49(10):e2021GL097413. 10.1029/2021GL097413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2021GL097413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao W, Esper O, Gersonde R. Last glacial - holocene climate variability in the Atlantic sector of the Southern Ocean. Quaternary Sci Rev. 2016;135:115&#x2013;37. 10.1016/j.quascirev.2016.01.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.quascirev.2016.01.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas ER, Allen CS, Etourneau J, King ACF, Severi M, Winton VHL, et al. Antarctic Sea ice proxies from Marine and ice core archives suitable for reconstructing Sea ice over the past 2000 years. Geosciences. 2019;9(12):506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/geosciences9120506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chadwick M, Crosta X, Esper O, Th&#xf6;le L, Kohfeld KE. Compilation of Southern Ocean sea-ice records covering the last glacial-interglacial cycle (12-130 &amp; amp;thinsp;ka). Clim. Past. 2022;18(8):1815&#x2013;29. 10.5194/cp-18-1815-2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/cp-18-1815-2022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainley D, Woehler EJ, Lescro&#xeb;l A. Birds and Antarctic sea ice. In: Thomas D, editor. Sea ice. Hoboken, UK: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Incorporated; 2017. p. 570&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauser C, Delord K, Barbraud C. Sea ice and local weather affect reproductive phenology of a polar seabird with breeding consequences. Ornithol Appl. 2021;123(4). 10.1093/ornithapp/duab032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorne LH, Clay TA, Phillips RA, Silvers LG, Wakefield ED. Effects of wind on the movement, behavior, energetics, and life history of seabirds. Mar Ecol Prog Ser. 2023;723:73&#x2013;117. 10.3354/meps14417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps14417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Sol&#xed;s J, Croxall JP, Wood AG. Sexual dimorphism and sexual segregation in foraging strategies of northern giant petrels. Macronectes Halli, Dur Incubation. Oikos. 2000;90(2):390&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips RA, Silk JRD, Phalan B, Catry P, Croxall JP. Seasonal sexual segregation in two thalassarche albatross species: competitive exclusion, reproductive role specialization or foraging niche divergence? Proceedings of the Royal Society of London Series B-Biological Sciences. 2004;271(1545):1283&#x2013;91; 10.1098/rspb.2004.2718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1691717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15306353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fauchald P. Spatial interaction between seabirds and prey: review and synthesis. Mar Ecol-Prog Ser. 2009;391:139&#x2013;51. 10.3354/meps07818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps07818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakefield ED, Bodey TW, Bearhop S, Blackburn J, Colhoun K, Davies R, et al. Space partitioning without territoriality in gannets. Science. 2013;341(6141):68&#x2013;70. 10.1126/science.1236077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1236077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23744776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson A, Gilchrist HG, Benjaminsen S, Bolton M, Bonnet-Lebrun AS, Davoren GK, et al. Foraging range scales with colony size in high-latitude seabirds. Curr Biol. 2022;32(17):3800&#x2013;7.e3. 10.1016/j.cub.2022.06.084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cub.2022.06.084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35870447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cline DR, Siniff DB, Erickson AW. Summer birds of the pack ice in the Weddell Sea, Antarctica. Auk. 1969;86(4):701&#x2013;16. 10.2307/4083458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/4083458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumont D. Marginal ice zone dynamics: history, definitions and research perspectives. Philosophical transactions of the Royal society a: mathematical. Phys Eng Sci. 2022;380(2235):20210253. 10.1098/rsta.2021.0253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40462-025-00609-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36088925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massom RA, Stammerjohn SE. Antarctic sea ice change and variability - physical and ecological implications. Polar Sci. 2010;4(2):149&#x2013;86. 10.1016/j.polar.2010.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polar.2010.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakefield ED, McClymont EL, Carneiro AB, Croxall JP, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Sol&#xed;s J, Granroth-Wilding HMV, et al. Seasonal resource tracking and use of sea-ice foraging habitats by albatrosses and large petrels. Prog Oceanogr. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woehler EJ, Raymond B, Watts DJ. Decadal-scale seabird assemblages in Prydz Bay, East Antarctica. Mar Ecol-Prog Ser. 2003;251:299&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps251299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woehler EJ, Raymond B, Boyle A, Stafford A. Seabird assemblages observed during the BROKE-West survey of the Antarctic coastline (30&#xb0;E-80&#xb0;E), January - March 2006. Deep Sea Res Part II. 2010;57(9):982&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.dsr2.2008.12.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dsr2.2008.12.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsworthy PM, Thomson PG. An extreme inland breeding locality of snow petrels (pagodroma nivea) in the southern Prince Charles Mountains, Antarctica. Polar Biol. 2000;23(10):717&#x2013;20. 10.1007/s003000000146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s003000000146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thatje S, Hillenbrand C-D, Mackensen A, Larter R. Life hung by a thread: endurance of antarctic fauna in glacial periods. Ecology. 2008;89(3):682&#x2013;92. 10.1890/07-0498.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/07-0498.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18459332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delord K, Pinet P, Pinaud D, Barbraud C, De Grissac S, Lewden A, et al. Species-specific foraging strategies and segregation mechanisms of sympatric Antarctic fulmarine petrels throughout the annual cycle. Ibis (Lond 1859). 2016;158(3):569&#x2013;86. 10.1111/ibi.12365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ibi.12365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthiopoulos J, Wakefield E, Jeglinski JWE, Furness RW, Trinder M, Tyler G, et al. Integrated modelling of seabird-habitat associations from multi-platform data: a review. J Educ Chang Appl Ecol. 2022;59(4):909&#x2013;20. 10.1111/1365-2664.14114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1365-2664.14114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Snow and Ice Data Center. Sea Ice Index, Version 3. https://nsidc.org/data/g02135/versions/3. Accessed 29 September 2024. Accessed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernet M, Geibert W, Hoppema M, Brown PJ, Haas C, Hellmer HH, et al. The Weddell gyre, Southern Ocean: present knowledge and future challenges. Rev Of Geophysics. 2019;57(3):623&#x2013;708. 10.1029/2018RG000604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2018RG000604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg S, Emmerson L, Heim C, Buchta E, Fromm T, Glaser B, et al. Reconstructing the paleo-ecological diet of snow petrels (pagodroma nivea) from modern samples and fossil deposits: implications for southern ocean paleoenvironmental reconstructions. J Geophys Res: Biogeosci. 2023;128(4):e2023JG007454. 10.1029/2023JG007454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2023JG007454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan P, Steele W, Siegfried WR, Vogel JC. Radiocarbon-dates of snow petrel regurgitations can reveal exposure periods for nunataks in Antarctica. South Afr J Sci. 1992;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honan EM, Wakefield ED, Phillips RA, Grecian WJ, Prince S, Robert H, et al. The foraging distribution and habitat use of chick-rearing snow petrels from two colonies in Dronning Maud Land, Antarctica. Mar Biol. 2025;172(7):109.https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00227-025-04657-w.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00227-025-04657-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12141146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40486183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner J, Holmes C, Caton Harrison T, Phillips T, Jena B, Reeves-Francois T, et al. Record low antarctic sea ice cover in February 2022. Geophys Res Lett. 2022;49(12):e2022GL098904. 10.1029/2022GL098904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2022GL098904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner J, Guarino MV, Arnatt J, Jena B, Marshall GJ, Phillips T, et al. Recent decrease of summer sea ice in the Weddell sea, Antarctica. Geophys Res Lett. 2020;47(11):e2020GL087127. 10.1029/2020GL087127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2020GL087127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roach LA, D&#xf6;rr J, Holmes CR, Massonnet F, Blockley EW, Notz D, et al. Antarctic sea ice area in CMIP6. Geophys Res Lett. 2020;47(9):e2019GL086729. 10.1029/2019GL086729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2019GL086729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowther A, von Quillfeldt C, Assmy P, De Steur L, Descamps S, Divine D, et al. A review of the scientific knowledge of the seascape off dronning maud land, Antarctica. Polar Biol. 2022;45(8):1313&#x2013;49. 10.1007/s00300-022-03059-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00300-022-03059-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaxter CB, Lascelles B, Sugar K, Cook ASCP, Roos S, Bolton M, et al. Seabird foraging ranges as a preliminary tool for identifying candidate marine protected areas. Biol Conserv. 2012;15653&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.biocon.2011.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biocon.2011.12.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schofield O, Cimino M, Doney S, Friedlaender A, Meredith M, Moffat C, et al. Antarctic pelagic ecosystems on a warming planet. Trends In Ecol Evol. 2024;39(12):1141&#x2013;53. 10.1016/j.tree.2024.08.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tree.2024.08.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39266440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan PC, Watkins BP. Birds of the inland mountains of western dronning maud land, Antarctica. Mar Ornith. 1988;16:34&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5038/2074-1235.16.1.187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haftorn S, Mehlum F, Bech C, Bech C, Mehlum F. Size variation in the snow petrel pagodroma nivea. Notornis. 1988;109&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbraud C, Weimerskirch H, Robertson GG, Jouventin P. Size-related life history traits: insights from a study of snow petrels (pagodroma nivea). J Anim Ecol. 1999;68(6):1179&#x2013;92. 10.1046/j.1365-2656.1999.00361.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2656.1999.00361.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehlum F, Gjessing Y, Haftorn S, Bech C. Census of breeding Antarctic petrels thalassoica antarctica and physical features of the breeding colony at Svarthamaren, Dronning Maud Land, with notes on breeding snow petrels pagodroma nivea and south polar skuas catharacta maccormicki. Polar Res. 1988;6(1):1&#x2013;9. 10.3402/polar.v6i1.6841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3402/polar.v6i1.6841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta Y, Eiken T, Polarinstitutt N. Nature environment map: gjelsvikfjella and Western Mhulig-Hofmannfjella, Dronning Maud Land, East Antarctica, 1: 100,000. Norwegian Polar Institute; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris CM, Lorenz K, Fishpool LDC, Lascelles B, Cooper J, Coria NR, et al. Important Bird Areas in Antarctica. Cambridge, UK: BirdLife International and Environmental Research &amp; Assessment Ltd; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodum PJ. Breeding biology of high-latitude Antarctic fulmarine petrels (Procellariidae). J Zool. 2002;256(2):139&#x2013;49. 10.1017/S0952836902000171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0952836902000171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pande A, Sivakumar K. Climate change and seabirds: insights from ecological monitoring of snow petrels in the Indian Antarctic program. In: Khare N, editor. Assessing the Antarctic environment from a climate change perspective: an integrated approach. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2022. p. 207&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips RA, Silk JRD, Croxall JP, Afanasyev V, Briggs DR. Accuracy of geolocation estimates for flying seabirds. Mar Ecol-Prog Ser. 2004;266:265&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps266265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer SA, Tremblay Y, Awkerman JA, Henry RW, Teo SLH, Anderson DJ, et al. Comparison of light- and SST-based geolocation with satellite telemetry in free-ranging albatrosses. Mar Biol. 2005;147(4):833&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00227-005-1631-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winship AJ, Jorgensen SJ, Shaffer SA, Jonsen ID, Robinson PW, Costa DP, et al. State-space framework for estimating measurement error from double-tagging telemetry experiments. Methods Ecol Evol. 2011;3:291&#x2013;302. 10.1111/j.2041-210X.2011.00161.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2041-210X.2011.00161.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetterer F, Knowles K, Meier W, Savoie M, Windnagel AK. Sea ice index, version 3 [data set]. Boulder, Colorado USA: National Snow and Ice Data Center; 2017. 10.7265/N5K072F8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier WN, Stewart JS. Assessing uncertainties in sea ice extent climate indicators. Environ Res Lett. 2019;14(3):035005. 10.1088/1748-9326/aaf52c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/aaf52c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe5;then V, Moe B, Am&#xe9;lineau F, Ekker M, Helgason H, Johansen M, et al. An automated procedure (v2.0) to obtain positions from light-level geolocators in large- scale tracking of seabirds a method description for the SEATRACK project. In. Trondheim, Norway: NINA Report 1893, 2021:52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerrish L, Fretwell P, Cooper P. High resolution vector polygons of the Antarctic coastline (7.6) [data set]. UK Polar Data Centre, Natural Environment Research Council, UK Research &amp; Innovation; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennison A, Bearhop S, Bodey TW, Votier SC, Grecian WJ, Wakefield ED, et al. Search and foraging behaviors from movement data: a comparison of methods. Ecol Evol. 2018;8(1):13&#x2013;24. 10.1002/ece3.3593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ece3.3593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5756868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooten MB, Johnson DS, McClintock BT, Morales JM. Animal movement: statistical models for telemetry data. New York: CRC Press; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelot T, Langrock R, Patterson TA. moveHMM: an R package for the statistical modelling of animal movement data using hidden Markov models. Methods Ecol Evol. 2016;7(11):1308&#x2013;15. 10.1111/2041-210X.12578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarroux A, Cherel Y, Fauchald P, Kato A, Love OP, Ropert-Coudert Y, et al. Foraging tactics in dynamic sea-ice habitats affect individual state in a long-ranging seabird. Funct Ecol. 2020;34(9):1839&#x2013;56. 10.1111/1365-2435.13632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1365-2435.13632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelot T, Langrock R. A short guide to choosing initial parameter values for the estimation in moveHMM. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fieberg J. Utilization distribution estimation using weighted kernel density estimators. J Wildl Manag. 2007;71(5):1669&#x2013;75. 10.2193/2006-370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2193/2006-370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming CH, Fagan WF, Mueller T, Olson KA, Leimgruber P, Calabrese JM. Rigorous home range estimation with movement data: a new autocorrelated kernel density estimator. Ecology. 2015;96(5):1182&#x2013;88. 10.1890/14-2010.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/14-2010.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26236833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming CH, Calabrese JM. A new kernel density estimator for accurate home-range and species-range area estimation. Methods In Ecol And Evol. 2017;8(5):571&#x2013;79. 10.1111/2041-210X.12673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.12673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming CH, Deznabi I, Alavi S, Crofoot MC, Hirsch BT, Medici EP, et al. Population-level inference for home-range areas. Methods Ecol Evol. 2022;13(5):1027&#x2013;41. 10.1111/2041-210X.13815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.13815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walli A, Teo SLH, Boustany A, Farwell CJ, Williams T, Dewar H, et al. Seasonal movements, aggregations and diving behavior of Atlantic bluefin tuna (thunnus thynnus) revealed with archival tags. PLoS One. 2009;4(7):18.e6151. 10.1371/journal.pone.0006151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19582150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calenge C, Adehabitat HR. Home range estimation. 2023. https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=adehabitatHR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kie JG. A rule-based ad hoc method for selecting a bandwidth in kernel home-range analyses. Anim Biotelem. 2013;1(1):13. 10.1186/2050-3385-1-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2050-3385-1-13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fieberg J, Kochanny CO. Quantifying home-range overlap: the importance of the utilization distribution. J Wildl Manag. 2005;69(4):1346&#x2013;59. 10.2193/0022-541x(2005)69[1346:qhotio]2.0.co;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2193/0022-541x(2005)69[1346:qhotio]2.0.co;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleasby IR, Wakefield ED, Bodey TW, Davies AM, Patrick S, Newton J, et al. Sexual segregation in a wide-ranging marine predator is a consequence of habitat selection. Mar Ecol-Prog Ser. 2015;518:1&#x2013;12. 10.3354/meps11112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps11112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winner K, Noonan MJ, Fleming CH, Olson KA, Mueller T, Sheldon D, et al. Statistical inference for home range overlap. Methods Ecol Evol. 2018;9(7):1679&#x2013;91. 10.1111/2041-210X.13027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.13027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarroux A, Weimerskirch H, Wang S-H, Bromwich DH, Cherel Y, Kato A, et al. Flexible flight response to challenging wind conditions in a commuting Antarctic seabird: do you catch the drift? Anim behaviour. 2016;113:99&#x2013;112. 10.1016/j.anbehav.2015.12.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anbehav.2015.12.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Etten J. Gdistance: distances and routes on geographical grids. R package version 1.6.4. 2023. https://AgrDataSci.github.io/gdistance/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates D, M&#xe4;chler M, Bolker B, Walker S. Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. J Stat Softw. 2015;67(1):1&#x2013;48. 10.18637/jss.v067.i01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v067.i01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenth rv: emmeans: estimated marginal means, aka least-squares Means_. R package version 1.10.1. 2024. https://CRAN.R-project.Org/package=emmeans%3E.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa S, Schielzeth H. Repeatability for Gaussian and non-Gaussian data: a practical guide for biologists. Biol Rev. 2010;85(4):935&#x2013;56. 10.1111/j.1469-185X.2010.00141.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-185X.2010.00141.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20569253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoffel M, Schielzeth H. rptR: repeatability estimation and variance decomposition by generalized linear mixed-effects models. Methods Ecol Evol. 2017;8. 10.1111/2041-210X.12797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.12797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis J, Wakefield E, Jamieson SSR, Phillips RA, Hodgson DA, Southwell C, et al. A circumpolar review of the breeding distribution and habitat use of the snow petrel (Pagodroma nivea), the world&#x2019;s most southerly breeding vertebrate. Polar Biol. 2024;48(1):9. 10.1007/s00300-024-03336-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00300-024-03336-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11655582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39712872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis J. Quantifying the breeding distribution and habitat use of the snow petrel (Pagodroma nivea), the world&#x2019;s most southerly breeding vertebrate. In: Durham University; 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11655582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39712872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hobbs W, Spence P, Meyer A, Schroeter S, Fraser AD, Reid P, et al. Observational evidence for a regime shift in summer Antarctic sea ice. J Retailing Clim. 2024. 10.1175/JCLI-D-23-0479.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1175/JCLI-D-23-0479.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soanes LM, Arnould JPY, Dodd SG, Sumner MD, Green JA. How many seabirds do we need to track to define 1 home-range area? J Educ Chang Appl Ecol. 2013;50(3):671&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1365-2664.12069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips RA, Xavier JC, Croxall JP. Effects of satellite transmitters on albatrosses and petrels. Auk. 2003;120(4):1082&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1642/0004-8038(2003)120[1082:EOSTOA]2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandenabeele SP, Shepard EL, Grogan A, Wilson RP. When three per cent may not be three per cent; device-equipped seabirds experience variable flight constraints. Mar Biol. 2012;159(1):1&#x2013;14. 10.1007/s00227-011-1784-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00227-011-1784-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennycuick CJ, Fast PLF, Ballerst&#xe4;dt N, Rattenborg N. The effect of an external transmitter on the drag coefficient of a bird&#x2019;s body, and hence on migration range, and energy reserves after migration. J Ornithol. 2012;153(3):633&#x2013;44. 10.1007/s10336-011-0781-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10336-011-0781-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portugal SJ, White CR. Externally attached biologgers cause compensatory body mass loss in birds. Methods In Ecol And Evol. 2022;13(2):294&#x2013;302. 10.1111/2041-210X.13754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.13754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisovski S, Hewson CM, Klaassen RHG, Korner-Nievergelt F, Kristensen MW, Hahn S. Geolocation by light: accuracy and precision affected by environmental factors. Methods In Ecol And Evol. 2012;3(3):603&#x2013;12. 10.1111/j.2041-210X.2012.00185.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2041-210X.2012.00185.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin LR, Ross JD, Ramos R, Mott R, Carlile N, Golding N, et al. Double-tagging scores of seabirds reveals that light-level geolocator accuracy is limited by species idiosyncrasies and equatorial solar profiles. Methods Ecol Evol. 2021;12(11):2243&#x2013;55. 10.1111/2041-210X.13698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/2041-210X.13698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill RD. in: Le Boeuf, BJ, Laws, RM Elephant, Seals., editors. Theory of geolocation by light levels. University of California Press; 1994. p. 227&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappes MA, Shaffer SA, Tremblay Y, Foley DG, Palacios DM, Bograd SJ, et al. Reproductive constraints influence habitat accessibility, segregation, and preference of sympatric albatross species. Mov Ecol. 2015;3(1):34. 10.1186/s40462-015-0063-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40462-015-0063-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4587674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26421151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamolard M, Weimerskirch H. Relationship between foraging effort and energy requirement throughout the breeding-season in the wandering albatross. Funct Ecol. 1993;7(6):643&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2390184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warham J. The petrels: their ecology and breeding systems. San Diego: Academic; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamburello N, C&#xf4;t&#xe9; IM, Dulvy NK. Energy and the scaling of animal space use. Am NaturaList. 2015;186(2):196&#x2013;211. 10.1086/682070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/682070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26655149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jouventin P, Viot C-R. Morphological and genetic variability of snow petrels pagodroma nivea. Ibis (Lond 1859). 1985;127(4):430&#x2013;41. 10.1111/j.1474-919X.1985.tb04839.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1474-919X.1985.tb04839.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;mmler M-C, Esefeld J, Pfeifer C, Mustafa O. Survey of a snow petrel nesting site in a remote high mountain region to inform designation of an antarctic specially protected area. Front Conserv Sci. 2024;5. 10.3389/fcosc.2024.1298962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcosc.2024.1298962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedd A, Montevecchi WA, Phillips RA, Fifield DA. Seasonal sexual segregation by monomorphic sooty shearwaters <i>puffinus griseus</i> reflects different reproductive roles during the pre-laying period. PLoS One. 2014;9(1):e85572. 10.1371/journal.pone.0085572.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0085572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3887055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24416429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Pascalis F, Imperio S, Benvenuti A, Catoni C, Rubolini D, Cecere JG. Sex-specific foraging behaviour is affected by wind conditions in a sexually size dimorphic seabird. Anim behaviour. 2020;166:207&#x2013;18. 10.1016/j.anbehav.2020.05.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anbehav.2020.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milit&#xe3;o T, K&#xfc;rten N, Bouwhuis S. Sex-specific foraging behaviour in a long-lived seabird. Mar Biol. 2023;170(11):132. 10.1007/s00227-023-04280-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00227-023-04280-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbraud C, Jouventin P. What causes body size variation in the snow petrel pagodroma nivea? J Avian Biol. 1998;29(2):161&#x2013;71. 10.2307/3677194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/3677194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croxall JP. Sexual dimorphism in snow petrels. Notornis. 1982;29:171&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.63172/566713myytrl</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenmann P. Contribution &#xe0; la biologie de reproduction du p&#xe9;trel des neiges (Pagodroma nivea Forster). Le probl&#xe8;me de la petite et de la grande forme. L&#x2019;Oiseau et la Revue francaise d&#x2019;ornithologie. 1970;40:99&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guilford T, Meade J, Willis J, Phillips RA, Boyle D, Roberts S, et al. Migration and stopover in a small pelagic seabird, the manx shearwater puffinus puffinus: insights from machine learning. Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences. 2009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19141421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kottmeier C, Sellmann L. Atmospheric and oceanic forcing of Weddell Sea ice motion. J Geophys Res-Oceans. 1996;101(C9):20809&#x2013;24. 10.1029/96jc01293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/96jc01293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fauchald P, Tarroux A, Tveraa T, Cherel Y, Ropert-Coudert Y, Kato A, et al. Spring phenology shapes the spatial foraging behavior of Antarctic petrels. Mar Ecol Prog Ser. 2017;568:203&#x2013;15. 10.3354/meps12082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps12082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jena B, Kshitija S, Bajish CC, Turner J, Holmes C, Wilkinson J, et al. Evolution of Antarctic Sea ice ahead of the record low annual maximum extent in September 2023. Geophys Res Lett. 2024;51(7):e2023GL107561. 10.1029/2023GL107561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2023GL107561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viola B, Wienecke B, Green C-P, Corney S, Raymond B, Southwell C, et al. Marine distribution and habitat use by snow petrels pagodroma nivea in East Antarctica throughout the non-breeding period. Front Mar Sci. 2023;10. 10.3389/fmars.2023.1278229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmars.2023.1278229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainley D, Ribic C, Spear L. Species-habitat relationships among Antarctic seabirds: a function of physical or biological factors? Condor. 1993;95. 10.2307/1369419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1369419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weimerskirch H, Zotier R, Jouventin P. The avifauna of the Kerguelen Islands. Emu. 1989;89(1):15&#x2013;29. 10.1071/MU9890015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/MU9890015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa DP. Reproductive and foraging energetics of high-latitude penguins, albatrosses and pinnipeds - implications for life-history patterns. Am Zoologist. 1991;31(1):111&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/icb/31.1.111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolton M, Conolly G, Carroll M, Wakefield ED, Caldow R. A review of the occurrence of inter-colony segregation of seabird foraging areas and the implications for marine environmental impact assessment. Ibis (Lond 1859). 2019;161(2):241&#x2013;59. 10.1111/ibi.12677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ibi.12677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainley DG, Nur N, Woehler EJ. Factors affecting the distribution and size of pygoscelid penguin colonies in the Antarctic. The Auk. 1995;112(1):171&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/4088776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehnhard N, Klekociuk AR, Emmerson L. Interactive effects of body mass changes and species-specific morphology on flight behavior of chick-rearing Antarctic fulmarine petrels under diurnal wind patterns. Ecol Evol. 2021;11:4972&#x2013;91. 10.1002/ece3.7501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ece3.7501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8093695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33976863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alerstam T, B&#xe4;ckman J, Evans TJ. Optimal central place foraging flights in relation to wind. J Ornithol. 2019;160(4):1065&#x2013;76. 10.1007/s10336-019-01677-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10336-019-01677-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson CL, Cavalieri DJ. Antarctic sea ice variability and trends, 1979-2010. Cryosphere. 2012;6(4):871&#x2013;80. 10.5194/tc-6-871-2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/tc-6-871-2012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mougin J. Etude &#xe9;cologique de quatre esp&#xe8;ces de p&#xe9;trels antarctiques. L&#x2019;Oiseau et la Revue francaise d&#x2019;ornithologie. 1968;38:1&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrea C, Burridge CP, Wienecke B, Emmerson LM, White D, Miller KJ. High vagility facilitates population persistence and expansion prior to the last glacial maximum in an antarctic top predator: the Snow petrel (Pagodroma nivea). J Biogeogr. 2019;46(2):442&#x2013;53. 10.1111/jbi.13513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jbi.13513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook D, Beck JR. Antarctic petrels, snow petrels and south polar skuas breeding in the Theron Mountains. Br Antarct Survey Bull. 1972;27:131&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drucker R, Martin S, Kwok R. Sea ice production and export from coastal polynyas in the Weddell and Ross Seas. Geophys Res Lett. 2011;38(17). 10.1029/2011GL048668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul S, Willmes S, Heinemann G. Long-term coastal-polynya dynamics in the southern Weddell Sea from modis thermal-infrared imagery. Cryosphere. 2015;9(6):2027&#x2013;41. 10.5194/tc-9-2027-2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/tc-9-2027-2015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins LG, Pike J, Allen CS, Hodgson DA. High-resolution reconstruction of southwest Atlantic sea-ice and its role in the carbon cycle during marine isotope stages 3 and 2. Paleoceanography. 2012;27(3). 10.1029/2011PA002264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gersonde R, Crosta X, Abelmann A, Armand L. Sea-surface temperature and sea ice distribution of the Southern Ocean at the epilog last Glacial maximum-a circum-Antarctic view based on siliceous microfossil records. Quaternary Sci Rev. 2005;24(7):869&#x2013;96. 10.1016/j.quascirev.2004.07.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.quascirev.2004.07.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JA, Hillenbrand C-D, Pudsey CJ, Allen CS, Graham AGC. The presence of polynyas in the Weddell Sea during the last glacial period with implications for the reconstruction of sea-ice limits and ice sheet history. Earth Planet Sci Lett. 2010;296(3):287&#x2013;98. 10.1016/j.epsl.2010.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2010.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comiso JC, Gordon AL. Recurring polynyas over the Cosmonaut sea and the Maud Rise. J Geophys Res: Oceans. 1987;92(C3):2819&#x2013;33. 10.1029/JC092iC03p02819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/JC092iC03p02819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiser F, Willmes S, Hausmann U, Heinemann G. Predominant sea ice fracture zones around Antarctica and their relation to bathymetric features. Geophys Res Lett. 2019;46(21):12117&#x2013;24. 10.1029/2019GL084624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2019GL084624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber ME, Clark PU, Kuhn G, Timmermann A, Sprenk D, Gladstone R, et al. Millennial-scale variability in Antarctic ice-sheet discharge during the last deglaciation. Nature. 2014;510(7503):134&#x2013;38. 10.1038/nature13397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature13397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24870232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RS, Johnson JS, Lin Y, Mackintosh AN, Sefton JP, Smith JA, et al. Stability of the Antarctic ice sheet during the pre-industrial holocene. Nat Rev Earth Environ. 2022;3(8):500&#x2013;15. 10.1038/s43017-022-00309-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43017-022-00309-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younger JL, Emmerson LM, Miller KJ. The influence of historical climate changes on Southern Ocean marine predator populations: a comparative analysis. Global Change Biol. 2016;22(2):474&#x2013;93. 10.1111/gcb.13104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.13104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26391440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond R, Sime LC, Holmes CR, Schroeder D. CMIP6 models rarely simulate antarctic Winter sea-ice anomalies as large as observed in 2023. Geophys Res Lett. 2024;51(10):e2024GL109265. 10.1029/2024GL109265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2024GL109265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post E. Implications of earlier sea ice melt for phenological cascades in arctic marine food webs. Food Webs. 2017;13:60&#x2013;66. 10.1016/j.fooweb.2016.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fooweb.2016.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sydeman W, Bograd S. Marine ecosystems, climate and phenology: introduction. Mar Ecol Prog Ser. 2009;393:185&#x2013;88. 10.3354/meps08382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps08382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constable AJ, Melbourne-Thomas J, Corney SP, Arrigo KR, Barbraud C, Barnes DKA, et al. Climate change and Southern ocean ecosystems I: how changes in physical habitats directly affect marine biota. Global Change Biol. 2014;20(10):3004&#x2013;25. 10.1111/gcb.12623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.12623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24802817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>