<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41346124</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-4998</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>82</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pest management science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pest Manag Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identification and field evaluation of sex pheromone for Erannis ankeraria Staudinger (Lepidoptera: Geometridae).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3041</StartPage><EndPage>3050</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3041-3050</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ps.70425</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Erannis ankeraria (Staudinger) (Lepidoptera: Geometridae) is a defoliator of Larix, Quercus, and Picea trees. Recent outbreaks of this pest have caused extensive damage to the larch forests in north-eastern China RESULTS: Through gas chromatography-electroantennographic detection (GC-EAD) and gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS), Z3Z6Z9-19:Hy, Z3Z9-cis-6,7-epo-19:Hy, Z6Z9-cis-3,4-epo-19:Hy, and Z3Z6-cis-9,10-epo-19:Hy were identified from sex pheromone glands of Erannis ankeraria females. The quaternary mixture of these synthetic pheromone components at a ratio of 1:0.5:1.2:1.3 achieved the optimal trapping effect in field experiments. Biotransformation and activity assays revealed that Z3Z6Z9-19:Hy serves as a precursor of epoxynonadecadienes, regulates the upwind flight behavior of male moths, and exhibits a synergistic effect with the epoxy pheromone components. Notably, the 3,4- and 9,10-epoxides, newly identified in the genus Erannis, both markedly decrease the captures of Colotois pennaria (Lepidoptera: Geometridae) CONCLUSIONS: The sex pheromone of Erannis ankeraria was identified as a quaternary blend, which exhibits a remarkable efficacy in attracting Erannis ankeraria males, thereby offering a reliable tool for population monitoring. Z3Z6Z9-19:Hy acts as a precursor in the biosynthesis of three epoxynonadecadiene pheromone components, and is also a critical synergistic pheromone component. The 3,4- and 9,10-epoxides likely mediate interspecific chemical communication between Erannis ankeraria and C. pennaria, enabling species-specific recognition and reproductive isolation &#xa9; 2025 Society of Chemical Industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Fu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9955-959X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Protection of National Forestry and Grassland Administration, Ecology and Nature Conservation Institute, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academy of Chemical Engineering and Biotechnology, Xingtai University, Xintai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Siyan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Protection of National Forestry and Grassland Administration, Ecology and Nature Conservation Institute, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Xiangbo</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1183-0459</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Protection of National Forestry and Grassland Administration, Ecology and Nature Conservation Institute, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Sufang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Protection of National Forestry and Grassland Administration, Ecology and Nature Conservation Institute, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Jiaxing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Protection of National Forestry and Grassland Administration, Ecology and Nature Conservation Institute, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Forest Protection of National Forestry and Grassland Administration, Ecology and Nature Conservation Institute, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Huihui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Permanent Scientific Research Base for Warm Temperate Zone Forestry of Jiulong Mountain in Beijing, Experimental Center of Forestry in North China, Chinese Academy of Forestry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Congkui</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Key Laboratory of Selenium Resources Research and Biological Applications, Institute of Selenium Science and Industry, Hubei Minzu University, Enshi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>the Fundamental Research Funds of CAF</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Pest Manag Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100898744</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1526-498X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012724">Sex Attractants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012724" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sex Attractants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009036" MajorTopicYN="Y">Moths</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008401" MajorTopicYN="N">Gas Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Insect Control</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Erannis ankeraria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biotransformation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">field bioassay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sex pheromone</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41346124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ps.70425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Karnosky DF, Micropropagation of larches (Larix spp.), in High&#x2010;Tech and Micropropagation II. Biotechnology in Agriculture and Forestry, Vol. 18, ed. by Bajaj YPS. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dion C, Chappuis E and Ripoll C, Does larch arabinogalactan enhance immune function? A review of mechanistic and clinical trials. Nutr Metab 13:1&#x2013;11 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riede L, Grube B and Gruenwald J, Larch arabinogalactan effects on reducing incidence of upper respiratory infections. Curr Med Res Opin 29:251&#x2013;258 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SH, Larch arabinogalactan attenuates myocardial injury by inhibiting apoptotic cascades in a rat model of ischemia&#x2010;reperfusion. J Med Food 20:691&#x2013;699 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prescott JH, Enriquez P, Jung C, Menz E and Groman EV, Larch arabinogalactan for hepatic drug delivery: isolation and characterization of a 9 kDa arabinogalactan fragment. Carbohydr Res 278:113&#x2013;128 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salyers AA, Arthur R and Kuritza A, Digestion of larch arabinogalactan by a strain of human colonic Bacteroides growing in continuous culture. J Agric Food Chem 29:475&#x2013;480 (1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malyar YN, Borovkova VS, Kazachenko AS, Fetisova OY, Skipnikov AM, Sychev VV et al., Preparation and characterization of di&#x2010; and tricarboxylic acids&#x2010;modified arabinogalactan plasticized composite films. Polymers&#x2010;Basel 15:1999 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xf3;th B, Babics J and Benedek B, Contributions to knowledge of the geometrid fauna of Bulgaria and Greece, with four species new for the Greek fauna (Lepidoptera: Geometridae) (plate 12). Esperiana 18:221&#x2013;224 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihoci I and Franjevi&#x107; M, Rare and threatened geometrid moth Erannis ankeraria in Croatia: historical review, data analysis &amp; perspectives. &#x160;umar List 135:353&#x2013;359 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lees DR, The inheritance of melanism in the moths Erannis defoliaria (Clerck) and Agriopis marginaria (fab.) (Lepidoptera: Geometridae). Biol J Linn Soc 15:279&#x2013;285 (1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glavendeki&#x107; M, Parasitoids and Hyperparasitoids of Erannis defoliaria CL. (Lepidoptera, Geometridae) in oak forests. &#x160;umar List 134:403&#x2013;410 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan JP, Shao DH, Zhang ZL and Duan LQ, The bionomics of Erannis ankeraria Staudinger. Chin Bull Entomol 51:808&#x2013;813 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Li FY, Zhang SF, Kong XB and Zhang Z, Ultrastructure of antennal sensilla of Erannis ankeraria Staudinger (Lepidoptera: Geometridae). Microsc Res Tech 82:1903&#x2013;1910 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leraut P, Moths of Europe. Geometrid Moths. Vol. 2. N.A.P. Editions, Verri&#xe8;res le Buisson (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sz&#xf6;cs G, T&#xf3;th M, Francke W, Schmidt F, Philipp P, K&#xf6;nig WA et al., Species discrimination in five species of winter&#x2010;flying geometrids (Lepidoptera) based on chirality of semiochemicals and flight season. J Chem Ecol 19:2721&#x2013;2735 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahlberg N, Sn&#xe4;ll N, Viidalepp J, Ruohom&#xe4;ki K and Tammaru T, The evolution of female flightlessness among Ennominae of the Holarctic Forest zone (Lepidoptera, Geometridae). Mol Phylogenet Evol 55:929&#x2013;938 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando T, Inomata SI and Yamamoto M, Lepidopteran sex pheromones in The Chemisstry of Pheromones and Other Semiochemicals I, Topics in Current Chemistry, Vol. 239, ed. by Schulz S. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, pp. 51&#x2013;96 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando T, Ohtani K, Yamamoto M, Miyamoto T, Qin XR and Witjaksono, Sex pheromone of Japanese giant looper, Ascotis selenaria cretacea: identification and field tests. J Chem Ecol 23:2413&#x2013;2423 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millar JG, Polyene hydrocarbons and epoxides: a second major class of lepidopteran sex attractant pheromones. Annu Rev Entomol 45:575&#x2013;604 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;fstedt C, Wahlberg N and Millar JG, Evolutionary patterns of pheromone diversity in Lepidoptera. in Pheromone Communication in Moths: Evolution, Behavior and Application, ed. by Allison JD and Card&#xe9; RT. University of California Press, Berkeley, pp. 43&#x2013;78 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuvaraj JK, Corcoran JA, Andersson MN, Newcomb RD, Anderbrant O and L&#xf6;fstedt C, Characterization of odorant receptors from a non&#x2010;ditrysian moth, Eriocrania semipurpurella sheds light on the origin of sex pheromone receptors in Lepidoptera. Mol Biol Evol 34:2733&#x2013;2746 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T, Huang ZJ, Zhu Y, Lin N, Xiao Q, He YR et al., Progress in sex pheromone components in geometrid species (Lepidoptera: Geometridae) and their applications. Sci Silvae Sin 55:152&#x2013;162 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelofs W and Bjostad L, Biosynthesis of lepidopteran pheromones. Bioorg Chem 12:279&#x2013;298 (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlton RE and Roelofs WL, Biosynthesis of a volatile, methyl&#x2010;branched hydrocarbon sex pheromone from leucine by Arctiid moths (Holomelina spp.). Arch Insect Biochem Physiol 18:81&#x2013;97 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witzgall P, Kirsch P and Cork A, Sex pheromones and their impact on pest management. J Chem Ecol 36:80&#x2013;100 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T, Xiao Q, Yu YG, Wang C, Zhu CQ, Sun ZH et al., Analysis of tea geometrid (Ectropis grisescens) pheromone gland extracts using GC&#x2010;EAD and GC &#xd7; GC/TOFMS. J Agric Food Chem 64:3161&#x2013;3166 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshi H, Takabe M and Nakamuta K, Mating disruption of a carpenter moth, Cossus insularis (Lepidoptera: Cossidae) in apple orchards with synthetic sex pheromone, and registration of the pheromone as an agrochemical. J Chem Ecol 42:606&#x2013;611 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma T, Zhang YY, Wang SK, Lan LJ, Lin N, Wang C et al., Reproductive behavior and sex pheromone production in Eutectona machaeralis (Lepidoptera: Crambidae). Fla Entomol 101:189&#x2013;194 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levi&#x2010;Zada A, Fefer D, Madar R, Steiner S and Kaspi R, Evaluation of pheromone of false codling moth Thaumatotibia leucotreta in Israel by sequential SPME/GCMS analysis and field trials. J Pest Sci 93:519&#x2013;529 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Guo L, Zhang SF, Kong XB and Zhang Z, Synthesis and bioactivity of (13Z,15E)&#x2010;octadecadienal: a sex pheromone component from Micromelalopha siversi Staudinger (Lepidoptera: Notodontidae). Pest Manag Sci 77:264&#x2013;272 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan JJ, Zhang MD, Ali A, Du X, Mei XD and Gao YL, Optimization and field evaluation of sex&#x2010;pheromone of potato tuber moth, Phthorimaea operculella Zeller (Lepidoptera: Gelechiidae). Pest Manag Sci 78:3903&#x2013;3911 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian CY, Su ZQ, Xie WQ, Dong X, Li YH, Yuan PY et al., Structure, synthesis, and bioassays of sex pheromone for Pyrausta machaeralis (Lepidoptera: Crambidae). J Agric Food Chem 72:3904&#x2013;3912 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson BS, Sz&#xf6;cs G, Schmidt F, Francke W, L&#xf6;fstedt C and T&#xf3;th M, Electrophysiological and chemical analysis of sex pheromone communication system of the mottled umber, Erannis defoliaria (Lepidoptera: Geometridae). J Chem Ecol 16:1887&#x2013;1897 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goller S, Sz&#xf6;cs G, Francke W and Schulz S, Biosynthesis of (3Z,6Z,9Z)&#x2010;3,6,9&#x2010;octadecatriene: the main component of the pheromone blend of Erannis Bajaria. J Chem Ecol 33:1505&#x2013;1509 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conner WE, Eisner T, Vander Meer RK, Guerrero A, Ghiringelli D and Meinwald J, Sex attractant of an arctiid moth (Utetheisa ornatrix): a pulsed chemical signal. Behav Ecol Sociobiol 7:55&#x2013;63 (1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SF and Zhang AJ, Facile and efficient syntheses of (3Z,6Z,9Z)&#x2010;3,6,9&#x2010;nonadecatriene and homologues: pheromone and attractant components of lepidoptera. J Agric Food Chem 55:6929&#x2013;6932 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharov AA, Leonard D, Liebhold AM, Roberts AE and Dickerson W, Slow the spread: a National Program to contain the gypsy moth. J Forest 100:30&#x2013;36 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tcheslavskaia KS, Thorpe KW, Brewster CC, Sharov AA and Roberts EA, Optimization of pheromone dosage for gypsy moth mating disruption. Entomol Exp Appl 115:355&#x2013;361 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman TW, Foelker CJ, and Perkins T, A 20&#x2010;year synthesis of the Lymantria dispar slow the spread program in Slow the Spread: a 20&#x2010;year reflection on the national Lymantria dispar integrated pest management program, ed. by Coleman TW and Liebhold AM U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Northern Research Station, Madison, WI, pp. 45&#x2013;69 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sz&#xf6;cs G, T&#xf3;th M, Francke W, Franke S and Plass E, Homologous polyenic hydrocarbons in the sex pheromones of winter geometrids (Lepidoptera), Book of Abstracts. 13th Annual Meeting Int Soc Chem Ecol Prague 178 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lecheva I, Possibilities of implementing synthetic sex pheromones against the geometrid Erannis bajaria (Lepidoptera: Geometridae). Rasteniev dni Nauki 36:397&#x2013;400 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sz&#xf6;cs G, &#xd6;tv&#xf6;s IS and Sanders C, Erannis tiliaria (Lepidoptere: Geometridae) males attracted to enantiomerically identical pheromone blend of Erannis defoliaria. Can Entomol 133:297&#x2013;299 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando T, Kishi H, Akashio N, Qin XR, Saito N, Abe H et al., Sex attractants of geometrid and noctuid moths: chemical characterization and field test of monoepoxides of 6, 9&#x2010;dienes and related compounds. J Chem Ecol 21:299&#x2013;311 (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JW, Palaniswamy P, Underhill E, Steck W and Chisholm M, Sex pheromone components of fall cankerworm moth, Alsophila pometaria. J Chem Ecol 10:1579&#x2013;1596 (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millar JG, Underhill E, Giblin M and Barton D, Sex pheromone components of three species of Semiothisa (Geometridae), (Z, Z, Z)&#x2010;3,6,9&#x2010;heptadecatriene and two monoepoxydiene analogs. J Chem Ecol 13:1371&#x2013;1383 (1987).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryall K, Silk PJ, Wu J, Mayo P, Lemay MA and Magee D, Sex pheromone chemistry and field trapping studies of the elm spanworm Ennomos subsignaria (H&#xfc;bner) (Lepidoptera: Geometridae). Naturwissenschaften 97:717&#x2013;724 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei W, Miyamoto T, Ento M, Murakawa T, Pu GQ and Ando T, Polyunsaturated hydrocarbons in the hemolymph: biosynthetic precursors of epoxy pheromones of geometrid and arctiid moths. Insect Biochem Mol Biol 33:397&#x2013;405 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiyota R, Arakawa M, Yamakawa R, Yasmin A and Ando T, Biosynthetic pathways of the sex pheromone components and substrate selectivity of the oxidation enzymes working in pheromone glands of the fall webworm, Hyphantria cunea. Insect Biochem Mol Biol 41:362&#x2013;369 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto T, Yamamoto M, Ono A, Ohtani K and Ando T, Substrate specificity of the epoxidation reaction in sex pheromone biosynthesis of the Japanese giant looper (Lepidoptera: Geometridae). Insect Biochem Mol Biol 29:63&#x2013;69 (1999).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>