<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41686890</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vapor-deposited copper iodide cluster-based light-emitting diodes for pico-projector.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadz9942</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadz9942</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadz9942</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adz9942</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vapor-deposited metal halide clusters have demonstrated great potential for next-generation lighting and display applications. However, the direct synthesis-on-substrate of highly emissive materials via dry reaction technique is restricted by insufficient chemical reaction and precursor aggregation, leading to inferior device performance compared to their solution-processed counterparts. Here, we report a one-step vacuum synthesis deposition of copper(I) iodide clusters with near-unity photoluminescence quantum yields by engineering the stereohindrance of the organic ligand. When codeposited copper(I) iodide and 3,5-di(9H-carbazol-9-yl)pyridine (35DCzPPy) with minimal steric hindrance near the pyridine group, [35DCzPPy]<sub>4</sub>Cu<sub>2</sub>I<sub>2</sub> clusters are uniformly assembled without copper-copper aggregation. Consequently, light-emitting diodes (LEDs) based on clusters show a peak external quantum efficiency of 19.4%, a maximum luminance of 34,232 candelas per square meter, and a record operating <i>T</i><sub>50</sub> lifetime of 4186&#xa0;hours at 100 candelas per square meter. Moreover, we integrated the LEDs onto backplane drivers for active-matrix (AM) cluster LED (CLED) display panels, which enables the prototype of a high-dynamic-range pico-projector. Our results demonstrate the potential of vapor-deposited copper halide clusters for next-generation lighting and displays.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Yiqi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-6675-2180</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National Laboratory for Optoelectronics (WNLO) and School of Optical and Electronic Information, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), 1037 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei 430074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Longbo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1072-8084</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National Laboratory for Optoelectronics (WNLO) and School of Optical and Electronic Information, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), 1037 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei 430074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-8156-3418</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National Laboratory for Optoelectronics (WNLO) and School of Optical and Electronic Information, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), 1037 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei 430074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ou</LastName><ForeName>Jianfeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National Laboratory for Optoelectronics (WNLO) and School of Optical and Electronic Information, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), 1037 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei 430074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Optics Valley Smart Industrial Park, East Lake High-tech Development Zone, Wuhan China Star Optoelectronics Semiconductor Display Technology Co. Ltd., NO. 8 Zuoling Road, Wuhan, Hubei Province 430078, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Jiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2574-2943</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National Laboratory for Optoelectronics (WNLO) and School of Optical and Electronic Information, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), 1037 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei 430074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Jiajun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8358-5440</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan National Laboratory for Optoelectronics (WNLO) and School of Optical and Electronic Information, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), 1037 Luoyu Road, Wuhan, Hubei 430074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41686890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12904160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adz9942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shibata M., Sakai Y., Yokoyama D., Advantages and disadvantages of vacuum-deposited and spin-coated amorphous organic semiconductor films for organic light-emitting diodes. J. Mater. Chem. 3, 11178&#x2013;11191 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budida J., Srinivasan K., Review of thin film deposition and techniques. Mater. Today Proc. 92, 1030&#x2013;1033 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Qayyum M. F., Wu C., Whited M. T., Djurovich P. I., Hodgson K. O., Hedman B., Solomon E. I., Thompson M. E., A codeposition route to CuI&#x2212;pyridine coordination complexes for organic light-emitting diodes. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 133, 3700&#x2013;3703 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3066052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21366248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Du P., Guo Q., Sun L., Shen Z., Zhu J., Dong C., Wang L., Zhang X., Li L., Yang C., Pan J., Liu Z., Xia B., Xiao Z., Du J., Song B., Luo J., Tang J., Efficient all-thermally evaporated perovskite light-emitting diodes for active-matrix displays. Nat. Photonics 17, 435&#x2013;441 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calisi N., Galvanetto E., Borgioli F., Martinuzzi S. M., Bacci T., Caporali S., Thin films deposition of fully inorganic metal halide perovskites: A review. Mater. Sci. Semicond. Process. 147, 106721 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J., Li J., Grater L., Guo R., Mohd Yusoff A. R. B., Sargent E., Tang J., Vapour-deposited perovskite light-emitting diodes. Nat. Rev. Mater. 9, 282&#x2013;294 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au V. K.-M., Organic light-emitting diodes based on luminescent self-assembled materials of copper(I). Energy Fuels 35, 18982&#x2013;18999 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J.-J., Feng L.-Z., Shi G., Yang J.-N., Zhang Y.-D., Xu H., Song K.-H., Chen T., Zhang G., Zheng X.-S., Fan F., Xiao Z., Yao H.-B., High efficiency warm-white light-emitting diodes based on copper&#x2013;iodide clusters. Nat. Photonics 18, 200&#x2013;206 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Xu H., Electroluminescent clusters. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 63, e202317597 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38078881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamze R., Peltier J. L., Sylvinson D., Jung M., Cardenas J., Haiges R., Soleilhavoup M., Jazzar R., Djurovich P. I., Bertrand G., Thompson M. E., Eliminating nonradiative decay in Cu(I) emitters: &gt;99% quantum efficiency and microsecond lifetime. Science 363, 601&#x2013;606 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30733411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D., Zhu M., He Y., Cao Q., Gao Y., Li H., Lu G., Cui Q., Shen Y., He H., Dai X., Ye Z., Efficient and bright broadband electroluminescence based on environment-friendly metal halide nanoclusters. Light Sci. Appl. 13, 82 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10999448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38584197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford P. C., Cariati E., Bourassa J., Photoluminescence properties of multinuclear copper(I) compounds. Chem. Rev. 99, 3625&#x2013;3648 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11849032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z., Jin R., On the ligand&#x2019;s role in the fluorescence of gold nanoclusters. Nano Lett. 10, 2568&#x2013;2573 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20550101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie M., Han C., Liang Q., Zhang J., Xie G., Xu H., Highly efficient sky blue electroluminescence from ligand-activated copper iodide clusters: Overcoming the limitations of cluster light-emitting diodes. Sci. Adv. 5, eaav9857 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6588361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31245537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du P., Li J., Wang L., Sun L., Wang X., Xu X., Yang L., Pang J., Liang W., Luo J., Ma Y., Tang J., Efficient and large-area all vacuum-deposited perovskite light-emitting diodes via spatial confinement. Nat Commun. 12, 4751 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8346511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34362915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troyano J., Zamora F., Delgado S., Copper(I)&#x2013;iodide cluster structures as functional and processable platform materials. Chem. Soc. Rev. 50, 4606&#x2013;4628 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaskar A., Chen H.-F., Wong K.-T., Bipolar host materials: A chemical approach for highly efficient electrophosphorescent devices. Adv. Mater. 23, 3876&#x2013;3895 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21805507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai C., Su S.-H., Chiba T., Sasabe H., Pu Y.-J., Nakayama K., Kido J., High-efficiency red, green and blue phosphorescent homojunction organic light-emitting diodes based on bipolar host materials. Org. Electron. 12, 843&#x2013;850 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Zhang T., Ni T., Jiang N., Liu Z., Bian Z., Lu Z., Huang C., Co-deposited Cu(I) complex for tri-layered yellow and white organic light-emitting diodes. Adv. Funct. Mater. 24, 5385&#x2013;5392 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofbeck T., Monkowius U., Yersin H., Highly efficient luminescence of Cu(I) compounds: Thermally activated delayed fluorescence combined with short-lived phosphorescence. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 137, 399&#x2013;404 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25486064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Li N., Gong Z., Man Y., Zhong C., Duan C., Chen S., Zhang J., Han C., Xu H., Ligand-mediate exciton allocation enables efficient cluster-based white light-emitting diodes via single and heavy doping. Nat Commun. 15, 4997 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11169358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38866737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Svilainis, &#x201c;LEDs for projectors,&#x201d; in <i>Nitride Semiconductor Light-Emitting Diodes (LEDs)</i> (Elsevier, 2018), pp. 737&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S. K., Lampande R., Kwon J., Electro-optically efficient and thermally stable multilayer semitransparent pristine Ag cathode structure for top-emission organic light-emitting diodes. ACS Photonics 6, 2957&#x2013;2965 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulovi&#x107; V., Khalfin V. B., Gu G., Burrows P. E., Garbuzov D. Z., Forrest S. R., Weak microcavity effects in organic light-emitting devices. Phys. Rev. B 58, 3730 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Hsiang E.-L., Deng M.-Y., Wu S.-T., Mini-LED, Micro-LED and OLED displays: Present status and future perspectives. Light Sci. Appl. 9, 105 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7303200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32577221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Reinhard, &#x201c;High dynamic range imaging,&#x201d; in <i>Computer Vision: A Reference Guide</i> (Springer, 2020), pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravel B., Newville M., 
<i>ATHENA, ARTEMIS, HEPHAESTUS</i>: Data analysis for x-ray absorption spectroscopy using <i>IFEFFIT</i>. J. Synchrotron Radiat.
12, 
537&#x2013;541 (2005).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15968136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabinsky S. I., Rehr J. J., Ankudinov A., Albers R. C., Eller M. J., Multiple-scattering calculations of x-ray-absorption spectra. Phys. Rev. B 52, 2995&#x2013;3009 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9981373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang K.-M., Hsu B.-W., Chang Y.-A., Yang L., Tsai W.-L., Lin H.-W., Vacuum-deposited organometallic halide perovskite light-emitting devices. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 9, 40516&#x2013;40522 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29076335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim N., Shin M., Jun S., Choi B., Kim J., Park J., Kim H., Jung W., Lee J.-Y., Cho Y.-H., Shin B., 
Highly efficient vacuum-evaporated CsPbBr<sub>3</sub> perovskite light-emitting diodes with an electrical conductivity enhanced polymer-assisted passivation layer. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces
13, 
37323&#x2013;37330 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34337932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu C., Dumont A., Li P., Lu Z.-L., Thermally stable charge transport materials for vapor-phase fabrication of perovskite devices. Adv. Photonics Res. 2, 2000140 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh C.-A., Tan G.-H., Chuang Y.-T., Lin H.-C., Lai P.-T., Jan P.-E., Chen B.-H., Lu C.-H., Yang S.-D., Hsiao K.-Y., Lu M.-Y., Chen L.-Y., Lin H.-W., Vacuum-deposited inorganic perovskite light-emitting diodes with external quantum efficiency exceeding 10% via composition and crystallinity manipulation of emission layer under high vacuum. Adv. Sci. 10, 2206076 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10074115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36748267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Q., Wang L., Yang L., Duan J., Du H., Ji G., Liu N., Zhao X., Chen C., Xu L., Spectra stable deep-blue light-emitting diodes based on cryolite-like cerium(III) halides with nanosecond d-f emission. Sci. Adv. 8, eabq2148 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9757739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36525491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Du H., Li J., Luo Y., Lin X., Pang J., Liu Y., Gao L., He S., Kang J.-W., Liang W., Song H., Luo J., Tang J., Efficient deep-blue electroluminescence from Ce-based metal halide. Nat. Commun. 15, 6240 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11269580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39048553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo G., Jung H., Creason T. D., Yeddu V., Bamidele M., Echeverria E., Lee J., Mcilroy D., Saparov B., Kim D. Y., Lead-free halide light-emitting diodes with external quantum efficiency exceeding 7% using host&#x2013;dopant strategy. ACS Energy Lett. 6, 2584&#x2013;2593 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Qiu J., Wang Z., Liu Y., Wang Z., Liu Z., Bian Z., Lu Z., Huang C., High efficiency organic light-emitting diodes with in situ synthesized Cu(I) complex emitter: How to do chemical reaction in a vacuum chamber? Org. Electron. 37, 421&#x2013;427 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Qiu J., Wei F., Wang J., Liu X., Helander M. G., Rodney S., Wang Z., Bian Z., Lu Z., Thompson M., Huang C., Simple and high efficiency phosphorescence organic light-emitting diodes with codeposited copper(I) emitter. Chem. Mater. 26, 2368&#x2013;2373 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei F., Zhang T., Liu X., Li X., Jiang N., Liu Z., Bian Z., Zhao Y., Lu Z., Huang C., 
Efficient nondoped organic light-emitting diodes with Cu<sup>I</sup> complex emitter. Org. Electron.
15, 
3292&#x2013;3297 (2014).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>