<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41436762</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reservoir characterization and rock typing of the gas-bearing El Wastani Formation, Simian Field, offshore Nile Delta.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>44414</StartPage><MedlinePgn>44414</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">44414</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-31825-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Accurate prediction of reservoir performance in heterogeneous, clay-rich clastic systems remains a critical challenge in petrophysics. This study presents a novel, integrated workflow to overcome this challenge by delineating hydraulic flow units (HFUs) for robust rock typing and permeability prediction in the Pliocene El Wastani Formation, Simian field, offshore Nile Delta. Our methodology synergizes advanced petrophysical log analysis, conventional and special core analysis (SCAL), and sedimentological facies characterization to decipher controls on reservoir quality. The multi-technique approach included: spectral gamma ray (Th-K) cross-plots and Thomas-Stieber model analysis to characterize a dominant laminated illite/smectite clay assemblage; MDT pressure data to precisely define the Free Water Level at 2146&#xa0;m TVDSS; and Pickett plot analysis to determine a formation water resistivity (Rw) of 0.16 &#x3a9;.m. Core-based Flow Zone Indicator (FZI) analysis of 208 samples, identified six distinct HFUs, each defined by a unique, high-fidelity porosity-permeability transform (R<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.70-0.98). This hydraulic zonation, validated by stratified modified Lorenz (SML) analysis, showed a strong correlation with sedimentary facies, linking high-quality flow units (HFU-4, HFU-5) to high-energy channel deposits. The results quantitatively demonstrate that reservoir quality is primarily governed by the interplay of depositional environment and consequent pore architecture. The superior performance of the RQI/FZI method over the Pittman R35 technique establishes it as the preferred predictive model. This integrated workflow provides a transformative framework for characterizing heterogeneous reservoirs, ultimately enabling optimized well placement, enhanced recovery, and improved reservoir management decisions in the Nile Delta and analogous basins worldwide.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anwar</LastName><ForeName>Soliman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-3923-7640</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rashid Petroleum Company (Shell J.V), New Maadi, Cairo, 11742, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Kadi</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Geology Department, Al-Azhar University, Nasr City, P.O. Box 11884, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reda</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1255-8098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Geology Department, Al-Azhar University, Nasr City, P.O. Box 11884, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mostafa</LastName><ForeName>Taher</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3733-9353</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Geology Department, Al-Azhar University, Nasr City, P.O. Box 11884, Cairo, Egypt. taher_mostafa@azhar.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">El Wastani Formation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Flow zone indicator (FZI)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydraulic flow units (HFUs)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nile Delta</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Petrophysical analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reservoir characterization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rock typing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical statements: The manuscript has not been submitted or published anywhere, in whole or in part. In other words, the authors confirm that the article is unique. The manuscript will not be submitted to any other publication until the editorial process has been finished.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41436762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12738702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-31825-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-31825-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mamdouh, M., Othman, A. A. A. &amp; Mostafa, T. Multidisciplinary 3D geological-petrophysical reservoir characterization of Abu Sennan Field, Abu Gharadig Basin. <i>Egypt. Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 28896 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-13462-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12332090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40775263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abo Bakr, A., El Kadi, H. H. &amp; Mostafa, T. Petrographical and petrophysical rock typing for flow unit identification and permeability prediction in lower cretaceous reservoir AEB_IIIG, Western Desert. <i>Egypt. Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 5656 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-56178-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10920705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38454114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafa, T. et al. Exploring hydrocarbon potential with 3D modeling techniques: Lower Cretaceous formations in Abu Sennan field, North Western Desert. <i>Petroleum</i><b>11</b>, 158&#x2013;173 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petlm.2025.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, W. A., Deaf, A. S. &amp; Mostafa, T. 3D geological and petrophysical modeling of Alam El-Bueib formation using well logs and seismic data in Matruh field, northwestern Egypt. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 6849 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-56825-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10957879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38514735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beshry, S. <i>Reservoir Characterization of El Wastani Formation in Simian Channel, Simian Sienna Field, West Delta Deep Marine, Offshore Nile Delta, Egypt</i> (Menoufiya University, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwar, S., EL Kadi, H. H., Hosny, A., Reda, M. &amp; Mostafa, T. Identifying gas bearing sand using simultaneous pre-stack seismic inversion method: case study of the Simian field, Offshore Nile Delta. <i>Egypt. J. Pet. Explor. Prod. Technol.</i><b>15</b>, 1&#x2013;16 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kadi, H., Musaad, M. &amp; Mohamed, A.E.-S. Conventional and advanced petrophysical evaluation of pliocene sediments in Simian Field, Offshore Nile Delta. <i>Egypt. Delta J. Sci.</i><b>44</b>, 17&#x2013;34 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/djs.2022.119730.1014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aal, A. A. et al. Tectonic evolution of the Eastern Mediterranean Basin and its significance for hydrocarbon prospectivity in the ultradeepwater of the Nile Delta. <i>Lead. Edge</i><b>19</b>, 1086&#x2013;1102 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1190/1.1438485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eid, R., El-Anbaawy, M. &amp; Abdelhalim, A. Integrated seismic and well gamma-ray analysis for delineation Sienna channel depositional architecture, offshore West Nile Delta. <i>Egypt. NRIAG J. Astron. Geophys.</i><b>9</b>, 563&#x2013;571 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20909977.2020.1820267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross, N. E. et al. Three-dimensional seismic geomorphology of a deep-water slope-channel system: The Sequoia field, offshore west Nile Delta. <i>Egypt. Am. Assoc. Pet. Geol. Bull.</i><b>93</b>, 1063&#x2013;1086 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catterall, V., Redfern, J., Gawthorpe, R., Hansen, D. &amp; Thomas, M. Architectural style and quantification of a submarine Channel-Levee system located in a structurally complex area: Offshore Nile Delta. <i>J. Sediment. Res.</i><b>80</b>, 991&#x2013;1017 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2110/jsr.2010.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchum, R. M., Sangree, J. B., Vail, P. R. &amp; Wornardt, W. W. Recognizing sequences and systems tracts from well logs, seismic data, and biostratigraphy: examples from the Late Cenozoic of the Gulf of Mexico. (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval, B. C., Cramez, C. &amp; Vail, P. R. Stratigraphic cycles and major marine source rocks. <i>Mesozoic Cenozoic Seq. Stratigr. Eur. Basins at</i>10.2110/pec.98.02.0043 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2110/pec.98.02.0043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weimer, P. &amp; Slatt, R. M. <i>Petroleum Systems of Deepwater Settings</i> (Society of Exploration Geophysicists and European Association of Geoscientists and Engineers, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othman, A. A. A., Metwally, F., Fathy, M. &amp; Said, W. Reservoir characterization utilizing pre-stack inversion and artificial neural network techniques, Offshore Nile Delta. <i>Egypt. First Break</i><b>38</b>, 37&#x2013;42 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3997/1365-2397.fb2020086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said, W., Mohamed, I. A. &amp; Ali, A. <i>PSEnhancing Pre-Stack Seismic Inversion Using Neural Networks for Clastic Reservoir Characterization--Simian Field</i>. (Offshore Nile Delta, Egypt). (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atlas, D. Log interpretation charts. (1979).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basal, A. M. Analytical treatment of neutron-density crossplot for shaly sand reservoirs. <i>J. King Abdulaziz Univ. Earth Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 115&#x2013;142 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4197/Ear.10-1.8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke, J. A., Campbell, R. L. Jr. &amp; Schmidt, A. W. The litho-porosity cross plot a method of determining rock characteristics for computation of log data. In <i>SPE Illinois Basin Regional Meeting SPE-2771</i> (eds Burke, J. A. et al.) (SPE, 1969).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abukliesh, M., Mostafa, T., El Din, Z. &amp; Abdelhafeez, T. H. Integrating well logs and core data for better reservoir characterization of Mamuniyat formation, Murzuq Basin, Libya. <i>Iraqi Geol. J.</i> 1&#x2013;10 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asquith, G. &amp; Krygowski, D. <i>Basic Well Log Analysis</i> (The American Association of Petroleum Geologists, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worthington, P. F. The evolution of shaly-sand concepts in reservoir evaluation. <i>Log Anal.</i><b>26</b>, (1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clavier, C., Coates, G. &amp; Dumanoir, J. Theoretical and experimental bases for the dual-water model for interpretation of shaly sands. <i>Soc. Pet. Eng. J.</i><b>24</b>, 153&#x2013;168 (1984).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/6859-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limited, S. <i>Schlumberger Log Interpretation Charts</i> (Schlumberger, 1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, E. C. &amp; Stieber, S. J. The Distribution Of Shale In Sandstones And Its Effect Upon Porosity. <i>SPWLA 16th Annual Logging Symposium</i> SPWLA-1975-T at (1975).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud, H. M. &amp; Abou Ashour, N. M. H. An integrated approach for petrophysical evaluation of Shaly sand reservoirs in simian field, Nile Delta, Egypt. <i>Egypt. J. Geol.</i><b>64</b>, 73&#x2013;89 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/egjg.2020.215449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archie, G. E. The electrical resistivity log as an aid in determining some reservoir characteristics. <i>SPE Repr. Ser.</i> 9&#x2013;18 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poupon, A. &amp; Leveaux, J. Evaluation of water saturation in shaly formations. in <i>SPWLA Annual Logging Symposium</i> SPWLA-1971 (SPWLA, 1971).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiab, D. &amp; Donaldson, E. C. <i>Petrophysics: Theory and Practice of Measuring Reservoir Rock and Fluid Transport Properties</i> (Elsevier, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worden, R. H. &amp; Morad, S. Clay minerals in sandstones: Controls on formation, distribution and evolution. <i>Clay Mineral Cements Sandstones</i>10.1002/9781444304336.ch1 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781444304336.ch1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHardy, W. J., Wilson, M. J. &amp; Tait, M. Electron microscope and X-ray diffraction studies of filamentous illitic clay from sandstones of the Magnus Field. <i>Clay Miner.</i><b>17</b>, 23&#x2013;40 (1982).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1180/claymin.1982.017.1.04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, M. D. &amp; Pittman, E. D. Authigenic clays in sandstones; recognition and influence on reservoir properties and paleoenvironmental analysis. <i>J. Sediment. Res.</i><b>47</b>, 3&#x2013;31 (1977).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neasham, J. W. The morphology of dispersed clay in sandstone reservoirs and its effect on sandstone shaliness, pore space and fluid flow properties. In <i>SPE Annual Technical Conference and Exhibition?</i> SPE-6858 (SPE, 1977).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjorlykke, K. <i>Petroleum Geoscience: From Sedimentary Environments to Rock Physics</i> (Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carman, P. C. Fluid flow through granular beds. <i>Trans. Inst. Chem. Eng. London</i><b>15</b>, 150&#x2013;156 (1937).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozeny, J. Ueber kapillare leitung des wassers im boden. <i>Sitzungsberichte der Akad. der Wissenschaften Wien</i><b>136</b>, 271 (1927).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunter, G. W., Finneran, J. M., Hartmann, D. J. &amp; Miller, J. D. Early determination of reservoir flow units using an integrated petrophysical method. in <i>SPE Annual Technical Conference and Exhibition?</i> SPE-38679 (SPE, 1997).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>