<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41460845</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1708-8240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of esthetic and restorative dentistry : official publication of the American Academy of Esthetic Dentistry ... [et al.]</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Esthet Restor Dent</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Esthetic Biological Contour (EBC) Concept 2.0: How to Manage Each Zone of the Implant Restoration Emergence Profile.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jerd.70086</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Dental implants are at a biological disadvantage compared to natural teeth due to differences in the peri-implant mucosal architecture. Proper design of the prosthetic implant components plays an essential role in maintaining stable hard and soft tissues around implants. The Esthetic Biological Contour (EBC) zones have been described as a structured framework for understanding and managing the peri-implant emergence profile. Appropriate morphology, material selection, and surface treatment within each zone can enhance both esthetic and biological outcomes. This article illustrates a zone-by-zone guide for the design and management of the emergence profile of implant restorations, integrating esthetic, mechanical, and biological principles.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CONSIDERATIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Emergence profile design depends on multiple factors, including the three-dimensional position of the implant and the volume and quality of peri-implant soft tissues. A comprehensive understanding of how prosthetic decisions influence peri-implant health is essential for minimizing the risk of biological and esthetic complications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A well-designed emergence profile promotes the long-term stability of the peri-implant tissues and directly influences the esthetic and biological success of implant therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esquivel</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9428-665X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Private Practice, Metairie, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meda</LastName><ForeName>Ramon Gomez</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Private Practice, Meda Dental Institute, Ponferrada, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strauss</LastName><ForeName>Franz J</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5832-7327</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic of Reconstructive Dentistry, Center of Dental Medicine, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidad Autonoma de Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blatz</LastName><ForeName>Markus B</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6341-7047</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Professor of Restorative Dentistry, Chairman, Department of Preventive and Restorative Sciences, Assistant Dean for Digital Innovation and Professional Development, University of Pennsylvania School of Dental Medicine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Esthet Restor Dent</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101096515</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1496-4155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental implant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emergence profile</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prosthodontics</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41460845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jerd.70086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>T. Berglundh, J. Lindhe, I. Ericsson, C. P. Marinello, B. Liljenberg, and P. Thornsen, &#x201c;The Soft Tissue Barrier at Implants and Teeth,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 2 (1991): 81&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. S. Moon, T. Berglundh, I. Abrahamsson, E. Linder, and J. Lindhe, &#x201c;The Barrier Between the Keratinized Mucosa and the Dental Implant. An Experimental Study in the Dog,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 26 (1999): 658&#x2013;663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Al Rezk, G. Trimpou, H. C. Lauer, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Response of Soft Tissue to Different Abutment Materials With Different Surface Topographies: A Review of the Literature,&#x201d; General Dentistry 66 (2018): 18&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Fabbri and R. Sorrentino, &#x201c;A Biologically Driven Concept to Design the Emergence Profile Around Dental Implants: Surgical and Prosthetic Considerations to Optimize Hard and Soft Tissue Integration,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 41 (2021): 913&#x2013;921, https://doi.org/10.11607/prd.5063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Derks and C. Tomasi, &#x201c;Peri&#x2010;Implant Health and Disease. A Systematic Review of Current Epidemiology,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 42, no. S16 (2015), https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpe.12334.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. J. Strauss, J. Y. Park, J. S. Lee, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Wide Restorative Emergence Angle Increases Marginal Bone Loss and Impairs Integrity of the Junctional Epithelium of the Implant Supracrestal Complex: A Preclinical Study,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 51 (2024): 1677&#x2013;1687, https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpe.14070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Monje, J. Y. Kan, and W. Borgnakke, &#x201c;Impact of Local Predisposing/Precipitating Factors and Systemic Drivers on Peri&#x2010;Implant Diseases,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 25, no. 4 (2023): 640&#x2013;660, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.13155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Mattheos, M. Janda, A. Acharya, S. Pekarski, and C. Larsson, &#x201c;Impact of Design Elements of the Implant Supracrestal Complex (ISC) on the Risk of Peri&#x2010;Implant Mucositis and Peri&#x2010;Implantitis: A Critical Review,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 32, no. 21 (2021): 181&#x2013;202, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Mattheos, I. Vergoullis, M. Janda, and A. Miseli, &#x201c;The Implant Supracrestal Complex and Its Significance for Long&#x2010;Term Successful Clinical Outcomes,&#x201d; International Journal of Prosthodontics 34 (2021): 88&#x2013;100, https://doi.org/10.11607/ijp.7201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Gomez&#x2010;Meda, J. Esquivel, and M. B. Blatz, &#x201c;The Esthetic Biological Contour Concept for Implant Restoration Emergence Profile Design,&#x201d; Journal of Esthetic and Restorative Dentistry 33, no. 1 (2021): 173&#x2013;184, https://doi.org/10.1111/jerd.12714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Su, O. Gonzalez&#x2010;Martin, A. Weisgold, and E. Lee, &#x201c;Considerations of Implant Abutment and Crown Contour: Critical Contour and Subcritical Contour,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 30 (2010): 335&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Mart&#xed;n, E. Lee, A. Weisgold, M. Veltri, and H. Su, &#x201c;Contour Management of Implant Restorations for Optimal Emergence Profiles: Guidelines for Immediate and Delayed Provisional Restorations,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 40 (2020): 61&#x2013;70, https://doi.org/10.11607/prd.4422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Esquivel, R. Gomez Meda, and M. Villarroel, &#x201c;Timing Implant Provisionalization: Decision&#x2010;Making and Systematic Workflow,&#x201d; Journal of Esthetic and Restorative Dentistry 36 (2024): 858&#x2013;867, https://doi.org/10.1111/jerd.13197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. E. Jung, I. Sailer, C. H. H&#xe4;mmerle, T. Attin, and P. Schmidlin, &#x201c;In Vitro Color Changes of Soft Tissues Caused by Restorative Materials,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 27 (2007): 251&#x2013;257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Y. Kan, K. Rungcharassaeng, J. L. Lozada, and G. Zimmerman, &#x201c;Facial Gingival Tissue Stability Following Immediate Placement and Provisionalization of Maxillary Anterior Single Implants: A 2&#x2010; To 8&#x2010;Year Follow&#x2010;Up,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 26 (2011): 179&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Abrahamsson, T. Berglundh, and J. Lindhe, &#x201c;The Mucosal Barrier Following Abutment Dis/Reconnection. An Experimental Study in Dogs,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 24 (1997): 568&#x2013;572, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;051x.1997.tb00230.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Degidi, D. Nardi, and A. Piattelli, &#x201c;One Abutment at One Time: Non&#x2010;Removal of an Immediate Abutment and Its Effect on Bone Healing Around Subcrestal Tapered Implants,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 22, no. 11 (2011): 1303&#x2013;1307, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0501.2010.02111.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Koutouzis, G. Koutouzis, H. Gadalla, and R. Neiva, &#x201c;The Effect of Healing Abutment Reconnection and Disconnection on Soft and Hard Peri&#x2010;Implant Tissues: A Short&#x2010;Term Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial,&#x201d; International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants 28 (2013): 807&#x2013;814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. F. G. Pra&#xe7;a, R. C. Teixeira, and R. O. Rego, &#x201c;Influence of Abutment Disconnection on Peri&#x2010;Implant Marginal Bone Loss: A Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 31 (2020): 341&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Vat&#x117;nas and T. Linkevi&#x10d;ius, &#x201c;One Abutment One Time vs. Repeatable Abutment Disconnections in Implants, Restored With Cemented / Screw Retained Fixed Partial Dentures: Marginal Bone Level Changes. A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Stomatologija 23 (2021): 35&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Bressan, M. G. Grusovin, R. F. Visconti, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Influence of Repeated Abutment Changes on Peri&#x2010;Implant Tissue Stability and Keratinised Tissue on Peri&#x2010;Implant Health: 12&#x2010;Year Post&#x2010;Loading Results From a Multicentre Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontal Research 3 (2025): 373&#x2013;390, https://doi.org/10.1111/jre.13418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Bressan, M. G. Grusovin, F. D'Avenia, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Influence of Repeated Abutment Changes on Peri&#x2010;Implant Tissue Stability: 3&#x2010;Year Post&#x2010;Loading Results From a Multicentre Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; European Journal of Oral Implantology 10 (2017): 373&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Iglhaut, F. Schwarz, R. R. Winter, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Epithelial Attachment and Downgrowth on Dental Implant Abutments a Comprehensive Review,&#x201d; Journal of Esthetic and Restorative Dentistry 26 (2014): 324&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Saito, S. J. Chu, M. A. Reynolds, and D. P. Tarnow, &#x201c;Provisional Restorations Used in Immediate Implant Placement Provide a Platform to Promote Peri&#x2010;Implant Soft Tissue Healing: A Pilot Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 36 (2016): 47&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Rompen, N. Raepsaet, O. Domken, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Soft Tissue Stability at the Facial Aspect of Gingivally Converging Abutments in the Esthetic Zone: A Pilot Clinical Study,&#x201d; Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry 97 (2007): 119&#x2013;125, https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022&#x2010;3913(07)60015&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Siegenthaler, F. J. Strauss, F. Gamper, C. H. F. H&#xe4;mmerle, R. E. Jung, and D. S. Thoma, &#x201c;Anterior Implant Restorations With a Convex Emergence Profile Increase the Frequency of Recession: 12&#x2010;Month Results of a Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 49 (2022): 1145&#x2013;1157, https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpe.13696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Endres, F. J. Strauss, M. Siegenthaler, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Convex Versus Concave Emergence Profile of Implant&#x2010;Supported Crowns in the Aesthetic Zone: 3&#x2010;Year Results of a Randomized Controlled Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Periodontology 20 (2025): 1605&#x2013;1615, https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpe.70018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Camacho&#x2010;Alonso, J. C. Bernabeu&#x2010;Mira, J. S&#xe1;nchez, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Histological and Immunohistochemical Soft&#x2010;Tissue Response to Cylindrical and Concave Abutments: Multicenter Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontology 96 (2025): 418&#x2013;428, https://doi.org/10.1002/JPER.24&#x2010;0250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Esquivel, R. Gomez&#x2010;Meda, and M. B. Blatz, &#x201c;The Impact of 3D Implant Position on Emergence Profile Design,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 41 (2021): 79&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Fabbri, F. Mintrone, F. Aellos, and J. Lee, &#x201c;Defining the Biologic and Restorative Rooms for Implant Emergence Profile: A Concept for Clinical Implications and Its Impact on Hard and Soft Tissue Integration,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 0 (2025): 1&#x2013;32, https://doi.org/10.11607/prd.7779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Linkevicius and J. Vaitelis, &#x201c;The Effect of Zirconia or Titanium as Abutment Material on Soft Peri&#x2010;Implant Tissues: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 26 (2015): 139&#x2013;147, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.12631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Borie, D. Bosshardt, L. Liegeois, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Peri&#x2010;Implant Supracrestal Tissue Characteristics Related to Abutment Materials: A Comparative Histomorphometry Study,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 27 (2025): e70083, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.70083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. P. Nothdurft, D. Fontana, S. Ruppenthal, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Differential Behavior of Fibroblasts and Epithelial Cells on Structured Implant Abutment Materials: A Comparison of Materials and Surface Topographies,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 17, no. 6 (2015): 1237&#x2013;1249, https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Meyle, &#x201c;Proceedings of the 3rd European Workshop on Periodontology,&#x201d; in Cell Adhesion and Spreading on Different Implant Surfaces, ed. N. Lang, J. Lindhe, and T. Karring (Quintessence Publishing, 1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Rutkunas, V. Bukelskiene, V. Sabaliauskas, E. Balciunas, M. Malinauskas, and D. Baltriukiene, &#x201c;Assessment of Human Gingival Fibroblast Interaction With Dental Implant Abutment Materials,&#x201d; Journal of Materials Science. Materials in Medicine 26, no. 4 (2015): 169, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10856&#x2010;015&#x2010;5481&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Pandoleon, A. Bakopoulou, L. Papadopoulou, and P. Koidis, &#x201c;Evaluation of the Biological Behaviour of Various Dental Implant Abutment Materials on Attachment and Viability of Human Gingival Fibroblasts,&#x201d; Dental Materials 35 (2019): 1053&#x2013;1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Clavijo and A. Blasi, &#x201c;Decision&#x2010;Making Process for Restoring Single Implants,&#x201d; Quintessence of Dental Technology 40 (2017): 66&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Teughels, N. Van Assche, I. Sliepen, and M. Quirynen, &#x201c;Effect of Material Characteristics and/or Surface Topography on Biofilm Development,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 17 (2006): 68&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Brunot&#x2010;Gohin, J. L. Duval, E. E. Azogui, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Soft Tissue Adhesion of Polished Versus Glazed Lithium Disilicate Ceramic for Dental Applications,&#x201d; Dental Materials 29 (2013): e205&#x2013;e212, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dental.2013.05.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Brunot&#x2010;Gohin, J. L. Duval, S. Verbeke, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Biocompatibility Study of Lithium Disilicate and Zirconium Oxide Ceramics for Esthetic Dental Abutments,&#x201d; Journal of Periodontal &amp; Implant Science 46 (2016): 362&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. M. M. Alves, L. P. C. Contreras, M. G. Bueno, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Wear Performance of Glazed and Polished Full Contour Zirconia,&#x201d; Brazilian Dental Journal 30 (2019): 511&#x2013;518, https://doi.org/10.1590/0103&#x2010;6440201902801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Scotti, K. Zanini Kantorski, N. Scotti, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Early Biofilm Colonization on Polished&#x2010; and Glazed&#x2010;Zirconium Ceramic Surface. Preliminary Results,&#x201d; Minerva Stomatologica 55 (2006): 493&#x2013;502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Jung, M. M. Moser, J. Kleinheinz, and A. Happe, &#x201c;Biocompatibility of Lithium Disilicate and Zirconium Oxide Ceramics With Different Surface Topographies for Dental Implant Abutments,&#x201d; International Journal of Molecular Sciences 22 (2021): 7700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Mustafa, A. Od&#xe9;n, A. Wennerberg, K. Hultenby, and K. Arvidson, &#x201c;The Influence of Surface Topography of Ceramic Abutments on the Attachment and Proliferation of Human Oral Fibroblasts,&#x201d; Biomaterials 26 (2005): 373&#x2013;381, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biomaterials.2004.02.037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Chavali, C. P. Lin, and N. C. Lawson, &#x201c;Evaluation of Different Polishing Systems and Speeds for Dental Zirconia,&#x201d; Journal of Prosthodontics 26, no. 5 (2017): 410&#x2013;418, https://doi.org/10.1111/jopr.12396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Linkevicius, V. Valantiejiene, J. Alkimavicius, E. Gineviciute, R. Andrijauskas, and L. Linkeviciene, &#x201c;The Effect of a Polishing Protocol on the Surface Roughness of Zirconium Oxide,&#x201d; International Journal of Prosthodontics 33 (2020): 217&#x2013;223, https://doi.org/10.11607/ijp.6686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Pfefferle, N. L&#xfc;mkemann, F. Wiedenmann, and B. Stawarczyk, &#x201c;Different Polishing Methods for Zirconia: Impact on Surface, Optical, and Mechanical Properties,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Investigations 24, no. 1 (2020): 395&#x2013;403, https://doi.org/10.1007/s00784&#x2010;019&#x2010;02953&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Nomoto, M. Hirano, Y. Tsuyuki, T. Sakai, M. Yotsuya, and H. Sekine, &#x201c;Comparison of Polishing Methods for Two Types of Monolithic All&#x2010;Ceramic Crowns After Occlusal Adjustments: Polishing Paste Versus Glazed Porcelain,&#x201d; Dental Materials Journal 43, no. 5 (2024): 667&#x2013;671, https://doi.org/10.4012/dmj.2024&#x2010;058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Abdulmajeed, T. A. Sulaiman, A. A. Suliman, A. A. Abdulmajeed, and T. O. N&#xe4;rhi, &#x201c;Surface Roughness and Optical Characteristics Evaluations After Chairside Adjustment of Different Zirconia Types,&#x201d; Journal of Esthetic and Restorative Dentistry 36, no. 7 (2024): 1075&#x2013;1080, https://doi.org/10.1111/jerd.13246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Luchinskaya, R. Du, D. M. Owens, D. Tarnow, and N. Bittner, &#x201c;Various Surface Treatments to Implant Provisional Restorations and Their Effect on Epithelial Cell Adhesion &#x2010; A Comparative In&#xa0;Vitro Study,&#x201d; Implant Dentistry 26 (2017): 12&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Galindo&#x2010;Moreno, A. Le&#xf3;n&#x2010;Cano, I. Ortega&#x2010;Oller, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Prosthetic Abutment Height Is a Key Factor in Peri&#x2010;Implant Marginal Bone Loss,&#x201d; Journal of Dental Research 93 (2014): 80&#x2013;85, https://doi.org/10.1177/0022034513519800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Misch, S. Abu&#x2010;Reyal, D. Lohana, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Combined Effect of Abutment Height and Restoration Emergence Angle on Peri&#x2010;Implant Bone Loss Progression: A Retrospective Analysis,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 36 (2025): 600&#x2013;612, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.14408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Blanco, A. Pico, L. Caneiro, L. N&#xf3;voa, P. Batalla, and P. Mart&#xed;n&#x2010;Lancharro, &#x201c;Effect of Abutment Height on Interproximal Implant Bone Level in the Early Healing: A Randomized Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 29, no. 1 (2018): 108&#x2013;117, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. P&#xe9;rez&#x2010;Sayans, P. Castelo&#x2010;Baz, D. Penarrocha&#x2010;Oltra, F. Seijas&#x2010;Naya, M. Conde&#x2010;Amboage, and J. M. Somoza&#x2010;Mart&#xed;n, &#x201c;Impact of Abutment Geometry on Early Implant Marginal Bone Loss. A Double&#x2010;Blind, Randomized, 6&#x2010;Month Clinical Trial,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 33 (2022): 1038&#x2013;1048, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Dib&#x2010;Zaitum, Y. Guadilla&#x2010;Gonz&#xe1;lez, J. Flores&#x2010;Fraile, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Effect Morphology and Surface Treatment of the Abutments of Dental Implants on the Dimension and Health of Peri&#x2010;Implant Biological Space,&#x201d; Materials (Basel) 22, no. 15 (2022): 4422.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Att, N. D. Yajima, M. Wolkewitz, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Influence of Preparation and Wall Thickness on the Resistance to Fracture of Zirconia Implant Abutments,&#x201d; Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research 14, no. 1 (2012): e196&#x2013;e203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. J. Park, J. H. Phark, and W. W. Chee, &#x201c;Evaluation of Fracture Resistance of Varying Thicknesses of Zirconia Around Implant Abutment Cylinders,&#x201d; Journal of Oral Implantology 43, no. 5 (2017): 328&#x2013;332, https://doi.org/10.1563/aaid&#x2010;joi&#x2010;D&#x2010;16&#x2010;00204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Matsuura, K. Komatsu, D. Chao, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Cell Type&#x2010;Specific Effects of Implant Provisional Restoration Materials on the Growth and Function of Human Fibroblasts and Osteoblasts,&#x201d; Biomimetics (Basel) 16 (2022): 243, https://doi.org/10.3390/biomimetics7040243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. C. Halim, P. Pesce, N. De Angelis, S. Benedicenti, and M. Menini, &#x201c;Comparison of the Clinical Outcomes of Titanium and Zirconia Implant Abutments: A Systematic Review of Systematic Reviews,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 11 (2022): 5052, https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm11175052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Pelekanos and I. Vergoullis, &#x201c;Clinical Advances in Implant Transmucosal Contouring for Single Implant Sites: Prosthetic and Biologic Considerations,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 43 (2023): 301&#x2013;310, https://doi.org/10.11607/prd.6054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Conejo, W. Isleem, P. J. Atria, J. M. Ayub, H. S. Baumgarten, and M. B. Blatz, &#x201c;Implant Position and Guided Placement for In&#x2010;House&#x2010;Produced CAD/CAM Restorations With Titanium (Ti)&#x2010;Bases,&#x201d; International Journal of Computerized Dentistry 26 (2023): 75&#x2013;88, https://doi.org/10.3290/j.ijcd.b3818287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Park, J. B. Lee, S. J. Heo, and E. J. Park, &#x201c;A Comparative Study of Gold UCLA&#x2010;Type and CAD/CAM Titanium Implant Abutments,&#x201d; Journal of Advanced Prosthodontics 6 (2014): 46&#x2013;52, https://doi.org/10.4047/jap.2014.6.1.46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Jaggers, A. M. Simons, and S. E. Badr, &#x201c;Abutment Selection for Anterior Single Tooth Replacement. A Clinical Report,&#x201d; Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry 69, no. 2 (1993): 133&#x2013;135, https://doi.org/10.1016/0022&#x2010;3913(93)90128&#x2010;b.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zarauz, J. Pitta, G. Pradies, and I. Sailer, &#x201c;Clinical Recommendations for Implant Abutment Selection for Single&#x2010;Implant Reconstructions: Customized vs Standardized Ceramic and Metallic Solutions,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 40 (2020): 31&#x2013;37, https://doi.org/10.11607/prd.3913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. A. T&#xe2;rtea, M. Ionescu, H. O. Manolea, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Comparative Study of Dental Custom CAD&#x2010;CAM Implant Abutments and Dental Implant Stock Abutments,&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Medicine 12 (2023): 2128, https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm12062128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. B. Guncu, G. Aktas, G. N. Guncu, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Clinical, Technical, and Radiologic Outcomes of 182 Implant&#x2010;Supported Zirconia Single Crowns Using Titanium&#x2010;Base Abutments: A Retrospective Study,&#x201d; International Journal of Prosthodontics 35, no. 4 (2022): 553&#x2013;559, https://doi.org/10.11607/ijp.7796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Ntovas, O. Ladia, A. Pachiou, V. Fehmer, and I. Sailer, &#x201c;In Vitro Assessment of Cementation of CAD/CAM Fabricated Prostheses Over Titanium Bases. A Systematic Review,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 35 (2024): 1203&#x2013;1225, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.14347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. D. Fiore, E. Stellini, C. Monaco, and B. Yilmaz, &#x201c;Clinical Outcome of Monolithic Zirconia on Bonded or Mechanically Retained Prefabricated Titanium&#x2010;Base: A 4&#x2010;Year Retrospective Study,&#x201d; Journal of Dentistry 150 (2024): 105350, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdent.2024.105350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. Nguyen, S. J. Lee, and J. D. Lee, &#x201c;Influence of Varying Titanium Base Abutment Heights on Retention of Zirconia Restorations: An In&#xa0;Vitro Study,&#x201d; Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry 130, no. 4 (2023): 604.e1&#x2013;604.e5, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2023.07.034.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Serino and C. Str&#xf6;m, &#x201c;Peri&#x2010;Implantitis in Partially Edentulous Patients: Association With Inadequate Plaque Control,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 20, no. 2 (2009): 169&#x2013;174, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0501.2008.01627.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Linkevicius, E. Vindasiute, A. Puisys, and V. Peciuliene, &#x201c;The Influence of Margin Location on the Amount of Undetected Cement Excess After Delivery of Cement&#x2010;Retained Implant Restorations,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 22 (2011): 1379&#x2013;1384, https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0501.2010.02119.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Sancho&#x2010;Puchades, D. Crameri, M. &#xd6;zcan, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;The Influence of the Emergence Profile on the Amount of Undetected Cement Excess After Delivery of Cement&#x2010;Retained Implant Reconstructions,&#x201d; Clinical Oral Implants Research 28 (2017): 1515&#x2013;1522, https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. F. Hinds, &#x201c;Custom Impression Coping for an Exact Registration of the Healed Tissue in the Esthetic Implant Restoration,&#x201d; International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry 17 (1997): 584&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Papaspyridakos, A. Mariano, A. De Souza, et&#xa0;al., &#x201c;Digital Workflow With a Triple Scanning Technique for Implant Rehabilitation in the Esthetic Zone,&#x201d; Compendium of Continuing Education in Dentistry 41 (2020): e5&#x2013;e9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>