<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41275195</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of mHealth application on improving childhood immunization coverage and timeliness: a case of the Gurage Zone, SNNPR, Ethiopia, a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4424</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4424</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4424</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-025-25680-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Ethiopia has achieved remarkable decreases in under-5, infant, and neonatal mortality and has reached the target of MDG four three years ahead of the deadline, but child and infant health issues continue to result in high rates of mortality and morbidity. Therefore, to improve child and infant health services and accelerate the achievement of the Sustainable Development Goals, it is imperative that an innovative and cost-effective strategy be developed. Previous studies have found that the implementation of digital health technology, particularly through mobile health technology, such as short message reminder systems, has enhanced vaccination coverage and increased the demand for routine vaccinations in children among low- and middle-income countries. However, there is a paucity of research on the effect of mHealth applications on improving routine childhood immunization coverage and timeliness in the Gurage Zone, SNNPR, Southwest Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A randomized controlled trial with two arms and a parallel design was conducted with 408 mother-infant pairs. Using simple randomization, 204 mother-infant pairs from selected health institutions were assigned to the intervention group, which received routine health education and short message service reminders, and 204 mother-infant pairs to the control group, which received only routine health education. Mother-infant pairs were used as the randomization units and were randomized 1:1 into one of the two study arms. The data were exported to STATA version 14 statistical software for analysis after being cleaned and coded in EpiData version 4.1. The descriptive statistics were calculated first. To compare outcomes between study groups, log-binomial regression analyses and two-sample tests of proportions were employed. Variables were considered statistically significant when their <i>p</i>-value was less than 0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Four hundred mother-infant pairs were enrolled in the trial, 200 of whom were in the control group and 200 of whom were in the intervention group. Eight mother-infant pairs were excluded from the analysis as they had been relocated outside the study area. Compared with the control group, a higher percentage of infants in the intervention group received Penta 1, 199 (99.5%) vs. 191 (95.5%), Penta 2, 192 (96%) vs. 157 (78.5%), and Penta 3, 172 (86%) vs. 133 (66.5%). At 14&#xa0;weeks, the Penta 3 vaccine was administered to 172 (86%) and 133 (66.5%) infants in the intervention and control groups, respectively. The corresponding risk ratio (RR) was 1.29, with 95% CIs (1.15&#x2013;1.45; <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Additionally, the Penta 3 vaccine was administered on time to 159 (79.5%) and 123 (61.5%) infants in the intervention and usual care groups, respectively, with RRs of 1.29 and 95% CIs (1.13, 1.47; <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). In this study, 13.6% of infants in the intervention group and 31.4% in the control group dropped out of the Penta 3 immunization program. Despite a dropout rate exceeding an acceptable threshold, the intervention group demonstrated a significantly lower Penta 3 dropout rate than the control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Our research showed that using a mobile health application through SMS reminder system can increase vaccination timeliness and coverage and strengthen the quality and effectiveness of an immunization program. The intervention substantially improved both the uptake and timely administration of the Penta vaccines compared to usual care. It is therefore recommended that the intervention approach be integrated into routine immunization programs to enhance vaccination coverage and timeliness among infants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">Retrospective registration on the Pan African Clinical Trial Registry on March 24, 2025, PACTR202503488120509.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebreeyesus</LastName><ForeName>Fisha Alebel</ForeName><Initials>FA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Wolkite University, PO Box 07, Wolkite, Ethiopia. fishalebel@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Temere</LastName><ForeName>Bogale Chekole</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, School of Nursing and Midwifery, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Debre Birhan University, Debre Birhan, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amlak</LastName><ForeName>Baye Tsegaye</ForeName><Initials>BT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, DebreMarkos University, DebreMarkos, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarekegn</LastName><ForeName>Tadesse Tsehay</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Wolkite University, PO Box 07, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiferaw</LastName><ForeName>Bisrat Zeleke</ForeName><Initials>BZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Wolkite University, PO Box 07, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Emire</LastName><ForeName>Mamo Solomon</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Wolkite University, PO Box 07, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geleta</LastName><ForeName>Omega Tolessa</ForeName><Initials>OT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Wolkite University, PO Box 07, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Terefe</LastName><ForeName>Tamene Fetene</ForeName><Initials>TF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Injibara University, Injibara, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mewahegn</LastName><ForeName>Agerie Ayinalem</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Wolkite University, PO Box 07, Wolkite, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jimma</LastName><ForeName>Melkamu Senbeta</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Health Sciences, Assosa University, PoBox 18, Assosa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chanie</LastName><ForeName>Ermias Sisay</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Neonatal Nursing, College of Health Sciences, Debre Tabor University, PO Box 272, Debre Tabor, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Misganaw</LastName><ForeName>Natnael Moges</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Neonatal Nursing, College of Health Sciences, Debre Tabor University, PO Box 272, Debre Tabor, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lane-Krebs</LastName><ForeName>Katrina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Midwifery and Social Sciences, Central Queensland University, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gurage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SMS reminder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Text message reminder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was granted by the Ethical Review Committee of Wolkite University&#x2019;s College of Medicine and Health Sciences, reference RCSUILC/08/2013. Data were collected after written consent had been secured from the selected public health institutions, and study participants (mothers/caregivers) were asked to provide their informed written consent following detailed explanations of the study&#x2019;s aim, purpose, level of confidence, benefits, and potential risks. Participation in the study was entirely voluntary, and. all respondents were guaranteed complete confidentiality. The research was carried out in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41275195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12754971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-25680-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-025-25680-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fukuda-Parr S. From the millennium development goals to the sustainable development goals: shifts in purpose, concept, and politics of global goal setting for development. Gend Dev. 2016;24(1):43&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13552074.2016.1145895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaccines and immunization. Available from: https://www.who.int/health-topics/vaccines-and-immunization/#tab=tab_1. Cited 2 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Children&#x2019;s Fund (UNICEF). UNICEF immunization roadmap 2018&#x2013;2030. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Children&#x2019;s Fund. #Vac cinesWork: vaccines are safe and save lives. NewYork: UN NewsGlobalPerspective; 2019. https://vietnam.un.org/en/4017-unicef-launches-vaccineswork-campaign-inspire-support-vaccines.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbengue MA, Sarr M, Faye A, Badiane O, Camara FB, Mboup S, et al. Determinants of complete immunization among Senegalese children aged 12&#x2013;23 months: evidence from the demographic and health survey. BMC Public Health. 2017;17:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-017-4493-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5501441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28683781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Children&#x2019;s Fund. Child survival: under-five mortality. 2018. https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/under-five-mortality/. Accessed 16 Aug 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levels &amp; trends in child mortality: report 2021: estimates [Internet]. New York: United Nations Children&#x2019;s Fund (UNICEF); 2021 [cited 2025 Nov 18]. Available from: https://digitallibrary.un.org/record/3968643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frenkel LD. The global burden of vaccine preventable infectious diseases in children less than 5 years of age: can we do better. Adv Pediatr Res. 2020;7:2500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34474707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Machingaidze S, Wiysonge CS, Hussey GD. Strengthening the expanded programme on immunization in Africa: looking beyond 2015. PLoS Med. 2013;10(3):e1001405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1001405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3601964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23526886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan SB, Carnahan E, Shearer JC, Beylerian EN, Thompson J, Gilbert SS, et al. Redefining vaccination coverage and timeliness measures using electronic immunization registry data in low-and middle-income countries. Vaccine. 2019;37(13):1859&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2019.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6420680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30808566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World health organization Africa, business case for WHO immunization activities on the African continent 2018&#x2013;2030. https://www.afro.who.int/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bele O, Barakamfitiye DG. The ExpandedProgramonImmunizationin the WHOAfricanregion:current situation and implementation constraints. Sante. 1994;4(3):137&#x2013;42. PMID: 7921677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7921677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Immunization coverage. 2019. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/immunization-coverage. Accessed 22 Jul 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute EPH, ICF. Ethiopia mini demographic and health survey 2019: key indicators. Rockville: EPHI and ICF; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary TS, Reddy NS, Apte A, Sinha B, Roy S, Nair NP, et al. Delayed vaccination and its predictors among children under 2 years in India: insights from the national family health survey&#x2013;4. Vaccine. 2019;37(17):2331&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2019.03.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6996155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30914221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odutola A, Afolabi MO, Ogundare EO, Lowe-Jallow YN, Worwui A, Okebe J, et al. Risk factors for delay in age-appropriate vaccinations among Gambian children. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-015-1015-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4551385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26315547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fadnes LT, Nankabirwa V, Sommerfelt H, Tyllesk&#xe4;r T, Tumwine JK, Engebretsen IM, et al. Is vaccination coverage a good indicator of age-appropriate vaccination? A prospective study from Uganda. Vaccine. 2011;29(19):3564&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2011.02.093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21402043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babirye JN, Engebretsen IM, Makumbi F, Fadnes LT, Wamani H, Tylleskar T, et al. Timeliness of childhood vaccinations in Kampala Uganda: a community-based cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2012;7(4):e35432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0035432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3335141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22539972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne S, Townend J, Jasseh M, Lowe Jallow Y, Kampmann B. Achieving comprehensive childhood immunization: an analysis of obstacles and opportunities in The Gambia. Health Policy Plan. 2014;29(2):193&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapol/czt004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3944881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23426974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotkin SA. Vaccines: past, present and future. Nat Med. 2005;11(4S):S5-S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm1209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15812490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Extended Program on Immunization (EPI) coverage in selected Ethiopian zones: A baseline survey for L10K&#x2019;s Routine Immunization Improvement Initiative.&#xa0;https://l10k.jsi.com/Resources/Docs/EPI-baseline-report.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pertet AM, Wanjala C, Jaoko M, Odindo D, Kirika L. Completion, timeliness, and under-vaccination of childhood vaccinations in a nomadic pastoralist community of Kenya. Int J Contemp Pediatr. 2018;5(4):1162&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18203/2349-3291.ijcp20182530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>34. WHO/UNICEF. Ethiopia: WHO and UNICEF estimates of iimmunization coverage: 2017 revision. 2017. p. 1&#x2013;27. Available from: https://www.google.com/search?q=34.+WHO%2FUNICEF.+Ethiopia%3A+WHO+and+UNICEF+estimates+of+iimmunization+coverage%3A+2017+revision.+2017%3B1%E2%80%9327.&amp;oq=34.%09WHO%2FUNICEF.+Ethiopia%3A+WHO+and+UNICEF+estimates+of+iimmunization+coverage%3A+2017+revision.%092017%3B1%E2%80%9327.&amp;gs_lcrp=EgZjaHJvbWUyBggAEEUYOTIGCAEQRRg6MgYIAhBFGDzSAQgxNDIzajBqNKgCALACAQ&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8. Cited 16 May 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO). Global vaccine action plan 2011&#x2013;2020. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Animaw W, Taye W, Merdekios B, Tilahun M, Ayele G. Expanded program of immunization coverage and associated factors among children age 12&#x2013;23 months in Arba Minch town and Zuria District, Southern Ethiopia, 2013. BMC Public Health. 2014;14(1):464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-14-464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4032449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24884641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Epidemiology of the unimmunized child findings from the peer-reviewed published literature, 1999&#x2013;2009. Atlanta: Global Immunization Division Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadesse H, Deribew A, Woldie M. Predictors of defaulting from completion of child immunization in south Ethiopia, May 2008 &#x2013; a case control study. BMC Public Health. 2009;9(1):150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-9-150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2694177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19463164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maekawa M, Douangmala S, Sakisaka K, Takahashi K, Phathammavong O, Xeuatvongsa A, et al. Factors affecting routine immunization coverage among children aged 12&#x2013;59 months in Lao PDR after regional polio eradication in western Pacific region. Biosci Trends. 2007;1(1):43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20103866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M, Obaida-Nasrin S. Factors affecting acceptance of complete immunization coverage of children under five years in rural Bangladesh. Salud Publica Mex. 2010;52(2):134&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0036-36342010000200005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20485870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel TA, Pandit NB. Why infants miss vaccination during routine immunization sessions? Study in a rural area of Anand district, Gujarat. Indian J Public Health. 2011;55(4):321&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0019-557X.92417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22298144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haji A, Lowther S, Ngan&#x2019;ga Z, Gura Z, Tabu C, Sandhu H, et al. Reducing routine vaccination dropout rates: evaluating two interventions in three Kenyan districts, 2014. BMC Public Health. 2016;16(1):152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-2823-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4754928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26880141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutua MK, Kimani-Murage E, Ngomi N, Ravn H, Mwaniki P, Echoka E. Fully immunized child: coverage, timing and sequencing of routine immunization in an urban poor settlement in Nairobi, Kenya. Trop Med Health. 2016;44(1):13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-016-0013-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4940963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson DG, Kagucia EW, Ochieng B, Hariharan N, Obor D, Moulton LH, et al. The Mobile Solutions for Immunization (M-SIMU) trial: a protocol for a cluster randomized controlled trial that assesses the impact of mobile phone delivered reminders and travel subsidies to improve childhood immunization coverage rates and timeliness in western Kenya. JMIR Res Protoc. 2016;5(2):e72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/resprot.5030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4887657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domek GJ, Contreras-Roldan IL, O&#x2019;Leary ST, Bull S, Furniss A, Kempe A, et al. SMS text message reminders to improve infant vaccination coverage in Guatemala: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Vaccine. 2016;34(21):2437&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2016.03.065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4859823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27026145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazi AM, Ali M, Zubair K, Kalimuddin H, Kazi AN, Iqbal SP, et al. Effect of mobile phone text message reminders on routine immunization uptake in Pakistan: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Public Health Surveill. 2018;4(1):e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/publichealth.7026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29514773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazi AM. The role of mobile phone-based interventions to improve routine childhood immunisation coverage. Lancet Glob Health. 2017;5(4):e377-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(17)30088-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangure D, Chirundu D, Gombe N, Marufu T, Mandozana G, Tshimanga M, et al. Effectiveness of short message services reminder on childhood immunization programme in Kadoma, Zimbabwe - a randomized controlled trial, 2013. BMC Public Health. 2015;15(1):137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1470-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4339642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25885862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe9;glise C, Suggs LS, Odermatt P. SMS for disease control in developing countries: a systematic review of mobile health applications. J Telemed Telecare. 2012;18(5):273&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/jtt.2012.110810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22826375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan WA. Can the ubiquitous power of mobile phones be used to improve health outcomes in developing countries? Glob Health. 2006;2:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1744-8603-2-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1524730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16719925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilahun B, Smillie K, Bardosh KL, Murray M, Fitzgerald M, Cook V, et al. Identifying barriers and facilitators of 13 mHealth projects in North America and Africa: protocol for a 5-year implementation science study. JMIR Res Protoc. 2018;7(7):e9633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/resprot.9633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6053607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29970360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> mHealth: New horizons for health through mobile technologie | WHO | Regional Office for Africa [Internet]. 2025 [cited 2025 Nov 18]. Available from: https://www.afro.who.int/publications/mhealth-new-horizons-health-through-mobile-technologie.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FMOH. Ethiopian national eHealth strategy, 2014. Available: https://www.who.int/goe/policies/ethiopian_ehealth_strategy2014.pdf?ua=1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ETHIOPIA NATIONAL EXPANDED PROGRAMME ON IMMUNIZATION Federal Ministry of Health Addis Ababa [Internet]. 2015 [cited 2025 Nov 18]. https://extranet.who.int/countryplanningcycles/sites/default/files/country_docs/Ethiopia/ethiop_cmyp_latest_revised_may_12_2015.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Statistical Agency Addis Ababa E, The DHS Program ICF Rockville M, USA. ETHIOPIA Demographic and Health Survey 2016 Central Statistical Agency Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Key Indicators Report. 2016. https://preview.dhsprogram.com/pubs/pdf/SR241/SR241.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D, the CONSORT Group. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMC Med. 2010;8(1):18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-8-18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2860339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20334633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazi AM, Carmichael JL, Hapanna GW, Wang&#x2019;oo PG, Karanja S, Wanyama D, et al. Assessing mobile phone access and perceptions for texting-based mHealth interventions among expectant mothers and child caregivers in remote regions of Northern Kenya: a survey-based descriptive study. JMIR Public Health Surveill. 2017;3(1):e5386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/publichealth.5386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5306611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28137702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonnen ZA, Tilahun B, Alemu K, Were M. Effect of mobile phone text message reminders on improving completeness and timeliness of routine childhood vaccinations in North-West, Ethiopia: a study protocol for randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2019;9(11):e031254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-031254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6858152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31694849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonnen ZA, Gelaye KA, Were M, Tilahun B. Effect of Mobile Phone Text Message Reminders on the Completion and Timely Receipt of Routine Childhood Vaccinations: Superiority Randomized Controlled Trial in Northwest Ethiopia. JMIR MHealth UHealth. 2021;9(6):e27603. https://mhealth.jmir.org/2021/6/e27603/.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34128813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson DG, Ochieng B, Kagucia EW, Were J, Hayford K, Moulton LH, et al. Mobile phone-delivered reminders and incentives to improve childhood immunisation coverage and timeliness in Kenya (M-SIMU): a cluster randomised controlled trial. Lancet Glob Health. 2017;5(4):e428-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(17)30072-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5348605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman J, Black V, Thorson AE, Eriksen J. Evaluating the effect of maternal mHealth text messages on uptake of maternal and child health care services in South Africa: a multicentre cohort intervention study. Reprod Health. 2020;17(1):160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-020-01017-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7576764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33081795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oladepo O, Dipeolu IO, Oladunni O. Outcome of reminder text messages intervention on completion of routine immunization in rural areas, Nigeria. Health Promot Int. 2021;36(3):765&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/heapro/daaa092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8384379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33057615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibraheem R, Akintola M, Abdulkadir M, Ameen H, Bolarinwa O, Adeboye M. Effects of call reminders, short message services (SMS) reminders, and SMS immunization facts on childhood routine vaccination timing and completion in Ilorin, Nigeria. Afr Health Sci. 2021;21(2):951&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ahs.v21i2.57</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8568234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34795755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domek GJ, Contreras-Roldan IL, Bull S, O&#x2019;Leary ST, Bola&#xf1;os Ventura GA, Bronsert M, et al. Text message reminders to improve infant immunization in Guatemala: a randomized clinical trial. Vaccine. 2019;37(42):6192&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2019.08.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6761995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31492475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uddin MdJ, Shamsuzzaman Md, Horng L, Labrique A, Vasudevan L, Zeller K, et al. Use of mobile phones for improving vaccination coverage among children living in rural hard-to-reach areas and urban streets of Bangladesh. Vaccine. 2016;34(2):276&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2015.11.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4807732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26647290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen NT, Vu HM, Dao SD, Tran HT, Nguyen TXC. Digital immunization registry: evidence for the impact of mHealth on enhancing the immunization system and improving immunization coverage for children under one year old in Vietnam. mHealth. 2017;3:26&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/mhealth.2017.06.03</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5547172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28828373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekhaguere OA, Oluwafemi RO, Badejoko B, Oyeneyin LO, Butali A, Lowenthal ED, et al. Automated phone call and text reminders for childhood immunisations (PRIMM): a randomised controlled trial in Nigeria. BMJ Glob Health. 2019;4(2):e001232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2018-001232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6509606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31139442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timeliness of childhood vaccinations in Kampala Uganda: a community-based cross-sectional study. PLOS One. Available from: https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0035432. Cited 16 May 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3335141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22539972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Li Q, Chen Y. Timeliness of childhood primary immunization and risk factors related with delays: evidence from the 2014 Zhejiang provincial vaccination coverage survey. IJERPH. 2017;14(9):1086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph14091086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5615623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28930165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dissieka R, Soohoo M, Janmohamed A, Doledec D. Providing mothers with mobile phone message reminders increases childhood immunization and vitamin A supplementation coverage in C&#xf4;te d&#x2019;Ivoire: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Public Health in Africa. 2019;10(1). 10.4081/jphia.2019.1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/jphia.2019.1032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6589636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>