<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41711500</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1529-7535</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pediatric critical care medicine : a journal of the Society of Critical Care Medicine and the World Federation of Pediatric Intensive and Critical Care Societies</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Crit Care Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reconsidering Pediatric Critical Care Sequencing: A Qualitative Exploration of Postgraduate Year 1 PICU Rotations Among Senior Pediatric Residents.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PCC.0000000000003917</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Most pediatric residency programs introduce PICU rotations in postgraduate year (PGY) 2, although it is unclear whether this timing best supports trainees' skill development. Introduction during PGY1 may pose challenges due to clinical intensity, but could also have benefits in uniquely preparing residents for PGY2 responsibilities and autonomy. To address this question, this study explored the experiences and self-perceived impacts of a PGY1 PICU rotation among senior pediatric residents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A multi-institutional qualitative study was conducted using semi-structured interviews of senior (PGY2 and PGY3) residents who completed a PGY1 PICU rotation. Stratified purposive sampling was used at both institutional and resident levels. Data were coded using constant comparison and analyzed thematically.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Seven institutions requiring a 4-week PGY1 PICU rotation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Senior pediatric residents at participating institutions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">None.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MEASUREMENTS AND MAIN RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty-one interviews across seven institutions identified three key themes: 1) PGY1s can succeed in the PICU setting when supervisors actively cultivate a learning environment of inclusion, support, and appropriate autonomy; 2) PGY1 PICU rotations can foster self-perceived competence in skills that translate to the PGY2 year; and 3) Participants generally believed the benefits of early PICU exposure outweighed the challenges.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PGY1 PICU rotations can fall within the Zone of Proximal Development when the experience includes strong supervisory support. Findings highlighted the importance of psychologic safety for optimal learning, suggesting that strengthening psychologic safety may enhance the educational experience and outcomes. Further research exploring the impact of PGY1s on team dynamics and patient care, and comparing the effects of PGY1 vs. PGY2 introduction, could guide evidence-based recommendations on the optimal sequencing of PICU rotations for pediatric residents.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the Society of Critical Care Medicine and the World Federation of Pediatric Intensive and Critical Care Societies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Rachel R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8546-7456</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, New York University Grossman Long Island School of Medicine, Mineola, NY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flodman</LastName><ForeName>Kiersten</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lichak</LastName><ForeName>Brooke</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benoit</LastName><ForeName>Laelia</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asnes</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Child Safety, Advocacy, and Healing, Department of Pediatrics, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Osborn</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Pediatric Hospitalist Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watson</LastName><ForeName>Christopher M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Pediatric Critical Care Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Medical College of Georgia, Augusta, GA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuo</LastName><ForeName>Kevin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Pediatric Critical Care Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Stanford University School of Medicine, Palo Alto, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murtha</LastName><ForeName>Tanya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Critical Care, Department of Pediatrics, Warren Alpert Medical School of Brown University, Providence, RI.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brigham</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Pediatric Critical Care Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, West Virginia University School of Medicine, Morgantown, WV.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Priya N</ForeName><Initials>PN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Hospital Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Quillen College of Medicine, East Tennessee State University, Johnson City, TN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carney</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of General and Hospital Pediatrics, Department of Pediatrics, University of South Carolina School of Medicine-Columbia, Columbia, SC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gielissen</LastName><ForeName>Katherine A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Emory School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Crit Care Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100954653</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1529-7535</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical competence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">internship and residency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient care team</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric intensive care units</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr. Watson received funding from the Society of Critical Care Medicine. Dr. Gielissen received funding from the Yale Office Based Medicine Curriculum and the Society of General Internal Medicine Medical Education Scholars Faculty Development Program. The remaining authors have disclosed that they do not have any potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41711500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PCC.0000000000003917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00130478-990000000-00625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Johnson RR, Nagar R, Asnes A: Pediatric resident rotations in the pediatric and neonatal intensive care units. Poster session presented at: Association of Pediatric Program Directors 2024 Annual Spring Meeting; April 16&#x2013;19, 2024; Chicago, IL</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sewell JL, Maggio LA, Ten Cate O, et al.: Cognitive load theory for training health professionals in the workplace: A BEME review of studies among diverse professions: BEME guide no. 53. Med Teach 2019; 41:256&#x2013;270</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobel MC, Branson CF, Chipman JG, et al.: &#x201c;Who wants me to do what?&#x201d; Varied expectations from key stakeholder groups in the surgical intensive care unit creates a challenging learning environment. Am J Surg 2021; 221:394&#x2013;400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robillard N, Vincelette C: Barriers to workplace-based learning in the intensive care unit: A qualitative description of internal medicine residents&#x2019; and intensivists&#x2019; perspectives. Med Teach 2022; 44:629&#x2013;635</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gotlib Conn L, Haas B, Rubenfeld GD, et al.: Exclusion of residents from surgery-intensive care team communication: A qualitative study. J Surg Educ 2016; 73:639&#x2013;647</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe KK, Unti SM: Critical care rotation impact on pediatric resident mental health and burnout. BMC Med Educ 2017; 17:181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vygotsky LS: Mind and Society: The Development of Higher Psychological Processes. Cambridge, MA, Harvard University Press, 1978</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumagai AK: Discomfort, doubt, and the edge of learning. Acad Med 2022; 97:649&#x2013;654</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harden RM: What is a spiral curriculum? Med Teach 1999; 21:141&#x2013;143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolb DA: Experiential Learning: Experience As the Source of Learning and Development. Englewood Cliffs, NJ, Prentice-Hall, 1984</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backes CH, Bonachea EM, Rivera BK, et al.: Preparedness of pediatric residents for fellowship: A survey of US neonatal-perinatal fellowship program directors. J Perinatol 2016; 36:1132&#x2013;1137</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik RN, Langhan ML: Pediatric residency preparedness for pediatric emergency medicine fellowship. Pediatr Emerg Care 2022; 38:e1462&#x2013;e1468</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumacher DJ, Frintner MP, Cull W: Relationships between program size, training experience, and career intentions: Pediatrics resident reports from 2010 to 2014. Acad Pediatr 2016; 16:630&#x2013;637</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madill A, Jordan A, Shirley C: Objectivity and reliability in qualitative analysis: Realist, contextualist and radical constructionist epistemologies. Br J Psychol 2000; 91:1&#x2013;20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V: Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol 2006; 3:77&#x2013;101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiger ME, Varpio L: Thematic analysis of qualitative data: AMEE Guide No. 131. Med Teach 2020; 42:846&#x2013;854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson OC: Sampling in interview-based qualitative research: A theoretical and practical guide. Qual Res Psychol 2014; 11:25&#x2013;41</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln YS, Guba EG: Naturalistic Inquiry. Newbury Park, CA, Sage, 1985</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasileiou K, Barnett J, Thorpe S, et al.: Characterising and justifying sample size sufficiency in interview-based studies: Systematic analysis of qualitative health research over a 15-year period. BMC Med Res Methodol 2018; 18:148</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser BG: The constant comparative method of qualitative analysis. Soc Probl 1965; 12:436&#x2013;445</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J: Consolidated Criteria for Reporting Qualitative Research (COREQ): A 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care 2007; 19:349&#x2013;357</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trisukhon K, Thammasitboon S, Vaewpanich J, et al.: Workplace affordances and learning engagement in a Thai paediatric intensive care unit. Clin Teach 2024; 21:e13821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopstick AJ, Sanders BW, Felmet K, et al.: &#x201c;It&#x2019;s Kind of a Rite of Passage&#x201d;: An exploration into residents&#x2019; experience of learning in a critical care setting. J Grad Med Educ 2024; 16:701&#x2013;712</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RR, Shabanova V, Langhan ML: Insights into medical student pediatric intensive care unit rotations in developing essential skills for pediatric residency. Med Sci Educ 2025; 35:1195&#x2013;1201</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poeppelman RS, Moore-Clingenpeel M, Siems A, et al.: Faculty decision making in ad hoc entrustment of pediatric critical care fellows: A national case-based survey. Teach Learn Med 2025; 37:56&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almoosa KF, Goldenhar LM, Puchalski J, et al.: Critical care education during internal medicine residency: A national survey. J Grad Med Educ 2010; 2:555&#x2013;561</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education: ACGME Program Requirements for Graduate Medical Education in Pediatrics. 2025. Available at: https://www.acgme.org/globalassets/pfassets/programrequirements/2025-prs/320_pediatrics_2025_tcc.pdf. Accessed August 1, 2025</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>