<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41723434</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2407</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of nab-paclitaxel plus PD-1 inhibitor in elderly patients with advanced squamous lung cancer.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">411</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12885-026-15767-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">This study aimed to evaluate the clinical efficacy and safety of nab-paclitaxel in combination with PD-1 inhibitors in elderly patients with advanced squamous cell lung cancer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective analysis was performed on 40 elderly patients with advanced squamous cell lung cancer treated at the affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University between March 2020 and July 2024. Patients were assigned to either the chemotherapy group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;18), receiving nab-paclitaxel monotherapy, or the combination therapy group (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;22), receiving nab-paclitaxel plus a PD-1 inhibitor. Treatments were administered every three weeks (per cycle). Short-term efficacy and adverse events were evaluated after every 2&#x2013;3 cycles, and patients were followed up to assess the incidence of adverse reactions and clinical outcomes, including objective response rate (ORR), disease control rate (DCR), progression-free survival (PFS), and overall survival (OS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with the chemotherapy group, patients in the combination therapy group demonstrated improved clinical outcomes, including higher objective response rate(31.8% vs. 22.2%) and disease control rates (86.4% vs. 66.7%), as well as a longer median overall survival time (19 vs. 9 months). In addition, the combination therapy group exhibited significantly higher 6-month (100% vs. 77.8%) and 1-year (72.2% vs. 35.3%) survival rates. The most frequently observed adverse events were leukopenia, anemia, fatigue, nausea and vomiting, myalgia, cough, and interstitial pneumonia, all of which were generally manageable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Nab-paclitaxel combined with PD-1 inhibitors demonstrated superior short-term efficacy and an acceptable safety profile compared with chemotherapy alone in elderly patients with advanced squamous cell lung cancer.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Heya</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University, Zhangjiagang, Jiangsu Province, 215600, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University, Zhangjiagang, Jiangsu Province, 215600, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Siyuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University, Zhangjiagang, Jiangsu Province, 215600, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University, Zhangjiagang, Jiangsu Province, 215600, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Yanan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University, Zhangjiagang, Jiangsu Province, 215600, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University, Zhangjiagang, Jiangsu Province, 215600, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention of Suzhou High-tech Zone, Suzhou, 215010, Jiangsu Province, China. tzhuyzu@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, The Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University, Zhangjiagang, 215600, Jiangsu Province, China. sopheryanyan@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>KJXW2020059</GrantID><Agency>Suzhou Science and Education for Healthcare Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZKYL2435</GrantID><Agency>Zhangjiagang Science and Technology Bureau Medical and Health Science and Technology Innovation Guidance Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZKYL2547</GrantID><Agency>Zhangjiagang Science and Technology Bureau Medical and Health Science and Technology Innovation Guidance Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>CYTF2024055</GrantID><Agency>Jiangsu Provincial Society of Traditional Chinese Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>QNXM2025069</GrantID><Agency>Suzhou Youth Science and Technology Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>YJQN2020005</GrantID><Agency>Young Investigator Program of the Affiliated Zhangjiagang Hospital of Soochow University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2407</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Advanced squamous lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nab-paclitaxel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PD-1 inhibitor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Prior to the treatment, patients were informed about the procedures and provided their consent. Ethical approval for the study was obtained from the Medical Ethics Committee of Zhangjiagang First People&#x2019;s Hospital. Informed consent was taken from participants to participate in the study. This study was conducted in accordance with the principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki (archived version, DoH-Oct2013). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41723434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13032691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-026-15767-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12885-026-15767-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Siegel RL, Kratzer TB, Giaquinto AN, Sung H, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2025. Cancer J Clin. 2025;75(1):10&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11745215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39817679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smolarz B, &#x141;ukasiewicz H, Samulak D, Piekarska E, Ko&#x142;aci&#x144;ski R, Romanowicz H. Lung Cancer-Epidemiology, Pathogenesis, Treatment and Molecular Aspect (Review of Literature). Int J Mol Sci. 2025;26(5):2049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11900952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40076671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Gao H, Qi Z, Xu T, Wang G, Luo H, Cheng P. Prediction of immune subtypes and overall survival in lung squamous cell carcinoma. Curr Med Res Opin. 2023;39(2):289&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2022.2129231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36245361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satpathy S, Krug K, Jean Beltran PM, Savage SR, Petralia F, Kumar-Sinha C, Dou Y, Reva B, Kane MH, Avanessian SC, et al. A proteogenomic portrait of lung squamous cell carcinoma. Cell. 2021;184(16):4348&#x2013;e43714340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.07.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau SCM, Pan Y, Velcheti V, Wong KK. Squamous cell lung cancer: Current landscape and future therapeutic options. Cancer Cell. 2022;40(11):1279&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccell.2022.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36270277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Ma X, Yang Y, Ding Z, Luo Y. Successful treatment of an elderly patient with lung squamous cell carcinoma by tislelizumab and chemotherapy: a case report with novel imaging findings. Front Immunol. 2025;16:1543114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2025.1543114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11973309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40196110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Wang Q, Cao J, Fan C, Shen W, Xiao Q, Ge X, Zhang T, Liu X, Chen X, et al. Tislelizumab plus concurrent chemoradiotherapy versus concurrent chemoradiotherapy for elderly patients with inoperable locally advanced esophageal squamous cell carcinoma: a multicenter, randomized, parallel-controlled, phase II clinical trial. BMC Cancer. 2025;25(1):347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-025-13758-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11863415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40001034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Safi M, Hirsch FR, Lu S, Peters S, Govindan R, Rosell R, Park K, Zhang JJ. Immunotherapy for advanced-stage squamous cell lung cancer: the state of the art and outstanding questions. Nat reviews Clin Oncol. 2025;22(3):200&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41571-024-00979-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39762577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Rosell R, Hirsch FR, Lu S, Govindan R, Park K, Peters S, Zhang JJ. Emerging Options and Future Strategies in Immunotherapy for Advanced Lung Squamous Cell Carcinoma. Annals oncology: official J Eur Soc Med Oncol. 2025;37(3):289-313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41260258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forde PM, Spicer J, Lu S, Provencio M, Mitsudomi T, Awad MM, Felip E, Broderick SR, Brahmer JR, Swanson SJ, et al. Neoadjuvant Nivolumab plus Chemotherapy in Resectable Lung Cancer. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(21):1973&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2202170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9844511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35403841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto K, Yamada T, Yokoi T, Kijima T, Goto Y, Nakao A, Hibino M, Takeda T, Yamaguchi H, Takumi C, et al. Clinical impact of pembrolizumab combined with chemotherapy in elderly patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer. Lung cancer (Amsterdam Netherlands). 2021;161:26&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2021.08.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34500218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shroff GS, Strange CD, Ahuja J, Altan M, Sheshadri A, Unlu E, Truong MT, Vlahos I. Imaging of Immune Checkpoint Inhibitor Immunotherapy for Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer. Radiographics: Rev publication Radiological Soc North Am Inc. 2022;42(7):1956&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/rg.220108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36240075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Hu Y, Arkania E, Kilickap S, Ying K, Xu F, Wu L, Wang X, Viguro M, Makharadze T, et al. A global phase 3 study of serplulimab plus chemotherapy as first-line treatment for advanced squamous non-small-cell lung cancer (ASTRUM-004). Cancer Cell. 2024;42(2):198&#x2013;e208193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccell.2023.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38181795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst RS, Baas P, Kim DW, Felip E, P&#xe9;rez-Gracia JL, Han JY, Molina J, Kim JH, Arvis CD, Ahn MJ, et al. Pembrolizumab versus docetaxel for previously treated, PD-L1-positive, advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (KEYNOTE-010): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet (London England). 2016;387(10027):1540&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(15)01281-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26712084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok TSK, Wu YL, Kudaba I, Kowalski DM, Cho BC, Turna HZ, Castro G Jr., Srimuninnimit V, Laktionov KK, Bondarenko I, et al. Pembrolizumab versus chemotherapy for previously untreated, PD-L1-expressing, locally advanced or metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer (KEYNOTE-042): a randomised, open-label, controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet (London England). 2019;393(10183):1819&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32409-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30955977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellmann MD, Paz-Ares L, Bernabe Caro R, Zurawski B, Kim SW, Carcereny Costa E, Park K, Alexandru A, Lupinacci L. de la Mora Jimenez E : Nivolumab plus Ipilimumab in Advanced Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer. The New Eng J Med. 2019, 381(21):2020&#x2013;2031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socinski MA, Jotte RM, Cappuzzo F, Orlandi F, Stroyakovskiy D, Nogami N, Rodr&#xed;guez-Abreu D, Moro-Sibilot D, Thomas CA, Barlesi F, et al. Atezolizumab for First-Line Treatment of Metastatic Nonsquamous NSCLC. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(24):2288&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1716948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29863955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baladi A, Tafenzi HA, Zouiten O, Afani L, Essaadi I, El Fadli M, Belbaraka R. Immunotherapy for Elderly Patients with Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer: Challenges and Perspectives. Int J Mol Sci. 2025;26(5):2120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11899869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40076743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes F, Wong M, Battisti NML, Kordbacheh T, Kiderlen M, Greystoke A, Luciani A. Immunotherapy in older patients with non-small cell lung cancer: Young International Society of Geriatric Oncology position paper. Br J Cancer. 2020;123(6):874&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41416-020-0986-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7492214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32694695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi L, Rodr&#xed;guez-Abreu D, Gadgeel S, Esteban E, Felip E, De Angelis F, Domine M, Clingan P, Hochmair MJ, Powell SF, et al. Pembrolizumab plus Chemotherapy in Metastatic Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(22):2078&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1801005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novello S, Kowalski DM, Luft A, G&#xfc;m&#xfc;&#x15f; M, Vicente D, Mazi&#xe8;res J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Cid J, Tafreshi A, Cheng Y, Lee KH, et al. Pembrolizumab Plus Chemotherapy in Squamous Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer: 5-Year Update of the Phase III KEYNOTE-407 Study. J Clin oncology: official J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2023;41(11):1999&#x2013;2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.22.01990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10082300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36735893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan T, Li S, Hu W, Yue T, Zeng Q, Zeng X, Chen X, Zhao X, Xiao T. Efficacy and safety of nab-paclitaxel plus platinum in non-small cell lung cancer: a meta-analysis. Front Med. 2023;10:1139248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2023.1139248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10406255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37554498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang DY, Dmello C, Chen L, Arrieta VA, Gonzalez-Buendia E, Kane JR, Magnusson LP, Baran A, James CD, Horbinski C, et al. Ultrasound-mediated Delivery of Paclitaxel for Glioma: A Comparative Study of Distribution, Toxicity, and Efficacy of Albumin-bound Versus Cremophor Formulations. Clin cancer research: official J Am Association Cancer Res. 2020;26(2):477&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-19-2182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7050644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31831565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kratz F. Albumin as a drug carrier: design of prodrugs, drug conjugates and nanoparticles. J controlled release: official J Controlled Release Soc. 2008;132(3):171&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2008.05.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18582981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Zhao J, Ma Z, Cui J, Shu Y, Liu Z, Cheng Y, Leaw SJ, Wu Y, Ma Y, et al. A Phase 2 Study of Tislelizumab in Combination With Platinum-Based Chemotherapy as First-line Treatment for Advanced Lung Cancer in Chinese Patients. Lung cancer (Amsterdam Netherlands). 2020;147:259&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2020.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32769013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenhauer EA, Therasse P, Bogaerts J, Schwartz LH, Sargent D, Ford R, Dancey J, Arbuck S, Gwyther S, Mooney M, et al. New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1). Eur J cancer (Oxford England: 1990). 2009;45(2):228&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2008.10.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19097774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi S, Li J, Gu X, Zhang Y, Zhou W, Wang F, Wang W. Impacts of ageing on the efficacy of CAR-T cell therapy. Ageing Res Rev. 2025;107:102715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2025.102715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40058461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Cheng S, Zhang B, Zhong C. Burden of inflammatory bowel disease among elderly, 1990&#x2013;2019: A systematic analysis based on the global burden of disease study 2019. Autoimmun rev. 2025;24(2):103708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2024.103708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39586389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basch E, Reeve BB, Mitchell SA, Clauser SB, Minasian LM, Dueck AC, Mendoza TR, Hay J, Atkinson TM, Abernethy AP et al. Development of the National Cancer Institute&#x2019;s patient-reported outcomes version of the common terminology criteria for adverse events (PRO-CTCAE). J Natl Cancer Inst. 2014;106(9):dju244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4200059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25265940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uppal V, Retter S, Kehoe E, McKeen DM. Quadratus lumborum block for postoperative analgesia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Can J Anaesth = J canadien d&#x2019;anesthesie. 2020;67(11):1557&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12630-020-01793-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32808097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gridelli C. The ELVIS trial: a phase III study of single-agent vinorelbine as first-line treatment in elderly patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Elderly Lung Cancer Vinorelbine Italian Study. The Oncologist. 2001;6 Suppl 1:4&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11181997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almodovar T, Teixeira E, Barroso A, Soares M, Queiroga HJ, Cavaco-Silva J, Barata F. Elderly patients with advanced NSCLC: The value of geriatric evaluation and the feasibility of CGA alternatives in predicting chemotherapy toxicity. Pulmonology. 2019;25(1):40&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2018.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30266308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gridelli C, Perrone F, Gallo C, Cigolari S, Rossi A, Piantedosi F, Barbera S, Ferra&#xf9; F, Piazza E, Rosetti F, et al. Chemotherapy for elderly patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: the Multicenter Italian Lung Cancer in the Elderly Study (MILES) phase III randomized trial. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2003;95(5):362&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/95.5.362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Lu X, Lin Q, Li W. Is nab-paclitaxel better than conventional taxanes as neoadjuvant therapy for breast cancer? A meta-analysis. J Int Med Res. 2020;48(8):300060520943473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060520943473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7416144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>