<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41922389</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrating multi-spectral remote sensing and machine learning for quantifying and mapping heavy metal contamination in the Tarim River Basin, China.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-38887-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Heavy metal (HM) contamination in arid inland river basins is intensifying with economic development, posing ongoing ecological and public health risks. Conventional monitoring is constrained by landscape heterogeneity and limited field data, hindering basin-scale spatiotemporal analysis. This study integrates multispectral Sentinel&#x2011;2A imagery, Random Forest (RF) regression, and harmonized ground observations to quantify and map As, Cd, Cu, Pb, and Zn in soils and waters of China's Tarim River Basin (TRB), and to evaluate related health risks using the EPA model. Field data showed soil &#x3a3;HMs averaged 118.71&#xa0;mg kg&#x207b;&#xb9; (95.15-191.32&#xa0;mg kg&#x207b;&#xb9;) and river &#x3a3;HMs 3.89&#xa0;&#xb5;g L&#x207b;&#xb9; (1.14-99.00&#xa0;&#xb5;g L&#x207b;&#xb9;), with Cd and As above background levels. RF models yielded preliminary spatial patterns (R&#xb2; = 0.741-0.999; RMSE&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.12-0.38&#xa0;mg kg&#x207b;&#xb9; for soils, 0.21-0.57&#xa0;&#xb5;g L&#x207b;&#xb9; for waters). Spatial patterns revealed As and Cd hotspots in Aksu, Cu and Pb enrichment in central and southeastern sub&#x2011;basins, and Zn predominance in the east. Pearson correlation and principal component analyses attributed Pb-Cu-Zn mainly to natural sources and riverine metals to atmospheric deposition and hydrology. Oral ingestion was the major exposure route; ~10% of soil samples exceeded the non&#x2011;carcinogenic hazard index for children, while As and Cd posed carcinogenic risks&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;1&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10&#x207b;&#x2074;. The geo&#x2011;accumulation index (I_geo&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;2 for As) and HPI&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;100 in Hotan, Kashgar, and Aksu indicated localized hazards. Recommended actions include RS&#x2011;based quarterly monitoring, targeted As/Cd control, basin&#x2011;wide HM coordination, child health screening, and nature&#x2011;based remediation to reduce HM risks by 2035. This work provides the first high-resolution, basin-wide HM assessment in the TRB, demonstrating Sentinel-2A-RF inversion as a cost-effective tool for hotspot identification, risk-informed management, and alignment with China's dual-carbon goals, rural revitalization, and UN Sustainable Development Goals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Subsurface Hydrology and Ecological Effects in Arid Region, Ministry of Education, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Province Innovation and Introduction Base for Discipline of Urban and Rural Water Security and Rural Revitalization in Arid Areas, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Water and Environment, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Monitoring, Modelling and Early Warning of Watershed Spatial Hydrology International Science and Technology Cooperation Base, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Eco-hydrology and Water Security in Arid and Semi-arid Regions of the Ministry of Water Resources, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Mu</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Agricultural Development Group Co., Ltd.,, No. 7 Guangtai Road, High-tech Zone, Xi'an, 710075, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Pingping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Subsurface Hydrology and Ecological Effects in Arid Region, Ministry of Education, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China. lpp@chd.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Province Innovation and Introduction Base for Discipline of Urban and Rural Water Security and Rural Revitalization in Arid Areas, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China. lpp@chd.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Water and Environment, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China. lpp@chd.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Monitoring, Modelling and Early Warning of Watershed Spatial Hydrology International Science and Technology Cooperation Base, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China. lpp@chd.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Eco-hydrology and Water Security in Arid and Semi-arid Regions of the Ministry of Water Resources, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China. lpp@chd.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jianxin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710061, Shaanxi, China. zhangjx@chd.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rijal</LastName><ForeName>Madhab</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Subsurface Hydrology and Ecological Effects in Arid Region, Ministry of Education, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Province Innovation and Introduction Base for Discipline of Urban and Rural Water Security and Rural Revitalization in Arid Areas, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Water and Environment, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Monitoring, Modelling and Early Warning of Watershed Spatial Hydrology International Science and Technology Cooperation Base, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Eco-hydrology and Water Security in Arid and Semi-arid Regions of the Ministry of Water Resources, Chang'an University, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Zhihui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Environmental Science and Engineering, School of Metallurgy and Environment, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Chengguang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Transportatio, South China University of Technology, Guangzhou, 510641, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jiacha</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Engineering, Kyoto University, Katsura, Nishikyo-ku, Kyoto, 615-8530, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elbeltagi</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agricultural Engineering Department, Faculty of Agriculture, Mansoura University, Mansoura, 35516, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Razafindrabe</LastName><ForeName>Bam H N</ForeName><Initials>BHN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, University of the Ryukyus, 1 Senbaru, Nishihara, Okinawa, 903-0213 , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022xjkk010704</GrantID><Agency>Third Xinjiang Scientific Expedition Program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health risk assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heavy metals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Remote sensing inversion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable development</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tarim river basin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41922389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-38887-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-38887-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. S., Sun, H., Wang, L., Wu, Y. &amp; Wang, H. X, Pollution assessment and health risk of metals in surface soil near a Pb&#x2013;Zn mine, northeast China, Front. Environ. Sci., vol. no. 13, p. 1585272,https://doi.org/10.3389/fenvs.2025.1585272 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golan, G. I., Katzir, R., Sharabi, R. &amp; Nachshon, G. U, Soil contamination in arid environments and assessment of remediation applying surface evaporation capacitor model; a case study from the Judean Desert, Israel, EGUsphere, https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1014 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. R, Soil degradation and pollution as the global public health emergency. Med Res. Arch, 13, 5 https://doi.org/10.18103/mra.v13i5.6474, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahal, E. S. A., Mero&#xf1;o de Larriva, A. Y. &amp; Shokr, J. E. MS, Mapping Soil Contamination in Arid Regions: A GIS and Multivariate Analysis Approach, Minerals, vol. 15, no. 2, https://doi.org/10.3390/min15020124 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, O. C. D., Igalavithana, D., Alessi, A. D., Luo, D. S. &amp; Tsang, J. Metal contamination and bioremediation of agricultural soils for food safety and sustainability. Nat. Rev. Earth Environ. 1 (5), 232&#x2013;243. https://doi.org/10.1038/s43017-020-0061-y (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zikrullah Safi, Michael Miyittah, Benjamin Kwasi Offei, Godwin Amenorpe, A systematic review of wet and dry deposition of reactive nitrogen, sulfur, and heavy metals: ecosystem contamination and food chain disruption in Ghana. Environmental Science: Atmospheres, Volume 5, Issue 7, Pages 756-784. https://doi.org/10.1039/d5ea00018a (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sagymbayeva, T. N. et al. AA, Phytoremediation of Heavy Metal-Contaminated Soil Using Drought-Adapted Sweet Sorghum (Sorghum bicolor L.) in Arid Regions of Kazakhstan. Plants, 14(23), 3627; https://doi.org/10.3390/plants14233627(2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gacem, S. H. Assessment of soil characteristics and heavy metal pollution in a semi-arid region of Northeast Algeria. Revista de Agricultura Neotropical. 12 (3). https://doi.org/10.32404/rean.v12i3.9184 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wali, U. A. &amp; Danladi, S. U. Assessment of heavy metals (As, Ba, Co and Ni), pollution in rural drinking water sources, using correlation and principal component analysis in Western Sokoto Basin, Nigeria. Int. J. Hydrol.. 9 (2), 60&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.15406/ijh.2025.09.00404 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Abuduwaili, J., Ma, L., Liu, W. &amp; Zeng, T. Source apportionment and source-specific risk evaluation of potential toxic elements in Oasis agricultural soils of Tarim river basin. Sci. Rep. 13 (1), 2980. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-29911-3 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L. J. et al. D, Pollution and Health Risk Assessment of Potentially Toxic Elements in Groundwater in the K&#x1d2;nqi River Basin, Xinjiang, Northwest China, Toxics, vol. 12, no. 7, https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics12070474 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Health risk assessment of heavy metals in coal mine soils of Northwest China. J. Arid Land. 17, 933&#x2013;957 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daokun Chen, Shengfei Yang, Zhiyang Jiang, Zhirui Wang, Zhanbin Wang, Hui Tian, Spatial distribution, ecological risk and health risk assessment of heavy metals in agricultural soil from Ankang basin, Shaanxi Province, Heliyon, vol. 9, no. 12, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e22580(2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, M. C., Singh, J. &amp; Sur, K. Spatio&#x2013;temporal water quality assessment of Chohal and Damsal dams located in Kandi region of Punjab, India by geospatial technique and on-site investigation, Environ. Earth Sci., vol. 83, no. 2, p. 51, https://doi.org/10.1007/s12665-023-11354-8 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, S. &amp; Yu, H. Source apportionment and health risk assessment of heavy metals in groundwater of rural area: a case study in Huaibei plain, China. Hum. Ecol. Risk Assessment: Int. J. 30, 1&#x2013;2. https://doi.org/10.1080/10807039.2023.2301522 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X. et al. Heavy Metal Pollution and Risk Assessment of Surface Dust in the Arid NW China, Inter. J. Environ. Res. Public Health, vol. 19, no. 20, p. 13296, https://www.mdpi.com/1660-4601/19/20/13296. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng, M. X., Wen, D., Wu, X., Yu, J. &amp; Wu, H. Contamination characteristics, source identification, and source-specific health risks of heavy metal(loid)s in groundwater of an arid Oasis region in Northwest China. Sci. Total Environ. 1 (841), 156733. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. et al. Groundwater metal pollution and health risk assessment in river Valley heavy industrial cities of arid regions in China. China Geol., 8, 3, pp. 526&#x2013;539, https://doi.org/10.1016/S2096-5192(25)00091-6 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhaoyong, J. G. &amp; Pengwei, Z. W, Sources identification and health risk evaluation of 10 heavy metals (Metalloids) in soils of the Aibi lake Basin, Northwest China, ScientificWorldJournal, https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/8201972 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. et al. Risk assessment and source analysis of heavy metals in soil around an asbestos mine in an arid plateau region, China, Sci. Rep., vol. 14, no. 1, p. 7552 https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-58117-4 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, T. et al. Comparative assessment of health risks and water quality of groundwater in urban and rural Guiyang, Southwest china: insights from PMF and Monte Carlo simulation. Ecotoxicoll. nviron. Safety, 299, p. 118359, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2025.118359 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Xiao, S., Shen, R., Cheng, Q. &amp; Zhang, S. Rapid detection of soil heavy metal pollution using hyperspectral data and multiscale Spatial network. Environ. Technol. Innov., 37, p. 104031, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eti.2025.104031 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Application of machine learning in soil heavy metals pollution assessment in the southeastern Tibetan plateau. Sci. ep., 15, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X., Pan, J., Zhang, H. &amp; Lin, H. Progress in Remote Sensing of Heavy Metals in Water, Remote Sens., vol. 16, no. 20, p. 3888, https://www.mdpi.com/2072-4292/16/20/3888 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushwaha, N. L., Biwalkar, N., Sur, K. &amp; Rajput, J. Integrating water quality indices with machine learning algorithms for groundwater suitability in punjab: implications for drinking and sustainable irrigation. J. Water Process. Eng., 76, p. 108253, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2025.108253 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulieman, M. M., Kaya, F., Al-Farraj, A. S. &amp; Brevik, E. C. Jun, A novel method to determine background concentrations and Spatial distributions of heavy metals in soil at large scale using machine learning coupled with remote sensing-terrain attributes, (in eng), MethodsX, 14, p. 103180, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mex.2025.103180 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, Y., Li, B., Li, J., Guo, B. &amp; Feng, Q. Hyperspectral remote sensing for soil heavy metal inversion: insights and applications, Inter. J. Digital Earth, vol. 18, no. 1, p. 2520474, https://doi.org/10.1080/17538947.2025.2520474 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sur, K. et al. Monitoring vegetation degradation using remote sensing and machine learning over India &#x2013; a multi-sensor, multi-temporal and multi-scale approach, (in English), Front. Forests Glob. Change, https://doi.org/10.3389/ffgc.2024.1382557 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, V. K., Sur, K. &amp; Prakash, C. Ecotope-Based Diversity Monitoring of Wetland Using Infused Machine Learning Technique, Water Conserv. Sci. Eng., vol. 8, no. 1, p. 38, https://doi.org/10.1007/s41101-023-00212-0 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. A remote sensing analysis method for soil heavy metal pollution sources at site scale considering source-sink relationships. Sci. Total Environ., 946, p. 174021, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.174021 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovynska, V. et al. Monitoring Heavy Metals and Metalloids in Soils and Vegetation by Remote Sensing: A Review, Remote Sensing, vol. 16, no. 17, p. 3221, [Online]. (2024). Available: https://www.mdpi.com/2072-4292/16/17/3221</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Ren, J., Cui, R., Yu, K. &amp; Zhao, Y. Optical imaging spectroscopy coupled with machine learning for detecting heavy metal of plants: A review, (in eng). Front. Plant. Sci. 13, 1007991. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2022.1007991 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke&#xe7;eci, M., G&#xf6;kmen, F., Usul, M., Koca, C. &amp; Uygur, V. Prediction of cadmium content using machine learning methods, Environ. Earth Sci., vol. 83, no. 12, p. 362, https://doi.org/10.1007/s12665-024-11672-5 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradpour, S., Entezari, M., Ayoubi, S., Karimi, A. &amp; Naimi, S. Digital exploration of selected heavy metals using random forest and a set of environmental covariates at the watershed scale. J. Hazard. Materials, 455, p. 131609, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.131609 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, P. et al. Remote sensing inversion on heavy metal content in salinized soil of Yellow River Delta based on Random Forest Regression&#x2014;a case study of Gudao Town, Sci. Rep., vol. 14, no. 1, p. 11216, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62087-y (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, W., Tan, K. &amp; Du, P. Predicting soil heavy metal based on Random Forest model, In IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium (IGARSS), 10&#x2013;15, 4334, (2016). https://doi.org/10.1109/IGARSS.2016.7730129 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie, S., Chen, H., Sun, X. &amp; An, Y. Spatial Distribution Prediction of Soil Heavy Metals Based on Random Forest Model, Sustainability, vol. 16, no. 11, p. 4358, https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/16/11/4358 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, H. &amp; Jing, Y. X. Evaluation of soil heavy metal pollution remediation effect based on remote sensing and mapping technology in cultivated land. Int. J. Environ. Technol. Manag. 27, 4&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1504/ijetm.2024.139988 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang, C. et al. Prediction of soil heavy metal content around mine tailings using multiple methods combined with transformed hyperspectral reflectance data. Ore Energy Resource Geol., 18, p. 100072, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oreoa.2024.100072 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang, Y. The Application of Hyperspectral Remote Sensing Technology in the Identification of Soil Heavy Metal Elements, Sci. J. Technol., vol. 6, no. 10, pp. 15&#x2013;20, https://doi.org/10.54691/3y8z0709 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, W. et al. Heavy metal pollution and health risk assessment of agricultural land in the Southern margin of Tarim basin in Xinjiang, China. Int. J. Environ. Health Res. 31 (7), 835&#x2013;847. https://doi.org/10.1080/09603123.2019.1691157 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Deciphering the driving factors and probabilistic health risks of potentially toxic elements in arid surface water: insights from the Tarim river basin. Ecotoxicol. Environ. Safety, 286, p. 117211, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.117211 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Spatiotemporal Evolution Characteristics in Ecosystem Service Values Based on Land Use/Cover Change in the Tarim River Basin, China, Sustainability, vol. 12, no. 18, https://doi.org/10.3390/su12187759 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, J. et al. Scenario Analysis of Carbon Emissions in the Energy Base, Xinjiang Autonomous Region, China, Sustainability, vol. 11, no. 15, https://doi.org/10.3390/su11154220 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WANG Faxiang, Y. Y., Yi,XIAO, X. I. A. O., Zhou, Z. H. A. N. G. &amp; Shengnan Heavy metal pollution characteristics and potential ecological risk assessment of surface sediments in the upper reaches of Tarim river. J. Tarim Univ. 36 (01), 93&#x2013;99. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shengnan, M. F. Z. H. A. N. G., Yongjun, Y. O. U. &amp; Shan, W. A. N. G. APCS-MLR combined with PMF model for sediment heavy metal source analysis and risk assessment in the upper Tarim river basin. Environ. Chem. 42 (12), 4264&#x2013;4277 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiuping, B. Study on water quality characteristics of irrigation and drainage of cotton field in oasis of Southern Xinjiang, master, (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, W. et al. Water quality and health risk assessment of shallow groundwater in the southern margin of the Tarim Basin in Xinjiang, P. R. China, Hum. Ecol. Risk Assess. Inter. J., vol. 27, no. 2, pp. 483&#x2013;503, https://doi.org/10.1080/10807039.2020.1731680 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. et al. Enhanced Assessment of Water Quality and Pollutant Source Apportionment Using APCS-MLR and PMF Models in the Upper Reaches of the Tarim River, Water, vol. 16, no. 21, p. 3061, https://www.mdpi.com/2073-4441/16/21/3061 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, J., Jin, Z. &amp; Wang, J. Geochemistry of trace elements and water quality assessment of natural water within the Tarim river basin in the extreme arid region, NW China. J. Geochem. Explor. 136, 118&#x2013;126. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gexplo.2013.10.013 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abudumiti, Y. Spatial distribution characteristics of surface water quality in the Ogan-Kucha river oasis and its relationship with landscape pattern, Master&#x2019;s Degree, Xinjiang University, https://doi.org/10.27429/d.cnki.gxjdu.2020.000959 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, C. Research on distribution characteristics and Pollution evaluation of heavy metals in abandoned drilling mud in oil field, Master&#x2019;s Degree, Xinjiang University, https://kns.cnki.net/kcms2/article/abstract?v=3-fZNjprSazP8XdxQsrJPMuIzI5jEKJmdLyt4J9vxC85PKKfFKqjXOGu-v9j0fLv3R0LPVvGhoO7WqQhEIA1wlIBF9DbRP8W9lolswi861oRFGsUTZNaqh0mlJhvR1CJ95mkbIBJ0oOMYWooUFf5RvNF_1YCXsLVSeOaQmdTp6I6zCexkiZeeQ==&amp;uniplatform=NZKPT&amp;language=CHS (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J., Wu, G., Gu, F., Yu, Z. &amp; An, B. Elemental composition of the topsoil fine fraction at and around the Tibetan plateau. Environ. Pollut. 320 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2023.121098 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orwell, R. L., Wood, R. A., Burchett, M. D., Tarran, J. &amp; Torpy, F. The Potted-Plant microcosm substantially reduces indoor air VOC pollution: II. Laboratory study. Water Air Soil Pollut. 177, 1&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11270-006-9092-3 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, K. et al. Estimating the distribution trend of soil heavy metals in mining area from HyMap airborne hyperspectral imagery based on ensemble learning. J. Hazard. Mater. 401 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.123288 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scornet, E. Random forests and kernel methods. IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory. 62 (3), 1485&#x2013;1500. https://doi.org/10.1109/tit.2016.2514489 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drusch, M. et al. Sentinel-2: esa&#x2019;s optical High-Resolution mission for GMES operational services. Remote Sens. Environ. 120, 25&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2011.11.026 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulahci, F. &amp; Sen, Z. Cumulative ordinary kriging interpolation model to forecast radioactive fallout, and its application to Chernobyl and Fukushima assessment: a new method and mini review. Environ. Sci. Pollut Res. Int. 29 (43), 64298&#x2013;64311. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-022-21921-4 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tziachris, P., Aschonitis, V., Chatzistathis, T., Papadopoulou, M. &amp; Doukas, I. D. Comparing machine learning models and hybrid Geostatistical methods using environmental and soil covariates for soil pH prediction. ISPRS Int. J. Geo-Information. 9 (4). https://doi.org/10.3390/ijgi9040276 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, S. H. G. et al. Multiple linear regression and random forest to predict and map soil properties using data from portable X-ray fluorescence spectrometer (pXRF), Ci&#xea;ncia e Agrotecnologia, vol. 41, no. 6, pp. 648&#x2013;664, https://doi.org/10.1590/1413-70542017416010317 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan, C., Dai, Z., Yin, S., Carroll, K. C. &amp; Soltanian, M. R. Conceptualizing future groundwater models through a ternary framework of multisource data, human expertise, and machine intelligence. Water Res. 257, 121679. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121679 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, J. J., Yang, M. &amp; Ren, Z. J. Machine learning in environmental research: common pitfalls and best practices. Environ Sci. Technol, 57, 46, pp. 17671&#x2013;17689, Nov 21 2023, https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.3c00026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, H. et al. Assessment of global antibiotic exposure risk for crops: incorporating soil adsorption via machine learning. Environ Sci. Technol.. 20 https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03695 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., Neu, C. P. &amp; Pierce, D. M. Advances toward multiscale computational models of cartilage mechanics and mechanobiology. Curr. Opin. Biomedical Eng. 11, 51&#x2013;57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cobme.2019.09.013 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, Q. et al. Health risk assessment and bioaccessibilities of heavy metals for children in soil and dust from urban parks and schools of Jiaozuo, China. Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf. 191 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2019.110157 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J. et al. A new exploration of health risk assessment quantification from sources of soil heavy metals under different land use. Environ. Pollut. 243, 49&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2018.08.038 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, J. et al. Health risk assessment of heavy metal(loid)s in park soils of the largest megacity in China by using Monte Carlo simulation coupled with positive matrix factorization model. J. Hazard. Mater. 415 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2021.125629 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, Q. et al. Heavy metals in homestead soil: metal fraction contents, bioaccessibility, and risk assessment. J. Hazard. Mater. 480 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.135933 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. et al. A Spatial source-oriented and probability-based risk-assessment framework for heavy metal and PAH contamination of urban soils in Guangzhou, China. J. Hazard. Mater. 482 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136500 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, K. et al. Ecological risk assessment of heavy metals in sediments and water from the coastal areas of the Bohai sea and the yellow sea. Environ. Int. 136 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2020.105512 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. et al. Composition, distribution, and risk assessment of heavy metals in large-scale river water on the Tibetan plateau. J. Hazard. Mater. 476 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.135094 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Overview assessment of risk evaluation and treatment technologies for heavy metal pollution of water and soil. J. Clean. Prod. 379 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.134043 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solgi, E., Esmaili-Sari, A., Riyahi-Bakhtiari, A. &amp; Hadipour, M. Soil contamination of metals in the three industrial estates, Arak, Iran. Bull. Environ. Contam. Toxicol. 88 (4), 634&#x2013;638. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00128-012-0553-7 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eid, M. H. et al. Comprehensive approach integrating water quality index and toxic element analysis for environmental and health risk assessment enhanced by simulation techniques. Environ. Geochem. Health. 46 (10). https://doi.org/10.1007/s10653-024-02182-1 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, W. et al. Source-specific soil heavy metal risk assessment in arsenic waste mine site of yunnan: integrating environmental and biological factors. J. Hazard. Mater. 486, 136902. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136902 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, K. et al. Heavy metal pollution from standardized e-waste dismantling activities: pollution index, risk assessment and intervening measures. J. Hazard. Mater. 484, 136614. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136614 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sany, S. R. et al. Evaluation of groundwater quality and potential health risks in the Tengratila gas field blowout Region, bangladesh: an in-depth analysis utilizing multivariate statistics, heavy metal indices and Monte Carlo simulation. J. Hazard. Mater. 490, 137744. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.137744 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser, H. F. The Varimax Criterion for Analytic Rotation in Factor Analysis, Psychometrika, vol. 23, no. 3, pp. 187&#x2013;200, https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02289233 (1958).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dammi Djimi, E. G. et al. Multivariate Statistical and Hydrochemical Analysis of Drinking Water Resources in Northern Cameroon Watersheds, Water, vol. 13, no. 21, https://doi.org/10.3390/w13213055 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. et al. Multi-element features and trace metal sources of road sediment from a mega heavy industrial city in North China, Chemosphere, vol. 311, no. Pt 1, p. 137093, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2022.137093 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, M. &amp; Liang, H. Soil health assessment of dressing and smelting slag field based on heavy metal pollution-buffer-fertility three aspects. J. Hazard. Mater. 482, 136602. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136602 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kravchenko, E. et al. Ecological and health risk assessments of heavy metal contamination in soils surrounding a coal power plant. J. Hazard. Mater. 484, 136751. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136751 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veskovic, J. &amp; Onjia, A. Two-dimensional Monte Carlo simulation coupled with multilinear regression modeling of source-specific health risks from groundwater. J. Hazard. Mater. 488, 137309. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.137309 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, W. et al. Soil type data provide new methods and insights for heavy metal pollution assessment and driving factors analysis. J. Hazard. Mater. 480, 135868. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.135868 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, H., Lu, X. &amp; Lei, K. A comprehensive analysis of heavy metals in urban road dust of Xi&#x2019;an, China: Contamination, source apportionment and spatial distribution. Sci. Total Environ., 609, pp. 1361&#x2013;1369, Dec 31 2017, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2017.08.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, W., Hao, G. &amp; Liu, W. Source-specific risks apportionment and critical sources identification of potentially harmful elements in urban road dust combining positive matrix factorization model with multiple attribute decision making method. Ecol. Ind. 144 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2022.109449 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, B. et al. Potentially toxic elements in surface fine dust of residence communities in Valley industrial cities. Environ. Pollut. 327 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2023.121523 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veskovi&#x107;, J., Senti&#x107;, M. &amp; Onjia, A. Hydrogeochemical Facies and Health Hazards of Fluoride and Nitrate in Groundwater of a Lithium Ore Deposit Basin, Metals, vol. 14, no. 9 https://doi.org/10.3390/met14091062, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Efficient ultra-trace electrochemical detection of Cd2+, Pb2&#x2009;+&#x2009;and Hg2&#x2009;+&#x2009;based on hierarchical porous S-doped C3N4 tube bundles/graphene nanosheets composite. Chem. Eng. J. 420 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2021.130317 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, P. et al. Spatial distribution, risk Estimation and source apportionment of potentially toxic metal(loid)s in resuspended megacity street dust. Environ. Int. 160, 107073. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2021.107073 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z., Hao, M., Li, Y. &amp; Li, S. Contamination, sources and health risks of toxic elements in soils of karstic urban parks based on Monte Carlo simulation combined with a receptor model. Sci. Total Environ. 839, 156223. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.156223 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egbueri, J. C., Abu, M. &amp; Agbasi, J. C. An integrated appraisal of the hydrogeochemistry and the potential public health risks of groundwater nitrate and fluoride in Eastern Ghana. Groundw. Sustainable Dev. 26 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gsd.2024.101264 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veskovi&#x107;, J. &amp; Onjia, A. Environmental Implications of the Soil-to-Groundwater Migration of Heavy Metals in Mining Area Hotspots, Metals, vol. 14, no. 6, https://doi.org/10.3390/met14060719 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. et al. Integrating machine learning for enhanced Spatial prediction and risk assessment of soil heavy metal(loid)s. Environ. Pollut., 383, p. 126919, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2025.126919 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sorogy, A. S., Al-Kahtany, K., Shokr, M. S., Alharbi, T. &amp; de Larriva, J. E. M. On evaluating the possible hazard of soil contamination in arid regions using statistical analysis and GIS techniques, (in English), Front. Earth Sci., https://doi.org/10.3389/feart.2025.1605796 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Pollution characteristics and probabilistic risk assessment of heavy metal(loid)s in agricultural soils across the yellow river Basin, China. Ecol. Indicators, 167, p. 112676, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2024.112676 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S. &amp; Anshumali Heavy metal pollution and health risk assessment in upland and riparian soils of the Ganga River basin, Discover Soil, vol. 2, no. 1, p. 33, https://doi.org/10.1007/s44378-025-00061-4 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Heavy metal synergistic pollution risk assessment in the soil-crop system of the Nanyang basin. Sci. Rep. 15 (1), 19937. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-05236-1 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., Li, W., Zhu, C. &amp; Tang, X. Analysis of Heavy Metal Pollution in Cultivated Land of Different Quality Grades in Yangtze River Delta of China, Inter. J. Environ. Res. Public Health, vol. 18, no. 18, p. 9876, https://www.mdpi.com/1660-4601/18/18/9876 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. et al. Heavy Metal Pollution and Its Prior Pollution Source Identification in Agricultural Soil: A Case Study in the Qianguo Irrigation District, Northeast China, Sustainability, vol. 14, no. 8, p. 4494, https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/14/8/4494 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, L. et al. Improved model for human health risk assessment of soil heavy metal(loid)s in a mining area of southeastern China, (in eng), Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf., vol. 306, p. 119312,https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2025.119312 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, L., Gopalakrishnan, G., Wang, Z., Li, Y. &amp; Zhang, Y. Characteristics, source apportionment, and health risk assessment of heavy metal pollution in soil of jiangmen, China, Sci. Rep., vol. 15, no. 1, p. 31578,https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-17496-y (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, G., Chen, F., Zhang, H. &amp; Wang, Z. Pollution and health risk assessment of heavy metals in soils of Guizhou, China, Ecosystem Health Sustain., vol. 7, no. 1, p. 1859948, https://doi.org/10.1080/20964129.2020.1859948 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saifullah, M. K. et al. Seasonal variation, and ecological risks assessment of heavy metals pollution in an upstream tropical freshwater river, Bangladesh. Inter. J. River Basin Manag., pp. 1&#x2013;24, https://doi.org/10.1080/15715124.2025.2523413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, X. et al. Source-specific probabilistic health risk assessment of heavy metals in surface water of the Yangtze river basin. Science Total Environment, 926, p. 171923, 2024/05/20/ 2024, doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.171923</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X. et al. Status of heavy metals contamination in the topsoil of major Oasis cities in Northwest China, (in eng). Environ. Geochem. Health. 47, 362. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10653-025-02659-7 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, D. et al. Spatial and Temporal Variations in Heavy Metals in Lake and Reservoir Sediments in China: A Pollution Status and Risk Assessment, Sustainability, vol. 16, no. 21, p. 9218, https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/16/21/9218 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, Z. et al. Mapping mining-affected water pollution in china: status, patterns, risks, and implications. Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci. 29, 3957&#x2013;3973. https://doi.org/10.5194/hess-29-3957-2025 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. et al. Determination and application of soil heavy metal geochemical baseline in the southern region of Wushan County in the Yangtze River Basin, China, Scientific Reports, vol. 15, no. 1, p. 10889, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-86404-1 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., Zheng, J., Cao, Y. &amp; Jiang, Q. Policy Adjustments: Their Dual Impacts and Sustainability Assessment on Heavy Metal Concentration in Topsoil of Nantong City, China, Sustainability, vol. 17, no. 5, p. 1868, https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/17/5/1868 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mussakulkyzy, A. et al. Transmission of Heavy Metals in River Water and Self-Purification Capacity of Ile River, Appl. Sci., vol. 15, no. 12, p. 6548, https://www.mdpi.com/2076-3417/15/12/6548 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou, X., Liu, Q., Fan, Q., Guo, J. &amp; Qi, W. Comprehensive analysis of common heavy metals in the yellow river over 20 years: Spatiotemporal distribution, migration characteristics, traceability, and potential risk evaluation. Environ. Res., 281, p. 121931, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2025.121931 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Heavy Metal Pollution and Health-Ecological Risk Assessment in Agricultural Soils: A Case Study from the Yellow River Bend Industrial Parks, (in eng), Toxics, vol. 13, no. 10, https://doi.org/10.3390/toxics13100834 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, J. et al. Content, Distribution, and risk assessment of heavy metals in sandy soils of the ancient yellow river course. Soil Sediment. Contamination: Int. Journal, 34, 7, pp. 1911&#x2013;1931, https://doi.org/10.1080/15320383.2025.2467237 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, P. et al. Heavy metals in water and surface sediments of the Fenghe river Basin, china: assessment and source analysis. Water Sci. Technol. 84, 10&#x2013;11. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.2021.335 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, W., Rozainy Mohd Arif Zainol, M.R., Zha, X. &amp; Luo, P. Research trends and prospects in global riverine carbon fluxes: A bibliometric analysis, Ecological Indicators, p. 112985, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2024.112985 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zha, X., Fang, W., Zhu, W., Wang, S., Mu, Y., Wang, X., Luo, P., Zainol, M.R.R.M.A., Zawawi, M.H., Chong, K.L. &amp; Apip, A. Optimizing the deployment of LID facilities on a campus-scale and assessing the benefits of comprehensive control in Sponge City. Journal of Hydrology, p. 131189, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2024.131189 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, W., Wang, T., Liu, L., Luo, P., Cui, J., Wang, L., Hua, X., Duan, W. &amp; Su, F. A novel design and application of spatial data management platform for natural resources. Journal of Cleaner Production, p. 137183,https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.137183 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>