<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41840693</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2661-801X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Chem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sustainable chromatographic assays of a novel antifungal combination for keratomycosis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13065-026-01735-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Keratomycosis, a sight-threatening fungal infection of the cornea, can be more effectively treated with a novel combination of Natamycin (NAT, 5%) and Fluconazole (FLC, 0.2%) than with NAT alone. To support the development of this therapy, new sustainable, eco-friendly, and sensitive analytical methods were developed for the simultaneous quantification of both drugs in pharmaceutical formulations. Two techniques were successfully employed. The first was a Reversed-Phase High-Performance Liquid Chromatography (RP-HPLC) method using an isocratic mobile phase of methanol and water (70:30%v/v) at a 1 mL/min flow rate. Detection was accomplished with both diode array (DAD) and fluorescence (FLD) detectors. The second technique was a Capillary Zone Electrophoresis (CZE) method utilizing a capillary (56&#xa0;cm effective length, 50&#xa0;&#x3bc;m internal diameter) at ambient temperature. Samples were injected hydrodynamically at 50 mbar pressure. The environmental sustainability and practical applicability of these methods were rigorously evaluated using modern assessment tools: the Greenness, Whiteness, and Blueness approaches. Furthermore, their innovative character was formally quantified using a novel metric, the Violet Innovation Grade Index (VIGI).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aboukhalil</LastName><ForeName>Faten M</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Analytical Chemistry Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khamis</LastName><ForeName>Essam F</ForeName><Initials>EF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Analytical Chemistry Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Sayed</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Analytical Chemistry Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Yazbi</LastName><ForeName>Amira F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Analytical Chemistry Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt. amira.elyazbi@alexu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Youssef</LastName><ForeName>Rasha M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Analytical Chemistry Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Alexandria University, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Chem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101741142</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2661-801X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Capillary zone electrophoresis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fluconazole</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Greenness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Keratomycosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Natamycin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RP-HPLC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VIGI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Whiteness and Blueness approaches</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41840693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13065-026-01735-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13065-026-01735-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National Center for Biotechnology Information. (2025). PubChem Compound Summary for CID 5284447, N.R.A., 2025 from https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/Natamycin</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meena M et al. Natamycin: a natural preservative for food applications&#x2014;a review. Food Sci Biotechnol, 2021: pp. 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu S, et al. Natamycin in the treatment of fungal keratitis: a systematic review and Meta-analysis. Int J Ophthalmol. 2015;8(3):597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Biotechnology Information. (2025). PubChem Compound Summary for CID 3365, F.R.A., 2025 from https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/Fluconazole</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zervos M, Meunier F. Fluconazole (Diflucan<sup>&#xae;</sup>): a review. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 1993;3(3):147&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koul P, Padha A, Sharma S. Comparison of the efficacy of topical Natamycin 5% and fluconazole 0.3% eye drop therapy versus topical Natamycin 5% alone in deep fungal keratitis in Garhwal region of Uttarakhand, India. Int J Sci Stud. 2018;6(9):5&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koontz JL, et al. Stability of Natamycin and its cyclodextrin inclusion complexes in aqueous solution. J Agric Food Chem. 2003;51(24):7111&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, et al. Detection method optimization, content analysis and stability exploration of Natamycin in wine. Food Chem. 2016;194:928&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhari J, Chhabra G. Development and validation of stability indicating RP-HPLC method for Natamycin in bulk and ophthalmic dosage forms. Asian J Pharm Clin Res. 2014;7(3):54&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meena M, et al. Natamycin: a natural preservative for food applications&#x2014;a review. Food Sci Biotechnol. 2021;30(12):1481&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keith LH, et al. An introduction to the National environmental methods index. ACS; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowtharapu LP, et al. Green metric tools for analytical methods assessment critical review, case studies and crucify. TRAC Trends Anal Chem. 2023;166:117196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ga&#x142;uszka A, et al. Analytical Eco-Scale for assessing the greenness of analytical procedures. TRAC Trends Anal Chem. 2012;37:61&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Yazbi AF, et al. Simultaneous determination of Mometasone furoate and Salicylic acid in complex matrix using green analytical method. Microchem J. 2021;163:105900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena-Pereira F, Wojnowski W, Tobiszewski M. AGREE&#x2014;Analytical greenness metric approach and software. Anal Chem. 2020;92(14):10076&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#x142;otka-Wasylka J. A new tool for the evaluation of the analytical procedure: green analytical procedure index. Talanta. 2018;181:204&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaber Y, et al. HPLC-EAT (Environmental assessment Tool): a tool for profiling safety, health and environmental impacts of liquid chromatography methods. Green Chem. 2011;13(8):2021&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael AM, Lotfy HM, Nessim CK. Greenness profile and whiteness assessment of the stability-indicating HPLC method for the assay of Levetiracetam. Microchem J. 2023;190:108669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowak PM, Wietecha-Pos&#x142;uszny R, Pawliszyn J. White analytical chemistry: an approach to reconcile the principles of green analytical chemistry and functionality. TRAC Trends Anal Chem. 2021;138:116223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manousi N, et al. Blue applicability grade index (BAGI) and software: a new tool for the evaluation of method practicality. Green Chem. 2023;25(19):7598&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manousi N, P&#x142;otka-Wasylka J, Samanidou V. Novel sorptive extraction techniques in bioanalysis evaluated by blue applicability grade index: the paradigm of fabric phase sorptive extraction and capsule phase Microextraction. TRAC Trends Anal Chem. 2024;172:117586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuente-Ballesteros A, et al. Violet innovation grade index (VIGI): a new survey-based metric for evaluating innovation in analytical methods. Anal Chem. 2025;97(13):6946&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ermer J. ICH Q2 (R2): validation of analytical procedures. Method validation in pharmaceutical analysis: a guide to best practice, 2025: pp. 351&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace J, et al. Assay of fluconazole by high-performance liquid chromatography with a mixed-phase column. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1992;36(3):603&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paseiro-Cerrato R, et al. Rapid method to determine Natamycin by HPLC-DAD in food samples for compliance with EU food legislation. Food Control. 2013;33(1):262&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>http://www.biotek.lu.se/hplc-eat/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>