<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41841049</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Mystery of a Negative Workup: A Diagnostic Dilemma in Seronegative Immune-Mediated Transverse Myelitis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103440</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103440</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103440</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103440</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Transverse myelitis (TM) is an acquired inflammatory disorder of the spinal cord with a heterogeneous aetiology that includes demyelinating, autoimmune, infectious, granulomatous, and paraneoplastic causes. Although advances in antibody testing, particularly aquaporin-4 (AQP4-IgG) and myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein immunoglobulin G (MOG-IgG), have refined the classification of many cases, a significant proportion remain seronegative, presenting diagnostic and therapeutic challenges. We report the case of a 44-year-old man who presented with progressive fatigue, significant weight loss, lower abdominal numbness, urinary urgency, and intermittent blurred vision. Magnetic resonance imaging of the thoracic spine demonstrated an intramedullary T2 hyperintense lesion at the T10-T11 level with patchy gadolinium enhancement, consistent with inflammatory myelitis. An extensive diagnostic evaluation excluded infectious, systemic autoimmune, granulomatous, endocrine, demyelinating, and paraneoplastic causes. The patient showed marked clinical improvement following high-dose intravenous methylprednisolone, with resolution of sensory and autonomic symptoms and stabilisation of weight, while mild fluctuating fatigue persisted. This case highlights the diagnostic grey zone of seronegative immune-mediated TM and underscores the importance of systematic exclusion, longitudinal assessment, and therapeutic responsiveness in establishing diagnosis and guiding management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Ottu Para et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ottu Para</LastName><ForeName>Niyas Khalid</ForeName><Initials>NK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Burjeel Hospital, Abu Dhabi, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrinivas</LastName><ForeName>Uvashree</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Burjeel Medical City, Abu Dhabi, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Udyavar Karoda</LastName><ForeName>Fareeda</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Burjeel Medical City, Abu Dhabi, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acute transverse myelitis (atm)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis of exclusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory myelopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seronegative autoimmune disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">steroid responsive</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41841049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12989039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Transverse myelitis--a review of the presentation, diagnosis, and initial management. West TW. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24099672/ Discov Med. 2013;16:167&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24099672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoimmune myelopathies. Flanagan EP. Handb Clin Neurol. 2016;133:327&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27112686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autoimmune and paraneoplastic myelopathies. Zalewski NL, Flanagan EP. Semin Neurol. 2018;38:278&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30011409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AQP4 antibodies in neuromyelitis optica: diagnostic and pathogenetic relevance. Jarius S, Wildemann B. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/45272273_Wildemann_B_AQP4_antibodies_in_neuromyelitis_optica_diagnostic_and_pathogenetic_relevance_Nature_Reviews_Neurology_6_383-392. Nat Rev Neurol. 2010;6:383&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20639914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of neuromyelitis optica in the United States: a multicenter analysis. Mealy MA, Wingerchuk DM, Greenberg BM, Levy M. Arch Neurol. 2012;69:1176&#x2013;1180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22733096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute transverse myelitis in childhood: center-based analysis of 47 cases. Pidcock FS, Krishnan C, Crawford TO, Salorio CF, Trovato M, Kerr DA. Neurology. 2007;68:1474&#x2013;1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17470749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder and anti-MOG syndromes. Lana-Peixoto MA, Talim N. Biomedicines. 2019;7:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6631227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31212763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amphiphysin autoimmunity: paraneoplastic accompaniments. Pittock SJ, Lucchinetti CF, Parisi JE, et al. Ann Neurol. 2005;58:96&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15984030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic inflammatory-demyelinating diseases of the central nervous system. Ca&#xf1;ellas AR, Gols AR, Izquierdo JR, Subirana MT, Gairin XM. Neuroradiology. 2007;49:393&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17333161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical spectrum and prognostic value of CNS MOG autoimmunity in adults: the MOGADOR study. Cobo-Calvo A, Ruiz A, Maillart E, et al. Neurology. 2018;90:0&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29695592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical inflammatory demyelinating syndromes of the CNS. Hardy TA, Reddel SW, Barnett MH. Lancet Neurol. 2016;15:967&#x2013;981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27478954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>