<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41813935</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1863-2491</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of robotic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Robot Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Robot-assisted total knee arthroplasty: adverse events related to the robotic system.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">346</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11701-026-03162-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Robot-assisted total knee arthroplasty (RA-TKA) aims to enhance surgical precision and reproducibility. However, technical malfunctions occasionally occur. This study analyses single-centre RA-TKA malfunction cases to explore causative factors and reflect on the relationship between surgeons and robotic assistance.&#xa0;A retrospective analysis was conducted on 188 consecutive RA-TKA procedures performed between January 2020 and June 2025 by the same senior arthroplasty consultant using five distinct robotic systems (Brainlab template-guided, HURWA automated alignment, Smith &amp; Nephew CORI milling-drilling, BoneSage automated alignment, and Jianjia template-guided). Cases meeting predefined &#x2018;malfunction&#x2019; criteria. Malfunction defined as: inability to complete critical steps according to the robot&#x2019;s predetermined plan due to any cause, necessitating intraoperative abandonment of robotic assistance or major plan adjustments; or direct robot-related factors causing poor postoperative alignment (mechanical axis deviation&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;3&#xb0;) or abnormal soft tissue balance requiring early intervention. Systematic classification and statistical analysis of malfunction causes.&#xa0;Seventeen malfunction cases were categorised into three primary groups: (1) Robot malfunction (3 cases, 17.6%): intraoperative robotic system failure; (2) Technical malfunction (7 cases, 41.2%): loosening of positioning/reference frame (5 cases), misplacement of calibrator in osteotomy zone (2 cases); (3) Workflow and learning curve issues (2 cases, 11.8%): significant time prolongation and subsequent abandonment due to unfamiliarity with specific new system procedures (2 cases); (4) Conflict between surgeon decision-making and robotic planning (5 cases, 29.4%): surgeons performed unplanned mobilisation or osteotomy adjustments based on experience, ultimately resulting in failure to achieve anticipated balance/alignment.&#xa0;The success of RA-TKA relies on a reliable platform, standardised procedures, and human-machine collaboration. Clinical observations from 188 cases revealed: (1) 17 cases (9.0%) experienced robot-related malfunctions; (2) Different robotic systems exhibited distinct failure modes; (3) Malfunction rates were higher during the early learning curve phase; (4) All malfunctions were resolved through surgeon intervention without causing surgical failure. This indicates that technical malfunctions can be progressively mitigated through system optimisation and training, while intraoperative human-machine coordination and stepwise verification remain critical for surgical safety.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Xunzhou</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Panzhihua Central Hospital, Panzhihua, 617000, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Mingyou</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Panzhihua Central Hospital, Panzhihua, 617000, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hongping</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Panzhihua Central Hospital, Panzhihua, 617000, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Zhuodong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Panzhihua Central Hospital, Panzhihua, 617000, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lan</LastName><ForeName>Yuping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Panzhihua Central Hospital, Panzhihua, 617000, Sichuan, China. lanyuping@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Robot Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101300401</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1863-2483</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intraoperative decision-making</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Learning curve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Robot-assisted surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical malfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total knee arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41813935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12979380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11701-026-03162-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11701-026-03162-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Parratte S, Pagnano MW, Trousdale RT, Berry DJ (2010) Effect of postoperative mechanical axis alignment on the fifteen-year survival of modern, cemented total knee replacements. J Bone Joint Surg Am 92(12):2143&#x2013;2149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.I.01398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20844155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayani B, Konan S, Huq SS, Tahmassebi J, Haddad FS (2019) Robotic-arm assisted total knee arthroplasty has a learning curve of seven cases for integration into the surgical workflow but no learning curve effect for accuracy of implant positioning. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 27(4):1132&#x2013;1141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-018-5138-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6435632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30225554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sires JD, Wilson CJ (2021) CT validation of intraoperative implant position and knee alignment as determined by the MAKO total knee arthroplasty system. J Knee Surg 34(10):1133&#x2013;1137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0040-1701447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32131103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Chen X, Wang X, Zhang B, Wang W, Fan Y, Yan J, Zhang X, Zhao Y, Lin Y, Liu J, Lin J (2022) HURWA robotic-assisted total knee arthroplasty improves component positioning and alignment - a prospective randomized and multicenter study. J Orthop Translat 33:31&#x2013;40</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jot.2021.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8857449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35228995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermue H, Luyckx T, Winnock de Grave P, Ryckaert A, Cools AS, Himpe N, Victor J (2022) Robot-assisted total knee arthroplasty is associated with a learning curve for surgical time but not for component alignment, limb alignment and gap balancing. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 30(2):593&#x2013;602</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00167-020-06341-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33141246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sicat CS, Chow JC, Kaper B, Mitra R, Xie J, Schwarzkopf R (2021) Component placement accuracy in two generations of handheld robotics-assisted knee arthroplasty. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 141(12):2059&#x2013;2067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00402-021-04040-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34304279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Gang L, Guoqing W, Yang et al (2023) Early clinical efficacy of MAKO robotic-assisted total knee arthroplasty [J]. Chin J Orthop Joint Surg 16(03):232&#x2013;238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayani B, Konan S, Tahmassebi J, Pietrzak JRT, Haddad FS (2018) Robotic-arm assisted total knee arthroplasty is associated with improved early functional recovery and reduced time to hospital discharge compared with conventional jig-based total knee arthroplasty: a prospective cohort study. Bone Joint J 100-B(7):930&#x2013;937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.100B7.BJJ-2017-1449.R1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6413767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29954217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Londhe SB, Rudraraju RT, Shah RV, DeSouza C, Shetty V, Khan FS, Bajwa S (2024) Analysis of robot-specific operative time and surgical team anxiety level and its effect on alignment during robot-assisted TKA. J Robot Surg 18(1):86</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11701-024-01823-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38386217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi Xin P, Hangyu P, Wei et al (2023) Preliminary study on the learning curve of Robot-Assisted total knee arthroplasty using the Honghu system [J]. Chin J Orthop Joint Surg 16(04):340&#x2013;346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong MT, Yu M, Cao M et al (2025) Robotic-assisted burr preparation significantly improves cement penetration but not immediate fixation strength in total knee arthroplasty. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc 33(11):3935&#x2013;3943</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.12765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12582227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40622097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardou-Jacquet J, Murgier J, Laudet F, Fabre T (2022) Combining load sensor and robotic technologies for ligament balance in total knee arthroplasty. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res 108(5):102889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.otsr.2021.102889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33713872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Qianqian D, Lixiang G, Dawei et al (2022) Clinical risk analysis and countermeasures for the Tianji orthopaedic surgical robot [J]. Biomedical Eng Clin Pract 26(04):497&#x2013;501</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Kong X, Chai W (2022) Review of clinical applications of arthroscopic surgical robots in 2021. Orthopedics 13(6):562&#x2013;567</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Kong X, Chai W (2025) [Current Status and Prospects of Domestic Total Joint Replacement Surgical Robots in Clinical Practice]. J Clin Orthop Res 10(1):52&#x2013;56</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolodychuk N, Su E, Alexiades MM et al (2021) Can robotic technology mitigate the learning curve of total hip arthroplasty? Bone Jt Open 2(6):365&#x2013;370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/2633-1462.26.BJO-2021-0042.R1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8244790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34128384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>