<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41141185</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of the Semicircular Inverted Internal Limiting Membrane Flap Technique for Macular Hole Retinal Detachment in Hyperopic Eyes: A Case Series.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e93149</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e93149</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e93149</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.93149</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We report anatomical and functional outcomes for three hyperopic phakic women with macular hole retinal detachment (MHRD) treated using a superiorly based semicircular inverted internal limiting membrane (ILM) flap. All patients underwent 25-gauge pars plana vitrectomy with Brilliant Blue G-assisted ILM manipulation, inversion of a superior semicircular flap to cover the macular hole, and 20% sulfur hexafluoride (SF&#x2086;) tamponade. Postoperative assessment included decimal best-corrected visual acuity (BCVA) and spectral-domain optical coherence tomography (OCT). All eyes achieved immediate macular hole closure, and complete retinal reattachment was attained after 18-24 months. Final BCVA improved in two eyes (from 0.1 to 0.4) and remained 0.2 in one eye, underscoring delayed but meaningful recovery in hyperopic MHRD treated with a semicircular inverted ILM flap. OCT demonstrated stepwise foveal restoration with variable ellipsoid zone/external limiting membrane (ELM/EZ) integrity across cases, and no intraoperative complications, macular hole reopening, or recurrent detachment were observed. These findings indicate that in hyperopic MHRD, a semicircular inverted ILM flap is feasible and mechanically reliable for early hole closure, while SRF absorption and functional recovery may require prolonged follow-up, likely reflecting the timeline of outer-retinal reconstruction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Inuzuka et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Inuzuka</LastName><ForeName>Masayuki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology and Visual Sciences, Gifu University, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Gifu, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kubota</LastName><ForeName>Masaomi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology and Visual Sciences, Gifu University, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Gifu, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Kubota Eye Clinic, Gifu, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takaki</LastName><ForeName>Norifumi</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hisatomi</LastName><ForeName>Toshio</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology and Visual Sciences, Gifu University, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Gifu, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Hirokazu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology and Visual Sciences, Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inverted internal limiting membrane flap</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macular hole retinal detachment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optical coherence tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outer retinal layer restoration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pars plana vitrectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">semicircular ilm flap technique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subretinal fluid absorption</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Gifu University Graduate School of Medicine, Ethics Committee for Medical and Clinical Research issued approval Not applicable. This case report describes an anonymized patient, and ethics committee approval was not required at Gifu University. Written informed consent for publication of this case, including images, was obtained from the patient. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: Hirokazu Sakaguchi declare(s) personal fees from Santen. Hirokazu Sakaguchi declare(s) personal fees from Senjyu. Hirokazu Sakaguchi declare(s) personal fees from Alcon. Hirokazu Sakaguchi declare(s) personal fees from Chugai. Hirokazu Sakaguchi declare(s) personal fees from Hoya. Hirokazu Sakaguchi declare(s) personal fees from Novartis. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41141185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12552190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.93149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Inverted internal limiting membrane flap technique for large macular holes. Michalewska Z, Michalewski J, Adelman RA, Nawrocki J. Ophthalmology. 2010;117:2018&#x2013;2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitrectomy with inverted internal limiting membrane flap versus internal limiting membrane peeling for macular hole retinal detachment in high myopia: a systematic review of literature and meta-analysis. Xu Q, Luan J. Eye (Lond) 2019;33:1626&#x2013;1634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31073163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inverted internal limiting membrane flap technique for macular hole coexistent with rhegmatogenous retinal detachment. Stappler T, Montesel A, Konstantinidis L, Wolfensberger TJ, Eandi CM. Retina. 2022;42:1491&#x2013;1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9301978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35439799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persistent subretinal fluid after vitrectomy for macular hole-associated retinal detachment. Cheng FH, Lin HH, Zhu YC, et al. Retina. 2024;44:782&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38237083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macular hole closure over residual subretinal fluid by an inverted internal limiting membrane flap technique in patients with macular hole retinal detachment in high myopia. Okuda T, Higashide T, Kobayashi K, Ikuno Y, Sugiyama K. Retin Cases Brief Rep. 2016;10:140&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26383517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The dynamic healing process of idiopathic macular holes after surgical repair: a spectral-domain optical coherence tomography study. Bottoni F, De Angelis S, Luccarelli S, Cigada M, Staurenghi G. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2011;52:4439&#x2013;4446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21345999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Restoration process of the outer retinal layers after surgical macular hole closure. Iwasaki M, Ando R, Aoki S, Miyamoto H. Retina. 2022;42:313&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34723901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship between Full-Thickness Macular Hole Onset and Posterior Vitreous Detachment: A Temporal Onset Theory. Sakaguchi H, Kabata D, Sakimoto S, et al. Ophthalmol Sci. 2023;3:100339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10318498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37409190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The multifunctional choroid. Nickla DL, Wallman J. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2010;29:144&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2913695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inverted internal limiting membrane insertion versus standard internal limiting membrane peeling for macular hole retinal detachment in high myopia: one-year study. Wakabayashi T, Ikuno Y, Shiraki N, Matsumura N, Sakaguchi H, Nishida K. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2018;256:1387&#x2013;1393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29911271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inverted internal limiting membrane flap technique for treatment of macular hole retinal detachment in highly myopic eyes. Takahashi H, Inoue M, Koto T, Itoh Y, Hirota K, Hirakata A. Retina. 2018;38:2317&#x2013;2326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29065014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autologous transplantation of the internal limiting membrane for refractory macular holes. Morizane Y, Shiraga F, Kimura S, et al. Am J Ophthalmol. 2014;157:861&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24418265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>