<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41116928</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intravitreal Faricimab for the Management of Bilateral Macular Neovascularization Secondary to Macular Telangiectasia Type 2.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e92696</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e92696</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e92696</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.92696</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Macular telangiectasia type 2 (MacTel2) is a bilateral neurodegenerative disease characterized by telangiectasia of macular vasculature and foveal atrophy that is typically acquired during middle age. It may lead to visual loss due to progressive reduction of photoreceptor function or secondary to macular neovascularization. We report a case of bilateral macular neovascularization associated with MacTel2, which was treated with intravitreal faricimab injections. A 52-year-old female presented with a history of progressive reduction of vision in both eyes. Dilated fundus examination revealed the presence of perifoveal telangiectasia and right-angled venules in the juxtafoveal region. Diagnosis of MacTel2 and associated macular neovascularization (MNV) was confirmed with fundus fluorescein angiography (FA), optical coherence tomography (OCT), and angiography (OCTA). The patient was treated with three bilateral injections of faricimab on a monthly basis. Following the last injection, there was improvement of best corrected visual acuity (BCVA), reduction of macular thickening on OCT, and shrinkage of the MNV on OCTA. This is the first reported case of usage of intravitreal injection of faricimab for the management of visual loss due to macular neovascularization due to MacTel2.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Rao et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Prasan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Medcare Eye Centre, Dubai, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Anupama</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Medcare Eye Centre, Dubai, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaffer</LastName><ForeName>Jabeen Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Medcare Eye Centre, Dubai, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>John</LastName><ForeName>Ansu Sara</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology, Medcare Eye Centre, Dubai, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ellipsoid zone integrity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">faricimab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intraretinal cavitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macular neovascularization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macular telangiectasia type 2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Ahmed Abdelhameed &amp; Samer Hatoum issued approval not applicable. It is the principal investigator's responsibility to inform the committee of any changes in the research protocol and/or the research methodology, should the need for these changes arise prior to or during the conduct of this research study. The approval is valid for 1 year from the date of the approval. No breach in patient confidentiality is permitted. After completion of research, a copy of the final research report should be submitted for the records. . Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41116928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12535685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.92696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic juxtafoveolar retinal telangiectasis. Gass JD, Oyakawa RT. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7082207/ Arch Ophthalmol. 1982;100:769&#x2013;780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7082207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic macular telangiectasia. Yannuzzi LA, Bardal AM, Freund KB, et al. Arch Ophthalmol. 2006;124:450&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16606869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optical coherence tomography findings in nonproliferative group 2a idiopathic juxtafoveal retinal telangiectasis. Cohen SM, Cohen ML, El-Jabali F, Pautler SE. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17218917/ Retina. 2007;27:59&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17218917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optical coherence tomographic features of macular telangiectasia type 2: Korean macular telangiectasia type 2 study-report no. 1. Kim YH, Chung YR, Oh J, et al.  https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-020-73803-9. Sci Rep. 2020;10:825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7538897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The M&#xfc;ller cell: a functional element of the retina. Newman E, Reichenbach A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8843598/ Trends Neurosci. 1996;19:307&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8843598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long term follow-up of visual acuity and incidence of subretinal neovascularization in Mactel type 2 in 82 eyes. Marsonia K, Kiran Chandra K, Ali MH, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34027801/ Semin Ophthalmol. 2022;37:136&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macular telangiectasia type 2: a comprehensive review. Kedarisetti KC, Narayanan R, Stewart MW, et al.  https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9553319/ Clin Ophthalmol. 2022;16:3297&#x2013;3309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9553319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faricimab for neovascular age-related macular degeneration and diabetic macular edema: from preclinical studies to phase 3 outcomes. Agostini H, Abreu F, Baumal CR, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38847896/ Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2024;262:3437&#x2013;3451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11584429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38847896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of faricimab for macular edema due to retinal vein occlusion: 24-week results from the BALATON and COMINO trials. Tadayoni R, Paris LP, Danzig CJ, et al. Ophthalmology. 2024;131:950&#x2013;960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38280653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic juxtafoveolar retinal telangiectasis: update of classification and follow-up study. Gass JD, Blodi BA. Ophthalmology. 1993:1536&#x2013;1546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8414413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juxtafoveal telangiectasis-a name change? Gass JD. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/15187680/ Retina. 2005;25:234&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15689826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Identification of intraretinal neovascularization by high-speed indocyanine green angiography in idiopathic perifoveal telangiectasia. Soheilian M, Tavallali A, Peyman GA. Ophthalmic Surg Lasers Imaging. 2007;38:167&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17396702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic juxtafoveolar retinal telangiectasis: a current review. Nowilaty SR, Al-Shamsi HN, Al-Khars W. Middle East Afr J Ophthalmol. 2010;17:224&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2934714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20844678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revakinagene taroretcel: first approval. Hoy SM. Mol Diagn Ther. 2025;29:553&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12343658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40540142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neovascular membranes associated with idiopathic juxtafoveolar telangiectasis. Engelbrecht NE, Aaberg TM Jr, Sung J, Lewis ML. Arch Ophthalmol. 2002;120:320&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11879135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of idiopathic macular telangiectasia type 2. Khodabande A, Roohipoor R, Zamani J, et al. Ophthalmol Ther. 2019;8:155&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6514016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30788805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranibizumab for macular telangiectasia type 2 in the absence of subretinal neovascularization. Do DV, Bressler SB, Cassard SD, et al. Retina. 2014;34:2063&#x2013;2071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24978428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monthly ranibizumab for nonproliferative macular telangiectasia type 2: a 12-month prospective study. Charbel Issa P, Finger RP, Kruse K, et al. Am J Ophthalmol. 2011;151:876&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anti-vascular endothelial growth factor treatment outcomes in macular telangiectasia: a systematic review. Sriranganathan A, Grad J, Mihalache A, et al. Ophthalmologica. 2025;248:123&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11999654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39961284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>