<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41414010</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0250-3301</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Huan jing ke xue= Huanjing kexue</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Huan Jing Ke Xue</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Interaction and Zoning Management of Landscape Ecological Risk and Ecosystem Services around Poyang Lake from Multi-scale Perspective].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7918</StartPage><EndPage>7934</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7918-7934</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.13227/j.hjkx.202412081</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Optimizing landscape structure and patterns can effectively reduce regional landscape ecological risks and promote the sustainable supply of ecosystem services. Taking the area around Poyang Lake as the research object, based on the land use data of three periods in 2000, 2010, and 2020, and using Pearson correlation analysis, bivariate Moran index, coupling coordination degree, and other research methods, the temporal and spatial interaction between landscape ecological risk and ecosystem services was explored from a multi-scale perspective. The results show that&#xff1a; &#x2460; In the past 20 years, the landscape ecological risk around Poyang Lake has slightly increased, and the overall landscape ecological risk level was low. Overall, ecosystem services showed a spatial distribution pattern of low in the middle and high in the surrounding areas, high in the east and low in the west, with a downward trend in time. &#x2461; In the past 20 years, the landscape ecological risk and ecosystem services and their subsystems in the Poyang Lake area have been negatively correlated on three scales. Their spatial clustering effect was stronger at the basin scale but weaker at the administrative scale, and their negative spatial correlation has been slightly weakened over the past 20 years. &#x2462; In the past 20 years, the coupling and coordination degree of landscape pattern and ecosystem services and their subsystems were high, but it showed a slight downward trend, with a distribution pattern of high around the lake and low in the middle. &#x2463; On the whole, the low-risk and high-supply areas were mainly distributed in the eastern hills and mountains, the high-risk and low-supply areas were mainly distributed in the Greater Nanchang metropolitan area in the middle, the low-risk and low-supply areas were scattered in the north and middle, and the high-risk and high-supply areas were alternately distributed in the zone between the east and the middle. Based on the spatial correlation and coupling coordination on various scales, the study area was divided into four types for differentiated control. The research results provide reference for a comprehensive understanding of the spatio-temporal interactive coupling relationship and complex response mechanism between landscape ecological risk and ecosystem services.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Fang</ForeName><Initials>XF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Land Resources and Environment, Jiangxi Agricultural University, Nanchang 330045, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Shao-Kang</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Field Scientific Observation and Research Station for Ecological Protection Red Line in Poyang Lake Basin of the Ministry of Natural Resources, Nanchang 330025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangxi Institute of Land Space Survey and Planning, Nanchang 330025, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Zhi-Jun</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Land Resources and Environment, Jiangxi Agricultural University, Nanchang 330045, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Song-Kai</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Land Resources and Environment, Jiangxi Agricultural University, Nanchang 330045, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Xin-Ran</ForeName><Initials>XR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Land Resources and Environment, Jiangxi Agricultural University, Nanchang 330045, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>chi</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>Huan Jing Ke Xue</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8405344</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0250-3301</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">around Poyang Lake area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coupling coordination degree</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ecosystem services value&#xff08;ESV&#xff09;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">landscape ecological risk&#xff08;LER&#xff09;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multiple scale</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spatial correlation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41414010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13227/j.hjkx.202412081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>