<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41324462</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Patellar obliquity causes altered patellofemoral biomechanics in total knee replacement: An in vitro study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70201</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Patellofemoral joint (PFJ) complications are a common cause of dissatisfaction and revision after total knee arthroplasty (TKA). Asymmetric patellar resections may alter PFJ biomechanics. This study investigated the effects of patellar obliquity on PFJ kinematics and contact forces in a cadaveric model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eleven fresh-frozen cadaveric knees (mean age 71.2 years) were resurfaced under three conditions: neutral thickness, medial-thick oblique (+2&#x2009;mm) and lateral-thick oblique (+2&#x2009;mm). A six-degree-of-freedom robotic system simulated passive flexion (0&#xb0;-90&#xb0;) and stair descent (10&#xb0;-60&#xb0;). Kinematics were measured with optical tracking; PFJ forces were recorded using a calibrated three-zone sensor (C1-C3). Kruskal-Wallis tests with Bonferroni-adjusted post hoc comparisons were applied (&#x3b1;&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">During passive flexion, medial-thick oblique produced greater medialization than native and lateral-thick (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.013 and p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.009, respectively) and increased internal rotation versus native (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Central ridge pressure (C2) was higher in medial-thick versus lateral-thick (0.80&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.54&#x2009;V vs. 0.52&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.44&#x2009;V; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0189). Composite PFJ force (Newtons) did not differ between groups (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.9126). During stair descent, medial-thick oblique showed greater medialization than native and lateral-thick (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.017 and p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.039) and increased internal rotation versus native (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). C2 was higher in medial-thick than neutral (0.77&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.49&#x2009;V vs. 0.50&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.49&#x2009;V; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0106) and lateral-thick (0.45&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.42&#x2009;V; p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0169). Composite force again showed no between-group difference (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.3186).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patellar obliquity alters PFJ tracking and regional loading-even without increasing total joint force-with a medial-thick oblique patella consistently elevating central ridge pressures. Prioritizing symmetric patellar resection may help avoid maltracking and focal overload that predispose to PFJ-related symptoms following TKA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level IV, controlled laboratory study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shatrov</LastName><ForeName>Jobe</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3073-2416</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Musculoskeletal Health, Kolling Institute, Faculty of Medicine and Health, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Landmark Orthopaedics, St. Leonards, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mounir Boudali</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Musculoskeletal Health, Kolling Institute, Faculty of Medicine and Health, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abe</LastName><ForeName>Koki</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Musculoskeletal Health, Kolling Institute, Faculty of Medicine and Health, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parker</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Landmark Orthopaedics, St. Leonards, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatic Surgery, Royal North Shore Hospital, St. Leonards, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clarke</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Musculoskeletal Health, Kolling Institute, Faculty of Medicine and Health, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Murray Maxwell Biomechanics Laboratory, Kolling Institute, Northern Sydney Local Health District, St. Leonards, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walter</LastName><ForeName>William L</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sydney Musculoskeletal Health, Kolling Institute, Faculty of Medicine and Health, University of Sydney, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatic Surgery, Royal North Shore Hospital, St. Leonards, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Murray Maxwell Biomechanics Laboratory, Kolling Institute, Northern Sydney Local Health District, St. Leonards, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Ramsay Healthcare Australia</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Smith &amp; Nephew</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Physician Fund Royal North Shore Hospital, Sydney</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">contact forces</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kinematics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patella obliquity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patellofemoral joint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total knee arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41324462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Anglin C, Brimacombe JM, Wilson DR, Masri BA, Greidanus NV, Tonetti J, et al. Intraoperative vs. weightbearing patellar kinematics in total knee arthroplasty: a cadaveric study. Clin Biomech. 2008;23:60&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anglin C, Ho KCT, Briard JL, de Lambilly C, Plaskos C, Nodwell E, et al. In vivo patellar kinematics during total knee arthroplasty. Comput Aided Surg. 2008;13:377&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Orthopaedic Association. National Joint Replacement Registry: 2024 Annual Report. Adelaide (AU): Australian Orthopaedic Association; 2024. p. 270&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldini A, Anderson JA, Cerulli&#x2010;Mariani P, Kalyvas J, Pavlov H, Sculco TP. Patellofemoral evaluation after total knee arthroplasty. Validation of a new weight&#x2010;bearing axial radiographic view. J Bone Joint Surg. 2007;89:1810&#x2013;1817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldini A, Anderson JA, Zampetti P, Pavlov H, Sculco TP. A new patellofemoral scoring system for total knee arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2006;452:150&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batailler C, Greiner S, Rekik HL, Olivier F, Servien E, Lustig S. Intraoperative patellar tracking assessment during image&#x2010;based robotic&#x2010;assisted total knee arthroplasty: technical note and reliability study. SICOT&#x2010;J. 2024;10:44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengs BC, Scott RD. The effect of patellar thickness on intraoperative knee flexion and patellar tracking in total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2006;21:650&#x2013;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudali AM, Shatrov J, Abe K, Zavala M, Parker D, Walter WL, et al. A novel in vitro experimental design for biomechanical testing of patellofemoral joint kinetics and kinematics. SICOT&#x2010;J. 2025;11:49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camp CL, Martin JR, Krych AJ, Taunton MJ, Spencer&#x2010;Gardner L, Trousdale RT. Resection technique does affect resection symmetry and thickness of the patella during total knee arthroplasty: a prospective randomized trial. J Arthroplasty. 2015;30:2110&#x2013;2115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KC, Gill GS. Postoperative patellar tilt in total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 1999;14:300&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlmann S, Ziegeler K, Mau&#x2010;M&#xf6;ller A, Mittelmeier W, Bergschmidt P. Patellar tracking in total knee arthroplasty&#x2010;influence on clinical and functional outcome. Diagnostics. 2022;12:1082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeOrio JK, Peden JP. Accuracy of haptic assessment of patellar symmetry in total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2004;19:629&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahmand F, Tahmasbi MN, Amis AA. Lateral force&#x2010;displacement behaviour of the human patella and its variation with knee flexion&#x2014;a biomechanical study in vitro. J Biomech. 1998;31:1147&#x2013;1152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri R, Digennaro V, Panciera A, Bulzacki Bogucki BD, Cecchin D, Manzetti M, et al. Management of patella maltracking after total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review. Musculoskelet Surg. 2023;107:143&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh KM, Merican AM, Iranpour F, Deehan DJ, Amis AA. The effect of femoral component rotation on the extensor retinaculum of the knee. J Orthop Res. 2010;28:1136&#x2013;1141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh KM, Merican AM, Iranpour F, Deehan DJ, Amis AA. The effect of overstuffing the patellofemoral joint on the extensor retinaculum of the knee. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2009;17:1211&#x2013;1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiaghajani S, Bahrami O, Hefzosseheh M, Alaei M, Mehrvar A, Poursalehian M. Anatomic patella design versus medialized dome design in the modern posterior stabilized (ATTUNE) total knee arthroplasty: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Orthop Surg. 2025;20:442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heegaard J, Leyvraz PF, Curnier A, Rakotomanana L, Huiskes R. The biomechanics of the human patella during passive knee flexion. J Biomech. 1995;28:1265&#x2013;1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirschmann MT, Moser LB, Amsler F, Behrend H, Leclerq V, Hess S. Functional knee phenotypes: a novel classification for phenotyping the coronal lower limb alignment based on the native alignment in young non&#x2010;osteoarthritic patients. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2019;27:1394&#x2013;1402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper J, Walker P, Hsu TT, Kurtz A, Reynolds R, Hennessy D, et al. Biomechanical implications of an oblique knee joint line. J Knee Surg. 2018;31:761&#x2013;766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu HC, Luo ZP, Rand JA, An KN. Influence of patellar thickness on patellar tracking and patellofemoral contact characteristics after total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 1996;11:69&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huberti HH, Hayes WC. Patellofemoral contact pressures. The influence of q&#x2010;angle and tendofemoral contact. J Bone Joint Surg. 1984;66:715&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenny JY, Lef&#xe8;bvre Y, Vernizeau M, Lavaste F, Skalli W. [In vitro analysis of the continuous active patellofemoral kinematics of the normal and prosthetic knee]. Rev Chir Orthop Reparatrice Appar Mot. 2002;88:797&#x2013;802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawano T, Miura H, Nagamine R, Urabe K, Matsuda S, Mawatari T, et al. Factors affecting patellar tracking after total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2002;17:942&#x2013;947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutserimpas C, Saffarini M, Bonnin M, Hirschmann MT, Lustig S. Optimizing the patellofemoral compartment in total knee arthroplasty: is it time for dynamic assessment? Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:387&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledger M, Shakespeare D, Scaddan M. Accuracy of patellar resection in total knee replacement. A study using the medial pivot knee. Knee. 2005;12:13&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee TQ, Gerken AP, Glaser FE, Kim WC, Anzel SH. Patellofemoral joint kinematics and contact pressures in total knee arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1997;(340):257&#x2013;266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee TQ, Yang BY, Sandusky MD, McMahon PJ. The effects of tibial rotation on the patellofemoral joint: assessment of the changes in in situ strain in the peripatellar retinaculum and the patellofemoral contact pressures and areas. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2001;38:463&#x2013;469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merican AM, Ghosh KM, Baena FRY, Deehan DJ, Amis AA. Patellar thickness and lateral retinacular release affects patellofemoral kinematics in total knee arthroplasty. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22:526&#x2013;533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merican AM, Ghosh KM, Iranpour F, Deehan DJ, Amis AA. The effect of femoral component rotation on the kinematics of the tibiofemoral and patellofemoral joints after total knee arthroplasty. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2011;19:1479&#x2013;1487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mochizuki T, Yano K, Ikari K, Hiroshima R, Okazaki K. Effect on patellar kinematics of the different patellar component designs in total knee arthroplasty: intraoperative measurement of dome type versus anatomic type. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2020;30:419&#x2013;424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh JH, Kim NY, Song KI. Intraoperative patellar maltracking and postoperative radiographic patellar malalignment were more frequent in cases of complete medial collateral ligament release in cruciate&#x2010;retaining total knee arthroplasty. Knee Surg Relat Res. 2021;33:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagnano MW, Trousdale RT. Asymmetric patella resurfacing in total knee arthroplasty. Am J Knee Surg. 2000;13:228&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rex EL, Gaudelli C, Illical EM, Person J, Arlt KCT, Wylant B, et al. Guiding device for the patellar cut in total knee arthroplasty: design and validation. Bioengineering. 2018;5:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shatrov J, Khasian M, Lording T, Monk AP, Parker D, Lustig S. Robotic assessment of patella tracking in total knee arthroplasty. J ISAKOS. 2024;9:100287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shon OJ, Kim GB. The design of the patellar component does not affect the patient&#x2010;reported outcome measures in primary posterior&#x2010;stabilized total knee arthroplasty: a randomized prospective study. J Clin Med. 2022;11:1363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuma S, Kato S, Usami T, Hattori Y, Joyo Y, Shiraga H, et al. Internal rotational patellar resection and patella alta induced patellar maltracking in total knee arthroplasty: intraoperative measurement of the patellofemoral pressure. Knee Surg Relat Res. 2024;36:25.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>