<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41380013</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1603</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical neurophysiology : official publication of the American Electroencephalographic Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High-Gain Analysis of Postictal sEEG Suppression Identifies Otherwise Invisible Multifrequency Activity, Including Persisting Ictal Discharges.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNP.0000000000001221</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Recent studies have challenged the assumption that brain activity is absent or only slow postictally, with reports of higher frequency activity. However, there are conflicting reports as to whether such activity is present under significant postictal suppression. To address this question, we performed a high-gain review combined with spectrographic analysis of postictal stereo-EEG suppression.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The postictal stereo-EEG of six focal to bilateral tonic-clonic seizures was reviewed both at standard gain (50-100 &#x3bc;V/mm) and at ultra-high gain (2-5 &#x3bc;V/mm). Time-frequency spectrographic analysis was performed of one channel in the seizure onset zone during the periictal period. Power of the gamma frequency band was quantified in the first 15 seconds postictally and compared with a preictal baseline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">(1) Review at ultra-high gain identified an otherwise invisible evolving mixed-frequency background including high-frequency oscillatory activity, continuing ictal activity in one seizure, and early sharp activity (83.33%). (2) Activity was present despite significant suppression (18.46 &#x3bc;V in the seizure onset zone channel). (3) Time-frequency spectrogram revealed a steep drop of EEG power postictally, including gamma power, yet power was not completely absent.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">(1) Although the stereo-EEG appeared suppressed postictally, the combination of direct review at ultra-high gain and spectrographic analysis identified otherwise invisible low-power activity. (2) We found intermittent high-frequency oscillatory activity, early postictal sharp activity, as well as the first report of persistent ictal discharges under apparent suppression. (3) Unmasking this activity could help explain postictal seizure-like behaviors and would challenge how the onset of the postictal state is declared.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 by the American Clinical Neurophysiology Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karkar</LastName><ForeName>Kameel M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4072-2385</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology, University of Texas Health San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koneru</LastName><ForeName>Sreekanth</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology, University of Texas Health San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Werry-McFarlin</LastName><ForeName>Amy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology, University of Texas Health San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karkar</LastName><ForeName>Meera C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California, Berkeley, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiedner</LastName><ForeName>Crystal D</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas Health San Antonio, Biggs Institute, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Himali</LastName><ForeName>Jayandra J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas Health San Antonio, Biggs Institute, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Papanastassiou</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Texas Health San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szabo</LastName><ForeName>Charles Akos</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6731-3245</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology, University of Texas Health San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Neurophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506708</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0736-0258</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PGES</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postictal gamma power</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postictal high-frequency oscillations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postictal semiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postictal state</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Postictal suppression</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None of the authors has any conflict of interest to disclose relative to the content of this publication. We confirm that we have read the Journal's position on issues involved in ethical publication and affirm that this report is consistent with those guidelines. This study was approved by the University of Texas Health San Antonio institutional Review Board, with an exemption from informed consent because of the retrospective records review nature of the study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41380013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNP.0000000000001221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004691-990000000-00277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fisher RS, Schachter SC. The postictal state: a neglected entity in the management of epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav 2000;1:52&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doudoux H, Fournier M, Vercueil L. Postictal syndrome: the forgotten continent. An overview of the clinical, biochemical and imaging features. Rev Neurol (Paris) 20202020;176:62&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pottk&#xe4;mper JCM, Hofmeijer J, van Waarde JA, van Putten MJAM. The postictal state&#x2013;what do we know?. Epilepsia 2020;61:1045&#x2013;1061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesdorffer DC, Tomson T, Benn E, et al. Combined analysis of risk factors for SUDEP. Epilepsia 2011;52:1150&#x2013;1159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajakulendran S, Nashef L. Postictal generalized EEG suppression and SUDEP: a review. J Clin Neurophysiol 2015;32:14&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryvlin P, Nashef L, Lhatoo SD, et al. Incidence and mechanisms of cardiorespiratory arrests in epilepsy monitoring units (MORTEMUS): a retrospective study. Lancet Neurol 2013;12:966&#x2013;977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lhatoo SD, Faulkner HJ, Dembny K, Trippick K, Johnson C, Bird JM. An electroclinical case-control study of sudden unexpected death in epilepsy. Ann Neurol 2010;68:787&#x2013;796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher RS, Engel JJ. Definition of the postictal state: when does it start and end?. Epilepsy Behav 2010;19:100&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altenm&#xfc;ller DM, Schulze-Bonhage A, Elger CE, Surges R. Local brain activity persists during apparently generalized postictal EEG suppression. Epilepsy Behav 2016;62:218&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmaeili B, Weisholtz D, Tobochnik S, et al. Association between postictal EEG suppression, postictal autonomic dysfunction, and sudden unexpected death in epilepsy: evidence from intracranial EEG. Clin Neurophysiol 2023;146:109&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xf6;nberger J, Birk N, Lachner-Piza D, D&#xfc;mpelmann M, Schulze-Bonhage A, Jacobs J. High-frequency oscillations mirror severity of human temporal lobe seizures. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 2019;6:2479&#x2013;2488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman LM, Mendiratta A, Liou JY, et al. Postictal clinical and electroencephalographic activity following intracranially recorded bilateral tonic-clonic seizures. Epilepsia 2019;60:74&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchi A, Giusiano B, King M, et al. Postictal electroencephalographic (EEG) suppression: a stereo-EEG study of 100 focal to bilateral tonic-clonic seizures. Epilepsia 2019;60:63&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell JS, Colangeli R, Wolff MD, et al. Postictal hypoperfusion/hypoxia provides the foundation for a unified theory of seizure-induced brain abnormalities and behavioral dysfunction. Epilepsia 2017;58:1493&#x2013;1501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGonigal A, Marquis P, Medina S, et al. Postictal stereo-EEG changes following bilateral tonic-clonic seizures. Epilepsia 2019;60:1743&#x2013;1745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunez P, Srinivasan R. Electrical fields of the brain. 2nd ed. New York, NY: Oxford University Press, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karkar K, Karkar M, Papanastassiou A, Szabo CA. High gain sEEG study of early postictal sharp activity: Comparison with the interictal irritative zone. American Epilepsy Society, 2020. www.aesnet.org</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xe9;mi J, Noachtar S. Clinical features of the postictal state: correlation with seizure variables. Epilepsy Behav 2010;19:114&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed W, Ahuja N, Shah A. Palinacousis-evidence to suggest a post-ictal phenomenon. J Neurol Sci 2012;317:6&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subota A, Khan S, Josephson CB, et al. Signs and symptoms of the postictal period in epilepsy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Epilepsy Behav 2019;94:243&#x2013;251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba-Armah DM, Donner EJ, Ochi A, et al. Saved by the bell: near SUDEP during intracranial EEG monitoring. Epilepsia Open 2018;3:98&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson M, Samudra N, Gallagher MJ, Abou-Khalil B, Nobis WP. Near SUDEP during bilateral stereo-EEG monitoring characterized by diffuse postictal EEG suppression. Epilepsia 2021;62:e60&#x2013;e64.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>