<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41617905</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhancing cucumber production through compost and plant growth promoting rhizobacteria in an unheated soil based greenhouse.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6742</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6742</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6742</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-36907-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">The transition toward more sustainable horticultural practices requires approaches that maintain productivity while reducing environmental impact. The use of organic amendments such as compost and plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria (PGPR) offers environmentally friendly strategies to enhance soil health, nutrient availability, and plant resilience. Here, we investigated the effects of different compost doses and PGPR inoculation on plant growth, yield, and fruit quality of greenhouse-grown cucumber, cv. &#x2018;Oscar&#x2019;. Compost was applied to the upper 10 cm depth of soil at four rates (0 g m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup>, 100 g m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup>, 200 g m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup>, 300 g m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup>) and two PGPR strains, <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> and <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i>, were applied twice to the root zone. Correlation analysis and Principal Component Analysis were used to evaluate associations between growth parameters, yield, and leaf nutrient status. The interaction between compost and PGPR significantly increased root fresh and dry weight. The most effective treatment&#x2014;200 g m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup> compost combined with <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i>&#x2014;enhanced marketable yield by 9.3% relative to the untreated control. Yield improvements were closely linked to increased nutrient uptake, particularly magnesium (Mg) and phosphorus (P), as confirmed by PCA. The highest nutrient enrichment was observed with the 300 g m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup> compost + <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> treatment, where Mg and P increased by 13.5% and 27%, respectively, compared to the control. Overall, the combination of compost at 200 g m<sup>&#x2212;2</sup> with <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> represents a practical and sustainable strategy to improve cucumber performance under greenhouse conditions. Future research should assess its effectiveness across diverse soil types, stress conditions, and production systems to optimize long-term implementation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-36907-2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Memel&#x130;</LastName><ForeName>&#x130;brahim</ForeName><Initials>&#x130;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agriculture, Ege University, Bornova, 35100, &#x130;zmir, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>T&#xfc;zel</LastName><ForeName>Y&#xfc;ksel</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agriculture, Ege University, Bornova, 35100, &#x130;zmir, T&#xfc;rkiye. yuksel.tuzel@ege.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Durdu</LastName><ForeName>Tun&#xe7;</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agriculture, Ege University, Bornova, 35100, &#x130;zmir, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tepec&#x130;k</LastName><ForeName>Mahmut</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Soil Science and Plant Nutrition, Faculty of Agriculture, Ege University, Bornova, 35100, &#x130;zmir, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gruda</LastName><ForeName>Nazim S</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticultural Sciences, University of Bonn, INRES-Institute of Crop Science and Resource Conservation, 53113, Bonn, Germany. ngruda@uni-bonn.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacillus subtilis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pseudomonas fluorescens</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Compost dose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Greenhouse cucumber</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Principal component analysis (PCA)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Permissions and compliance statement: The experiments were conducted by the authors, and no external permissions were required for data collection. All biological materials and commercial products used in this study were properly licensed and complied with applicable regulations.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41617905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12914054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-36907-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-36907-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mishra, H. Environmental degradation and impacts on agricultural production: a challenge to urban sustainability. In <i>Sustainable Urban Environment and Waste Management: Theory and Practice</i> (eds. Parray, J. A., Shameem, N. &amp; Haghi, A. K.) 53&#x2013;92 (Springer, Singapore, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Urbanization and agriculture intensification jointly enlarge the spatial inequality of river water quality. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>878</b>, 162559 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.162559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36907406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera, M. et al. Effects of intensive agriculture and urbanization on water quality and pesticide risks in freshwater ecosystems of the Ecuadorian Amazon. <i>Chemosphere</i><b>337</b>, 139286 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2023.139286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37379974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruda, N. S., Samuolien&#x117;, G., Li, X. &amp; Dong, J. The golden mean of balancing nutritional quality and yield in greenhouse vegetable cultivation. <i>Int. J. Veg. Sci.</i><b>31</b>, 795&#x2013;802 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19315260.2025.2538489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xfc;zel, Y. &amp; Bertschinger, L. Future direction and opportunities for horticultural research. <i>Chron. Horticult</i>. <b>60</b>, 9&#x2013;19 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamatha, B. et al. Enhancing soil health and fertility management for sustainable agriculture: A review. <i>Asian J. Soil. Sci. Plant. Nutr.</i><b>10</b>, 182&#x2013;190 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ajsspn/2024/v10i3330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toor, G. S., Shober, A. L. &amp; Soils &amp; fertilizers for master gardeners: soil organic matter and organic amendments: SL273/MG454, rev. 1/2009. <i>EDIS</i><b>2009</b>, (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WWF-T&#xfc;rkiye. <i>The past, present and future of agricultural lands in Turkey</i> (in Turkish) (2021). https://wwftr.awsassets.panda.org/downloads/toprakraporu.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivero, C., Chirenje, T., Ma, L. Q. &amp; Martinez, G. Influence of compost on soil organic matter quality under tropical conditions. <i>Geoderma</i>. <b>123</b>, 355&#x2013;361 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2004.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayara, T., Basheer-Salimia, R., Hawamde, F. &amp; Sanchez, A. Recycling of organic wastes through composting: process performance and compost application in agriculture. <i>Agronomy</i>. <b>10</b>, 1838 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy10111838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan, N. Y. I., Wahed, E., Abdelhamid, N. H. A., Ashraf, A. N., Abdelfattah, E. A. &amp; M. &amp; Composting: an eco-friendly solution for organic waste management to mitigate the effects of climate change. <i>Innovare J. Social Sci.</i><b>11</b>, 1&#x2013;7 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22159/ijss.2023.v11i4.48529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assefa, S. &amp; Tadesse, S. The principal role of organic fertilizer on soil properties and agricultural productivity-a review. <i>Agric. Res. Technol. Open. Access. J.</i><b>22</b>, 1&#x2013;5 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtaza, G. et al. The impact of Biochar addition on morpho-physiological characteristics, yield and water use efficiency of tomato plants under drought and salinity stress. <i>BMC Plant. Biol.</i><b>24</b>, 356 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-024-05058-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11080165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38724950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, F. et al. Effect of selenium and compost on physiological, biochemical, and productivity of Chili under chromium stress. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 10076 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-95012-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11933677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40128359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin, B., Akhoundnejad, Y., Dasgan, H. Y. &amp; Gruda, N. S. Fulvic acid, amino acids, and vermicompost enhanced yield and improved nutrient profile of soilless iceberg lettuce. <i>Plants</i>. <b>14</b>, 609 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants14040609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11859859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40006868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;im&#x15f;ek Er&#x15f;ahin, Y. &amp; Kavd&#x131;r, Y. Alternative Plant Nutrient Sources and Soil Conditioners (in Turkish). In <i>Toprak Amenajman&#x131;</i> (eds. Er&#x15f;ahin, S., &#xd6;zta&#x15f;, T., Naml&#x131;, A. &amp; Karahan, G.) 449&#x2013;506 (Gazi Kitabevi, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeiner, C. A., Kisch, M. N., Lynch, E. D., Shrestha, P. &amp; Small, G. E. Soil microbial activity profiles associated with organic compost fertilizers in an urban garden. <i>Urban Agric. Reg. Food Syst.</i><b>9</b>, e20059 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carnimeo, C., Gelsomino, A., Cirrottola, G., Panuccio, M. R. &amp; Loffredo, E. Compost and vermicompost in cucumber rhizosphere promote plant growth and prevent the entry of anthropogenic organic pollutants. <i>Sci. Hortic.</i><b>303</b>, 111250 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2022.111250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gab Allah, E. A., Shahein, M. M., Abuarab, M. E., Shaker, V. &amp; Abdeldaym, E. A. Enhancing greenhouse cucumber production and quality utilizing organic residues as potting media through various cultivation modes and assessing application economics. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 20152 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-05242-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12181275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40542076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum, C., El-Tohamy, W. &amp; Gruda, N. Increasing the productivity and product quality of vegetable crops using arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi: a review. <i>Sci. Hortic.</i><b>187</b>, 131&#x2013;141 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2015.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgan, H., Bol, A. &amp; Gruda, N. S. Mycorrhiza improves yield and some quality properties of soilless-grown tomatoes under reduced mineral fertilization. <i>Acta Hortic.</i><b>1391</b>, 605&#x2013;612 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17660/ActaHortic.2024.1391.82</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Andrade, L. A., Santos, C. H. B., Frezarin, E. T., Sales, L. R. &amp; Rigobelo, E. C. Plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria for sustainable agricultural production. <i>Microorganisms</i>. <b>11</b>, 1088 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms11041088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10146397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37110511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal, M. Z., Singh, K. &amp; Chandra, R. Recent advances of plant growth promoting rhizobacteria (PGPR) for eco-restoration of polluted soil. <i>Clean. Eng. Technol.</i><b>23</b>, 100845 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clet.2024.100845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habtewold, J. Z. &amp; Goyal, R. K. The plant-rhizobial symbiotic interactions provide benefits to the host beyond nitrogen fixation that promote plant growth and productivity. In <i>Symbiosis in Nature</i> (ed. Rigobelo, E.) (IntechOpen, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeremko, L., Czopek, K., Staniak, M., Marenych, M. &amp; Hanhur, V. Role of environmental factors in legume-rhizobium symbiosis: A review. <i>Biomolecules</i><b>15</b>, 118 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom15010118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11764364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39858512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karapire, M. &amp; &#xd6;zg&#xf6;nen, H. Interactions between beneficial microorganisms in nature and their importance in agricultural production (in Turkish). <i>T&#xfc;rk Bilimsel Derlemeler Dergisi</i>. <b>6</b>, 149&#x2013;157 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, D. et al. Plant growth promoting rhizobacteria (PGPR) and arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi combined application reveals enhanced soil fertility and rice production. <i>Agronomy</i><b>13</b>, 550 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy13020550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai, G. K. et al. Integrating physiological, molecular, and epigenetic strategies for drought&#x2013;resilient crops. <i>CRC Crit. Rev. Plant. Sci.</i><b>44</b>, 422&#x2013;448 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgan, H. Y., Kacmaz, S., Arpaci, B. B., Ikiz, B. &amp; Gruda, N. S. Biofertilizers improve the leaf quality of hydroponically grown baby spinach (<i>Spinacia Oleracea</i> L). <i>Agronomy</i><b>13</b>, 575 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy13020575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgan, H. Y., Yilmaz, M., Dere, S., Ikiz, B. &amp; Gruda, N. S. Bio-fertilizers reduced the need for mineral fertilizers in soilless-grown Capia pepper. <i>Horticulturae</i><b>9</b>, 188 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/horticulturae9020188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgan, H. Y., Yilmaz, D., Zikaria, K., Ikiz, B. &amp; Gruda, N. S. Enhancing the yield, quality and antioxidant content of lettuce through innovative and eco-friendly biofertilizer practices in hydroponics. <i>Horticulturae</i><b>9</b>, 1274 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/horticulturae9121274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikiz, B., Dasgan, H. Y., Balik, S., Aldiyab, A. &amp; Gruda, N. S. Improved salt stress resilience, growth, and quality of soilless Basil through biostimulant application. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 35522 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-19670-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12514057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41073595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikiz, B., Dasgan, H. Y. &amp; Gruda, N. S. Utilizing the power of plant growth promoting rhizobacteria on reducing mineral fertilizer, improved yield, and nutritional quality of Batavia lettuce in a floating culture. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 1616 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-51818-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10796387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38238449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortune Business Insights. Biofertilizers market size, share &amp; industry analysis. (2025). https://www.fortunebusinessinsights.com/industry-reports/biofertilizers-market-100413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dataintelo PGPR plant growth promoting rhizobacteria market outlook. (2025). https://dataintelo.com/report/pgpr-plant-growth-promoting-rhizobacteria-market</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuzel, Y. et al. Effects of winter green manuring on organic cucumber production in unheated greenhouse conditions. <i>Turk. J. Agric. Forestry</i>. <b>37</b>, 315&#x2013;325 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solmaz, Y. et al. Effect of the various doses of vermicompost implementation on some heavy metal contents (Cr, Co, Cd, Ni, Pb) of cucumber (<i>Cucumis sativus</i> L). <i>Eurasian J. For. Sci.</i><b>5</b>, 29&#x2013;34 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, F., Wang, X. &amp; Song, N. Biochar and vermicompost improve the soil properties and the yield and quality of cucumber (<i>Cucumis sativus</i> L.) grown in plastic shed soil continuously cropped for different years. <i>Agric. Ecosyst. Environ.</i><b>315</b>, 107425 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agee.2021.107425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salim, H. A. et al. Response of cucumber plants to PGPR bacteria (<i>Azospirillum brasilense</i>, <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> and <i>Bacillus megaterium</i>) and bread yeast (<i>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</i>). <i>Syst. Rev. Pharm.</i><b>12</b>, 969&#x2013;975 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, T. et al. Enrichment of beneficial cucumber rhizosphere microbes mediated by organic acid secretion. <i>Hortic. Res.</i><b>7</b>, (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33082961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sileshi, G. W. et al. Nutrient use efficiency and crop yield response to the combined application of cattle manure and inorganic fertilizer in sub-Saharan Africa. <i>Nutr. Cycl. Agroecosyst</i>. <b>113</b>, 181&#x2013;199 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10705-019-09974-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerssa, G. W., Kim, D. G., Koal, P. &amp; Eichler-Lobermann, B. Combination of compost and mineral fertilizers as an option for enhancing maize (<i>Zea Mays</i> L.) yields and mitigating greenhouse gas emissions from a Nitisol in Ethiopia. <i>Agronomy</i><b>11</b>, 2097 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy11112097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou-El-Hassan, S., Abdrabbo, M. A. A. &amp; Desoky, A. H. Enhancing organic production of cucumber by using plant growth promoting rhizobacteria and compost tea under sandy soil condition. <i>Res. J. Agric. Biol. Sci.</i><b>10</b>, 162&#x2013;169 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasool, M., Akhter, A., Soja, G. &amp; Haider, M. S. Role of biochar, compost and plant growth promoting rhizobacteria in the management of tomato early blight disease. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>11</b>, 6092 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-85633-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7971063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33731746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ait Rahou, Y. et al. Application of plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria combined with compost as a management strategy against verticillium dahliae in tomato. <i>Can. J. Plant Pathol.</i><b>44</b>, 806&#x2013;827 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07060661.2022.2089235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multi Tohum. Oscar F1. (2025). http://www.multitohum.com/en/m/beith-alpha1/oscar-f11.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syngenta Vitalley. (2025). https://www.syngentavegetables.com/tr-tr/product/seed/anac/vitalley</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortiturkey. Serenade, S. C. (in Turkish). (2023). https://www.hortiturkey.com/urunler/serenadesc</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuhoff, D., Neumann, G. &amp; Weinmann, M. Testing plant growth promoting microorganisms in the field&#x2014;a proposal for standards. <i>Front. Plant. Sci.</i><b>14</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10824932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38293625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabanci, B. <i>The Effects of Different Doses of Compost Application on Yield and Quality in Curly Lettuce Cultivation</i> (in Turkish) (Ege Univ. Fac. Of Agric., 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wichmann, W. <i>IFA World Fertilizer Use Manual</i> (International Fertilizer Association, 1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Optimal drip fertigation management improves yield, quality, water and nitrogen use efficiency of greenhouse cucumber. <i>Sci. Hortic.</i><b>243</b>, 357&#x2013;366 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2018.08.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacar, B. &amp; &#x130;nal, A. <i>Bitki Analizleri</i> [Plant Analysis] (in Turkish) (Nobel Publishing, 2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire, R. G. Reporting of objective color measurements. <i>Hortscience</i>. <b>27</b>, 1254&#x2013;1255 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21273/HORTSCI.27.12.1254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kara&#xe7;ali, &#x130;. <i>Bah&#xe7;e &#xdc;r&#xfc;nlerinin Muhafazas&#x131; Ve Pazarlanmas&#x131;</i> [Storage and Marketing of Garden Products] (in Turkish) (Ege University, 2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davras, &#x130;., Koyuncu, M. A. &amp; Erba&#x15f;, D. Reducing quality losses during cold storage with Salicylic acid application in tomatoes (in Turkish). <i>Uluslararas&#x131; Tar&#x131;m Ve Yaban Hayat&#x131; Bilimleri Dergisi</i>. <b>5</b>, 176&#x2013;186 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24180/ijaws.536754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nas, Y. <i>Determination of the Last Irrigation Date before Harvest in Industrial Tomatoes Produced in Aegean Region Conditions and Different Soil Types</i> (in Turkish) (Ege University, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowling, C. W. &amp; Blaesing, D. T. <i>Plant Sampling for Agriculture: A Guide</i> (Fertilizer Australia, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cepuliene, R., Butkeviciene, L. M. &amp; Steponaviciene, V. Nutrient use efficiency and cucumber productivity as a function of the nitrogen fertilization rate and the wood fiber content in growing media. <i>Plants</i>. <b>13</b>, 2911 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants13202911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11510781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39458858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metsalu, T. &amp; Vilo, J. ClustVis: a web tool for visualizing clustering of multivariate data using principal component analysis and heatmap. <i>Nucleic Acids Res.</i><b>43</b>, W566&#x2013;W570 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkv468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carillo, P. et al. Biostimulant application with a tropical plant extract enhances <i>Corchorus olitorius</i> adaptation to sub-optimal nutrient regimens by improving physiological parameters. <i>Agronomy</i>. <b>9</b>, 249 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy9050249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SAS Institute. <i>JMP 8 Introductory Guide</i> (JMP Statistical Discovery LLC, 2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SAS Institute. <i>JMP&#xae; 17 Multivariate Methods</i> (JMP Statistical Discovery LLC, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. <i>R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. http://www. R-project. org/</i> (R Foundation for Statistical Computing, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham, H. Data analysis. In <i>ggplot2: Elegant Graphics for Data Analysis</i>, 189&#x2013;201 (Springer, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham, H. Reshaping data with the reshape package. <i>J. Stat. Softw.</i><b>21</b>, 1&#x2013;20 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v021.i12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunteman, G. H. <i>Principal Components Analysis</i>, vol. 69 (Sage, 1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldan, E. et al. Assessment of manure compost used as soil amendment&#x2014;A review. <i>Processes</i><b>11</b>, 1167 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11041167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade, F. C. et al. Enrichment of organic compost with beneficial microorganisms and yield performance of corn and wheat. <i>Revista Brasileira De Engenharia Agricola E Ambiental</i>. <b>25</b>, 332&#x2013;339 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1807-1929/agriambi.v25n5p332-339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imran, A. et al. Tailored bioactive compost from agri-waste improves the growth and yield of Chili pepper and tomato. <i>Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol.</i><b>9</b>, 787764 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2021.787764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8819593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoso, M. A. et al. Impact of plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria (PGPR) on plant nutrition and root characteristics: current perspective. <i>Plant. Stress</i>. <b>11</b>, 100341 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.stress.2023.100341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallaku, G., Babaj, I., Kaciu, S. &amp; Balliu, A. The influence of vermicompost on plant growth characteristics of cucumber (<i>Cucumis sativus</i> L.) seedlings under saline conditions. <i>J. Food Agric. Environ.</i><b>7</b>, 869&#x2013;872 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadeem, S. M. et al. Synergistic use of biochar, compost and plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria for enhancing cucumber growth under water deficit conditions. <i>J. Sci. Food Agric.</i><b>97</b>, 5139&#x2013;5145 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsfa.8393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28436040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Garcia, L. A. et al. Plant growth promoting rhizobacteria enhances germination and bioactive compound in cucumber seedlings under saline stress. <i>Ecosistemas Y Recursos Agropecuarios</i><b>12</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castiglione, A. M., Mannino, G., Contartese, V., Bertea, C. M. &amp; Ertani, A. Microbial biostimulants as response to modern agriculture needs: Composition, role and application of these innovative products. <i>Plants</i><b>10</b>, 1533 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants10081533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8400793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34451578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson, A. E., Barea, J. M., McNeill, A. M. &amp; Prigent-Combaret, C. Acquisition of phosphorus and nitrogen in the rhizosphere and plant growth promotion by microorganisms. <i>Plant. Soil.</i><b>321</b>, 305&#x2013;339 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11104-009-9895-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;k&#xe7;imen, H. <i>General Characteristics of Enterprises Growing Cucumber in Menderes District</i> (in Turkish) (Ege University, 2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuzel, Y. et al. Organic cucumber production in the greenhouse: A case study from Turkey. <i>Renew. Agric. Food Syst.</i><b>20</b>, 206&#x2013;213 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/RAF2005105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seymen, M., Turkmen, O., Dursun, A., D&#xf6;nmez, M. F. &amp; Paksoy, M. Effects of bacterium inoculation on yield and yield components of cucumber (<i>Cucumis sativus</i>). <i>Bull. Univ. Agric. Sci. Vet. Med. Cluj-Napoca Hortic.</i><b>67</b>, 305&#x2013;311 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gul, A., Ozaktan, H., Kidoglu, F. &amp; Tuzel, Y. Rhizobacteria promoted yield of cucumber plants grown in perlite under fusarium wilt stress. <i>Sci. Hortic.</i><b>153</b>, 22&#x2013;25 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2013.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahamd, M. et al. Improving the productivity of cucumber through combined application of organic fertilizers and <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i>. <i>Pak. J. Agric. Sci.</i><b>52</b>, 1011&#x2013;1016 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zapata-Sifuentes, G. et al. Plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria improve growth and fruit quality of cucumber under greenhouse conditions. <i>Plants</i><b>11</b>, 1612 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants11121612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9227633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35736761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Viveros, O., Jorquera, M. A., Crowley, D. E., Gajardo, G. &amp; Mora, M. L. Mechanisms and practical considerations involved in plant growth promotion by rhizobacteria. <i>J. Soil. Sci. Plant. Nutr.</i><b>10</b>, 293&#x2013;319 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/S0718-95162010000100006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutsal, &#x130;. K. <i>The Effects of some Plant Growth Promoting Rhizobacteria Species on Plant Development and Fruit Quality in Melons Grown Under Irrigated and non-irrigated Conditions</i> (in Turkish) (In&#xf6;n&#xfc; University, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Fonseca, M. et al. C. da <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> inoculation improves nutrient uptake and physiological activity in sugarcane under drought stress. <i>Microorganisms</i>. <b>10</b>, 809 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9029642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35456859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Qu, F., Liang, J., Yang, M. &amp; Hu, X. <i>Bacillus velezensis</i> SX13 promoted cucumber growth and production by accelerating the absorption of nutrients and increasing plant photosynthetic metabolism. <i>Sci. Hortic.</i><b>301</b>, 111151 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2022.111151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egamberdieva, D., Wirth, S., Bellingrath-Kimura, S. D., Mishra, J. &amp; Arora, N. K. Salt-tolerant plant growth promoting rhizobacteria for enhancing crop productivity of saline soils. <i>Front. Microbiol.</i><b>10</b>, 2791 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2019.02791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6930159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31921005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez, J. I. et al. <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> affects nutrient dynamics in plant-soil system for melon production. <i>Chil. J. Agric. Res.</i><b>79</b>, 223&#x2013;233 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/S0718-58392019000200223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orouji, E., Fathi Ghare baba, M., Sadeghi, A., Gharanjik, S. &amp; Koobaz, P. Specific streptomyces strain enhances the growth, defensive mechanism, and fruit quality of cucumber by minimizing its fertilizer consumption. <i>BMC Plant. Biol.</i><b>23</b>, 246 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-023-04259-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10173507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37170247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marschner, H. <i>Marschner&#x2019;s Mineral Nutrition of Higher Plants</i> (Academic, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, W., Nazim, H., Liang, Z. &amp; Yang, D. Magnesium deficiency in plants: an urgent problem. <i>Crop J.</i><b>4</b>, 83&#x2013;91 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cj.2015.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plaxton, W. C. &amp; Tran, H. T. Metabolic adaptations of phosphate-starved plants. <i>Plant. Physiol.</i><b>156</b>, 1006&#x2013;1015 (2011).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.111.175281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3135920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21562330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puga, M. I., Poza-Carrion, C., Martinez-Hevia, I., Perez-Liens, L. &amp; Paz-Ares, J. Recent advances in research on phosphate starvation signaling in plants. <i>J. Plant. Res.</i><b>137</b>, 315&#x2013;330 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10265-024-01545-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11081996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38668956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feil, S. B., Zuluaga, M. Y. A., Cesco, S. &amp; Pii, Y. Copper toxicity compromises root acquisition of nitrate in the high affinity range. <i>Front. Plant. Sci.</i><b>13</b>, 1034425 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2022.1034425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9895927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36743562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herben, T., Novakova, Z., Klimesova, J. &amp; Hrouda, L. Species traits and plant performance: functional trade-offs in a large set of species in a botanical garden. <i>J. Ecol.</i><b>100</b>, 1522&#x2013;1533 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2745.2012.02018.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vesela, A., Duongova, L. &amp; Munzbergova, Z. Plant origin and trade-off between generative and vegetative reproduction determine germination behaviour of a dominant grass species along climatic gradients. <i>Flora</i><b>297</b>, 152177 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.flora.2022.152177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casler, M. D. et al. Nitrogen demand associated with increased biomass yield of Switchgrass and big bluestem: implications for future breeding strategies. <i>Bioenergy Res.</i><b>13</b>, 120&#x2013;131 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12155-019-10081-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciampitti, I. et al. A global dataset to parametrize critical nitrogen Dilution curves for major crop species. <i>Sci. Data</i>. <b>9</b>, 277 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-022-01395-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9174182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35672371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalozoumis, P. et al. Impact of plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria inoculation and grafting on tolerance of tomato to combined water and nutrient stress assessed via metabolomics analysis. <i>Front. Plant. Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 670236 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2021.670236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8212936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34149768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pataczek, L. et al. Single-Strain inoculation of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> and rhizobium phaseoli affects nitrogen acquisition of an improved Mungbean cultivar. <i>J. Soil. Sci. Plant. Nutr.</i><b>24</b>, 6746&#x2013;6759 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42729-024-02001-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahirwar, N. K., Gupta, G., Singh, V., Rawlley, R. K. &amp; Ramana, S. Influence on growth and fruit yield of tomato (<i>Lycopersicon esculentum</i> Mill.) plants by inoculation with <i>Pseudomonas fluorescence</i> (SS5): possible role of plant growth promotion. <i>Int. J. Curr. Microbiol. Appl. Sci.</i><b>4</b>, 720&#x2013;730 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noureldeen, A. et al. Effect of individual, simultaneous and sequential inoculation of <i>Pseudomonas fluorescens</i> and meloidogyne incognita on growth, biochemical, enzymatic and nonenzymatic antioxidants of tomato (<i>Solanum lycopersicum</i> L). <i>Plants</i>. <b>10</b>, 1145 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants10061145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8228199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kloepper, J. W., Leong, J., Teintze, M. &amp; Schroth, M. N. Enhanced plant growth by siderophores produced by plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria. <i>Nature</i><b>286</b>, 885&#x2013;886 (1980).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/286885a0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Oliveira, C. E. Yield, nutrition, and leaf gas exchange of lettuce plants in a hydroponic system in response to <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> inoculation. <i>Front. Plant. Sci.</i><b>14</b>, 1248044 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2023.1248044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10634435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37954988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhayay, V. K. et al. Zinc-solubilizing bacterial consortia: a promising approach for zinc biofortification of crops. <i>Front. Microbiol.</i><b>16</b>, 1575514 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2025.1575514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12239759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40636493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, R. C. et al. Zinc-solubilizing <i>Bacillus</i> spp. In conjunction with chemical fertilizers enhance growth, yield, nutrient content, and zinc biofortification In wheat crop. <i>Front. Microbiol.</i><b>14</b>, 1210938 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1210938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10352851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37469421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Piqueres, A., Mart&#xed;nez-Alc&#xe1;ntara, B., Canet, R., Del Val, R. &amp; Qui&#xf1;ones, A. Plant growth-promoting microorganisms as natural stimulators of nitrogen uptake in citrus. <i>PLoS One</i>. <b>20</b>, e0311400 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0311400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11790095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39899540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwar, H. et al. Comparative effects of bio-wastes in combination with plant growth-promoting bacteria on growth and productivity of Okra. <i>Agronomy</i><b>11</b>, 2065 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy11102065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacio-Rodriguez, R., Nava-Reyes, B., Sanchez-Galvan, H., Quezada-Rivera, J. J. &amp; Saenz-Mata, J. Effect of plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria inoculation on tomato under commercial shade-house conditions. <i>Rev. Mex De Cienc. Agric.</i><b>13</b>, 231&#x2013;242 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, Z. et al. Effect of biochar-containing compost on cucumber quality and antibiotic resistance genes abundance in soil&#x2013;cucumber system. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b>, 9563 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15129563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruda, N., Savvas, D., Colla, G. &amp; Rouphael, Y. Impacts of genetic material and current technologies on product quality of selected greenhouse vegetables&#x2014;A review. <i>Eur. J. Hortic. Sci.</i><b>83</b>, 319&#x2013;328 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17660/eJHS.2018/83.5.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruda, N. S. et al. Advancing protected cultivation: A pathway for nutrient-rich vegetables. <i>CRC Crit. Rev. Plant. Sci</i><b>1&#x2013;29</b> (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafi, S. A. et al. <i>Pseudomonas putida</i> P3-57 induces cucumber (<i>Cucumis sativus</i> L.) defense responses and improves fruit quality characteristics under commercial greenhouse conditions. <i>Sci. Hortic.</i><b>280</b>, 109942 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2021.109942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favati, F. et al. Processing tomato quality as affected by irrigation scheduling. <i>Sci. Hortic.</i><b>122</b>, 562&#x2013;571 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2009.06.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>