<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41569940</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2694-1902</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>23</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neurosurgery. Case lessons</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neurosurg Case Lessons</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A rare anatomical variant of the relationship between a branch of the superior cerebellar artery and the rootlets of the trochlear nerve: illustrative case.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CASE25653</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3171/CASE25653</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The superior cerebellar artery (SCA) typically has the most consistent course of the infratentorial branches; however, variations do occur. Originating near the basilar artery (BA) bifurcation, the SCA proceeds to its pontomesencephalic segment, where it may contact the trochlear nerve (cranial nerve [CN] IV) or its rootlets emerging dorsally from the brainstem.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBSERVATIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">During routine dissection, a previously undescribed SCA variation was identified. The left SCA arose as a single trunk from the BA and divided into the rostral trunk (RoTr) and caudal trunk. The RoTr then bifurcated into the medial hemispheric artery (inferior branch) and vermian artery (superior branch). The superior branch of the RoTr gave rise to the precerebellar artery, which coursed 3.2 mm before passing between two trochlear nerve rootlets in the rootlet exit zone.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LESSONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Understanding complex anatomical variations of the SCA and its relationship to CN IV is crucial for accurate diagnosis of the trochlear nerve dysfunction and for effective surgical planning. A thorough understanding of these variations enables physicians to anticipate potential challenges and adapt their approach accordingly. Intraoperative identification of unexpected vascular patterns underscores the importance of the surgeon's knowledge of anatomical variability, which may significantly impact both safety and surgical strategy. https://thejns.org/doi/10.3171/CASE25653.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mordarski</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B&#x105;k</LastName><ForeName>Kacper</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bartoszcze</LastName><ForeName>J&#x119;drzej</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iskra</LastName><ForeName>Tomasz</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghosh</LastName><ForeName>Sanjib K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>All India Institute of Medical Sciences Patna, Bihar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noro</LastName><ForeName>Shusaku</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2985-087X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Nakamura Memorial Hospital, Sapporo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walocha</LastName><ForeName>Jerzy A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krak&#xf3;w, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Neurosurg Case Lessons</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918227275606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2694-1902</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microvascular decompression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rootlets</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superior cerebellar artery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">superior oblique myokymia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">trochlear nerve</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41569940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12684242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/CASE25653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">CASE25653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pease AP.. The Definitive Book of Body Language. Orion Publishing Group; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY Motlagh M Naqvi IA.. Neuroanatomy, cranial nerve 4 (trochlear). In: StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#x105;k K, Mordarski M, Iskra T.Variations in the number of rootlets of the trochlear nerve. Ann Anat. 2025;262:152700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40684888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline LB Demer JL Vaphiades MS Tavakoli M.. Disorders of the fourth cranial nerve. J Neuroophthalmol. 2021;41(2):176-193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33999889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freddi TAL.. The trochlear nerve: anatomy and pathology. Semin Ultrasound CT MR. 2022;43(5):400-402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36116852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandon A Oliveira C.. Superior oblique myokymia, a review. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2019;30(6):472-475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31503076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagcinar A, Kaya AH, Pirzirenli ME.The superior cerebellar artery: anatomic study with review. Neurosurg Q. 2007;17(3):235-240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusu MC Vrapciu AD P&#x103;tra&#x15f;cu JM.. Variable relations of the trochlear nerve with the pontomesencephalic segment of the superior cerebellar artery. Surg Radiol Anat. 2015;37(5):555-559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25234318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhoton AL Jr.. The cerebellar arteries. Neurosurgery. 2000;47(3)(suppl):S29-S68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10983304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#x142;aszczyk M, Dziedzic M, Stachera B.The anatomy of the superior cerebellar artery: a detailed analysis. Folia Morphol (Warsz). 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40727992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballesteros-Acu&#xf1;a L G&#xf3;mez-Torres F Estupi&#xf1;&#xe1;n HY.. Morphologic characterization of the superior cerebellar artery. A direct anatomic study. Transl Res Anat. 2021;25:100150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snow EL.. Variation is the rule: insights about translational research on anatomical variations. Transl Res Anat. 2024;37:100333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wysiadecki G, Varga I, Klejbor I.Reporting anatomical variations: should unified standards and protocol (checklist) for anatomical studies and case reports be established? Transl Res Anat. 2024;35:100284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousry I Moriggl B Dieterich M Naidich TP Schmid UD Yousry TA.. MR anatomy of the proximal cisternal segment of the trochlear nerve: neurovascular relationships and landmarks. Radiology. 2002;223(1):31-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11930045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samii M Rosahl SK Carvalho GA Krzizok T.. Microvascular decompression for superior oblique myokymia: first experience. Case report. J Neurosurg. 1998;89(6):1020-1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9833830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto M Ohtsuka K Suzuki Y Minamida Y Houkin K.. Superior oblique myokymia caused by vascular compression. J Neuroophthalmol. 2004;24(3):237-239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15348993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikami T Minamida Y Ohtsuka K Houkin K.. Resolution of superior oblique myokymia following microvascular decompression of trochlear nerve. Acta Neurochir (Wien). 2005;147(9):1005-1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16041468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaoka K Terasaka S Suzuki Y.. Microvascular decompression for superior oblique myokymia: case report and review of the literature. Skull Base. 2008;18(S 01).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fam MD Scott C Forster A Kamel MH.. Microvascular decompression for superior oblique myokymia: case report. Br J Neurosurg. 2014;28(4):552-555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24392739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawasaki T, Fujitsu K, Ichikawa T.Superior oblique myokymia: a case report of surgical treatment, review of the literature, and consideration of surgical approach. World Neurosurg. 2019;131:197-199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31299312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noro S, Seo Y, Honjo K.Lateral supracerebellar infratentorial approach for superior oblique myokymia: a case series. Oper Neurosurg. 2022;22(3):101-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabarkheel R Tomlinson S Borja AJ Ajmera S Miranda SP Lee JYK.. Fully endoscopic microvascular decompression of the trochlear nerve for treatment of medically refractory superior oblique myokymia: technical case instruction and operative video. Oper Neurosurg. 2024;29(1):135-138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39679674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vignolles-Jeong J Finger G Damante M Weber MD Wu KC Prevedello DM.. Trochlear nerve decompression by endoscopic suboccipital supracerebellar infratentorial approach: a technical note: 2-dimensional operative video. Oper Neurosurg. 2025;29(3):434-439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39774098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noro S, Asayama B, Saiki S.Superior oblique myokymia caused by vascular compression in the peripheral trochlear nerve: a case report. Neurosurg Pract. 2025;6(2):e00132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12560690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41163994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinkovi&#x107; S Gibo H Zeli&#x107; O Nikodijevi&#x107; I.. The neurovascular relationships and the blood supply of the trochlear nerve: surgical anatomy of its cisternal segment. Neurosurgery. 1996;38(1):161-169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8747965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa M, Hatayama T, Kondo A.Prosthesis used in microvascular decompressions: a multicenter survey in Japan focusing on adverse events. World Neurosurg. 2019;130:e251-e258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31207376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS Ahn YH.. Glossopharyngeal neuralgia. J Korean Neurosurg Soc. 2023;66(1):12-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9837485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36480819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng W, Zhao R, Guan F.Fully endoscopic microvascular decompression for the treatment of hemifacial spasm, trigeminal neuralgia, and glossopharyngeal neuralgia: a retrospective study. BMC Surg. 2023;23(1):331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10612333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37891595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanazawa R Uchida T Higashida T Watanabe S Takahashi Y Yamazaki K.. Use of n-butyl-2-cyanoacrylate for microvascular decompression in a Jehovah's Witness patient. Br J Neurosurg. 2024;38(6):1479-1482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35400248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng WJ, He R, Zhang X.Glue-transposition technique for hemifacial spasm involving vertebrobasilar dolichoectasia: a comparative study and literature review. Neurosurg Rev. 2025;48(1):495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40481849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sindou M Leston JM Decullier E Chapuis F.. Microvascular decompression for trigeminal neuralgia: the importance of a noncompressive technique&#x2014;Kaplan-Meier analysis in a consecutive series of 330 patients. Neurosurgery. 2008;63(4)(suppl 2):341-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18981841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsushima T Yamaguchi T Inoue TK Matsukado K Fukui M.. Recurrent trigeminal neuralgia after microvascular decompression using an interposing technique. Teflon felt adhesion and the sling retraction technique. Acta Neurochir (Wien). 2000;142(5):557-561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10898363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakuta N Abe H Nonaka M Higashi T Ueba T Inoue T.. Management of trigeminal neuralgia caused by an intraneural spiral trigeminocerebellar artery: a case report. J Neurol Surg Rep. 2015;76(1):e59-e61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4520972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26251812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Feng B, Hong W.Management of intraneural vessels during microvascular decompression surgery for trigeminal neuralgia. World Neurosurg. 2012;77(5-6):771-774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22120295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takano Y Tanaka Y Kaneoka A Imamura M Tamura K Maehara T.. A case of hemifacial spasm caused by penetration of the anterior inferior cerebellar artery between the facial nerve and the nervus intermedius. NMC Case Rep J. 2024;11:371-375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11664047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39717207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Z Yu F Xue F Wang Y Kwok SC Yin J.. Treatment strategies for different types of intraneural offending vessels in microvascular decompression surgery for trigeminal neuralgia: an analytic report of 58 cases. Neurosurgery. 2022;90(5):562-568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35175236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jito J Nozaki K.. Trigeminal neuralgia attributable to intraneural trigeminocerebellar artery: case report and review of the literature. World Neurosurg. 2016;88:687.e7-687.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26714300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto Y Inoue T.. Surgical management of the trigeminocerebellar artery in microvascular decompression for trigeminal neuralgia. Oper Neurosurg. 2020;19(4):E379-E384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32357229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helbig GM Callahan JD Cohen-Gadol AA.. Variant intraneural vein-trigeminal nerve relationships: an observation during microvascular decompression surgery for trigeminal neuralgia. Neurosurgery. 2009;65(5):958-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19834410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanayama S Shono N Inoue M.. The visualization of intraneural venous compression in trigeminal neuralgia by using advanced three-dimensional computer graphics: an illustrative case report. Cureus. 2024;16(4):e57935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11082426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38738094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar T, Virador GM, Brahmbhatt P.High-resolution 7T MR imaging of the trochlear nerve. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2023;44(2):186-191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9891327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36657953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noro S Asayama B Nakamura H.. Microvascular decompression surgery: advances and expansion of strategy and techniques. Springer Nature Singapore; 2025:201-209.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>