<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41513759</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>GIS-based assessment of land degradation vulnerability and environmental indices as ecological indicators in Western Agro-climatic zone of Tamil Nadu, India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4944</StartPage><MedlinePgn>4944</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4944</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35211-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Land degradation is a critical global issue that affects soil fertility, food production, and biomass, driven by climate change and human activities. This study evaluates land degradation (LD) vulnerability across various land use and land cover (LULC) types in the Western Agroclimatic Zone of Theni district, Tamil Nadu, India. The GIS-based land degradation vulnerability index (LDVI) is calculated to identify site-specific degradation rates by combining four indicators (QI): Soil Quality Index (SQI), Climate Quality Index (CQI), Vegetation Quality Index (VQI), and Land Management Quality Index (MQI), derived from various geo-environmental and climatic variables. The LDVI map classifies the area into four categories: (i) non- affected zones (N), (ii) potential vegetative cover (P) with LDVI&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;1. 22, (iii) fragile zones (F 1, F 2, and F 3) with LDVI values from 1. 23 to 1. 1.37, and (iv) critical zones (C 1 and C 2) with LDVI values between 1. 38 and 1. 53. A critical zone (C 3) with LDVI&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;1.53. 53 indicates a severe land degradation risk, covering 3.68% of the total area. About 25. Approximately 38% of the region is affected by severe land degradation, primarily on pediplains, barrens, and fallows, resulting from soil erosion, salinity intrusion, nutrient loss, and inadequate land management. Meanwhile, 44. 38% falls within fragile categories, primarily on alluvial plains with red loamy soils. Conversely, 26. 3% of the area is classified as lower risk zones, such as forests, plantations, and irrigated lands, which benefit from soil fertility retention and effective management. The geographic correlation analysis reveals a strong positive relationship with VQI and MQI, with &#x2018;r&#x2019; values of 0.835 and 0.831, respectively, indicating a risk to cultivable lands. Significantly, Pearson&#x2019;s correlation confirms a strong positive relationship between LDVI and SQI and VQI, with coefficient values of 0.99 and 0.84, respectively, indicating that changes in soil properties and vegetation (NDVI) have a direct influence on land degradation across various regions. These findings provide a site-specific land degradation rate and its spatial relationship to quality indicators, emphasizing the importance of land-water-soil management for mitigation. Although the LDVI map reveals a spatial pattern of land degradation at a 30&#xa0;m x 30&#xa0;m pixel scale, limited by the resolution and temporal scale of the input datasets, future work could improve the LDVI by incorporating higher-resolution input data and field observations. This research directly supports UN-SDG 2 - Zero Hunger (sustainable agriculture and food security), and SDG 13 - Climate Action (climate resilience and adaptation).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaliraj</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Earth Science Studies (NCESS), Ministry of Earth Sciences, Govt. of India, Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala, 695011, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joe</LastName><ForeName>R J Jerin</ForeName><Initials>RJJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PG and Research Department of Geology, V.O. Chidambaram College, Thoothukudi, Tamil Nadu, 628008, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>(Reg. No. 22212232221012), Sundaranar University, Tirunelveli, Tamil Nadu, 627012, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pitchaimani</LastName><ForeName>V Stephen</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PG and Research Department of Geology, V.O. Chidambaram College, Thoothukudi, Tamil Nadu, 628008, India. stephen.geo@voccollege.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abishek</LastName><ForeName>S Richard</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Centre for Earth Science Studies (NCESS), Ministry of Earth Sciences, Govt. of India, Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala, 695011, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karuppannan</LastName><ForeName>Shankar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5014-7885</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Geology, College of Applied Natural Science, Adama Science and Technology University, P.O. Box: 1888, Adama, Ethiopia. geoshankar1984@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research Analytics, Saveetha Dental College and Hospitals, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences (SIMATS), Saveetha University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600077, India. geoshankar1984@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Agro climatic zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GIS techniques</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LDVI model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Land degradation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multiparametric analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality indicators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Remote sensing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Southern india</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Human face consent to publish a declaration: We have carefully reviewed all the images in our manuscript and confirm that no human faces are present.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41513759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12877193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35211-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35211-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Afzali, S. F., Khanamani, A., Maskooni, E. K. &amp; Berndtsson, R. Quantitative assessment of environmental sensitivity to desertification using the modified MEDALUS model in a semiarid area. <i>Sustainability</i><b>13</b>, 7817 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13147817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara, A. et al. Updating the MEDALUS-ESA framework for worldwide land degradation and desertification assessment. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>31</b>, 1593&#x2013;1607 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.3559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hembram, T. K. &amp; Saha, S. Spatial land degradation vulnerability assessment in a plateau fringe river basin of Jharkhand, India. <i>Environ. Monit. Assess.</i><b>197</b>, 143 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-024-13529-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39775187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmas, C. et al. Evaluation and selection of indicators for land degradation and desertification monitoring: methodological approach. <i>Environ. Manage.</i><b>54</b>, 951&#x2013;970 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00267-013-0109-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23797485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moln&#xe1;rov&#xe1;, K. J. et al. Impacts of land consolidation on land degradation: A systematic review. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>329</b>, 117026 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2022.117026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36608617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, C. et al. Spatial assessment of land degradation using MEDALUS, focusing on potential afforestation and reforestation areas in Ethiopia. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>33</b>, 79&#x2013;93 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.4130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantechi, R. <i>Desertification in a European Context: Physical and Socio-Economic Aspects</i> (European Commission, 1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conacher, A. J. &amp; Sala, M. <i>Land Degradation in Mediterranean Environments of the World: Nature and Extent, Causes and Solutions.</i> (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmas, C., Ferrara, A. M. S., Briasouli, H. &amp; Imeson, A. Methodology for mapping environmentally sensitive areas (ESAs) to desertification. In Medalus Project Mediterranean Desertification and Land use. Manual on Key Indicators of Desertification and Mapping Environmentally Sensitive Areas To Desertification 31&#x2013;47 (European Commission, (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao, A. K. et al. Increased arid and semi-arid areas in India with associated shifts during 1971&#x2013;2004. <i>J. Agrometeorology</i>. <b>15</b>, 11&#x2013;18 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54386/jam.v15i1.1431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudjemline, F. &amp; Semar, A. Assessment and mapping of desertification sensitivity with MEDALUS model and GIS &#x2013; Case study: basin of Hodna, Algeria. <i>J. Water Land. Dev.</i><b>36</b>, 17&#x2013;26 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/jwld-2018-0002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.N.E.P. Provisional Methodology for the Assessment and Mapping of Desertification. In Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations and United Nations Environment Programme. (1983).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avni, Y., Porat, N., Plakht, J. &amp; Avni, G. Geomorphic changes leading to natural desertification versus anthropogenic land conservation in an arid environment, the Negev Highlands, Israel. <i>Geomorphology</i> 82, (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvati, L., Mavrakis, A., Colantoni, A., Mancino, G. &amp; Ferrara, A. Complex adaptive Systems, soil degradation and land sensitivity to desertification: A multivariate assessment of Italian agro-forest landscape. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>521</b>, 235&#x2013;245 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2015.03.094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25847168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharumarajan, S. et al. Status of desertification in South India&#x2013;assessment, mapping and change detection analysis. <i>Curr. Sci.</i><b>115</b>, 331&#x2013;338 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18520/cs/v115/i2/331-338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pankaj, P. K. et al. Diversification and Land Use Management Practices for Food and Nutritional Security Under the Climate Change Scenario in Arid and Semi-arid Regions of India. In <i>Food Security and Land Use Change under Conditions of Climatic Variability</i> (eds Squires, V. R. &amp; Gaur, M. K.) 281&#x2013;309 (2020). 10.1007/978-3-030-36762-6_15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNCCD. Desertification: The Invisible Frontline. UNCCD, (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, R. R. &amp; El Baroudy, A. A. Use of GIS in mapping the environmental sensitivity to desertification in Wadi El Natrun depression, Egypt. <i>Aust. J. Basic Appl. Sci.</i><b>2</b>, 157&#x2013;164 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta, S. &amp; Chaudhuri, G. Evaluating environmental sensitivity of arid and semiarid regions in Northeastern Rajasthan, India. <i>Geogr. Rev.</i><b>105</b>, 441&#x2013;461 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1931-0846.2015.12093.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budak, M., G&#xfc;nal, H. &amp; &#xc7;elik, I. Environmental sensitivity to desertification in Northern Mesopotamia; application of modified MEDALUS by using analytical hierarchy process. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>11</b>, 481 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-018-3813-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedoui, C. Study of desertification sensitivity in Talh region (Central Tunisia) using remote sensing. G.I.S., and the M.E.D.A.L.U.S. approach. <i>Geoenviron. Disasters</i><b>7</b>, 16 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40677-020-00148-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzuner, &#xc7;. &amp; Dengiz, O. Desertification risk assessment in Turkey based on environmentally sensitive areas. <i>Ecol. Indic.</i><b>114</b>, 106295 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2020.106295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijitkosum, S. Factor influencing land degradation sensitivity and desertification in a drought prone watershed in Thailand. <i>Int. Soil. Water Conserv. Res.</i><b>9</b>, 217&#x2013;228 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iswcr.2020.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahmasebi, T., Karami, E. &amp; Keshavarz, M. Agricultural land use change under climate variability and change: drivers and impacts. <i>J. Arid Environ.</i><b>180</b>, 104202 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaridenv.2020.104202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajocco, S., De Angelis, A., Perini, L., Ferrara, A. &amp; Salvati, L. The impact of land Use/Land cover changes on land degradation dynamics: A mediterranean case study. <i>Environ. Manage.</i><b>49</b>, 980&#x2013;989 (2012).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00267-012-9831-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22419398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, H., Zhang, Y., Wu, Z. &amp; Lv, T. A bibliometric analysis on land degradation: current status, development, and future directions. <i>Land</i><b>9</b>, 28 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land9010028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ontel, I. et al. Assessing the recent trends of land degradation and desertification in Romania using remote sensing indicators. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>15</b>, 4842 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15194842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Quraishi, A. M. F. &amp; Mustafa, Y. T. <i>Natural Resources Deterioration in MENA Region: Land Degradation, Soil Erosion, and Desertification</i> (Springer Nature, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basso, F. et al. Evaluating environmental sensitivity at the basin scale through the use of geographic information systems and remotely sensed data: an example covering the Agri basin (Southern Italy). <i>Catena</i><b>40</b>, 19&#x2013;35 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0341-8162(99)00062-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diallo, H. A. United nations convention to combat desertification (UNCCD. in The Future of Drylands (eds Lee, C. &amp; Schaaf, T.) (Springer, Dordrecht, doi:10.1007/978-1-4020-6970-3_4. (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds, J. F. et al. Scientific concepts for an integrated analysis of desertification. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>22</b>, 166&#x2013;183 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.1104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abuzaid, A. S. &amp; Abdelatif, A. D. Assessment of desertification using modified MEDALUS model in the North nile delta. <i>Egypt. Geoderma</i>. <b>405</b>, 115400 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2021.115400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MoEFCC. <i>India&#x2019;s NATIONAL PLAN (NAP) TO COMBAT DESERTIFICATION AND LAND DEGRADATION THROUGH FORESTRY INTERVENTIONS</i>. (2023). https://moef.gov.in/uploads/2023/07/NAP%20final-2023.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliraj, S., Chandrasekar, N. &amp; Ramachandran, K. K. Mapping of Coastal landforms and volumetric change analysis in the Southwest Coast of Kanyakumari, South India, using remote sensing and GIS techniques. <i>Egypt. J. Remote Sens. Space Sci.</i>10.1016/j.ejrs.2016.12.006 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejrs.2016.12.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SAC, I. Desertification and land degradation atlas of India (Assessment and analysis of changes over 15 years based on remote sensing. <i>Ahmedabad: Space Applications</i> (2021). https://www.researchgate.net/publication/353605049_Desertification_and_Land_Degradation_Atlas_of_India_Assessment_and_analysis_of_changes_over_15_years_based_on_remote_sensing</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliraj, S., Shunmugapriya, S. &amp; Lakshumanan, C. S. &amp; D. <i>Flood risk zone mapping and future projections for the Thamirabarani river Basin, Southern india: insights from decadal rainfall trends and GIS-Based analytical hierarchy process technique</i>. <i>Nat. Hazards</i>, 10.1007/s11069-024-07007-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masoudi, M. &amp; Zakerinejad, R. Hazard assessment of desertification using MEDALUS model in Mazayjan plain, Fars province, Iran. <i>Ecol. Environ. Conserv.</i><b>16</b>, 425&#x2013;430 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, E. S. Spatial assessment of desertification in North Sinai using the modified MEDLAUS model. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>6</b>, 4647&#x2013;4659 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-012-0723-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okin, G. S., D&#x2019;Odorico, P. &amp; Liu, J. A. Mechanism of land degradation in Turf-Mantled slopes of the Tibetan plateau. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>45</b>, 4041&#x2013;4048 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2018GL077055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, E. J. et al. Assessing environmentally sensitive land to desertification using MEDALUS method in Mongolia. <i>For. Sci. Technol.</i><b>15</b>, 210&#x2013;220 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir, Y. H. et al. Overview of land use and land cover change and its impacts on natural resources. In Ecologically Mediated Development: Promoting Biodiversity Conservation and Food Security (eds (eds Jatav, H. S., Raiput, V. D. &amp; Minkina, T.) 101&#x2013;130 (Springer Nature, Singapore, doi:10.1007/978-981-96-2413-3_5. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassas, M. Arid and semi-arid lands: problems and prospects. <i>Agro-Ecosystems</i><b>3</b>, 185&#x2013;204 (1976).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-3746(76)90120-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izzo, M., Araujo, N., Aucelli, P. P. C., Maratea, A. &amp; S&#xe1;nchez A. land sensitivity to desertification in the Dominican republic: an adaptation of the ESA methodology. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>24</b>, 486&#x2013;498 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.2241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanafi, A. &amp; Jauffret, S. Are long-term vegetation dynamics useful in monitoring and assessing desertification processes in the arid steppe, Southern Tunisia. <i>J. Arid Environ.</i><b>72</b>, 557&#x2013;572 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaridenv.2007.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ait Lamqadem, A., Pradhan, B., Saber, H. &amp; Rahimi, A. Desertification sensitivity analysis using MEDALUS model and GIS: a case study of the oases of middle Draa Valley, Morocco. <i>Sensors</i><b>18</b>, 2230 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s18072230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6069148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29997342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain, A. et al. Agricultural land degradation: processes and problems undermining future food security. In Environment, Climate, Plant and Vegetation Growth (ed (ed Fahad, S.) 17&#x2013;61 (Springer International Publishing, Cham, doi:10.1007/978-3-030-49732-3_2. (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO, U. N. E. P. <i>Provisional Methodology for the Assessment and Mapping of Desertification</i> (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations and United Nations Environment Programme, 1983).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamqadem, A. A., Pradhan, B., Saber, H. &amp; Rahimi, A. Desertification sensitivity analysis using MEDALUS model and GIS: A case study of the oases of middle Draa Valley, Morocco. <i>Sensors</i><b>18</b>, 2230 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s18072230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6069148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29997342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliraj, S. Elsevier, USA, ISBN,. Assessment of land degradation vulnerability in the semi-arid region of Southern India using GIS-based MEDALUS approach. In <i>Remote Sensing of Soils: Mapping, Monitoring, and Measurement</i> (ed. Dharumarajan) 978-0-44-318773&#x2013;5, (2023). 10.1016/B978-0-443-18773-5.00038-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irvine, B. &amp; Cosmas, C. PESERA (Pan-European Soil Erosion Risk Assessment model. <i>Journal</i> (2003). (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berberoglu, S., Cilek, A., Kirkby, M., Irvine, B. &amp; Donmez, C. Spatial and Temporal evaluation of soil erosion in Turkey under climate change scenarios using the Pan-European soil erosion risk assessment (PESERA) model. <i>Environ. Monit. Assess.</i><b>192</b>, 491 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-020-08429-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32638113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liniger, H., Van Lynden, G., Nachtergaele, F., Schwilch, G. &amp; Biancalani, R. <i>A Questionnaire for Mapping Land Degradation and Sustainable Land Management</i> (CDE/WOCAT, FAO/LADA, ISRIC, 2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#x103;v&#x103;lie, R., Patriche, C. &amp; Bandoc, G. Quantification of land degradation sensitivity areas in Southern and central southeastern Europe. New results based on improving DISMED methodology with new climate data. <i>Catena</i><b>158</b>, 309&#x2013;320 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2017.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Asadi, M. A., Sultan, N. S. &amp; Mohammed, R. A. H. A study of desertification indicators and sensitivity in Basra Governorate using the model developed by the desertification information systems project for the mediterranean region (DISMED). <i>ADAB AL-BASRAH</i><b>105</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari, M., Ownegh, M., Asgari, H. R., Sadoddin, A. &amp; Khosravi, H. Desertification risk assessment and management program. <i>Global J. Environ. Sci. Manage.</i><b>2</b>, 365&#x2013;380 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimanpour, S. M., Naeimi, M., Rahmati, O. &amp; Moatamednia, M. Investigate desertification using underground water and subsidence criteria by IMDPA model (Case study: Rafsanjan watershed). <i>Environ. Eros. Res. J.</i><b>14</b>, 126&#x2013;140 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.61186/jeer.14.2.8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ownegh, M. Assessing land degradation hazard intensity and management plans using subjective models and the analytical hierarchy process in Gorgan, Iran. <i>Int. J. Sustainable Dev. Plann.</i><b>4</b>, 35&#x2013;45 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2495/SDP-V4-N1-35-45</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xfc;rke&#x15f;, M. et al. Desertification vulnerability and risk assessment for Turkey via an analytical hierarchy process model. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>31</b>, 205&#x2013;214 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.3441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepehr, A. &amp; Zucca, C. Ranking desertification indicators using TOPSIS algorithm. <i>Nat. Hazards</i>. <b>62</b>, 1137&#x2013;1153 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-012-0139-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Assessment of the effectiveness of sand-control and desertification in the mu US desert, China. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>14</b>, 837 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14040837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boali, A., Asgari, H. R., Behbahani, A. M., Salmanmahiny, A. &amp; Naimi, B. Remotely sensed desertification modeling using ensemble of machine learning algorithms. <i>Remote Sens. Applications: Soc. Environ.</i><b>34</b>, 101149 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rsase.2024.101149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro, R. et al. MEDALUS model evolutions and prospects case study Sicily. in Computational Science and its Applications &#x2013; ICCSA 2023 Workshops (ed (ed Gervasi, O.) vol. 14107 310&#x2013;326 (Springer Nature Switzerland, Cham, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogbue, C. et al. Remote sensing analysis of desert sensitive areas using MEDALUS model and GIS in the Niger river basin. <i>Ecol. Ind.</i><b>158</b>, 111404 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.111404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliraj, S. Remote sensing indices-based soil properties measurement &#x2013; a case study of the Thamirabarani River Basin, South India. In <i>Remote Sensing of Soils: Mapping, Monitoring, and Measurement</i> (ed. Dharumarajan) 978-0-44-318773&#x2013;5. 10.1016/B978-0-443-18773-5.00030-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Vieira, R. M. Socio-environmental vulnerability to drought conditions and land degradation: an assessment in two Northeastern Brazilian river basins. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b>, 8029 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15108029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwivedi, C. S. et al. Geoinformatics-Based Mapping of Environmental Sensitive Areas for Desertification over Satara and Sangli Districts of Maharashtra, India. <i>GeoHazards</i> 5, 415&#x2013;440 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, R., Khaira, J. K., Ahmed, R., Devrani, R. &amp; Deshmukh, B. Land degradation vulnerability mapping using Geospatial techniques: a case study of Nandakini river basin, NW Himalaya, India. <i>Int. J. River Basin Manage.</i><b>1&#x2013;16</b>10.1080/15715124.2024.2396141 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajbanshi, J. &amp; Das, S. Monitoring land sensitivity to desertification using the ESAI approach and evaluation of the key indicators: A spatio-temporal study in India. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>32</b>, 3045&#x2013;3061 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.3965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praveen, D. et al. The urgent call for land degradation vulnerability assessment for conserving land quality in the purview of climate change: perspective from South Indian Coast. <i>AIMSAGRI</i><b>1</b>, 330&#x2013;341 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3934/agrfood.2016.3.330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliraj, S., Parmar, M., Bahuguna, I. M. &amp; Rajawat, A. S. Assessment of desertification and land degradation vulnerability in humid tropics and Sub-tropical regions of India using remote sensing and GIS techniques. In: (eds Sajjad, H., Siddiqui, L., Rahman, A., Tahir, M. &amp; Siddiqui, M. A.) Challenges of Disasters in Asia. Springer Natural Hazards. Springer, Singapore. 10.1007/978-981-19-3567-1_2. (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magesh, N. S., Chandrasekar, N. &amp; Soundranayagam, J. P. Delineation of groundwater potential zones in Theni district, Tamil Nadu, using remote sensing, GIS and MIF techniques. <i>Geoscience Frontiers</i><b>3</b>, (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannan, K. et al. Soil Erosion Status, Priority Treatment Areas and Conservation Measures for Different Districts of Tamil Nadu. in <i>ICAR&#x2013;Indian Institute of Soil &amp; Water Conservation (IISWC), Dehradun. ISBN 978-81-924624-4&#x2013;8</i>, 31 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contador, J. F. L., Schnabel, S., Guti&#xe9;rrez, A. G. &amp; Fern&#xe1;ndez M. P. Mapping sensitivity to land degradation in Extremadura. SW Spain. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>20</b>, 129&#x2013;144 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, N. &amp; Pandey, P. Assessment and monitoring of land degradation using Geospatial technology in Bathinda district, Punjab, India. <i>Solid Earth</i>. <b>9</b>, 75&#x2013;90 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/se-9-75-2018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, B. et al. Modeling and assessment of land degradation vulnerability in arid ecosystem of Rajasthan using analytical hierarchy process and Geospatial techniques. <i>Land</i><b>12</b>, 106 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/land12010106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliraj, S. et al. Chapter 37 - Assessment of land degradation vulnerability in the semi-arid region of Southern India using GIS-based MEDALUS approach. in <i>Remote Sensing of Soils</i> (eds Dharumarajan, S., Kaliraj, S., Adhikari, K., Lalitha, M. &amp; Kumar, N.) 591&#x2013;608 (2024). 10.1016/B978-0-443-18773-5.00038-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosmas, C., Ferrara, A. M. S., Briasouli, H. &amp; Imeson, A. Methodology for mapping environmentally sensitive areas (ESAs) to desertification. in &#x2019;The Medalus Project Mediterranean Desertification and Land use. Manual on Key Indicators of Desertification and Mapping Environmentally Sensitive Areas To Desertification 31&#x2013;47 (European Commission, (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvati, L. &amp; Sabbi, A. Exploring long-term land cover changes in an urban region of Southern Europe. <i>Int. J. Sustainable Dev. World Ecol.</i><b>18</b>, 273&#x2013;282 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13504509.2011.560453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mfondoum, A. H. N., Etouna, J., Nongsi, B. K., Moto, F. M. &amp; Deussieu, F. N. Assessment of land degradation status and its impact in arid and semi-arid areas by correlating spectral and principal component analysis neo-bands. <i>Int. J. Adv. Remote Sens. GIS</i>. <b>5</b>, 1539&#x2013;1560 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23953/cloud.ijarsg.77</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IPCC. Climate Change 2007: The Physical Science Basis. Contribution of Working Group I to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baartman, J. E., van Lynden, G. W., Reed, M. S., Ritsema, C. J. &amp; Hessel, R. Desertification and land degradation: origins, processes and solutions. <i>DESIRE Report series: Scientific Report,(Wageningen: DESIRE)</i> (2007). https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Jantiene-Baartman/publication/288485820_Desertification_and_land_degradation_origins_processes_and_solution_-_A_literature_review/links/56ab635308aed814bdea13f0/Desertification-and-land-degradation-origins-processes-and-solution-A-literature-review.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salunkhe, S. S. et al. Evaluation of indicators for desertification risk assessment in part of Thar desert region of Rajasthan using Geospatial techniques. <i>J. Earth Syst. Sci.</i><b>127</b>, 116 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12040-018-1016-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S. K., Batta, R. K. &amp; Chatterji, S. Land use planning for arresting land Degradation, combating climate change and ensuring food Security &#x2013; A training manual. <i>ICAR-National Bureau Soil. Surv. Land. Use Plann.</i><b>171</b>, 135 (2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>