<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41217636</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2959</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>197</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental monitoring and assessment</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Monit Assess</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring soil organic carbon dynamics based on climatic change in the Central Black Sea Region through machine learning algorithms and future scenarios.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1324</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1324</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10661-025-14776-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recent studies have been conducted to mitigate the effects of global climate change by re-sequestering carbon released into the atmosphere into the soil and increasing soil organic carbon (SOC) levels. The present study analyses the organic carbon content of soil samples collected in different periods (2005 (I. Period) and 2022 (II. Period)) within the Central Black Sea climate zone. Climate parameters Mean Annual Precipitation (MAP) and Mean Annual Temperature (MAT) and climate indices (Emberger Pluviothermic Ratio (QE), UNEP-UNCCD Aridity Index (AI), De Martonne Drought Index (IDM), Fournier Climate Aggressiveness Index (MFI), and Bagnouls-Gaussen Drought Index (BGI)) were used in the analysis. Projections for the III. period (2034) were estimated using the Time Series SARIMA model. Additionally, this study aimed to evaluate the predictability of SOC content in the future period (III) using various machine learning algorithms, including Multivariate Linear Regression (MLR), Support Vector Machine Regression (SVR), Artificial Neural Networks (ANN), Random Forest Regression (RF), and XGBoost Regression. According to the SARIMA time series model, the RMSE values obtained for the prediction of mean precipitation and temperature ranged between 1.377-1.817&#xa0;mm and 23.595-58.039&#xa0;&#xb0;C, respectively. Among the machine learning models, the lowest error rate in predicting the SOC content for 2034 was achieved with the RF algorithm (RMSE: 0.39, MAE: 0.28, R<sup>2</sup>: 0.61), and IDM was identified as the most influential parameter in the prediction. The predicted SOC values for 2034 were found to be lower levels (1.46-1.95%) compared to previous periods. The SARIMA model projected an increase of approximately 1-1.5&#xa0;&#xb0;C in future temperature values, while precipitation was expected to decrease. The aridity index indicated that regions previously not at risk of desertification during periods I and II were projected to become more susceptible to desertification by 2034.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;a&#x11f;lar</LastName><ForeName>Aykut</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Republic of T&#xfc;rkiye Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry, Black Sea Agricultural Research Institute, Samsun, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alaboz</LastName><ForeName>Pelin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Soil Science and Plant Nutrition, Faculty of Agriculture, Isparta University of Applied Science, Isparta, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dengiz</LastName><ForeName>Orhan</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Soil Science and Plant Nutrition, Faculty of Agriculture, Ondokuz May&#x131;s University, Samsun, Turkey. odengiz@omu.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Monit Assess</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8508350</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0167-6369</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012987">Soil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7440-44-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002244">Carbon</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057231" MajorTopicYN="Y">Climate Change</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012987" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002244" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carbon</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059038" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Black Sea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drought index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil organic carbon</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Time series</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: We hereby confirm that the manuscript represents original work that is not being considered for publication, in whole or in part, in another journal, book, conference proceedings, or government publication with a substantial circulation. I ensure that all previously published work cited in the manuscript has been fully acknowledged. In addition, our manuscript has not been submitted to a preprint server prior to submission to any journal. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41217636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-025-14776-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10661-025-14776-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Adhikari, K., &amp; Hartemink, A. E. (2015). Digital mapping of topsoil carbon content and changes in the Driftless Area of Wisconsin, USA. Soil Science Society of America Journal, 79(1), 155&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2136/sssaj2014.09.0392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alaboz, P., I&#x15f;&#x131;ldar, A. A., Co&#x15f;kan, A., &amp; Demir, S. (2023). Different approaches to aggregate stability estimation in the semi-arid climate conditions. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis, 54(1), 96&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00103624.2022.2109666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anggrainingsih, R., Aprianto, Romadhon, G., Sihwi, SW. (2015). Time Series Forecasting Using Exponential Smoothing to Predict the Number of Website Visitor of Sebelas Maret University. 2nd Int. Conference on Information Technology, Computer and Electrical Engineering (ICITACEE). pp. 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnoldus, H. M. J. (1977). Methodology used to determine the maximum potential average annual soil loss due to sheet and rill erosion in Morocco. FAO Soils Bulletin, 5, 39&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azadi, A., Shakeri, S., Zareian, G., &amp; Pahlavan Rad, M. R. (2025). Machine learning approach for soil organic carbon prediction using auxiliary environmental variables in agricultural lands. Eurasian Soil Science, 58(5), 64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S1064229324603949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagnouls, F., &amp; Gaussen, H. (1953). Saison s&#xe9;che et indice x&#xe9;rothermique. Docum. Pour Les Cartes des Prod. Veget. Serie: Generalit&#xe9;,1, 1&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhunia, G. S., Shit, P. K., &amp; Maiti, R. (2018). Comparison of GIS-based interpolation methods for spatial distribution of soil organic carbon (SOC). Journal of the Saudi Society of Agricultural Sciences, 17(2), 114&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jssas.2016.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum, W. E., B&#xfc;sing, J., &amp; Montanarella, L. (2004). Research needs in support of the European thematic strategy for soil protection. TrAC - Trends in Analytical ChemistRy,23(10&#x2013;11), 680&#x2013;685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trac.2004.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;l&#xfc;k, E. (2016). According to Erin&#xe7; Climate Classification Turkish Climate&#xa0;(1991-2020). Ministry of Forestry and Water Management General Directorate of Meteorology, Ankara,&#xa0;p 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;ak&#x131;r, F. S. (2019).&#xa0;Artificial neural networks (2nd ed.). Nobel Yay&#x131;nc&#x131;l&#x131;k.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T., He, T., Benesty, M., Khotilovich, V., Tang, Y., Cho, H., &amp; Zhou, T. (2015). Xgboost: Extreme gradient boosting. R Package Version 0.4-2,1(4), 1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuevas, R. M., Hidalgo, C., Pay&#xe1;n, F., Etchevers, J. D., &amp; Campo, J. (2013). Precipitation influences on active fractions of soil organic matter in seasonally dry tropical forests of the Yucatan: Regional and seasonal patterns. European Journal of Forest Research, 132, 667&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10342-013-0703-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Martonne, E. (1926). Une nouvelle fanction climatologique: L&#x2019;indice d&#x2019;aridit&#xe9;. La M&#xe9;t&#xe9;orologie, 2, 449&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>dos Santos, W. P., Vaz, C. M. P., Martin-Neto, L., Anselmi, A., Tomasella, J., de Souza Costa, F., ... &amp; Perina, F. J. (2025). Predicting bulk density in Brazilian soils for carbon stocks calculation: a comparative study of multiple linear regression and random forest models using continuous and categorical variables. Discover Soil, 2(1), 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duru &#xd6;. (2007).&#xa0;ARIMA models in time series analysis and an application [Master&#x2019;s thesis]. Istanbul University Institute of Social Sciences, Department of Econometrics, Istanbul, Turkey.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emami, M., Khormali, F., Pahlavan-Rad, M. R., &amp; Ebrahimi, S. (2025). Predicting the spatial distribution of organic carbon in soil by combining machine learning algorithms and spline depth function in a part of Golestan Province, Iran. Soil and Tillage Research, 251, Article 106530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.still.2025.106530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emberger, L. (1932). Sur une Formule Climatique et Ses Applications en Botanique (On a climatic formula and its application in Botany). La M&#xe9;t&#xe9;orologie, 192&#x2013;193, 423&#x2013;432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdo&#x11f;an E. (2006).&#xa0;ARIMA models in time series [Master's thesis, Mu&#x11f;la University]. Mu&#x11f;la University, Institute of Natural Sciences, Department of Statistics and Computer Science.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantappie, M., L&#x2019;Abate, G., &amp; Costantini, E. (2011). The influence of climate change on the soil organic carbon content in Italy from 1961 to 2008. Geomorphology, 135, 343&#x2013;352. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.GEOMORPH.2011.02.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.GEOMORPH.2011.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouda, M., Abu-hashim, M., Nassrallah, A., Khalil, M. N., Hendawy, E., Benhasher, F. F., &amp; Mohamed, E. S. (2024). Integration of remote sensing and artificial neural networks for prediction of soil organic carbon in arid zones. Frontiers in Environmental Science, 12, Article 1448601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenvs.2024.1448601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustriansyah, R., Sensuse, D. I., &amp; Ramadhan, A. (2017). A sales prediction model adopted the recency-frequency-monetary concept. Indonesian Journal of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, 6(3), 711&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11591/ijeecs.v6.i3.pp711-720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IPCC. (2013)&#xa0;Climate Change 2013: the physical science basis. In T. F. Stocker, D. Qin, G.-K. Plattner, M. Tignor, S. K. Allen, J. Boschung, A. Nauels, Y. Xia, V. Bex, &amp; P. M. Midgley (Eds.), Contribution of working group I to the fifth assessment report of the intergovernmental panel on climate change (1535 pp.). Cambridge University Press.&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>IPCC. (2018).&#xa0;Annex I: Glossary Matthews, J.B.R. (ed). In V. Masson-Delmotte, P. Zhai, H.-O. P&#xf6;rtner, D. Roberts, J. Skea, P.R. Shukla, A. Pirani, W. Moufouma-Okia, C. P&#xe9;an, R. Pidcock, S. Connors, J.B.R. Matthews, Y. Chen, X. Zhou, M.I. Gomis, E. Lonnoy, T. Maycock, M. Tignor, &amp; T. Waterfield (Eds.), Global Warming of 1.5&#xb0;C. An IPCC Special Report on the impacts of global warming of 1.5&#xb0;C above pre-industrial levels and related global greenhouse gas emission pathways, in the context of strengthening the global response to the threat of climate change, sustainable development, and efforts to eradicate poverty (pp. 541&#x2013;562). Cambridge University Press. https://doi.org/10.1017/9781009157940.008 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson, M. L. (1958). Soil chemical analysis. Prentice Hall Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jobbagy, E. G., &amp; Jackson, R. B. (2000). The vertical distribution of soil organic carbon and its relation to climate and vegetation. Ecological Applications, 10, 423&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/1051-0761(2000)010[0423:TVDOSO]2.0.CO;2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John, A. S., &amp; Brema, J. (2018). Rainfall trend analysis by Mann-Kendall test for Vamanapuram river basin. Kerala. International Journal of Civil Engineering and Technology, 9, 1549&#x2013;1556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutner, M. H., Nachtsheim, C. J., Neter, J., &amp; Li, W. (2005). Applied linear statistical models. McGraw-hill.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamichhane, S., Kumar, L., &amp; Wilson, B. (2019). Digital soil mapping algorithms and covariates for soil organic carbon mapping and their implications: A review. Geoderma, 352, 395&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2019.05.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lembaid, I., Moussadek, R., Mrabet, R., &amp; Bouhaouss, A. (2022). Modeling soil organic carbon changes under alternative climatic scenarios and soil properties using DNDC model at a semi-arid mediterranean environment. Climate, 10(2), Article 23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cli10020023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q.-Q., Yue, T.-X., Wang, C.-Q., Zhang, W.-J., Yu, Y., Li, B., Yang, J., &amp; Bai, G.-C. (2013). Spatially distributed modeling of soil organic matter across China: An application of artificial neural network approach. CATENA, 104, 210&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2012.11.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lychuk, T., Moulin, A., Lemke, R., Izaurralde, R., Johnson, E., Olfert, O., &amp; Brandt, S. (2019). Climate change, agricultural inputs, cropping diversity, and environment affect soil carbon and respiration: A case study in Saskatchewan, Canada. Geoderma. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.GEODERMA.2018.10.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihalikova, M., &amp; Dengiz, O. (2019). Towards more effective irrigation water usage by employing land suitability assessment for various irrigation techniques. Irrigation and Drainage, 68(4), 617&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ird.2349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minasny, B., McBratney, A. B., Malone, B. P., &amp; Wheeler, I. (2013). Digital mapping of soil carbon, advances in agronomy, 118, edited by: Sparks, D. L., Academic Press Inc., 1&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-405942-9.00001-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondal, B. P., Sahoo, R. N., Das, B., Ahmed, N., Bandyopadhyay, K. K., Mukherjee, J., Arora, A., &amp; Moursy, A. R. A. (2025). Comparison of multivariate machine learning models for major soil nutrients prediction using laboratory-based and airborne (AVIRIS-NG) visible near-infrared spectroscopy. European Journal of Agronomy, 170, Article 127726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eja.2025.127726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montanarella, L., Pennock, D. J., McKenzie, N., Badraoui, M., Chude, V., Baptista, I., ..., Vargas, R. (2016). World&#x2019;s soils are under threat. Soil, 2(1), 79-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabiollahi, K., Eskandari, S., Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R., Kerry, R., &amp; Triantafilis, J. (2019). Assessing soil organic carbon stocks under land-use change scenarios using random forest models. Carbon Management, 10(1), 63&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17583004.2018.1553434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyatuame, M., &amp; Agodzo, S. K. (2018). Stochastic ARIMA model for annual rainfall and maximum temperature forecasting over Tordzie watershed in Ghana. Journal of Water and Land Development, 37, 127&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/jwld-2018-0032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padarian, J., Minasny, B., &amp; McBratney, A. B. (2019). Using deep learning for digital soil mapping. The Soil, 5, 79&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/soil-5-79-2019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossel, R. V., McGlynn, R. N., &amp; McBratney, A. B. (2006). Determining the composition of mineral-organic mixes using UV&#x2013;vis&#x2013;NIR diffuse reflectance spectroscopy. Geoderma, 137(1&#x2013;2), 70&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2006.07.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayg&#x131;n, F., Aksoy, H., Alaboz, P., &amp; Dengiz, O. (2023). Different approaches to estimating soil properties for digital soil map integrated with machine learning and remote sensing techniques in a sub-humid ecosystem. Environmental Monitoring and Assessment, 195(9), 1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-023-11681-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;en, H., &amp; Polat, H. (2013). Y&#x131;ll&#x131;k K&#xfc;resel S&#x131;cakl&#x131;k Anomalilerinin Zaman Serileri Analizi &#x130;le &#x130;ncelenmesi ve &#xd6;ng&#xf6;r&#xfc;lmesi. Dumlup&#x131;nar &#xdc;niversitesi Fen Bilimleri Enstit&#xfc;s&#xfc; Dergisi, 30, 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabani, F., Kumar, L., &amp; Solhjouy-Fard, S. (2017). Variances in the projections, resulting from CLIMEX, boosted regression trees and random forests techniques. Theoretical and Applied Climatology, 129, 801&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00704-016-1812-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegenthaler, U., Stocker, T. F., Monnin, E., Luthi, D., Schwander, J., Stauffer, B., ..., &amp; Jouzel, J. (2005). Stable carbon cycle climate relationship during the Late Pleistocene. Science, 310(5752), 1313&#x2013;1317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S. K., Pandey, C. B., Sidhu, G. S., Sarkar, D., &amp; Sagar, R. (2011). Concentration and stock of carbon in the soils affected by land uses and climates in the western Himalaya, India. CATENA, 87(1), 78&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2011.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soldatova, E., Krasilnikov, S., &amp; Kuzyakov, Y. (2024). Soil organic matter turnover: Global implications from &#x3b4;13C and &#x3b4;15N signatures. Science of the Total Environment, 912, Article 169423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.169423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somarathna, P., Malone, B., &amp; Minasny, B. (2016). Mapping soil organic carbon content over New South Wales, Australia using local regression kriging. Geoderma Regional, 7(1), 38&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geodrs.2015.12.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoffer, D. S., Dhumway, R. H. (2010). Time series analysis and its application, 3rd edn. Springer, New York, (p, 596). ISBN 1441978658</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R., Schmidt, K., Amirian-Chakan, A., Rentschler, T., Zeraatpisheh, M., Sarmadian, F., &amp; Scholten, T. (2020). Improving the spatial prediction of soil organic carbon content in two contrasting climatic regions by stacking machine learning models and rescanning covariate space. Remote Sensing, 12(7), Article 1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs12071095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, H. N., Seaks, T. G., &amp; Wichern, D. W. (1972). Box Jenkins methods: An alternative to econometric model. International Statistical&#xa0;Review/Revue Internationale de Statistique, 40, 123&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xfc;rke&#x15f;, M. (1999). Vulnerability of Turkey to desertification with respect to precipitation and aridity conditions. Turkish Journal of Engineering and Environmental Sciences, 23, 363&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xfc;rke&#x15f;, M., &amp; Musao&#x11f;lu, N. (2016). Technical report of the vulnerability assessment of Mediterranean forest ecosystem to climate change: Pilot site of D&#xfc;zler&#xe7;am&#x131; (Turkey). FAO</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Gray, J. M., Waters, C. M., Anwar, M. R., Orgill, S. E., Cowie, A. L., &amp; Li Liu, D. (2022). Modelling and mapping soil organic carbon stocks under future climate change in south-eastern Australia. Geoderma, 405, Article 115442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Waters, C., Orgill, S., Cowie, A., Clark, A., Li Liu, D., Simpson, M., McGowen, I., &amp; Sides, T. (2018). Estimating soil organic carbon stocks using different modelling techniques in the semi-arid rangelands of eastern Australia. Ecological Indicators, 88, 425&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2018.01.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Waters, C., Orgill, S., Gray, J., Cowie, A., Clark, A., &amp; Li Liu, D. (2018b). High resolution mapping of soil organic carbon stocks using remote sensing variables in the semi-arid rangelands of eastern Australia. Science of the Total Environment, 630, 367&#x2013;378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Zhang, X., Adhikari, K., Wang, Z., Shi, D., Jin, X., &amp; Qian, F. (2023). Impact of future climate warming on soil organic carbon stocks in Inner Mongolia, China. Ecological Indicators, 156, Article 111208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.111208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Were, K., Bui, D. T., Dick, &#xd8;. B., &amp; Singh, B. R. (2015). A comparative assessment of support vector regression, artificial neural networks, and random forests for predicting and mapping soil organic carbon stocks across an Afromontane landscape. Ecological Indicators, 52, 394&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2014.12.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesmeier, M., Sp&#xf6;rlein, P., Geu&#xdf;, U., Hangen, E., Haug, S., Reischl, A., Schilling, B., von L&#xfc;tzow, M., &amp; K&#xf6;gel-Knabner, I. (2012). Soil organic carbon stocks in southeast Germany (Bavaria) as affected by land use, soil type and sampling depth. Global Change Biology, 18(7), 2233&#x2013;2245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2486.2012.02699.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesmeier, M., Urbanski, L., Hobley, E., Lang, B., von L&#xfc;tzow, M., Marin-Spiotta, E., &amp; K&#xf6;gel-Knabner, I. (2019). Soil organic carbon storage as a key function of soils-A review of drivers and indicators at various scales. Geoderma, 333, 149&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2018.07.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, L., He, N., Wang, Y., &amp; Han, X. (2008). Storage and dynamics of carbon and nitrogen in soil after grazing exclusion in Leymus chinensis grasslands of northern China. Journal of Environmental Quality, 37(2), 663&#x2013;668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2134/jeq2007.0196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., Li, H., Liang, X., Jiang, M., He, S., &amp; He, Y. (2025). Mechanisms behind the soil organic carbon response to temperature elevations. Agriculture, 15(11), Article 1118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agriculture15111118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, W., Huang, W., Weintraub-Leff, S. R., &amp; Hall, S. J. (2022). Where and why do particulate organic matter (POM) and mineral-associated organic matter (MAOM) differ among diverse soils? Soil Biology and Biochemistry, 172, Article 108756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soilbio.2022.108756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zema, D. A., Parhizkar, M., Plaza-Alvarez, P. A., et al. (2024). Using random forest and multiple-regression models to predict changes in surface runoff and soil erosion after prescribed fire. Model Earth Syst Environ, 10, 1215&#x2013;1228. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40808-023-01838-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40808-023-01838-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Y., Chen, S., Zhu, A., Hu, B., Shi, Z., &amp; Li, Y. (2021). Revealing the scale- and location-specific controlling factors of soil organic carbon in Tibet. Geoderma, 382, Article 114713. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.GEODERMA.2020.114713</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.GEODERMA.2020.114713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>