<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41327065</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2415</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC ophthalmology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Corneal optical densitometry and anterior segment parameters in healthy upper Egyptian population: a prospective observational cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>679</StartPage><MedlinePgn>679</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">679</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12886-025-04476-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">to evaluate corneal optical densitometry (COD) and its associations with age, refractive error, central corneal thickness (CCT), anterior chamber depth (ACD), and corneal curvature in healthy Upper Egyptian subjects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This prospective cross-sectional study included 379 eyes of 379 healthy subjects aged 16&#x2009;years or older. All participants underwent a comprehensive ophthalmologic evaluation. Corneal optical densitometry was assessed using the Oculus Pentacam, which measures COD in grayscale units (GSU) across four annular zones and three lamellar layers. Cases with a history of corneal or intraocular surgery, habitual contact lens use, or systemic diseases were excluded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The mean COD over the entire cornea (0&#x2013;12&#x2009;mm) was 16.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.6 GSU. A strong positive correlation was found between age and COD across all zones and layers (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). Negative correlations were observed between COD and mean refractive spherical equivalent (MRSE) in the 10&#x2013;12&#x2009;mm zone (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and between COD and CCT in the 0&#x2013;2&#x2009;mm zone (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004). Anterior chamber depth (ACD) was negatively correlated with COD in multiple zones (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Positive correlations were identified between COD and keratometry readings (K<sub>m</sub> and K<sub>max</sub>) across all zones and layers (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study highlights the associations between corneal optical densitometry and basic population characteristics in healthy Upper Egyptian subjects. This enhances understanding of factors influencing corneal transparency and underscores the importance of considering these variables in clinical and research settings.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamid</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Minia University, El-Minya, 611111, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esmail</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed Esmail Khalil</ForeName><Initials>MEK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8055-8607</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Minia University, El-Minya, 611111, Egypt. mohamed.ismaeel@mu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zein</LastName><ForeName>Hosny A</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Minia University, El-Minya, 611111, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Ophthalmol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967802</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2415</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corneal optical densitometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corneal transparency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Healthy egyptian cohort</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scheimpflug imaging</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: The study was conducted at the Department of Ophthalmology, Minia University Hospital, Minia, Egypt. The study protocol was approved by the local Research Ethics Committee of Minia University (Approval No. 218&#x2013;2022) and adhered to the tenets of the Declaration of Helsinki. Informed consent was obtained from the patients or their guardians. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41327065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12667085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12886-025-04476-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12886-025-04476-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tekin K, Sekeroglu MA, Kiziltoprak H, Yilmazbas P. Corneal densitometry in Healthy Corneas and its correlation with endothelial morphometry. Cornea. 2017;36(11):1336&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garz&#xf3;n N, Poyales F, Illarramendi I, Mendicute J, J&#xe1;&#xf1;ez &#xd3;, Caro P, L&#xf3;pez A, Arg&#xfc;eso F. Corneal densitometry and its correlation with age, pachymetry, corneal curvature, and refraction. Int Ophthalmol. 2017;37(6):1263&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27837355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otri AM, Fares U, Al-Aqaba MA, Dua HS. Corneal densitometry as an indicator of corneal health. Ophthalmology. 2012;119(3):501&#x2013;08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22133793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nd S, Rozema JJ, Jongenelen S, Ruiz Hidalgo I, Zakaria N, Tassignon MJ. Normative values for corneal densitometry analysis by scheimpflug optical assessment. Invest Ophthalmol Visual Sci. 2014;55(1):162&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24327608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GT, Brown NA, Shun-Shin GA. Light scatter from the central human cornea. Eye (lond, Engl). 1990;4(Pt 4):584&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2226988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>[https://www.capmas.gov.eg/pages/staticpages.aspx?page_id=5034]. Accessed January 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J, Zhang Y, Zhang H, Jia Z, Zhang S, Sun B, Han Y, Wang X. Corneal densitometry in high myopia. BMC Ophthalmol. 2018;18(1):182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6060530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30045701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cankaya AB, Tekin K, Kiziltoprak H, Karahan S, Yilmazbas P. Assessment of corneal backward light scattering in the healthy cornea and factors affecting corneal transparency. Jpn J Ophthalmol. 2018;62(3):335&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29549461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning J, Sun S, Zhang Q, Jin L, Liu X, Xu J, Zhang L. Corneal densitometry in Chinese adults with healthy corneas: associations with sex, age, ocular metrics, and optical characteristics. BMC Ophthalmol. 2024;24(1):230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11143677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38822272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi A, Nabovati P, Hashemi H, Mortazavi AG, Khabazkhoob M. Corneal densitometry and associated factors in an elderly population. Clin Exp Optometry. 2024;107(5):522&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37674266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzahrani K, Carley F, Brahma A, Morley D, Hillarby MC. Corneal clarity measurements in healthy volunteers across different age groups: observational study. Med (baltim). 2017;96(46):e 8563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5704810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29145265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng CY, Wang N, Wong TY, Congdon N, He M, Wang YX, Braithwaite T, Casson RJ, Cicinelli MV, Das A, et al. Prevalence and causes of vision loss in East Asia in 2015: magnitude, temporal trends and projections. Br J Ophthalmol. 2020;104(5):616&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahar A, Pekel G. How does light intensity of the recording room affect the evaluation of lens and corneal clarity by Scheimpflug Tomography? Cornea. 2020;39(2):137&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31714403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakbin M, Khabazkhoob M, Pakravan M, Fotouhi A, Jafarzadehpur E, Aghamirsalim M, Hashemi H. Corneal scheimpflug densitometry in Photorefractive Keratectomy candidates. Cornea. 2020;39(11):1381&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33017121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederer RL, Perumal D, Sherwin T, McGhee CN. Age-related differences in the normal human cornea: a laser scanning in vivo confocal microscopy study. Br J Ophthalmol. 2007;91(9):1165&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1954900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruberti JW, Sinha Roy A, Roberts CJ. Corneal biomechanics and biomaterials. <i>annual review of biomedical engineering</i>. 2011;13:269&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21568714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillenaar T, Cals RH, Eilers PH, Wubbels RJ, van Cleynenbreugel H, Remeijer L. Normative database for corneal backscatter analysis by in vivo confocal microscopy. Invest Ophthalmol Visual Sci. 2011;52(10):7274&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21849426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abass A, Hayes S, White N, Sorensen T, Meek KM. Transverse depth-dependent changes in corneal collagen lamellar orientation and distribution. Interface Focus. 2015;12(104):20140717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4345466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25631562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghamohammadzadeh H, Newton RH, Meek KM. X-ray scattering used to map the preferred collagen orientation in the human cornea and limbus. In: Structure. Vol. 12(2): (<i>London, England</i>; 1993). 2004; p. 249&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14962385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen T. Light scattering from the human cornea. <i>investigative ophthalmology &amp; visual science</i>. 1982;23(1):81&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7085224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daxer A, Misof K, Grabner B, Ettl A, Fratzl P. Collagen fibrils in the human corneal stroma: structure and aging. Invest Ophthalmol Visual Sci. 1998;39(3):644&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9501878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gipson IK. Age-related changes and diseases of the ocular surface and cornea. Invest Ophthalmol Visual Sci. 2013;54(14):Orsf48&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24335068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faragher RG, Mulholland B, Tuft SJ, Sandeman S, Khaw PT. Aging and the cornea. Br J Ophthalmol. 1997;81(10):814&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1722015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9486017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen M, Fan F, Xue A, Wang J, Zhou X, Lu F. Biomechanical properties of the cornea in high myopia. Vision Res. 2008;48(21):2167&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18638498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delshad S, Chun JM. Corneal endothelial cell density and morphology in low and moderate myopic Chinese eyes. Int J Ophthalmol. 2013;6(4):467&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3755305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghaian E, Choe JE, Lin S, Stamper RL. Central corneal thickness of caucasians, Chinese, Hispanics, Filipinos, African Americans, and Japanese in a glaucoma clinic. Ophthalmology. 2004;111(12):2211&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15582076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Zhang Y, Zhang Y, Li T, Wang J, Du Z. Analysis of potential impact factors of corneal biomechanics in myopia. BMC Ophthalmol. 2023;23(1):143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10077661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37024820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>