<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41497376</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2090-8113</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2025</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Veterinary medicine international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet Med Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence and Risk Factors of Bacterial Pathogens Causing Camel Calf Diarrhea in Shabeley and Kebribayah Districts, Fafan Zone, Eastern Ethiopia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5519712</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5519712</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5519712</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/vmi/5519712</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Infectious diarrhea is one of the most serious health threats to camel calves, causing death and substantial loss. This study aimed to determine the prevalence of bacterial pathogens causing diarrhea in camel calves and identify the associated risk factors in the Shabeley and Kebribayah Districts of the Fafan zone, Eastern Ethiopia. A cross-sectional study was conducted from March 2022 to January 2023 to isolate and identify bacteriological infections of camel calf diarrhea and their associated risk factors in selected districts of the Fafen zone of the Somali region, Eastern Ethiopia. In total, 384 fecal swabs were collected from diarrheal, convalescent, and healthy camel calves. Using pure culture and bacteriological isolation, the overall prevalence of a bacterial infection was 66 (17.2%; 95% Cl: 0.13-0.21). Similarly, the distribution of the identified bacterial species was as follows: <i>Escherichia coli</i> (58%), <i>Salmonella</i> spp. (30%), and <i>Enterococcus</i> spp. (12%). The prevalence of camel calf infections in Kebribayah (9.0%) was higher than that in Shabeley (8.3%). Similarly, calves aged 7-12&#x2009;months and diarrheal calves showed higher infection rates (7.6% and 8.6%, respectively). However, younger calves aged 0-3&#x2009;months and apparently healthy calves had the lowest prevalence (4.7% and 3.4%, respectively). In the univariate logistic regression analysis, calves aged 7-12&#x2009;months and calves with diarrhea showed statistically significant differences (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05). Furthermore, the incidence of diarrhea in camel calves was statistically significant (<i>p</i> &gt; 0.05) in the multivariable logistic analysis. However, convalescent calves (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.79, 95% Cl: 0.38-1.64) were 1.79 times more likely to be infected with bacterial species than apparently healthy camel calves. This study indicated the presence of enteric bacteria in the study areas; therefore, further epidemiological investigations on other species of enteric bacteria and the implementation of public health education are warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Dek Kahin Yosef et al. Veterinary Medicine International published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yosef</LastName><ForeName>Dek Kahin</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-2361-0204</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Microbiology and Public Health, College of Veterinary Medicine, Jigjiga University, Jigjiga, Somali Regional State, Ethiopia, jju.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahad</LastName><ForeName>Abdullahi Adan</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4101-6503</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Microbiology and Public Health, College of Veterinary Medicine, Jigjiga University, Jigjiga, Somali Regional State, Ethiopia, jju.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arog</LastName><ForeName>Hassan Abdi</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-4498-3123</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Studies, College of Veterinary Medicine, Jigjiga University, Jigjiga, Somali Regional State, Ethiopia, jju.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Vet Med Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101524203</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2042-0048</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacteriological</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">camel calf</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diarrhea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">identification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isolation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factor</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41497376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12767372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/vmi/5519712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">VMI5519712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tschopp R., Gebregiorgis A., Tassachew Y. et al., Integrated human-animal sero-surveillance of Brucellosis in the Pastoral Afar and Somali Regions of Ethiopia, PLoS Neglation Tropical Diseases. (2021) 15, no. 8, 10.1371/journal.pntd.0009593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0009593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8372887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34358232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abri M. A. A. and Faye B., Genetic Improvement in Dromedary Camels: Challenges and Opportunities, Frontiers in Genetics. (2019) 10, 10.3389/fgene.2019.00167, 2-s2.0-85066630823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2019.00167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6422876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30915101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younan M., Bornstein S., and Gluecks I., MERS and the Dromedary Camel Trade Between Africa and the Middle East, Tropical Animal Health and Production. (2016) 48, no. 6, 1277&#x2013;1282, 10.1007/s11250-016-1089-3, 2-s2.0-84975247305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11250-016-1089-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7089074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27324244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoke K., Ali S. M., and Hussein M., Assessment of Challenges and Opportunities of Traditional Camel Calf Management Practices in Fafen Zone, Somali Regional State, Ethiopia, International Journal of Current Science and Technology. (2015) 3, no. 6, 20&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamuka P. O., Njeruh F. M., Gitao G. C., and Abey K. A., Camel Health Management and Pastoralists&#x2019; Knowledge and Information on Zoonoses and Food Safety Risks in Isiolo County, Kenya, Pastoralism. (2017) 7, no. 1, 10.1186/s13570-017-0095-z, 2-s2.0-85026858831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13570-017-0095-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmedin U. M. and Assen A. A., Calf Morbidity, Mortality, and Management Practices in Dairy Farms in Jimma City, Southwestern Ethiopia, BMC Veterinary Research. (2023) 19, no. 1, 10.1186/s12917-023-03815-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-023-03815-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10683357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38017486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Co&#x15f;kun M. and &#x15e;ahin M., Prevalence of Neonatal Calf Diarrhea Caused by Escherichia coli and Investigation of Virulence Factors, Serotypes, and Antibiotic Susceptibility, Polish Journal of Veterinary Sciences. (2023) 26, no. 3, 335&#x2013;341, 10.24425/pjvs.2023.145058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24425/pjvs.2023.145058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37727028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sazmand A. and Nourian A., Camel-Related Zoonoses: a Light on &#x201c;Ship of the Desert&#x201d; Camels and Public Health, Zoonoses: Infections Affecting Humans and Animals. (2023) .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafalla A. I., Neonatal Diarrhea, Infectious Diseases of Dromedary Camels: A Concise Guide. (2021) 307&#x2013;310, 10.1007/978-3-030-79389-0_49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-79389-0_49</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robi D. T., Mossie T., and Temteme S., Eukaryotic Infections in Dairy Calves: Impacts, Diagnosis, and Strategies for Prevention and Control, Medicine (Auckland). (2023) 14, 195&#x2013;208, 10.2147/vmrr.s442374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/vmrr.s442374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10697087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38058381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robi D. T., Mossie T., and Temteme S., A Comprehensive Review of the Common Bacterial Infections in Dairy Calves and Advanced Strategies for Health Management, Veterinary Medicine: Research and Reports. (2024) 15, 1&#x2013;14, 10.2147/vmrr.s452925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/vmrr.s452925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10822132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessop E., Li L., Renaud D. L. et al., Neonatal Calf Diarrhea and Gastrointestinal Microbiota: Etiologic Agents and Microbiota Manipulation for Treatment and Prevention of Diarrhea, Veterinary Sciences. (2024) 11, no. 3, 10.3390/vetsci11030108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/vetsci11030108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10975090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38535842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J. Q., Fan Y. Y., Lei Y. D. et al., Molecular Characterization of Common Zoonotic Protozoan Parasites and Bacteria Causing Diarrhea in Dairy Calves in Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, China, Parasite. (2024) 31, 10.1051/parasite/2024059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/parasite/2024059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11444552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39353100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayele A., Seyoum Z., and Leta S., Cryptosporidium Infection in Bovine Calves: Prevalence and Potential Risk Factors in Northwest Ethiopia, BMC Research Notes. (2018) 11, no. 1, 10.1186/s13104-018-3219-7, 2-s2.0-85041649055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-018-3219-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5803921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29415766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alebie A., Molla A., Adugna W., Tesfaye A., and Ejo M., Prevalence, Isolation, Identification, and Risk Factors of Major Bacterial Cause of Camel Subclinical Mastitis, BioMed Research International. (2021) 2021, no. 1, 10.1155/2021/5522331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/5522331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8270707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34307655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali D. A., Deininger K., and Harris A., Using National Statistics to Increase Transparency of Large Land Acquisition: Evidence from Ethiopia, World Development. (2017) 93, 62&#x2013;74, 10.1016/j.worlddev.2016.12.027, 2-s2.0-85028282878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2016.12.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awoke K. and Ali S. M., Traditional Husbandry Practices and Major Challenge of Young Stock (Camel Calf) in Fafen Zone, Ethiopian Somali Regional State, Ethiopia, Journal of Environmental &amp; Analytical Toxicology. (2015) 5, no. 6, 10.4172/2161-0525.1000321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2161-0525.1000321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrusfield M., Veterinary Epidemiology, 2018, John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faires M. C., Evaluation of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus and the Characterization of Staphylococcus pseudintermedius in Dogs and Cats, 2008, University of Guelph.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Ruwaili M. A., Khalil O. M., and Selim S. A., Viral and Bacterial Infections Associated with Camel (Camelus dromedarius) Calf Diarrhea in North Province, Saudi Arabia, Saudi Journal of Biological Sciences. (2012) 19, no. 1, 35&#x2013;41, 10.1016/j.sjbs.2011.10.001, 2-s2.0-84855205882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sjbs.2011.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3730540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23961160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebru M., Zeru F., Kumar N., Tashew A., and Meresa A., Intestinal Bacteria L Pathogens and Risk Factors Leading to Bacterial Diarrhea in Camel Calves in Selecte D Districts of Afar National Regional State, North East Ethiopia, Indian Journal Animal Health. (2018) 57, no. 1, 35&#x2013;50, 10.36062/ijah.57.1.2018.35-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36062/ijah.57.1.2018.35-50</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessalah S., Fairbrother J. M., Salhi I. et al., Antimicrobial Resistance and Molecular Characterization of Virulence Genes, Phylogenetic Groups of Escherichia coli Isolated from Diarrheic and Healthy camel-calves in Tunisia, Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases. (2016) 49, 1&#x2013;7, 10.1016/j.cimid.2016.08.008, 2-s2.0-84985993439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cimid.2016.08.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27865260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahein M. A., Dapgh A. N., Kamel E. et al., Advanced Molecular Characterization of Enteropathogenic Escherichia coli Isolated from Diarrheic Camel Neonates in Egypt, Veterinary World. (2021) 14, no. 1, 85&#x2013;91, 10.14202/vetworld.2021.85-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14202/vetworld.2021.85-91</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33642790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayh G., Ben Haj Yahia A., Selmi R. et al., Prevalence of Escherichia coli O157:H7 Isolated from Fecal Samples of Diarrheic Camels in Tunisia, Veterinaria Italiana. (2022) 58, no. 3, 10.12834/VetIt.2555.16997.2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12834/VetIt.2555.16997.2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37219830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Gburi N. M., Prevalence of Escherichia coli O157: H7 in Camels Fecal Samples, Journal of Genetic Environmental Resource Conservation. (2016) 4, 46&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narnaware S. D., Ranjan R., Jyotsana B., and Sahoo A., Virulence Genes and Antimicrobial Resistance Profile of Escherichia coli Isolates from Diarrhoeic Neonatal Dromedary Camels, Journal of Camel Practice and Research. (2022) 29, no. 2, 127&#x2013;132, 10.5958/2277-8934.2022.00017.0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5958/2277-8934.2022.00017.0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraha A., Urge B., Kemal J., Siyoum T., Tadele M., and Muktar Y., Major Microbial and Parasitic Pathogens Causing Calf Diarrhea of Dromedary Camel in Selected Areas of Eastern Ethiopia, Livestock Research Results. (2020) 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eissa N. M., Incidence and Antimicrobial Susceptibility of Salmonella Carrier Among Apparently Healthy Camels in Some Libyan Regions, Libyan Journal of Veterinary and Medical Sciences. (2016) 2, no. 2, 19&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamire Ane M. and Muktar Y., Isolation and Identification of Salmonella spp and E. coli from Dromedary Camel Calves with Diarrhea in Selected Districts of Eastern Ethiopia, 2019, Haramaya university.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar G. and Chander H., Ethno-Veterinary and Fodder Plants of Awah-Devi Region of Hamirpur District, Himachal Pradesh, Journal of Biology Chemistry Chronics. (2018) 4, no. 1, 08&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson S., Innes E. A., Jonsson N. N., and Katzer F., Shedding of Cryptosporidium in Calves and Dams: Evidence of re-infection and Shedding of Different gp60 Subtypes, Parasitology. (2019) 146, no. 11, 1404&#x2013;1413, 10.1017/s0031182019000829, 2-s2.0-85069527478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0031182019000829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S. H., Kim H. Y., Choi E. W., and Kim D., Causative Agents and Epidemiology of Diarrhea in Korean Native Calves, Journal of Veterinary Science. (2019) 20, no. 6, 10.4142/jvs.2019.20.e64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4142/jvs.2019.20.e64</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6883198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31775191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan P., Kim M., Liu G. et al., The Gut Microbiota of Newborn Calves and Influence of Potential Probiotics on Reducing Diarrheic Disease by Inhibition of Pathogen Colonization, Frontiers in Microbiology. (2021) 12, 10.3389/fmicb.2021.772863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2021.772863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8567051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34745079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>