<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41843678</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>123</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Coevolving topography, patchy soils, and forest structure.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2519374123</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2519374123</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2519374123</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2519374123</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The transition from soil-mantled to bedrock-dominated landscapes is important to hydrology, ecology, and landscape evolution. Where classical theory predicts that this transition abruptly occurs once erosion rates exceed soil production ones, actual landscapes show a much more gradual transition. The Rampart Range, CO, is an unglaciated, forested mountain range with uniform lithology that spans this transition, providing an opportunity to interrogate how topography, soil cover, and forest structure coevolve. Using drone imagery and airborne lidar, we show the utility of object-based methods that segment the lidar topography into individual outcrops. Lower elevation hillslopes are rockier (~14% rock) than their higher elevation counterparts (~2% rock) due to late Cenozoic incision of a regional, high elevation, low relief surface. After accounting for the erosional control on rockiness, we show that bedrock exposure also depends on topographic aspect. Equator-facing hillslopes are rockier (~20% rock at low elevations; ~3% rock at high elevations) than their more heavily forested, pole-facing counterparts (~11% rock at low elevations; ~1% rock at high elevations). To simulate these patterns, hillslope evolution models need "humped" soil production functions that can generate rocky outcrops within a soil mantle. When combined with depth-dependent soil creep, such models readily produce large gradients in the height and frequency of bedrock outcrops in response to aspect-dependent weathering. Given the correspondence between higher forest biomass (e.g., increased tree density, canopy height) with lower bedrock exposure on pole-facing hillslopes, we argue that forest dynamics may be an underappreciated regulator of hillslope morphology via root zone weathering.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rossi</LastName><ForeName>Matthew W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1846-5191</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cooperative Institute for Research in Environmental Sciences, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Earth Lab, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tucker</LastName><ForeName>Gregory E</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0364-5800</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cooperative Institute for Research in Environmental Sciences, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geological Sciences, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>Suzanne P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6796-6649</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geological Sciences, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Arctic and Alpine Research, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>Robert S</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2759-4833</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geological Sciences, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Arctic and Alpine Research, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGlinchy</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2135-0168</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cooperative Institute for Research in Environmental Sciences, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Earth Lab, University of Colorado, Boulder, CO 80309.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>1822062</GrantID><Agency>NSF (NSF)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bedrock exposure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forest structure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">landscape evolution modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lidar analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soil production</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests statement:The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41843678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13012095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2519374123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brantley S. L., et al. , Reviews and syntheses: On the roles trees play in building and plumbing the critical zone. Biogeosciences 14, 5115&#x2013;5142 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich W. E., Perron J. T., The search for a topographic signature of life. Nature 439, 411&#x2013;418 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16437104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert G. K.,Report on the Geology of the Henry Mountains (U.S. Government Printing Office, 1877).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimsath A. M., DiBiase R. A., Whipple K. X., Soil production limits and the transition to bedrock-dominated landscapes. Nat. Geosci. 5, 210&#x2013;214 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson M. J., Kirkby M. A., Hillslope Form and Process (Cambridge University Press, 1972).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson R. S., Modeling the tor-dotted crests, bedrock edges, and parabolic profiles of high alpine surfaces of the Wind River Range, Wyoming. Geomorphology 46, 35&#x2013;58 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strudley M. W., Muray A. B., Haff P. K., Emergence of pediments, tors, and piedmont junctions from a bedrock weathering&#x2013;regolith thickness feedback. Geology 34, 805&#x2013;808 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudd S. M., Furbish D. J., Responses of soil-mantled hillslopes to transient channel incision rates. J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf. 112, 3&#x2013;18 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon J. L., Heimsath A. M., Kaste J., Amundson R., Climate-driven processes of hillslope weathering. Geology 37, 975&#x2013;978 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall J. A., Roering J. J., Diagenetic variation in the Oregon Coast Range: Implications for rock strength, soil production, hillslope form, and landscape evolution. J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf. 119, 1395&#x2013;1417 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neely A. B., DiBiase R. A., Corbett L. B., Bierman P. R., Caffee M. W., Bedrock fracture density controls on hillslope erodibility in steep, rocky landscapes with patchy soil cover, southern California, USA. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 522, 186&#x2013;197 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahm W. J., Riebe C. S., Lukens C. E., Araki S., Bedrock composition regulates mountain ecosystems and landscape evolution. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 111, 3338&#x2013;3343 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3948264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24516144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen I. J., et al. , The influence of erosion and vegetation on soil production and chemical weathering rates in the Southern Alps. New Zealand. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 608, 118036 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulos M. J., Pierce J. L., Flores A. N., Benner S. G., Hillslope asymmetry maps reveal widespread, multi-scale organization. Geophys. Res. Lett. 39, 6406 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelletier J. D., et al. , Which way do you lean? Using slope aspect variations to understand Critical Zone processes and feedbacks. Earth Surf. Process. Landforms 43, 1133&#x2013;1154 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith T., Bookhagen B., Climatic and biotic controls on topographic asymmetry at the global scale. J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf. 126, e2020JF005692 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabet E. J., Mudd S. M., Bedrock erosion by root fracture and tree throw: A coupled biogeomorphic model to explore the humped soil production function and the persistence of hillslope soils. J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf. 115, 2009JF001526 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roering J. J., Marshall J., Booth A. M., Mort M., Jin Q., Evidence for biotic controls on topography and soil production. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 298, 183&#x2013;190 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefsky M., Cohen W., Parker G., Harding D. H., Lidar remote sensing for ecosystem studies. BioScience 52, 19&#x2013;30 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enquist B. J., Niklas K. J., Global allocation rules for patterns of biomass partitioning in seed plants. Science 295, 1517&#x2013;1520 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11859193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiBiase R. A., Heimsath A. M., Whipple K. X., Hillslope response to tectonic forcing in threshold landscapes. Earth Surf. Process. Landforms 37, 855&#x2013;865 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarrett R. D., Paleohydrologic techniques used to define the spatial occurrence of floods. Geomorphology 3, 181&#x2013;195 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi M. W., Anderson R. S., Anderson S. P., Tucker G. E., Orographic controls on subdaily rainfall statistics and flood frequency in the Colorado Front Range, USA. Geophys. Res. Lett. 47, e2019GL085086 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gochis D., et al. , The Great Colorado Flood of September 2013. Bull. Am. Meteorol. Soc. 96, 1461&#x2013;1487 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson S. W., Anderson S. P., Anderson R. S., Exhumation by debris flows in the 2013 Colorado Front Range storm. Geology 43, 391&#x2013;394 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe J. A., et al. , New insights into debris-flow hazards from an extraordinary event in the Colorado Front Range. GSA Today 24, 4&#x2013;10 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire L. A., et al. , Elucidating the role of vegetation in the initiation of rainfall-induced shallow landslides: Insights from an extreme rainfall event in the Colorado Front Range. Geophys. Res. Lett. 43, 9084&#x2013;9092 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epis R. C., Chapin C. E., Geomorphic and tectonic implications of the post-Laramide, late Eocene erosion surface in the Southern Rocky Mountains. Mem. Geol. Soc. Am. 144, 45&#x2013;74 (1975).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan M. E., Heller P. L., Wing S. L., History and causes of post-Laramide relief in the Rocky Mountain orogenic plateau. Bull. Geol. Soc. Am. 118, 393&#x2013;405 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory K. M., Chase C. G., Tectonic and climatic significance of a late Eocene low-relief, high-level geomorphic surface, Colorado. J. Geophys. Res. 99, 20141&#x2013;20160 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wobus C. W., Tucker G. E., Anderson R. S., Does climate change create distinctive patterns of landscape incision? J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf. 115, 4008 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith D. R., Noblett J., Wobus R. A., Unruh D., Chamberlain K. R., A review of the Pikes Peak batholith, Front Range, central Colorado A &#x201c;type example&#x201d; of A-type granitic magmatism. Rocky Mt. Geol. 34, 289&#x2013;312 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dethier D. P., Ouimet W., Bierman P. R., Rood D. H., Balco G., Basins and bedrock: Spatial variation in 10Be erosion rates and increasing relief in the southern Rocky Mountains, USA. Geology 42, 167&#x2013;170 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PRISM, PRISM Climate Group at Oregon State University (Oregon State University, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peet R. K., Forest vegetation of the Colorado Front Range&#x2014;Composition and dynamics. Vegetatio 45, 3&#x2013;75 (1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson R. S., Allen C. D., Toney J. L., Jass R. B., Bair A. N., Holocene vegetation and fire regimes in subalpine and mixed conifer forests, southern Rocky Mountains, USA. Int. J. Wildl. Fire 17, 96&#x2013;114 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veblen T. T., Kitzberger T., Donnegan J., Climatic and human influences on fire regimes in ponderosa pine forests in the Colorado Front Range. Ecol. Appl. 10, 1178&#x2013;1195 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battaglia M. A., et al. , Changes in forest structure since 1860 in ponderosa pine dominated forests in the Colorado and Wyoming Front Range, USA. For. Ecol. Manage. 422, 147&#x2013;160 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milodowski D. T., Mudd S. M., Mitchard E. T. A., Topographic roughness as a signature of the emergence of bedrock in eroding landscapes. Earth Surf. Dyn. 3, 483&#x2013;499 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi M. W., Evaluating the accuracy of binary classifiers for geomorphic applications. Earth Surf. Dyn. 12, 765&#x2013;782 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson R. S., Riihimaki C. A., Safran E. B., MacGregor K. R., Facing reality: Late Cenozoic evolution of smooth peaks, glacially ornamented valleys, and deep river gorges of Colorado&#x2019;s Front Range. Spec. Pap. Geol. Soc. Am. 398, 397&#x2013;418 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whipple K. X., DiBiase R. A., Crosby B., Johnson J. P. L., Bedrock Rivers. Treat. Geomorphol. 9, 865&#x2013;903 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eppes M. C., Keanini R., Mechanical weathering and rock erosion by climate-dependent subcritical cracking. Rev. Geophys. 55, 470&#x2013;508 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall J. A., et al. , Earth Sciences: Frost for the Trees: Did climate increase erosion in unglaciated landscapes during the late Pleistocene? Sci. Adv. 1, e1500715 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4681330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26702434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>French H. M., Millar S. W. S., Permafrost at the time of the last glacial maximum (LGM) in North America. Boreas 43, 667&#x2013;677 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janke J. R., Modeling past and future alpine permafrost distribution in the Colorado Front Range. Earth Surf. Process. Landforms 30, 1495&#x2013;1508 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Istanbulluoglu E., Yetemen O., Vivoni E. R., Guti&#xe9;rrez-Jurado H. A., Bras R. L., Eco-geomorphic implications of hillslope aspect: Inferences from analysis of landscape morphology in central New Mexico. Geophys. Res. Lett. 35, 14403 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Jurado H. A., et al. , On the observed ecohydrologic dynamics of a semiarid basin with aspect-delimited ecosystems. Water Resour. Res. 49, 8263&#x2013;8284 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhart K. R., et al. , Short communication: Landlab v2.0: A software package for Earth surface dynamics. Earth Surf. Dyn. 8, 379&#x2013;397 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhart K. R., Glade R. C., Shobe C. M., Tucker G. E., Terrainbento 1.0: A python package for multi-model analysis in long-term drainage basin evolution. Geosci. Model Dev. 12, 1267&#x2013;1297 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimsath A. M., Dietrichs W. E., Nishiizuml K., Finkel R. C., The soil production function and landscape equilibrium. Nature 388, 358&#x2013;361 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigtl&#xe4;nder A., Rheinwalt A., Tofelde S., Quantifying Earth&#x2019;s topography: Steeper and larger than projected in digital terrain models. Geophys. Res. Lett. 51, e2024GL109517 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viles H. A., Linking weathering and rock slope instability: Non-linear perspectives. Earth Surf. Process. Landforms 38, 62&#x2013;70 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chicco D., Jurman G., The advantages of the Matthews correlation coefficient (MCC) over F1 score and accuracy in binary classification evaluation. BMC Genomics 21, 1&#x2013;13 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6941312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31898477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayaram M., Fleyeh H., Convex hulls in image processing: A scoping review. Am. J. Intell. Syst. 6, 48&#x2013;58 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaeedi S., Didehvar F., Mohades A., &#x3b1;-Concave hull, a generalization of convex hull. Theor. Comput. Sci. 702, 48&#x2013;59 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwanghart W., Scherler D., Short communication: TopoToolbox 2&#x2014;MATLAB-based software for topographic analysis and modeling in Earth surface sciences. Earth Surf. Dyn. 2, 1&#x2013;7 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X., Chen T., High spatial resolution remote sensing image segmentation based on the multiclassification model and the binary classification model. Neural Comput. Appl. 35, 3597&#x2013;3604 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnstone S. A., Hilley G. E., Lithologic control on the form of soil-mantled hillslopes. Geology 43, 83&#x2013;86 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganti V., Passalacqua P., Foufoula-Georgiou E., A sub-grid scale closure for nonlinear hillslope sediment transport models. J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf. 117, 2012 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strudley M. W., Muray A. B., Haff P. K., Regolith thickness instability and the formation of tors in arid environments. J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf. 111, 3010 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi M. W., Anderson S. P., Anderson R. S., Tucker G. E., Bedrock exposure, canopy density, and runoff generation in the Rampart Range, CO 2018. OpenTopography. 10.5069/G9CV4FXZ. Accessed 26 March 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5069/G9CV4FXZ</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi M. W., Data and Code for &#x201c;Coevolving topography, patchy soils, and forest structure.&#x201d; Figshare. 10.6084/m9.figshare.29602223. Deposited 5 March 2026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6084/m9.figshare.29602223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13012095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41843678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>