<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41523609</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2090-908X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2025</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientifica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scientifica (Cairo)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Alligator Weed (<i>Alternanthera philoxeroides</i>) Invasion on Floral Composition and Soil Microbiota.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7359416</StartPage><MedlinePgn>7359416</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7359416</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/sci5/7359416</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Plant invasion modifies the aboveground and belowground biota directly or indirectly via allelopathic effect. This study aimed to ascertain if the invasive species <i>Alternanthera philoxeroides</i> impacts plant diversity, plant composition, and soil microbes or not. The soil microbial activity (CO<sub>2</sub> release) and soil pH were also recorded. The plant communities invaded and uninvaded with <i>Alternanthera philoxeroides</i> were examined using the quadrat method. Soil samples were collected from 0 to 10&#x2009;cm depth, and the culture method was used for soil microbial analysis. The plant species richness and soil fungi were found to be reduced at <i>A. philoxeroides</i> invaded plots than at uninvaded plots. The IVI of all common species such as <i>Cynodon dactylon</i>, <i>Bidens pilosa,</i> and <i>Trifolium repens</i> was highly suppressed in the invaded zone. The parameters like plant diversity indices, colony count of soil microbes, soil microbial activity (CO<sub>2</sub> release), and soil pH were found to be reduced at invaded sites than at uninvaded sites. The results indicated that the invasive <i>A. philoxeroides</i> modifies the plant community composition, and the underlying mechanism for the change is possibly by altering the soil microbiota, microbial respiration, and soil pH with their successful invasion.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Shristi Khanal et al. Scientifica published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khanal</LastName><ForeName>Shristi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-4469-756X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, Amrit Campus (Tribhuvan University), Kathmandu, 44600, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adhikari</LastName><ForeName>Hari Sharan</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1472-1469</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, Amrit Campus (Tribhuvan University), Kathmandu, 44600, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, Bhaktapur Multiple Campus (Tribhuvan University), Bhaktapur, 44800, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chettri</LastName><ForeName>Mukesh Kumar</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-7710-371X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, Amrit Campus (Tribhuvan University), Kathmandu, 44600, Nepal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Scientifica (Cairo)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101589932</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-908X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">allelopathic effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plant invasion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plant&#x2013;soil feedback</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soil microbes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soil microbial activity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41523609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12782342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/sci5/7359416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">SCI57359416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Henery M. L., Bowman G., Mr&#xe1;z P. et al., Evidence for a Combination of Pre-Adapted Traits and Rapid Adaptive Change in the Invasive Plant Centaurea stoebe, Journal of Ecology. (2010) 98, no. 4, 800&#x2013;813, 10.1111/j.1365-2745.2010.01672.x, 2-s2.0-77954716937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2745.2010.01672.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukhorukov A. P., Plant Invasion Ecology, Plants. (2023) 12, no. 22, 10.3390/plants12223887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants12223887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10674497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38005783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadotte M. W., Campbell S. E., Li S., and Mandrak N. E., Preadaptation and Naturalization of Nonnative Species: Darwin&#x2019;s Two Fundamental Insights into Species Invasion, Annual Review of Plant Biology. (2018) 69, 585&#x2013;609, 10.1146/annurev-arplant-042817-040248, 2-s2.0-85045153171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-arplant-042817-040248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm L., Doll J., Holm E., Pancho J. V., and Herberger J. P., World Weeds: Natural Histories and Distribution, 1997, John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Bisht N., 
Joshi S., 
Shrestha B. B. et al., Manual on Invasive Alien Plant Species in Kailash Sacred Landscape-Nepal, 2016, http://lib.icimod.org/record/32444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhikari B., Shrestha B. B., Watson M. F. et al., Invasive Alien Plants of Nepal: a Field Guide to 27 Problematic Species, Nepal Academy of Science and Technology, Khumaltar, Lalitpur, Nepal. (2022) .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassett I., Paynter Q., Beggs J., Preston C., Watts J. H., and Crossman N. D., Alligator Weed (Alternanthera philoxeroides) Invasion Affects Decomposition Rates in a Northern New Zealand Lake, 15th Australian Weeds Conference, Papers and Proceedings, 2006, Adelaide, South Australia, 24&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Shen J., 
Shen M., 
Wang X., and 
Lu Y., Effect of Environmental Factors on Shoot Emergence and Vegetative Growth of Alligatorweed (<i>Alternanthera philoxcroides</i>), Weed Science. (2005) 53, no. 4, 471&#x2013;478, 10.1614/WS-04-198R, 2-s2.0-33748038388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1614/WS-04-198R</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosterhout E. V., Alligator Weed Control Manual: Eradication and Suppression of Alligator Weed (Alternanthera philoxeroides) in Australia, 2007, NSW Department of Primary Industries, Australia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao L., Geng Y., Yang H., Hu Y., and Yang J., Gene Expression Reaction Norms Unravel the Molecular and Cellular Processes Underpinning the Plastic Phenotypes of Alternanthera philoxeroides in Contrasting Hydrological Conditions, Frontiers in Plant Science. (2015) 6, 10.3389/fpls.2015.00991, 2-s2.0-84947591841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2015.00991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26617628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee A. and Dewanji A., Effect of Varying Alternanthera philoxeroides (Alligator Weed) Cover on the Macrophyte Species Diversity of Pond Ecosystems: a Quadrat-based Study, Aquatic Invasions. (2014) 9, no. 3, 343&#x2013;355, 10.3391/ai.2014.9.3.09, 2-s2.0-84907258917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3391/ai.2014.9.3.09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo S., Ma Y., and Shinobu I., Differences in Ecological and Allelopathic Traits Among Alternanthera philoxeroides Populations, Weed Biology and Management. (2012) 12, no. 3, 123&#x2013;130, 10.1111/j.1445-6664.2012.00443.x, 2-s2.0-84865613869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1445-6664.2012.00443.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeiger C. F., Biological Control of alligator-weed with Agasicles n. sp. in Florida, Hyacinth Control Journal. (1967) 6, 31&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Buckingham G. R., Biological Control of Alligatorweed, Alternanthera philoxeroides, the World&#x2019;s First Aquatic Weed Success Story, Castanea. (1996) 61, no. 3, 232&#x2013;243, http://www.jstor.org/stable/4033676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X., He M., Ding J., and Siemann E., Latitudinal Variation in Soil Biota: Testing the Biotic Interaction Hypothesis with an Invasive Plant and a Native Congener, The ISME Journal. (2018) 12, no. 12, 2811&#x2013;2822, 10.1038/s41396-018-0219-5, 2-s2.0-85049927965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41396-018-0219-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6246596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30013163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niroula B., Phenology, Biomass and Associated Species of Alligator Weed at Biratnagar, Nepal, Nepalese Journal of Biosciences. (2013) 2, 148&#x2013;150, 10.3126/njbs.v2i0.7502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/njbs.v2i0.7502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha B. B., Invasive Alien Plant Species in Nepal, Front. of Bot. (2016) 269&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oli P. S., Adhikari U., and Bhattarai R., Study of Wheat Field Weeds in Biratnagar, Eastern Nepal, Journal of Agricultural Research. (2019) 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panedy K., Poudel G., Neupane A., Acharya K. R., and Adhikari S., Status of Invasive Alien Plant Species in Urban Forest of Hetauda, Nepal, Forestry: Journal of Institute of Forestry, Nepal. (2021) 18, no. 01, 107&#x2013;118, 10.3126/forestry.v18i01.41764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3126/forestry.v18i01.41764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak H. N., Bhuju D. R., Shrestha B. B., and Ranjitkar S., Impacts of Invasive Alien Plants on Ecosystem Services of Ramsar Lake Cluster in Middle Mountain Nepal, Global Ecology and Conservation. (2021) 27, 10.1016/j.gecco.2021.e01597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gecco.2021.e01597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak H. N., Shrestha B. B., Bhuju D. R., and Subedi D. S., Spatial Distribution of Invasive Alien Plants in Pokhara Valley, Nepal, Pakistan Journal of Botany. (2021) 53, no. 3, 1015&#x2013;1024, 10.30848/PJB2021-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30848/PJB2021-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H., Carrillo J., and Ding J., Species Diversity and Environmental Determinants of Aquatic and Terrestrial Communities Invaded by Alternanthera philoxeroides, Science of The Total Environment. (2017) 581-582, 666&#x2013;675, 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2016.12.177, 2-s2.0-85008698346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2016.12.177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28069304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Bo H., Song B. et al., Reshaping of the Soil Microbiome by the Expansion of Invasive Plants: Shifts in Structure, Diversity, co-occurrence, Niche Breadth, and Assembly Processes, Plant and Soil. (2022) 477, no. 1&#x2013;2, 629&#x2013;646, 10.1007/s11104-022-05445-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11104-022-05445-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J., Zhang B., Liu J., Fang Y., and Wang A., Spatiotemporal Dynamics in Microbial Communities Mediating Biogeochemical Cycling of Nutrients Across the Xiaowan Reservoir in Lancang River, Science of The Total Environment. (2022) 813, 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.151862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.151862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34826492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasgupta D. and Brahmaprakash G. P., Soil Microbes are Shaped by Soil Physicochemical Properties: a Brief Review of Existing Literature, International Journal of Plant &amp; Soil Science. (2021) 59&#x2013;71, 10.9734/ijpss/2021/v33i130409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/ijpss/2021/v33i130409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson J. K. and Hofmockel K. S., Soil Microbiomes and Climate Change, Nature Reviews Microbiology. (2020) 18, no. 1, 35&#x2013;46, 10.1038/s41579-019-0265-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-019-0265-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31586158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens K. L., Dantzler&#x2010;Kyer M. E., Patten M. A., and Souza L., Differential Responses to Global Change of Aquatic and Terrestrial Invasive Species: Evidences from a Meta&#x2010;Analysis, Ecosphere. (2019) 10, no. 4, 10.1002/ecs2.2680, 2-s2.0-85065014855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ecs2.2680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H., Liu Q., Wang S., Yang G., and Xue S., A Global meta-analysis of the Impacts of Exotic Plant Species Invasion on Plant Diversity and Soil Properties, Science of The Total Environment. (2022) 810, 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.152286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.152286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad Dar M., Ahmad M., Singh R., Kumar Kohli R., Singh H. P., and Batish D. R., Invasive Plants Alter Soil Properties and Nutrient Dynamics: a Case Study of Anthemis Cotula Invasion in Kashmir Himalaya, Catena. (2023) 226, 10.1016/j.catena.2023.107069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2023.107069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah K. K., Tiwari I., Tripathi S., Subedi S., and Shrestha J., Invasive Alien Plant Species: a Threat to Biodiversity and Agriculture in Nepal, Agriways. (2020) 08, no. 01, 62&#x2013;73, 10.38112/agw.2020.v08i01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.38112/agw.2020.v08i01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waksman S. A., A Method for Counting the Number of Fungi in the Soil, Journal of Bacteriology. (1922) 7, no. 3, 339&#x2013;341, 10.1128/JB.7.3.339-341.1922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JB.7.3.339-341.1922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC378974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aneja K. R., Experiments in Microbiology, Plant Pathology and Biotechnology, 2003, New Age International (P) Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe T., Pictorial Atlas of Soil and Seed Fungi. Boca raton (US), 2010, Lewis Publishers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilman J., A Manual of Soil Fungi, Soil Science. (1957) 84, no. 2, 10.1097/00010694-195708000-00021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00010694-195708000-00021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zobel D. B., Jha P. K., Behan M. J., and Yadav U. K. R., A Practical Manual for Ecology, 1987, Ratna Pustak Distributors, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtis J. T. and Mcintosh R. P., The Interrelations of Certain Analytic and Synthetic Phytosociological Characters, Ecology. (1950) 31, no. 3, 434&#x2013;455, 10.2307/1931497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/1931497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magurran A. E., Measuring Biological Diversity Blackwell Science, Biological Diversity: Frontiers in Measurement and Assessment. (2004) Oxford.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorenson T., A Method of Establishing Groups of Equal Amplitude in Plant Sociology Based on Similarity of Species Content, and its Application to Analysis of Vegetation on Danish Commons, Kongelige Danske Videnskabernes Selskab Biologiske Skrifter. (1948) 5, 1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grice A. C., The Impacts of Invasive Plant Species on the Biodiversity of Australian Rangelands, The Rangeland Journal. (2006) 28, no. 1, 27&#x2013;35, 10.1071/RJ06014, 2-s2.0-33744749204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/RJ06014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha B. B. and Shrestha K. K., Invasions of Alien Plant Species in Nepal: Patterns and Process, Invasive Alien Species. (2021) 2, 168&#x2013;183, 10.1002/9781119607045.ch20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781119607045.ch20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha U. B. and Shrestha B. B., Climate Change Amplifies Plant Invasion Hotspots in Nepal, Diversity and Distributions. (2019) 25, no. 10, 1599&#x2013;1612, 10.1111/ddi.12963, 2-s2.0-85073024651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ddi.12963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You W. H., Han C. M., Fang L. X., and Du D. L., Propagule Pressure, Habitat Conditions and Clonal Integration Influence the Establishment and Growth of an Invasive Clonal Plant, Alternanthera philoxeroides, Frontiers in Plant Science. (2016) 7, 10.3389/fpls.2016.00568, 2-s2.0-84966335603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2016.00568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4853405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27200041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Julien M. H., Groves R. H. et al., Alternanthera philoxeroides (Mart.) Griseb, /s. the Biology of Australian Weeds, 1995, RG and FJ Richardson, Melbourne, https://hdl.handle.net/102.100.100/235348?index=1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Tang X., Sun X. et al., An Invasive Plant Rapidly Increased the Similarity of Soil Fungal Pathogen Communities, Annals of Botany. (2021) 127, no. 3, 327&#x2013;336, 10.1093/aob/mcaa191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aob/mcaa191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7872125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L. and Wang T., Impact of Invasion of Exotic Plant Alternanthera philoxeroides on Interspecies Association and Stability of Native Plant Community, Chinese Journal of Eco-Agriculture. (2009) 17, no. 5, 851&#x2013;856, 10.3724/SP.J.1011.2009.00851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3724/SP.J.1011.2009.00851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Chen J. X., Liu M. C., Arnold P. A., Wang W. B., and Feng Y. L., Phenotypic Plasticity and Exotic Plant Invasions: Effects of Soil Nutrients, Species Nutrient Requirements, and Types of Traits, Physiologia Plantarum. (2022) 174, no. 1, 10.1111/ppl.13637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ppl.13637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35092017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gioria M., Hulme P. E., Richardson D. M., and Py&#x161;ek P., Why are Invasive Plants Successful?, Annual Review of Plant Biology. (2023) 74, no. 1, 635&#x2013;670, 10.1146/annurev-arplant-070522-071021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-arplant-070522-071021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36750415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Du Y., 
Pei L., 
Liu J. et al., Chemical Strategy of the Invasive Plant Alternanthera philoxeroides Leading Ecological Adaptation in Constructed Wetlands, Chiang Mai Journal of Science. (2020) 47, no. 5, 899&#x2013;911, http://cmuir.cmu.ac.th/jspui/handle/6653943832/69903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pii Y., Mimmo T., Tomasi N., Terzano R., Cesco S., and Crecchio C., Microbial Interactions in the Rhizosphere: Beneficial Influences of Plant growth-promoting Rhizobacteria on Nutrient Acquisition Process. A Review, Biology and Fertility of Soils. (2015) 51, no. 4, 403&#x2013;415, 10.1007/s00374-015-0996-1, 2-s2.0-84934763940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00374-015-0996-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si C., Liu X., Wang C. et al., Different Degrees of Plant Invasion Significantly Affect the Richness of the Soil Fungal Community, PLoS One. (2013) 8, no. 12, 10.1371/journal.pone.0085490, 2-s2.0-84893667973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0085490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3877371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24392015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vujanovi&#x107; D., Losapio G., Mili&#x107; S., and Mili&#x107; D., The Impact of Multiple Species Invasion on Soil and Plant Communities Increases with Invasive Species co-occurrence, Frontiers in Plant Science. (2022) 13, 10.3389/fpls.2022.875824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2022.875824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9194948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35712554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangla S., Inderjit, and Callaway R. M., Exotic Invasive Plant Accumulates Native Soil Pathogens Which Inhibit Native Plants, Journal of Ecology. (2008) 96, no. 1, 58&#x2013;67, 10.1111/j.1365-2745.2007.01312.x, 2-s2.0-37149048050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2745.2007.01312.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B., Zhang X., Zagorchev L., Li J., Frey B., and Li M., Parasitism Changes Rhizospheric Soil Microbial Communities of Invasive Alternanthera philoxeroides, Benefitting the Growth of Neighboring Plants, Applied Soil Ecology. (2019) 143, 1&#x2013;9, 10.1016/j.apsoil.2019.05.025, 2-s2.0-85066603712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsoil.2019.05.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen S., Pan Y., Chen L., Tu Y., and Pan X., Plant-Soil Feedbacks Differ Between Native and Introduced Populations of Alternanthera philoxeroides, Biodiversity Science. (2023) 31, no. 3, 10.17520/biods.2022436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17520/biods.2022436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge Y., Wang Q., Wang L. et al., Response of Soil Enzymes and Microbial Communities to Root Extracts of the Alien Alternanthera philoxeroides, Archives of Agronomy and Soil Science. (2018) 64, no. 5, 708&#x2013;717, 10.1080/03650340.2017.1373186, 2-s2.0-85029438744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03650340.2017.1373186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann A., Schmid M., Tuinen D. V., and Berg G., Plant-Driven Selection of Microbes, Plant and Soil. (2009) 321, no. 1-2, 235&#x2013;257, 10.1007/s11104-008-9814-y, 2-s2.0-70449708588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11104-008-9814-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Ge Y., Wang Q., Zhou H., Liu W., and Christie P., Allelopathic Effects of Aqueous Extracts of Alternanthera philoxeroides on the Growth of Zoysia matrella, Polish Journal of Environmental Studies. (2017) 26, no. 1, 97&#x2013;105, 10.15244/pjoes/65039, 2-s2.0-85034827307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15244/pjoes/65039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X. and Zhang S., Nitrogen Addition Shapes Soil Enzyme Activity Patterns by Changing pH Rather than the Composition of the Plant and Microbial Communities in an Alpine Meadow Soil, Plant and Soil. (2019) 440, no. 1-2, 11&#x2013;24, 10.1007/s11104-019-04054-5, 2-s2.0-85064353592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11104-019-04054-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly P. K., Entry J. A., Crawford D. L., and Cromack K.Jr, Cellulose and Lignin Degradation in Forest Soils: Response to Moisture, Temperature, and Acidity, Microbial Ecology. (1990) 20, no. 1, 289&#x2013;295, 10.1007/BF02543884, 2-s2.0-0025652816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02543884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24193981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H. Q., Yu J. F., Wu Y. M., Zhang T. Y., and Wang H. F., Diversity Analysis of Soil Dematiaceous Hyphomycetes from the Yellow River Source Area: I, Journal of Zhejiang University SCIENCE B. (2008) 9, no. 10, 829&#x2013;834, 10.1631/jzus.B0860002, 2-s2.0-53549106893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1631/jzus.B0860002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2565748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18837112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rousk J., B&#xe5;&#xe5;th E., Brookes P. C. et al., Soil Bacterial and Fungal Communities Across a pH Gradient in an Arable Soil, The ISME Journal. (2010) 4, no. 10, 1340&#x2013;1351, 10.1038/ismej.2010.58, 2-s2.0-77956996314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ismej.2010.58</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20445636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha B. B., Garkoti S., Van Bloem S., Ful&#xe9; P., and Semwal R., Management of Invasive Alien Plants in Nepal: Current Practices and Future Prospects, Tropical Ecosystems: Structure, Functions and Challenges in the Face of Global Change, 2019, Springer, Singapore, 10.1007/978-981-13-8249-9_4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-13-8249-9_4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>