<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41651905</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Synthesis of highly conducting molybdenum disulfide electrode for asymmetric supercapacitor applications.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7547</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-38362-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Binder-free (BF) homogeneous Molybdenum disulfide (MoS<sub>2</sub>) nanosheets showing an average crystallite size of 34.59 nm, are deposited on nickel foam (NiF) by chemical vapor deposition process. The MoS<sub>2</sub>/NiF electrode exhibited a surface area of 109 m<sup>2</sup>/g, specific capacitance of 2726 F/g at 5 mV/s, charge transfer resistance of 2.36 &#x3a9;, and diffusion resistance of 1.16 for 10,000 cycles. The electrode is presented cyclic stability and Coulombic efficiency of 83% and 95% after 10,000 cycles. The capacitive contributions are remained lower than diffusion across scan rates 5-140 mV/s. The assembled device delivers capacitance of 191 F/g at 1.5 A/g, with maximum energy density of 68Wh/kg at minimum power density of 1200 W/kg. The theoretical model simulations is confirmed that the synthesized electrode showed excellent electrochemical performance due to combined current contributions of capacitive and diffusion controlled processes. Therefore, the MoS<sub>2</sub>/NiF electrodes are suitable for hybrid supercapacitive performance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Ahsan Riaz</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical Informational Engineering, Shandong University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Jinan, 250355, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National United Engineering Laboratory for Biomedical Material Modification, Branden Industrial Park, Qihe Economic &amp; Development Zone, Dezhou City, 251100, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badshah</LastName><ForeName>Fazal</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shiyan Key Laboratory of Electromagnetic Induction and Energy Saving Technology, School of Artificial Intelligence, Hubei University of Automotive Technology, Shiyan, 442002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Awais</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Key Laboratory for Super Microstructure and Ultrafast Process, School of Physics, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imran</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Advanced Materials Science (RCAMS), King Khalid University, P.O. Box 9004, 61413, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Faculty of Science, King Khalid University, P.O. Box 9004, 61413, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Rajwali</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Water and Energy Center, United Arab Emirates University, 15551, Al Ain, United Arab Emirates. rajjjzju4@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Lakki Marwat, Khyber Pakhtoonkhwa, Pakistan. rajjjzju4@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sangaraju</LastName><ForeName>Sambasivam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Water and Energy Center, United Arab Emirates University, 15551, Al Ain, United Arab Emirates. s_sambasivam@uaeu.ac.ae.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zulqarnain</LastName><ForeName>Rana Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, Saveetha School of Engineering, SIMATS Thandalam, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 602105, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdullaev</LastName><ForeName>Sherzod</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Researcher of Scientific Department, National Pedagogical University of Uzbekistan, Tashkent, Uzbekistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Andijan State Technical Institute , Andijan, Uzbekistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Capacitive contributions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Faradic redox reactions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MoS2/NiF</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanosheets</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41651905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12932845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-38362-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-38362-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kumbhar, M. B. et al. Enhancing energy storage with binder-free nickel oxide cathodes in flexible hybrid asymmetric solid-state supercapacitors. <i>J. Alloy. Compd.</i><b>1010</b>, 177311 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumbhar, M. B. et al. Exploring copper-doped nickel oxide as a superior cathode electrode material for flexible hybrid solid-state supercapacitor device. <i>J. Ind. Eng. Chem.</i><b>147</b>, 422&#x2013;435 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2024.12.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randive, S. G. &amp; Lokhande, B. J. Spray pyrolyzed hydrophilic nickel oxide electrodes with nano-granular morphology for a symmetric supercapacitor device. <i>J. Alloy. Compd.</i><b>944</b>, 169046 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2023.169046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumbhar, M. B. et al. Flexible hybrid solid-state supercapacitors based on cobalt-doped nickel oxide@ stainless steel versus reduced graphene oxide@ stainless steel. J. Solid State Electrochem. 1&#x2013;19 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, I. et al. High-performance aqueous asymmetric pseudo-supercapacitor using potassium doped Maganese oxide and resorcinol-formaldehyde aerogel for extended voltage operation. <i>Mater. Res. Bull.</i><b>194</b>, 113725 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, S. et al. Fabrication of binder free CVD based molybdenum disulfide ASC device: Supercapacitive performance. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>111</b>, 115383 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2025.115383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. et al. Controlled synthesis and fine-tuned interface of NiS nanoparticles/Bi<sub>2</sub>WO<sub>6</sub> nanosheets heterogeneous as electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction. <i>Appl. Surf. Sci.</i><b>526</b>, 146718 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2020.146718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumbhar, M. B., Chandak, V. S. &amp; Kulal, P. M. Enhanced ammonia gas sensing performance at room temperature of binder-free NiO, Cu and Co-doped NiO thin films synthesized via the SILAR method. <i>Mater. Chem. Phys.</i><b>329</b>, 130065 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.130065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arif, D. et al. Design of ZnO&#x2013;VSe<sub>2</sub> nanocomposite for high performance asymmetric supercapacitors. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>(1), 17592 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-02531-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12095500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40399416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, R. et al. Transition metal dichalcogenides for next-generation supercapacitors: Recent advances, challenges, and future perspectives. <i>J. Alloys Compd.</i><b>1039</b>, 182874 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.182874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran, T. et al. MOF-infused gels: A new era in advanced energy storage, adsorption, and environmental remediation. <i>Surfaces Interfaces</i><b>72</b>, 107420 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfin.2025.107420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randive, S. G. &amp; Lokhande, B. J. Utilization of spray pyrolyzed porous nickel cobaltite electrode as an advanced material for NiCo<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub>@ Graphite asymmetric supercapacitor device. <i>Inorg. Chem. Commun.</i><b>161</b>, 112099 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil, V. V. et al. Crystallinity transformation engineering of hydrous cobalt nickel phosphate cathodes for hybrid supercapacitor devices: extrinsic/battery to intercalation type pseudocapacitors. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>485</b>, 150055 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.150055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randive, S. G. et al. Impact of different optical energies on the electrochemical performance of NiO@ KOH assembly and NiO@ NiO symmetric supercapacitor device. <i>Inorg. Chem. Commun.</i><b>178</b>, 114600 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inoche.2025.114600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, I. et al. Uniform growth of ZnS nanoflakes for high-performance supercapacitor applications. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>36</b>, 102408 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2021.102408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govindaraj, B. S. P. et al. Facile hydrothermal synthesis of 2D tin sulphide (SnS2) nanoflakes for supercapacitor applications. <i>Z. Phys. Chem.</i><b>239</b>(7), 1085&#x2013;1100 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majumdar, D. Recent progress in copper sulfide based nanomaterials for high energy supercapacitor applications. <i>J. Electroanal. Chem.</i><b>880</b>, 114825 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelechem.2020.114825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, B. et al. Synthesis of Mo doped Ni<sub>2</sub>S<sub>3</sub> nanaorods arrays for overall water splitting. <i>Int. J. Electrochem. Sci.</i><b>13</b>(9), 8506&#x2013;8517 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20964/2018.09.57</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charapale, M. R. et al. Enhancing capacitive performance of MoS<sub>2</sub> through Fe doping: Synthesis, characterization, and electrochemical evaluation for supercapacitor applications. <i>Surfaces Interfaces</i><b>52</b>, 104814 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, R. et al. Charge transport and ferromagnetic interactions in Ti double-doped ZnO nanorods for spin electronic applications. <i>J. Saudi Chem. Soc.</i><b>29</b>(1), 4 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44442-025-00006-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, R. et al. Carrier-mediated ferromagnetism and dielectric tailoring in dual-doped ZnO semiconductor nanoparticles for spintronics. <i>Mater. Sci. Semicond. Process.</i><b>193</b>, 109487 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safeen, A. et al. Enhancing the physical properties and photocatalytic activity of TiO<sub>2</sub> nanoparticles via cobalt doping. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>12</b>(25), 15767&#x2013;15774 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2RA01948E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9132072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35685706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arif, D. et al. Influence of defects on the enhancement of thermoelectric properties in Sn-doped ZnO nanostructure synthesized via hydrothermal route. <i>Front. Chem.</i><b>13</b>, 1598509 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchem.2025.1598509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12170524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40529531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safeen, K. et al. Structure phase-dependent dielectric and photodegradation properties of Co-doped TiO<sub>2</sub> nanoparticles synthesized via co-precipitation route. <i>J. Saudi Chem. Soc.</i><b>27</b>(5), 101711 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jscs.2023.101711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amani, M. et al. Electrical performance of monolayer MoS<sub>2</sub> field-effect transistors prepared by chemical vapor deposition. <i>Appl. Phys. Lett.</i><b>102</b>(19), 193107 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.4804546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. The microstructure evolution during MoS<sub>2</sub> films growth and its influence on the MoS<sub>2</sub> optical-electrical properties in MoS<sub>2</sub>/p-Si heterojunction solar cells. <i>Superlattices Microstruct.</i><b>137</b>, 106352 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spmi.2019.106352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaabani, R. et al. Effect of sulfurization on physical and electrical properties of MoS<sub>2</sub> films synthesized by electrodeposition route. <i>Mater. Res. Express</i><b>6</b>(11), 115902 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/ab438c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahbazi, M. &amp; Khanlary, M. R. Study of optical, electrochemical, and morphological properties of MoS<sub>2</sub> thin films prepared by thermal evaporation. <i>Braz. J. Phys.</i><b>51</b>(4), 1182&#x2013;1190 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13538-021-00917-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, W., Wang, J. &amp; Hong, R. Laser thinning induced the tunable of nonlinear optical property of MoS<sub>2</sub> thin film. <i>Opt. Mater.</i><b>129</b>, 112506 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optmat.2022.112506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taherkhani, A. &amp; Shahbazi, M. Probing the optical and structural properties of pristine MoS<sub>2</sub> nanoflakes and TM/MoS<sub>2</sub> hybrids fabricated by spray pyrolysis and PVD techniques. <i>Mater. Today Commun.</i><b>34</b>, 105092 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2022.105092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza, A. et al. Enhanced industrial dye degradation using Co doped in chemically exfoliated MoS<sub>2</sub> nanosheets. <i>Appl. Nanosci.</i><b>10</b>(5), 1535&#x2013;1544 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13204-019-01239-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Two-step electrodeposition synthesis of NiCo<sub>2</sub>S<sub>4</sub>/MoSx composite on nickel foam as electrodes for supercapacitors. <i>J. Alloy. Compd.</i><b>932</b>, 167628 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2022.167628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, H. et al. Hydrothermal preparation of MoS<sub>2</sub> nanoflake arrays on Cu foil with enhanced supercapacitive property. <i>Electrochim. Acta</i><b>227</b>, 101&#x2013;109 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2017.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karade, S. S., Dubal, D. P. &amp; Sankapal, B. R. MoS<sub>2</sub> ultrathin nanoflakes for high performance supercapacitors: Room temperature chemical bath deposition (CBD). <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>6</b>(45), 39159&#x2013;39165 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6RA04441G</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujari, R. et al. Chemically deposited nano grain composed MoS<sub>2</sub> thin films for supercapacitor application. <i>J. Colloid Interface Sci.</i><b>496</b>, 1&#x2013;7 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2016.11.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28209539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pazhamalai, P. et al. High energy symmetric supercapacitor based on mechanically delaminated few-layered MoS<sub>2</sub> sheets in organic electrolyte. <i>J. Alloy. Compd.</i><b>771</b>, 803&#x2013;809 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2018.08.203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnamoorthy, K. et al. Mechanically delaminated few layered MoS<sub>2</sub> nanosheets based high performance wire type solid-state symmetric supercapacitors. <i>J. Power Sources</i><b>321</b>, 112&#x2013;119 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.04.116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, X. et al. Nanostructured Mo-based electrode materials for electrochemical energy storage. <i>Chem. Soc. Rev.</i><b>44</b>(8), 2376&#x2013;2404 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C4CS00350K</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25688809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo, S. &amp; Rout, C. S. Facile electrochemical synthesis of porous manganese-cobalt-sulfide based ternary transition metal sulfide nanosheets architectures for high performance energy storage applications. <i>Electrochim. Acta</i><b>220</b>, 57&#x2013;66 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2016.10.043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raza, A. et al. Synthesis of binder-free, low-resistant randomly orientated nanorod/sheet ZnS&#x2013;MoS<sub>2</sub> as electrode materials for portable energy storage applications. <i>ACS Omega</i><b>9</b>(26), 27919&#x2013;27931 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c09560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11223144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38973928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumuthini, R. et al. Electrochemical properties of electrospun MoS<sub>2</sub>@ C nanofiber as electrode material for high-performance supercapacitor application. <i>J. Alloy. Compd.</i><b>705</b>, 624&#x2013;630 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2017.02.163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. From bulk to monolayer MoS<sub>2</sub>: Evolution of Raman scattering. <i>Adv. Func. Mater.</i><b>22</b>(7), 1385&#x2013;1390 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.201102111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanger, A., Malik, V. K. &amp; Chandra, R. One step sputtered grown MoS<sub>2</sub> nanoworms binder free electrodes for high performance supercapacitor application. <i>Int. J. Hydrogen Energy</i><b>43</b>(24), 11141&#x2013;11149 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2018.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary, N. et al. Directly deposited MoS<sub>2</sub> thin film electrodes for high performance supercapacitors. <i>J. Mater. Chem. A</i><b>3</b>(47), 24049&#x2013;24054 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5TA08095A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem, S. et al. Electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction on sulfur-deficient MoS<sub>2</sub> nanostructures. <i>Int. J. Hydrogen Energy</i><b>47</b>(12), 7713&#x2013;7723 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2021.12.081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnamoorthy, K. et al. Designing two dimensional nanoarchitectured MoS<sub>2</sub> sheets grown on Mo foil as a binder free electrode for supercapacitors. <i>Electrochim. Acta</i><b>190</b>, 305&#x2013;312 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2015.12.148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvamani, P. S. et al. Microwave synthesized &#x3b1;-Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/MoS<sub>2</sub>/rGO composites as high-performance supercapacitor. <i>Mater. Lett.</i><b>293</b>, 129721 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2021.129721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvamani, P. S. et al. High-performance supercapacitor based on Cu<sub>2</sub>O/MoS<sub>2</sub>/rGO nanocomposite. <i>Mater. Lett.</i><b>275</b>, 128095 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2020.128095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, W. et al. One-step extended strategy for the ionic liquid-assisted synthesis of Ni<sub>3</sub>S<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;MoS<sub>2</sub> heterojunction electrodes for supercapacitors. <i>J. Mater. Chem. A</i><b>5</b>(22), 11278&#x2013;11285 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C7TA02268A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X., Zhao, L. &amp; Lian, J. Arrays of hierarchical nickel sulfides/MoS<sub>2</sub> nanosheets supported on carbon nanotubes backbone as advanced anode materials for asymmetric supercapacitor. <i>J. Power Sources</i><b>343</b>, 373&#x2013;382 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2017.01.078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo, D. et al. High-performance MnO<sub>2</sub> nanowire/MoS<sub>2</sub> nanosheet composite for a symmetrical solid-state supercapacitor. <i>ACS Omega</i><b>7</b>(20), 16895&#x2013;16905 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c06852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9134226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35647444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X. et al. Amorphous CoMoS4 for a valuable energy storage material candidate. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>301</b>, 266&#x2013;275 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2016.05.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnamoorthy, K. et al. Supercapacitive properties of hydrothermally synthesized sphere like MoS<sub>2</sub> nanostructures. <i>Mater. Res. Bull.</i><b>50</b>, 499&#x2013;502 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.materresbull.2013.11.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, W. et al. One-step extended strategy for the ionic liquid-assisted synthesis of Ni&#x2083;S&#x2084;&#x2013;MoS&#x2082; heterojunction electrodes for supercapacitors (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D. et al. Kelp-like structured NiCo<sub>2</sub>S<sub>4</sub>-C-MoS<sub>2</sub> composite electrodes for high performance supercapacitor. <i>J. Alloy. Compd.</i><b>735</b>, 1505&#x2013;1513 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2017.11.249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal, M. Z. &amp; Khan, J. Optimization of cobalt-manganese binary sulfide for high performance supercapattery devices. <i>Electrochim. Acta</i><b>368</b>, 137529 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2020.137529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Reducing graphene oxide carbon skeleton supported PN heterostructure of bimetallic sulfide CoS-MoS<sub>2</sub> nanorods for high-performance lithium storage. <i>J. Colloid Interface Sci.</i><b>630</b>, 623&#x2013;633 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2022.09.067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36343554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palanisamy, R. et al. High-performance asymmetric supercapacitor fabricated with a novel MoS<sub>2</sub>/Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>/Graphene composite electrode. <i>Colloid Interface Sci. Commun.</i><b>46</b>, 100573 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colcom.2021.100573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madeshwaran, M., Rajni, K. &amp; Ulaganathan, M. Polyaniline@ MoS<sub>2</sub>: An organic and inorganic hybrid framework for asymmetric supercapacitor applications. <i>Mater. Today Chem.</i><b>42</b>, 102390 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J. et al. Smart in situ construction of NiS/MoS<sub>2</sub> composite nanosheets with ultrahigh specific capacity for high-performance asymmetric supercapacitor. <i>J. Alloy. Compd.</i><b>811</b>, 151915 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2019.151915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis, M. K. et al. Binder free aluminium incorporated MoS<sub>2</sub>@ CC electrode for supercapacitor applications. <i>J. Energy Storage</i><b>71</b>, 108054 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2023.108054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>