<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41835767</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Role of Neck Imaging Reporting and Data System in Evaluation of Recurrent/Residual Lesions of Head and Neck Cancers by Contrast-Enhanced Computed Tomography (CECT) With Pathological Correlation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103321</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103321</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103321</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103321</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Head and neck cancers remain a major global health concern, mainly involving the oral cavity, pharynx, larynx, thyroid, and salivary glands. The Neck Imaging Reporting and Data System (NI-RADS) has been developed as a structured framework in order to enhance the quality and consistency of imaging reports for patients undergoing surveillance after treatment for head and neck cancers.&#xa0;NI-RADS provides a standardized lexicon that simplifies the communication of imaging findings. This is crucial given the intricate anatomical and pathological changes that can occur following treatment, which often complicate the interpretation of imaging studies. In the context of head and neck cancer, the post-treatment landscape is characterized by a range of changes, including surgical alterations, radiation effects, and potential disease recurrence. Traditional reporting methods can lead to ambiguities, misinterpretations, and inconsistent management decisions. NI-RADS mitigates these challenges by categorizing findings into a systematic reporting structure that emphasizes clarity. Each category (NI-RADS 1 through NI-RADS 4) offers specific definitions and criteria that assist radiologists in assessing the likelihood of residual disease or recurrence, thus facilitating more informed clinical decision-making and improving patient outcomes. By providing a common language, NI-RADS helps bridge the gap between imaging interpretation and clinical management, ultimately enhancing the overall quality of care for patients with head and neck cancers. Methods Contrast-enhanced computed tomography head and neck images of 64 post-treatment cancer patients were evaluated and allotted a NI-RADS category for the primary site and lymph node involvement using the NI-RADS lexicon, and consequently followed up with clinical correlation and histopathological report to determine the sensitivity, specificity, negative predictive value, and positive predictive value. Results The majority of cases were classified as NI-RADS 1 (36 cases), followed by NI-RADS 3 (21 cases), and the least were NI-RADS 2 (7 cases). The overall recurrence rate at the primary site was 21.88% (14/64 cases). A strong correlation was observed between NI-RADS categorization and recurrence rates. NI-RADS 1 demonstrated a 0% recurrence rate, confirming its high negative predictive value (100%). It was also observed that NI-RADS 3 is highly effective in detecting recurrences, with a positive predictive value of 61.9% for the primary site and 100% for nodal recurrence.&#xa0;The findings also suggested that NI-RADS 2 remains a gray zone, where careful evaluation and further diagnostic steps are necessary. The lower positive predictive value (33.33%) of NI-RADS 2 for nodal recurrence and the recurrence rate at the primary site (14.3%) indicate that some cases categorized as NI-RADS 2 may progress to recurrence, necessitating individualized follow-up strategies. Conclusion This study reinforces the utility of NI-RADS as a reliable tool for risk stratification in head and neck cancer surveillance. The high statistical significance in both primary site and nodal recurrence underscores its predictive accuracy. NI-RADS 1 effectively rules out recurrence and requires routine follow-up. NI-RADS 2 has moderate recurrence rates and requires further evaluation. NI-RADS 3 has a high predictive value for recurrence and necessitates immediate attention.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Yeerasam et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeerasam</LastName><ForeName>Vaishnavi</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology, Vydehi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research Centre, Bengaluru, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nadamani</LastName><ForeName>Aditi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology, Vydehi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research Centre, Bengaluru, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>A</LastName><ForeName>Suresh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology, Vydehi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research Centre, Bengaluru, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varunya</LastName><ForeName>Mary</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology, Vydehi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research Centre, Bengaluru, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cect neck</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">head and neck ct</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">head and neck radiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">local recurrence of head and neck cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nirads</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Vydehi Institutional Ethics Committee issued approval ECR/747/Inst/KA/2015/RR21. This is to certify that the thesis synopsis titled "ROLE OF NI-RADS IN EVALUATION OF RECURRENT/RESIDUAL HEAD AND NECK CANCERS BY CECT WITH PATHOLOGICAL CORRELATION" submitted by Dr. Vaishnavi Yeerasam, Post Graduate, Department of Radiodiagnosis under the guidance of Dr. Suresh A, Professor and HOD, Department of Radiodiagnosis, Vydehi Institute of Medical Sciences and Research Centre, Bangalore, is approved by Vydehi Institutional Ethics Committee (VIEC). Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41835767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12981607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology, risk factors, and prevention of head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Barsouk A, Aluru JS, Rawla P, Saginala K, Barsouk A. Med Sci (Basel) 2023;11:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10304137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37367741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reviewing the epidemiology of head and neck cancer: definitions, trends and risk factors. Gormley M, Creaney G, Schache A, Ingarfield K, Conway DI. Br Dent J. 2022;233:780&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9652141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contemporary imaging and reporting strategies for head and neck cancer: MRI, FDG PET/MRI, NI-RADS, and carcinoma of unknown primary-AJR expert panel narrative review. Mukherjee S, Fischbein NJ, Baugnon KL, Policeni BA, Raghavan P. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2023;220:160&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Agrawal N, Fakhry C. HPV and Head and Neck Cancers. Berlin: Springer; 2015. Anatomical sites and subsites of head and neck cancer; pp. 1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Late side effects of radiation treatment for head and neck cancer. Brook I. Radiat Oncol J. 2020;38:84&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33012151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-treatment surveillance imaging in head and neck cancer: a systematic review. Van Hoe S, Hermans R. Insights Imaging. 2024;15:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10844183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38315325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevalence of locoregional recurrence and survival post-treatment of head and neck cancers in Africa: a&#xa0;systematic review and meta-analysis. Melariri H, Els T, Oyedele O, et al. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;59:101964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10139903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37125401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interreader reproducibility of the Neck Imaging Reporting and Data system (NI-RADS) lexicon for the detection of residual/recurrent disease in treated head and neck squamous cell carcinoma (HNSCC) Abdelaziz TT, Abdel Razk AA, Ashour MM, Abdelrahman AS. Cancer Imaging. 2020;20:61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posttreatment head and neck cancer imaging: anatomic considerations based on cancer subsites. Hiyama T, Miyasaka Y, Kuno H, Sekiya K, Sakashita S, Shinozaki T, Kobayashi T. Radiographics. 2024;44:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38386602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical treatment of head and neck cancers in the ancient world. Kelly J, Mahalingam S. J Laryngol Otol. 2015;129:535&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26004289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best practices: application of NI-RADS for posttreatment surveillance imaging of head and neck cancer. Strauss SB, Aiken AH, Lantos JE, Phillips CD. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2021;216:1438&#x2013;1451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32876470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Response assessment of post-treatment head and neck cancers to determine further management using NI-RADS (Neck Imaging Reporting and Data System): a subgroup analysis of a randomized controlled trial. Mahajan A, Unde H, Sable NP, et al. Front Oncol. 2023;13:1200366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10552531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37810970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MRI posttreatment surveillance for head and neck squamous cell carcinoma: proposed MR NI-RADS criteria. Ashour MM, Darwish EA, Fahiem RM, Abdelaziz TT. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2021;42:1123&#x2013;1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8191657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33707288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PET-CT for staging and detection of recurrence of head and neck cancer. Wong WL. Semin Nucl Med. 2021;51:13&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33246535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACR Neck Imaging Reporting and Data Systems (NI-RADS): a&#xa0;white paper of the&#xa0;ACR NI-RADS Committee. Aiken AH, Rath TJ, Anzai Y, et al. J Am Coll Radiol. 2018;15:1097&#x2013;1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29983244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predictive value of neck imaging reporting and data system (NI-RADS) in CECT/CEMRI of laryngeal and oral cavity squamous cell carcinoma. Abdelrahman AS, Ashour MMM, Abdelaziz TT. Egypt J Radiol Nucl Med. 2020;51:241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Performance of Neck Imaging Reporting and Data System (NI-RADS) for diagnosis of recurrence of head and neck squamous cell carcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Baba A, Kurokawa R, Kurokawa M, Yanagisawa T, Srinivasan A. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2023;44:1184&#x2013;1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10549942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37709352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Performance of the Neck Imaging Reporting and Data System (NI-RADS) as applied by general neuroradiologists to predict recurrence of head and neck cancers. Lee J, Kaht D, Ali S, et al. Head Neck. 2022;44:2257&#x2013;2264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35801334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>