<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41194010</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ameliorative effects of biofertilizers on yield, water use efficiency and quality of bean under drought stress conditions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1512</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1512</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1512</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-025-07339-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The use of Plant Growth-Promoting Rhizobacteria (PGPR) is one of the alternative strategies to mitigate the effects of drought. This study aimed to determine the effects of the Partial Root-Zone Drying (PRD) and conventional deficit irrigation techniques on dwarf bean by reducing drought stress through microbial fertilizer applications. The parameters evaluated included yield, plant water consumption, water use efficiency (WUE), irrigation water use efficiency (IWUE), plant growth characteristics, chlorophyll content and biochemical properties. The Gina dwarf bean variety (Phaseolus vulgaris L. cv. Gina) was used in the research conducted at Akdeniz University. Biofertilizers consisting of Pantoea agglomerans RK-92, Paenibacillus polymyxa TV-12E, Bacillus megaterium TV-6D and Pseudomonas fluorescens FDG-37 bacterial strains were supplied by Atat&#xfc;rk University Plant Protection Department. The study was planned with and without biofertilizer (BF) application, and five irrigation treatments were considered. Three conventional irrigation treatments were applied: 100% of the evaporation (I<sub>100</sub>), 75% of the evaporation (I<sub>75</sub>), and 50% of the evaporation (I<sub>50</sub>). And, two treatments were applied to Partial Root Zone Drying (PRD): 75% of the evaporation (PRD<sub>75</sub>) and 50% of the evaporation (PRD<sub>50</sub>).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">According to the research results, remarkable results were obtained from the biofertilizer treatments. The highest first-class (8.44 t ha<sup>-1</sup>) and total yield (10.50 t ha<sup>-1</sup>) was recorded from the BF-I<sub>100</sub> treatment. Compared to the control treatment (I<sub>100</sub>) with a first-class yield of 4.40 t ha<sup>-1</sup> and a total yield of 9.31 t ha<sup>-1</sup>, the BF-I<sub>100</sub> treatment provided a 14.5% higher first-class yield and a 12.78% higher total yield. Similarly, compared to the control, the BF-I<sub>75</sub> resulted in higher first-class (7.36 t ha<sup>-1</sup>; 6.6%) and total yields (9.34 t ha<sup>-1</sup>; 9.88%). Among the deficit irrigation treatments, the highest total yield was recorded in the BF-PRD<sub>75</sub> (9.54 t ha<sup>-1</sup>) treatment with biofertilizer. The total yield obtained from BF-PRD<sub>75</sub> was 2.47% higher than that of the I<sub>100</sub> treatment and was one of the most striking results. The BF-PRD<sub>50</sub> treatment exhibited the highest WUE (11.26&#xa0;kg m<sup>-3</sup>) and IWUE (13.88&#xa0;kg m<sup>-3</sup>) for both first-class and total yield, with no statistically significant differences among BF-I<sub>50</sub>, BF-I<sub>100</sub>, and BF-PRD<sub>50</sub> treatments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In conclusion, growth, yield, and quality characteristics were significantly influenced by the irrigation treatments. Biofertilizer applications were effective under both optimized and deficit irrigation conditions. The ameliorative and drought-reducing effects of biofertilizer treatments were clearly observed. This study found that biofertilizers positively impact yield and quality, potentially enabling water savings of 25-50%. They can be effectively used in regions with drought-related water shortages.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demir</LastName><ForeName>Halil</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Agricultural Faculty, Akdeniz University, Antalya, Turkey. hdemir@akdeniz.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaman</LastName><ForeName>Harun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural Structures and Irrigation, Agricultural Faculty, Akdeniz University, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saka</LastName><ForeName>Anda&#xe7; Kutay</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Agricultural Faculty, Ordu University, Ordu, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>U&#xe7;an</LastName><ForeName>Ufuk</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Agricultural Faculty, Akdeniz University, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kotan</LastName><ForeName>Recep</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Protection, Agricultural Faculty, Ataturk University, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akg&#xfc;n</LastName><ForeName>&#x130;smail Hakk&#x131;</ForeName><Initials>&#x130;H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Production, Elmal&#x131; Vocational School, Akdeniz University, Antalya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005308">Fertilizers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D027805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Phaseolus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005308" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fertilizers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055864" MajorTopicYN="Y">Droughts</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057914" MajorTopicYN="N">Agricultural Irrigation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018517" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Roots</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013312" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bean</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drought</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PGPR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Partial root zone drying</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yield</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Informed consent: Not applicable. Statement specifying permissions: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41194010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12590805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-025-07339-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-025-07339-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Yasmin F, Song BH. Neglected treasures in the wild legume wild relatives in food security and human health. Curr Opin Plant Biol. 2019;49:17&#x2013;26. 10.1016/j.pbi.2019.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pbi.2019.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6817337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31085425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morosan M, Hassan MA, Naranjo MA, L&#xf3;pez-Gresa MP, Boscaiu M, Vicente O. Comparative analysis of drought responses in <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> (common bean) and <i>P. coccineus</i> (runner bean) cultivars. EuroBiotech J. 2017;1(3):247&#x2013;52. 10.24190/ISSN2564-615X/2017/03.09.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24190/ISSN2564-615X/2017/03.09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karavidas I, Ntatsi G, Vougeleka V, Karkanis A, Ntanasi T, Saitanis C, Agathokleous E, Ropokis A, Sabatino L, Tran F, Lannetta PPM, Savvas D. Agronomic practices to increase the yield and quality of common bean (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L). Syst Rev Agron. 2022;12(2):271. 10.3390/agronomy12020271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy12020271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. Crops and livestock products. 2024. https://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data/QCL (Accessed 8 July 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Amri SM. Application of bio-fertilizers for enhancing growth and yield of common bean plants grown under water stress conditions. Saudi J Biol Sci. 2021;28:3901&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.sjbs.2021.03.064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sjbs.2021.03.064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8241702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34220246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samanc&#x131;o&#x11f;lu A, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m E, &#x15e;ahin &#xdc;. Effect of seedlings development, some physiological and biochemical properties of cabbage seedlings grown at different irrigation levels of the plant growth promoting rhizobacteria application. KSU J Na Sci. 2016;19(3):332&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bueno PCP, Lopes NP. Metabolomics to characterize adaptive and signaling responses in legume crops under abiotic stresses. ACS Omega. 2020;5(4):1752&#x2013;63. 10.1021/acsomega.9b03668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.9b03668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32039310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanch M, Dolores Alvarez M, Sanchez-Ballesta MT, Escribano MI, Merodio C. Water relations, short-chain oligosaccharides and rheological properties in lettuces subjected to limited water supply and low temperature stress. Sci Hortic. 2017;225:726&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.scienta.2017.08.00.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2017.08.00</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, &#xd6;zbek &#xd6;, Polat E. Response of greenhouse grown cucumber to partial root zone drying and conventional deficit irrigation. KSU J Agric Nat. 2022;25(2):337&#x2013;47. 10.18016/ksutarimdoga.vi.883294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18016/ksutarimdoga.vi.883294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, &#xd6;zbek &#xd6;. Salt accumulation in the root zone of eggplant irrigated using partial root drying technique. Int J Agric Biol. 2016;18:435&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17957/IJAB/15.0109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forchetti G, Masciarelli O, Izaguirre MJ, Alemano S, Alvarez D, Abdala G. Endophytic bacteria improve seedling growth of sunflower under water stress, produce Salicylic acid, and inhibit growth of pathogenic fungi. Curr Microbiol. 2010;61:485&#x2013;93. 10.1007/s00284-010-9642-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00284-010-9642-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vacheron J, Desbrosses G, Bouffaud M, Touraine B, Moenne-Loccoz Y, Muller D, Legendre L, Wisniewski-Dy&#xe9; F, Prigent-Combaret C. Plant growth promoting rhizobacteria and root system functioning. Front Plant Sci. 2013;4:1&#x2013;19. 10.3389/fpls.2013.00356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2013.00356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3551192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23346092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco El, Rada F, Paolini J, Guerrero JA. Effects of induced water deficit and biofertilization on growth dynamics and bulb yield of onion (<i>Allium Cepa</i> L.) in a Neotropical semi-arid environment. Can J Soil Sci. 2021;101:3. 10.1139/cjss-2021-0011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cjss-2021-0011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shultana R, Zuan ATK, Naher UA, Islam AKMM, Rana MM, Rashid MH, Irin IJ, Islam SS, Rim AA, Hasan AK. The PGPR mechanisms of salt stress adaptation and plant growth promotion. Agronomy. 2022;12:2266. 10.3390/agronomy12102266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy12102266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlidag H, Esitken A, Yildirim E, Donmez MF, Turan M. Effects of plant growth promoting bacteria on yield, growth, leaf water content, membrane permeability, and ionic composition of strawberry under saline conditions. J Plant Nutr. 2011;34(1):34&#x2013;45. 10.1080/01904167.2011.531357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01904167.2011.531357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qurashi AW, Sabri AN. Osmoadaptation and plant growth promotion by salt tolerant bacteria under salt stress. Afr J Microbiol Res. 2011;5(21):3546&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim E, Turan M, Ekinci M, Dursun A, Cakmakci R. Plant growth promoting rhizobacteria ameliorate deleterious effect of salt stress on lettuce. Sci Res Essays. 2011;6(20):4389&#x2013;96. 10.5897/SRE11.219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/SRE11.219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulyani O, Trinurani E, Sudirja R, Joy B. The effect of bio-fertilizer on soil chemical properties of sugarcane in purwadadi Subang. KnE Life Sci. 2017;164&#x2013;71. 10.18502/kls.v2i6.1035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suhag M. Potential of biofertilizers to replace chemical fertilizers. Int Adv Res J Sci Eng Technol. 2016;3(5):163&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JH, Kim SD. Induction of drought stress resistance by multi-functional PGPR <i>Bacillus licheniformis</i> K11 in pepper. Plant Pathol J. 2013;29(2):201&#x2013;8. 10.5423/PPJ.SI.02.2013.0021.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5423/PPJ.SI.02.2013.0021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4174774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25288947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasmin H, Bano A, Samiullah. Screening of PGPR isolates from semi-arid region and their implication to alleviate drought stress. Pak J Bot. 2013;45(SI):51&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma RK, Saikia R. Alleviation of drought stress in mung bean by strain <i>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</i> GGRJ21. Plant Soil. 2014;377:111&#x2013;26. 10.1007/s11104-013-1981-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11104-013-1981-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin U, Ekinci M, Yildirim E, Kiziloglu MF, Turan M, Kotan R, Ors S. Ameliorative effects of plant growth promoting bacteria on water-yield relationships, growth and nutrient uptake of lettuce plants under different irrigation levels. Hort Sci. 2015;50(9):1379&#x2013;86. 10.21273/HORTSCI.50.9.1379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21273/HORTSCI.50.9.1379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;ne&#x15f; A, Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m E, Turan M, Kotan R, Ekinci M, Arg&#x131;n S. Amino acid and hormone content of plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria grown in drought stress created by PEG6000. Eur J Sci Technol. 2021;21:95&#x2013;112. 10.31590/ejosat.831176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31590/ejosat.831176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildirim E, Ekinci M, &#x15e;ahin &#xdc;, Ors S, Turan M, Demir &#x130;, Dursun A, Kotan R. Improved water productivity in summer squash under water deficit with PGPR and synthetic Methyl amine applications. Rhizospehere. 2021;203:2075&#x2013;85. 10.1016/j.rhisph.2021.100446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rhisph.2021.100446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backer R, Rokem JS, Ilangumaran G, Lamont J, Praslickova D, Ricci E, Subramanian S, Smith DL. Plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria: context, mechanisms of action, and roadmap to commercialization of biostimulants for sustainable agriculture. Front Plant Sci. 2018;9:1473. 10.3389/fpls.2018.01473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2018.01473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30405652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima BC, Moro AL, Santos ACP, Bonifacio A, Araujo ASF, Araujo FF. <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> ameliorates water stress tolerance in maize and common bean. J Plant Interact. 2019;14(1):432&#x2013;9. 10.1080/17429145.2019.1645896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17429145.2019.1645896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacar B. 2012. Toprak analizleri. 3.bask&#x131;, Nobel Yay&#x131;nevi (Soil analysis. 3rd edition, Nobel Publishing) Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye. 2012;484:466 (sayfa say&#x131;s&#x131;), ISBN: 978-605-133-386-1 (in Turkish).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, &#xd6;zbek &#xd6;. Performance evaluation of PR2 in determination of soil water content. YYU J Agr Sci. 2021;31(3):543&#x2013;50. 10.29133/yyutbd.878567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29133/yyutbd.878567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;amo&#x11f;lu G, Gen&#xe7; L. Use of thermal imaging and spectral data to detect water stress in green bean. COMU J Agric Fac. 2013;1(1):15&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;lg&#xfc;l &#x130;. 2019. The effects of different irrigation water levels on mung beans yield and the possibility of using water stress index in irrigation scheduling. Erciyes University, Institute of Science, Department of Biosystems Engineering, MSc Thesis, 68 pages, Kayseri T&#xfc;rkiye. https://tez.yok.gov.tr/UlusalTezMerkezi/ (Accessed 8 July 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirda C, Cetin M, Dasgan Y, Topcu S, Kaman H, Ekici B, Derici MR, Ozguven AI. Yield response of greenhouse grown tomato to partial root drying and conventional deficit irrigation. Agric Water Manage. 2004;69(3):191&#x2013;201. 10.1016/j.agwat.2004.04.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agwat.2004.04.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, Kirda C, Cetin M, Topcu S. Salt accumulation in the root zones of tomato and cotton irrigated with partial root-drying technique. Irrig Drain. 2006;(55):533&#x2013;44. 10.1002/ird.276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topcu S, Kirda C, Dasgan Y, Kaman H, Cetin M, Yazici A, Bacon MA. Yield response and N-fertiliser recovery of tomato grown under deficit irrigation. Europ J Agron. 2007;26(1):64&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.eja.2006.08.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eja.2006.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart JI, Cuenca RH, Pruitt WO, Hagan RM, Tosso J. Determination and utilization of water production functions for principal California crops. W-67 CA contributing project report. Davis, USA: University of California; 1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doorenbos J, Kassam AH. Yield response to water. FAO irrigation and drainage. Paper No: 33, 1979;193 pages, Rome, Italy.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir H, Kaman H, S&#xf6;nmez I, Mohamoud SS, Polat E, &#xdc;&#xe7;ok Z. Yield, quality and plant nutrient contents of lettuce under different deficit irrigation conditions. Acta Sci Pol Hortorum Cultus. 2022;21(1):115&#x2013;29. 10.24326/asphc.2022.1.10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24326/asphc.2022.1.10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozturk B, Ozer H. Effects of grafting and green manure treatments on postharvest quality of tomatoes. J Soil Sci Plant Nutr. 2019;19(4):780&#x2013;92. 10.1007/s42729-019-00077-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42729-019-00077-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U&#x11f;ur A, Saka AK, &#xd6;zer H, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk B. Impacts of Methyl jasmonate treatments on quality characteristics of tomato fruit harvested at different maturity level during shelf life. Bah&#xe7;e. 2022;51(Special issue 1):154&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;lmaz B, &#xc7;ilingir T&#xfc;t&#xfc;nc&#xfc; A, Saka AK, Demirkaya S, Y&#x131;lmaz H, Ozer H. Effects of different nutrient inputs in organic parsley cultivation. Biol Agric Hortic. 2024;40(3):161&#x2013;72. 10.1080/01448765.2024.2351371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01448765.2024.2351371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peksen A, Ates U, Ic S, Ozturk B. Impact of biodegradable mulches on qualitative characteristics and bioactive compounds of Capia pepper (<i>Capsicum annum</i> L.) under cold storage. J J Soil Sci Plant Nutr. 2023;23:4412&#x2013;25. 10.1007/s42729-023-01359-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42729-023-01359-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozturk A, Yildiz K, Ozturk B, Karakaya O, Gun S, Uzun S, Gundogdu M. Maintaining postharvest quality of medlar (<i>Mespilus germanica</i>) fruit using modified atmosphere packaging and Methyl jasmonate. LWT. 2019;111:117&#x2013;24. 10.1016/j.lwt.2019.05.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lwt.2019.05.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, Demir H, S&#xf6;nmez &#x130;, Polat E, Mohamoud SS, &#xdc;&#xe7;ok Z. Salinity accumulation in the root area of the Curly lettuce grown in deficit irrigation conditions. J Tekirdag Agricultural Fac. 2021;18(3):508&#x2013;20. 10.33462/jotaf.846652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33462/jotaf.846652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaman H, G&#xfc;bb&#xfc;k H, Tezcan A, Can M, &#xd6;zbek &#xd6;. Water-yield relationship of greenhouse-grown strawberry under limited irrigation. Notulae Botanicae Horti Agrobotanici Cluj-Napoca. 2023a;51(2):13235. 10.15835/nbha51213235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15835/nbha51213235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezen SM, Yazar A, Akyildiz A, Dasgan HY, Gencel B. Yield and quality response of drip irrigated green beans under full and deficit irrigation. Sci Hortic. 2008;117(2):95&#x2013;102. 10.1016/j.scienta.2008.03.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2008.03.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El-Waheda MH, Baker GA, Ali MM, Abd El-Fattah FA. Effect of drip deficit irrigation and soil mulching on growth of common bean plant, water use efficiency and soil salinity. Sci Hortic. 2017;225:235&#x2013;42. 10.1016/j.scienta.2017.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2017.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cant&#xfc;rk A, Cemek B, Ta&#x15f;an M, Ta&#x15f;an S. Effect of deficit irrigation on yield, water productivity, energy indices and economic productivity in eggplant cultivation. Gesunde Pflanzen. 2023;75:1579&#x2013;89. 10.1007/s10343-022-00814-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10343-022-00814-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tunc T, Sahin U, Evren S, Dasci E, Guney E, Aslantas R. The deficit irrigation productivity and economy in strawberry in the different drip irrigation practices in a high plain with semi-arid climate. Sci Hortic. 2019;245:47&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.scienta.2018.10.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2018.10.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sar&#x131;da&#x15f; MA, Kapur B, &#xc7;eliktopuz E, &#x15e;ahiner Y, Payda&#x15f; Karg&#x131; S. Land productivity, irrigation water use efficiency and fruit quality under various plastic mulch colors and irrigation regimes of strawberry in the Eastern mediterranean region of Turkey. Agric Water Manage. 2021;245:106568. 10.1016/j.agwat.2020.106568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agwat.2020.106568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavuz D, Seymen M, Yavuz N, &#xc7;oklar H, Ercan M. Effects of water stress applied at various phenological stages on yield, quality, and water use efficiency of melon. Agric Water Manage. 2021;246:106673. 10.1016/j.agwat.2020.106673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agwat.2020.106673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;ksal ES, &#xdc;st&#xfc;n H, &#x130;lbeyi A. Threshold values of leaf water potential and crop water stress index as an indicator of irrigation time for Dwarf green beans. J Agricultural Fac Uludag Univ. 2010;24(1):25&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos K, Schwember AR, Machado D, Ozores-Hampton M, Gil PM. Physiological and yield responses of green-shelled beans (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L.) grown under restricted irrigation. Agronomy. 2021;11(3):562. 10.3390/agronomy11030562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy11030562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Kloepper JW, Ryu CM. Rhizosphere bacteria help plants tolerate abiotic stress. Trends Plant Sci. 2008;14:1&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.tplants.2008.10.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tplants.2008.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima BC, Bonifacio A, Alcantara Neto F, Araujo FF, Araujo ASF. <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> rhizobacteria ameliorate heat stress in the common bean. Rhizosphere. 2022;21:100472. 10.1016/j.rhisph.2022.100472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rhisph.2022.100472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastor-Bueis R, Jim&#xb4;enez-G&#xb4;omez A, Barquero M, Mateos PF, Gonz&#xb4;alez-Andr&#xb4;es F. Yield response of common bean to co-inoculation with rhizobium and Pseudomonas endophytes and microscopic evidence of different colonised spaces inside the nodule. Eur J Agron. 2021;122:126187. 10.1016/j.eja.2020.126187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eja.2020.126187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir H, Kaman H, S&#xf6;nmez &#x130;, U&#xe7;an U, Akg&#xfc;n &#x130;H. Yield and yield parameters response of cabbage to partial root drying and conventional deficit irrigation. Agronomy. 2024;14(11):2721. 10.3390/agronomy14112721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14112721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simsek M, Comlekcioglu N, Ozturk I. The effects of the regulated deficit irrigation on yield and some yield components of common bean (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L.) under semi-arid conditions. Afr J Biotechnol. 2011;10(20):4057&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezen SM, Celikel G, Yazar A, Tekin S, Kapur B. Effect of irrigation management on yield and quality of tomatoes grown in different soilless media in a glasshouse. Sci Res Essays. 2010;5(1):41&#x2013;8. 10.5897/SRE.9000392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5897/SRE.9000392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussen A, Worku W, Zewdie M. Effects of deficit irrigation and phosphorus levels on growth, yield, yield components and water use efficiency of mung bean (Vigna radiata (l.) Wilczek) at alage, central rift Valley of Ethiopia. Agric Res Tech. 2019;21(3):556167. 10.19080/ARTOAJ.2019.21.556167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19080/ARTOAJ.2019.21.556167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakrim R, Wahbi S, Tahi H, Aganchich B, Serraj R. Comparative effects of partial root drying (PRD) and regulated deficit irrigation (RDI) on water relations and water use efficiency in common bean (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L). Agric Ecosyst Environ. 2005;106(2&#x2013;3):275&#x2013;87. 10.1016/j.agee.2004.10.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agee.2004.10.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Admasu R, Tamiru Z. Effect of deficit irrigation on common bean (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L.) under conventional, fixed and alternate furrow irrigation systems at West wellega, Ethiopia. J Nat Sci Res. 2019;9(1):31&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikan C, Soussani FE, Ouhaddou R, Ech-Chatir L, Errouh F, Boutasknit A, Assouguem A, Ali EA, Ullah R, Ait Barka E, Lahlali R, Meddich A. Use of biofertilizers as an effective management strategy to improve the photosynthetic apparatus, yield, and tolerance to drought stress of drip-irrigated wheat in semi-arid environments. Agronomy. 2024;14(6):1316. 10.3390/agronomy14061316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14061316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Li H, Yuan Z, Feng J, Chen S, Sun G, Wei Z, Hu T. Effects of microbial fertilizer and irrigation amount on growth, physiology and water use efficiency of tomato in greenhouse. Sci Hortic. 2024;323:112553. 10.1016/j.scienta.2023.112553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2023.112553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. Yield response to water. Irrigation and Drainage Paper. 1986;33. Rome.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madakba&#x15f; SY, Kar H, K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;komuzlu B. Adaptation of dwarfing fresh bean varieties on &#xc7;ar&#x15f;amba plain. J Agricultural Fac GOU. 2004;21(2):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;im&#x15f;ek &#xdc;. Influence of water stress factor on yield and yield components of Vicia faba varieties in semi-arid climate conditions. Harran University, Institute of Science, Department of Agricultural Structures and Irrigation. MSc Thesis, 55 pages, &#x15e;anl&#x131; Urfa, T&#xfc;rkiye. https://tez.yok.gov.tr/UlusalTezMerkezi/ (Accessed 8 July 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrero-Dom&#xed;nguez L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-P&#xe9;rez BL, Jerez-Mompie EI, Morales-Guevara D, Amico-Rodr&#xed;guez JD, Cruz-Su&#xe1;rez AS. Behavior of common bean plants (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L.) subjected to two irrigation systems. Revista Ciencias T&#xe9;cnicas Agropecuarias. 2023;32(4):e06.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m M, Bahar E, Demirel K. The effects of different irrigation levels on the yield and physical properties of lettuce cultivars (<i>Lactuca sativa</i> var.<i>campania</i>). COMU J Agric Fac. 2015;3(1):29&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangash N, Khalid A, Mahmood T, Tariq Siddique M. Screening rhizobacteria containing ACC-Deaminase for growth promoting of wheat under water stress. Pak J Bot. 2013;45:91&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo MV, Bonifacio A, Rodrigues AC, de Araujo FF. Plant growth-promoting rhizobacteria: key mechanisms of action. In: Choudhary DK, Varma A, editors. Microbial-mediated induced systemic resistance in plants. Singapore: Springer; 2016. pp. 23&#x2013;37. 10.1007/978-981-10-0388-2_3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshad M, Shaharoona B, Mahmood T. Inoculation with Pseudomonas spp. Containing ACC deaminase partially eliminates the effects of drought stress on growth, yield, and ripening of pea (<i>Pisum sativum</i> L). Pedosphere. 2008;18(5):611&#x2013;20. 10.1016/S1002-0160(08)60055-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1002-0160(08)60055-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejaz S, Batool S, Anjum MA, Naz S, Qayyum MF, Naqqash T, Shah KH, Ali S. Effects of inoculation of root-associative azospirillum and Agrobacterium strains on growth, yield and quality of pea (<i>Pisum sativum</i> L.) grown under different nitrogen and phosphorus regimes. Sci Hortic. 2020;270:109401. 10.1016/j.scienta.2020.109401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2020.109401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;st&#xfc; G. 2019. Different watering levels effect of root bacteria applications increasing plant growth on pepper (<i>Capsicum annuum</i> L.) yield and quality. Harran University, Institute of Science, Department of Agricultural Structures and Irrigation, MSc Thesis, 59 pages, &#x15e;anl&#x131; Urfa, T&#xfc;rkiye. https://tez.yok.gov.tr/UlusalTezMerkezi. (Accessed 8 July 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grangah MF, Rashidi V, Mirshekari B, Behrouzyar EK, Farahvash F. Effects of nano-fertilizers on physiological and yield characteristics of Pinto bean cultivars under water deficit stress. J Plant Nutr. 2020;43(19):2898&#x2013;910. 10.1080/01904167.2020.1799000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01904167.2020.1799000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anzuma A, Hossain MM, Mohiuddin M, Nazran A, Khan HI, Islam SMN, Ghosh TK. Enhancing drought tolerance in common bean by plant growth promoting rhizobacterium <i>Bacillus amyloliquefaciens</i>. Acta Agriculturae Slov. 2024;120(3):1&#x2013;14. 10.14720/aas.2024.120.3.18249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14720/aas.2024.120.3.18249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiryaki D, Ayd&#x131;n &#x130;, At&#x131;c&#x131; &#xd6;. Psychrotolerant bacteria isolated from the leaf Apoplast of cold-adapted wild plants improve the cold resistance of bean (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L.) under low temperature. Cryobiology. 2019;86:111&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.cryobiol.2018.11.001.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cryobiol.2018.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30419217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samanc&#x131;o&#x11f;lu A. 2016. Effects of bacteria applications on water use efficiency, plant growth, yield and quality of cabbage grown under different irrigation levels. Ataturk University, Institute of Science, PhD Thesis, 225 pages, Erzurum, T&#xfc;rkiye. https://tez.yok.gov.tr/UlusalTezMerkezi. (Accessed 8 July 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petropoulos SA, Fernandes &#xc2;, Plexida S, Chrysargyris A, Tzortzakis N, Barreira JC, Barros L, Ferreira ICFR. Biostimulants application alleviates water stress effects on yield and chemical composition of greenhouse green bean (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L). Agronomy. 2020;10(2):181. 10.3390/agronomy10020181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy10020181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes &#xc2;, Figueiredo S, Finimundy TC, Pinela J, Tzortzakis N, Ivanov M, Sokovic M, Ferreira ICFR, Petropoulos SA, Barros L. Chemical composition and bioactive properties of purple French bean (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L.) as affected by water deficit irrigation and biostimulants application. Sustainability. 2021;13(12):6869. 10.3390/su13126869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13126869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-F&#xe9;l&#x131;x CS, L&#xf3;pez-Casta&#xf1;eda C, Kohash&#x131;-Sh&#x131;bata J, Mart&#xed;nez-Rueda CG, M&#x131;randa-Col&#xed;n S, Agu&#x131;larr&#x131;nc&#xf3;n VH. Variabilidad En caracter&#xed;sticas morfo-fisiol&#xf3;gicas Del Frijol Com&#xfa;n Bajo Sequ&#xed;a terminal. Agrociencia. 2021;55:471&#x2013;85. 10.47163/agrociencia.v55i6.2554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.47163/agrociencia.v55i6.2554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nematollahi D, Eisvand HR, Sanavi A, Akbari N, Ismaili A. The effects of various levels of water deficit stress on forage yield and physiological characteristics of four cultivars of clover (<i>Trifolium spp.</i>) under low input condition. Iran J Plant Physiol. 2017;7(3):2125&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santillan Huaman A, Tejada-Alvarado JJ, Garc&#xed;a L, V&#xe1;squez-Garc&#xed;a J, Fernandez E, Vilca-Valqui NC, Oliva-Cruz M. Morpho-physiological response of four native accessions of <i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> L. subjected to water stress under greenhouse conditions in Northeastern Peru. Agronomy. 2024;14:2044. 10.3390/agronomy14092044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/agronomy14092044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito P, Alonso-Vega P, Aguado C, Luj&#xb4;an R, Anzai Y, Hirsch AM, Trujillo ME. Monitoring the colonization and infection of legume nodules by micromonospora in co-inoculation experiments with rhizobia. Sci Rep. 2017;7:11051. 10.1038/s41598-017-11428-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-11428-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5591303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28887555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavoshi S, Nourmohamadi Gh, Madani H, Heidari Sharif Abad H, Alavi Fazel M. The effect of biofertilizers on physiological traits and biomass accumulation of red beans (<i>Phaseolus vulgaris</i> cv. Goli) under water stress. Iran J Plant Physiol. 2018;8(4):2555&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asraf M, Iram A. Drought stress induced changes in some organic substances in nodules and other plant parts of two potential legumes differing in salt tolerance. Flora. 2005;200:535&#x2013;46. 10.1016/j.flora.2005.06.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.flora.2005.06.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suheri S, Hussein NMH, Kurtar ES, Yavuz N, Dal Y. Determination of yield and quality of different snap bean varieties under deficit irrigation. J Tekirdag Agricultural Fac. 2020;17(2):252&#x2013;63. 10.33462/jotaf.654879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33462/jotaf.654879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>