<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41784879</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1614-7499</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental science and pollution research international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation of coal fire surface anomalies: a case study of Sulabulak, Xinjiang, China.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11356-026-37551-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coal fires are pervasive global issues that affect the environment continuously, particularly in coal-rich regions; these fires can cause significant environmental damage, safety hazards, and economic losses. While numerous studies have investigated coal fires using remote sensing techniques, research integrating multisource remote sensing data for comprehensive coal fire zone detection and monitoring remains relatively limited. Current methods often analyze different data sources independently, limiting our understanding of the complex relationships between various surface manifestations of coal fires. This study presents a novel comprehensive analysis method employing multisource remote sensing technology to identify and monitor coal fires. Using 29 Landsat-8 images from Sulabulak fire area, we derived fractional vegetation cover (FVC) and land surface temperature (LST) parameters to identify vegetation loss patterns and thermal anomalies. In addition, 135 dual-polarized Sentinel-1A images were analyzed using small baseline subset interferometric synthetic aperture radar (SBAS-InSAR) and persistent scatter interferometric synthetic aperture radar (PS-InSAR) techniques to obtain surface deformation data. The integration of these datasets, validated by field survey data, revealed a significant correlation between the identified coal fire zones and subsidence areas. Our results revealed an increase in sparse vegetation areas of 2.77 km<sup>2</sup>, an expansion of high-temperature anomalies of 0.75 km<sup>2</sup>, and a cumulative surface subsidence of -123.9&#xa0;mm in the study area. These findings indicate ongoing and intensified coal fire combustion as well as an expansion of coal fire zones. The effectiveness of this method in identifying coal fire areas highlights its potential for enhancing coal fire monitoring and management strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Zhicheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Underground Coal Fire, College of Ecology and Environment, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830017, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Oasis Ecology of Ministry of Education, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830017, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2191-7304</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Underground Coal Fire, College of Ecology and Environment, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830017, China. zengqiang@xju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Oasis Ecology of Ministry of Education, Xinjiang University, Urumqi, 830017, China. zengqiang@xju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023TSYCLJ0003</GrantID><Agency>Xinjiang Department of Science and Technology of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022B03025-4</GrantID><Agency>Xinjiang Department of Science and Technology of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021D14018</GrantID><Agency>Xinjiang Department of Science and Technology of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9441769</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0944-1344</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coal fire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fractional vegetation cover</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">InSAR technique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Land surface temperature</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: This is not applicable. Consent to participate: This is not applicable. Consent for publication: This is not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41784879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-026-37551-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11356-026-37551-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aditiya A, Ito T (2023) Present-day land subsidence over Semarang revealed by time series InSAR new small baseline subset technique. Int J Appl Earth Obs Geoinf 125:103579. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2023.103579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jag.2023.103579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswal SS, Raval S, Gorai AK (2019) Delineation and mapping of coal mine fire using remote sensing data&#x2014;a review. Int J Remote Sens 40(17):6499&#x2013;6529. https://doi.org/10.1080/01431161.2018.1547455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2018.1547455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll M, Gao CX, Campbell TCH, Smith CL, Dimitriadis C, Berger E, Maybery D, Ikin J, Abramson MJ, Sim MR, McFarlane A, Smith K, Guo Y (2022) Impacts of coal mine fire-related PM2.5 on the utilisation of ambulance and hospital services for mental health conditions. Atmos Pollut Res 13(5):101415. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apr.2022.101415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apr.2022.101415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Peng J, Song Z, Zheng Y, Zhang B (2022) Monitoring persistent coal fire using Landsat time series data from 1986 to 2020. IEEE Trans Geosci Remote Sens 60:5001616. https://doi.org/10.1109/TGRS.2022.3142350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TGRS.2022.3142350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Xue Y, Xue Y, Peng J, Guo J, Liang H (2024) Assessing the effects of climate and human activity on vegetation change in Northern China. Environ Res 247:118233. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envres.2024.118233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2024.118233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S-K, Ramirez RA, Lim H-H, Kwon T-H (2024) Multi-source remote sensing-based landslide investigation: the case of the August 7, 2020, Gokseong landslide in South Korea. Sci Rep 14(1):12048. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-59008-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-59008-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claverie M, Ju J, Masek JG, Dungan JL, Vermote EF, Roger J-C, Skakun SV, Justice C (2018) The harmonized Landsat and Sentinel-2 surface reflectance data set. Remote Sens Environ 219:145&#x2013;161. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2018.09.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2018.09.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford CJ, Roy DP, Arab S, Barnes C, Vermote E, Hulley G, Gerace A, Choate M, Engebretson C, Micijevic E, Schmidt G, Anderson C, Anderson M, Bouchard M, Cook B, Dittmeier R, Howard D, Jenkerson C, Kim M, Kleyians T, Maiersperger T, Mueller C, Neigh C, Owen L, Page B, Pahlevan N, Rengarajan R, Roger J-C, Sayler K, Scaramuzza P, Skakun S, Yan L, Zhang HK, Zhu Z, Zahn S (2023) The 50-year Landsat collection 2 archive. Sci Remote Sens 8:100103. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.srs.2023.100103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.srs.2023.100103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Ge S, Qi H, Zhou F, Shi B (2021) Underground coal fire emission of spontaneous combustion, Sandaoba coalfield in Xinjiang, China: investigation and analysis. Sci Total Environ 777:146080. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.146080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2021.146080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X, Sun D, Li F, Tong J (2022) A study on the propagation trend of underground coal fires based on night-time thermal infrared remote sensing technology. Sustainability 14(22):14741. https://doi.org/10.3390/su142214741</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su142214741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwyer JL, Roy DP, Sauer B, Jenkerson CB, Zhang HK, Lymburner L (2018) Analysis ready data: enabling analysis of the Landsat archive. Sustainability 10(9):1363. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs10091363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs10091363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galve JM, S&#xe1;nchez JM, Garc&#xed;a-Santos V, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Piqueras J, Calera A, Villodre J (2022) Assessment of land surface temperature estimates from Landsat 8-TIRS in a high-contrast semiarid agroecosystem. Algorithms intercomparison. Remote Sens 14(8):8. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs14081843</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14081843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X, Yang X, Luo Z, Guan T (2020) Application of unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) thermal infrared remote sensing to identify coal fires in the Huojitu coal mine in Shenmu city, China. Sci Rep 10(1):13895. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-70964-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-70964-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper A, Bekaert D, Spaans K, Ar&#x131;kan M (2012) Recent advances in SAR interferometry time series analysis for measuring crustal deformation. Tectonophysics 514&#x2013;517:1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tecto.2011.10.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tecto.2011.10.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Lin H, Ma J, Kong B, Wang Y (2011a) Potential of small-baseline SAR interferometry for monitoring land subsidence related to underground coal fires: Wuda (Northern China) case study. Remote Sens Environ 115(2):257&#x2013;268. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2010.08.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2010.08.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang W, Wu J, Gu L, Yang B, Chen Q, Liu X (2011) Monitoring method of underground coal fire based on night thermal infrared remote sensing technology. SPECTROSCOPY AND SPECTRAL ANALYSIS 31(2):357&#x2013;361. https://doi.org/10.3964/j.issn.1000-0593(2011)02-0357-05</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3964/j.issn.1000-0593(2011)02-0357-05</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly J, Kljun N, Olsson P-O, Mihai L, Liljeblad B, Weslien P, Klemedtsson L, Eklundh L (2019) Challenges and best practices for deriving temperature data from an uncalibrated UAV thermal infrared camera. Remote Sens 11(5):567. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs11050567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs11050567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenzer C, Zhang J, Tetzlaff A, van Dijk P, Voigt S, Mehl H, Wagner W (2007) Uncontrolled coal fires and their environmental impacts: investigating two arid mining regions in north-central China. APPLIED GEOGRAPHY 27(1):42&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apgeog.2006.09.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apgeog.2006.09.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Yang W, Liu X, Sun G, Liu J (2018) Using high-resolution UAV-borne thermal infrared imagery to detect coal fires in Majiliang mine, Datong coalfield, Northern China. Remote Sens Lett 9(1):71&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1080/2150704X.2017.1392632</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/2150704X.2017.1392632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Yang Y, Guo S, Tian F, Wang S (2023) Combustion mechanism and control approaches of underground coal fires: a review. Int J Coal Sci Technol 10(1):24. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40789-023-00581-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-023-00581-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Zeng Q (2023) Application of fusion remote sensing technology for coal fire identification in the Sikeshu sealed fire area. Mining Safety &amp; Environmental Protection 50(6):104&#x2013;110. https://doi.org/10.19835/j.issn.1008-4495.2023.06.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19835/j.issn.1008-4495.2023.06.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Wang Y, Li Y, Dang L, Liu X, Zhao H, Yan S (2019) Underground coal fires identification and monitoring using time-series InSAR with persistent and distributed scatterers: a case study of Miquan Coal Fire Zone in Xinjiang, China. IEEE Access 7:164492&#x2013;164506. https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2952363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2952363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martha TR, Guha A, Kumar KV, Kamaraju MVV, Raju EVR (2010) Recent coal-fire and land-use status of Jharia Coalfield, India from satellite data. Int J Remote Sens 31(12):3243&#x2013;3262. https://doi.org/10.1080/01431160903159340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431160903159340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masek JG, Wulder MA, Markham B, McCorkel J, Crawford CJ, Storey J, Jenstrom DT (2020) Landsat 9: empowering open science and applications through continuity. Remote Sens Environ 248:111968. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2020.111968</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2020.111968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna P, Erskine PD, Lechner AM, Phinn S (2018) Measuring fire severity using UAV imagery in semi-arid Central Queensland, Australia (vol 38, pg 4244, 2017). Int J Remote Sens 39(12):4285&#x2013;4285. https://doi.org/10.1080/01431161.2018.1443780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431161.2018.1443780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meghraj KC, Leigh L, Pinto CT, Kaewmanee M (2023) Method of validating satellite surface reflectance product using empirical line method. Remote Sens 15(9):2240. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs15092240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15092240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minx JC, Lamb WF, Andrew RM, Canadell JG, Crippa M, Doebbeling N, Forster PM, Guizzardi D, Olivier J, Peters GP, Pongratz J, Reisinger A, Rigby M, Saunois M, Smith SJ, Solazzo E, Tian H (2021) A comprehensive and synthetic dataset for global, regional, and national greenhouse gas emissions by sector 1970&#x2013;2018 with an extension to 2019. Earth Syst Sci Data 13(11):5213&#x2013;5252. https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-13-5213-2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/essd-13-5213-2021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra RK, Bahuguna PP, Singh VK (2011) Detection of coal mine fire in Jharia Coal Field using Landsat-7 ETM+ data. Int J Coal Geol 86(1):73&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coal.2010.12.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2010.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramzan U, Fan H, Aeman H, Ali M, Al-qaness MAA (2022) Combined analysis of PS-InSAR and hypsometry integral (HI) for comparing seismic vulnerability and assessment of various regions of Pakistan. Sci Rep 12(1):22423. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-26159-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-26159-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riyas MJ, Syed TH, Kumar H, Kuenzer C (2021) Detecting and analyzing the evolution of subsidence due to coal fires in Jharia Coalfield, India using Sentinel-1 SAR data. Remote Sens 13(8):1521. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs13081521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs13081521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy P, Guha A, Kumar KV (2015) An approach of surface coal fire detection from ASTER and Landsat-8 thermal data: Jharia coal field, India. Int J Appl Earth Obs Geoinf 39:120&#x2013;127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2015.03.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jag.2015.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy D, Singh G, Seo Y-C (2019) Coal mine fire effects on carcinogenicity and non-carcinogenicity human health risks. Environ Pollut 254:113091. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2019.113091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2019.113091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder W, Oliva P, Giglio L, Quayle B, Lorenz E, Morelli F (2016) Active fire detection using Landsat-8/OLI data. Remote Sens Environ 185:210&#x2013;220. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2015.08.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2015.08.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvakumaran S, Plank S, Gei&#xdf; C, Rossi C, Middleton C (2018) Remote monitoring to predict bridge scour failure using interferometric synthetic aperture radar (InSAR) stacking techniques. Int J Appl Earth Obs Geoinf 73:463&#x2013;470. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2018.07.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jag.2018.07.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Z, Kuenzer C (2014) Coal fires in China over the last decade: a comprehensive review. Int J Coal Geol 133:72&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coal.2014.09.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coal.2014.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian H, Tao Y, Kou P, Alonso A, Luo X, Gong C, Fan Y, Lei C, Gou Y (2023) Monitoring and evaluation of gully erosion in China&#x2019;s largest loess tableland based on SBAS-InSAR. Nat Hazards 117(3):2435&#x2013;2454. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11069-023-05950-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-023-05950-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Cui C-Q, Zhao Y-X, Yang B, Yang Q-Z (2019) Carbon emissions accounting for China&#x2019;s coal mining sector: invisible sources of climate change. Nat Hazards 99(3):1345&#x2013;1364. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11069-018-3526-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-018-3526-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Zhou J, Liu S, Li M, Zhang X, Huang Z, Dong W, Ma J, Ai L (2022) A land surface temperature retrieval method for UAV broadband thermal imager data. IEEE Geosci Remote Sens Lett. https://doi.org/10.1109/LGRS.2021.3100586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/LGRS.2021.3100586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan S, Shi K, Li Y, Liu J, Zhao H (2020) Integration of satellite remote sensing data in underground coal fire detection: a case study of the Fukang region, Xinjiang, China. Front Earth Sci 14(1):1&#x2013;12. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11707-019-0757-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11707-019-0757-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Zeng Q (2021) Analysis of surface subsidence in Shuixigou sealed fire area by using D-InSAR technology. Mining Safety &amp; Environmental Protection 48(3):68&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.19835/j.issn.1008-4495.2021.03.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19835/j.issn.1008-4495.2021.03.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu B, She J, Liu G, Ma D, Zhang R, Zhou Z, Zhang B (2022) Coal fire identification and state assessment by integrating multitemporal thermal infrared and InSAR remote sensing data: a case study of Midong District, Urumqi, China. ISPRS J Photogramm Remote Sens 190:144&#x2013;164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2022.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2022.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Q, Dong J, Zhao L (2018) Investigation of the potential risk of coal fire to local environment: a case study of Daquanhu coal fire, Xinjiang region, China. Sci Total Environ 640:1478&#x2013;1488. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.05.135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.05.135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Thanh HV, Han F, Wang Y, Zhang X, Zhao R, Sasaki K, Zhang X (2023) Development of an in-situ gel from CO2-captured complex solution and inhibiting coal spontaneous combustion: a case study in thermal engineering. Case Studies in Thermal Engineering 50:103423. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csite.2023.103423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csite.2023.103423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Qian X, Guo S, Wang B, Xia J, Zheng X (2023b) A new method for continuous track monitoring in regions of differential land subsidence rate using the integration of PS-InSAR and SBAS-InSAR. Remote Sensing 15(13):13. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs15133298</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs15133298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Hu C, Wu Z, Zhang Z, Yang S, Yang W (2023c) Monitoring and analysis of ground subsidence in Shanghai based on PS-InSAR and SBAS-InSAR technologies. Scientific Reports 13(1):8031. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-35152-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-35152-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Zhang D, Wang J, Huang Z, Pan D (2013) Mapping land subsidence related to underground coal fires in the Wuda Coalfield (Northern China) using a small stack of ALOS PALSAR differential interferograms. Remote Sens 5(3):3. https://doi.org/10.3390/rs5031152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs5031152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>