<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41715990</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of haematology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Haematol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Circulating angiogenesis-related biomarkers in sickle cell retinopathy and maculopathy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bjh.70385</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sickle cell disease (SCD), encompassing genotypes such as HbSS and HbSC,&#xa0;leads to retinal complications such as sickle cell retinopathy (SCR) and maculopathy (SCM) through poorly understood mechanisms. This study explored associations of a panel of circulating angiogenesis-related factors with SCR and SCM. Adult HbSS (homozygous SCD; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;33) and HbSC (compound heterozygous SCD; n&#x2009;=&#x2009;33) patients underwent ophthalmic examination, including optical coherence tomography angiography, to assess SCR stage and presence of SCM. Plasma levels of circulating angiogenesis-related factors were analysed, with selected markers (angiopoietin-2, vascular endothelial growth factor [VEGF], granulocyte colony-stimulating factor, endoglin, endostatin, interleukin [IL]-6 and IL-10) assessed using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Proliferative SCR (PSCR) was present in 5 (15.2%) HbSS and 21 (63.6%) HbSC patients. Foveal avascular zone abnormalities and macular thinning were present in 50.8% and 48.4% of patients respectively. Most vascular factors, including VEGF, showed no association with SCR or SCM. However, angiopoietin-2 was higher in HbSS patients, independent of SCR stage or SCM, and correlated with IL-6, IL-10, VEGF, reticulocyte counts, and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH). In HbSC patients, endostatin levels were highest in those with PSCR (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.030). While most proteins were unrelated to retinal outcomes, angiopoietin-2 elevation may reflect HbSS-specific systemic hypoxia. Elevated endostatin in HbSC patients with PSCR suggests a potential role in PSCR development. These findings offer new leads for understanding SCD-related retinal disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). British Journal of Haematology published by British Society for Haematology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brandsen</LastName><ForeName>Rajani P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Haematology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klaassen</LastName><ForeName>Ingeborg</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ocular Angiogenesis Group, Department of Ophthalmology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Caluwe</LastName><ForeName>Ren&#xe9;e</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ocular Angiogenesis Group, Department of Ophthalmology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nur</LastName><ForeName>Erfan</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Haematology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sanquin Research and Landsteiner Laboratory, Department of Blood Cell Research, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biemond</LastName><ForeName>Bart J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Haematology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diederen</LastName><ForeName>Roselie M H</ForeName><Initials>RMH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlingemann</LastName><ForeName>Reinier O</ForeName><Initials>RO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ocular Angiogenesis Group, Department of Ophthalmology, Amsterdam UMC, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, University of Lausanne, Jules-Gonin Eye Hospital, Fondation Asile des Aveugles, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Stichting Pupil</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Landelijke Stichting voor Blinden en Slechtzienden</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Het oogfonds</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Stichting Beheer het Schild</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UZ 2022-24</GrantID><Agency>Stichting UitZicht</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Het sikkelcelfonds</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Maarten Kappelle Stichting</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Rotterdamse Stichting Blindenbelangen</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Haematol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372544</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-1048</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angiogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sickle cell disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sickle cell maculopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sickle cell retinopathy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41715990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjh.70385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Conran N, Belcher JD. Inflammation in sickle cell disease. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2018;68(2&#x2013;3):263&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandsen RP, Diederen RMH, Bakhlakh S, Nur E, Schlingemann RO, Biemond BJ. Natural history and rate of progression of retinopathy in adult patients with sickle cell disease: an 11&#x2010;year follow&#x2010;up study. Blood Adv. 2023;7(13):3080&#x2013;3086.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minniti CP, Suman PD, Dahlan K, Crouch A, Goodman M, Mian UK. Healthcare utilization patterns in sickle cell patients and their association with sickle cell retinopathy. Eur J Haematol. 2025;114(4):615&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandsen RP, Biemond BJ, Nasim GZ, Nur E, Schlingemann RO, Diederen RMH. Macular neurodegenerative and vascular changes on OCTA in sickle cell disease are not related to its ocular and systemic complications. Retina. 2024;44(12):2185&#x2013;2195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin GC, D&#xe9;nier C, Zambrowski O, Gr&#xe9;vent D, Bru&#xe8;re L, Brousse V, et&#xa0;al. Visual function in asymptomatic patients with homozygous sickle cell disease and temporal macular atrophy. JAMA Ophthalmol. 2017;135(10):1100&#x2013;1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla Elsayed MEA, Mura M, Al Dhibi H, Schellini S, Malik R, Kozak I, et&#xa0;al. Sickle cell retinopathy. A focused review. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2019;257(7):1353&#x2013;1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrawes NG, Ismail EA, Roshdy MM, Ebeid FSE, Eissa DS, Ibrahim AM. Angiopoietin&#x2010;2 as a marker of retinopathy in children and adolescents with sickle cell disease: relation to subclinical atherosclerosis. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2019;41(5):361&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jee K, Rodrigues M, Kashiwabuchi F, Applewhite BP, Han I, Lutty G, et&#xa0;al. Expression of the angiogenic mediator, angiopoietin&#x2010;like 4, in the eyes of patients with proliferative sickle retinopathy. PLoS One. 2017;12(8):e0183320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J, Mathews MK, McLeod DS, Merges C, Hjelmeland LM, Lutty GA. Angiogenic factors in human proliferative sickle cell retinopathy. Br J Ophthalmol. 1999;83(7):838&#x2013;846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutty GA, Merges C, Crone S, McLeod DS. Immunohistochemical insights into sickle cell retinopathy. Curr Eye Res. 1994;13(2):125&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Mocanu C, McLeod DS, Bhutto IA, Merges C, Eid M, et&#xa0;al. Expression of pigment epithelium&#x2010;derived factor (PEDF) and vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) in sickle cell retina and choroid. Exp Eye Res. 2003;77(4):433&#x2013;445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan JS, Lip PL, Blann AD, Bareford D, Lip GY. The angiopoietin/Tie&#x2010;2 system in proliferative sickle retinopathy: relation to vascular endothelial growth factor, its soluble receptor Flt&#x2010;1 and von Willebrand factor, and to the effects of laser treatment. Br J Ophthalmol. 2005;89(7):815&#x2013;819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz PR, Lira RP, Pereira Filho SA, Souza BB, Mitsuushi FN, Menaa F, et&#xa0;al. Increased circulating PEDF and low sICAM&#x2010;1 are associated with sickle cell retinopathy. Blood Cells Mol Dis. 2015;54(1):33&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg MF. Classification and pathogenesis of proliferative sickle retinopathy. Am J Ophthalmol. 1971;71(3):649&#x2013;665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart MJ, Setty BNY. Sickle cell acute chest syndrome: pathogenesis and rationale for treatment. Blood. 1999;94(5):1555&#x2013;1560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koshy M, Entsuah R, Koranda A, Kraus AP, Johnson R, Bellvue R, et&#xa0;al. Leg ulcers in patients with sickle cell disease. Blood. 1989;74(4):1403&#x2013;1408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmas E, K&#xe4;lsch T, Suvajac N, Leweling H, Neumaier M, Dempfle C&#x2010;E, et&#xa0;al. Activation of coagulation during alimentary lipemia under real&#x2010;life conditions. Int J Cardiol. 2007;114(2):172&#x2013;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunsilius E, Petzer A, Stockhammer G, Nussbaumer W, Schumacher P, Clausen J, et&#xa0;al. Thrombocytes are the major source for soluble vascular endothelial growth factor in peripheral blood. Oncology. 2000;58(2):169&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duits AJ, Rodriguez T, Schnog JJ. Serum levels of angiogenic factors indicate a pro&#x2010;angiogenic state in adults with sickle cell disease. Br J Haematol. 2006;134(1):116&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walia A, Yang JF, Huang YH, Rosenblatt MI, Chang JH, Azar DT. Endostatin's emerging roles in angiogenesis, lymphangiogenesis, disease, and clinical applications. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2015;1850(12):2422&#x2013;2438.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes FC, Traina F, Almeida CB, Leonardo FC, Franco&#x2010;Penteado CF, Garrido VT, et&#xa0;al. Key endothelial cell angiogenic mechanisms are stimulated by the circulating milieu in sickle cell disease and attenuated by hydroxyurea. Haematologica. 2015;100(6):730&#x2013;739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witmer AN, Vrensen GF, Van Noorden CJ, Schlingemann RO. Vascular endothelial growth factors and angiogenesis in eye disease. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2003;22(1):1&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlingemann RO, Van Noorden CJ, Diekman MJ, Tiller A, Meijers JC, Koolwijk P, et&#xa0;al. VEGF levels in plasma in relation to platelet activation, glycemic control, and microvascular complications in type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2013;36(6):1629&#x2013;1634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niers TM, Richel DJ, Meijers JC, Schlingemann RO. Vascular endothelial growth factor in the circulation in cancer patients may not be a relevant biomarker. PLoS One. 2011;6(5):e19873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wun T, Paglieroni T, Rangaswami A, Franklin PH, Welborn J, Cheung A, et&#xa0;al. Platelet activation in patients with sickle cell disease. Br J Haematol. 1998;100(4):741&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villagra J, Shiva S, Hunter LA, Machado RF, Gladwin MT, Kato GJ. Platelet activation in patients with sickle disease, hemolysis&#x2010;associated pulmonary hypertension, and nitric oxide scavenging by cell&#x2010;free hemoglobin. Blood. 2007;110(6):2166&#x2013;2172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han IC, Zhang AY, Liu TYA, Linz MO, Scott AW. Utility of ultra&#x2010;widefield retinal IMAGING for the staging and management of sickle cell retinopathy. Retina. 2019;39(5):836&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>