<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41257138</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Traffic Light Planning Algorithm for Breast Augmentation Mastopexy: A Case Series Analysis on Optimizing Early Ptosis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e94758</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e94758</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e94758</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.94758</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Breast augmentation is one of the most commonly performed aesthetic procedures, yet cases involving breast ptosis often require a more individualized approach. Determining the optimal strategy for combining augmentation with lift procedures can be challenging, particularly for surgeons early in their aesthetic practice. This study introduces the Traffic Light Planning Algorithm as a structured and objective framework to assess breast anatomy, guide implant positioning, and determine the need for adjunctive lift procedures. The algorithm categorizes patients into three groups (green, amber, and red) to help select the most appropriate management plan. This paper focuses on the amber zone, representing cases with early ptosis, which often present the greatest challenge in achieving optimal correction. Objectives The primary aim of this study was to evaluate the safety and patient satisfaction outcomes associated with the Traffic Light Planning Algorithm over five years (2018-2023). The secondary objective was to conduct a focused retrospective case series analysis of the "amber zone" over&#xa0;12 months (December 2022-December 2023). This subset analysis aimed to assess whether Mentor MemoryGel Xtra implants (Mentor Worldwide LLC, Irvine, CA, USA) could correct early ptosis without adjunctive mastopexy and to provide supporting evidence for the validity of the algorithm. A representative case report is also included to illustrate the practical application of this approach. Methods A comprehensive description of the algorithm is provided. Over the five-year study period, patient satisfaction, complication rates, and revision rates were analyzed. The 12-month subset analysis further explored patient satisfaction and various patient and surgical factors through cross-tabulation. This retrospective study design was appropriate for assessing real-world outcomes related to patient satisfaction and complications associated with this new structured planning algorithm. The Likert scale was used as an effective tool for evaluating patient satisfaction. Results During the study period, 9,000 breast consultations and 3,000 implant surgeries were performed by the senior author (MM). Overall, 93% of patients reported high satisfaction with their outcomes, with low revision rates of 2% for primary augmentations and 6% for augmentation mastopexies. This method proved particularly effective for cases of early ptosis, providing a structured and reproducible decision-making framework. The subset case series of 59 patients over a 12-month period showed high satisfaction levels: 54 (91.5%) were "very happy," 3 (5.1%) were "happy," 1 (1.7%) was "satisfied," and 1 (1.7%) was "not happy." Complications were reported in four cases (6.8%), including bilateral bottoming out, two cases of implant loss due to infection, and one case of unilateral capsular contracture. The remaining 55 patients (93.2%) experienced no postoperative complications. Conclusions The algorithm provides a reliable and objective framework for planning breast augmentation, particularly valuable for surgeons new to aesthetic practice. By promoting personalized, tissue-based surgical planning, this approach helps minimize complications and enhance patient satisfaction. The case series further demonstrates that applying the algorithm, together with the use of Mentor MemoryGel Xtra implants, can offer an effective strategy for avoiding mastopexy in appropriately selected amber zone patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Nijran et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nijran</LastName><ForeName>Amit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plastic Surgery, Queen Elizabeth Hospital Birmingham, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Reconstructive Surgery/Regenerative Medicine Research Centre, Swansea University, Swansea, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maklad</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Plastic Surgery, Enhance Medical Group, Birmingham, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aesthetic surgeries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">augmentation mastopexy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast plastic surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">planning algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plastic and reconstructive surgery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: Stephen Ali declare(s) employment from Welsh Clinical Academic Training Fellowship. Stephen Ali is funded by the Welsh Clinical Academic Training Fellowship. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41257138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12620097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.94758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Trends in surgical and nonsurgical aesthetic procedures: a 14-year analysis of the International Society of Aesthetic Plastic Surgery-ISAPS. Triana L, Palacios Huatuco RM, Campilgio G, Liscano E. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2024;48:4217&#x2013;4227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39103642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nine-year core study data for Sientra's FDA-approved round and shaped implants with high-strength cohesive silicone gel. Stevens WG, Calobrace MB, Harrington J, Alizadeh K, Zeidler KR, d'Incelli RC. Aesthet Surg J. 2016;36:404&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26961987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast ptosis. Definition and treatment. Regnault P. https://www.plasticsurgery.theclinics.com/article/S0094-1298(20)30220-0/abstract. Clin Plast Surg. 1976;3:193&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1261176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achieving a zero percent reoperation rate at 3 years in a 50-consecutive-case augmentation mammaplasty premarket approval study. Tebbetts JB. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2006;118:1453&#x2013;1457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17051118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The process of breast augmentation: four sequential steps for optimizing outcomes for patients. Adams WP Jr. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2008;122:1892&#x2013;1900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19050543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Five critical decisions in breast augmentation using five measurements in 5 minutes: the high five decision support process. Tebbetts JB, Adams WP. https://journals.lww.com/plasreconsurg/abstract/2006/12001/five_critical_decisions_in_breast_augmentation.9.aspx Plast Reconstructivive Surgery. 2006;118:35&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17099482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breast implant selection based on patient tissue characteristics and dynamics: the TEPID approach. Tebbetts JB. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2002;190:1396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11964998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastopexy augmentation with form stable breast implants. Hed&#xe9;n P. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0094129808000874. Clin Plast Surg. 2009;36:91&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19055964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical results of mentor MemoryGel Xtra breast implants from the GLOW clinical trial. Alderman A, Caplin D, Hammond DC, Keane A, Turetzky J, Kane WJ. https://academic.oup.com/asj/article/43/12/NP1021/7248863 Aesthetic Surgery Journal. 2023;43:0&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10653354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37610252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A review of key Likert scale development advances: 1995-2019. Jebb AT, Ng V, Tay L. Front Psychol. 2021;12:637547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34017283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A scoping review of the application of BREAST-Q in surgical research. Arora N, Patel R, Sohi G, Merchant S, Martou G. JPRAS Open. 2023;37:9&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10242639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37288429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The R Project for Statistical Computing.  [
Dec;
2024 
]. 2021. https://www.R-project.org/ https://www.R-project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A systematic review of single-stage augmentation-mastopexy. Khavanin N, Jordan SW, Rambachan A, Kim JY. https://journals.lww.com/plasreconsurg/abstract/2014/11000/a_systematic_review_of_single_stage.13.aspx. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2014;134:922&#x2013;931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25347628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achieving predictability in augmentation mastopexy: an update. Xue AS, Dayan E, Rohrich RJ. https://journals.lww.com/prsgo/fulltext/2020/09000/achieving_predictability_in_augmentation.14.aspx Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2020;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7544390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Optimizing breast implant outcomes: MemoryGel Xtra implants and future research directions. Benyaminpour S, Shalom M. https://academic.oup.com/asj/article/44/7/NP519/7630665 Aesthetic Surgery Journal. 2024;44:0&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11177551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38494943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The anatomy of revisions after primary breast augmentation: one surgeon&#x2019;s perspective. Spear SL, Dayan JH, West J. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0094129808000709. Clin Plast Surg. 2009;36:157&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19055970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augmentation/mastopexy: a 3-year review of a single surgeon&#x2019;s practice. Spear SL, Boehmler JH, Clemens MW. https://journals.lww.com/plasreconsurg/abstract/2006/12001/augmentation_mastopexy__a_3_year_review_of_a.21.aspx Plast Reconstr Surg. 2006;118:136&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17099493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>