<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41578760</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4058</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied immunohistochemistry &amp; molecular morphology : AIMM</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Immunohistochem Mol Morphol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Summary and Analysis of Molecular Biological Changes, PD-L1 Immune Status and Clinicopathological Features of 78 Cases of Papillary Thyroid Carcinoma (&lt;1&#xa0;cm in Diameter) Combined With Lateral Cervical Lymph Node Metastasis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>95</StartPage><EndPage>107</EndPage><MedlinePgn>95-107</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PAI.0000000000001297</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To observe and analyze the variation status of BRAF, K-RAS, N-RAS, RET, TERT and PIK3CA genes and the expression of PD-L1 immune factors in patients with papillary thyroid carcinoma (&lt;1&#xa0;cm in diameter) combined with lateral cervical lymph node metastasis, and to further explore the potential relationship and significance between the above 7 indexes and clinical ultrasound pathology and multiple parameters of ER, PR, and KI-67 protein. Seventy-eight cases of papillary thyroid carcinoma (&lt;1&#xa0;cm in diameter) combined with lateral cervical lymph node metastasis diagnosed after the first treatment in Yantai Yuhuangding Hospital from April 1, 2013, to April 1, 2021, were retrospectively analyzed (another 102 cases were not included in this study due to incomplete information), and the relevant clinical ultrasonic pathologic data were collected. The tumor DNA was extracted and the mutations of BRAF, K-RAS, N-RAS, RET, TERT, and PIK3CA were analyzed by ARMS fluorescence quantitative PCR. The expressions of PD-L1, ER, PR, and KI-67 were detected by immunohistochemistry. There were 78 patients of papillary thyroid carcinoma (&lt;1&#xa0;cm in diameter) combined with lateral cervical lymph node metastasis, including 20 males (mean age: 32.75&#xa0;y) and 58 females (mean age: 49.97&#xa0;y). Other clinical ultrasound pathologic parameters include: (1) preoperative serological thyroid function analysis includes TSH, FT4, FT3, TGAB, ATPO, and TRAB. (2) Ultrasound abnormalities include calcification, aspect ratio &#x2265;1, unclear boundary and irregular shape. (3) Pathologic image analysis included tumor size, capsule invasion, extraglandular strap muscle invasion, the number of lymph node metastasis and the expression of ER, PR, and KI-67. (4) Postoperative I131 treatment. Combined molecular detection showed that, in 78 cases, BRAF gene mutation was the most common (52 cases), followed by N-RAS gene mutation (30 cases), then K-RAS (12 cases), TERT (7 cases), and RET (4 cases), while PIK3CA gene was wild-type. BRAF and K-RAS gene mutations only appeared in female patients. The former was related to 7 parameters: patient sex ( P =0.000), onset age ( P =0.000), TSH ( P =0.000), ultrasonic aspect ratio ( P =0.030), tumor size ( P =0.002), ER ( P =0.000), and PR ( P =0.003). The latter was related to 5 parameters: sex ( P =0.000), onset age ( P =0.008), TSH ( P =0.018), TGAB ( P =0.049), and strap muscle invasion ( P =0.021). Only one case of N-RAS gene mutation was male, and the other 29 cases were female. It was related to 5 parameters: patient sex ( P =0.000), onset age ( P =0.001), TF4 ( P =0.027), strap muscle invasion ( P =0.048), and KI-67 index ( P =0.009). TERT gene mutation was slightly more in men (4 cases) than in women (3 cases), which was not only related to sex ( P =0.045), but also related to strap muscle invasion( P =0.013). The RET gene mutation was associated with capsule invasion ( P =0.031) and strap muscle invasion ( P =0.022). Single gene, double gene and triple gene mutations were found in 63 of 78 tumors: single gene mutations were found in 26 cases, among which BRAF gene mutations were the most common (17 cases). There were 32 cases of double gene mutation, and the simultaneous mutation of BRAF + N-RAS gene was the most common (25 cases). There were 5 cases of triple gene mutation, and the combined mutation of BRAF + N-RAS + TERT gene was the most common (2 cases). PD-L1 immune factor status showed that the positive expression rate of PD-L1 in 78 tumors was about 94.9% (74 cases), which was related to 4 parameters: patient sex ( P =0.000), onset age ( P =0.000), TSH ( P =0.036), and ER ( P =0.025). Among them, 17.9% (14 cases) were &#x2265; 50% strong positive, and all of them were female patients (accounting for 34.5% of female patients). Papillary thyroid carcinoma (&lt;1&#xa0;cm in diameter) combined with lateral cervical lymph node metastasis mainly occurs in young and middle-aged female (female: male = 2.9:1), but male patients are younger. In molecular genetics, 5 gene abnormalities of BRAF, K-RAS, N-RAS, RET, and TERT were detected, which can be manifested in 3 modes: single gene mutation, double gene mutation, and triple gene mutation. The tumors with double gene mutation and triple gene mutation may be more invasive. The above 5 gene mutations and PD-L1-mediated immune escape play an important role in the pathogenesis of papillary thyroid carcinoma (&lt;1&#xa0;cm in diameter) and lateral cervical lymph node metastasis, while the PIK3CA gene may not be involved in the pathogenesis of the tumor. BRAF, K-RAS, and N-RAS gene mutations were more common in female patients, while RET and TERT gene mutations were more common in male patients. Among them, patients with BRAF and K-RAS gene mutations are usually accompanied by positive expression of ER and PR, suggesting that these patients may benefit from endocrine therapy. In addition, PD-L1-mediated immunotherapy has broad application prospects in this tumor, female patients may benefit more, and immunotherapy combined with endocrine therapy is expected to become a good adjuvant treatment option for female cases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoteng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Rushan People's Hospital, Weihai.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Zhengyan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Practice, Fulaishan Health Service Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Weijie</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Yantai Yeda Hospital, Yantai Economic and Technological Development Zone.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Baoyuan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Otorhinolaryngology Head and Neck Surgery, Yantai Yuhuangding Hospital of Qingdao University, Yantai, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Xinmiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Yantai Yeda Hospital, Yantai Economic and Technological Development Zone.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Yantai Yeda Hospital, Yantai Economic and Technological Development Zone.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Minglong</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Yantai Yeda Hospital, Yantai Economic and Technological Development Zone.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Immunohistochem Mol Morphol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100888796</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1533-4058</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C423236">CD274 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008207" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lymphatic Metastasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="Y">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013964" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thyroid Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077273" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thyroid Cancer, Papillary</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PD-L1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lateral cervical lymph node metastasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecule</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">papillary thyroid carcinoma (&lt;1&#xa0;cm in diameter)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41578760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PAI.0000000000001297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00129039-990000000-00259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Miranda-Filho A, Lortet-Tieulent J, Bray F, et al. Thyroid cancer incidence trends by histology in 25 countries: a population-based study. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2021;9:225&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F, Wang L, Jia H. Research trends for papillary thyroid carcinoma from 2010 to 2019: a systematic review and bibliometrics analysis. Medicine (Baltimore). 2021;100:e26100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLellis RA, Lloyd RV, Heitz PU. Pathology and genetics of tumors of endocrine organs. World Health Organization classification of tumors by DeLellis RA, Lloyd RV, et al. IARC Press, Lyon. 2004:64&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant EG, Tessler FN, Hoang JK, et al. Thyroid ultrasound reporting lexicon: White paper of the ACR thyroid imaging reporting and data system (TIRADS)committee. J Am Coll Radiol. 2015;12:1272&#x2013;1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Y, Lu Y, li C. Clinical application of ultrasound-guided thyroid fine needle aspiration biopsy and thinprep cytology test in diagnosis of thyroid disease. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2016;17:4689&#x2013;4692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon MJ, Chung MS, Kwon H, et al. Features of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma associated with lateral cervical lymph node metastasis. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2017;86:845&#x2013;851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K, Zheng X, Kim JK, et al. The contributing factors for lateral neck lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma (PTMC). Endocrine. 2020;69:149&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang K, Gao N, Bian D, et al. Associations of BRAF V600E, clinical pathology and imaging factors with the recurrence rate of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Exp Ther Med. 2020;20:243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisanu A, Saba A, Podda M, et al. Nodal metastasis and recurrence in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Endocrine. 2015;48:575&#x2013;581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karvounis E, Kechagias A, Kappas I, et al. Papillary thyroid carcinoma micro-deposits in cervical lymph nodes without intra-thyroid malignancy: a comment in consideration of the latest American Thyroid Association guidelines. Mol Clin Oncol. 2021;15:164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HY, Park WY, Lee KE, et al. Comparative analysis of gene expression profiles of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma and papillary thyroid carcinoma. J Cancer Res Ther. 2010;6:452&#x2013;457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues AC, Penna G, Rodrigues E, et al. The genetics of papillary microcarcinomas of the thyroid: diagnostic and prognostic implications. Curr Genomics. 2017;18:244&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu FX, Hu MX, Zhao HX, et al. Precise detection of gene mutations in fine-needle aspiration specimens of the papillary thyroid microcarcinoma using next-generation sequencing. Int J Endocrinol. 2019;2019:4723958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera D, Ghossein R, Camacho N, et al. Genomic and transcriptomic characterization of papillary microcarcinomas with lateral neck lymph node metastases. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2019;104:4889&#x2013;4899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuong HG, Altibi AM, Abdelhamid AH, et al. The changing characteristics and molecular profiles of papillary thyroid carcinoma over time: a systematic review. Oncotarget. 2017;8:10637&#x2013;10649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojciechowska-Durczy&#x144;ska K, Krawczyk-Rusiecka K, Cyniak-Magierska A, et al. Relative quantification of PIK3CA gene expression level in fine-needle aspiration biopsy thyroid specimens collected from patients with papillary thyroid carcinoma and non-toxic goitre by real-time RT-PCR. Thyroid Res. 2010;3:5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacevic B, Vucevic D, Cerovic S, et al. Peripheral versus intraparenchymal papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: different morphologies and PD-L1 expression. Head Neck Pathol. 2022;16:200&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldien MMS, Abdou AG, Rageh T, et al. Immunohistochemical expression of ER-&#x3b1; and PR in papillary thyroid carcinoma. Ecancermedicalscience. 2017;11:748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito Y, Miyauchi A, Kakudo K, et al. Prognostic significance of Ki-67 labeling index in papillary thyroid carcinoma. World J Surg. 2010;34:3015&#x2013;3021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu JH, Zhao YN, Xie RL, et al. Analysis of risk factors for cervical lymph node metastasis of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a study of 268 patients. BMC Endocr Disord. 2019;19:124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue S, Han Z, Lu Q, et al. Clinical and ultrasonic risk factors for lateral lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Oncol. 2020;10:436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Li B, Zheng C, et al. Predicting factors of lateral neck lymph node metastases in patients with papillary thyroid Microcarcinoma. Medicine (Baltimore). 2019;98:e16386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Peng C, Gao M, et al. Risk factors for cervical lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a study of 1,587 patients. Cancer Biol Med. 2019;16:121&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng F, Chen Y, Zhu L, et al. Risk factors for cervical lymph node metastasis of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a single-center retrospective study. Int J Endocrinol. 2019;2019:8579828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grodski S, Delbridge L. An update on papillary microcarcinoma. Curr Opin Oncol. 2009;21:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doubi A, Al-Qannass A, Al-Angari SS, et al. Trends in thyroid carcinoma among thyroidectomy patients: a 12-year multicenter study. Ann Saudi Med. 2019;39:345&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugitani I, Toda K, Yamada K, et al. Three distinctly different kinds of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma should be recognized: our treatment strategies and outcomes. World J Surg. 2010;34:1222&#x2013;1231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M, Kim HI, Ha J, et al. Tumor volume doubling time in active surveillance of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a multicenter cohort study in Korea. Thyroid. 2021;31:1494&#x2013;1501.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue S, Wang P, Zhang Q, et al. Routine lateral level v dissection may not be necessary for papillary thyroid microcarcinoma with lateral lymph node metastasis: a retrospective study of 252 cases. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2019;10:558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song YS, Kang BH, Lee S, et al. Genomic and transcriptomic characteristics according to size of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Cancers (Basel). 2020;12:1345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Chen G, Sheng C, et al. BRAFV600E mutation in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a meta-analysis. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2015;22:159&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee X, Gao M, Ji Y, et al. Analysis of differential BRAF V600E mutational status in high aggressive papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Ann Surg Oncol. 2009;16:240&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Li J, Wang Y, et al. Association of BRAF gene and TSHR with cervical lymph node metastasis of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Oncol Lett. 2019;17:183&#x2013;194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Sadow PM, Suh H, et al. BRAF(V600E) is correlated with recurrence of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a systematic review, multi-institutional primary data analysis, and meta-analysis. Thyroid. 2016;26:248&#x2013;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma YJ, Deng XL, Li HQ. BRAFV600E mutation and its association with clinicopathological features of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a meta-analysis. J Huazhong Univ Sci Technolog Med Sci. 2015;35:591&#x2013;599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park AY, Son EJ, Kim JA, et al. Associations of the BRAF V600E mutation with sonographic features and clinicopathologic characteristics in a large population with conventional papillary thyroid carcinoma. PLoS One. 2014;9:e110868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SY, Park H, Kang MK, et al. The relationship between the BRAF V600E mutation in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma and clinicopathologic factors. World J Surg Oncol. 2013;11:291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TY, Kim WB, Song JY, et al. The BRAF mutation is not associated with poor prognostic factors in Korean patients with conventional papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2005;63:588&#x2013;593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji W, Xie H, Wei B, et al. Relationship between BRAF V600E gene mutation and the clinical and pathologic characteristics of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma. Int J Clin Exp Pathol. 2019;12:3492&#x2013;3499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Zhang Z, Wang K, et al. Association of BRAFV600E mutation with ultrasonographic features and clinicopathologic characteristics of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma: a retrospective study of 116 cases. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2019;73:545&#x2013;552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fakhruddin N, Jabbour M, Novy M, et al. BRAF and NRAS mutations in papillary thyroid carcinoma and concordance in BRAF mutations between primary and corresponding lymph node metastases. Sci Rep. 2017;7:4666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon MJ, Chun SM, Lee JY, et al. Mutational profile of papillary thyroid microcarcinoma with extensive lymph node metastasis. Endocrine. 2019;64:130&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penna GC, Vaisman F, Vaisman M, et al. Molecular markers involved in tumorigenesis of thyroid carcinoma: focus on aggressive histotypes. Cytogenet Genome Res. 2016;150(3-4):194&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Biase D, Gandolfi G, Ragazzi M, et al. Tert promoter mutations in thyroid papillary microcarcinomas. Thyroid. 2015;25:1013&#x2013;1019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Kim T, Kim K, et al. Highly prevalent BRAF V600E and low-frequency TERT promoter mutations underlie papillary thyroid carcinoma in Koreans. J Pathol Transl Med. 2020;54:310&#x2013;317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yabuta T, Matsuse M, Hirokawa M, et al. TERT promoter mutations were not found in papillary thyroid microcarcinomas that showed disease progression on active surveillance. Thyroid. 2017;27:1206&#x2013;1207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue JC, Liu QJ, Tian YX, et al. Clinical significance of BRAFV600E and TERT promoter mutation in papillary thyroid microcarcinoma *. Oncol Transl Med. 2019;5:P75&#x2013;P79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo SK, Song YS, Lee EK, et al. Integrative analysis of genomic and transcriptomic characteristics associated with progression of aggressive thyroid cancer. Nat Commun. 2019;10:2764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan H, Li Y, Hu P, et al. Mutational profiling of poorly differentiated and anaplastic thyroid carcinoma by the use of targeted next-generation sequencing. Histopathology. 2019;75:890&#x2013;899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren H, Shen Y, Hu D, et al. Co-existence of BRAF V600E and TERT promoter mutations in papillary thyroid carcinoma is associated with tumor aggressiveness, but not with lymph node metastasis. Cancer Manag Res. 2018;10:1005&#x2013;1013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu PC, Tan LC, Zhu XL, et al. Arms-qPCR improves detection sensitivity of earlier diagnosis of papillary thyroid cancers with worse prognosis determined by coexisting BRAF V600E and TERT promoter mutations. Endocr Pract. 2021;27:698&#x2013;705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing M, Liu R, Liu X, et al. Braf v600e and tert promoter mutations cooperatively identify the most aggressive papillary thyroid cancer with highest recurrence. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32:2718&#x2013;2726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trybek T, Walczyk A, G&#x105;sior-Perczak D, et al. Impact of BRAF V600E and TERT promoter mutations on response to therapy in papillary thyroid cancer. Endocrinology. 2019;160:2328&#x2013;2338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Shi Y, Xu Y, et al. The predictive value of coexisting BRAFV600E and TERT promoter mutations on poor outcomes and high tumour aggressiveness in papillary thyroid carcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 2021;94:731&#x2013;742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R, Xing M. TERT promoter mutations in thyroid cancer. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2016;23:R143&#x2013;R155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury S, Veyhl J, Jessa F, et al. Programmed death-ligand 1 overexpression is a prognostic marker for aggressive papillary thyroid cancer and its variants. Oncotarget. 2016;7:32318&#x2013;32328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi RL, Qu N, Luo TX, et al. Programmed death-ligand 1 expression in papillary thyroid cancer and its correlation with clinicopathologic factors and recurrence. Thyroid. 2017;27:537&#x2013;545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An HJ, Ko GH, Lee JH, et al. Programmed death-ligand 1 expression and its correlation with lymph node metastasis in papillary thyroid carcinoma. J Pathol Transl Med. 2018;52:9&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn S, Kim TH, Kim SW, et al. Comprehensive screening for PD-L1 expression in thyroid cancer. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2017;24:97&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha LL, Marcello MA, Morari EC, et al. Differentiated thyroidcarcinomas may elude the immune system by B7H1 upregulation. Endocrine-Related Cancer. 2013;20:103&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y, Guo T, Huang X, et al. In papillary thyroid carcinoma, expression by immunohistochemistry of BRAF V600E, PD-L1, and PD-1 is closely related. Virchows Arch. 2018;472:779&#x2013;787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siraj AK, Parvathareddy SK, Pratheeshkumar P, et al. PD-L1 is an independent prognostic marker in Middle Eastern PTC, and its expression is upregulated by BRAFV600E mutation. Cancers (Basel). 2021;13:555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y, Niu D, Huang X, et al. PD-L1 and PD-1 expression are correlated with distinctive clinicopathological features in papillary thyroid carcinoma. Diagn Pathol. 2017;12:72.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>