<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41321751</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2296-6870</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biomedicine hub</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Hub</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Atrial Fibrillation in 63-Year-Old Former Elite Endurance Athletes: A 38-Year Follow-Up Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>191</StartPage><EndPage>196</EndPage><MedlinePgn>191-196</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000548326</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There are many reports on atrial fibrillation/flutter (AF) in previous elite endurance athletes (ExA) and veteran athletes (VA), but no prospective studies on AF in elite endurance athletes (EA) have been published. Most studies are on males and increased risk in males has been found, but the explanation of this has been controversial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We present a study where 15 male and 15 female EA and matched groups of sports students and non-athletes were studied with clinical examination, a questionnaire, standard ECG, echocardiography, and 24-h ECG (Holter) monitoring in 1985. Twenty-nine EA were re-examined with the same examinations in 2000, and in 2023, a follow-up of 24 of them was done with a questionnaire and ambulatory ECG recording, aiming at the effect of risk factors, training parameters and sex on the occurrence of AF in ExA. The ambulatory ECG recording was done with smartphone (ECG 247) for 72 h or more.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The mean age was 62.6 years. All had ended their competition career before the age of 39. Three had known AF, all males, with the sex difference being significant. Another two males and one female had a history of tachycardia, and the sex difference in total tachycardias was also significant. None of the ExA had asymptomatic AF. A paternal history of AF was significantly more frequent in males with AF than in males without AF. There were no significant sex differences in training parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We think our study does not support doing ambulatory ECG recording of all ExA at age 65, but one should be aware of increased risk in males with a paternal history of AF. Both AF and symptomatic tachycardias were significantly increased in males. However, the low number of AF is a limitation of these conclusions and does not permit concluding on whether training during middle age confers a higher risk of AF than training at a younger age. No sex differences in training in ExA indicate that biological factors (like hormones) contribute considerably to the sex difference in the risk of AF in ExA. Despite the low number of AF cases, we believe our study provides new knowledge as it is prospective, free of baseline selection bias, includes detailed investigations both at baseline and at follow-up, and addresses a gap in prospective studies on AF in EA.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bj&#xf8;rnstad</LastName><ForeName>Hans Halvor</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Heart Disease, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bj&#xf8;rnstad-Tuveng</LastName><ForeName>Tor Halvor</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Municipality of Tynset, Tynset, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sandberg</LastName><ForeName>Edvard Liljedahl</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Sorlandet Hospital Arendal, Arendal, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hjertvikrem</LastName><ForeName>Nina</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Heart Disease, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Heart Disease, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Biomed Hub</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101692630</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-6870</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atrial fibrillation/flutter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Continuous ambulatory ECG recording</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Former elite endurance athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sex</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Veteran athletes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>E.L.S. has received speaking fees from Pfizer and AstraZeneca.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41321751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12659206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000548326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">548326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Karjalainen J, Kujala UM, Kaprio J, Sarna S, Viitasalo M. Lone atrial fibrillation in vigorously exercising middle-aged men: case-control study. BMJ. 1998;316(7147):1784&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC28577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9624065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulla J, Nielsen JR. Is the risk of atrial fibrillation higher in athletes than in the general population? A systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. Europace. 2009;111:1156&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19633305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnstad H, Smith G, Storstein L, Meen HD, Hals O. Electrocardiographic and echocardiographic findings in top athletes, athletic students and sedentary controls. Cardiology. 1993;82(1):66&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8519012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnstad H, Storstein L, Meen HD, Hals O. Ambulatory electrocardiographic findings in top athletes, athletic students and control subjects. Cardiology. 1994;84(1):42&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8149388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf8;rnstad HH, Bj&#xf8;rnstad TH, Urheim S, Hoff PI, Smith G, Maron BJ. Long-Term assessment of electrocardiographic and echocardiographic findings in Norwegian elite endurance athletes. Cardiology. 2009;112(3):234&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18719347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elosua R, Arquer A, Mont L, Sambola A, Molina L, Garc&#xed;a-Mor&#xe1;n E, et al. Sport practice and the risk of lone atrial fibrillation: a case-control study. Int J Cardiol. 2006;108(3):332&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15963583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drca N, Wolk M, Jensen-Urstad M, Larsson SC. Atrial fibrillation is Elite Endurance Athletes associated with different levels of physical activity levels at different ages in men. Heart. 2014;100(13):1037&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24829373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guasch ML. Exercise, sex and atrial fibrillation: arrhythmogenesis beyond Y-chromosome? Heart. 2015(20):8 (Editorial).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26206849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandberg EL, Grenne BL, Berge T, Grimsmo J, Atar D, Halvorsen S, et al. Diagnostic accuracy and usability of the ECG247 Smart heart sensor compared to conventional holter technology. J Healthc Eng. 2021;2021:5230947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34765102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoogsteen J, Schep G, Van Hemel N, Van der Wall E. Paroxysmal atrial fibrillation in male endurance athletes. A 9 -year follow-up. Europace. 2004;6(3):222&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15121075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furlanello F, Bertoldi A, Dallago M, Galassi A, Fernando F, Biffi A, et al. Atrial fibrillation in elite athletes. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1998(Suppl l):563&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9727678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson SC, Drca N, Wolk A. Alcohol consumption and risk of atrial fibrillation: a prospective study and dose-response meta-analysis and incidence analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2014;64(3):281&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25034065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox CS, Parise H, D&#x2019;Agostino R, Lloyd-Jones DM, Vasan RS, Wang TJ, et al. Parental atrial fibrillation as a risk factor for atrial fibrillation in the offspring. JAMA. 2004;291(23):2851&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15199036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel AJ, Hennekens CH, Rosner B, Karlson LK. Paternal history of coronary heart disease reported by marathon runners. N Engl J Med. 1979;301(2):90&#x2013;1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">449950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drca N, Larsson SC, Grannas D, Jensen-Urstad M. Elite female endurance athletes are at increased risk of atrial fibrillation compared to the general population: a matched cohort study. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57(18):1175&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37433586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldesberger S, Bauersfeld U, Candinas R, Seifert B, Zuber M, Ritter M, et al. Sinus node disease and arrhythmias in the long-term follow up of former professional cyclists. Eur Heart J. 2008;29(1):71&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18065754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimsmo J, Grundvold I, Maehlum S, Arnesen H. High prevalence of atrial fibrillation in long-term endurance cross-country skiers: echocardiographic findings and possible predictors-a 28-30 years follow-up study. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil. 2010;17(1):100&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20065854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storstein L, Bj&#xf8;rnstad H, Hals O, Meen HD. Electrocardiographic findings according to sex in athletes and controls. Cardiology. 1991;79(3):227&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1769038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>