<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41113230</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0972-8988</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Veterinary world</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet World</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thermoregulatory, physiological, and intestinal responses to functional waters in heat-stressed rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2761</StartPage><EndPage>2773</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2761-2773</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14202/vetworld.2025.2761-2773</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Climate change and global warming have intensified the challenges of heat stress (HS) in mammals, compromising thermoregulation, hydration, and physiological stability. Functional waters such as alkaline reduced water (ALKA), Zamzam water (ZMZM), and ozonated water (OZON) have been proposed to provide therapeutic and protective benefits. However, limited research has explored their roles in thermoregulation under chronic HS. This study investigated the effects of ALKA, ZMZM, and OZON on thermophysiology, serum metabolites, and intestinal morphology in Wistar rats exposed to variable thermal climates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Seventy male Wistar rats (8 weeks old, 180-200 g) were randomized into five groups (n = 14): Control, distilled water (DIST), ALKA, ZMZM, and OZON. The experiment lasted 71 days, consisting of thermoneutral zone (TNZ; days 0-7), HS (32.3 &#xb1; 0.8&#xb0;C; days 8-35), and a return to TNZ (days 36-71). Core body temperature (Tcore) was monitored using thermal microchips and loggers. Daily water intake, body weight, serum biochemical markers, and intestinal villi morphology were evaluated. Data were analyzed using repeated measures analysis of variance and general linear model procedures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">HS induced hyperthermia and increased daily water intake by 69.2% across all groups. ZMZM significantly reduced Tcore, especially at night, and increased water intake during HS. OZON consumption elevated water intake during TNZ, reduced serum creatinine, and enhanced alkaline phosphatase levels, while both OZON and DIST groups exhibited elevated antidiuretic hormone levels. ALKA intake significantly reduced serum sodium+ and chloride- levels under post-HS TNZ. Histological analysis revealed that ZMZM markedly increased villus length, width, and crypt depth in the duodenum, jejunum, and ileum, indicating enhanced intestinal absorptive capacity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ZMZM demonstrated superior thermoregulatory and intestinal benefits, supporting hydration, physiological recovery, and intestinal health during and after HS. OZON showed nephroprotective and metabolic modulation potential, while alkaline water contributed to electrolyte regulation. These findings highlight the potential of functional waters as supportive strategies against HS, warranting further translational studies in livestock and humans.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Al-Dawood, et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Dawood</LastName><ForeName>Amani</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Biology, College of Sciences, Tafila Technical University, Tafila 66110, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Shalabi</LastName><ForeName>Raneem</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Food Technology, Faculty of Agriculture, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid 22110, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Tamimi</LastName><ForeName>Hosam</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Production, Faculty of Agriculture, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid 22110, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halalsheh</LastName><ForeName>Raed</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Sciences, Faculty of Applied Medical Sciences, The Hashemite University, Zarqa 13133, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Vet World</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101504872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0972-8988</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zamzam water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alkaline reduced water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">functional waters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heat stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intestinal morphology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ozonated water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermoregulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41113230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12535440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14202/vetworld.2025.2761-2773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">Vetworld-18-2761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Gasparrini A, Armstrong B.G, Tawatsupa B, Tobias A, Lavigne E, Coelho M.S.Z.S, Pan X, Kim H, Hashizume M, Honda Y, Guo Y.L, Wu C.F, Zanobetti A, Schwartz J.D, Bell M.L, Scortichini M, Michelozzi P, Punnasiri K, Li S, Tian L, Garcia S.D.O, Seposo X, Overcenco A, Zeka A, Goodman P, Dang T.N, Dung D.V, Mayvaneh F, Saldiva P.H.N, Williams G, Tong S. Heat wave and mortality:A multicountry, multicommunity study. Environ Health Perspect. 2017;125(8):087006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5783630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28886602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modell H, Cliff W, Michael J, McFarland J, Wenderoth M.P, Wright A. A physiologist's view of homeostasis. Adv. Physiol. Educ. 2015;39(4):259&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4669363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26628646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckett E.A.H, Gaganis V, Bakker A.J, Towstoless M, Hayes A, Hryciw D.H, Lexis L, Tangalakis K. Unpacking the homeostasis core concept in physiology:An Australian perspective. Adv Physiol Educ. 2023;47(3):427&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37078527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yam Y.L.J. Body temperature and its regulation. Anest Intens Care Med. 2024;25(8):584&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Rivas P.A, Chauhan S.S, Ha M, Fegan N, Dunshea F.R, Warner R.D. Effects of heat stress on animal physiology, metabolism, and meat quality:A review. Meat Sci. 2020;162:108025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31841730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall J.E, Guyton A.C. Textbook of Medical Physiology. PA, USA: Saunders/Elsevier; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbalis J.G. Disorders of body water homeostasis. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003;17(4):471&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nose H, Kamijo Y.I, Masuki S. Interactions between body fluid homeostasis and thermoregulation in humans. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;156:417&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30454604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong L.E. Rehydration during endurance exercise:Challenges, research, options, methods. Nutrients. 2021;13(3):887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8001428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crespo P.V, Campos F, Leal M, Maraver F. Effects of sodium chloride-rich mineral water on intestinal epithelium. Experimental study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(6):3261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33809886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez R, Prieto I, Amor S, Patel G, De La Fuente M, Granado M, Monsalve M. Evaluation of the potential benefits of alkaline drinking water on tumor development reveals vascular protective effects. Arch. Med. Sci. Civil Dis. 2021;6(1):84&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zergui A, Aledeh M, Hamad S. Metallic profile of Zamzam water:Determination of minerals, metals and metalloids by ICP-MS. J. Trace Elem. Min. 2022;2:100031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Q, Zhang J, Su Z, Wang X, Fang H, Qian S, Shi H, Wang Q, Li Y, Lin J, Wang X, Wang Z, Liao L. Clinical trial of ozonated water enema for the treatment of fibromyalgia:A randomized, double-blind trial. Pain Physician. 2025;28(1):E13&#x2013;E22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39903016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Tamimi H.J, Eichen P.A, Rottinghaus G.E, Spiers D.E. Nitric oxide supplementation alleviates hyperthermia induced by intake of ergopeptine alkaloids during chronic heat stress. J. Therm. Biol. 2007;32(4):179&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider C, Rasband W, Eliceiri K. NIH image to imageJ:25 years of image analysis. Nat. Methods. 2012;9(7):671&#x2013;675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill J.L, Hafs H.D. Analysis of repeated measurements of animals. J. Anim. Sci. 1971;33(2):331&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5106166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steel R.G, Torrie J.H. Principles and Procedures of Statistics:A Biometrical Approach. United States: McGraw-Hill; 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littell R.C, Henry P.R, Ammerman C.B. Statistical analysis of repeated measures data using SAS procedures. J. Anim. Sci. 1998;76(4):216&#x2013;1231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9581947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon C.J. Twenty-four hour rhythms of selected ambient temperature in rat and hamster. Physiol. Behav. 1993;53(2):257&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8446688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran D.S, Horowitz M, Meiri U, Laor A, Pandolf K.B. The physiological strain index applied to heat-stressed rats. J. Appl. Physiol. 1999;86(3):895&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10066702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Sawada T, Kondo Y, Kondo K, Levy J.H. Morphological changes in blood cells in a rat model of heatstroke:A pilot study. J. Clin. Med. 2022;11(16):4821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9410003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36013060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon C.J. Thermal biology of the laboratory rat. Physiol. Behav. 1990;47(5):963&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2201986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra M.E.G, Baeza-Noci J, Mendes Abdala C.V, Luvisotto M.M, Bertol C.D, Anzolin A.P. The role of ozone treatment as integrative medicine. An evidence and gap map. Front. Public Health. 2023;10:1112296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9885089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36726625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhina I.V, Dudina E.V, Yakovleva E.I, Zhemarina N.V, Prodanecs N.N, Evdokimova O.S. The Dose-Dependent Effect of Ozonated Physiological Solution on Arterial Vasodilation. In:Proceedings of the IOA 17th World Ozone Congress-Strasbourg. 2005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toto K.H. Regulation of plasma osmolality:Thirst and vasopressin. Crit. Care Nurs. Clin. North Am. 1994;6(4):661&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7766344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zocchi D, Wennemuth G, Oka Y. The cellular mechanism for water detection in the mammalian taste system. Nat. Neurosci. 2017;20(7):927&#x2013;933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28553944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams H, Burlingame G, Ikehata K, Furatian L, Suffet I.H. The effect of pH on taste and odor production and control of drinking water. Aqua Water Infrastruct. Ecosyst. Soc. 2022;71(11):1278&#x2013;1290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodcock T. Fluid physiology part 1:Volume and distribution of water and its major solutes between plasma, the interstitium and intracellular fluid. In: Malbrain M.L, Wong A, Nasa P, Ghosh S, editors. Rational Use of Intravenous Fluids in Critically Ill Patients. Cham: Springer; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKinley M.J. Osmoreceptors for thirst in thirst. In: Ramsay D.J, Booth D, editors. ILSI, Human Nutrition Reviews. London: Springer; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Zaiat S.Y. Inherent optical properties of Zamzam water in the visible spectrum:Dispersion analysis. Arab J. Sci. Eng. 2007;32(2):171&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mota-Rojas D, Titto C.G, Orihuela A, Mart&#xed;nez-Burnes J, G&#xf3;mez-Prado J, Torres-Bernal F, Flores-Padilla K, Carvajal-De La Fuente V, Wang D. Physiological and behavioral mechanisms of thermoregulation in mammals. Animals (Basel) 2021;11(6):1733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8227286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34200650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chibly A.M, Aure M.H, Patel V.N, Hoffman M.P. Salivary gland function, development, and regeneration. Physiol. Rev. 2022;102(3):1495&#x2013;1552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35343828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calamita G, Delporte C. Insights into the function of aquaporins in gastrointestinal fluid absorption and secretion in health and disease. Cells. 2023;12(17):2170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10486417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37681902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv H, Li Y, Xue C, Dong N, Bi C, Shan A. Aquaporin:Targets for dietary nutrients to regulate intestinal health. J. Anim. Physiol. Anim. Nutr. (Berl) 2022;106(1):167&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M.A, Cosemi E, Kamel S, Mohammed S, Elhefnawy M, Farid L, Shaker S. Miracle of Zamzam Water:The Effect on Human Endometrial Aquaporin. In:13th International Water Technology Conference IWTC. 2009:1515&#x2013;1520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung S.M, Kim S. In vitro models of the small intestine for studying intestinal diseases. Front. Microbiol. 2022;12:767038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8765704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35058894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Xiao X, Zhang X. Hydration status in older adults:current knowledge and future challenges. Nutrients. 2023;15(11):2609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10255140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37299572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud H.S, Eltahlawi R.A, Alhadramy O, Soliman T.M, El-Kot Y.M.F, Omar N.A.A, El Sayed S.M, Abdallah H.I, El-Shazley M, Allithy A.N.A, El-Dabie N, Abdel-Haleem M, El-Dardear A, Hassan S.M.A, Helmy M.M, El-Alaf H, Baghdadi H, El-Sawy S, El Sayed S.M. Zamzam water is pathogen-free, cardioprotective and tissue-protective:Relieving the BBC concerns. Am. J. Clin. Med. Res. 2020;8(1):5&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgadillo-Valero L.F, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Cruz E.Y, Pedraza-Chaverri J. The protective role of ozone therapy in kidney disease:A review. Life (Basel) 2023;13(3):752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10057350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36983907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrego A, Zamora Z.B, Gonz&#xe1;lez R, Romay C, Men&#xe9;ndez S, Hern&#xe1;ndez F, Montero T, Rojas E. Protection by ozone preconditioning is mediated by the antioxidant system in cisplatin-induced nephrotoxicity in rats. Mediators Inflamm. 2004;13(1):13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1781537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15203559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peralta C, Le&#xf3;n O.S, Xaus C, Prats N, Jalil E.C, Planell E.S, Puig-Parellada P, Gelp&#xed; E, Rosell&#xf3;-Catafau J. Protective effect of ozone treatment on the injury associated with hepatic ischemia-reperfusion:Antioxidant-prooxidant balance. Free Radic. Res. 1999;31(3):191&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10499775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peralta C, Xa C, Bartrons R, Leon O.S, Gelpi E, Rosell&#xf3;-Catafau J. Effect of ozone treatment on reactive oxygen species and adenosine production during hepatic ischemia-reperfusion. Free Radic. Res. 2000;33(5):595&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11200091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber E, Men&#xe9;ndez S, Le&#xf3;n O.S, Barber M.O, Merino N, Calunga J.L, Cruz E, Bocci V. Prevention of renal injury after induction of ozone tolerance in rats submitted to warm ischaemia. Mediators Inflamm. 1999;8(1):37&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1781776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10704088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue B, Song J, Liu L, Luo J, Tian G, Yang Y. Effect of epigallocatechin gallate on growth performance and antioxidant capacity in heat-stressed broilers. Arch. Anim. Nutr. 2017;71(5):362&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28741959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman C.L, Johnson B.D, Parker M.D, Hostler D, Pryor R.R, Schlader Z. Kidney physiology and pathophysiology during heat stress and the modification by exercise, dehydration, heat acclimation and aging. Temperature (Austin) 2020;8(2):108&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8098077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33997113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finaud J, Lac G, Filaire E. Oxidative stress:Relationship with exercise and training. Sports Med. 2006;36(4):327&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16573358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiron F, Thomas C, Bardin J, Mullie F, Bennett S, Ch&#xe9;radame J, Caliz L, Hanon C, Tiollier E. Influence of ingestion of bicarbonate-rich water combined with an alkalizing or acidizing diet on acid-base balance and anaerobic performance. J. Hum. Kinet. 2024;93:105&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11307191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39132426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Zuhair N, Khounganian R. A comparative study between the chemical composition of potable water and Zamzam water in Saudi Arabia. Saudi Dent. J. 2006;18:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batarseh M.I. The quality of potable water types in Jordan. Environ. Monit. Assess. 2006;117(1-3):235&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16917709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franceschelli S, Gatta D.M, Pesce M, Ferrone A, Patruno A, De Lutiis M.A, Grilli A, Felaco M, Croce F, Speranza L. New approach in translational medicine:Effects of electrolyzed reduced water (ERW) on NF-kB/iNOS pathway in U937 cell line under altered redox State. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2016;17(9):1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5037740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27598129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elnour A, Bamosa A, Al Meheithif A, Aleissa K. Amelioration of severe carbon tetrachloride toxicity by Zamzam water in rats. J. Nutr. Food Sci. 2013;3(2):1000197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Doghaither H.A, Al-Sohaibani R.M, Omar U.M, Alharbi H.A. Biochemical and histological effects of five weeks ingestion of Zamzam water on the liver and kidneys of wistar rats. Saudi Pharm. J. 2021;29(1):91&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33603543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ero&#x11e;Lu H.A, Makav M, Findik Guvendi G, Buyuk B, Adali Y. Ozone vs melatonin:The therapeutic effects in alcoholic liver disease. Harran. Univ. Tip Fak. Derg. 2020;17(1):133&#x2013;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leigh S.J, Uhlig F, Wilmes L, Sanchez-Diaz P, Gheorghe C.E, Goodson M.S, Kelley-Loughnane N, Hyland N.P, Cryan J.F, Clarke G. The impact of acute and chronic stress on gastrointestinal physiology and function:A microbiota-gut-brain axis perspective. J Physiol. 2023;601(20):4491&#x2013;4538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37756251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson A, Hemphill D, Jeejeebhoy K.N. Oxidative stress and antioxidants in intestinal disease. Dig. Dis. 1998;16(3):152&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9618134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwan A.J. Effect of Zamzam's water and magnetized water on E Coli o157:H7 growth compared to other pathogens. Eurasia J Biosci. 2020;14(1):645&#x2013;650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimulddin S.A, Al-Ghafari A.B, Omar U.M, Al Doghaither H.A, Al Zahrani S.M. Influence of pH and sterilization conditions on the inhibitory effects of Zamzam water on the cell viability of cancer cells. J Biol Sci. 2016;16(6):229&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badar A, Bamosa A.O, Salahuddin M, Al Meheithif A. Effect of Zamzam water on blood methemoglobin level in young rats. J. Family Community Med. 2019;26(1):30&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6335836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30697102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutfiah H. The scientific analysis of Zamzam water in the perspective of hadith prophet muhammad saw. As-Salam J. Studi Hukum Islam Pendidikan. 2020;9(1):91&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yason C.V, Summers B.A, Schat K.A. Pathogenesis of rotavirus infection in various age groups of chickens and turkeys:Pathology. Am J Vet Res. 1987;48(6):927&#x2013;938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3605809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodlad R.A, Plumb J.A, Wright N.A. Epithelial cell proliferation and intestinal absorptive function during starvation and refeeding in the rat. Clin Sci (Lond) 1988;74(3):301&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3345639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodlad R.A, Wright N.A. The effects of starvation and refeeding on intestinal cell proliferation in the mouse. Virchows Arch B Cell Pathol. Incl Mol Pathol. 1984;45(1):63&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6142558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldewachi H.S, Wright N.A, Appleton D.R, Watson A.J. The effect of starvation and refeeding on cell population kinetics in the rat small bowel mucosa. J Anat. 1975;119(1):105&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1231620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1133081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian S, Yan S, Pang R, Zhang J, Liu K, Shi Z, Wang Z, Chen P, Zhang Y, Luo T, Hu X, Xiong Y, Zhou Y. A temperature-regulated circuit for feeding behavior. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):4229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9307622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>