<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41452457</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-3023</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International urogynecology journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int Urogynecol J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pelvic Floor Dysfunction Research: A Bibliometric Analysis with Retrospective Clinical Validation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00192-025-06452-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION AND HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Pelvic floor dysfunction (PFD), primarily manifesting as pelvic organ prolapse (POP) and urinary incontinence (UI), is a prevalent condition that severely impairs women's quality of life. While management strategies exist, outcomes are often suboptimal, highlighting the need for a deeper understanding of research trends and their clinical relevance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study employed a mixed-methods exploratory design. First, a comprehensive bibliometric analysis of 23,005 publications from the Web of Science Core Collection (2003-2023) was conducted to map the global PFD research landscape, identify key trends, and detect thematic shifts. Second, to contextualize these findings, a retrospective analysis of clinical outcomes from 350 women with moderate PFD who received standardized pelvic floor muscle training (PFMT) was performed. Pre- and post-treatment pelvic floor muscle function (via surface electromyography) and anatomical support (via perineal ultrasound) were compared.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Bibliometric analysis revealed a significant acceleration in publications after 2011, led by the United States, China, and the United Kingdom. Keyword analysis identified a clear thematic shift from a focus on surgical management (pre-2018) towards prevention, rehabilitation, and quality of life (post-2018), with PFMT emerging as a prominent research hotspot. The retrospective clinical analysis demonstrated that after one to two courses of PFMT, patients showed statistically significant improvements in muscle strength, endurance, and resting tone (all p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). These functional gains were corroborated by ultrasound evidence of pelvic organ elevation and a reduced levator hiatus area.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">By synergistically integrating macro-level bibliometric trends with micro-level clinical evidence, this study provides a holistic overview of the evolving PFD research landscape. The alignment of a growing academic focus on conservative management with real-world clinical outcomes from a PFMT cohort suggests a paradigm shift towards function-oriented, patient-centered care and highlights its role as a cornerstone of PFD management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive license to International Urogynecological Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Tianhui</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0298-902X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology and Reproductive Sciences, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China. niuhui81@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology and Reproductive Sciences, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology and Reproductive Sciences, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Mengnan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ai</LastName><ForeName>Manhong</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology and Reproductive Sciences, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology and Reproductive Sciences, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology and Reproductive Sciences, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jia</LastName><ForeName>Jinghui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology and Reproductive Sciences, Air Force Medical University, Air Force Medical Center, PLA, Beijing, China. 690352711@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 23JSZ06</GrantID><Agency>General Project of the Special Scientific Research on Military Family Planning</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int Urogynecol J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101567041</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0937-3462</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bibliometric Analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor dysfunction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor muscle training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic organ prolapse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Research Trends</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary incontinence</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Statement: This study utilized publicly available datasets. Ethics review and approval were approved by the Institutional Ethics Committee of the Air Force Medical Center. Conflicts of interest: The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41452457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-025-06452-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00192-025-06452-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Quaghebeur J, Petros P, Wyndaele JJ, et sl. Pelvic-floor function, dysfunction, and treatment. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2021;265:143&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchsbaum GM. Urinary incontinence and pelvic organ prolapse. Minerva Urol Nefrol. 2006;58(4):311&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17268396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo Z, Wang C, Yu H, et al. The relationship between pelvic floor function and sexual function in perimenopausal women. Sex Med. 2021;9(6):100441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esxm.2021.100441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34628115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8766258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung VW, Hampton BS. Epidemiology of pelvic floor dysfunction. Obstet Gynecol Clin North Am. 2009;36(3):421&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ogc.2009.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19932408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peinado-Molina RA, Hernandez-Martinez A, Martinez-Vazquez S, et al. Pelvic floor dysfunction: prevalence and associated factors. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-16901-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37838661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10576367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulak NA, Trzcinski R. The burden of pelvic floor dysfunction. J Sci Med Sport. 2022;25(4):293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2021.11.042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34916168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flusberg M, Xi Y, Jambhekar K, et al. Variability in utilization and techniques of pelvic floor imaging: findings of the SAR pelvic floor dysfunction disease-focused panel. Abdom Radiol. 2021;46(4):1294&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00261-021-02957-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace SL, Miller LD, Mishra K. Pelvic floor physical therapy in the treatment of pelvic floor dysfunction in women. Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol. 2019;31(6):485&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GCO.0000000000000584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31609735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Ju B, Wang X, et al. Global knowledge mapping and emerging research trends in non-coding RNAs related to animal and plant male sterility: A visual analysis of CiteSpace maps. Medicine (Baltimore). 2025Jun 6;104(23):e42612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000042612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40489841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arruda H, Silva ER, Lessa M, et al. VOSviewer and Bibliometrix. J Med Libr Assoc. 2022Jul 1;110(3):392&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5195/jmla.2022.1434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36589296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9782747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber AM, Abrams P, Brubaker L, et al. The standardization of terminology for researchers in female pelvic floor disorders. Int Urogynecol J Pelvic Floor Dysfunct. 2001;12(3):178&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/PL00004033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11451006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2815805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bump RC, Mattiasson A, Bo K, et al. The standardization of terminology of female pelvic organ prolapse and pelvic floor dysfunction. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1996;175(1):10&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-9378(96)70243-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8694033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams P, Cardozo L, Fall M, et al. The standardisation of terminology of lower urinary tract function: report from the Standardisation Sub-committee of the International Continence Society. Neurourol Urodyn. 2002;21(2):167&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.10052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11857671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haylen BT, Ridder DD, Freeman RM, et al. An international urogynecological association (IUGA)/international continence society (ICS) joint report on the terminology for female pelvic floor dysfunction. Int Urogynecol J. 2010;21(1):5&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-009-0976-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19937315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen AL, Smith VJ, Bergstrom JO, Colling JC, Clark AL. Epidemiology of surgically managed pelvic organ prolapse and urinary incontinence. Obstet Gynecol. 1997;89(4):501&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0029-7844(97)00058-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9083302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haylen BT, de Ridder D, Freeman RM, et al. An International Urogynecological Association (IUGA)/International Continence Society (ICS) joint report on the terminology for female pelvic floor dysfunction. Neurourol Urodyn. 2010;29(1):4&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.20798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19941278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery K, Donovan J, Peters TJ, et al. ICIQ: a brief and robust measure for evaluating the symptoms and impact of urinary incontinence. Neurourol Urodyn. 2004;23(4):322&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.20041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15227649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nygaard I, Barber MD, Burgio KL, et al. Prevalence of symptomatic pelvic floor disorders in US women. JAMA. 2008;300(11):1311&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.300.11.1311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2918416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin DE, Milsom I, Hunskaar S et al. Population-based survey of urinary incontinence, overactive bladder, and other lower urinary tract symptoms in five countries: results of the EPIC study. Eur Urol. 2006;50(6):1306&#x2013;14; discussion 1314&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber MD, Walters MD, Bump RC. Short forms of two condition-specific quality-of-life questionnaires for women with pelvic floor disorders (PFDI-20 and PFIQ-7). Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005;193(1):103&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2004.12.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16021067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart WF, Van Rooyen JB, Cundiff GW, et al. Prevalence and burden of overactive bladder in the United States. World J Urol. 2003;20(6):327&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00345-002-0301-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12811491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JM, Matthews CA, Conover MM, Pate V, Jonsson FM. Lifetime risk of stress urinary incontinence or pelvic organ prolapse surgery. Obstet Gynecol. 2014;123(6):1201&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000000286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24807341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4174312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher C, Feiner B, Baessler K, Schmid C. Surgical management of pelvic organ prolapse in women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;(4):CD004014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumoulin C, Hay-Smith J. Pelvic floor muscle training versus no treatment, or inactive control treatments, for urinary incontinence in women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010; (1): CD005654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford AA, Rogerson L, Cody JD, Aluko P, Ogah JA. Mid-urethral sling operations for stress urinary incontinence in women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;7(7):CD006375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28756647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamseer L, Moher D, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: elaboration and explanation. BMJ. 2015;350:g7647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g7647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25555855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gormley EA, Lightner DJ, Faraday M, Vasavada SP. Diagnosis and treatment of overactive bladder (non-neurogenic) in adults: AUA/SUFU guideline amendment. J Urol. 2015;193(5):1572&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.juro.2015.01.087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25623739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Ancona C, Haylen B, Oelke M, et al. The International Continence Society (ICS) report on the terminology for adult male lower urinary tract and pelvic floor symptoms and dysfunction. Neurourol Urodyn. 2019;38(2):433&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.23897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30681183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams P, Andersson KE, Birder L, et al. Fourth international consultation on incontinence recommendations of the international scientific committee: evaluation and treatment of urinary incontinence, pelvic organ prolapse, and fecal incontinence. Neurourol Urodyn. 2010;29(1):213&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.20870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20025020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lightner DJ, Gomelsky A, Souter L, Vasavada SP. Diagnosis and treatment of overactive bladder (non-neurogenic) in adults: AUA/SUFU guideline amendment 2019. J Urol. 2019;202(3):558&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JU.0000000000000309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman D, Vayrynen T, Engh ME, Axelsen S, Falconer C. Anterior colporrhaphy versus transvaginal mesh for pelvic-organ prolapse. N Engl J Med. 2011;364(19):1826&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1009521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21561348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter HE, Albo ME, Zyczynski HM, et al. Retropubic versus transobturator midurethral slings for stress incontinence. N Engl J Med. 2010;362(22):2066&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0912658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2962585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JM, Vaughan CP, Goode PS, et al. Prevalence and trends of symptomatic pelvic floor disorders in U.S. women. Obstet Gynecol. 2014;123(1):141&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000000057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24463674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3970401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akin Y, Young M, Elmussareh M, Charalampogiannis N, Gozen AS. The novel and minimally invasive treatment modalities for female pelvic floor muscle dysfunction; beyond the traditional. Balkan Med J. 2018;35(5):358&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4274/balkanmedj.2018.0869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29952311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6158473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Lin Y, Zhou X, Ren A, Li X. Progress in the genetics and epigenetics of pelvic floor disorder. Gene. 2025;943:149277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2025.149277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39880343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riaz H, Nadeem H, Rathore FA. Recent advances in the pelvic floor assessment and rehabilitation of women with pelvic floor dysfunction. J Pak Med Assoc. 2022;72(7):1456&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36156584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodner-Adler B, Alarab M, Ruiz-Zapata AM, Latthe P. Effectiveness of hormones in postmenopausal pelvic floor dysfunction-International Urogynecological Association research and development-committee opinion. Int Urogynecol J. 2020;31(8):1577&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-019-04070-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31392363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Yang L, Yuan J, et al. Potential therapeutic targets for pelvic organ prolapse: insights from key genes related to blood vessel development. Front Med (Lausanne). 2024;11:1435135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2024.1435135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39118664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong M<sup>#</sup>, Wang Z<sup>#</sup>, Hao Y et al. Role of the integrin-beta1/TGF-beta1 signaling pathway in the pathogenesis of pelvic organ prolapse: A study on vaginal wall tissue alterations and molecular dysfunction. Mol Med Rep. 2025;31(4).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Z, Wang X, Fu L, et al. The effect of home-based behavioural weight loss combined with pelvic floor muscle training in women seeking weight loss combined with stress urinary incontinence: protocol for a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2025;15(3):e092789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2024-092789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40147981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11956368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang C, Zeng Z, Ye J, et al. Progress of mesenchymal stem cells affecting extracellular matrix metabolism in the treatment of female stress urinary incontinence. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2025;16(1):95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13287-025-04220-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40001265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11863768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin M, Lu Y, Chen J. Tissue-engineered repair material for pelvic floor dysfunction. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2022;10:968482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2022.968482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36147522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9485870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Sima Y, Xiao C, Chen Y. Exosomes derived from mesenchymal stromal cells: a promising treatment for pelvic floor dysfunction. Hum Cell. 2023;36(3):937&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13577-023-00887-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36940057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min AP, Zeng D, Zhang RJ, et al. A cross-sectional investigation on the function of the female pelvic floor in the Sichuan Province, China. BMC Womens Health. 2025;25(1):203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-025-03720-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40275256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12023435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira AP, Janela D, Areias AC, et al. Innovating care for postmenopausal women using a digital approach for pelvic floor dysfunctions: prospective longitudinal cohort study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2025;13:e68242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/68242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40173388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12038761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>