<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41796436</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1559-7016</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cerebral blood flow and metabolism : official journal of the International Society of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cereb Blood Flow Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Microvascular network organization and hemodynamic perfusion protect the brain against hypoxia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>271678X251410034</StartPage><MedlinePgn>271678X251410034</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">0271678X251410034</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/0271678X251410034</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mechanistic simulations of blood flow and oxygen exchange showed regions of cortical tissue tolerating substantial increase in local oxygen consumption (CMRO<sub>2</sub>) before reaching hypoxia (pO<sub>2</sub>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;10&#x2009;mmHg). The observed robustness in O<sub>2</sub> supply was attributed to overcapacity in convective oxygen transport in the pial arterial network combined with a surplus in the number of capillary flow paths. Microcirculatory flux analysis suggests that <i>network</i> induced hemodynamic flow patterns impart <i>intrinsic reserve</i> to protect the brain against perfusion variances or metabolic demand surges during activation. Furthermore, oxygen transport in cortical tissue is characterized by two regimes: in the <i>transport zone-</i>centered on <i>penetrating arteriole trees</i> composed of a single penetrating vessel connected to the post-arteriole capillary transition zone-strong diffusion supports high oxygen tension with only modest contribution from capillaries. This regime transitions into the <i>terminal/reactive zone</i> where oxygenation is sensitive to capillary density and perfusion. Quasi-dynamic simulations also enabled reconstruction of the BOLD signal underlying functional imaging. Simulations at single micron resolution further show that age-related reductions in arterial saturation and systemic hematocrit were sufficient to induce hypoxic tissue pockets in the terminal zone at nominal perfusion (CBF) and metabolic activity (CMRO<sub>2</sub>), and neutrophil adhesion induced capillary flow stalling further exacerbates hypoxia.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ventimiglia</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-9951-0712</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, University of Illinois Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lesage</LastName><ForeName>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering, Polytechnique Montreal, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Linninger</LastName><ForeName>Andreas A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2694-630X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, University of Illinois Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Illinois Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cereb Blood Flow Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8112566</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0271-678X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf"><RefSource>bioRxiv. 2026 Feb 06:2026.02.03.703617. doi: 10.64898/2026.02.03.703617.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41676666</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">capillaries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropathology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurovascular unit</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41796436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12971520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0271678X251410034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Desjardins M, Berti R, Lefebvre J, et al. Aging-related differences in cerebral capillary blood flow in anesthetized rats. Neurobiol Aging 2014; 35: 1947&#x2013;1955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moeini M, Lu X, Avti PK, et al. Compromised microvascular oxygen delivery increases brain tissue vulnerability with age. Sci Rep 2018; 8: 8219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29844478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdener &#x15e; E, Tang J, K&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7; K, et al. Dynamic capillary stalls in reperfused ischemic penumbra contribute to injury: a hyperacute role for neutrophils in persistent traffic jams. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 2021; 41: 236&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8370003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32237951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Amki M, Gl&#xfc;ck C, Binder N, et al. Neutrophils obstructing brain capillaries are a major cause of no-reflow in ischemic stroke. Cell Rep; 33(2): 108260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33053341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz Hern&#xe1;ndez JC, Bracko O, Kersbergen CJ, et al. Neutrophil adhesion in brain capillaries reduces cortical blood flow and impairs memory function in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease mouse models. Nat Neurosci 2019; 22: 413&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6508667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30742116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krogh A. The number and distribution of capillaries in muscles with calculations of the oxygen pressure head necessary for supplying the tissue. J Physiol 1919; 52: 409&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1402716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16993405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crone C. The permeability of capillaries in various organs as determined by use of the &#x201c;indicator diffusion&#x201d; method. Acta Physiol Scand 1963; 58: 292&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14078649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jespersen SN, &#xd8;stergaard L. The roles of cerebral blood flow, capillary transit time heterogeneity, and oxygen tension in brain oxygenation and metabolism. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 2012; 32: 264&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3272609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22044867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linninger AA, Gould IG, Marinnan T, et al. Cerebral microcirculation and oxygen tension in the human secondary cortex. Ann Biomed Eng 2013; 41: 2264&#x2013;2284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3878164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23842693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould IG, Linninger AA. Hematocrit distribution and tissue oxygenation in large microcirculatory networks. Microcirculation 2015; 22: 1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25040825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould IG, Tsai P, Kleinfeld D, et al. The capillary bed offers the largest hemodynamic resistance to the cortical blood supply. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 2017; 37: 52&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5363755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27780904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goirand F, Le Borgne T, Lorthois S. Network-driven anomalous transport is a fundamental component of brain microvascular dysfunction. Nat Commun 2021; 12: 7295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8674232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid F, Conti G, Jenny P, et al. The severity of microstrokes depends on local vascular topology and baseline perfusion. Elife 2021; 10: e60208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8421069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Y, Georgakopoulou T, Van der Wijk A-E, et al. Quantification of hypoxic regions distant from occlusions in cerebral penetrating arteriole trees. PLoS Comput Biol 2022; 18: e1010166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9385041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35930591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Materne S, Possenti L, Pisani F, et al. Patient-specific microvascular computational modeling for estimating radiotherapy outcomes. Comput Biol Med 2025; 190: 110014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40132300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blinder P, Tsai PS, Kaufhold JP, et al. The cortical angiome: an interconnected vascular network with noncolumnar patterns of blood flow. Nat Neurosci 2013; 16: 889&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23749145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji X, Ferreira T, Friedman B, et al. Brain microvasculature has a common topology with local differences in geometry that match metabolic load. Neuron 2021; 109: 1168&#x2013;1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8525211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamshidi M, Ventimiglia T, Sudres P, et al. Impact of stalling events on microcirculatory hemodynamics in the aged brain. Microcirculation 2024; 31: e12845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11014774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38265175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartung G, Vesel C, Morley R, et al. Simulations of blood as a suspension predicts a depth dependent hematocrit in the circulation throughout the cerebral cortex. PLoS Comput Biol 2018; 14: e1006549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6277127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30452440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartung G, Badr S, Moeini M, et al. Voxelized simulation of cerebral oxygen perfusion elucidates hypoxia in aged mouse cortex. PLoS Comput Biol 2021; 17: 1&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7842915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33507970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventimiglia T, Linninger AA. Mesh-free high-resolution simulation of cerebrocortical oxygen supply with fast Fourier preconditioning. Int J Numer Methods Biomed Eng 2023; 39: e3735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10524481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37246333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventimiglia T, Linninger AA. A fast-Fourier preconditioned Schur complement method for the simulation of cerebrocortical oxygen supply. In: Linninger AA, Mardal KA, and Zunino P (eds) Quantitative approaches to microcirculation: mathematical models, computational methods and data analysis. Cham, Switzerland: Springer Nature, 2024, pp.103&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih AY, Blinder P, Tsai PS, et al. The smallest stroke: occlusion of one penetrating vessel leads to infarction and a cognitive deficit. Nat Neurosci 2013; 16: 55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3952571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23242312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartung G, Badr S, Mihelic S, et al. Mathematical synthesis of the cortical circulation for the whole mouse brain&#x2014;part II: microcirculatory closure. Microcirculation 2021; 28: e12687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8504684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33615601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meigel FJ, Cha P, Brenner MP, et al. Robust increase in supply by vessel dilation in globally coupled microvasculature. Phys Rev Lett 2019; 123: 228103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31868401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill AV. The possible effects of the aggregation of the molecules of haemoglobin on its dissociation curves. J Physiol 1910; 40: 4&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guibert R, Fonta C, Est&#xe8;ve F, et al. On the normalization of cerebral blood flow. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 2013; 33: 669&#x2013;672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3652705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23486290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogler S. Elements of chemical reaction engineering. 4th ed. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Pearson Education, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mughal A, Nelson MT, Hill-Eubanks D. The post-arteriole transitional zone: a specialized capillary region that regulates blood flow within the CNS microvasculature. J Physiol 2023; 601: 889&#x2013;901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9992301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36751860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
DiNuzzo M, Dienel GA, Behar KL, et al. Neurovascular coupling is optimized to compensate for the increase in proton production from nonoxidative glycolysis and glycogenolysis during brain activation and maintain homeostasis of pH, pCO<sub>2</sub>, and pO<sub>2</sub>. J Neurochem
2024; 168: 632&#x2013;662.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10628336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37150946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X-H, Chen JM, Tu T-W, et al. Simultaneous and noninvasive imaging of cerebral oxygen metabolic rate, blood flow and oxygen extraction fraction in stroke mice. Neuroimage 2013; 64: 437&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3508145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23000789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakad&#x17e;i&#x107; S, Mandeville ET, Gagnon L, et al. Large arteriolar component of oxygen delivery implies a safe margin of oxygen supply to cerebral tissue. Nat Commun 2014; 5: 5734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4260810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25483924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intaglietta M, Johnson PC, Winslow RM. Microvascular and tissue oxygen distribution. Cardiovasc Res 1996; 32: 632&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8915182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann DA, Coelho-Santos V, Shih AY. Pericyte control of blood flow across microvascular zones in the central nervous system. Annu Rev Physiol 2022; 84: 331&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10480047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longden TA, Zhao G, Hariharan A, et al. Pericytes and the control of blood flow in brain and heart. Annu Rev Physiol 2023; 85: 137&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10280497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36763972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Davis CM, Zeppenfeld DM, et al. Role of endothelium-pericyte signaling in capillary blood flow response to neuronal activity. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 2021; 41: 1873&#x2013;1885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8327110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33853406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buxton R. Interpreting oxygenation-based neuroimaging signals: the importance and the challenge of understanding brain oxygen metabolism. Front Neuroenergetics 2010; 2: 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2899519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20616882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reina-De La Torre F, Rodriguez-Baeza A, Sahuquillo-Barris J. Morphological characteristics and distribution pattern of the arterial vessels in human cerebral cortex: a scanning electron microscope study. Anat Rec 1998; 251: 87&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9605225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>