<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41851762</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2090-2735</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2026</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pregnancy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pregnancy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inadequate Gestational Weight Gain and Associated Factors Among Pregnant Women in Gamo Zone Public Hospitals, South Ethiopia: A Facility-Based Cross-Sectional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e7453325</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e7453325</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/jp/7453325</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Globally, inadequate gestational weight gain is a significant public health problem. It may lead to poor pregnancy outcomes. It is associated with the development of a small for gestational age fetus, prematurity, and low birthweight. It is grave trouble in middle- and low-income countries like Ethiopia. However, evidence is scarce on the magnitude of inadequate gestational weight gain and associated factors in our country, particularly in the study area. Hence, this study is aimed at assessing inadequate gestational weight gain and associated factors among pregnant women in Gamo zone public hospitals in South Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A facility-based cross-sectional study was conducted from February 01, 2024, to March 30, 2024, among systematically selected 373 pregnant women. The data were collected by using a structured interviewer-administered questionnaire, patient record review, and physical measurements. A binary logistic regression model was used to assess the association between dependent and independent variables. A p&#x2009;value &lt; 0.05 with its 95% confidence interval (CI) was considered statistically significant and interpreted accordingly.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The magnitudes of inadequate gestational weight gain were 53.1% (95% CI: 48%, 58.4%). First ANC visit after 8 weeks of gestational age (adjusted&#x2009;odds&#x2009;ratio&#x2009;(AOR) = 1.79; 95% CI: 1.02, 3.14), unable to read and write (AOR = 2.86; 95% CI: 1.37, 5.98), and primigravidity (AOR = 2.86; 95% CI: 1.37, 5.98) were the significant predictors of inadequate gestational weight gain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The findings of this study revealed that more than half of pregnant women still gain inadequate weight, and it has complex relationships with various factors, including women's education, primigravidity, and gestational age at first ANC contact. Therefore, a comprehensive approach is needed that considers the interplay of these various factors to effectively address the issue of inadequate gestational weight gain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Simegn Wagaye Kefene et al. Journal of Pregnancy published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kefene</LastName><ForeName>Simegn Wagaye</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Arba Minch College of Health Sciences, Arba Minch, Ethiopia, amu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merid</LastName><ForeName>Fasika</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Arba Minch College of Health Sciences, Arba Minch, Ethiopia, amu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hailu</LastName><ForeName>Rahel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Arba Minch College of Health Sciences, Arba Minch, Ethiopia, amu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alula</LastName><ForeName>Rahel Abera</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Arba Minch College of Health Sciences, Arba Minch, Ethiopia, amu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tesfaye</LastName><ForeName>Selamnesh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Arba Minch College of Health Sciences, Arba Minch, Ethiopia, amu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guyo</LastName><ForeName>Tamirat Gezahegn</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7084-3570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Arba Minch College of Health Sciences, Arba Minch, Ethiopia, amu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regional Data Management Center, South Ethiopia Region Health Bureau Public Health Institute, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Pregnancy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101553823</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-2727</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078064" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gestational Weight Gain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006779" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals, Public</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011295" MajorTopicYN="N">Prenatal Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011248" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pregnancy Complications</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005865" MajorTopicYN="N">Gestational Age</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">South Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inadequate gestational weight gain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">public hospitals</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41851762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/jp/7453325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kac G., Carrillo T., Rasmussen K., and Del Rosso J., What We Know About Weight Gain During Pregnancy in Low and Middle Income Countries, 2022, Alive &amp; Thrive, Technical brief https://www.aliveandthrive.org/sites/default/files/technical_brief_gestational_weight_gain_v15mdcit.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Technical Report, The Use and Interpretation of Anthropometry, 1995, World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RasmussenK. M. and YaktineA. L., Weight Gain During Pregnancy: Reexamining the Guidelines, 2009, National Academies Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Hortelano J. A., Cavero-Redondo I., Alvarez-Bueno C., Garrido-Miguel M., Soriano-Cano A., and Martinez-Vizcaino V., Monitoring Gestational Weight Gain and Prepregnancy BMI using the 2009 IOM Guidelines in the Global Population: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis, BMC Pregnancy and Childbirth. (2020) 20, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12884-020-03335-7, 33109112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33109112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebremedhin S. and Bekele T., Gestational Weight Gain in Sub-Saharan Africa: Estimation Based on Pseudo-Cohort Design, PLoS One. (2021) 16, no. 5, e0252247, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0252247, 34038488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34038488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Wang M., Darling A. M., Perumal N., Liu E., Danaei G., and Fawzi W. W., Gestational Weight Gain in Low-Income and Middle-Income Countries: A Modelling Analysis Using Nationally Representative Data, Health. (2020) 5, no. 11, https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjgh-2020-003423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asefa F., Cummins A., Dessie Y., Hayen A., and Foureur M., Gestational Weight Gain and Its Effect on Birth Outcomes in Sub-Saharan Africa: Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis, PLoS One. (2020) 15, no. 4, e0231889, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0231889, 32324783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32324783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson J. L., Farr S. L., Dietz P. M., Sharma A. J., Barfield W. D., and Robbins C. L., Trends in Gestational Weight Gain: The Pregnancy Risk Assessment Monitoring System, 2000-2009, American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology. (2015) 212, no. 6, 806.e1&#x2013;806.e8, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajog.2015.01.030, 2-s2.0-84931574978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asefa F., Cummins A., Dessie Y., Foureur M., and Hayen A., Patterns and Predictors of Gestational Weight Gain in Addis Ababa, Central Ethiopia: A Prospective Cohort Study, Reproductive Health.(2021) 18, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12978-021-01202-y, 34321037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34321037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asefa F. and Nemomsa D., Gestational Weight Gain and Its Associated Factors in Harari Regional State: Institution Based Cross-Sectional Study, Eastern Ethiopia, Reproductive Health. (2016) 13, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12978-016-0225-x, 2-s2.0-84984783704, 27576539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27576539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engidaw M. T., Gebremariam A. D., Abate B. A., Tesfa D., Tiruneh S. A., Addisu Y., and Belachew Y. Y., Magnitude and Factors Associated With Gestational Weight Gain Adequacy Among Pregnant Women in South Gondar Zone, Northwest Ethiopia, Current Developments in Nutrition.(2023) 7, no. 12, 102031, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cdnut.2023.102031, 38162997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38162997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed T., Hossain M., and Sanin K. I., Global Burden of Maternal and Child Undernutrition and Micronutrient Deficiencies, Annals of Nutrition &amp; Metabolism. (2013) 61, no. Suppl 1, 8&#x2013;17, https://doi.org/10.1159/000345165, 2-s2.0-84879487482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frederick I. O., Williams M. A., Sales A. E., Martin D. P., and Killien M., Pre-Pregnancy Body Mass Index, Gestational Weight Gain, and Other Maternal Characteristics in Relation to Infant Birth Weight, Maternal and Child Health Journal.(2008) 12, no. 5, 557&#x2013;567, 17713848, https://doi.org/10.1007/s10995-007-0276-2, 2-s2.0-53749086325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17713848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel R. M., Short- and Long-Term Outcomes for Extremely Preterm Infants, American Journal of Perinatology. (2016) 33, no. 3, 318&#x2013;328, https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0035-1571202, 2-s2.0-84959159025, 26799967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26799967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lertbunnaphong T., Talungjit P., and Titapant V., Does Gestational Weight Gain in Normal Pre-Pregnancy BMI Pregnant Women Reflect Fetal Weight Gain?, Journal of the Medical Association of Thailand.(2012) 95, no. 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darling A. M., Wang D., Perumal N., Liu E., Wang M., Ahmed T., Christian P., Dewey K. G., Kac G., Kennedy S. H., Subramoney V., Briggs B., Fawzi W. W., and Members of the GWG Pooling Project Consortium, Risk Factors for Inadequate and Excessive Gestational Weight Gain in 25 Low- and Middle-Income Countries: An Individual-Level Participant Meta-Analysis, PLoS Medicine.(2023) 20, no. 7, e1004236, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1004236, 37486938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37486938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH, WHO Recommendations on Antenatal Care for a Positive Pregnancy Experience: Summary: Highlights and Key Messages From the World Health Organization&#x2032;s 2016 Global Recommendations for Routine Antenatal Care, 2018, World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel J. P., Habib N. A., Souza J. P., G&#xfc;lmezoglu A. M., Dowswell T., Carroli G., Baaqeel H. S., Lumbiganon P., Piaggio G., and Oladapo O. T., Antenatal Care Packages With Reduced Visits and Perinatal Mortality: A Secondary Analysis of the WHO Antenatal Care Trial, Reproductive Health.(2013) 10, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/1742-4755-10-19, 2-s2.0-84876900366.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health, Ethiopian National Antenatal Care Guideline, 2022, Available from: http://repository.iphce.org/bitstream/handle/123456789/1647/ANC-GUIDELINE_Feb-24-2022.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department Gzh, Annual HMIS Report of Gamo Zone Health Breaue, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arimond M., Ballard T. J., Deitchler M., Kennedy G., and Martin-Pr&#xe9;vel Y., Minimum Dietary Diversity for Women: A Guide for Measurement, 2016, FAO.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutstein S. O., Steps to Constructing the New DHS Wealth Index, 2015, ICF International.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH, Global Physical Activity Questionnaire (GPAQ) Analysis Guide, 2012, World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coates J. S. A. and Bilinsky P., Household Food Insecurity Access Scale (HFIAS) for Measurement of Food Access: Indicator Guide, 2007, Food and Nutrition Technical Assistance.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee on Nutritional Status During Pregnancy, Nutrition During Pregnancy: Part I: Weight Gain, Part II: Nutrient Supplements, 1990, National Academies Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Research Council, Weight Gain During Pregnancy: Reexamining the Guidelines, 2009, National Academies Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoyama S., Haruna M., Yonezawa K., Tahara-Sasagawa E., Usui Y., Ohori R., Tanaka M., Fujita M., Matsuzaki M., Suetsugu Y., Sato Y., and Takeuchi A., Factors Associated With Inadequate Gestational Weight Gain: A Prospective Multicenter Cohort Study, Nursing &amp; Health Sciences.(2025) 27, no. 1, e70047, https://doi.org/10.1111/nhs.70047, 39914995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39914995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyene G. A., Yunus M. A., Deribew A. B., and Kasahun A. W., Gestational Weight Gain and Its Determinants Among Pregnant Women in Gurage Zone, Central Ethiopia: A Cohort Study, BMC Women&#x2032;s Health.(2024) 24, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12905-024-03223-8, 38937766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38937766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi H., Lim J.-Y., Lim N.-K., Ryu H. M., Kwak D. W., Chung J. H., Park H. J., and Park H. Y., Impact of Pre-Pregnancy Body Mass Index and Gestational Weight Gain on the Risk of Maternal and Infant Pregnancy Complications in Korean Women, International Journal of Obesity.(2022) 46, no. 1, 59&#x2013;67, https://doi.org/10.1038/s41366-021-00946-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edi M., Chin Y. S., Woon F. C., Appannah G., Lim P. Y., and MICOS Research Group, Inadequate Gestational Weight Gain and Exposure to Second-Hand Smoke During Pregnancy Increase the Risk of Low Birth Weight: A Cross-Sectional Study Among Full-Term Infants, International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health.(2021) 18, no. 3, https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18031068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halle-Ekane G., Nsom J., Atashili J., Palle J., Nsagha D., Nguefack C., and Njotang P. N., Outcome of Pregnancy in Patients With Excessive Gestational Weight Gain in Two District Hospitals in Douala, Cameroon, 2015, SM Journal of Gynecology and Obstetrics.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen T. and Lv Y., Inadequate Gestational Weight Gain and Adverse Pregnancy Outcomes Among Normal Weight Women in China, International Journal of Clinical and Experimental Medicine.(2015) 8, no. 2, 2881&#x2013;2886, 25932249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25932249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Wang M., Tobias D. K., Rich-Edwards J. W., Darling A. M., Abioye A. I., Pembe A. B., Madzorera I., and Fawzi W. W., Gestational Weight Gain During the Second and Third Trimesters and Adverse Pregnancy Outcomes, Results From a Prospective Pregnancy Cohort in Urban Tanzania, Reproductive Health. (2022) 19, no. 1, https://doi.org/10.1186/s12978-022-01441-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terfassa T. G., Wirtu D., and Egata G., Gestational Weight Gain and Its Determinants Among Pregnant Women Attending Antenatal Care at West Shawa Hospitals, Oromia, Ethiopia, PLoS One. (2025) 20, no. 6, e0323725, https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0323725, 40489558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40489558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development of Global Gestational Weight Gain Standards [Internet], [cited December 9, 2025]. Available from: https://www.who.int/teams/nutrition-and-food-safety/development-of-global-gestational-weight-gain-standards.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>