<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41731007</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Insights from spatial Markov chain and dynamic QCA into the spatiotemporal evolution and configurational pathways of eco-efficiency in China's coastal megaregions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10277</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40460-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">As critical zones subject to intensive human activities and significant environmental pressures, coastal megaregions require differentiated improvements in ecological efficiency (EE) to advance sustainable development. Adopting an institutional logics perspective, this study examines China&#x2019;s five major national coastal city clusters and develops a triple-dimensional framework integrating &#x201c;government&#x2013;market&#x2013;technology&#x201d; forces to enhance EE. By innovatively combining a spatial Markov chain model with dynamic qualitative comparative analysis (QCA), we investigate the dynamic evolution of EE and the spatiotemporal heterogeneity of its configuration pathways. The results indicate that: (1) EE in coastal megaregions exhibited fluctuating growth, with the Pearl River Delta and the West Coast Straits regions consistently leading. The number of high-efficiency cities increased annually, showing a clear pattern of spatial agglomeration. (2) Latitudinally, EE displayed a south-high-north-low gradient with a central trough; longitudinally, it followed a persistent U-shaped distribution. (3) EE demonstrated significant path dependency and club convergence, which constrain short-term rapid improvement. However, spatial spillover effects from adjacent areas facilitated dynamic transitions and gradient leaps. (4) High EE is not determined by any single factor but arises from the synergistic interaction of multiple conditions, manifested through three dominant configuration paths: market-dominated, government&#x2013;market dual-driven, and market&#x2013;technology dual-driven. The explanatory power of these pathways strengthens over time, exhibiting pronounced spatial imbalance and geographic dependence within city clusters. This study extends the theoretical framework for promoting EE and offers practical insights for optimizing ecological governance in coastal megaregions, thereby supporting the acceleration of sustainable development goals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-40460-3.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di</LastName><ForeName>Jiao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Business school, Economics Faculty, Liaoning University, Jingshen Street 58, Daoyi Economic Development Zone, Shenyang, 110136, Liaoning, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yuewei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Business school, Economics Faculty, Liaoning University, Jingshen Street 58, Daoyi Economic Development Zone, Shenyang, 110136, Liaoning, China. yueweiwang@lnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Business school, Economics Faculty, Liaoning University, Jingshen Street 58, Daoyi Economic Development Zone, Shenyang, 110136, Liaoning, China. yueweiwang@lnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Configuration pathways</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ecological efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Institutional logics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatio-temporal evolution</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41731007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13031267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40460-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40460-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tian, K. et al. Measurement and Spatiotemporal dynamic evolution of regional ecological efficiency in China from the perspective of undesirable outputs. <i>Econ. Anal. Policy</i>. <b>86</b>, 1897&#x2013;1913 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eap.2025.05.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, J., Ding, R., Zhu, Y., Peng, L. &amp; Jiang, S. Urban eco-efficiency of china: Spatial evolution, network characteristics, and influencing factors. <i>Ecol. Indic.</i><b>167</b>, 112641 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2024.112641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaltegger, S. &amp; Sturm, A. &#xd6;kologische Rationalit&#xe4;t: ansatzpunkte Zur ausgestaltung von &#xf6;kologieorientierten managementinstrumenten. <i>Die Unternehmung</i>. <b>44</b> (4), 273&#x2013;290 (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, F. Y., Fang, C. L. &amp; Lin, X. Q. Evaluation of eco-efficiency of four major urban agglomerations in Eastern coastal area of China. <i>Acta Geogr. Sin</i>. <b>72</b> (11), 2047&#x2013;2063 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boroushaki, M. &amp; Olsen, T. L. Beyond green: navigating the economic and environmental dynamics of eco-efficiency in agriculture. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>512</b>, 145629 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, X., Zhou, H. &amp; Gao, J. Enhancing renewable energy productivity and energy efficiency of energy projects: how does cost of capital influence? <i>Energy Strategy Rev.</i><b>57</b>, 101608 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esr.2024.101608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satrovic, E., Onifade, S. T. &amp; Haouas, I. Synthesizing eco-efficiency within eu&#x2019;s inclusive finance: do environmental policy stringency and renewable energy make a difference? <i>Energy</i><b>325</b>, 136045 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2025.136045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., An, L. &amp; Chen, H. Spillover effects and influencing factors of tourism eco-efficiency for sustainable development: A case study of cities in the Yangtze river delta. <i>Sustain. Dev.</i><b>32</b> (6), 6201&#x2013;6214 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sd.2969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;ssling, S. et al. The eco-efficiency of tourism. <i>Ecol. Econ.</i><b>54</b> (4), 417&#x2013;434 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolecon.2004.10.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molinos-Senante, M., Maziotis, A. &amp; Sala-Garrido, R. Estimating the eco-efficiency of urban waste services towards sustainable waste management. <i>Sustain. Dev.</i><b>32</b> (5), 5677&#x2013;5691 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sd.2983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, M. &amp; Nie, Y. Impact of marine ranching demonstration areas on regional ecological efficiency&#x2014;trial evidence based on the SCM. <i>Mar. Pollut Bull.</i><b>205</b>, 116636 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.116636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38964189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, H. et al. Urbanization and urban energy eco-efficiency: a meta-frontier super EBM analysis based on 271 cities of China. <i>Sustain. Cities Soc.</i><b>101</b>, 105089 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2023.105089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, D. F., Hao, S., Sun, C. Z. &amp; Lv, L. T. Spatio-temporal pattern evolution of eco-efficiency and the forecast in Mainland of China. <i>Geogr. Res.</i><b>37</b> (5), 1034&#x2013;1046 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W. &amp; Yang, Y. Spatial-temporal differentiation characteristics and driving factors of china&#x2019;s energy eco-efficiency based on geographical detector model. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>434</b>, 140153 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.140153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha, L. et al. Regional eco-efficiency evaluation and Spatial pattern analysis of the Yangtze river economic zone. <i>J. Geogr. Sci.</i><b>30</b> (7), 1117&#x2013;1139 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11442-020-1773-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai, A., Li, Z., Hu, X. &amp; Wang, Q. Does digital economy improve city-level eco-efficiency in china? <i>Econ. Anal. Policy</i>. <b>81</b>, 1198&#x2013;1213 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eap.2024.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, L., Yao, Y. &amp; Xu, K. Can environmental regulation improve the industrial ecology efficiency? Evidence from china&#x2019;s environmental protection tax reform. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>373</b>, 123792 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39754804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, H., Jiang, L., Pan, X. &amp; Pan, X. Green technology innovation spillover effect and urban eco-efficiency convergence: evidence from Chinese cities. <i>Energy Econ.</i><b>114</b>, 106307 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eneco.2022.106307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, B. &amp; Zhu, J. Impact of energy saving and emission reduction policy on urban sustainable development: empirical evidence from China. <i>Appl. Energy</i>. <b>239</b>, 12&#x2013;22 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.01.166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Q., Zhang, R. P. &amp; Gao, L. H. Can environmental policies improve marine ecological efficiency? Examining china&#x2019;s ecological civilization pilot zones. <i>Mar. Pollut Bull.</i><b>203</b>, 116479 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marpolbul.2024.116479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38744049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oude Essink, G. H. P. Improving fresh groundwater supply&#x2014;problems and solutions. <i>Ocean. Coast Manage.</i><b>44</b> (5), 429&#x2013;449 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0964-5691(01)00057-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Zhao, L. &amp; Wang, Y. An empirical correlation mechanism of economic growth and marine pollution: A case study of 11 coastal provinces and cities in China. <i>Ocean. Coast Manage.</i><b>198</b>, 105380 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ocecoaman.2020.105380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alford, R. R. &amp; Friedland, R. <i>Powers of Theory: Capitalism, the State, and Democracy</i> (Cambridge University Press, 1985).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. &amp; Ji, X. M. Dual-scale evaluation for High-quality development of marine tourism in China and its configuration path. <i>Econ. Geogr.</i><b>45</b> (1), 214&#x2013;224 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, N. T. T., Nguyen, P. V., Vrontis, D. &amp; Vo, N. T. T. Enhancing organizational sustainable performance through green innovation: the roles of knowledge application, government policy, and green market orientation. <i>J. Knowl. Manage.</i><b>29</b> (3), 870&#x2013;890 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JKM-06-2024-0688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. R., Wang, Z. T. &amp; Wang, Y. F. Green technology Innovation, industrial Agglomeration,and the development of green economy. <i>Econ. Probl.</i><b>4</b>, 101&#x2013;110 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, F., Zhang, L. J. &amp; Zhao, J. Multiple paths of agricultural green total factor productivity improvement from the perspective of institutional grouping: A panel data analysis based on dynamic QCA. <i>Chin. Rural Econ.</i><b>2</b>, 44&#x2013;66 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Xu, H., Li, H. &amp; Xu, Y. Environmental regulation, opening up to the outside world, and regional green industry development: policy effects and optimization strategies. <i>Financ Res. Lett.</i><b>75</b>, 106837 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.frl.2025.106837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, W. D. &amp; Wang, F. A. Configurational exploration of how institutional pressures affect local governments&#x2019; environmental governance Performance&#x2014; A longtitudinal QCA on Prefecture-Level cities. <i>Chin. Public. Adm.</i><b>1</b>, 28&#x2013;42 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. S., Deng, F. &amp; Yuan, B. S. Peer effects of corporate green transformation: competition mechanism and learning mechanism. <i>Chin. Popul. Resour. Environ.</i><b>35</b> (1), 111&#x2013;123 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo, C., Mao, Y. &amp; Rong, J. Policy dividend or policy trap? Environmental welfare of Establishing free trade zone in China. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>756</b>, 143856 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.143856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33280866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, X. X., Wang, A. P. &amp; Hu, H. F. Green investor and corporate green innovation: from the perspective ofinstitutional investor attention. <i>Stud. Int. Financ</i>. <b>2</b>, 85&#x2013;96 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, S., Ge, L. M. &amp; Zhu, J. L. How to achieve the harmony between humanity and nature:environmental regulation and environmental welfare performance fromthe perspective of geographical factors. <i>J. Manage. World</i>. <b>40</b> (8), 119&#x2013;146 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, W. Y., Yan, W. F., Zhu, W. &amp; Ma, Y. Y. Digital economy, technological innovation and eco-efficiency: evidence from panel data from 30 provinces and cities in China. <i>China Soft Sci.</i><b>2</b>, 181&#x2013;195 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Q., Wang, S., Ma, X. &amp; Xu, W. Digital technologies and corporate green innovation: opening the black box of resource orchestration mechanisms. <i>Sustain. Acc. Manag Policy J.</i><b>15</b> (4), 884&#x2013;912 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan, C., Li, X., Peng, B. &amp; Li, X. Unlocking urban ecological resilience: the dual role of environmental regulation and green technology innovation. <i>Sustain. Cities Soc.</i><b>128</b>, 106466 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2025.106466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z. J. &amp; Gao, Y. P. Local government environmental protection concern and corporate green sustainable innovation levels. <i>Syst. Eng. -Theory Pract.</i><b>45</b> (01), 17&#x2013;35 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. P. &amp; Chen, S. Y. Financial Development, environmental regulations and green economic transition. <i>J. Financ Econ.</i><b>47</b> (11), 78&#x2013;93 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, C., Shi, C., Wang, S. &amp; Zhang, G. Estimation of eco-efficiency and its influencing factors in Guangdong Province based on Super-SBM and panel regression models. <i>Ecol. Indic.</i><b>86</b>, 67&#x2013;80 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2017.12.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y., Tong, Z., Wang, Z., Xu, Z. &amp; Yao, Y. Evolutionary characteristics and influencing mechanisms of green development efficiency in Chinese urban agglomerations: analysis of the Yangtze river delta urban agglomeration. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>375</b>, 124236 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39862813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. H. &amp; Yuan, Q. J. Do public environmental concerns promote the development of green finance? Empirical evidence from 284 cities in china? <i>J. Audit Econ.</i><b>39</b> (3), 107&#x2013;116 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, C. C. &amp; Lee, C. C. How does green finance affect green total factor productivity? Evidence from China. <i>Energy Econ.</i><b>107</b>, 105863 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eneco.2022.105863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, F., Zhu, P., Qiu, C. Z. &amp; Wang, X. R. The impact of digital technology innovation on enterprise market value. <i>J. Quant. Technol. Econ.</i><b>40</b> (5), 68&#x2013;91 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, T., Cheng, H. S., Zhao, W., Liu, W. L. &amp; Zhang, Y. J. Research on the impact of green innovation on firm Performanc. <i>Syst. Eng. -Theory Pract.</i><b>45</b> (06), 1812&#x2013;1827 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>TONE, K. An epsilon-based measure of efficiency in DEA-a third pole of technical efficiency. <i>Eur. J. Oper. Res.</i><b>207</b> (3), 1554&#x2013;1563. 10.1016/j.ejor.2010.07.014 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejor.2010.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. J., Gao, S., Huang, Y. Y. &amp; Shi, C. Y. Spatio-temporal evolution and trend prediction of urban carbon emission performance in China based on super-efficiency SBM model. <i>Acta Geogr. Sin</i>. <b>75</b> (6), 1316&#x2013;1330 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. Y., Di, J. &amp; Du, J. Coordination effect and dynamic response of outdoor sports tourism network attention and tourism economic connection in china&#x2019;s Yangtze river delta. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 35689. 10.1038/s41598-025-19647-7 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-19647-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12518599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41083572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rey, S. J. Spatial empirics for economic growth and convergence. <i>Geogr. Anal.</i><b>33</b> (3), 195&#x2013;214 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1538-4632.2001.tb00444.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furnari, S. et al. Capturing causal complexity: heuristics for configurational theorizing. <i>Acad. Manage. Rev.</i><b>46</b> (4), 778&#x2013;799 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amr.2019.0298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beynon, M. J., Jones, P. &amp; Pickernell, D. Country-level entrepreneurial attitudes and activity through the years: A panel data analysis using FsQCA. <i>J. Bus. Res.</i><b>115</b>, 443&#x2013;455 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbusres.2019.11.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, L. Q. &amp; Liu, G. M. Does central environmental protection inspection promote corporate green governance? <i>Financ Trade Res.</i><b>35</b> (12), 92&#x2013;106 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiss, P. C. Building better causal theories: a fuzzy set approach to typologies in organization research. <i>Acad. Manage. J.</i><b>54</b>, 393&#x2013;420 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5465/amj.2011.60263120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRECKHAMER T. CEO compensation in relation to worker compensation across countries: the configurational impact of country-level institutions. <i>Strat Mgmt J.</i><b>37</b> (4), 793&#x2013;815. 10.1002/smj.2370 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smj.2370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro, R. G. &amp; Ari&#xf1;o, M. A. A general approach to panel data Set-Theoretic research. <i>J. Adv. Manage. Sci. Inf. Syst.</i><b>2</b>, 63&#x2013;76 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, Y. J., Liu, H. B. &amp; Jiang, X. H. Research on the typology-fit patterns of research institutions and international collaboration modalities: a configurational analysis based on fsQCA. <i>Sci. Sci. Manage. S.&amp;T.</i> 1&#x2013;23. Advance online publication (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greckhamer, T., Furnari, S., Fiss, P. C. &amp; Aguilera, R. V. Studying configurations with qualitative comparative analysis: best practices in strategy and organization research. <i>Strat Organ.</i><b>16</b> (4), 482&#x2013;495 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1476127018786487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, B. &amp; Wang, S. Opening up, international trade, and green technology progress. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>142</b>, 1002&#x2013;1012 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.08.145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J., Zhang, L. &amp; Dong, Z. Exploring the effect of green finance on green development of china&#x2019;s energy-intensive industry&#x2014;A Spatial econometric analysis. <i>Resour. Environ. Sustain.</i><b>16</b>, 100159 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, J. J. &amp; Fang, Y. Green Credit, financing structure and corporate environmental investment. <i>J. World Econ.</i><b>45</b> (8), 57&#x2013;80 (2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>