<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41858938</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular mechanism of silver nanoparticles inhibiting primary root growth of <i>Oryza sativa</i> L.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15187</StartPage><EndPage>15203</EndPage><MedlinePgn>15187-15203</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5ra05319f</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Elucidating the phytotoxicity of silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) at the primary tissue level is essential for a comprehensive assessment of their ecotoxicological risks. This study systematically investigated the phytotoxic mechanisms of polyethyleneimine-coated silver nanoparticles (AgNPs@PEI) on plant primary roots using rice (<i>Oryza sativa</i> L.) primary roots as an experimental model through integrated physiological, transcriptomic, and metabolomic analyses. Exposure to AgNPs@PEI induced concentration-dependent growth inhibition, with a 10 mg L<sup>-1</sup> treatment causing a 44% reduction in root length, a 50% decrease in biomass, and a 28.3% shortening of the root meristematic zone, accompanied by abnormal root hair development and cap detachment. Physiological assessments revealed significant disturbances in root vitality and antioxidant enzyme activities (SOD, POD, and CAT). Transcriptomic profiling identified significant downregulation (fold change &gt; 2) of genes involved in nine key metabolic pathways, most notably phenylpropanoid biosynthesis, aromatic amino acid (phenylalanine/tyrosine/tryptophan) biosynthesis, and glutathione metabolism. Metabolomic analysis revealed concomitant disruptions in seven essential pathways, particularly those involved in unsaturated fatty acid biosynthesis. These transcriptomic and metabolic alterations collectively impaired cell wall lignification through suppression of the phenylpropanoid pathway and compromised membrane integrity <i>via</i> dysregulation of fatty acid metabolism. This research elucidates the phytotoxic effects of AgNPs from a primary plant tissue perspective, providing novel evidence for understanding nanomaterial-plant interactions at the tissue level.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Jiajia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science, Shanxi Normal University Taiyuan 030031 China zzfsx2012@126.com +(86)-0351 2051196.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ruihua</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science, Shanxi Normal University Taiyuan 030031 China zzfsx2012@126.com +(86)-0351 2051196.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Huan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science, Shanxi Normal University Taiyuan 030031 China zzfsx2012@126.com +(86)-0351 2051196.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ruonan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science, Shanxi Normal University Taiyuan 030031 China zzfsx2012@126.com +(86)-0351 2051196.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhifeng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8997-6349</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science, Shanxi Normal University Taiyuan 030031 China zzfsx2012@126.com +(86)-0351 2051196.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41858938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12997423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5ra05319f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5ra05319f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Johnston K. A. Diemler N. A. Cooper V. S. Millstone J. E. Haig S. J. Gilbertson L. M. Role of bacterial motility in differential resistance mechanisms of silver nanoparticles and silver ions. Nat. Nanotechnol. 2021;16:996&#x2013;1003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34155383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budhani S. Egboluche N. P. Arslan Z. Yu H. Deng H. Phytotoxic effect of silver nanoparticles on seed germination and growth of terrestrial plants. J. Environ. Sci. Health. 2019;37:330&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7773158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31661365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L. Sun J. Lin L. Fu Y. Alenius H. Lindsey K. Chen C. Silver nanoparticles regulate Arabidopsis root growth by concentration-dependent modification of reactive oxygen species accumulation and cell division. Ecotox. Environ. Safe. 2019;190:110072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31864120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yekeen T. A. Azeez M. A. Akinboro A. Lateef A. Asafa T. B. Oladipo I. C. Oladokun S. O. Ajibola A. A. Safety evaluation of green synthesized Cola nitida pod, seed and seed shell extract-mediated silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) using an Allium cepa assay. J. Taibah. Univ. Sci. 2018;11:895&#x2013;909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L. Colman B. P. Mcgill B. M. Wright J. P. Bernhardt E. S. Effects of Silver Nanoparticle Exposure on Germination and Early Growth of Eleven Wetland Plants. PlosOne. 2012;7:e47674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3473015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23091638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzajani F. Askari H. Hamzelou S. Farzaneh M. Ghassempour A. Effect of silver nanoparticles on Oryza sativa L and its rhizosphere bacteria. Ecotox. Environ. Safe. 2013;88:48&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23174269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lequeux H. Hermans C. Lutts S. Verbruggen N. Response tocopper excess in Arabidopsis thaliana: Impact on the root system architecture, hormone distribution, ligninaccumulation and mineral profile. Plant. Physiol. Biochem. 2010;48:673&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20542443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke M. Qu Q. Peijnenburg W. J. G. M. Li X. Zhang M. Zhang Z. Lu T. Pan X. L. Qian H. Phytotoxic effects of silver nanoparticles and silver ions to Arabidopsis thaliana as revealed by analysis of molecular responses and of metabolic pathways. Sci. Total. Environ. 2018;644:1070&#x2013;1079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30743820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair P. M. G. Chung I. M. Physiological and molecular level studies on the toxicity of silver nanoparticles in germinating seedlings of mung bean (Vigna radiata L.) Acta. Physiol. Plant. 2015;37:1719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui M. Ma C. Tang X. Yang J. Jiang F. Pan Y. Xiang Z. Hao Y. Rui Y. Cao W. Xing B. Phytotoxicity of Silver Nanoparticles to Peanut (Arachis hypogaea L.): physiological responses and food safety. ACS. Sustainable. Chem. Eng. 2017;5:6557&#x2013;6567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqi K. S. Husen A. Plant response to silver nanoparticles: a critical review. Crit. Rev. Biotechnol. 2022;42:973&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A. Q. Long Z. Q. Xiao Y. Feng Y. M. Zhou Y. Yang S. Liao Y. M. Zhou X. Liu L. W. Wu Z. B. Yang S. Application of natural product-based quorum sensinginhibitors in plant pathogen control: A review. Arab. J. Chem. 2024;18:106050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdallah O. M. Sedky Y. Shebl H. R. Comprehensive evaluation of the antibacterialand antibiofilm activities of NiTi orthodontic wires coated with silver nanoparticles and nanocomposites: an in vitro study. BMC. Oral. Health. 2024;24:1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11539822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39501221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balciunaitiene A. Januskevice V. Saunoriute S. Raubyte U. Viskelis J. Memvanga P. B. Viskelis P. Antimicrobial Antioxidant Polymer Films with Green Silver Nanoparticles from Symphyti radix. Polymers. 2024;16:317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10857429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y. Sun Q. Liu P. Fan W. Fan B. Antibacterial Property and Mechanisms of Au@Ag Core-Shell Nanoparticles with Near-Infrared Absorption Against E. faecalis Infection of Dentin. Int. J. Nanomed. 2024;19:6981&#x2013;6997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11246666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39005961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In&#xe1;cio V. Santos R. Prazeres R. Gra&#xe7;a J. Miguel C. M. Morais-Cec&#xed;lio L. Epigenetics at the crossroads of secondary growth regulation. Front. Plant. Sci. 2022;13:970342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9389228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35991449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X. P. Ma C. X. Sun L. R. Hao F. S. Roles and mechanisms of Ca2+ in regulating primary root growth of plants. Plant. Signaling. Behav. 2020;15:1748283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32264747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan S. H. Huang Z. H. Liu H. F. Zhang X. F. Hua W. Fu Z. W. Sucrose mediates moderate salinity-promoted primary root growth in rapeseed. Plant. Physiol. Biochem. 2025;227:110133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40513362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W. W. Zhou X. Tang W. X. Takahashi K. Pan X. Dai J. W. Ren H. Zhu X. Y. Pan S. Q. Zheng H. Y. Gray W. M. Xu T. D. Kinoshita T. Yang Z. B. Tmk-based cell-surface auxin signalling activates cell-wall acidification. Nature. 2021;599:278&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8549421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34707287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada M. Han X. Benfey P. N. RGF1 controls root meristem size through ROS signalling. Nature. 2020;577:85&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6930331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31801996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberto D. Ramel F. Sulmon C. Gouesbet G. Cou&#xe9;e I. Differential effects of root-level exposure to triazine xenobiotics on root development plasticity in Arabidopsis thaliana. Acta. Physiol. Plant. 2022;44:111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L. Zhang P. Liu F. Ju Q. Xu J. Molecular and genetic analyses revealed the phytotoxicity of perfluorobutane sulfonate. Environ. Int. 2022;170:107646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36410239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berners-Lee M. Kennelly C. Watson R. Hewitt C. N. Current global food production is sufficient to meet human nutritional needs in 2050 provided there is radical societal adaptation. Elem. Sci. Anth. 2018;6:52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S. Wang P. T. Yamaji N. Ma J. F. Plant Nutrition for Human Nutrition: Hints from Rice Research and Future Perspectives. Mol. Plant. 2020;13:825&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J. J. Duan H. Y. Wang X. Y. Zhang H. Zhang Z. F. Effects of rice root exudates on aggregation, dissolution and bioaccumulation of differently-charged Ag nanoparticles. RSC Adv. 2022;12:9435&#x2013;9444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8985187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35424848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee W. M. Kwak J. I. An Y. J. Effect of silver nanoparticles in crop plants phaseolus radiatus and sorghum bicolor: media effect on phytotoxicity. Chemosphere. 2012;86:491&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22075051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q. Q. Xu W. Liu G. L. Song M. Y. Tan Z. Q. Mao Y. X. Yin Y. G. Cai Y. Liu J. F. Jiang G. B. Transformation and uptake of silver nanoparticles and silver ions in rice plant (Oryza sativa L.): the effect of iron plaque and dissolved iron. Environ. Sci. Nano. 2020;7:599&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W. Y. Wang Q. Li M. Dang F. Zhou D. M. Nonselective uptake of silver and gold nanoparticles by wheat. Nanotoxicology. 2019;13:1073&#x2013;1086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31271319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalman J. Paul K. B. Khan F. R. Stone V. Fernandes T. F. Characterisation of bioaccumulation dynamics of three differently coated silver nanoparticles and aqueous silver in a simple freshwater food chain. Environ. Chem. 2015;12:662&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R. G. Xu N. Yu B. Wu Q. Li X. X. Wang G. Huang J. L. The WUSCHEL-related homeobox transcription factor OsWOX4 controls the primary root elongation by activating OsAUX1 in rice. Plant Sci. 2020;298:110575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32771139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacyn Baker C. Mock N. M. An improved method for monitoring cell death in cell suspension and leaf disc assays using evans blue. Plant. Cell. Tissue. Organ. Cult. 1994;39:7&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idrees I. Razzaq A. Zafar M. Umer A. Mustafa F. Rehman F. Kim W. Y. Silver (Ag) doped graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) photocatalyst for enhanced degradation of Ciprofloxacin (CIP) under visible light irradiation. Arab. J. Chem. 2024;17:105615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacyn Baker C. Mock N. M. An improved method for monitoring cell death in cell suspension and leaf disc assays using evans blue. Plant. Cell. Tissue. Organ. Cult. 1994;39:7&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X. Chen Y. Liu W. Huang T. Yang Y. Mao Y. Meng Y. Combined transcriptomics and metabolomics to analyse the response of Cuminum cyminum L. under Pb stress. Sci. Total. Environ. 2024;923:171497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38453091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. F. Chen H. J. Wu W. M. Pang W. T. Yan G. Q. Efficient removal of Alizarin Red s from aqueous solution by polyethyleneimine functionalized magnetic carbon nanotubes. Bioresour. Technol. 2019;293:122100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31518817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen C. P. King G. Plocher M. Storm M. Pokhrel L. R. Johnson M. G. Rygiewicz P. T. Germination and early plant development of ten plant species exposed to titanium dioxide and cerium oxide nanoparticles. Environ. Toxicol. Chem. 2016;35:2223&#x2013;2229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26773270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skiba E. Pietrzak M. Gapi&#x144;ska M. Wolf W. M. Metal Homeostasis and Gas Exchange Dynamics in Pisum sativum L. Exposed to Cerium Oxide Nanoparticles. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2020;21:8497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7696629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33187383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G. Gao Q. Nyande A. Dong Z. Khan E. H. Han Y. Wu H. Cerium oxide nanoparticles promoted lateral root formation in Arabidopsis by modulating reactive oxygen species and Ca 2+ level. Funct. Plant. Biol. 2024;51:24196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39365897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A. Hussein A. M. Altalbawy F. M. A. Kaur M. Kaur H. Jalal S. S. Hassan Zain Al-Abdeen S. Muzammil K. Alhadrawi M. Synthesis of g-C3N4 decorated with ZIF-8 and CuFe2O4 as a highly efficient and magnetically separable photocatalystfor degradation of tetracycline. Arab. J. Chem. 2024;17:105912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M. Seth K. Choudhary S. Kumawat G. Nigam S. Joshi G. Saharan V. Meena M. Harish A. K. G. Toxicity evaluation of iron oxide nanoparticles to freshwater cyanobacteria nostoc ellipsosporum. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2023;30:55742&#x2013;55755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36905545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar H. Ali A. Zia M. CuO Nanoparticles Inhibited Root Growth from Brassica nigra Seedlings but Induced Root from Stem and Leaf Explants. Appl. Biochem. Biotech. 2017;181:365&#x2013;378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27562818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee W. M. An Y. J. Yoon H. Kweon H. S. Toxicity and bioavailability of copper nanoparticles to the terrestrial plants mung bean (Phaseolus radiatus) and wheat (Triticumaestivum): plant agar test for water-insoluble nanoparticles. Environ. Toxicol. Chem. 2008;27:1915&#x2013;1921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19086317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W. Su B. Song H. Zhang X. Ren G. Wang X. Yan L. Ma S. Li L. Guo L. Xu S. Zhang B. Diao H. Wu Z. Li S. Zhang C. Photothermal-triggered release of alkyl radicals hydrogel via versatile carbon dots chelating Ag+ and its synergistic anti-bacterial and biofilm activities. Arab. J. Chem. 2024;17:105755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercado-D&#xed;az de Le&#xf3;n L. Garcidue&#xf1;as-Pi&#xf1;a C. P&#xe9;rez-Molphe-Balch E. Loera-Muro A. Morales-Dom&#xed;nguez J. F. Effect of BvAgNP on growth, development, and glyoxalase gene expression analysis in Mammillaria bombycina and Selenicereus undatus, Mol. Biol. Rep. 2024;51:681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38796603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G. Pan M. Song J. Guo M. Xu L. Xin Y. Investigating the effects of biocharcolloids and nanoparticles on cucumber early seedlings. Sci. Total. Environ. 2022;804:150233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34520920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park M. G. Kim Y. N. Lee J. s. Kim Y. J. Kim S. Y. Choi S. Yang M. H. Kwon B. O. Rho J. R. Jeong E. J. Variations in metabolites content and bioactivity to regulate biomarkers of benign prostatic hyperplasia according to the growth stages of Sida rhombifolia. Arab. J. Chem. 2025;18:106071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payamifar S. Abdouss M. Marjani-Arabian A. P. The application of magnetic nanoparticles based &#x3b2;-cyclodextrin as recoverable catalyst in various organic transformations: An overview. Arab. J. Chem. 2025;18:106080.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plokhovska S. Fuente-Gonz&#xe1;lez E. Gutierrez-Albanchez E. Gutierrez-Ma&#xf1;ero F. J. Ramos-Solano B. AgNPs biosynthesized from Pseudomonas Z9.3 metabolites as antimicrobial agents against bacterial and fungal pathogens. Front. Microbiol. 2025;16:1565689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12009911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40260084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed A. M. M. Cao G. P. Al-Fatesh A. S. Alreshaidan S. B. Ali N. Shehu M. S. Yan J. Y. Highly efficient platinum nano-particles decorated multi-walled carbon nanotubes (Pt/MWCNTs) catalyst for catalytic hydrogenation of styrene&#x2013;butadiene&#x2013;styrene (SBS)copolymer. Arab. J. Chem. 2024;17:105983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S. L. Zhang Y. X. Liu H. Z. Xin H. Phytotoxicity of copper oxide nanoparticles to metabolic activity in the roots of rice. Acta. Sci. Circumstantiae. 2014;35:1968&#x2013;1973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25055694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C. Yu Y. Liu H. Xin H. Effect of different copper oxide particles on cell division and related genes of soybean roots. Plant. Physiol. Biochem. 2021;163:205&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33862500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S. Akhtar N. Rehman S. U. Shujah S. Rha E. S. Jamil M. Bacillus subtilis Synthesized Iron Oxide Nanoparticles (Fe3O4 NPs) Induced Metabolic and Anti-Oxidative Response in Rice (Oryza sativa L.) under Arsenic Stress. Toxics. 2022;10:618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9606974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36287898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitzschke A. Forzani C. Hirt H. Reactive oxygen species signaling in plants. Antioxid. Redox Signal. 2006;8:1757&#x2013;1764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16987029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debnath P. Mondal A. Sen K. Mishra D. Mondal N. K. Genotoxicity study of nano Al2O3, TiO2 and ZnO along with UV-B exposure: An Allium cepa root tip assay. Sci. Total. Environ. 2020;713:136592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31955093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza L. R. R. Bernardes L. E. Barbetta M. F. S. Da Veiga M. A. M. S. Iron oxide nanoparticle phytotoxicity to the aquatic plant Lemna minor: effect on reactive oxygen species (ROS) production and chlorophyll a/chlorophyll b ratio. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2019;26:24121&#x2013;24131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31228067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Garrido I. P&#xe9;rez S. Blasco J. Toxicity of silver and gold nanoparticles on marine microalgae. Mar. Environ. Res. 2015;111:60&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26002248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaveh R. Li Y. S. Ranjbar S. Tehrani R. Brueck C. L. Aken B. V. Changes in arabidopsis thaliana gene expression in response to silver nanoparticles and silver ions. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2013;47:10637&#x2013;10644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23962165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baghkheirati E. K. Lee J. G. Gene Expression, Protein Function and Pathways of Arabidopsis thaliana Responding to Silver Nanoparticles in Comparison to Silver Ions, Cold, Salt, Drought, and Heat. Nanomaterials. 2015;5:436&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5312895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28347022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amist N. Singh N. B. Yadav K. Singh S. C. Pandey J. K. Comparative studies ofAl3+ ions and Al2O3 nanoparticles on growth and metabolism of cabbage seedlings. J. Biotechnol. 2017;254:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28602792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanik F. Vardar F. Toxic Effects of Aluminum Oxide (Al2O3) Nanoparticles on Root Growth and Development in Triticum aestivum. Water Air Soil Poll. 2015;226:296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musgrave W. B. Yi H. Kline D. Cameron J. C. Wignes J. Dey S. Pakrasi H. B. Jez J. M. Probing the origins of glutathione biosynthesis through biochemical analysis ofglutamate-cysteine ligase and glutathione synthetase from a model photosynthetic prokaryote. Biochem. J. 2012;450:63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23170977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Est&#xe9;vez I. H. Hern&#xe1;ndez M. R. Plant glutathione S-transferases: An overview. Plant Gene. 2020;23:100233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J. H. Jiang H. W. Hsieh E. J. Chen H. Y. Chien C. T. Hsieh H. L. Lin T. P. Drought and salt stress tolerance of an Arabidopsis glutathione S-transferase U17 knockout mutant are attributed to the combined effect of glutathione and abscisic acid. Plant. Physiol. 2011;158:340&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3252094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22095046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha B. Sharma A. Mishra A. Expression of SbGSTU (tau class glutathione S-transferase) gene isolated from Salicornia brachiata in tobacco for salt tolerance. Mol. Biol. Rep. 2010;38:4823&#x2013;4832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21136169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diao G. Wang Y. Wang C. Yang C. Cloning and Functional Characterization of a Novel Glutathione S-Transferase Gene from Limonium bicolor. Plant. Mol. Biol. Rep. 2010;29:77&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai J. Li H. Gao S. Sun H. Zhao C. Yu D. Lin X. Cheng S. Li J. Corrigendum to &#x201c;Palladium nanocubes-mediated Fenton catalysis combined with chloride ion-amplified electro-driven catalysis for dye degradation&#x201d;. Arab. J. Chem. 2024;18:106087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanzinger A. Frank T. Reichenberger G. Herz M. Engel K. H. Metabolite profiling of barley grain subjected to induced drought stress: responses of free amino acids in differently adapted cultivars. J. Agr. Food. Chem. 2015;63:4252&#x2013;4261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25867895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zemanov&#xe1; V. Pavl&#xed;k M. Pavl&#xed;kov&#xe1; D. Tlusto P. The significance of methionine, histidine and tryptophan in plant responses and adaptation to cadmium stress. Plant. Soil. Environ. 2014;60:426&#x2013;432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoghlami L. B. Djebali W. Abbes Z. Hediji H. Maucourt M. Moing A. Brouquisse R. Chaibi W. Metabolitemodifications in Solanum lycopersicum roots and leaves under cadmium stress. Afr. J. Biotechnol. 2011;10:567&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J. Wang L. Li S. Yin L. Huang J. Chen C. Toxicity of silver nanoparticles to Arabidopsis: Inhibition of root gravitropism by interfering with auxin pathway. Environ. Toxicol. Chem. 2017;36:2773&#x2013;2780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28440569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan C. C. Chung T. Y. Wu H. Y. Juo Y. A. Hsieh M. H. Exogenous glutamate rapidly induces the expression of genes involved in metabolism and defense responses in rice roots. BMC Genomics. 2017;18:186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5316172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28212609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T. H. Kim E. C. Kim S. W. Lee H. S. Choi D. W. ExogenousGlutamate Inhibits the Root Growth and Increases the Glutamine Content in Arabidopsis thaliana. J. Integr. Plant Biol. 2009;53:45&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pia W. L. Ivanov I. I. Sophie F. Yinbo G. Tony R. Briang F. Nitrogen Regulation of Root Branching. Ann. Bot. 2006;97:875&#x2013;881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2803407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinoan C. M. Katas H. Sustainable production and antibacterial efficacy of silver nanoparticles on cellulose nanofibers from mushroom waste. RSC Adv. 2025;15:19726&#x2013;19740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12152727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40503294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S. H. Ahn S. J. Im Y. J. Cho K. Chung G. C. Cho B. H. Han O. Differential impact of low temperature on fatty acid unsaturation and lipoxygenase activity in figleaf gourd and cucumber roots. Biochem. Bioph. Res. Co. 2005;330:1194&#x2013;1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15823569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongsheree T. Ketsa S. Van Doorn W. G. Technology, The relationship between chilling injury and membrane damage in lemon basil (Ocimum &#xd7; citriodourum) leaves. Postharvest Biol. Technol. 2009;51:91&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim G. H. Singhal R. Kachroo A. Kachroo P. Fatty Acid- and Lipid-Mediated Signaling in Plant Defense. Annu. Rev. Phytopathol. 2017;55:505&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28777926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurel C. Verdoucq L. Luu D. T. Santoni V. Plant aquaporins: membrane channels with multiple integrated functions. Annu. Rev. Plant Biol. 2008;59:595&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18444909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartels D. Sunkar R. Drought and Salt Tolerance in Plants. Crit. Rev. Plant. Sci. 2005;1:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M. S. Cho S. M. Kang E. Y. Im Y. J. Hwangbo H. Kim Y. C. Ryu C. M. Yang K. Y. Chung G. C. Cho B. H. Galactinol Is a Signaling Component of the Induced Systemic Resistance Caused by Pseudomonas chlororaphis O6 Root Colonization. Mol.Plant. Microbe. In. 2008;21:1643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18986260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheller H. Ulvskov P. Hemicelluloses. Annu. Rev. Plant Biol. 2010;61:263&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20192742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franke R. H&#xf6;fer R. Briesen I. Emsermann M. Efremova N. Yephremov A. Schreiber L. The DAISY gene from Arabidopsis encodes a fatty acid elongase condensing enzyme involved in the biosynthesis of aliphatic suberin in roots and the chalaza-micropyle region of seeds. Plant J. 2009;57:80&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18786002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla V. Barberon M. Building and breaking of a barrier: Suberinplasticity and function in the endodermis. Curr. Opin. Plant Biol. 2021;64:102153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34861611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolattukudy P. E. Polyesters in Higher Plants. Biopolyesters. 2001;71:1&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11217409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollard M. Beisson F. Li Y. H. Ohlrogge J. B. Building lipid barriers: biosynthesis of cutin and suberin. Trends. Plant. Sci. 2008;13:236&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18440267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;fer R. Briesen I. Beck M. Pinot F. Schreiber L. Franke R. The Arabidopsis cytochromeP450 CYP86A1 encodes a fatty acid &#x3c9;-hydroxylase involved in suberin monomer biosynthesis. J. Exp. Bot. 2008;59:2347&#x2013;2360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2423664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18544608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Silva N. D. G. Murmu J. Chabot D. Hubbard K. Ryser P. Molina I. Rowland O. Root Suberin Plays Important Roles in Reducing Water Loss and Sodium Uptake in Arabidopsis thaliana. Metabolites. 2021;11:735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8618449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34822393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soler M. Serra O. Molinas M. Huguet G. Fluch S. Figueras M. A Genomic Approach to Suberin Biosynthesis and Cork Differentiation. Plant. Physiol. 2007;144:419&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1913797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17351057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;fer R. Briesen I. Beck M. Pinot F. Schreiber L. Franke R. The Arabidopsis cytochrome P450 CYP86A1 encodes a fatty acid omega-hydroxylase involved in suberin monomer biosynthesis. J. Exp. Bot. 2008;59:2347&#x2013;2360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2423664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18544608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng W. Sun Z. Liu Y. Zhou Q. Zhang Y. Qiu Y. Fu H. Zou H. Pu H. Xue W. Design and research of new virulence factor inhibitors for plant bacterial disease control. Arab. J. Chem. 2024;17:106042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albright C. D. Friedrich C. B. Brown E. C. Mar M. H. Zeisel S. H. Maternal dietary choline availability alters mitosis, apoptosis and the localization of TOAD-64 protein in the developing fetal rat septum. Dev. Brain. Res. 1999;115:123&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10407130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabdullkarem E. A. Khan J. Dual-function g-C3N4 anchored Cu&#x2013;ZnS hybrid nanostructures for sustainable energy storage and environmental remediation. RSC Adv. 2025;15:23801&#x2013;23818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12236335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40630698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;usler R. E. Ludewig F. Krueger S. Amino acids&#x2013;A life between metabolism and signaling. Plant Sci. 2014;229:225&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25443849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wipf D. Ludewig U. Tegeder M. Rentsch D. Koch W. Frommer W. B. Conservation of amino acid transporters in fungi, plants and animals. Trends. Biochem. Sci. 2002;27:139&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11893511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G. S. Ji Y. Y. Bhuiyan N. H. Pilot G. Selvaraj G. Zou J. Wei Y. D. Amino acid homeostasis modulates salicylic acid-associated redox status and defense responses in Arabidopsis. Plant Cell. 2010;22:3845&#x2013;3863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3015111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21097712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S. S. Dietz K. J. The significance of amino acids and amino acid-derived molecules in plant responses and adaptation to heavy metal stress. J. Exp. Bot. 2006;57:711&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16473893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das B. Padhiary A. Behera S. Mishra S. Jena M. Swain S. Rout S. Biochemical Changes in Some Rice Varieties in Response to Waterlogged and Submerged Conditions. Energy. Environ. Sci. 2017;5:972&#x2013;978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moukhtari A. E. Cabassa-Hourton C. Farissi M. Savour&#xe9; A. How DoesProline Treatment Promote Salt Stress Tolerance During Crop Plant Development. Front. Plant. Sci. 2020;11:1127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32793273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinnersley A. M. Turano F. Gamma Aminobutyric Acid (GABA) and Plant Responses to Stress. Crit. Rev. Plant Sci. 2000;19:479&#x2013;509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C. T. Slocum R. D. Biochemistry, Expression and functional analysis of aspartate transcarbamoylase and role of de novo pyrimidine synthesis in regulation of growth and development in Arabidopsis. Plant Physiol. Biochem. 2008;46:150&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18053734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katahira R. Ashihara H. Dual function of pyrimidine metabolism in potato(Solanum tuberosum) plants: pyrimidine salvage and supply of &#x3b2;-alanine to pantothenic acid synthesis. Physiol. Plantarum. 2006;127:38&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stasolla C. Katahira R. Thorpe T. A. Ashihara H. Purine and pyrimidine nucleotide metabolism in higher plants. J. Plant Physiol. 2003;160:1271&#x2013;1295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14658380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>