<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41674675</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-8153</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental science. Nano</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Sci Nano</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Atomic-scale structure of gadolinium in nanocrystalline fluorapatite from marine sediments.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1004</StartPage><EndPage>1016</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1004-1016</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d5en01056j</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Deep-sea sediments hold large quantities of critical rare earth-elements and yttrium (REY) sequestered in nanoparticulate biogenic fluorapatite (Ca<sub>5</sub>(CO<sub>3</sub>) <sub><i>x</i></sub> (PO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>3-<i>x</i></sub> F<sub>1+<i>x</i></sub> ). Understanding their enrichment processes and improving recovery and mineral processing methods require atomic-scale information about their chemical form, but it is difficult to obtain. Here, we use novel high-energy-resolution fluorescence-detected extended X-ray absorption fine structure (HERFD-EXAFS) spectroscopy to elucidate the local structure of gadolinium (Gd) in the highly enriched REY deposit from the Clarion-Clipperton fracture zone (CCFZ) in the Pacific Ocean. Our findings reveal that Gd is neither incorporated into the apatite structure nor precipitated alongside Ce in a Ce-PO<sub>4</sub> precipitate. Instead, it is bound at short-range distances to Ca and PO<sub>4</sub> in a defective apatite-type bonding environment within an amorphous matrix that encases fluorapatite nanocrystals. Density functional theory (DFT) suggests that Gd and Y, whose atomic fraction is ten times higher than that of Gd, are not dispersed throughout the amorphous matrix, but are likely segregated at medium-range distances. The entrapment of Ce, Gd, and Y within an amorphous matrix explains, at the microscopic level, why REY can be easily recovered through straightforward acid leaching. This is due to the intrinsic instability of disordered atomic structures compared to crystalline phases. This research highlights the complementarity of HERFD-EXAFS and DFT calculations for atomic-scale analysis of trace elements in complex natural matrices. It establishes a basis for their use across diverse terrestrial and marine materials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manceau</LastName><ForeName>Alain</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0845-611X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Synchrotron Radiation Facility (ESRF) 38043 Grenoble France alain.manceau@esrf.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENS de Lyon, CNRS, Laboratoire de Chimie 69342 Lyon France alain.manceau@ens-lyon.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giacomelli</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-2115-6164</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENS de Lyon, CNRS, Laboratoire de Chimie 69342 Lyon France alain.manceau@ens-lyon.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8456-0352</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Synchrotron Radiation Facility (ESRF) 38043 Grenoble France alain.manceau@esrf.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaillot</LastName><ForeName>Anne-Claire</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2694-6756</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nantes Universit&#xe9;, CNRS, Institut des Mat&#xe9;riaux de Nantes Jean Rouxel, IMN 44000 Nantes France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Jianlin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5504-3487</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Synchrotron Radiation Facility (ESRF) 38043 Grenoble France alain.manceau@esrf.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spadini</LastName><ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Grenoble Alpes, CNRS, Institut des G&#xe9;osciences de l'Environnement 38000 Grenoble France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simionovici</LastName><ForeName>Alexandre</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5349-6482</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Grenoble Alpes, CNRS, ISTerre 38000 Grenoble France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koschinsky</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9224-0663</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Science, Department of Physics and Earth Sciences, Constructor University D-28759 Bremen Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathon</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Synchrotron Radiation Facility (ESRF) 38043 Grenoble France alain.manceau@esrf.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steinmann</LastName><ForeName>Stephan N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2777-356X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENS de Lyon, CNRS, Laboratoire de Chimie 69342 Lyon France alain.manceau@ens-lyon.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Sci Nano</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101624843</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41674675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12888085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d5en01056j</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d5en01056j</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Caravan P. Ellison J. J. McMurry T. J. Lauffer R. B. Gadolinium(III) chelates as MRI contrast agents: Structure, dynamics, and applications. Chem. Rev. 1999;99:2293&#x2013;2352. doi: 10.1021/cr980440x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/cr980440x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11749483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A. Bahl C. R. H. Bjork R. Engelbrecht K. Nielsen K. K. Pryds N. Materials Challenges for High Performance Magnetocaloric Refrigeration Devices. Adv. Energy Mater. 2012;2:1288&#x2013;1318. doi: 10.1002/aenm.201200167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.201200167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumazert J. Coulon R. Lecomte Q. Bertrand G. H. V. Hamel M. Gadolinium for neutron detection in current nuclear instrumentation research: A review. Nucl. Instrum. Methods Phys. Res., Sect. A. 2018;882:53&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1016/j.nima.2017.11.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nima.2017.11.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrowski T. Neutron shielding evaluation of concretes and mortars: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;277:122238. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.122238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.122238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K. B. Ma L. T. Yang C. Bian Z. Y. Zhang D. D. Cui S. Wang M. L. Chen Z. Li X. F. Recent Progress in Gd-Containing Materials for Neutron Shielding Applications: A Review. Materials. 2023;16:4305. doi: 10.3390/ma16124305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16124305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10303270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37374489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C. Kynicky J. Smith M. P. Kopriva A. Brtnicky M. Urubek T. Yang Y. Zhao Z. He C. Wenlei S. Origin of heavy rare earth mineralization in South China. Nat. Commun. 2017;8:14598. doi: 10.1038/ncomms14598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms14598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5321793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28220784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moldoveanu G. A. Papangelakis G. V. An overview of rare-earth recovery by ion-exchange leaching from ion-adsorption clays of various origins. Mineral. Mag. 2016;80:63&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1180/minmag.2016.080.051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1180/minmag.2016.080.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borst A. M. Smith M. P. Finch A. A. Estrade G. Villanova-de-Benavent C. Nason P. Marquis E. Horsburgh N. J. Goodenough K. M. Xu C. Kynicky J. Geraki K. Adsorption of rare earth elements in regolith-hosted clay deposits. Nat. Commun. 2020;11:4386. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-17801-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-17801-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7463018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32873784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodenough K. M. Wall F. Merriman D. The Rare Earth Elements: Demand, Global Resources, and Challenges for Resourcing Future Generations. Nat. Resour. Res. 2018;27:201&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G. F. Zhu J. X. Liang X. L. Ling B. W. Xu J. Yang Y. Q. Kang S. C. Tan W. Xu Y. J. Zou X. S. Ran L. Y. Wei J. M. He H. P. Industrial-scale sustainable rare earth mining enabled by electrokinetics. Nat. Sustain. 2025;8:182&#x2013;189. doi: 10.1038/s41893-024-01501-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41893-024-01501-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato Y. Fujinaga K. Nakamura K. Takaya Y. Kitamura K. Ohta J. Toda R. Nakashima T. Iwamori H. Deep-sea mud in the Pacific Ocean as a potential resource for rare-earth elements. Nat. Geosci. 2011;4:535&#x2013;539. doi: 10.1038/ngeo1185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ngeo1185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takaya Y. Yasukawa K. Kawasaki T. Fujinaga K. Ohta J. Usui Y. Nakamura K. Kimura J. I. Chang Q. Hamada M. Dodbiba G. Nozaki T. Iijima K. Morisawa T. Kuwahara T. Ishida Y. Ichimura T. Kitazume M. Fujita T. Kato Y. The tremendous potential of deep-sea mud as a source of rare-earth elements. Sci. Rep. 2018;8:5763. doi: 10.1038/s41598-018-23948-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-23948-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5893572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29636486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi D. Shi X. Huang M. Yu M. Zhou T. Zhang Y. Zhu A. Shi M. Fang X. Geochemical and mineralogical characteristics of deep-sea sediments from the western North Pacific Ocean: Constraints on the enrichment processes of rare earth elements. Ore Geol. Rev. 2021;138:104318. doi: 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2021.104318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2021.104318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T. C. Shi X. F. Huang M. Yu M. Bi D. J. Ren X. W. Liu J. H. Zhu A. M. Fang X. S. Shi M. U. Genesis of REY-rich deep-sea sediments in the Tiki Basin, eastern South Pacific Ocean: Evidence from geochemistry, mineralogy and isotope systematics. Ore Geol. Rev. 2021;138:104330. doi: 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2021.104330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2021.104330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T. C. Shi X. F. Huang M. Yu M. Bi D. J. Ren X. W. Yang G. Zhu A. M. The Influence of Hydrothermal Fluids on the REY-Rich Deep-Sea Sediments in the Yupanqui Basin, Eastern South Pacific Ocean: Constraints from Bulk Sediment Geochemistry and Mineralogical Characteristics. Minerals. 2020;10:1141. doi: 10.3390/min10121141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min10121141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta J. Yasukawa K. Machida S. Fujinaga K. Nakamura K. Takaya Y. Iijima K. Suzuki K. Kato Y. Geological factors responsible for REY-rich mud in the western North Pacific Ocean: Implications from mineralogy and grain size distributions. Geochem. J. 2016;50:591&#x2013;603. doi: 10.2343/geochemj.2.0435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2343/geochemj.2.0435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J. L. Sun X. M. Li D. F. Sa R. N. Lu Y. Lin Z. Xu L. Zhan R. Z. Pan Y. G. Xu H. F. New insights into nanostructure and geochemistry of bioapatite in REE-rich deep-sea sediments: LA-ICP-MS, TEM, and Z-contrast imaging studies. Chem. Geol. 2019;512:58&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1016/j.chemgeo.2019.02.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemgeo.2019.02.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J. L. Chen J. Y. Sun X. M. Wu Z. W. Deng Y. A. Shi X. F. Wang Y. J. Y. Chen Y. Koschinsky A. Quantifying the controlling mineral phases of rare-earth elements in deep-sea pelagic sediments. Chem. Geol. 2022;595:120792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon Y. Hoshino M. Sanematsu K. Morita S. Tsunematsu M. Okamoto N. Yano N. Tanaka M. Takagi T. Geochemical characteristics of apatite in heavy REE-rich deep-sea mud from Minami-Torishima area, Southeastern Japan. Resour. Geol. 2014;64:47&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashiwabara T. Toda R. Nakamura K. Yasukawa K. Fujinaga K. Kubo S. Nozaki T. Takahashi Y. Suzuki K. Kato Y. Synchrotron X-ray spectroscopic perspective on the formation mechanism of REY-rich muds in the Pacific Ocean. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 2018;240:274&#x2013;292. doi: 10.1016/j.gca.2018.08.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gca.2018.08.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manceau A. Paul S. Simionovici A. Magnin V. Balvay M. Findling N. Rovezzi M. Muller S. Garbe-Schonberg D. Koschinsky A. Fossil Bioapatites with Extremely High Concentrations of Rare Earth Elements and Yttrium from Deep-Sea Pelagic Sediments. ACS Earth Space Chem. 2022;6:2093&#x2013;2103. doi: 10.1021/acsearthspacechem.2c00169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsearthspacechem.2c00169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J. Chen J. Sun X. Deng Y. Wang Y. Wang D. Hong G. Klose L. Koschinsky A. Controlling Factors on REY Enrichments in Basins From the Pacific Ocean: Early Diagenesis and Local Constraints. Geochem., Geophys., Geosyst. 2024;25:e2023GC01111. doi: 10.1029/2023GC011111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2023GC011111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan W. X. Zhou J. M. Jiang X. D. Zhang H. Mi M. Yuan P. Dong Y. H. Liu D. Wei Y. F. Peckmann J. Carbonate fluorapatite coatings on phillipsite represent a significant sink of phosphorus in abyssal plains of the western Pacific Ocean. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2025;122:e2407683122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11804476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39869794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruttenberg K. C. Berner R. A. Authigenic apatite formation and burial in sediments from non-upwelling, continental margin environments. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 1993;57:991&#x2013;1007. doi: 10.1016/0016-7037(93)90035-U.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0016-7037(93)90035-U</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J. Wang D. Sun X. M. Hong G. Deng Y. Yao W. Manceau A. Koschinsky A. Carbonate fluorapatite pellets in pelagic sediments: Implications for REY enrichment and Nd isotopic signatures in abyssal environments. Earth Planet. Sci. Lett. 2025;671:119658. doi: 10.1016/j.epsl.2025.119658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.epsl.2025.119658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashiwabara T. Toda R. Fujinaga K. Honma T. Takahashi Y. Kato Y. Determination of host phase of lanthanum in deep-sea REY-rich mud by XAFS and &#x3bc;-XRF using high-energy synchrotron radiation. Chem. Lett. 2014;43:199&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1246/cl.130853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1246/cl.130853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasukawa K. Liu H. Fujinaga K. Machida S. Haraguchi S. Ishii T. Nakamura K. Kato Y. Geochemistry and mineralogy of REY-rich mud in the eastern Indian Ocean. J. Asian Earth Sci. 2014;93:25&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.jseaes.2014.07.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2014.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sa R. N. Sun X. M. He G. W. Xu L. Pan Q. Q. Liao J. L. Zhu K. C. Deng X. G. Enrichment of rare earth elements in siliceous sediments under slow deposition: A case study of the central North Pacific. Ore Geol. Rev. 2018;94:12&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2018.01.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2018.01.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y. Zhang H. Dong Y. Wang T. Zhang W. Lu J. Zhu Z. Li X. Chu F. In-situ geochemistry of fish teeth in REE-rich mud: Indicating Missing REE-Bearing Mineral Phases for Mass Balance. Ore Geol. Rev. 2025;184:106746. doi: 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2025.106746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2025.106746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berna F. Matthews A. Weiner S. Solubilities of bone mineral from archaeological sites: the recrystallization window. J. Archaeol. Sci. 2004;31:867&#x2013;882. doi: 10.1016/j.jas.2003.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jas.2003.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antignano A. Manning C. E. Fluorapatite solubility in H2O and H2O&#x2013;NaCl at 700 to 900 &#xb0;C and 0.7 to 2.0 GPa. Chem. Geol. 2008;251:112&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1016/j.chemgeo.2008.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemgeo.2008.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha&#xef;rat C. Schott J. Oelkers E. H. Lartigue J. E. Harouiya N. Kinetics and mechanism of natural fluorapatite dissolution at 25 &#xb0;C and pH from 3 to 12. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta. 2007;71:5901&#x2013;5912. doi: 10.1016/j.gca.2007.08.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gca.2007.08.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manceau A. Gaillot A.-C. Liao J. Li Y. Mathon O. Lomachenko K. A. Glatzel P. Simionovici A. Balvay M. Paul S. A. L. Koschinsky A. Steinmann S. N. Cerium occurs as cerium-phosphate clusters around bioapatite nanocrystals in deep-sea sediments. Commun. Earth Environ. 2025;6:466. doi: 10.1038/s43247-025-02439-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43247-025-02439-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12170343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40534633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manceau A. Li Y. Giacomelli A. Gaillot A.-C. Liao J. L. Magnin V. Spadini L. Deng Y. Koschinsky A. Mathon O. Steinmann S. N. Structural Form of Yttrium in Nanocrystalline Fluorapatite from Marine Sediments at 0.11 &#xc5; Resolution. Chem. Mater. 2025;37:7939&#x2013;7951. doi: 10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c01722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.5c01722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12529902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41113091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ondrejka M. Uher P. Ferenc S. Majzlan J. Pollok K. Mikus T. Milovsk&#xe1; S. Moln&#xe1;rov&#xe1; A. Skoda R. Kop&#xe1;cik R. Kurylo S. Bacik P. Monazite-(Gd), a new Gd-dominant mineral of the monazite group from the Zimna Voda REE-U-Au quartz vein, Prakovce, Western Carpathians, Slovakia. Mineral. Mag. 2023;87:568&#x2013;574. doi: 10.1180/mgm.2023.37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1180/mgm.2023.37</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glatzel P. Weng T. C. Kvashnina K. Swarbrick J. Sikora M. Gallo E. Smolentsev N. Mori R. A. Reflections on hard X-ray photon-in/photon-out spectroscopy for electronic structure studies. J. Electron Spectrosc. Relat. Phenom. 2013;188:17&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/j.elspec.2012.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.elspec.2012.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merkulova M. Mathon O. Glatzel P. Batanova V. Marion P. Boiron M. C. Manceau A. Revealing the chemical form of &#x2018;invisible&#x2019; gold in natural arsenian pyrite and arsenopyrite with high energy-resolution X-ray absorption spectroscopy. ACS Earth Space Chem. 2019;3:1905&#x2013;1914. doi: 10.1021/acsearthspacechem.9b00099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsearthspacechem.9b00099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manceau A. Merkulova M. Mathon O. Glatzel P. Murdzek M. Batanova V. Simionovici A. Steinmann S. N. Paktunc D. The mode of incorporation of As(-I) and Se(-I) in natural pyrite revisited. ACS Earth Space Chem. 2020;4:379&#x2013;390. doi: 10.1021/acsearthspacechem.9b00301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsearthspacechem.9b00301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laskar C. Bazarkina E. F. Kokh M. A. Hazemann L. Foulon S. Leynaud O. Desmaele E. Pokrovski G. S. Exploring Platinum Speciation with X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy under High-Energy Resolution Fluorescence Detection Mode. Minerals. 2022;12:1602. doi: 10.3390/min12121602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min12121602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokrovski G. S. Desmaele E. Laskar C. Bazarkina E. F. Testemale D. Hazemann J. L. Vuilleumier R. Seitsonen A. P. Ferlat G. Saitta A. M. Gold speciation in hydrothermal fluids revealed by in situ high energy resolution X-ray absorption spectroscopy. Am. Mineral. 2022;107:369&#x2013;376. doi: 10.2138/am-2022-8008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2138/am-2022-8008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filimonova O. N. Tagirov B. R. Trigub A. L. Nickolsky M. S. Rovezzi M. Belogub E. V. Reukov V. L. Vikentyev I. V. The state of Au and As in pyrite studied by X-ray absorption spectroscopy of natural minerals and synthetic phases. Ore Geol. Rev. 2020;121:103475. doi: 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2020.103475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2020.103475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pokrovski G. S. Kokha M. A. Proux O. Hazemann J. L. Bazarkina E. F. Testemale D. Escoda C. Boiron M. C. Blanchard M. Aigouya T. Gouya S. de Perseval P. Thibauta M. The nature and partitioning of invisible gold in the pyrite-fluid system. Ore Geol. Rev. 2019;109:545&#x2013;563. doi: 10.1016/j.oregeorev.2019.04.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oregeorev.2019.04.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lender T. Murphy G. Bazarkina E. Bukaemskiy A. Gilson S. Henkes M. Hennig C. Kaspor A. Marquardt J. Niessen J. Peters L. Poonoosamy J. Rossberg A. Svitlyk V. Kvashnina K. O. Huittinen N. Investigation of Radiation Damage in the Monazite-Type Solid Solution La1&#x2212;xCexPO4. Inorg. Chem. 2024;63:17525&#x2013;17535. doi: 10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11423408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39231923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manceau A. Brossier R. Mathon O. Lomachenko K. A. Retegan M. Glatzel P. Steinmann S. N. DFT2FEFFIT: a density-functional-theory-based structural toolkit to analyze EXAFS spectra. J. Appl. Crystallogr. 2024;57:1229&#x2013;1234. doi: 10.1107/S1600576724005454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S1600576724005454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11299619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39108809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahbi S. Rosa A. Manceau A. Steinmann S. N. Prediction and Rationalization of Site Preference of Rare Earth Elements in Fluorapatite from Density Functional Theory. ACS Earth Space Chem. 2025;9:1633&#x2013;1641. doi: 10.1021/acsearthspacechem.5c00048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsearthspacechem.5c00048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George S. J. Webb S. M. Abraham J. L. Cramer S. P. Synchrotron X-ray analyses demonstrate phosphate-bound gadolinium in skin in nephrogenic systemic fibrosis. Br. J. Dermatol. 2010;163:1077&#x2013;1081. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.09918.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2010.09918.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4334379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20560953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes J. M. Cameron M. Crowley K. D. Structural variations in natural F, OH, and Cl apatites. Am. Mineral. 1989;74:870&#x2013;876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teo B. K., EXAFS: basic principles and data analysis, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, 1986</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robblee J. H. Messinger J. Cinco R. M. McFarlane K. L. Fernandez C. Pizarro S. A. Sauer K. Yachandra V. K. The Mn cluster in the S0 state of the oxygen-evolving complex of photosystem II studied by EXAFS spectroscopy:: Are there three di-&#x3bc;-oxo-bridged Mn2 moieties in the tetranuclear Mn complex? J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2002;124:7459&#x2013;7471. doi: 10.1021/ja011621a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja011621a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3960400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12071755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;ppe H. Sedlmaier S. J. Crystal structures of incommensurately modulated Ln(PO3)3 (Ln = Tb-Yb) and commensurate Gd(PO3)3 and Lu(PO3)3. Inorg. Chem. 2007;46:3467&#x2013;3474. doi: 10.1021/ic0616030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ic0616030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17411030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corno M. Busco C. Bolis V. Tosoni S. Ugliengo P. Water Adsorption on the Stoichiometric (001) and (010) Surfaces of Hydroxyapatite: A Periodic B3LYP Study. Langmuir. 2009;25:2188&#x2013;2198. doi: 10.1021/la803253k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la803253k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19161264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park C. Fenter P. Zhang Z. Cheng L. Sturchio N. C. Structure of the fluorapatite (100)-water interface by high-resolution X-ray reflectivity. Am. Mineral. 2004;89:1647&#x2013;1654. doi: 10.2138/am-2004-11-1209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2138/am-2004-11-1209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleet M. Liu X. Pan Y. Site preference of rare earth elements in hydroxyapatite [Ca10(PO4)6(OH)2] J. Solid State Chem. 2000;149:391&#x2013;398. doi: 10.1006/jssc.1999.8563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jssc.1999.8563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chehimi-Moumen F. Ben Hassen-Chehimi D. Ferid M. Trabelsi-Ayadi M. Preparation and structure of HGdP2O7&#xb7;3H2O. Mater. Res. Bull. 2001;36:365&#x2013;373. doi: 10.1016/S0025-5408(01)00514-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0025-5408(01)00514-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolten G. M. Structure of the M'-phase of YTaO4, a third fergusonite polymorph. Acta Crystallogr. 1967;23:939&#x2013;944. doi: 10.1107/S0365110X67004098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S0365110X67004098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer A. J. Cole J. M. Host-guest prospects of neodymium and gadolinium ultraphosphate frameworks for nuclear waste storage: Multi-temperature topological analysis of nanoporous cages in RP5O14. J. Solid State Chem. 2018;266:250&#x2013;257. doi: 10.1016/j.jssc.2018.07.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jssc.2018.07.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettis H. Na&#xef;li H. Mhiri T. Reinvestigation of the GdP5O14 crystal structure at room temperature and magnetic properties. Mater. Chem. Phys. 2007;102:275&#x2013;280. doi: 10.1016/j.matchemphys.2007.01.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2007.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Liviano S. Becerro A. I. Alc&#xe1;ntara D. Graz&#xfa; V. de la Fuente J. M. Oca&#xf1;a M. Synthesis and Properties of Multifunctional Tetragonal Eu:GdPO4 Nanocubes for Optical and Magnetic Resonance Imaging Applications. Inorg. Chem. 2013;52:647&#x2013;654. doi: 10.1021/ic3016996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ic3016996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23268550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni Y. Hughes J. M. Mariano A. N. Crystal chemistry of the monazite and xenotime structures. Am. Mineral. 1995;80:21&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbarek A. Graia M. Chadeyron G. Zambon D. Bouaziz J. Fourati M. Synthesis and crystal structure determination of yttrium ultraphosphate YP5O14. J. Solid State Chem. 2009;182:509&#x2013;516. doi: 10.1016/j.jssc.2008.11.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jssc.2008.11.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiuddin M. R. Tyagi C. Haq M. A. Synthesis and structural investigation of churchite-type REPO4.2H2O (RE = Y, Gd, Dy) nanocrystals. J. Solid State Chem. 2022;311:123150. doi: 10.1016/j.jssc.2022.123150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jssc.2022.123150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essehli R. El Bali B. Dusek M. Fejfarova K. Lachkar M. Yttrium hydrogendiphosphate trihydrate. Acta Crystallogr., Sect. E: Struct. Rep. Online. 2007;63:i80&#x2013;i82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullica D. F. Sappenfield E. L. Boatner L. A. A structural investigation of several mixed lanthanide orthophosphates. Inorg. Chim. Acta. 1990;174:155&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1016/S0020-1693(00)80293-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0020-1693(00)80293-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakhmouradian A. Wall F. Rare Earth Elements: Minerals, Mines, Magnets (and More) Elements. 2012;8:333&#x2013;340. doi: 10.2113/gselements.8.5.333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2113/gselements.8.5.333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkhust D. L. and Appelo C. A. J., Description of input and examples for PHREEQC version 3&#x2014;A computer program for speciation, batch-reaction, one-dimensional transport, and inverse geochemical calculations, U.S. Geological Survey Techniques and Methods, 2013, vol. 6, p. 497</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams-Jones A. Migdisov A. Samson I. Hydrothermal Mobilisation of the Rare Earth Elements &#x2013; a Tale of &#x2018;Ceria&#x2019; and &#x2018;Yttria&#x2019;. Elements. 2012;8:355&#x2013;360. doi: 10.2113/gselements.8.5.355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2113/gselements.8.5.355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeckel M. and Linke P., RV SONNE Fahrtbericht/Cruise Report SO268 &#x2013; Assessing the Impacts of Nodule Mining on the Deep-sea Environment: NoduleMonitoring, Manzanillo (Mexico) &#x2013; Vancouver (Canada), 17.02.&#x2013;27.05.2019, 2021, p. 820</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manceau A. Mathon O. Lomachenko K. A. Rovezzi M. Kvashnina K. O. Boiron M. C. Brossier R. Steinmann S. N. Revealing the incorporation of cerium in fluorapatite. ACS Earth Space Chem. 2024;8:119&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1021/acsearthspacechem.3c00274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsearthspacechem.3c00274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levinskas G. J. Neuman W. F. The solubility of bone mineral. I. Solubility studies of synthetic hydroxylapatite. J. Phys. Chem. 1955;59:164&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1021/j150524a017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j150524a017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitch A. Dejoie C. Covacci E. Confalonieri G. Grendal O. Claustre L. Guillou P. Kieffer J. de Nolf W. Petitdemange S. Ruat M. Watier Y. ID22-the high-resolution powder-diffraction beamline at ESRF. J. Synchrotron Radiat. 2023;30:1003&#x2013;1012. doi: 10.1107/S1600577523004915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S1600577523004915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10481261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lessing P. A. Erickson A. W. Synthesis and characterization of gadolinium phosphate neutron absorber. J. Eur. Ceram. Soc. 2003;23:3049&#x2013;3057. doi: 10.1016/S0955-2219(03)00100-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0955-2219(03)00100-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Moreno S. Amboage M. Basham M. Boada R. Bricknell N. E. Cibin G. Cobb T. Filik J. Freeman A. Geraki K. Gianolio D. Hayama S. Ignatyev K. Keenan L. Mikulska I. Mosselmans J. F. W. Mudd J. Parry S. A. The Spectroscopy Village at Diamond Light Source. J. Synchrotron Radiat. 2018;25:998&#x2013;1009. doi: 10.1107/S1600577518006173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S1600577518006173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6038600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29979161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayama S. Duller G. Sutter J. P. Amboage M. Boada R. Freeman A. Keenan L. Nutter B. Cahill L. Leicester P. Kemp B. Rubies N. Diaz-Moreno S. The scanning four-bounce monochromator for beamline I20 at the Diamond Light Source. J. Synchrotron Radiat. 2018;25:1556&#x2013;1564. doi: 10.1107/S1600577518008974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S1600577518008974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6140387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30179197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravel B. Newville M. ATHENA, ARTEMIS, HEPHAESTUS: data analysis for X-ray absorption spectroscopy using IFEFFIT. J. Synchrotron Radiat. 2005;12:537&#x2013;541. doi: 10.1107/S0909049505012719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S0909049505012719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15968136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ressler T. WinXAS: a program for X-ray absorption spectroscopy data analysis under MS-Windows. J. Synchrotron Radiat. 1998;5:118&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1107/S0909049597019298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S0909049597019298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16687813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ankudinov A. L. Rehr J. J. Relativistic calculations of spin-dependent X-ray-absorption spectra. Phys. Rev. B: Condens. Matter Mater. Phys. 1997;56:1712&#x2013;1716. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevB.56.R1712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.56.R1712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neese F. Software update: The ORCA program system-Version 5.0. Wiley Interdiscip. Rev.: Comput. Mol. Sci. 2022:e1606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kresse G. Ab-initio molecular-dynamics for liquid crystals. J. Non-Cryst. Solids. 1995;193:222&#x2013;229. doi: 10.1016/0022-3093(95)00355-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-3093(95)00355-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kresse G. Furthmuller J. Efficiency of ab-initio total energy calculations for metals and semiconductors using a plane-wave basis set. Comput. Mater. Sci. 1996;6:15&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/0927-0256(96)00008-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0927-0256(96)00008-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdew J. P. Burke K. Ernzerhof M. Generalized gradient approximation made simple. Phys. Rev. Lett. 1996;77:3865&#x2013;3868. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.77.3865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.77.3865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10062328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corno M. Rimola A. Bolis V. Ugliengo P. Hydroxyapatite as a key biomaterial: quantum-mechanical simulation of its surfaces in interaction with biomolecules. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2010;12:6309&#x2013;6329. doi: 10.1039/C002146F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C002146F</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20485772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canepa P. Chiatti F. Corno M. Sakhno Y. Martra G. Ugliengo P. Affinity of hydroxyapatite (001) and (010) surfaces to formic and alendronic acids: a quantum-mechanical and infrared study. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2011;13:1099&#x2013;1111. doi: 10.1039/C0CP01143F.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C0CP01143F</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21076734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corno M. Busco C. Civalleri B. Ugliengo P. Periodic ab initio study of structural and vibrational features of hexagonal hydroxyapatite Ca10(PO4)6(OH)2. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2006;8:2464&#x2013;2472. doi: 10.1039/B602419J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/B602419J</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16721430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmann S. N. Corminboeuf C. Comprehensive Benchmarking of a Density-Dependent Dispersion Correction. J. Chem. Theory Comput. 2011;7:3567&#x2013;3577. doi: 10.1021/ct200602x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ct200602x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26598255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautier S. Steinmann S. N. Michel C. Fleurat-Lessard P. Sautet P. Molecular adsorption at Pt(111). How accurate are DFT functionals? Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2015;17:28921&#x2013;28930. doi: 10.1039/C5CP04534G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5CP04534G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26455444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quemener E. Corvellec M. SIDUS&#x2014;the solution for extreme deduplication of an operating system. Linux J. 2013:235.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>