<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41816189</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2589-5370</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>93</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>EClinicalMedicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>EClinicalMedicine</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimal exercise modalities for enhancing motor function recovery after stroke: a Bayesian systematic review with pairwise and network meta-analyses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>103815</StartPage><MedlinePgn>103815</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">103815</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.eclinm.2026.103815</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to compare the effectiveness of different exercise interventions in improving motor function recovery after stroke and to identify optimal rehabilitation strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A comprehensive search of five databases was conducted for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) up to March 13, 2025. Primary outcomes included the 6-min walk test (6MWT), 10-m walk test (10MWT), Berg Balance Scale (BBS), and FMA (total, UE, LE). Pairwise and Bayesian network meta-analyses were performed to compare the relative effects of different exercise modalities. Risk of bias was assessed using the RoB 2 tool, and evidence certainty was rated using CINeMA. This systematic review was prospectively registered in PROSPERO (CRD420251091242).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 317 RCTs involving 14,464 stroke patients were included. Network meta-analysis showed that, compared with routine care, electrical stimulation plus exercise (ESX) was associated with the largest improvement in walking endurance (MD = 53.4 m, 95% CI 14.27-92.58, p &lt; 0.05, I<sup>2</sup> = 0%), while aerobic exercise (AE), functional training (FT), gait training (GT), and mind-body exercise (MBE) showed smaller effects. Lower limb training (LLT) demonstrated the greatest improvement in gait speed (MD = 0.18 m/s, 95% CI 0.14-0.23, p &lt; 0.05, I<sup>2</sup> = 0%), with TCMEX, task-oriented training (TOT), and MBE also showing benefits. For balance (BBS), core stability training (CST) ranked highest (SMD = 0.77, 95% CI 0.30-1.24, p &lt; 0.05, I<sup>2</sup> = 93.24%), followed by MBE and FT. FT showed the largest pooled effect for total FMA (SMD = 2.15, 95% CI 0.48-3.81, p &lt; 0.05, I<sup>2</sup> = 93.86%), whereas MBE showed larger pooled effects for FMA-LE (SMD = 1.94, 95% CI 0.04-3.85, p &lt; 0.05, I<sup>2</sup> = 97.54%) and FMA-UE (SMD = 1.85, 95% CI 1.08-2.63, p &lt; 0.05, I<sup>2</sup> = 95.57%). Substantial heterogeneity was observed in several pooled comparisons. Meta-regression analyses identified multiple outcome-specific clinical and contextual factors (e.g., intervention duration, stroke phase, stroke severity, routine rehabilitation, age, sex distribution, and socioeconomic setting) that partially explained between-study variability, although no single factor accounted for heterogeneity across all outcomes. Importantly, global network diagnostics indicated acceptable overall model fit and consistency, supporting cautious interpretation of the comparative estimates at the network level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Several structured exercise interventions were associated with improved motor outcomes after stroke. High heterogeneity was observed in some comparisons; however, meta-regression analyses suggested several potential sources of variability, and global network assessments indicated generally acceptable heterogeneity. These findings should therefore be interpreted cautiously, particularly for outcomes with substantial between-study variation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study received no specific funding.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Liqun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Physical Education, Myongji University, Yongin, 17058, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Huimin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Physical Education, Myongji University, Yongin, 17058, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Hyun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Leisure Studies, Graduate School, Korea University, Sejong, 02841, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chun</LastName><ForeName>Buongo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Physical Education, Myongji University, Yongin, 17058, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>EClinicalMedicine</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101733727</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2589-5370</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Balance performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gait speed</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Motor function recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Walking endurance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>All authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41816189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12972736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2026.103815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2589-5370(26)00062-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee D., Patil C.G. Epidemiology and the global burden of stroke. World Neurosurg. 2011;76(6 Suppl):S85&#x2013;S90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22182277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global, regional, and national burden of stroke and its risk factors, 1990-2019: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20(10):795&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8443449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34487721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R.-J., Chen S., Ganesh A., Hill M.D. Long-term neurological, vascular, and mortality outcomes after stroke. Int J Stroke. 2018;13(8):787&#x2013;796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30160619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley A., Medcalf P., Hellier K., Dutta D. Movement disorders after stroke. Age Ageing. 2009;38(3):260&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna C., Chen P., Barrett A.M. In: Changes in the Brain: Impact on Daily Life. Chiaravalloti N.D., Goverover Y., editors. Springer New York; New York, NY: 2017. Stroke: impact on life and daily function; pp. 87&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajsic S., Gothe H., Borba H.H., et al. Economic burden of stroke: a systematic review on post-stroke care. Eur J Health Econ. 2019;20(1):107&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29909569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Gonzalo R., Fernandez-Gonzalo S., Turon M., Prieto C., Tesch P.A., Garc&#xed;a-Carreira Mdel C. Muscle, functional and cognitive adaptations after flywheel resistance training in stroke patients: a pilot randomized controlled trial. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2016;13:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4823904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27052303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X.M., Jin X.M., Lu Y., et al. Effects of body weight support-tai Chi footwork training on balance control and walking function in stroke survivors with hemiplegia: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2020;2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7769631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moncion K., Rodrigues L., De Las Heras B., et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness benefits of high-intensity interval training after stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Stroke. 2024;55(9):2202&#x2013;2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39113181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhao W., Wan C., et al. Exoskeleton rehabilitation robot training for balance and lower limb function in sub-acute stroke patients: a pilot, randomized controlled trial. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2024;21(1):98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11162020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38851703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Yu X., Liao W., et al. Effects of body weight-supported Tai Chi Yunshou training on upper limb motor function in stroke patients: a three-arm parallel randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2025;20(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11717223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39787119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKay-Lyons M.J., Howlett J. Exercise capacity and cardiovascular adaptations to aerobic training early after stroke. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2005;12(1):31&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders D.H., Sanderson M., Hayes S., et al. Physical fitness training for stroke patients. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;3(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27010219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flansbjer U.B., Miller M., Downham D., Lexell J. Progressive resistance training after stroke: effects on muscle strength, muscle tone, gait performance and perceived participation. J Rehabil Med. 2008;40(1):42&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18176736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabanas-Vald&#xe9;s R., Bagur-Calafat C., Girabent-Farr&#xe9;s M., Caballero-G&#xf3;mez F.M., Hern&#xe1;ndez-Vali&#xf1;o M., Urr&#xfa;tia Cuch&#xed; G. The effect of additional core stability exercises on improving dynamic sitting balance and trunk control for subacute stroke patients: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2016;30(10):1024&#x2013;1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26451007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno-Segura N., Mart&#xed;n-San Agust&#xed;n R., Garc&#xed;a-Bafalluy S., Escriche-Escuder A. Effects of core training on trunk function, balance, and gait in stroke patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Clin Rehabil. 2022;36(12):1635&#x2013;1654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35892183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou L., Yeung A., Li C., et al. Effects of mind&#x2013;body movements on balance function in stroke survivors: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6025433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29925770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J., Chi J., Wang D. Effects of mind-body exercise on physical ability, mental health and quality of life in stroke patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Public Health. 2024;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11697286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39758196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flansbjer U.B., Holmb&#xe4;ck A.M., Downham D., Patten C., Lexell J. Reliability of gait performance tests in men and women with hemiparesis after stroke. J Rehabil Med. 2005;37(2):75&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera S., Mody S.H., Woodman R.C., Studenski S.A. Meaningful change and responsiveness in common physical performance measures in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2006;54(5):743&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16696738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blum L., Korner-Bitensky N. Usefulness of the Berg Balance Scale in stroke rehabilitation: a systematic review. Phys Ther. 2008;88(5):559&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18292215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladstone D.J., Danells C.J., Black S.E. The fugl-meyer assessment of motor recovery after stroke: a critical review of its measurement properties. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2002;16(3):232&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12234086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X., Gao Y., Chen X., Lu J., Dai Q., Lai J. Rehabilitative effects of Baduanjin in Chinese stroke patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Prev Med Rep. 2024;41</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11002574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38595729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazavi Dozin S.M., Mohammad Rahimi N., Aminzadeh R. Wii fit-based biofeedback rehabilitation among post-stroke patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trial. Biol Res Nurs. 2024;26(1):5&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37247514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klassen T.D., Dukelow S.P., Bayley M.T., et al. Higher doses improve walking recovery during stroke inpatient rehabilitation. Stroke. 2020;51(9):2639&#x2013;2648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders D.H., Greig C.A., Mead G.E. Physical activity and exercise after stroke: review of multiple meaningful benefits. Stroke. 2014;45(12):3742&#x2013;3747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25370588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billinger S.A., Arena R., Bernhardt J., et al. Physical activity and exercise recommendations for stroke survivors: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2014;45(8):2532&#x2013;2553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24846875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veerbeek J.M., van Wegen E., van Peppen R., et al. What is the evidence for physical therapy poststroke? A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2014;9(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24505342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panic N., Leoncini E., de Belvis G., Ricciardi W., Boccia S. Evaluation of the endorsement of the preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analysis (PRISMA) statement on the quality of published systematic review and meta-analyses. PLoS One. 2013;8(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3873291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24386151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan X., Wang W., Liu J., Tong T. Estimating the sample mean and standard deviation from the sample size, median, range and/or interquartile range. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25524443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo D., Wan X., Liu J., Tong T. Optimally estimating the sample mean from the sample size, median, mid-range, and/or mid-quartile range. Stat Methods Med Res. 2018;27(6):1785&#x2013;1805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27683581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J., Luo D., Weng H., et al. Optimally estimating the sample standard deviation from the five-number summary. Res Synth Methods. 2020;11(5):641&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VA HJTJCJCMLTPMW . The Cochrane Collaboration; London: 2022. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crozier J., Roig M., Eng J.J., et al. High-Intensity interval training after stroke: an opportunity to promote functional recovery, cardiovascular health, and neuroplasticity. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2018;32(6&#x2013;7):543&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29676956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann S.D., Willis E.A., Ainsworth B.E., et al. 2024 Adult compendium of physical activities: a third update of the energy costs of human activities. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13(1):6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38242596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compagnat M., Mandigout S., David R., Lacroix J., Daviet J.C., Salle J.Y. Compendium of physical activities strongly underestimates the oxygen cost during activities of daily living in stroke patients. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2019;98(4):299&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30358568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainsworth B.E., Haskell W.L., Herrmann S.D., et al. 2011 Compendium of physical activities: a second update of codes and MET values. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(8):1575&#x2013;1581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21681120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne J.A.C., Savovi&#x107; J., Page M.J., et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolakopoulou A., Higgins J.P.T., Papakonstantinou T., et al. CINeMA: an approach for assessing confidence in the results of a network meta-analysis. PLoS Med. 2020;17(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7122720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32243458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balduzzi S., R&#xfc;cker G., Nikolakopoulou A., et al. Netmeta: an R package for network meta-analysis using frequentist methods. J Stat Software. 2023;106(2):1&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;cker G., Schwarzer G. Reduce dimension or reduce weights? Comparing two approaches to multi-arm studies in network meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2014;33(25):4353&#x2013;4369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24942211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S., Sutton A.J., Ades A.E., Welton N.J. Evidence synthesis for decision making 2: a generalized linear modeling framework for pairwise and network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Med Decis Making. 2013;33(5):607&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3704203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efthimiou O., Debray T.P., van Valkenhoef G., et al. GetReal in network meta-analysis: a review of the methodology. Res Synth Methods. 2016;7(3):236&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26754852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Valkenhoef G., Lu G., de Brock B., Hillege H., Ades A.E., Welton N.J. Automating network meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2012;3(4):285&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26053422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J.P.T., Thompson S.G. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1539&#x2013;1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim S., Yoon B.H., Shin I.S., Bae J.M. Network meta-analysis: application and practice using Stata. Epidemiol Health. 2017;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5733388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29092392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson S.G., Higgins J.P. How should meta-regression analyses be undertaken and interpreted? Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1559&#x2013;1573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias S., Welton N.J., Caldwell D.M., Ades A.E. Checking consistency in mixed treatment comparison meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2010;29(7&#x2013;8):932&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20213715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S., Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot&#x2013;based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56(2):455&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim S.R., Kim S.J., Lee J., R&#xfc;cker G. Network meta-analysis: application and practice using R software. Epidemiol Health. 2019;41</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6635665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30999733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedder H., Dias S., Bennetts M., Boucher M., Welton N.J. Joining the dots: linking disconnected networks of evidence using dose-response model-based network meta-analysis. Med Decis Making. 2021;41(2):194&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7879230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mawdsley D., Bennetts M., Dias S., Boucher M., Welton N.J. Model-based network meta-analysis: a framework for evidence synthesis of clinical trial data. CPT Pharmacometrics Syst Pharmacol. 2016;5(8):393&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27479782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt J.A., Del Giovane C., Jackson D., et al. Incorporating dose effects in network meta-analysis. BMJ. 2022;376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7614774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35042687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . WHO Guidelines on Physical Activity and Sedentary Behaviour. World Health Organization; Geneva: 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33369898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. ggplot2. WIREs Comp Stat. 2011;3(2):180&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedder H. 2021. MBNMAdose: an R Package for Incorporating Dose-Response Information Into Network Meta-Analysis. Evidence Synthesis and Meta-Analysis in R Conference 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Doi S.A.R. The robust error meta-regression method for dose&#x2013;response meta-analysis. Int J Evid Based Healthc. 2018;16(3):138&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29251651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page M.J., McKenzie J.E., Bossuyt P.M., Boutron I., Hoffmann T.C., Mulrow C.D., et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n71. doi: 10.1136/bmj.n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee I.-H. Does the speed of the treadmill influence the training effect in people learning to walk after stroke? A double-blind randomized controlled trial. Clin Rehabil. 2015;29(3):269&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25027443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKay-Lyons M., McDonald A., Matheson J., Eskes G., Klus M.-A. Dual effects of body-weight supported treadmill training on cardiovascular fitness and walking ability early after stroke: a randomized controlled trial. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2013;27(7):644&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23599221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todhunter-Brown A., Sellers C.E., Baer G.D., et al. Physical rehabilitation approaches for the recovery of function and mobility following stroke. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2025;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39932103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapointe T., Houle J., Sia Y.-T., Payette M., Trudeau F. Addition of high-intensity interval training to a moderate intensity continuous training cardiovascular rehabilitation program after ischemic cerebrovascular disease: a randomized controlled trial. Front Neurol. 2023;13:963950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9846748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36686521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill G., Johnson F., Uy J., et al. Moderate intensity aerobic exercise may enhance neuroplasticity of the contralesional hemisphere after stroke: a randomised controlled study. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10475034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37660093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmcrantz S., Wall A., Vreede K.S., et al. Impact of intensive gait training with and without electromechanical assistance in the chronic phase after Stroke&#x2013;A multi-arm randomized controlled trial with a 6 and 12 months follow up. Front Neurosci. 2021;15:660726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8100236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33967683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jharbade M., Ramachandran S., V S., Solomon M.J. Functional training for lower extremities in stroke survivors: a scoping review. Cureus. 2024;16(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11088721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38738032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young W. Electrical stimulation and motor recovery. Cell Transplant. 2015;24(3):429&#x2013;446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25646771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipchase L.S., Schabrun S.M., Hodges P.W. Peripheral electrical stimulation to induce cortical plasticity: a systematic review of stimulus parameters. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122(3):456&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>French B., Thomas L.H., Coupe J., et al. Repetitive task training for improving functional ability after stroke. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27841442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gjellesvik T.I., Becker F., Tj&#xf8;nna A.E., et al. Effects of high-intensity interval training after stroke (The HIIT Stroke Study) on physical and cognitive function: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102(9):1683&#x2013;1691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto S., Uema T., Ikeda K., et al. Effect of underwater exercise on lower-extremity function and quality of life in post-stroke patients: a pilot controlled clinical trial. J Altern Complement Med. 2016;22(8):635&#x2013;641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27351560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H., Kim Y.L., Lee S.M. Effects of therapeutic Tai Chi on balance, gait, and quality of life in chronic stroke patients. Int J Rehabil Res. 2015;38(2):156&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25591053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green C.S., Bavelier D. Exercising your brain: a review of human brain plasticity and training-induced learning. Psychol Aging. 2008;23(4):692&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2896818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19140641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzolatti G., Fabbri-Destro M., Cattaneo L. Mirror neurons and their clinical relevance. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2009;5(1):24&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19129788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamura R., Nakashima A., Moriuchi T., et al. Effects of a virtual reality-based mirror therapy system on upper extremity rehabilitation after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Neurol. 2023;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10800725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38259644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S., Wu C.Y., Hussein R., et al. Associations between time after stroke and exercise training outcomes: a meta-regression analysis. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10(24)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9075264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dromerick A.W., Geed S., Barth J., et al. Critical Period After Stroke Study (CPASS): a phase II clinical trial testing an optimal time for motor recovery after stroke in humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021;118(39)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34544853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ada L., Dorsch S., Canning C.G. Strengthening interventions increase strength and improve activity after stroke: a systematic review. Aust J Physiother. 2006;52(4):241&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17132118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalimuthu S. Effectiveness of neurodevelopmental technique and task specific training with strengthening exercise on functional performance of lower extremities in spastic diplegia children 4-12 years. J Nov Physiother. 2018;8(5):399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laver K.E., Lange B., George S., et al. Virtual reality for stroke rehabilitation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2025;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12178777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40537150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang D.-H., Cho H.-S. Effect of body awareness training on balance and walking ability in chronic stroke patients: a randomized controlled trial. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28(1):198&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4756003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26957757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rensink M., Schuurmans M., Lindeman E., Hafsteinsd&#xf3;ttir T. Task-oriented training in rehabilitation after stroke: systematic review. J Adv Nurs. 2009;65(4):737&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Any D.A., Daniel D.A., Gogu A., Jianu C. Role of task-oriented training after stroke. Sci Mov Health. 2016;16(2):164&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm D.G., Anderson K., Curnew R.S. Muscle force and activation under stable and unstable conditions. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16(3):416&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12173956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges P.W. Core stability exercise in chronic low back pain. Orthop Clin North Am. 2003;34(2):245&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12914264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller S., Engel T., Mueller J., Stoll J., Baur H., Mayer F. Sensorimotor exercises and enhanced trunk function: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Sports Med. 2018;39(7):555&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29775985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y.M.Y., Chan M.M.Y., Choi C.X.T., Law M.C.H., Ahorsu D.K., Tsang H.W.H. The neurobiological effects of mind&#x2013;body exercise: a systematic review and meta-analysis of neuroimaging studies. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10326064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37415072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou L., Yeung A., Zeng N., et al. Effects of mind-body exercises for mood and functional capabilities in patients with stroke: an analytical review of randomized controlled trials. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15(4)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5923763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29641483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comerford M.J., Mottram S.L. Functional stability re-training: principles and strategies for managing mechanical dysfunction. Man Ther. 2001;6(1):3&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11243904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liebenson C. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2014. Functional training handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang R., Braver T.S. Towards an individual differences perspective in mindfulness training research: theoretical and empirical considerations. Front Psychol. 2020;11:818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menzies V., Taylor A.G., Bourguignon C. Absorption: an individual difference to consider in mind&#x2013;body interventions. J Holist Nurs. 2008;26(4):297&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2810559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazzarelli A., Scafuto F., Crescentini C., et al. Interoceptive ability and emotion regulation in mind&#x2013;body interventions: an integrative review. Behav Sci. 2024;14(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11591285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39594407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wookey E. Pepperdine University; 2023. A systematic review of movement-oriented mind-body interventions and psychoneuroimmunological outcomes for psychological stress and trauma.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Zong B., Zhao W., Li L. Effects of mind-body exercise on brain structure and function: a systematic review on MRI studies. Brain Sci. 2021;11(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaribeygi H., Atkin S.L., Simental-Mend&#xed;a L.E., Sahebkar A. Molecular mechanisms by which aerobic exercise induces insulin sensitivity. J Cell Physiol. 2019;234(8):12385&#x2013;12392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30605232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahl M.P., Scalzo R.L., Regensteiner J.G., Reusch J.E.B. Mechanisms of aerobic exercise impairment in diabetes: a narrative review. Front Endocrinol. 2018;9:181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5915473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscella A., Stef&#xe0;no E., Lunetti P., Capobianco L., Marsigliante S. The regulation of fat metabolism during aerobic exercise. Biomolecules. 2020;10(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33371437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J., Liu J., Chen X., et al. Mind-body exercise improves cognitive function and modulates the function and structure of the hippocampus and anterior cingulate cortex in patients with mild cognitive impairment. Neuroimage Clin. 2019;23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6535682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31128522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang D.-H., Shin W.-S., Choi H.-S. Effects of modified constraint-induced movement therapy with trunk restraint in early stroke patients: a single-blinded, randomized, controlled, pilot trial. NeuroRehabilitation. 2018;42(1):29&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29400671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamweel H., Gupta N. Constraint-induced movement therapy through telerehabilitation for upper extremity function in stroke. J Neurorestoratol. 2024;12(2)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riley R.D., Debray T.P.A., Fisher D., et al. Individual participant data meta-analysis to examine interactions between treatment effect and participant-level covariates: statistical recommendations for conduct and planning. Stat Med. 2020;39(15):2115&#x2013;2137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7401032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke D.L., Ensor J., Riley R.D. Meta-analysis using individual participant data: one-stage and two-stage approaches, and why they may differ. Stat Med. 2017;36(5):855&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5297998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27747915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>