<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41456045</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1479-5876</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of translational medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Transl Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Meta-analysis of comparing CAR-T and bispecific antibody therapy in relapsed/refractory indolent B-cell non-Hodgkin's lymphomas.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">116</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12967-025-07571-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Indolent B-cell non-Hodgkin&#x2019;s lymphomas (B-NHLs), including follicular lymphoma (FL) and marginal zone lymphoma (MZL), typically demonstrate slow progression but frequently follow a relapsing-remitting course with conventional therapies. Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell (CAR-T) and bi-specific antibodies (BsAbs) therapies have revolutionized treatment for relapsed/refractory (R/R) B-NHLs. However comparative data on the efficacy of CAR-T therapy versus BsAbs in indolent B-NHLs remain limited. This meta-analysis systematically evaluated the efficacy and safety profiles of these two innovative treatments in patients with R/R FL and MZL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a comprehensive search of MEDLINE, Embase, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trial databases, and international conference abstracts (through June 30, 2025) for studies investigating CAR-T or BsAb therapies in R/R FL and MZL. Primary outcome was pooled complete response (CR) rate. Other outcomes included 2-year progression-free survival (PFS), 2-year overall survival (OS), non-relapse mortality (NRM), and adverse events (AEs). Meta-regression analyses were performed to adjust for relevant clinical covariates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Our analysis included 19 publications (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;1,760 patients), comprising 10 CAR-T and 9 BsAbs studies. The single-arm meta-analysis showed that CAR-T therapy demonstrated superior efficacy, with higher pooled CR rate (80.73% vs. 67.14%; <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0003), 2-year PFS (68.84% vs. 47.71%; <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0006), and 2-year OS (88.37% vs. 75.26%; <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.049) compared to BsAbs. NRM per 100 person-years was similar between two modalities (3.89 vs 3.86, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.9871). CAR-T benefits persisted in third-line or later settings, as well as in analyses restricted to clinical trial data. Multivariate meta-regression confirmed CAR-T&#x2019;s superiority for CR independent of median age. Safety analysis revealed CAR-T group had higher incidence of grade &#x2265;3 neurotoxicity (7.48% vs. 0.23%, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0029), neutropenia (58.90% vs. 26.21%; <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0007), thrombocytopenia (16.77% vs. 5.00%; <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.005), but lower incidence of grade &#x2265;3 infection per 100 person-months (0.38 vs. 0.91, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.040) than BsAb group. No differences were observed in grade &#x2265;3 cytokine release syndrome or anemia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">CAR-T therapy offered superior efficacy and survival in R/R indolent B-NHLs compared to BsAbs, albeit with increased AEs, highlighting the need for careful patient selection and toxicity management.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12967-025-07571-3.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Min-Yue</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3393-215X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Ren Ji Hospital, School of Medicine, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200127, PR China. zhangminyue@connect.hku.hk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Yong-Mei</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Ren Ji Hospital, School of Medicine, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200127, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xiao-Qing</ForeName><Initials>XQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Ningbo Hangzhou Bay Hospital, Ningbo, 315336, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Ke-Jie</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Ningbo Hangzhou Bay Hospital, Ningbo, 315336, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Li-Jing</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Ren Ji Hospital, School of Medicine, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200127, PR China. shenlijing@renji.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Ren Ji Hospital, School of Medicine, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200127, PR China. juan_du@live.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Transl Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-5876</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bispecific antibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CAR-T</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indolent B-cell non-Hodgkin&#x2019;s lymphomas</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41456045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12853995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-025-07571-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12967-025-07571-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kordic A, Phillips TJ, Weiss J. The Current State of bispecific antibodies and T-Cell directed therapy in NHL. Cancers (Basel). 2025;17(7).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11988123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40227768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatake IJ, Arnason JE. CARs for lymphoma. Best Pract Res Clin Haematol. 2024;37(4):101601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beha.2025.101601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40074511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nizamuddin IA, Ghobadi A. Chimeric antigen receptor T-Cell therapy and bispecific antibody use in earlier lines of treatment of large B-Cell lymphoma, follicular lymphoma, and Mantle Cell lymphoma. Am Soc Clin Oncol Educ Book. 2025;45(3):e473302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/EDBK-25-473302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40446182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerhard GM, von Keudell G. Bispecific antibody therapy for lymphoma. Best Pract Res Clin Haematol. 2024;37(4):101598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beha.2025.101598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40074512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han L, Wang K, Jiang Z, Guo X, Yu J. Recent development in bispecific antibody immunotherapy for hematological malignancies. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2025;212:104752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.critrevonc.2025.104752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40320222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedele PL, Opat S. Indolent lymphoma: addressing the needs of survivors. Leuk Lymphoma. 2025;66(6):1021&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10428194.2025.2456970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39876569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serroukh Y, Montoto S. Indolent lymphoma. In: Sureda A, Corbacioglu S, Greco R, Kr&#xf6;ger N, Carreras E, editors. The EBMT Handbook: hematopoietic cell transplantation and cellular. Therapies. edn. Cham (CH): Springer Copyright; 2024. 2024, The Author(s)p. 763&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silkenstedt E, Salles G, Campo E, Dreyling M. B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphomas. Lancet. 2024;403(10438):1791&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(23)02705-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12261310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38614113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang TZ, Zhang C, Strati P. SOHO State of the art updates and next questions | novel immunotherapy combinations for the treatment of indolent B-Cell lymphoma. Clin Lymphoma Myeloma Leuk. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40011100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler NH, Samaniego F, Jurczak W, Ghosh N, Derenzini E, Reeves JA, et al. Umbralisib, a dual PI3K&#x3b4;/CK1&#x3b5; inhibitor in patients with relapsed or refractory indolent lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2021;39(15):1609&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.20.03433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8148421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33683917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus R, Davies A, Ando K, Klapper W, Opat S, Owen C, et al. Obinutuzumab for the first-line treatment of follicular lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(14):1331&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1614598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28976863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(11):777&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M14-2385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slim K, Nini E, Forestier D, Kwiatkowski F, Panis Y, Chipponi J. Methodological index for non-randomized studies (minors): development and validation of a new instrument. ANZ J Surg. 2003;73(9):712&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1445-2197.2003.02748.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12956787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartlett NL, Sehn LH, Assouline SE, Giri P, Kuruvilla J, Schuster SJ, et al. Subcutaneous mosunetuzumab leads to High rates of durable responses, Low rates of cytokine release syndrome, and non-inferior Exposure compared with intravenous administration in patients with Relapsed/Refractory follicular lymphoma: primary analysis of a pivotal phase II. Blood. 2024;144(Supplement 1):1645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2024-194612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budde LE, Sehn LH, Matasar M, Schuster SJ, Assouline S, Giri P, et al. Safety and efficacy of mosunetuzumab, a bispecific antibody, in patients with relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma: a single-arm, multicentre, phase 2 study. Lancet Oncol. 2022;23(8):1055&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(22)00335-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35803286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler NH, Dickinson M, Dreyling M, Martinez-Lopez J, Kolstad A, Butler J, et al. Tisagenlecleucel in adult relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma: the phase 2 ELARA trial. Nat Med. 2022;28(2):325&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01622-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto H, Kumode T, Mishima Y, Kataoka K, Ogawa Y, Kanemura N, et al. Efficacy and safety of mosunetuzumab monotherapy for Japanese patients with relapsed/refractory follicular lymphoma: FLMOON-1. Int J Clin Oncol. 2025;30(2):389&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10147-024-02662-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11785659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39652156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacoboni G, Serna A, Navarro Garces V, Jimenez Ubieto A, Valencia E, Lopez Garcia A, et al. Impact of prior bendamustine exposure on bispecific antibody treatment outcomes for patients with B-cell lymphoma. Blood. 2023;142(Suppl 1):310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2023-184883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson C, Hemmer MT, Hu Z, Frank M, Popplewell L, Ahmed N, et al. Real-World early outcomes of axicabtagene ciloleucel for relapsed or refractory (R/R) follicular lymphoma (FL). Hematol Oncol. 2023;41(S2):375&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hon.3164_271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson CA, Chavez JC, Sehgal AR, William BM, Munoz J, Salles G, et al. Axicabtagene ciloleucel in relapsed or refractory indolent non-Hodgkin lymphoma (ZUMA-5): a single-arm, multicentre, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2022;23(1):91&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(21)00591-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34895487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TM, Cho S-G, Taszner M, Chong G, Cai J, Uppala A, et al. Efficacy and safety of Odronextamab in Relapsed/Refractory marginal zone lymphoma (R/R MZL): data from the R/R MZL cohort in the ELM-2 study. Blood. 2024;144(Supplement 1):862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2024-200190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TM, Taszner M, Novelli S, Cho SG, Villasboas JC, Merli M, et al. Safety and efficacy of odronextamab in patients with relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma. Ann Oncol. 2024;35(11):1039&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2024.08.2239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39147364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landsburg DJ, Maziarz RT, Moskop A, Popplewell LL, Solomon SR, Tees MT, et al. Efficacy and safety of Tisagenlecleucel in patients with relapsed/refractory follicular lymphoma: a real-world analysis from the center for blood and marrow transplant research (CIBMTR) Registry. Blood. 2024;144(Suppl 1):4398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2024-204207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linton KM, Vitolo U, Jurczak W, Lugtenburg PJ, Gyan E, Sureda A, et al. Epcoritamab monotherapy in patients with relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma (EPCORE NHL-1): a phase 2 cohort of a single-arm, multicentre study. Lancet Haematol. 2024;11(8):e593&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3026(24)00166-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38889737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Cibrian N, Ortiz-Maldonado V, Brillembourg H, Alserawan L, Espa&#xf1;ol-Rego M, Benitez-Ribas D, et al. Varnimcabtagene autoleucel (var-cel or ari-0001) in relapsed/refractory adult follicular lymphoma. In: EHA. Spain; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morschhauser F, Carlo-Stella C, Dickinson M, Phillips T, Houot R, Offner F, et al. Glofitamab as monotherapy and in combination with obinutuzumab induces high complete response rates in patients (pts) with multiple relapsed or refractory (R/R) follicular lymphoma (FL). Blood. 2021;138(Suppl 1):128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2021-148778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morschhauser F, Dahiya S, Palomba ML, Martin Garcia-Sancho A, Reguera Ortega JL, Kuruvilla J, et al. Lisocabtagene maraleucel in follicular lymphoma: the phase 2 transcend FL study. Nat Med. 2024;30(8):2199&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-024-02986-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11333271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38830991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palomba M, Schuster S, Karmali R, Skarbnik A, Abramson J, Ardeshna K, et al. Lisocabtagene Maraleucel (LISO-CEL) in patients (pts) with relapsed or refractory (R/R) marginal zone lymphoma (MZL) in the phase 2 transcend FL study. Hematol Oncol. 2025;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp J, Strati P, Bhatta S, Huang JJ, Thomas C, Reef DK, et al. Evaluation of outcomes and toxicities of commercial axicabtagene ciloleucel (axi-cel) and tisagenlecleucel (tisa-cel) for relapsed or refractory (R/R) follicular lymphoma (FL): real-World evidence (RWE) from 10 us Academic centers. Blood. 2024;144(Suppl 1):2377 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2024-203753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying Z, Zou D, Yang H, Wu J, Guo Y, Li W, et al. Preliminary efficacy and safety of relmacabtagene autoleucel (carteyva) in adults with relapsed/refractory follicular lymphoma in China: a phase I/II clinical trial. Am J Hematol. 2022;97(12):E436&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajh.26711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36053875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ysebaert L, Houot R, Casasnovas O, Sylvain C, Jardin F, Loschi M, et al. Real-word experience of car T-Cells in patients with Relapsed/Refractory follicular lymphoma: a descart Registry analysis from the Lysa. Blood. 2023;142(Supplement 1):296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2023-184653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou K, Xie Y, Li Z, Liang A, Tao R, Zhang J, et al. TQB2825, a novel 2: 1 structured CD20xCD3 bispecific antibody, in the relapsed/refractory follicular lymphoma. In: EHA. Italy; 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Cho J, Lee MH, Yoon SE, Kim WS, Kim SJ. Car T cells vs bispecific antibody as third- or later-line large B-cell lymphoma therapy: a meta-analysis. Blood. 2024;144(6):629&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2023023419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38696731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson CA, Munoz J, Sun F, Kanters S, Limbrick-Oldfield EH, Spooner C, et al. Real-World outcomes with chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapies in large B cell lymphoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Transpl Cell Ther. 2024;30(1):.e77.1&#x2013;.15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37890589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemoine J, Vic S, Houot R. Disease-specific outcomes after chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy. Eur J Cancer. 2022;160:235&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2021.10.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34865943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenbaum AM, Fromm JR, Gopal AK, Houghton AM. Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL) is infiltrated with activated CD8(+) T-cells despite immune checkpoint signaling. Blood Res. 2022;57(2):117&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5045/br.2022.2021145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9242835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35551108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nastoupil LJ, Bonner A, Wang P, Almuallem L, Desai J, Farazi T, et al. Matching-adjusted indirect comparison of efficacy and safety of lisocabtagene maraleucel and mosunetuzumab for the treatment of third-line or later relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma. Exp Hematol Oncol. 2025;14(1):30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40164-025-00610-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11881270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40045329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray MD, Kanters S, Beygi S, Best T, Wulff J, Limbrick-Oldfield E, et al. Matching-adjusted indirect comparisons of Axicabtagene Ciloleucel to mosunetuzumab for the treatment of Relapsed/Refractory follicular lymphoma. Transpl Cell Ther. 2024;30(9):.e885.1&#x2013;.11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38901633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budde LE, Matasar M, Sehn LH, Assouline SE, Kuruvilla J, Flinn IW, et al. Mosunetuzumab monotherapy demonstrates encouraging activity and a manageable safety profile in patients with heavily pre-treated relapsed or refractory Mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2024;144(Supplement 1):1646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2024-197902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhomoud M, Ibrahim R, Demetres M, Rejeski K, Scordo M, Shouval R, et al. Safety and efficacy of bridging radiation therapy prior to CD19 car T for non-Hodgkin lymphoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Haematologica. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40637750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Q, Zhang X, Wang N, Li C, Zhang Y, Zhou J, et al. Radiation prior to chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy is an optimizing bridging strategy in relapsed/refractory aggressive B-cell lymphoma. Radiother Oncol. 2022;177:53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2022.10.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36309153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhomoud M, Foley M, Sugita M, Yamazaki T, Martinez L, Yamshon S, et al. Low dose total body irradiation improves CD19 CAR-T expansion, persistence, and trafficking, leading to enhanced efficacy in large B-Cell lymphoma. Blood. 2023;142(Suppl 1):1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2023-185216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Besien Hj, Easwar N, Demetres M, Pasciolla M, Shore T, Leonard JP, et al. Comparative infection risk in CAR T vs bispecific antibodies in B cell lymphoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Blood Adv. 2025 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12686707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40590871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>