<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41362435</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2405-6731</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Parasite epidemiology and control</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Parasite Epidemiol Control</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Visceral leishmaniasis outbreak investigation and risk factors among communities in South Omo Zone, Southern Ethiopia, 2022-2023.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e00466</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e00466</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e00466</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.parepi.2025.e00466</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Visceral leishmaniasis (VL), also known as kala-azar, remains a major public health problem in Ethiopia, caused mainly by <i>Leishmania donovani</i> and transmitted through infected female <i>Phlebotomine</i> sandflies. The disease disproportionately affects impoverished, rural populations. Understanding the epidemiology and risk factors of outbreaks is vital for timely prevention and control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study was aimed to investigate a VL outbreak and associated risk factors among communities in South Omo Zone, Southern Ethiopia, 2022-2023.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A descriptive cross-sectional study followed by an unmatched case-control study (1:2 ratio) was conducted from June 2022 to January 2023. Forty-five laboratory-confirmed VL cases and ninety controls without previous VL history were included. Data on socio-demographic, environmental, and behavioral factors were collected using structured interviews. Logistic regression analysis was performed to identify independent risk factors, and the strength of association was expressed using adjusted odds ratios (AORs) with 95&#xa0;% confidence intervals (CI). Statistical significance was set at <i>p</i>&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 45 VL cases and 3 deaths were recorded, yielding an attack rate of 9.7 per 100,000 population and a case fatality rate of 7&#xa0;%. The highest attack rate occurred in Salamago District (51.6/100,000), followed by Nyangatom (19.5/100,000). Adults were the most affected group (87&#xa0;% of cases). The epidemic curve suggested a propagated outbreak peaking in week 24 of 2022. Independent predictors of VL infection included never using long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLINs) (AOR&#xa0;=&#xa0;7.97; 95&#xa0;% CI: 1.63-39.04), inconsistent LLIN use (AOR&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.33; 95&#xa0;% CI: 1.59-17.83), sleeping under acacia trees (AOR&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.13; 95&#xa0;% CI: 1.26-20.78), and living in houses with wooden walls (AOR&#xa0;=&#xa0;6.62; 95&#xa0;% CI: 2.07-21.25).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The outbreak was concentrated in the Salamago District, predominantly affecting adult males. Inconsistent use of LLINs, outdoor sleeping under acacia trees, and poor housing conditions significantly increased VL risk. Strengthening vector control programs, promoting consistent LLIN utilization, improving housing quality, and enhancing community awareness are essential to prevent future VL outbreaks in pastoral settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd on behalf of World Federation of Parasitologists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ango</LastName><ForeName>Tadele Shiwito</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Mizan-Tepi University, Mizan Aman, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dana</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Dansa</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regional Health Bureau Public Health Institute, South Ethiopia Region, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Getachew</LastName><ForeName>Sefonias</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deressa</LastName><ForeName>Wakgari</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Parasite Epidemiol Control</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101687137</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-6731</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Outbreak investigation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">South Omo zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Southern Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Visceral leishmaniasis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41362435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12681898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parepi.2025.e00466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-6731(25)00059-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aklilu E., Gebresilassie A., Yared S., Kindu M., Tekie H., Balkew M., et al. Comparative study on the nocturnal activity of phlebotomine sand flies in a highland and lowland foci of visceral leishmaniasis in North-Western Ethiopia with special reference to Phlebotomus orientalis. Parasit. Vectors. 2017;10:393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5568301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28830569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argaw D., Mulugeta A., Herrero M., Nombela N., Teklu T., Tefera T., et al. Risk factors for visceral Leishmaniasis among residents and migrants in Kafta-Humera, Ethiopia. PLoS Negl. Trop. Dis. 2013;7(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3820755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24244778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canessa M. 2025. Zika Virus: Emerging Neuropathologic Panendemic.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosma C., Maia C., Khan N., Infantino M., Del Riccio M. Leishmaniasis in humans and animals: a one health approach for surveillance, prevention and control in a changing world. Trop. Med. Infect. Dis. 2024;9(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11598728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39591264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deribe K., Meribo K., Gebre T., Hailu A., Ali A., Aseffa A., et al. The burden of neglected tropical diseases in Ethiopia, and opportunities for integrated control and elimination. Parasit. Vectors. 2012;5(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3551690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23095679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshetu E., Awekew A., Bassa T. The public health significance of Leishmaniasis: an overview. J. Nat. Sci. Res. 2016;6(5):48&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadisa E., Tsegaw T., Abera A., Elnaiem D.E., Den Boer M., Aseffa A., et al. Eco-epidemiology of visceral leishmaniasis in Ethiopia. Parasit. Vectors. 2015;8(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4506599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26187584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gize A., Workineh A., Hailu T. A trend prevalence of visceral Leishmaniasis in west Armachiho District, Amhara region, Northwest Ethiopia. Trop. Dis. Travel. Med. Vaccines. 2020;6:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7694413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33292689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail A., Yared S., Dugassa S., Abera A., Animut A., Erko B., et al. Sero-prevalence of visceral leishmaniasis and its associated factors among asymptomatic individuals visiting Denan health center, southeastern Ethiopia. Trop. Dis. Travel. Med. Vaccines. 2023;9:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10334561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37430336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanyina E.W. Characterization of visceral leishmaniasis. BMC Public Health. 2020;1&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7132962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32248804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolaczinski J.H., Hope A., Ruiz J.A., Rumunu J., Richer M., Seaman J. Kala-azar epidemiology and control, southern Sudan. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 2008;14(4):664&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2570907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18394290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagu J., Nyambati V.C.S., Muita M., Muchiri E. Risk factors for the transmission of kala-azar in Fangak, South Sudan. South Sudan Med. J. 2011;4(2):26&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaria Consortium Leishmaniasis control in eastern Africa: past and present efforts and future needs. Situat. Gap Anal. 2010;November:87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health-Ethiopia . Addis Ababa; Ethiopia: 2013. Guidelines for Diagnosis, Treatment, and Prevention of Leishmaniasis in Ethiopia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moh Kenya M of HK . Republic of Kenya Ministry of Health; 2017. Prevention, Diagnosis and Treatment of Visceral Leishmaniasis (Kala-Azar) in Kenya.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oryan A., Akbari M. Worldwide risk factors in leishmaniasis. Asian Pac J Trop Med. 2016;9(10):925&#x2013;932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27794384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry D., Dixon K., Garlapati R., Gendernalik A., Poch&#xe9; D., Poch&#xe9; R. Visceral leishmaniasis prevalence and associated risk factors in the Saran District of Bihar, India, from 2009 to July of 2011. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 2013;88(4):778&#x2013;784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3617869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23382167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picado A., Dash A.P., Bhattacharya S., Boelaert M. Vector control interventions for visceral Leishmaniasis elimination initiative in South Asia, 2005-2010. Indian J. Med. Res. 2012;136(1):22&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3461713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22885260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regassa B., Deyessa N., Addissie A., Abagero A., Shumi G., Gudina G. Outbreak investigation of visceral Leishmaniasis in Borena zone, Oromia region, Ethiopia, November 2019: case control study. Res. Rev. Res. J. Biol. 2021;9(2):01.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sordo L., Gadisa E., Custodio E., Cruz I., Sim&#xf3;n F., Abraham Z., et al. Short report: low prevalence of Leishmania infection in post-epidemic areas of Libo Kemkem, Ethiopia. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 2012;86(6):955&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3366538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22665599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steverding D. The history of leishmaniasis. Parasit. Vectors. 2017;10(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5312593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadese D., Hailu A., Bekele F., Belay S. An epidemiological study of visceral leishmaniasis in north East Ethiopia using serological and leishmanin skin tests. PLoS One. 2019;14(12):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6934302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31881021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Control of the leishmaniases. World Health Organ. Tech. Rep. Ser. 2010;949:22&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21485694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Leishmaniasis: Key facts [Internet] 2023. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/leishmaniasis Available from:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yared S., Deribe K., Gebreselassie A., Lemma W., Akililu E., Kirstein O.D., et al. Risk factors of visceral leishmaniasis: a case control study in North-Western Ethiopia. Parasit. Vectors. 2014;7(1):470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4205297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25312308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamboni P., Antoncecchi E. Determination of the action of anterior pituitary hormones on choleresis in rats. Arch. Ital. Sci. Farmacol. 1962;12:130&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14003155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng C., Wang L., Li Y., Zhou X.N. Visceral leishmaniasis in Northwest China from 2004 to 2018: a spatio-temporal analysis. Infect. Dis. Poverty. 2020;9(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7713028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33267898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>