<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41327022</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Temporal and spatial distribution of pectin, &#x3b2;(1-4)-galactan, xylan and lignin during differentiation of living fibres in young shoots of Leucaena leucocephala (Lam.) de wit.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1693</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1693</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1693</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-025-07793-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Living xylem fibres play important physiological and mechanical functions in trees. Despite a significant role of secondary cell wall chemical composition in performing these functions, little information is available on the developmental changes in the cell wall of living fibres. In the present study, the distribution pattern of pectins, hemicelluloses, and lignin in the cell walls during the differentiation and maturation of living fibres in the secondary xylem of <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i> was examined by light and electron microscopy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The expansion of primary walls during the early stage of fibre development was characterised by a change in the organisation of pectic polysaccharides in the middle lamellae region. The intercellular regions became filled with pectic polysaccharides following initiation of secondary wall deposition. Subsequently, lignification started at cell corners with the deposition of guaiacyl units that co-polymerise with syringyl moieties in the final stages of fibre development. The transmission electron microscopic analysis confirmed the disorganisation of pectic polysaccharides in the middle lamellae region during cell expansion and their inhomogeneous distribution in the cell corners following secondary wall deposition. Immunofluorescence microscopy revealed that &#x3b2;(1&#x2013;4)-galactan are mainly incorporated in the middle lamellae region that undergoes disorganisation and reorganisation during and after cell expansion. Immunogold labelling experiments using JIM5, JIM7 and CCRCM1 antibodies revealed dynamic changes in the distribution pattern of homogalacturonan with different degrees of methylation and fucosylated xyloglucan during cell wall loosening and secondary wall maturation stages of xylem fibres. In mature fibres, LM10 labelling indicated that the less substituted xylans are distributed throughout the secondary wall, while labelling of highly substituted xylans with LM11 appeared more intense at the corner regions of the secondary wall compared to other regions. The KMnO<sub>4</sub> staining revealed the relatively higher lignin distribution in xylem fibres in compound middle lamellae and S<sub>3</sub> wall layers. The transition zone between S<sub>1</sub> and S<sub>2</sub> layers showed relatively high lignin distribution compared to the rest of the S<sub>2</sub> wall layer. The ultrastructural studies demonstrated that the inhomogeneous distribution of lignin corresponds with that of pectins at the cell corners of fibres. The cell wall delignification resulted in a significant reduction of lignin at cell corners, compound middle lamellae and secondary wall layers of fibres.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study revealed the dynamic developmental changes in the structure of the cell wall during secondary wall development by assembly of cell wall polysaccharides and lignin during differentiation of living fibres in <i>L. leucocephala</i>. These insights are very important to understand the development and functional dynamics of wood fibres.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12870-025-07793-z.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sivan</LastName><ForeName>Pramod</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Division of Glycoscience, KTH Royal Institute of Technology, AlbaNova University Centre, Stockholm, 106 91, Sweden. psivan@kth.se.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajput</LastName><ForeName>K S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Botany, The M.S. University of Baroda, Vadodara, 390 002, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Karumanchi S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Sardar Patel University, Vallabh Vidyanagar, Gujarat, 388 120, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell wall polymers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunofluorescence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leucaena leucocephala</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Living fibres</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transmission electron microscopy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Plant samples were collected from the Botanical Garden of Sardar Patel University with permission from the administrative authority. The plants are grown in the Botanical Garden for academic research. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41327022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12690861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-025-07793-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-025-07793-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mellerowicz E, Sundberg B. Wood cell walls: Biosynthesis, developmental dynamics and their implication for wood properties. Curr Opin Plant Biol. 2008;11:293&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pbi.2008.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18434240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lev-Yadun S. Plant fibres: initiation, growth, model plants and open questions. Russ J Plant Physiol. 2010;57(3):305&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S1021443710030015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilvessalo-Pf&#xe4;ffli M-S. Fiber atlas. Identification of papermaking fibers. Berlin: Springer-; 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan P, Vilaplana F, Mellerowicz EJ. Cell wall polysaccharide matrix dynamics during wood development. In: A. Geitmann, editor, Plant Cell Walls: Research Milestones and Conceptual Insights. Taylor and Francis, CRC Press. Informa UK Limited. 2023. pp. 412&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma JF, Yang GH, Mao JZ, Xu F. Characterization of anatomy, ultrastructure and lignin microdistribution in <i>Forsythia suspense</i>. Ind Crop Prod. 2011;33:358&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2010.11.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis NG, Davin LB, Sarkanen S. The nature and function of lignins. In: Brton DHR, Nakanishi K, Meth-Cohn O, editors. Comprehensive natural products chemistry. Volume 3. London: Elsvier; 1999. pp. 618&#x2013;745.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta G, Palit P. Characterization of lignified secondary phloem fibre-deficient mutant of jute (<i>Chorchorus capsularis</i>). Ann Bot. 2004;93:211&#x2013;20.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aob/mch029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4241083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14707004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan BM, Rawal SK, Arha M, Gupta SK, Srivastava S, Shaik NM, Yadav AK, Kulkarni PS, Abhilash OV, Kumar S, Sunitha O, Vishwakarma RK, Singh S, Kumar RJS, Sonawane P, Patel P, Kannan C, Abbassi S. Genetic engineering of phenyl propanoid pathway in <i>Leucaena leucocephala</i>. In: Barrera-Saldana HA, editor Genetic engineering-basics, new application and responsibilities. In Tech Publishers, Janeza tradinea, Rijeka, Croatia. 2012. pp 93&#x2013;120. </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez F, Garcia MM, Yanez R, Tapias R, Fernadez M, Diaz MJ. <i>Leucaena</i> species valoration for biomass and paper production in 1 and 2 year harvest. Bioresour Technol. 2008;99:4849&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2007.09.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17967535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz MJ, Garcia MM, Eugenio ME, Tapias R, Fernadez M, Lopez F. Variations in fibre length and some pulp chemical properties of <i>Leucaena</i> varieties. Ind Crop Prod. 2007;26:142&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2007.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rastogi S, Dwivedi UN. Down-regulation of lignin biosynthesis in Transgenic <i>Leucaena Leucocephala</i> harboring O-methyltransferase gene. Biotechnol Prog. 2006;22:609&#x2013;16.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bp050206+</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16739940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prashant S, Sunitha MS, Pramod S, Rao KS, Rawal SK, Kavi Kishor PB. Down-regulation of <i>Leucaena Leucocephala</i> cinnamoyl coa reductase (<i>LlCCR</i>) gene induces significant changes in phenotype, soluble phenolic pools and lignin in Transgenic tobacco. Plant Cell Rep. 2011;30:2215&#x2013;31.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00299-011-1127-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21847621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirisha VL, Kumar RD, Prashant S, Pramod S, Jalaja N, Rao MP, Rao NS, Mishra P, Rao KS, Khan BM, Kavi Kishor PB. Cloning, characterization and impact of up- and down-regulating subabul Cinnamyl alcohol dehydrogenase (<i>CAD</i>) gene on plant growth and lignin profiles in Transgenic tobacco. Plant Growth Regul. 2011;66:239&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10725-011-9647-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pramod S, Rao KS. Anatomical changes during transition from juvenile to adult wood in branch and main trunk xylem of subabul (<i>Leucaena Leucocephala</i> [Lam.] de Wit). J Sustain for. 2012;31(7):661&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10549811.2012.684300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Awano T, Yoshinaga A, Takabe K. Immunolocalization of &#x3b2;-1-4-galactan and its relationship with lignin distribution in developing compression wood of <i>Cryptomeria Japonica</i>. Planta. 2010;232:109&#x2013;19.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-010-1152-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20376677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen DA. Plant microtechnique. New York: McGraw Hill; 1940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallet C, Chabbert B, Czaninski Y, Monties B. Histochemistry of lignin deposition during sclerenchyma differentiation in alfalfa stems. Ann Bot. 1996;78:625&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/anbo.1996.0170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehistsuka G, Nakano J. Studies on the mechanism of lignin color reaction (XIII): Ma&#xfc;le color reaction (9). Mokuzai Gakkaishi. 1979;25:588&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Awano T, Yoshinaga A, Takabe K. Temporal and Spatial immunolocalization of glucomannans in differentiating earlywood tracheid cell walls of <i>Cryptomeria Japonica</i>. Planta. 2010;232:545&#x2013;54.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-010-1189-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20499086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo J. Electron microscopy. Methods and protocols. 2nd edition. 2007; Human press Inc., New Jersey.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spurr AR. A low viscosity embedding medium for electron microscopy. J Ultrastruct Res. 1969;26:31&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-5320(69)90033-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4887011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson LA. Lignin distribution during late wood formation in <i>Pinus radiate</i> D. Don. IAWA Bull. 1992;13(4):381&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1163/22941932-90001291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barakat A, Winter H, Rondeau-Mouro C, Saake B, Chabbert B, Cathala B. Studies of Xylan interactions and cross-linking to synthetic lignins formed by bulk and end-wise polymerization: a model study of lignin carbohydrate complex formation. Planta. 2007;226:267&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-007-0479-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17333255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiery JP. Mise En evidence des polysaccharides Sur coupes fines En microscopie Elecronique. J Microsc. 1967;6:987&#x2013;1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellerowicz EJ, Baucher M, Sundberg B, Boerjan W. Unravelling cell wall formation in the Woody Dicot stem. Plant Mol Biol. 2001;47:239&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1010699919325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11554475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knox JP. The use of antibodies to study the architecture and developmental regulation of plant cell walls. Int Rev Cytol. 1997;171:79&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0074-7696(08)62586-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9066126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catesson AM. Cambial ultrastructure and biochemistry: changes in relation to vascular tissue differentiation and the seasonal cycle. Int J Plant Sci. 1994;155(3):251&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/297165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQueen-Mason S. Plant cell walls and the control of growth. Biochem Soc Trans. 1997;25:204&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/bst0250204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9056872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altaner CM, Tokareva EN, Jarvis MC, Harris PJ. Distribution of (1&#x2013;4)-&#x3b2;-galacatan, Arabinagalactan protein, Xylan and (1&#x2013;3) &#x3b2;-glucan in tracheid cell walls of Softwoods. Tree Physiol. 2010;30:782&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/treephys/tpq021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20382964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Hou J, Chen H, Pei K, Li Y, He XQ. Dynamic changes of pectin epitopes in cell walls during the development of the Procambium-Cambium continuum in Poplar. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18(8):1716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms18081716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5578106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28783076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mast SW, Donaldson LA, Torr K, Phillips L, Flint H, West M, Strabala TJ, Wagner A. Exploring the ultrastructural localization and biosynthesis of &#xdf; (1,4)-galactan in <i>Pinus radiata</i> compression wood. Plant Physiol. 2009;150:573&#x2013;83.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.108.134379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2689987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson LA, Knox JP. Localization of cell wall polysaccharides in normal and compression wood of radiata pine; relationship with lignification and microfibril orientation. Plant Physiol. 2012;158:648&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.111.184036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3271756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22147521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Awano T, Yoshinaga A, Takabe K. Occurrence of Xylan and Mannan polysaccharides and their Spatial relationship with other cell wall components in differentiating compression wood tracheids of <i>Cryptomeria Japonica</i>. Planta. 2011;233:721&#x2013;35.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-010-1333-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21184094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenkanen M, Tamminen T, Hortling B. Investigation of lignin carbohydrate complexes in kraft pulps by selective enzymatic treatments. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 1999;51:241&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s002530051388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busse-Wicher M, Gomes TC, Tryfona T, Nikolovski N, Stott K, Grantham NJ, Bolam DN, Skaf MS, Dupree P. The pattern of Xylan acetylation suggests Xylan May interact with cellulose microfibrils as a twofold helical screw in the secondary plant cell wall of <i>Arabidopsis Thaliana</i>. Plant J. 2014;79(3):492&#x2013;506.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tpj.12575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4140553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24889696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons T, Mortimer J, Bernardinelli O, P&#xf6;ppler A-C, Brown SP, deAzevedo ER, Dupree R, Dupree P. Folding of Xylan onto cellulose fibrils in plant cell walls revealed by solid-state NMR. Nat Commun. 2016;7:13902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms13902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5187587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28000667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivan P, Heinonen E, Escudero L, Gandla ML, Jim&#xe9;nez-Quero A, J&#xf6;nsson LJ, Mellerowicz EJ, Vilaplana F. Unraveling the unique structural motifs of glucuronoxylan from hybrid Aspen wood. Carbohydr Polym. 2024;343:122434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2024.122434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39174079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhlmann J, Bucheli E, Swain MJ, Dunning N, Albersheim P, Darvill AG, Hahn MG. Generation of monoclonal antibodies against plant cell wall polysaccharides. I. Characterization of a monoclonal antibody to a terminal &#x3b1;-(1&#x2192;2)-linked fucosyl-containing epitope. Plant Physiol. 1994;104:699&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.104.2.699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC159249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7512736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persson S, Caffall KH, Freshour G, Hilley MT, Bauer S, Poindexter P, Hahn MG, Mohnen D, Somerville C. The Arabidopsis irregular xylem8 mutant is deficient in glucuronoxylan and homogalacturonan, which are essential for secondary cell wall integrity. Plant Cell. 2007;19(1):237&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1105/tpc.106.047720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1820957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17237350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stacey NJ, Roberts K, Carpita NC, Wells B, McCann MC. Dynamic changes in cell surface molecules are very early events in the differentiation of mesophyll cells from <i>Zinnia elegans</i> into tracheary elements. Plant J. 1995;8:891&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-313X.1995.8060891.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takashia H, Rumi K. Functions of Xyloglucan in plant cells. Mol Plant. 2011;4:17&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/mp/ssq063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20943810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Sandquist D, Sundberg B, Daniel G. Spatial and Temperol variability of Xylan distribution in differentiating secondary xylem of hybrid Aspen. Planta. 2012;235:1315&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-011-1576-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22207424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Daniel G. Immunolocalization of hemicelluloses in <i>Arabidopsis Thaliana</i> stem part 1: Temporal and Spatial distribution of Xylans. Planta. 2012;236:1275&#x2013;88.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00425-012-1686-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22711286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grunward C, Ruel K, Schmitt U. On the cytochemistry of cell wall formation in Poplar trees. Plant Biol. 2002;4:13&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2002-20431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awano T, Takabe K, Fujita M. Xylan deposition on secondary wall of <i>Fagus crenata</i> fiber. Protoplasma. 2002;219:106&#x2013;15.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s007090200011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11926061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reis D, Vian B. Helicoidal pattern in secondary cell walls and possible role of Xylans in their construction. C R Biol. 2004;327:785&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crvi.2004.04.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15587069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micco VD, Aronne G. Anatomical features, monomer lignin composition and accumulation of phenolics in 1 year old branches of the mediterranean <i>Cistus ladanifer</i> L. Bot J Linn Soc. 2007;155:361&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1095-8339.2007.00705.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terashima N. A new mechanism for formation of structurally ordered protolignin macromolecule in the cell walls of tree xylem. J Pulp Paper Sci. 1990;16:J150&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshinaga A, Fujita M, Saiki H. Secondary wall thickening and lignification of oak xylem components during late wood formation. Mokuzai Gakkaishi. 1997;43(5):377&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terashima N. Formation and ultrastructure of lignified plant cell walls. In: Kim YS, editor. New horizons in wood anatomy. Kwangju: Chonnam National University; 2000. pp. 169&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarvis MC, Briggs SPH, Knox JP. Intercellular adhesion and cell separation in plants. Plant Cell Environ. 2003;26:977&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-3040.2003.01034.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knox JP. Cell and developmental biology of pectins. In: Seymour GB, Knox JP, editors. Pectins and their manipulation. Oxford, London: Blackwell; 2002. pp. 131&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wi SG, Singh AP, Lee KH, Kim YS. The pattern of pectin, peroxidase and lignin in the middle lamellae of secondary xylem fibres in alfalfa (<i>Medicago sativa</i>). Ann Bot. 2005;95:863&#x2013;8.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aob/mci092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4246741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15710645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terashima N, Atalla RH, Ralph SA, Landuci LL, Lapierre C, Monties B. New preparations of lignin polymer models under conditions that approximate cell wall lignification. II. Structural characterization of the models by thioacidolysis. Holzforschung. 1996;50:9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hfsg.1996.50.1.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil HPSA, Yusra AFI, Bhat AH, Jawaid M. Cell wall ultrastructure, anatomy, lignin distribution and chemical composition of Malaysian cultivated Kenaf fiber. Ind Crop Prod. 2010;31:113&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2009.09.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>