<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41341119</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2459-4148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of frailty, sarcopenia and falls</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Frailty Sarcopenia Falls</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Use of Electrical Stimulation for Older Adults at Risk for Developing Sarcopenia: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>269</StartPage><EndPage>278</EndPage><MedlinePgn>269-278</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.22540/JFSF-10-269</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to compile evidence on the effectiveness of neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) for improving muscle strength in older adults, with or without systemic pathologies. A systematic search of PubMed, Cochrane Library, and Scopus databases was conducted for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) published between 2017 and 2023. Eligible studies included: older adults over 55 years, the use of either static stimulation (neuromuscular electrical stimulation NMES) in a stationary position or dynamic stimulation (functional electrical stimulation - FES applied during single or multi-joint movement), examined at least one muscle strength outcome, reported stimulation parameters (e.g., frequency, duration, amplitude), and involved participants with or at risk for sarcopenia. This review included 12 RCTs with Physiotherapy Evidence Database (PEDro) scores ranging from 5-9 (good quality). 9 studies reported significant increase in isometric muscle strength following electrical stimulation. Common parameters were 50-100 Hz with variable intensity and pulse duration. The findings suggest that both dynamic stimulation, or static stimulation delivered prior to strength or endurance training, respectively, proved more effective than static stimulation alone. However, parameter selection varied widely and was often unjustified, highlighting the need for standardization to optimize outcomes in community-dwelling older adults.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Hylonome Publications.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deshmukh</LastName><ForeName>Swaranka M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD program in Rehabilitation Sciences, Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLean</LastName><ForeName>Gillian A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD program in Rehabilitation Sciences, Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purohit</LastName><ForeName>Rudri M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PhD program in Rehabilitation Sciences, Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arena</LastName><ForeName>Ross</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatt</LastName><ForeName>Tanvi S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Greece</Country><MedlineTA>J Frailty Sarcopenia Falls</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101756655</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2459-4148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamometer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional electrical stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscular strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parameter</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41341119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12670216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22540/JFSF-10-269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JFSF-010-04-269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, Boirie Y, Bruy&#xe8;re O, Cederholm T, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age and Ageing. 2019;48:16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans WJ, Lexell J. Human aging, muscle mass, and fiber type composition. The Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences. 1995;50(Special_Issue):11&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7493202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, van Loon LJ. Aging, exercise, and muscle protein metabolism. Journal of applied physiology. 2009;106(6):2040&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Gleeson BG, Jonkers RA, Meijer K, Savelberg HH, Dendale P, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance training is accompanied by a fiber type&#x2013;specific increase in satellite cell content in elderly men. Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biomedical Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2009;64(3):332&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Charifi N, Denis C, Lexell J. Satellite cells and myonuclei in young and elderly women and men. Muscle &amp; Nerve: Official Journal of the American Association of Electrodiagnostic Medicine. 2004;29(1):120&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14694507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips BE, Williams JP, Gustafsson T, Bouchard C, Rankinen T, Knudsen S, et al. Molecular networks of human muscle adaptation to exercise and age. PLoS genetics. 2013;9(3):e1003389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23555298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Sen A, Gordon PM. Resistance exercise for muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Ageing research reviews. 2010;9(3):226&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2892859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20385254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton LA, Sumukadas D. Optimal management of sarcopenia. Clinical interventions in aging. 2010:217&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20852669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Koopman R, Schaart G, Meijer K, Savelberg HH, van Loon LJ. Satellite cell content is specifically reduced in type II skeletal muscle fibers in the elderly. American Journal of Physiology-Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2007;292(1):E151&#x2013;E7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borst SE. Interventions for sarcopenia and muscle weakness in older people. Age and ageing. 2004;33(6):548&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana JU, Dias JMD, Pereira LSM, Silva SLAd, Dias RC, Lustosa LP. Resistance training as a tool for changing muscle mass and frailty status in sarcopenic older women: a quasi-experimental study. Fisioterapia e Pesquisa. 2022;29(3):224&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth S, Martel G, Ivey F, Lemmer J, Tracy B, Metter E, et al. Skeletal muscle satellite cell characteristics in young and older men and women after heavy resistance strength training. The Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2001;56(6):B240&#x2013;B7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11382785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morcillo-Losa JA, D&#xed;az-Mart&#xed;nez MDP, Ceylan H&#x130;, Moreno-Vecino B, Bragazzi NL, P&#xe1;rraga Montilla J. Effects of high-intensity interval training on muscle strength for the prevention and treatment of sarcopenia in older adults: a systematic review of the literature. J Clin Med. 2024;13(5):1299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10931549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38592165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talar K, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Belmonte A, Vetrovsky T, Steffl M, Ka&#x142;amacka E, Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J. Benefits of resistance training in early and late stages of frailty and sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies. J Clin Med. 2021;10(8):1630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8070531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vries N, Van Ravensberg C, Hobbelen J, Rikkert MO, Staal J, Nijhuis-Van der Sanden M. Effects of physical exercise therapy on mobility, physical functioning, physical activity and quality of life in community-dwelling older adults with impaired mobility, physical disability and/or multi-morbidity: a meta-analysis. Ageing research reviews. 2012;11(1):136&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipila S, Suominen H. Effects of strength and endurance training on thigh and leg muscle mass and composition in elderly women. J Appl Physiol. 1995;78(1):334&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7713834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarasheski KE, Zachwieja JJ, Bier DM. Acute effects of resistance exercise on muscle protein synthesis rate in young and elderly men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 1993;265(2):E210&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8368290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst C, Dismore L, Granic A, Tullo E, Noble JM, Hillman SJ, et al. Attitudes and barriers to resistance exercise training for older adults living with multiple long-term conditions, frailty, and a recent deterioration in health: qualitative findings from the Lifestyle in Later Life&#x2013;Older People's Medicine (LiLL-OPM) study. BMC geriatrics. 2023;23(1):772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10675908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38001414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim K, Taylor L. Factors associated with physical activity among older people&#x2014;a population-based study. Preventive medicine. 2005;40(1):33&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15530578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billot M, Calvani R, Urtamo A, S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez JL, Ciccolari-Micaldi C, Chang M, et al. Preserving mobility in older adults with physical frailty and sarcopenia: opportunities, challenges, and recommendations for physical activity interventions. Clin Interv Aging. 2020;15:1675&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32982201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor D, Brennan L, Caulfield B. The use of neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) for managing the complications of ageing related to reduced exercise participation. Maturitas. 2018;113:13&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29903643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton E, Farrier K, Lewin G, Pettigrew S, Hill A-M, Airey P, et al. Motivators and barriers for older people participating in resistance training: a systematic review. Journal of aging and physical activity. 2017;25(2):311&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27620535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baert V, Gorus E, Mets T, Bautmans I. Motivators and barriers for physical activity in older adults with osteoporosis. Journal of geriatric physical therapy. 2015;38(3):105&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25594524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Melo M, Arag&#xe3;o FA, Vaz MA. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation for muscle strengthening in elderly with knee osteoarthritis&#x2013;a systematic review. Complementary therapies in clinical practice. 2013;19(1):27&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23337561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharififar S, Shuster JJ, Bishop MD. Adding electrical stimulation during standard rehabilitation after stroke to improve motor function. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Annals of physical and rehabilitation medicine. 2018;61(5):339&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29958963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P-Y, Cheen J-R, Jheng Y-C, Wu H-K, Huang S-E, Kao C-L. Clinical applications and consideration of interventions of electrotherapy for orthopedic and neurological rehabilitation. Journal of the Chinese Medical Association. 2022;85(1):24&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12755623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34643619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen MGH, Busk H, Wienecke T. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation improves activities of daily living post stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Archives of rehabilitation research and clinical translation. 2022;4(1):100167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8904887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35282150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Gong Y, Zhang C, Meng P, Gai Y, Han X, et al. Effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation combined with early rehabilitation therapy on mechanically ventilated patients: a prospective randomized controlled study. BMC pulmonary medicine. 2023;23(1):272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10362773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37480065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glinsky J, Harvey L, Van Es P. Efficacy of electrical stimulation to increase muscle strength in people with neurological conditions: a systematic review. Physiotherapy research international. 2007;12(3):175&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17624871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobo-Vicente F, San Juan AF, Larumbe-Zabala E, Est&#xe9;vez-Gonz&#xe1;lez AJ, Donadio MVF, Perez-Ruiz M. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation improves muscle strength, biomechanics of movement, and functional mobility in children with chronic neurological disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Physical therapy. 2021;101(10):pzab170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34184031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaz MA, Baroni BM, Geremia JM, Lanferdini FJ, Mayer A, Arampatzis A, et al. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation (NMES) reduces structural and functional losses of quadriceps muscle and improves health status in patients with knee osteoarthritis. Journal of orthopaedic research. 2013;31(4):511&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23138532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess L. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation to improve muscle weakness in hip osteoarthritis: A feasibility study: Bournemouth University. 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langeard A, Bigot L, Chastan N, Gauthier A. Does neuromuscular electrical stimulation training of the lower limb have functional effects on the elderly?: A systematic review. Experimental gerontology. 2017;91:88&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28216413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Almeida Neves D, Pereira LC, Garcia KR, de Santana FS, de Caldas Fujita RY, dos Santos Faria B, et al. Impact of the association of strength training with neuromuscular electrostimulation on the functionality of individuals with functional decline during senescence: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clinics. 2025;80:100586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11850139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39922123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borzuola R, Laudani L, Labanca L, Macaluso A. Superimposing neuromuscular electrical stimulation onto voluntary contractions to improve muscle strength and mass: A systematic review. European Journal of Sport Science. 2023;23(8):1547&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35856620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancinelli R, Toniolo L, Di Filippo ES, Doria C, Marrone M, Maroni CR, et al. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation induces skeletal muscle fiber remodeling and specific gene expression profile in healthy elderly. Frontiers in Physiology. 2019;10:1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6890722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31827446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki M, Ireland A, Jones DA, McPhee JS. Age-dependent motor unit remodelling in human limb muscles. Biogerontology. 2016;17:485&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4889636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafri M, Laufer Y. Therapeutic effects of functional electrical stimulation on gait in individuals post-stroke. Annals of biomedical engineering. 2015;43:451&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25316590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caulfield B, Prendergast A, Rainsford G, Minogue C, editors. Self directed home based electrical muscle stimulation training improves exercise tolerance and strength in healthy elderly. 2013 35th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC) 2013 IEEE.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24111365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coletti C, Acosta GF, Keslacy S, Coletti D. Exercise-mediated reinnervation of skeletal muscle in elderly people: An update. European journal of translational myology. 2022;32(1):10416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8992679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roman NA, Tuchel VI, Nicolau C, Grigorescu O-D, Necula R. Functional electrostimulation in patients affected by the most frequent central motor neuron disorders&#x2014;a scoping review. Applied Sciences. 2023;13(6):3732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massobrio P, Micera S, Pedrocchi A, Bertoldo A, Martinoia S. Neurotechnologies to understand and restore the nervous system. 2024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trost W, Hars M, Fernandez N, Herrmann F, Chevalley T, Ferrari S, et al. Functional brain changes in sarcopenia: evidence for differential central neural mechanisms in dynapenic older women. Aging Clinical and Experimental Research. 2023;35(5):1015&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10149465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakauer JW, Hadjiosif AM, Xu J, Wong AL, Haith AM. Motor learning. Compr Physiol. 2019;9(2):613&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30873583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderthommen M, Duchateau J. Electrical stimulation as a modality to improve performance of the neuromuscular system. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2007;35(4):180&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17921786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savvakis I, Adamakidou T, Kleisiaris C. Physical-activity interventions to reduce fear of falling in frail and pre-frail older adults: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. European geriatric medicine. 2024;15(2):333&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10997712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38411771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondi D, Jandova T, Verratti V, D'Amico M, Kinel E, D'Attilio M, et al. Static balance adaptations after neuromuscular electrical stimulation on quadriceps and lumbar paraspinal muscles in healthy elderly. Sport Sci Health. 2022;18:85&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xfc;ggemann AK, Mello CL, Dal Pont T, Kunzler DH, Martins DF, Bobinski F, et al. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation during hemodialysis on peripheral muscle strength and exercise capacity: a randomized clinical trial. Archives of physical medicine and rehabilitation. 2017;98(5):822&#x2013;31.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28093194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acar&#xf6;z Candan S, Ako&#x11f;lu AS, B&#xfc;&#x11f;&#xfc;&#x15f;an S, Y&#xfc;ksel F. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation of quadriceps on the quadriceps strength and functional performance in nursing home residents: A comparison of short and long stimulation periods. Geriatrics &amp; Gerontology International. 2019;19(5):409&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30884073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteve V, Carneiro J, Moreno F, Fulquet M, Garriga S, Pou M, et al. The effect of neuromuscular electrical stimulation on muscle strength, functional capacity and body composition in haemodialysis patients. Nefrolog&#xed;a (English Edition) 2017;37(1):68&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27575930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanada M, Soyama A, Hidaka M, Nagura H, Oikawa M, Tsuji A, et al. Effects of quadriceps muscle neuromuscular electrical stimulation in living donor liver transplant recipients: phase-II single-blinded randomized controlled trial. Clinical Rehabilitation. 2019;33(5):875&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30607983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumin AN, Oleinik PA, Bezdenezhnykh AV, Ivanova AV. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation in early rehabilitation of patients with postoperative complications after cardiovascular surgery: A randomized controlled trial. Medicine. 2020;99(42):e22769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7572009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33080746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acheche A, Mekki M, Paillard T, Tabka Z, Trabelsi Y. The effect of adding neuromuscular electrical stimulation with endurance and resistance training on exercise capacity and balance in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomized controlled trial. Canadian Respiratory Journal. 2020;2020(1):9826084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7542502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33062081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani M, Ehsani F, Gohari A. Effect of functional electrical stimulation on muscle mass, fatigue, and quality of life in older patients with COVID-19: a randomized clinical trial study. Journal of Manipulative and Physiological Therapeutics. 2023;46(2):65&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37777938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa N, Yang J-G, Bae S, Kim G-M, Park H-J, Park H. Effect of electrical muscle stimulation and resistance exercise intervention on physical and brain function in middle-aged and older women. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2022;20(1):101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9819342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36612423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schinner L, Nagels K, Scherf J, Schmaderer C, Heemann U, K&#xfc;chle C, et al. Intradialytic neuromuscular electrical stimulation with optional virtual reality distraction improves not only muscle strength and functional capacity but also serum albumin level in haemodialysis patients: a pilot randomized clinical trial. BMC nephrology. 2023;24(1):246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37608265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki T, Ikeda M, Minami M, Matayoshi Y, Nakao M, Nakamura T, et al. Beneficial effect of intradialytic electrical muscle stimulation in hemodialysis patients: a randomized controlled trial. Artificial Organs. 2018;42(9):899&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30069942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang EM, Park SH. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation combined with exercises versus an exercise program on the physical characteristics and functions of the elderly: a randomized controlled trial. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2021;18(5):2463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Mao L, Feng Y, Ainsworth BE, Liu Y, Chen N. Effects of different exercise training modes on muscle strength and physical performance in older people with sarcopenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr. 2021;21(1):708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trost W, Hars M, Fernandez N, Herrmann F, Chevalley T, Ferrari S, et al. Functional brain changes in sarcopenia: evidence for differential central neural mechanisms in dynapenic older women. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2023;35(5):1015&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10149465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37029271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmel JB, Martin JH. Motor cortex electrical stimulation augments sprouting of the corticospinal tract and promotes recovery of motor function. Front Integr Neurosci. 2014;8:51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4061747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24994971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charette SL, McEvoy L, Pyka G, Snow-Harter C, Guido D, Wiswell R, et al. Muscle hypertrophy response to resistance training in older women. Journal of applied Physiology. 1991;70(5):1912&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1864770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staron R, Malicky E, Leonardi M, Falkel J, Hagerman F, Dudley G. Muscle hypertrophy and fast fiber type conversions in heavy resistance-trained women. European journal of applied physiology and occupational physiology. 1990;60:71&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2311599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffler LR, Chae J. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation in neurorehabilitation. Muscle &amp; Nerve: Official Journal of the American Association of Electrodiagnostic Medicine. 2007;35(5):562&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17299744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderthommen M, Duteil S, Wary C, Raynaud J-S, Leroy-Willig A, Crielaard J-M, et al. A comparison of voluntary and electrically induced contractions by interleaved 1H-and 31P-NMRS in humans. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2003;94(3):1012&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12571132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell WK, Williams J, Atherton P, Larvin M, Lund J, Narici M. Sarcopenia, dynapenia, and the impact of advancing age on human skeletal muscle size and strength;a quantitative review. Frontiers in physiology. 2012;3:260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3429036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22934016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foldvari M, Clark M, Laviolette LC, Bernstein MA, Kaliton D, Castaneda C, et al. Association of muscle power with functional status in community-dwelling elderly women. The Journals of Gerontology Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences. 2000;55(4):M192&#x2013;M9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10811148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canavan JL, Maddocks M, Nolan CM, Jones SE, Kon SS, Clark AL, et al. Functionally relevant cut point for isometric quadriceps muscle strength in chronic respiratory disease. American journal of respiratory and critical care medicine. 2015;192(3):395&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4584252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26230240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmati M, Gondin J, Malakoutinia F. Effects of neuromuscular electrical stimulation on quadriceps muscle strength and mass in healthy young and older adults: a scoping review. Physical Therapy. 2021;101(9):pzab144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34106246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollen JC, Dean SG, Siegert RJ, Howe TE, Goodwin VA. A systematic review of measures of self-reported adherence to unsupervised home-based rehabilitation exercise programmes, and their psychometric properties. BMJ open. 2014;4(6):e005044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4078771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24972606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naaman SC, Stein RB, Thomas C. Minimizing discomfort with surface neuromuscular stimulation. Neurorehabilitation and neural repair. 2000;14(3):223&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11272479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller MG, Cheatham CC, Holcomb WR, Ganschow R, Michael TJ, Rubley MD. Subcutaneous tissue thickness alters the effect of NMES. Journal of sport rehabilitation. 2008;17(1):68&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18270388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu X, Gao X, Liu Y, Liu H. Surface bioelectric dry Electrodes: A review. Measurement. 2021;183:109774.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaviano NR, Saliba S. Can the use of neuromuscular electrical stimulation be improved to optimize quadriceps strengthening? Sports health. 2016;8(1):79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26582349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turi Z, Ambrus GG, Ho K-A, Sengupta T, Paulus W, Antal A. When size matters: large electrodes induce greater stimulation-related cutaneous discomfort than smaller electrodes at equivalent current density. Brain stimulation. 2014;7(3):460&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24582373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismond KP. Improving self-management with eHealth in cirrhosis using a patient-centered approach [dissertation] Edmonton (AB): University of Alberta; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas RJ, Beatty AL, Beckie TM, Brewer LC, Brown TM, Forman DE, et al. Home-based cardiac rehabilitation: a scientific statement from the American Association of Cardiovascular and Pulmonary Rehabilitation, the American Heart Association, and the American College of Cardiology. Circulation. 2019;140(1):e69&#x2013;e89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31082266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbraecken J. Telemedicine applications in sleep disordered breathing: thinking out of the box. Sleep medicine clinics. 2016;11(4):445&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28118869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferdinand KC, Senatore FF, Clayton-Jeter H, Cryer DR, Lewin JC, Nasser SA, et al. Improving medication adherence in cardiometabolic disease: practical and regulatory implications. Journal of the American College of Cardiology. 2017;69(4):437&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5604316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28126162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly JA, Bogart LM, Benotsch EG, McAuliffe TL. Patterns, correlates, and barriers to medication adherence among persons prescribed new treatments for HIV disease. Health Psychology. 2000;19(2):124&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10762096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>