<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41233382</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antiviral potential of Corchorus olitorius fixed oil loaded into poly(D,L-lactide-co-glycolide)/poly(&#x3b5;-caprolactone) (PLGA/PCL) nanoparticles against HSV-1 virus, supported by network analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39748</StartPage><MedlinePgn>39748</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">39748</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-15718-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Although <i>Corchorus olitorius</i> has been traditionally used in folk medicine for various purposes for a long time and has components that may have antiviral effects, there is not much scientific data to support any particular antiviral effects of the plant. More research is required to investigate its antiviral effectiveness against certain viral infections and to comprehend the underlying mechanisms.The goals of this research were to create biodegradable and partially soluble polymeric nanoparticles (polylactide-co-glycolide- poly(&#x3b5;-caprolactone) nanoparticles) (PLGA-PCL NPs) loaded with <i>C. olitorius</i> (referred to as C.O./PLGA-PCL-NPs) and to examine their potential impact against the Herpes simplex type 1 (HSV-1) virus. Gas chromatography coupled with mass spectrometry (GC-MS) was used to chemically characterize the fixed oil of the shrub <i>Corchorus olitorius</i> (<i>C. olitorius</i>, family Malvaceae). Additionally, we used all the components identified in an in silico molecular docking investigation, screening them against HSV-1 DNA polymerase (PDB ID: 2GV9) and thymidine kinase from HSV-1 complexed with 5-iododeoxyuridine (HSV-1 TK; PDB ID: 1KI7).&#xa0;The possibility of using <i>Corchorus olitorius</i> oil (C.O.) to cure Herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1) is examined in this study. C.O., a plant oil rich in fatty acids and sterols, was encapsulated in nanoparticles (NPs) made from a blend of polylactide-co-glycolide (PLGA) and poly(&#x3b5;-caprolactone) (PCL) polymers. We optimized the formulation to create NPs with minimal clumping, a small size, and a stable electrical charge. The optimized NPs displayed a spherical morphology with minimal agglomeration, the smallest hydrodynamic size (151.2 &#xb1; 0.24 nm), the lowest polydispersity index (0.326 &#xb1; 0.04), and the highest &#x3b6; potential -25.6 &#xb1; 0.04 mV) compared to other formulations. These NPs effectively trapped C.O. (77.5 &#xb1; 0.44%) and released it gradually (89 &#xb1; 0.98%) over 72 h. Both C.O. and the C.O.-loaded NPs displayed significant antiviral activity against HSV-1. To understand this effect, we built a network analysis of HSV-1 genes and identified potential interactions between C.O. components and these genes. The top 10 hub genes, AKT1, TNF, EGFR, STAT3, SRC, BCL2, IL1B, HSP90AA1, PPARG, and MTOR, are reported. Additionally, computer modeling predicted how the chemical compounds of C.O. might interact with a key HSV-1 enzyme. These findings suggest that C.O./PLGA-PCL NPs hold promise as a new treatment for HSV-1 infections.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Youssif</LastName><ForeName>Khayrya A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Faculty of Pharmacy, El Salehya El Gadida University, El Sharquia, El Salehya El Gadida, Egypt. Khayrya.Youssif@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elkomy</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, College of Pharmacy, Jouf University, 72341, Sakaka, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elhabal</LastName><ForeName>Sammar Fathy</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Industrial Pharmacy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Modern University for Technology and Information (MTI), Mokattam, Cairo, 11571, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abd El-Mordy</LastName><ForeName>Fatma Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5554-2064</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy and Medicinal Plants, Faculty of Pharmacy (Girls), Al-Azhar University, Cairo, 11754, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hisham</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Deraya University, New Minia, 61111, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abd El-Aleam</LastName><ForeName>Rehab H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Modern University for Technology and Information (MTI), Mokattam, Cairo, 11571, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Zuhairy</LastName><ForeName>Saeed Abdul Kareem Saeed</ForeName><Initials>SAKS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Kut University College, Kut, Wasit, 52001, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Nabarawi</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Industrial Pharmacy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Cairo University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Shoubki</LastName><ForeName>Adam A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Industrial Pharmacy, Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Derna, Derna, Libya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Industrial Pharmacy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Cairo University, Cairo, 11562, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Manakhly</LastName><ForeName>Arwa Ramadan</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Modern University for Technology and Information (MTI), Mokattam, Cairo, 11571, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>A Safwat</LastName><ForeName>Nesreen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Modern University for Technology and Information (MTI), Mokattam, Cairo, 11571, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bringmann</LastName><ForeName>Gerhard</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3583-5935</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Organic Chemistry, University of W&#xfc;rzburg, Am Hubland, 97074, W&#xfc;rzburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelmohsen</LastName><ForeName>Usama Ramadan</ForeName><Initials>UR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Deraya University, New Minia City, 61111, Egypt. usama.ramadan@mu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shady</LastName><ForeName>Nourhan Hisham</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Faculty of Pharmacy, Deraya University, New Minia City, 61111, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Deraya Center for Research and Sustainability, Deraya University, Universities Zone, New Minia City, 61111, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corchorus olitorius</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-viral</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fixed oil</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Herpes simplex type 1 (HSV-1)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular docking study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network pharmacology analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Poly(&#x3b5;-caprolactone) (PLC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polylactide-co-glycolide (PLGA)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41233382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12615623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-15718-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-15718-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haggag, E. G. et al. Antiviral potential of green synthesized silver nanoparticles of Lampranthus coccineus and Malephora lutea. <i>Int. J. Nanomed.</i><b>14</b>, 6217&#x2013;6229 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJN.S214171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6690046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31496682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Rahman, I. A. M. et al. Metabolite profiling of green algae Halimeda opuntia to target hepatitis C virus-796 polymerase inhibitors assisted by molecular docking. <i>S. Afr. J. Bot.</i><b>151</b>, 538&#x2013;543 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sajb.2022.10.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, J.-Y. et al. Natural products reverse cancer multidrug resistance. <i>Front. Pharmacol.</i><b>15</b>, 1348076 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1348076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10988293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kundu, A., Sarkar, D., Mandal, N. A., Sinha, M. K. &amp; Mahapatra, B. S. A secondary phloic (bast) fibre-shy (bfs) mutant of dark jute (Corchorus olitorius L.) develops lignified fibre cells but is defective in cambial activity. <i>Plant Growth Regul.</i><b>67</b>, 45&#x2013;55 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10725-012-9660-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shady, N. H. et al. The Potential of Corchorus olitorius Seeds Buccal Films for Treatment of Recurrent Minor Aphthous Ulcerations in Human Volunteers. <i>Mol. (Basel, Switzerland)</i><b>27</b>(20), 7020 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27207020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9610436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36296628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giro, A. &amp; Ferrante, A. Yield and quality of Corchorus olitorius baby leaf grown in a floating system. <i>J. Hortic. Sci. Biotechnol.</i><b>91</b>(6), 603&#x2013;610 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14620316.2016.1200955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M. M. Biochemistry, medicinal and food values of jute (Corchorus capsularis L. and C. olitorius L.) leaf: A review. <i>Int J Enhanc Res Sci Technol Eng.</i><b>2</b>(11), 135&#x2013;144 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Razek, M. A., Abdelwahab, M. F., Abdelmohsen, U. R. &amp; Hamed ANJRa.,. Pharmacological and phytochemical biodiversity of Corchorus olitorius. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>12</b>(54), 35103&#x2013;35114 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2RA07406K</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9727694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36540263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Yousef, H. M., Amina, M. &amp; Ahamad, S. R. Comparative study on the chemical composition of Corchorus olitoriusl leaf and stem dry oils. <i>Biomed Res.</i><b>28</b>(10), 4581&#x2013;4587 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasinmirin, J. &amp; Olufayo, A. Yield and water use efficiency of jute mallow Corchorus olitorius under varying soil water management strategies. <i>J. Med. Plants Res.</i><b>3</b>(4), 186&#x2013;191 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M., Bano, S., Javed, K. &amp; Mueed, M. A. A comprehensive review on the chemistry and pharmacology of Corchorus species&#x2014;a source of cardiac glycosides, triterpenoids, ionones, flavonoids, coumarins, steroids and some other compounds. <i>J. Sci. Ind. Res.</i><b>65</b>(4), 283&#x2013;298 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furumoto, T. et al. Antitumor promoters in leaves of jute (Corchorus capsularis and Corchorus olitorius). <i>Food Sci. Technol. Res.</i><b>8</b>(3), 239&#x2013;243 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3136/fstr.8.239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagbohun T.I.E. (2011). 2. physicochemical properties and in vitro anti-bacterial activity of <i>Corchorus olitorius linn.</i> seed oil by 1 TA Ibrahim and 2 ED Fagbohun. Life Sciences Leaflets. 15: 499-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oboh, G. et al. Inhibitory effect of polyphenol-rich extracts of jute leaf (Corchorus olitorius) on key enzyme linked to type 2 diabetes (&#x3b1;-amylase and &#x3b1;-glucosidase) and hypertension (angiotensin I converting) in vitro. <i>J. Funct. Foods.</i><b>4</b>(2), 450&#x2013;458 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2012.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagdy, R. et al. neuromodulatory activity of dietary phenolics derived from Corchorus olitorius L. <i>J. Food Sci.</i><b>84</b>(5), 1012&#x2013;1022 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.14587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31017668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shariare, M. H. et al. Liposomal drug delivery of Corchorus olitorius leaf extract containing phytol using design of experiment (DoE): In-vitro anticancer and in-vivo anti-inflammatory studies. <i>Colloids Surf., B</i><b>199</b>, 111543 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2020.111543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33360927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiruddin, Z. Z., Neelendran, M., Pubalan, S., Sulaiman, M. &amp; Fatimah, C. Effects of opioid and non-opioid antagonists, pH and enzymes on Corchorus olitorius antinociception in mice. <i>Adv. Tradit. Med.</i><b>6</b>(3), 186&#x2013;195 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, M., Abdelwahab, M., Abdelmohsen, U. &amp; Hamed, A. Pharmacological and phytochemical biodiversity of Corchorus olitorius. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>12</b>, 35103&#x2013;35114 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2RA07406K</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9727694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36540263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam, M. T. et al. Revision: Chemical and biological activities of Corchorus olitorius L. <i>Am J PharmTech Res.</i><b>3</b>, 337&#x2013;348 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhayal, K. &amp; Kumar, D. <i>Qualitative and Quantitative Evaluation of Flavonoids from Corchorus olitorius L. Journal of Drug Delivery and Therapeutics.</i><b>9</b>(4-s), 348&#x2013;352 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22270/jddt.v9i4-s.3329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhabal, S. F. et al. Transdermal fluocinolone acetonide loaded decorated hyalurosomes cellulose acetate/polycaprolactone nanofibers mitigated Freund&#x2019;s adjuvant-induced rheumatoid arthritis in rats. <i>J. Pharm. Investig.</i><b>55</b>(1), 113&#x2013;132 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40005-024-00693-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhabal, S. F. et al. Development of thermosensitive hydrogel of Amphotericin-B and Lactoferrin combination-loaded PLGA-PEG-PEI nanoparticles for potential eradication of ocular fungal infections: In-vitro, ex-vivo and in-vivo studies. <i>Int. J. Pharm.: X.</i><b>5</b>, 100174 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9992749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36908304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Zuhairy, S. A. K. S. et al. Polylactic-co-glycolic acid/alginate/neem oil-reduced graphene oxide as a pH-sensitive nanocarrier for hesperidin drug delivery: Antimicrobial and acute otitis media assessments. <i>Pharmaceuticals.</i><b>18</b>(3), 381 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph18030381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11944605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40143156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima, TdPd. L. et al. Poly (&#x3b5;-caprolactone)-Based Scaffolds with Multizonal Architecture: Synthesis, Characterization, and In Vitro Tests. <i>Polymers</i><b>15</b>(22), 4403 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15224403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10674666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38006127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhabal, S. F. et al. Enhanced antibacterial activity of clindamycin using molecularly imprinted polymer nanoparticles loaded with polyurethane nanofibrous scaffolds for the treatment of acne vulgaris. <i>Pharmaceutics.</i><b>16</b>(7), 947&#x2013;1026 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics16070947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11279838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39065644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azzazy, H. M. E. S. et al. Essential oils extracted from boswellia sacra oleo gum resin loaded into PLGA&#x2212;PCL nanoparticles: Enhanced cytotoxic and apoptotic effects against breast cancer cells. <i>ACS Omega</i><b>8</b>, 1017&#x2013;1025 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.2c06390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9835537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36643489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Nabarawi, M. et al. Development of canagliflozin nanocrystals sublingual tablets in the presence of sodium caprate permeability enhancer: Formulation optimization, characterization, in-vitro, in silico, and in-vivo study. <i>Drug Delivery</i><b>30</b>(1), 2241665 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10717544.2023.2241665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10946264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37537858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmonem, R., Elhabal, S. F., Abdelmalak, N. S., El-Nabarawi, M. A. &amp; Teaima, M. H. Formulation and characterization of acetazolamide/carvedilol niosomal gel for glaucoma treatment: In vitro, and in vivo study. <i>Pharmaceutics.</i><b>13</b>(2), 221 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics13020221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7915822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33562785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhabal, S. F. et al. Biosynthesis and characterization of gold and copper nanoparticles from Salvadora persica fruit extracts and their biological properties. <i>Int. J. Nanomed.</i><b>17</b>, 6095&#x2013;6112 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJN.S385543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9741820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36514376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed, M. H. H. et al. Metabolic profiling and cytotoxic activities of ethanol extract of Dypsis leptocheilos aerial parts and its green synthesized silver nanoparticles supported by network pharmacology analysis. <i>S. Afr. J. Bot.</i><b>161</b>, 648&#x2013;665 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sajb.2023.08.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Nawawy, T. M. et al. Intranasal bilosomes in thermosensitive hydrogel: advancing desvenlafaxine succinate delivery for depression management. <i>Pharm. Dev. Technol.</i><b>29</b>(7), 663&#x2013;674 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10837450.2024.2376067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38965754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewedah, T. M. et al. Enhancing cellular affinity for skin disorders: Electrospun polyurethane/collagen nanofiber mats coated with phytoceramides. <i>Int. J. Pharm.</i><b>663</b>, 124541 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2024.124541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39089344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethi, P. Activity of Turbinaria ornata (turner) J. Agade against blue tongue virus (Btv). <i>IOSR J Pharm.</i><b>6</b>(7), 93&#x2013;95 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrighetti-Fr&#xf6;hner, C., Antonio, R., Creczynski-Pasa, T., Barardi, C. &amp; Sim&#xf5;es, C. Cytotoxicity and potential antiviral evaluation of violacein produced by Chromobacterium violaceum. <i>Mem. Inst. Oswaldo Cruz</i><b>98</b>, 843&#x2013;848 (2003).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0074-02762003000600023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14595466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd El-Kareem, M. S., Rabbih, M. A. E. F. &amp; SelimElsherbiny EAE-m, El-Khateeb AY., E. T. M. Application of GC/EIMS in combination with semi-empirical calculations for identification and investigation of some volatile components in basil essential oil. <i>Int. J. Anal. Mass Spectrom. Chromatogr.</i><b>4</b>(1), 14&#x2013;25 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ijamsc.2016.41002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru, J. et al. TCMSP: A database of systems pharmacology for drug discovery from herbal medicines. <i>J. Cheminform.</i><b>6</b>, 13 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-2946-6-13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4001360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24735618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UniProt, C. UniProt: The universal protein knowledgebase in 2021. <i>Nucleic Acids Res.</i><b>49</b>(D1), D480&#x2013;D489 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkaa1100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33237286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveros JCJhbccetvih. VENNY. An interactive tool for comparing lists with Venn Diagrams. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szklarczyk, D. et al. The STRING database in 2023: Protein-protein association networks and functional enrichment analyses for any sequenced genome of interest. <i>Nucleic Acids Res.</i><b>51</b>(D1), D638&#x2013;D646 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkac1000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36370105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon, P. et al. Cytoscape: A software environment for integrated models of biomolecular interaction networks. <i>Genome Res.</i><b>13</b>(11), 2498&#x2013;2504 (2003).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gr.1239303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC403769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14597658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan, S. T., &#x160;udomov&#xe1;, M., Berchov&#xe1;-B&#xed;mov&#xe1;, K., &#x160;mejkal, K. &amp; Echeverr&#xed;a, J. Psoromic acid, a lichen-derived molecule, inhibits the replication of HSV-1 and HSV-2, and inactivates HSV-1 DNA polymerase: Shedding light on antiherpetic properties. <i>Molecules</i><b>24</b>(16), 2912 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24162912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6720901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31405197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shoubki, A. A., Teaima, M. H., Abdelmonem, R., El-Nabarawi, M. A. &amp; Elhabal, S. F. Potential application of sucrose acetate isobutyrate, and glyceryl monooleate for nanonization and bioavailability enhancement of rivaroxaban tablets. <i>Pharm. Sci. Adv.</i><b>2</b>, 100015 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pscia.2023.100015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37870222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Shoubki, A. A., Teaima, M. H., Abdelmonem, R., El-Nabarawi, M. A. &amp; Elhabal, S. F. Sucrose acetate isobutyrate (SAIB) and glyceryl monooleate (GMO) hybrid nanoparticles for bioavailability enhancement of rivaroxaban: An optimization study. <i>Pharm. Dev. Technol.</i><b>28</b>(10), 928&#x2013;938 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10837450.2023.2274944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37870222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, Y. et al. Alpha-herpesvirus thymidine kinase genes mediate viral virulence and are potential therapeutic targets. <i>Front. Microbiol.</i><b>10</b>, 941 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2019.00941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6517553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31134006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>