<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41696340</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on Leakage Diffusion and Prediction Model of Multifactor High-Pressure Buried Hydrogen-Blended Natural Gas Pipeline.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8154</StartPage><EndPage>8171</EndPage><MedlinePgn>8154-8171</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c10547</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hydrogen is an important carrier of clean energy, and its transport through existing natural gas pipeline networks has become an international consensus for large-scale delivery. The existing large-scale, long-distance transportation of natural gas relies on buried pipelines. However, there are significant differences in the physical and chemical properties of methane and hydrogen. Hydrogen mixed into the natural gas pipeline network for transportation may cause hydrogen embrittlement in the pipeline, which can lead to leakage and explosion accidents, causing serious injury to the surrounding personnel and property. In this study, numerical simulation was used to explore the leakage and diffusion laws of buried high-pressure hydrogen-blended natural gas (HBNG) pipelines as well as the initial explosion time (IET) and leakage of HBNG in forming the ground surface explosion zone under different hydrogen blending ratios (HBRs), soil properties, pipeline pressure, burial depth, soil temperature, leakage hole diameter, and other influencing factors. The results demonstrate that soil properties significantly influence the diffusion characteristics of gas leakage. The increases in leakage hole diameter, pipeline pressure, HBRs, and soil temperature all contribute to an earlier IET. The formation of IET is significantly delayed with increasing burial depth. The increase in HBR will lead to a decrease in gas leakage, and the two are negatively correlated. Multivariate function prediction models of IET and mass flow rate were established by coupling multiple influencing factors with average errors of 4.7 and 2.67%, respectively. This study provides a numerical reference for optimizing the maintenance and repair plans and emergency response plans after the HBNG pipeline leakage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ban</LastName><ForeName>Jiuqing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Natural Gas Technology, PetroChina Southwest Oil and Gas Field Company, Chengdu 610213, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">201377</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Natural Gas Quality Control and Energy Measurement for State Market Regulation, Chengdu 610213, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Chongqing University of Science &amp; Technology, Chongqing 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Natural Gas Technology, PetroChina Southwest Oil and Gas Field Company, Chengdu 610213, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">201377</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Natural Gas Quality Control and Energy Measurement for State Market Regulation, Chengdu 610213, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Gang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6476-3395</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Chongqing University of Science &amp; Technology, Chongqing 401331, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaodong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PetroChina Southwest Oil and Gas Field Company, Chengdu 610056, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">201377</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Xiaopeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7422-2963</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy, School of Petroleum and Natural Gas Engineering, Changzhou University, Changzhou 213164, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12412</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNPC-CZU Innovation Alliance, Changzhou University, Changzhou 213164, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12412</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoyun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of Natural Gas Technology, PetroChina Southwest Oil and Gas Field Company, Chengdu 610213, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">201377</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Natural Gas Quality Control and Energy Measurement for State Market Regulation, Chengdu 610213, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41696340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12903143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c10547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Xiao H., Li S.. et al. Improved hydrogen storage capacity and cyclic properties of TiCr&#xad;(FeV80) alloys by heat treatment and Ce doping. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;94:341&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ban J., Yan X., Song B.. et al. Research Progress and Prospects on Hydrogen Damage in Welds of Hydrogen-Blended Natural Gas Pipelines. Processes. 2023;11(11):3180. doi: 10.3390/pr11113180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11113180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng S., Liu Q., Xu S.. et al. Local practices and insights of China&#x2019;s hydrogen energy industry. Chem. Eng. Oil Gas. 2024;53(05):7&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu E., Li T., Pang J.. Research on the leakage characteristics of hydrogen-blended natural gas pipelines in urban residential courtyards. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2025;189:152178. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.152178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Fu G., Liao Q.. et al. Large-scale hydrogen supply chain vision with blended pipeline transportation of China. Renewable Energy. 2025;240:122230. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2024.122230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2024.122230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Li J., Yu B.. Simulation of Explosion of Hydrogen-enriched Natural Gas in Indoor Confined Space. Sci. Technol. Eng. 2022;22(14):5608&#x2013;5614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P., Hu L., Zhang J.. et al. Considerations on blending hydrogen into natural gas pipeline networks in western China. Int. Petrol. Econ. 2021;29(09):73&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F., Dong S., Chen L.. et al. Key Safety Technologies And Advances In Long-Distance Pipeline Transportation Of Hydrogen Blended Natural Gas. Mech. Eng. 2023;45(02):230&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Y., Li Q., Wang J.. et al. Scheme and economic analysis of hydrogen blended natural gas separation. Chem. Eng. Oil Gas. 2023;52(04):41&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Li C., Jia W.. et al. Under-expanded jet and diffusion characteristics for small-hole leakage of hydrogen-blended natural gas in high-pressure pipelines. Process Safety Environ. Protect. 2024;190:195&#x2013;211. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2024.07.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2024.07.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L., Qiao L., Fan J.. et al. Investigation on leakage characteristics and consequences of hydrogen-blended gas pipelines based on CFD with the full multicomponent diffusion model. Renewable Energy. 2025;252:123502. doi: 10.1016/j.renene.2025.123502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.renene.2025.123502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao X., Shi W., Li P.. et al. Explosion-prevention strategies of airflow controlling and closed-inerting for hydrogen dilution in utility tunnel. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2023;48(37):14095&#x2013;14111. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.12.221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.12.221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Li C., Jia W.. et al. Study on multicomponent leakage and diffusion characteristics of hydrogen-blended natural gas in utility tunnels. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;50:740&#x2013;760. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.06.262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.06.262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K., Zheng Z., Li W.. et al. Dynamic evolution of flame and overpressure of leakage and explosion of hydrogen-blended natural gas in utility tunnels. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;96:1&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J., Pan J., Zhang Y.. et al. Leakage and diffusion behavior of a buried pipeline of hydrogen-blended natural gas. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2023;48(30):11592&#x2013;11610. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.10.185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2022.10.185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Chen J., Ma T.. et al. Numerical study of leakage characteristics of hydrogen-blended natural gas in buried pipelines. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;49:1166&#x2013;1179. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.07.293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.07.293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi-Moghadam A., Farzaneh-Gord M., Deymi-Dashtebayaz M.. Correlations for estimating natural gas leakage from above-ground and buried urban distribution pipelines&#xad;[J] J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2016;34:185&#x2013;196. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2016.06.062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2016.06.062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Wang Y., Liang Y.. et al. CFD analysis of leakage and diffusion characteristics in the buried hydrogen-blended natural gas pipeline. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;60:354&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11411537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39310181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H., Guo B., Chen X.. et al. Numerical investigation on leakage and diffusion characteristics of buried hydrogen-blended natural gas pipelines. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;59:1491&#x2013;1506. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Xie B., Gong L.. Numerical Research on Leakage Characteristics of Pure Hydrogen/Hydrogen-Blended Natural Gas in Medium-and Low-Pressure Buried Pipelines&#xad;[J] Energies. 2024;17(12):2951. doi: 10.3390/en17122951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17122951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Tian X.. Numerical investigation of the leakage and diffusion characteristics of hydrogen-blended natural gas in long-distance pipelines. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;90:950&#x2013;960. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Zhao G.. Leakage and diffusion characteristics of underground hydrogen pipeline. Petroleum. 2024;10(2):319&#x2013;325. doi: 10.1016/j.petlm.2023.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petlm.2023.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu W., Chen G., Qi B.. et al. Numerical simulation of leakage and diffusion of buried pure hydrogen/hydrogen-doped natural gas pipeline. Oil Gas Storage Transp. 2023;42(10):1118&#x2013;1127+1136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng S., Luo X.. Numerical simulation of leakage and diffusion in buried hydrogen-blended natural gas pipeline. China Safety Sci. J. 2024;34(03):63&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Yang Y., Wu F.. et al. Numerical investigation on pinhole leakage and diffusion characteristics of medium-pressure buried hydrogen pipeline. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2024;51:807&#x2013;817. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.04.209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.04.209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng S., Luo X., Yang L.. Numerical simulation of leakage and diffusion rules of hydrogen blended natural gas long-distance transportation pipelines. Chem. Eng. Oil Gas. 2023;52(06):44&#x2013;52+59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi-Moghadam A., Farzaneh-Gord M., Arabkoohsar A.. et al. CFD analysis of natural gas emission from damaged pipelines: Correlation development for leakage estimation. J. Clean. Prod. 2018;199:257&#x2013;271. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.07.127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.07.127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Tan Y., Zhang T.. et al. Numerical study on the diffusion process of pinhole leakage of natural gas from underground pipelines to the soil. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2021;87:103792. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, X. Numerical Simulation of Leakage and Diffusion Flow Field of Urban Buried Gas Pipeline; Lanzhou University of Technology: Lanzhou, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ergun S.. Fluid flow through packed columns. Chem. Eng. Progr. 1952;48(2):89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shur M., Spalart P., Strelets M.. et al. Detached-eddy simulation of an airfoil at high angle of attack. Eng. Turbul. Modell. Exp. 1999;4:669&#x2013;678. doi: 10.1016/B978-008043328-8/50064-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-008043328-8/50064-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Zhang P., Zhou N.. et al. Application of detached-eddy simulation based on Spalart-Allmaras turbulence model. J. Beijing Univ. Aeronaut. Astronaut. 2012;38(07):905&#x2013;909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Su Z., Li X.. Three-dimensional numerical simulation of flow around two side-by-side circular cylinders at high Reynolds numbers using DES method. Chin. J. Hydrodyn. 2014;29(04):412&#x2013;420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spalart, P. R. Comments on the Feasibility of LES for Wings and on the Hybrid RANS/LES Approach. In Proceedings of the First AFOSR International Conference on DNS/LES, 1997; pp 137&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, D. Investigations and Applications of Detached Eddy Simulation; Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics: Nanjing, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu F., Liu Y., Chen S.. et al. Real scenario analysis of buried natural gas pipeline leakage based on soil-atmosphere coupling. Int. J. Pressure Vessels Piping. 2022;199:104713. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpvp.2022.104713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpvp.2022.104713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou H., Pei P., Hao D.. et al. Numerical analysis of the effect of different soil types and water content on heat transfer performance of horizontal buried pipes. Coal Geol. Explorat. 2021;49(06):221&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Z. H., Xu Z. D., Lu H. F.. et al. Leakage analysis and prediction model of underground high-pressure natural gas pipeline considering box culvert protection. Process Saf. Environ. Prot. 2023;180:837&#x2013;855. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2023.10.052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2023.10.052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. Numerical Simulation and Experimental Study on Leakage Diffusion of Buried Gas Pipeline; Tianjin Chengjian University: Tianjin, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GB 50251-2015. Code for Design of Transmission Pipeline Engineering, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Liu J., Zhang B.. et al. Development status and trend of pipeline steel for long-distance natural gas transportation in China. Trans. Mater. Heat Treat. 2024;45(03):98&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu P., Pan D., Yuan X.. et al. Progress of research on leakage diffusion of gas pipelines. Oil Gas Storage Transport. 2022;41(01):21&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen J., Wu L., Zhang Y.. Investigation on natural gas leakage and diffusion characteristics. World Pet. Ind. 2024;31(05):65&#x2013;72+82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao Y., Yan D., Ma L.. et al. Simulation detection and evaluation of pipeline leakage based on computational fluid dynamics. J. Water Res. Water Eng. 2024;35(02):122&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Y., Dong X., Li J.. Experimental study of methane diffusion in soil for an underground gas pipe leak. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2015;27:82&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2015.08.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2015.08.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao B., Zhao R., Kuai C.. et al. Numerical Simulation of Leak Diffusion and Failure Consequences of High- Pressure Hydrogen-Doped Natural Gas Pipelines. J. Liaoning Pet. Univ. 2023;43(02):60&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H., Chang X., Duan P.. et al. Study on the leakage and diffusion behavior of hydrogen-blended natural gas in utility tunnels. J. Loss Prevent. Process Ind. 2023;85:105151. doi: 10.1016/j.jlp.2023.105151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jlp.2023.105151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koshiba Y., Hasegawa T., Kim B.. et al. Flammability limits, explosion pressures, and applicability of Le Chatelier&#x2019;s rule to binary alkane&#x2013;nitrous oxide mixtures. J. Loss Prev. Process Ind. 2017;45:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.jlp.2016.11.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jlp.2016.11.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molnarne M., Schroeder V.. Hazardous properties of hydrogen and hydrogen containing fuel gases. Process Safety Environ. Protect. 2019;130:1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2019.07.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2019.07.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GB/T 50493-2019. Petrochemical combustible gas and toxic gas detection and alarm design standard[S], 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bu F., Liu Y., Liu Y.. et al. Leakage diffusion characteristics and harmful boundary analysis of buried natural gas pipeline under multiple working conditions. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2021;94:104047. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>