<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41480404</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1948-0210</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of stem cells</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Stem Cells</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does standalone/combined subchondral bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem/stromal cell injection offer significantly better clinical benefit to intraarticular injection in knee osteoarthritis?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>112778</StartPage><MedlinePgn>112778</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">112778</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4252/wjsc.v17.i12.112778</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Knee osteoarthritis (OA) is a degenerative joint disease traditionally viewed through the lens of cartilage degradation. However, emerging evidence positions subchondral bone pathology - particularly bone marrow lesions (BMLs) - as a key contributor to pain, progression, and structural deterioration. Mesenchymal stem cell exhaustion within the osteoarthritic subchondral zone further impairs intrinsic repair mechanisms, reinforcing the rationale for biologic interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the clinical efficacy of bone marrow aspirate concentrate (BMAC) therapy for knee OA, comparing subchondral <i>vs</i> intra-articular delivery routes, and elucidating the therapeutic impact on symptom relief and structural preservation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses guidelines, five clinical studies were included - comprising three randomized controlled trials and two prospective cohorts - with pooled data from 298 knees. Data on functional outcomes, imaging findings, and progression to total knee arthroplasty (TKA) were extracted and qualitatively synthesized.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Subchondral BMAC injections demonstrated superior improvements compared to intra-articular injection or placebo: Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score improved from 49.1 &#xb1; 1.9 to 61.2 &#xb1; 6.3 at 12 months (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05), Knee Society Score increased from 57 &#xb1; 12 to 87.3 &#xb1; 12 at two years, and Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Arthritis Index scores showed significant improvement favoring combined approaches. Magnetic resonance imaging analyses revealed mean BML volume regression of 2.1 cm<sup>3</sup>, with 80% of knees avoiding TKA over 13-year follow-up. Magnetic resonance imaging analyses revealed regression of BMLs and increased cartilage preservation in subchondral-treated knees. Long-term data indicated delayed progression to TKA and biomechanical improvements (<i>e.g.</i>, Hip-Knee-Ankle angle correction). No major adverse events were reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Targeting subchondral bone with BMAC addresses underlying OA pathology and may offer disease-modifying potential beyond symptom relief. These findings support a paradigm shift toward whole-joint biologic therapy, positioning the subchondral matrix as a therapeutic epicenter in OA management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nallakumarasamy</LastName><ForeName>Arulkumar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha 442004, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Mother Cell Regenerative Centre, Tiruchirappalli 620017, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Agathisha Institute of Stemcell and Regenerative Medicine (AISRM), Chennai 600030, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shrivastava</LastName><ForeName>Sandeep</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha 442004, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rangarajan</LastName><ForeName>Ravi Velamoor</ForeName><Initials>RV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Mother Cell Regenerative Centre, Tiruchirappalli 620017, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeyaraman</LastName><ForeName>Naveen</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha 442004, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Mother Cell Regenerative Centre, Tiruchirappalli 620017, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Agathisha Institute of Stemcell and Regenerative Medicine (AISRM), Chennai 600030, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Devadas</LastName><ForeName>Avinash Gandi</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Mother Cell Regenerative Centre, Tiruchirappalli 620017, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramasubramanian</LastName><ForeName>Swaminathan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Agathisha Institute of Stemcell and Regenerative Medicine (AISRM), Chennai 600030, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muthu</LastName><ForeName>Sathish</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Agathisha Institute of Stemcell and Regenerative Medicine (AISRM), Chennai 600030, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Research Laboratory, Meenakshi Medical College Hospital and Research Institute, Meenakshi Academy of Higher Education and Research, Kanchipuram 631552, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bapat</LastName><ForeName>Asawari</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Stem Cells and Regenerative Medicine, Infohealth FZE, Dubai 6824, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Stem Cells and Regenerative Medicine, Questar Enterprise, LLC, Dubai 6824, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Stem Cells and Regenerative Medicine, Clinical Affairs, Regenerative Outcomes, Nashville, TN 40211, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeyaraman</LastName><ForeName>Madhan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Mother Cell Regenerative Centre, Tiruchirappalli 620017, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Regenerative Medicine, Agathisha Institute of Stemcell and Regenerative Medicine (AISRM), Chennai 600030, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, ACS Medical College and Hospital, Dr. MGR Educational and Research Institute, Chennai 600077, Tamil Nadu, India. madhanjeyaraman@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Stem Cells</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535826</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1948-0210</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone marrow aspirate concentrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone marrow lesions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intra-articular injection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal stem cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Orthobiologics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Regenerative medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subchondral injection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41480404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12754453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4252/wjsc.v17.i12.112778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hunter DJ, Bierma-Zeinstra S. Osteoarthritis. Lancet. 2019;393:1745&#x2013;1759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31034380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Yin J, Gao J, Cheng TS, Pavlos NJ, Zhang C, Zheng MH. Subchondral bone in osteoarthritis: insight into risk factors and microstructural changes. Arthritis Res Ther. 2013;15:223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4061721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24321104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x10c;amernik K, Miheli&#x10d; A, Mihali&#x10d; R, Marolt Presen D, Jane&#x17e; A, Treb&#x161;e R, Marc J, Zupan J. Increased Exhaustion of the Subchondral Bone-Derived Mesenchymal Stem/ Stromal Cells in Primary Versus Dysplastic Osteoarthritis. Stem Cell Rev Rep. 2020;16:742&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernigou J, Vertongen P, Rasschaert J, Hernigou P. Role of Scaffolds, Subchondral, Intra-Articular Injections of Fresh Autologous Bone Marrow Concentrate Regenerative Cells in Treating Human Knee Cartilage Lesions: Different Approaches and Different Results. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:3844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Mai Y, Fang X, Wang Z, Xue S, Chen H, Dang Q, Wang X, Tang S, Ding C, Zhu Z. Bone marrow lesions in osteoarthritis: From basic science to clinical implications. Bone Rep. 2023;18:101667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9996250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36909666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Chan YT, Yung PSH, Tuan RS, Jiang Y. Subchondral Bone Remodeling: A Therapeutic Target for Osteoarthritis. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8:607764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7859330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33553146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Chen X, Wang S, Jing Y, Su J. Subchondral bone microenvironment in osteoarthritis and pain. Bone Res. 2021;9:20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7969608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33731688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donell S. Subchondral bone remodelling in osteoarthritis. EFORT Open Rev. 2019;4:221&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6549114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31210964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanamas SK, Wluka AE, Pelletier JP, Pelletier JM, Abram F, Berry PA, Wang Y, Jones G, Cicuttini FM. Bone marrow lesions in people with knee osteoarthritis predict progression of disease and joint replacement: a longitudinal study. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2010;49:2413&#x2013;2419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20823092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthu S, Kandasamy R, Palanisamy S, Palaniappan AA. Subchondral Cellular Density Decreases with Increasing Grade of Cartilage Degeneration in Knee Osteoarthritis - An Ex vivo Histopathological Analysis. J Orthop Case Rep. 2025;15:227&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11823870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39957951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pabinger C, Lothaller H, Kobinia GS. Intra-articular injection of bone marrow aspirate concentrate (mesenchymal stem cells) in KL grade III and IV knee osteoarthritis: 4 year results of 37 knees. Sci Rep. 2024;14:2665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38302491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park D, Koh HS, Choi YH, Park I. Bone Marrow Aspirate Concentrate (BMAC) for Knee Osteoarthritis: A Narrative Review of Clinical Efficacy and Future Directions. Medicina (Kaunas) 2025;61:853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12113016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40428811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si-Hyeong Park S, Li B, Kim C. Efficacy of intra-articular injections for the treatment of osteoarthritis: A narrative review. Osteoarthr Cartil Open. 2025;7:100596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11938051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40144957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pabinger C, Kobinia GS, Dammerer D. Injection therapy in knee osteoarthritis: cortisol, hyaluronic acid, PRP, or BMAC (mesenchymal stem cell therapy)? Front Med (Lausanne) 2024;11:1463997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11466841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39399118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon E, Boffa A, Andriolo L, Di Martino A, Di Matteo B, Magarelli N, Trenti N, Zaffagnini S, Filardo G. Combined subchondral and intra-articular injections of bone marrow aspirate concentrate provide stable results up to 24 months. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31:2511&#x2013;2517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36326876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva S, Andriolo L, Boffa A, Di Martino A, Reale D, Vara G, Miceli M, Cavallo C, Grigolo B, Zaffagnini S, Filardo G. Prospective double-blind randomised controlled trial protocol comparing bone marrow aspirate concentrate intra-articular injection combined with subchondral injection versus intra-articular injection alone for the treatment of symptomatic knee osteoarthritis. BMJ Open. 2022;12:e062632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9462121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36468635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernigou P, Bouthors C, Bastard C, Flouzat Lachaniette CH, Rouard H, Dubory A. Subchondral bone or intra-articular injection of bone marrow concentrate mesenchymal stem cells in bilateral knee osteoarthritis: what better postpone knee arthroplasty at fifteen years? A randomized study. Int Orthop. 2021;45:391&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32617651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madrazo-Ibarra A, Barve R, Carroll KM, Proner R, Topar C, Ibarra C, Coleman SH, Vad V. Carboplasty, a Simple Tibial Marrow Technique for Knee Osteoarthritis: A Placebo-Controlled Randomized Trial. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10:23259671221143743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9793044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36582935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernigou P, Delambre J, Quiennec S, Poignard A. Human bone marrow mesenchymal stem cell injection in subchondral lesions of knee osteoarthritis: a prospective randomized study versus contralateral arthroplasty at a mean fifteen&#xa0;year follow-up. Int Orthop. 2021;45:365&#x2013;373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32322943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centeno C, Cartier C, Stemper I, Dodson E, Freeman M, Azuike U, Williams C, Hyzy M, Silva O, Steinmetz N. The Treatment of Bone Marrow Lesions Associated with Advanced Knee Osteoarthritis: Comparing Intraosseous and Intraarticular Injections with Bone Marrow Concentrate and Platelet Products. Pain Physician. 2021;24:E279&#x2013;E288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33988949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon E, Boffa A, Andriolo L, Di Martino A, Di Matteo B, Magarelli N, Marcacci M, Onorato F, Trenti N, Zaffagnini S, Filardo G. Subchondral and intra-articular injections of bone marrow concentrate are a safe and effective treatment for knee osteoarthritis: a prospective, multi-center pilot study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2021;29:4232&#x2013;4240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33772602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell TM, Churchman SM, Gomez A, McGonagle D, Conaghan PG, Ponchel F, Jones E. Mesenchymal Stem Cell Alterations in Bone Marrow Lesions in Patients With Hip Osteoarthritis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016;68:1648&#x2013;1659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4941540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26866940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>