<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41204152</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oral health-related knowledge, attitudes, and practices among high school students in Robe Town, Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3848</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3848</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3848</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12889-025-25169-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Oral health is crucial for overall well-being and quality of life. Poor hygiene can lead to dental issues like cavities, gum disease, and bad breath, negatively impacting students' daily activities and health. However, many students, especially in low-income areas, lack adequate knowledge, hold negative attitudes toward oral care, and practice insufficient oral hygiene. This study aimed to assess the oral health knowledge, attitudes, practices, and related factors among high school students in Robe Town, Bale Zone, Oromia, Ethiopia, in 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">From June 1 to July 30, 2024, a cross-sectional survey was conducted with 422 high school students selected via simple random sampling. Data were collected using a structured interviewer questionnaire and analyzed with SPSS version 24. Results were presented in tables and charts, with demographic data summarized descriptively, and Binary logistic regression were calculated to examine relationships between dependent and independent variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">50% demonstrated strong oral health knowledge, 47% had a positive attitude, and 54% adequate oral health habits. Male students had lower odds of strong knowledge (AOR: 0.60; 95% CI: 0.39-0.93), while Grade 11 students had higher odds. Key factors associated with strong knowledge included proper brushing (AOR: 2.34), using a toothbrush (AOR: 2.35), regular dental visits (AOR: 1.24), and a positive attitude toward dental care (AOR: 1.93). Males also had lower odds of a positive attitude while Grade 11 students had higher odds (AOR: 1.98; 95% CI: 1.03-3.82). Additionally, Grade 11 students were nearly three times more likely to engage in good practices (AOR: 2.89), with factors like visiting the dentist only when in pain (AOR: 2.12; 95% CI: 1.1-4.05), regular visits (AOR: 1.38), a positive attitude (AOR: 2.49), and strong knowledge (AOR: 2.71; 95% CI: 0.47-0.96) contributing to better oral health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Oral health-related knowledge, attitude, and practice among adolescents in Robe Town were found to be suboptimal. Female students, those in higher grades, students with educated parents, and those with prior exposure to oral health information showed significantly better outcomes. Strengthening school-based oral health education, integrating oral health into the curriculum, and engaging parents and teachers are crucial to improve adolescent oral health behaviors in Ethiopia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geda</LastName><ForeName>Zelalem Tolosa</ForeName><Initials>ZT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Natural and Computational Science, Madda Walabu University, Bale-Robe, Oromia, Ethiopia. zelalemtolosa714@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asefa</LastName><ForeName>Ketema Zerihun</ForeName><Initials>KZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Natural and Computational Science, Madda Walabu University, Bale-Robe, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonfa</LastName><ForeName>Asefu Nigussie</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Natural and Computational Science, Madda Walabu University, Bale-Robe, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Assefa</LastName><ForeName>Mesfin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Health Science, Salale University, Fiche, Oromia, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009909" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oral Health</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009910" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oral Hygiene</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attitude</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High school students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oral health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Practices</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study titled &#x201c;Knowledge, Attitude, Practice and Associated Factors towards Oral Health among High School Students in Robe Town, Bale Zone, Oromia South East Ethiopia, 2024&#x201d; was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles laid out in the Declaration of Helsinki and following the guidelines of the Salale University Institutional Research Ethics Review Committee (SIU-IRERC). The research protocol received ethical clearance from the SIU-IRERC under reference number SIU-IRERC-267/2016, dated 10 December 2016. The committee reviewed and approved the research for ethical soundness and adherence to responsible research conduct involving human participants. All participants were fully informed about the objectives and procedures of the study. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to their involvement. For participants under the age of 18, written informed consent was also obtained from their parents or legal guardians. The principal investigator is required to submit progress and final reports to the SIU-IRERC, in accordance with institutional requirements. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41204152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12595614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-25169-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12889-025-25169-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ORGANIZATION WH. Continuous improvement of oral health in the 21st century-the approach of the WHO Global Oral Health Program. The world oral health report. 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glick M, Williams DM, Kleinman DV, Vujicic M, Watt RG, Weyant RJ. A new definition for oral health developed by the FDI world dental federation opens the door to a universal definition of oral health. Br Dent J. 2016;221:792&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.bdj.2016.953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27981999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma K, Sharma A, Neemawat K. A study to evaluate the effectiveness of competency-based training program for the dental interns of a tertiary care center in Jaipur City. CHRISMED J Health Res. 2020;7:110&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/cjhr.cjhr_60_19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PERES MA, MACPHERSON LM, MATHUR WEYANTRJDALYBVENTURELLIR, LISTL MR, GUARNIZO-HERRE&#xd1;O SCELESTERK, C. C., KEARNS C. Oral diseases: a global public health challenge. Lancet. 2019;394:249&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)31146-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque M, Sartelli M, Haque SZ. Dental infection and resistance&#x2014;global health consequences. Dent J Basel. 2019;7:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/dj7010022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30823670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AIM&#xc9;E NR, VAN WIJK AJ, VARJ&#xc3;O MM, PAES, A. B., LOUREN&#xc7;O, J., MESTRINHO, H. D., CARVALHO JC. Changes in adolescents&#x2019; oral health status: responsiveness of the child perception Questionnaire11&#x2013;14. Caries Res. 2020;54:15&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000501587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31362297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HAQUE SE, RAHMAN M, MUTAHARA ITSUKOK, KAYAKO M, TSUTSUMI S, ISLAM A, M. J., MOSTOFA MG. Effect of a school-based oral health education in preventing untreated dental caries and increasing knowledge, attitude, and practices among adolescents in Bangladesh. BMC Oral Health. 2016;16:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-016-0202-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4807560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27016080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MULLA RO, OMAR OM. Assessment of oral health knowledge, attitude and practices among medical students of Taibah university in Madinah, KSA. Br J Med Med Res. 2016;18:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9734/BJMMR/2016/29778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baloch S, Panezai S, Murtaza G. Knowledge, attitude and practice of oral health among school students in Balochistan, Pakistan. Public Health Res. 2021;11:99&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton K, Yusuf H, Vassallo P. The WHO global oral health action plan 2023&#x2013;2030. Community Dent Health. 2023;40:68&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37265395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CITARISTI I. World health Organization&#x2014;WHO. The Europa directory of international organizations 2022. Routledge; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teshome A, Muche A, Girma B. Prevalence of dental caries and associated factors in East Africa, 2000&#x2013;2020: systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Public Health. 2021;9:645091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.645091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8116500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33996722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawal FB, Oke GA. Clinical and sociodemographic factors associated with oral health knowledge, attitude, and practices of adolescents in Nigeria. SAGE Open Med. 2020;8:2050312120951066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312120951066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7446260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ORGANIZATION WH. Promoting oral health in Africa. Republic of Congo. WHO Regional Office for Africa. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezzofranco L, Zalunardo F, Magliarditi A, Gracco A. Assessment of oral health in a child cohort of a rural zone of Ethiopia. Children. 2023. 10.3390/children10111824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/children10111824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10670308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38002914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualie YT, Tayachew AT. Assessment of knowledge, attitude, and practice toward oral hygiene among governmental secondary school students in Debre Tabor Town, Amhara Region, North central Ethiopia 2018: institutional-based cross-sectional survey. Int J Oral Health Sci. 2018;8:92&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijohs.ijohs_37_18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ABATE B, EPHREM M, GEBREMARIAM M, AYALEW Y, SHIMELS T. Knowledge, attitude and practices towards oral hygiene among students of Medhanealem High School, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghanbarzadegan A, Ivanovski S, Sloan A, Spallek H. Oral health research funding in relation to disease burden in Australia. Aust Dent J. 2023;68:42&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/adj.12949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36461728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Oral health Seventy-fourth world health assembly agenda item 13.2. J Dent Res Rev. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HEALTHORGANIZATION W. Oral Health condition world wide report.2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NEWMAN M, TAKEI H, KLOKKEVOLD P. Carranza&#x2019;s clinical periodontology 12th edition. Canada. Elsevier; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abate B, Ephrem M, Gebremariam M, Ayalew Y, Shimels T. Knowledge, attitude and practices towards oral hygiene among students of Medhanealem high school, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. J Dent Res Rev. 2020;7(2):42&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BEYENE DH, DIGESA SHASHAMOBB, L. E., TARIKU EZ. 2021. Oral hygiene practices and associated factors among patients visiting private dental clinics at Hawassa City, Southern Ethiopia. 2018. Int J Dent.&#xa0;2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Tayar BA, Ahmad A, Sinor MZ, Harun MH. Oral health knowledge, attitude, and practices among Yemeni school students. J Int Oral Health. 2019;11:15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jioh.jioh_176_18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Batayneh OB, Owais AI, Khader YS. Oral health knowledge and practices among diverse university students with access to free dental care: a cross-sectional study. Open J Stomatology. 2014;4:135&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojst.2014.43021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajbhandari A, Aryal N. Assessment of knowledge, attitude and practice (KAP) on oral health among secondary-level students: a cross-sectional study in Kathmandu, Nepal. BMJ Public Health. 2024. 10.1136/bmjph-2023-000438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjph-2023-000438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40018160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayingana JM, Shyaka G, Ogendi J. Knowledge, attitude and practices towards oral health among secondary school students in Huye district, Rwanda. Afr Health Sci. 2024;24:250&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/ahs.v24i1.30</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11217848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38962326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anuja R, Nishika A. Assessment of knowledge, attitude and practice (KAP) on oral health among secondary-level students: a cross-sectional study in Kathmandu, Nepal. BMJ Public Health. 2024;2:e000438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjph-2023-000438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11812795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40018160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvaraj S, Naing NN, Wan-Arfah N, Abreu MHNGD. Assessment on oral health knowledge, attitude, and behaviour and its association with sociodemographic and habitual factors of South Indian population. Pesqui Bras Odontopediatr Clin Integr. 2021a;21:e0135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/pboci.2021.159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opoku P, Salu S, Azornu CK, Komesuor J. Oral health knowledge, practice and associated factors among junior high school students of Koforidua, Ghana: a cross-sectional study. BMC Oral Health. 2024;24:449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-024-04148-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11015567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38609937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHANIE ES, CHANIE KS, MOGES N, ANLEY DT, ASMARE ZA, ZEMENE MA, GEBEYEHU NA, MENGSTIE MA, SEID MA, ABEBE EC, GESESE MM, KEBEDE YS, BANTIE B, FELEKE SF, DEJENIE TA, TESFA NA, DESSIE AM, HAILEMESKEL HS, CHANIE TS, &amp; CHANIE SS. Proportion of good oral hygiene and mean value oral hygiene index among children with cerebral palsy in Africa and Asia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Oral Health. 2024;24: 1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11619678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39639294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZHENG S, ZHAO L, ZHANG JUNHUAT, S., LIAO S. Relationship between oral health-related knowledge, attitudes, practice, self-rated oral health and oral health-related quality of life among Chinese college students: a structural equation modeling approach. BMC Oral Health. 2021a;21:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-021-01419-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7936478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MODIKOE MM. Oral health-related knowledge, attitude and practices [KAP] of adult patients in the Mangaung metropolitan Municipality, South Africa. University of the Free State; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FARMER-DIXON CM, THOMPSON MF, BARBOUR JA. Health disparities in oral health. Oral Health and Aging. Springer; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Anouti F, Abboud M, Papandreou D, Haidar S, Mahboub N, Rizk R. Oral health of children and adolescents in the United Arab Emirates: a systematic review of the past decade. Front Oral Health. 2021;2:744328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/froh.2021.744328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8757796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantaye W, Kifle Nura G, Engida F. Oral health knowledge and oral hygiene practice among visually impaired subjects in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. BMC Oral Health. 2022;22:167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-022-02199-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9077845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL-ANSARI JM, HONKALA S. Gender differences in oral health knowledge and behavior of the health science college students in Kuwait. J Allied Health. 2007;36:41&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17425190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar MS. Knowledge, attitude and practices towards oral health among law students in Chennai. J Pharm Sci Res. 2016;8:650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SCHENSUL JJ, SALVI A, HA T, LI GRADYJ, J., REISINE S. Evaluating Cognitive/Emotional and behavioral mediators of oral health outcomes in vulnerable older adults. J Appl Gerontol. 2022;41:187&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0733464820974920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8184860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33292050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SR, Kroon J, Schwarzer R, Hamilton K. Parental social-cognitive correlates of preschoolers&#x2019; oral hygiene behavior: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Soc Sci Med. 2020;264:113322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32916333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BROWN ME. The influence of conformity to masculine norms on relationship satisfaction: an examination of Rumination, emotional Inhibition, and gender differences. Purdue University; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakhata R, Balimuttajjo S, Mutarutinya V. Relationship between students&#x2019; attitude towards, and performance in mathematics word problems. PLoS ONE. 2024;19:e0278593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0278593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10846736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38319935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JONES A, TAYLOR ETAL. Educational progression and attitudes. Int J. 2019;25(2):145&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MILLER JR, HOHM C. The Impact of Educational Attainment on Life Satisfaction. Journal of Education and Human Development.&#xa0;2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GUARNIZO-HERRE&#xd1;O CC, LYU W, WEHBY GL. School students of oral health and academic performance: evidence of a persisting relationship over the last decade in the united States. J Pediatr. 2019;209:183&#x2013;e1892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2019.01.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6667186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30926152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadin A, Poljak Guberina R, Domazet J, Gavic L. Oral hygiene practices and oral health knowledge among students in Split, Croatia. Healthcare. 2022. 10.3390/healthcare10020406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10020406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8872387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35207018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VANGIPURAM S, JHA A, RAJU R, BASHYAM M. Effectiveness of peer group and conventional method (Dentist) of oral health education programme among 12&#x2013;15 year old school Children - A randomized controlled trial. J Clin Diagn Res. 2016;10:Zc125&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4948521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27437345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KAPHLE M, KARKI TAMANGA, REGMI R, N., KHADKA, R., BAJRACHARYA M. Assessment of oral hygiene practice and associated factors among Middle-aged people in a rural Municipality, Nepal. Archives Dentistry. 2023;5:19&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33696/dentistry.5.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VALDEZ R, SPINLER K, KOFAHL C, REISSMANN SEEDORFUHEYDECKEG, LIESKE DR, DINGOYAN B, D., AARABI G. Oral health literacy in migrant and ethnic minority populations: A systematic review. J Immigr Minor Health. 2022;24:1061&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10903-021-01266-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9256555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34448993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leggett H, Vinall-Collier K, Csikar J, Veronica Ann Douglas G. Barriers to prevention in oral health care for English NHS dental patients: a qualitative study of views from key stakeholders. BMC Oral Health. 2023;23:332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-023-03030-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10225091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swamy DF, Gurumurthy V, Vishwanath S, Rawat R, Aswal GS, Kumar VK. A cross-sectional assessment of knowledge, attitude, and practices toward oral hygiene among schoolchildren in Jimma, Ethiopia. Journal of Oral Health and Community Dentistry. 2021;15:1&#x2013;6. 10.5005/jp-journals-10062-0094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5005/jp-journals-10062-0094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawal FB, Oke GA. Clinical and sociodemographic factors associated with oral health knowledge, attitude, and practices of adolescents in Nigeria. SAGE Open Med. 2020. 10.1177/2050312120951066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312120951066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7446260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berhane HY, Worku A. Oral health of young adolescents in Addis Ababa&#x2014;a community-based study. Open J Prev Med. 2014;04:640&#x2013;8. 10.4236/ojpm.2014.48073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojpm.2014.48073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>