<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41327339</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2197-1714</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Injury epidemiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Inj Epidemiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology of pediatric road traffic injuries: a multicenter hospital-based study in Ghana.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>83</StartPage><MedlinePgn>83</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">83</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40621-025-00646-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Road traffic injury (RTI) is a major threat to children and adolescents worldwide. RTIs account for 25.7 deaths per 100,000 people in the general population. Unlike in other western countries where road fatalities are declining, deaths in Ghana continue to rise. This study examined the injury characteristics and spatiotemporal patterns of pediatric RTI cases and inpatient fatalities across three zones in Ghana.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study employed a retrospective cross-sectional design, analyzing pediatric RTI data from three teaching hospitals in Ghana, with each hospital located in one of Ghana's three geographic zones: northern, middle, and coastal/southern. The study included all pediatric RTI cases captured between 2021 and 2024. Data on sociodemographic, spatial-temporal information, type of injury, injury severity, and admission outcome were analyzed. Descriptive statistics and Chi-square tests were used to compare groups at p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05. Quantum Geographic Information System (QGIS) was used to develop choropleth maps.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 1,485 pediatric RTI cases were included. Boys constituted 72.3%. Adolescents aged 13-18 years (45.6%) and school children aged 6-12 years (32.4%) were the most affected age groups. The leading causes of RTI were pedestrian knockdown (51.1%) and motorcycle crash (33.2%). While pedestrian knockdowns were widespread across the country, motorcycle crashes were dominant in the northern zone. Head injury was commonly reported among patients seen in the middle (60.4%) and northern (59.5%) zones, while lower limb injuries (54.3%) were most frequently seen in the southern zone. Mortality rates differed among the zones: 6.9% northern, 2.8% southern, and 0% middle (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The differences in injury patterns, mortality rates, and crash types underscore regional disparities in risk exposure and point to the limited effectiveness of road safety interventions across the country. The local road safety authorities should intensify road safety education and law enforcement, with clear outcome indicators to monitor impacts. Improvements in road infrastructure are also necessary, which provide separate routes for pedestrians with strict adherence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Appiah</LastName><ForeName>Anthony Baffour</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidelberg Institute of Global Health, University of Heidelberg, Im Neuenheimer Feld 130.3, Heidelberg, 69120, Germany. anthony.baffour_appiah@stud.uni-heidelberg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Michael Lowery</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section for Oral Health, Heidelberg Institute of Global Health, Heidelberg University, Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dambach</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidelberg Institute of Global Health, University of Heidelberg, Im Neuenheimer Feld 130.3, Heidelberg, 69120, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MohammadNamdar</LastName><ForeName>Mahsa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Neurosciences, Injury Epidemiology and Prevention Research Group, Turku Brain Injury Centre, Turku University Hospital and University of Turku, Turku, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buunaaim</LastName><ForeName>Alexis Dun Bo-Ib</ForeName><Initials>ADB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University for Development Studies, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopaedics, Tamale Teaching Hospital, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alatiiga</LastName><ForeName>John Abanga</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Trauma Orthopaedics, Tamale Teaching Hospital, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ativor</LastName><ForeName>Vincent</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic and Trauma Surgery, Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital, Kumasi, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donkor</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, School of Medical Science, Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mock</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harborview Injury Prevention and Research Center, Harborview Medical Center, Seattle, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Inj Epidemiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101652639</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2197-1714</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geographic information system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ghana</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Road traffic accident</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Traumatic brain injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: The study protocol was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board of Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital (Ref: KATHIRB/AP/127/23), the Ethics Review Committee of Cape Coast Teaching Hospital (Ref: CCTHERC/EC/2023/120), and the Department ofResearch and Development of Tamale Teaching Hospital (Ref. TTH/R&amp;D/SR/031). The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki, which outlines ethical principles for medical research involving human participants, with strict adherence of data security and confidentiality. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41327339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12690968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40621-025-00646-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40621-025-00646-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ministry Of Roads and Highways. Ministry Of Roads And Highways Second National Household. 2013. https://www2.statsghana.gov.gh/nada/index.php/catalog/82/download/320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global status report on road safety 2023. 15. 2023. doi:Licence: CC BY-NC-SA 3.0 IGO. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240086517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unicef. Child and Adolescent Road Safety. 2022. https://www.unicef.org/media/130721/file/UNICEF_Child_and_Adolescent_Road_Safety_Technical_Guidance_2022.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Global Status Report on Road Safety 2018. Vol 2. 2018. https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/277370/WHO-NMH-NVI-18.20-eng.pdf?ua=1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The global economy.com. Ghana: Traffic accident deaths. The global economy.com. Published 2025. Accessed June 29. 2025. https://www.theglobaleconomy.com/Ghana/mortality_traffic_accidents</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peden AE, Cullen P, Francis KL, et al. Adolescent transport and unintentional injuries: a systematic analysis using the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet Public Health. 2022;7(8):e657&#x2013;69. 10.1016/S2468-2667(22)00134-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(22)00134-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9329128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35779567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesic A, Damsere-Derry J, Gyedu A, et al. Generating consensus on road safety issues and priorities in Ghana: a modified Delphi approach. Injury. 2023;54(9):110765. 10.1016/j.injury.2023.04.052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.injury.2023.04.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37193635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alejandro AJ, Obiri-Yeboah M, Appiah N, Zakariah A. Paediatric road traffic injuries in urban Ghana: a population-based study. Inj Prev. 2011;17(5):309&#x2013;12. 10.1136/ip.2010.028878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ip.2010.028878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21422026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baffour Appiah A, Akweongo P, Sackey SO et al. Determinants of motorcycle-related head injuries among children and youth: an unmatched case-control study in Northern Ghana. Inj Prev Published Online 2025:1&#x2013;8. 10.1136/ip-2024-045526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40858358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Roads and Highway. 2019 Annual Progress Report Ministry Of Roads and Highway. 2020. https://ndpc.gov.gh/media/Ministry_of_Roads_and_Highways_APR_2019.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Transport. Vehicle Population Rate Growth. Published online 2016. https://mofep.gov.gh/sites/default/files/pbb-estimates/2021/2021-PBB-MoT.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adanu EK, Dzinyela R, Agyemang W. A comprehensive study of child pedestrian crash outcomes in Ghana. Accid Anal Prev. 2023;189:107146. 10.1016/j.aap.2023.107146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aap.2023.107146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37285755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aidoo EN, Amoh-Gyimah R. Modelling the risk factors for injury severity in motorcycle users in Ghana. J Public Heal. 2020;28(2):199&#x2013;209. 10.1007/s10389-019-01047-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10389-019-01047-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MoH. Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital - Ministry Of Health. Ministry of Health,Republic of Ghana. Published 2024. Accessed June 19. 2025. https://www.moh.gov.gh/komfo-anokye-teaching-hospital/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital. Profile Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital. Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital. Published 2025. Accessed June 19. 2025. https://kath.gov.gh/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamale Teaching Hospital. Profile of Tamale Teaching Hospital. Tamale Teaching Hospital. Published 2025. Accessed June 19. 2025. https://www.tth.gov.gh/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World health organization. World health organization. Int Stat Classif Dis Relat Heal Probl. 2011;1:286&#x2013;7. 10th ed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>USAID Ghana HPNO. Ghana New 16 Region. ArcGIS Hub. Published 2019. Accessed June 23. 2025. https://hub.arcgis.com/datasets/USAID-Ghana-HPNO::ghana-new-16-region/explore?showTable=true</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albargi H, Alharbi RJ, Almuwallad A, et al. Traumatic head injuries in children: demographics, injury patterns, and outcomes in Saudi Arabia. Int J Emerg Med. 2025;18(1). 10.1186/s12245-024-00808-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11697731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39748284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartka TR, McMurry T, Weaver A, Vaca FE. Development of a concise injury severity prediction model for pediatric patients involved in a motor vehicle collision. Traffic Inj Prev. 2021;22(S1):S74&#x2013;81. 10.1080/15389588.2021.1975275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15389588.2021.1975275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8792360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34672889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Casares M. Unintentional childhood injuries in sub-Saharan Africa: an overview of risk and protective factors. J Health Care Poor Underserved. 2009;20(4 Suppl):51&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/hpu.0.0226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20168033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrero A, Amegashie J, Obiri-yeboah M, Appiah N, Zakariah A. Paediatric road traffic injuries in urban Ghana: a population-based study. Inj Prev. 2011;17:309&#x2013;12. 10.1136/ip.2010.028878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ip.2010.028878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21422026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akpinar G. Characteristics of pediatric injuries due to road traffic accidents and their effects on mortality. J Surg Med. 2021;5(1):12&#x2013;6. 10.28982/josam.844167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.28982/josam.844167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golfiroozi S, Nikbakht HA, Fahim Yegane SA, et al. Effective factors of severity of traffic accident traumas based on the Haddon matrix: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Med Surg. 2024;86(3):1622&#x2013;30. 10.1097/ms9.0000000000001792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ms9.0000000000001792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10923285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38463059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng V, Abanga WA, Bosoka SA, et al. Incidence, trend and distribution of transport- related injuries reported to health facilities in the Volta region of Ghana, 2019 to 2023. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(3309):1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11603924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39604980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesse CA, Ofosu JB. Epidemiology of road traffic accidents in Ghana. Eur Sci J. 2014;10(9):370&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ummah MS, Accra Road Safety, Report. 2022. <i>Sustain</i>. 2019;11(1):1&#x2013;14. 10.1016/j.regsciurbeco.2008.06.005%0Ahttps://www.researchgate.net/publication/305320484_SISTEM_PEMBETUNGAN_TERPUSAT_STRATEGI_MELESTARI</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.regsciurbeco.2008.06.005%0Ahttps://www.researchgate.net/publication/305320484_SISTEM_PEMBETUNGAN_TERPUSAT_STRATEGI_MELESTARI</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seid M, Azazh A, Enquselassie F, Yisma E. Injury characteristics and outcome of road traffic accident among victims at adult emergency department of Tikur Anbessa specialized hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: a prospective hospital based study. BMC Emerg Med. 2015;15(1):1&#x2013;10. 10.1186/s12873-015-0035-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12873-015-0035-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4493961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25990560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punchak M, Abdelgadir J, Obiga O, et al. Mechanism of pediatric traumatic brain injury in Southwestern Uganda: a prospective cohort of 100 patients. World Neurosurg. 2018;114:e396&#x2013;402. 10.1016/j.wneu.2018.02.191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2018.02.191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29530703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herman L. Understanding barriers to effective injury care in low-income contexts: a mixed methods analysis of insights from medical trainees and traffic law enforcement first responders in Uganda. Published Online 2025:1&#x2013;21. 10.1101/2025.02.22.25322712</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morna MT, Appiah Baffour A, Akakpo PK, et al. Epidemiology of childhood injury-related deaths: review of mortality data at the cape Coast teaching hospital. PAMJ - One Heal. 2020;1(7):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blankson PK, Amoako JKA, Asah-Opoku K, Odei-Ansong F, Lartey MY. Epidemiology of injuries presenting to the accident centre of Korle-Bu teaching Hospital, Ghana. BMC Emerg Med. 2019;19(1):1&#x2013;6. 10.1186/s12873-019-0252-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12873-019-0252-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6642582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31325955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baffour Appiah A, Akweongo P, Sackey S, et al. Factors associated with head injury among survivors of motorcycle crashes: a case-control study in Northern Ghana. Pan Afr Med J. 2022;43:73. 10.11604/pamj.2022.43.73.35900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj.2022.43.73.35900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9789779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36591000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkson RF, Akple MS, Biscoff R, Dzokoto STK, Klomegah W. Helmet usage among motorcycle riders in Ghana. Int J Sci Eng Technol Res. 2013;2(3):2278&#x2013;7798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appiah AB, Akweongo P, Sackey SO, et al. Effect of different helmet types in head injuries&#x202f;: a case &#x2013; control study in northern Ghana. Inj Prev. 2023;6. 10.1136/ip-2022-044683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36198481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjei BN, Nakua EK, Donkor P, et al. Determinants of motorcycle helmet availability and cost in retail outlets: outcomes of a market survey in Northern Ghana. BMC Public Health. 2023;23(1):1&#x2013;10. 10.1186/s12889-023-15695-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-15695-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10131362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37101192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Roads and Highways. Medium Term Expenditure Framework (MTEF) for 2023&#x2013;2026. 2022. https://mrh.gov.gh/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Press-Release-on-Completed-Roads-at-SONA.pdf</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>