<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41234382</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2398-8835</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health science reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Understanding Menopause: Knowledge and Influencing Factors Among Postmenopausal Women in Bench Sheko Zone, Southwest Ethiopia: Cross-Sectional Study Design.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e71511</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e71511</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e71511</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/hsr2.71511</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Menopause is the cessation of menstruation and reproductive capacity due to decreased ovarian function and hormone production. Menopausal symptoms affect about 70% of women during their menopausal period. Despite the increasing proportion of the population experiencing menopause, only a limited number of studies have been conducted to understand menopause among women, particularly in Ethiopia. Therefore, this study aims to assess knowledge and influencing factors among postmenopausal women in the Bench Sheko Zone, Southwest Ethiopia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A community-based cross-sectional study was conducted among 404 post-menopausal women in the Bench-Sheko Zone from August to September 2023. Simple random sampling was used to obtain the required sample size. The data was collected by using structured, pre-tested, and interviewer-administered questionnaires. Epi data version 3.1 was used to enter data and then exported to Statistical Package for Social Science version 25 for analysis. The binary Logistic regression model was used to select candidate variables, and only variables with a <i>p</i>-value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.25 in bivariate logistic regression analysis were checked for association in a multivariable logistic regression model, and variables with a <i>p</i>-value&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 were considered statistically significant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The overall level of knowledge about menopause among post-menopausal women was 24.8%. Factors associated with knowledge status included the educational status of college and above (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.23; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.74, 10.24), educational level of secondary school (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.87; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.58, 9.48), educational level of primary school (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.29; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.33, 8.13), being a government employee (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.56; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.31, 13.4), and history of contraceptive use (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.83; 95% CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.15, 6.94).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Post-menopausal women had low knowledge about menopause. Educational status, occupation, and use of contraception were significantly associated with knowledge about menopause. Further menopause education is recommended to empower women to increase health-seeking behavior and access to information and healthcare services.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Health Science Reports published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shifera</LastName><ForeName>Nigusie</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5563-1358</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Science Mizan-Tepi University Mizan Aman Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yosef</LastName><ForeName>Tewodros</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3173-6753</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Science Mizan-Tepi University Mizan Aman Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wondie</LastName><ForeName>Smegnew Gichew</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7358-3214</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Nutrition, College of Medicine and Health Science Mizan-Tepi University Mizan Aman Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aydiko</LastName><ForeName>Alemseged</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0178-8197</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, College of Medicine and Health Sciences Mizan-Tepi University Mizan Aman Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Health Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101728855</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2398-8835</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bench&#x2010;Sheko Zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menopause</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41234382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12606034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.71511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">HSR271511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>organization wh: Research on the menopause &#x201c;,Report of a WHO Scientific Research,WHO,geneva,1997.World Health Organ Tech Rep Ser. Geneva;. In: WHO Scientific Research on menopause. edn.; 1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8942292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practice Committee of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine , &#x201c;The Menopausal Transition,&#x201d; Fertility and Sterility 90, no. 5, Suppl (2008): S61&#x2013;S65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19007648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinton R. D., Yao J., Yin F., Mack W. J., and Cadenas E., &#x201c;Perimenopause as a Neurological Transition State,&#x201d; Nature Reviews Endocrinology 11, no. 7 (2015): 393&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9934205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26007613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlow S. D., Gass M., Hall J. E., et al., Group SC ., &#x201c;Executive Summary of the Stages of Reproductive Aging Workshop+ 10: Addressing the Unfinished Agenda of Staging Reproductive Aging,&#x201d; Climacteric 15, no. 2 (2012): 105&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3580996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22338612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo S., Hoffman B. L., Bradshaw K. D., Schaffer J. I., Halvorson L. M., and Corton M. M., Williams Gynecology (New York: McGraw Hill, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yisma E., Eshetu N., Ly S., and Dessalegn B., &#x201c;Prevalence and Severity of Menopause Symptoms Among Perimenopausal and Postmenopausal Women Aged 30&#x2010;49 Years in Gulele Sub&#x2010;City of Addis Ababa, Ethiopia,&#x201d; BMC Women's Health 17 (2017): 124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5721600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29216870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindh&#x2010;&#xc5;strand L.: Women's Knowledge, Attitudes, and Management of the Menopausal Transition: Linkopings Universitet (Sweden); 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhore N., &#x201c;Coping Strategies in Menopause Women: A Comprehensive Review,&#x201d; Innovational: Journal of Nursing and Healthcare 1 (2015): 244&#x2013;253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteley J., DiBonaventura M. C., Wagner J.&#x2010;S., Alvir J., and Shah S., &#x201c;The Impact of Menopausal Symptoms on Quality of Life, Productivity, and Economic Outcomes,&#x201d; Journal of Women's Health 22, no. 11 (2013): 983&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3820128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24083674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed H. A. A. and Lamadah S. M., &#x201c;Improving Women's Practices for Reducing the Severity of Menopausal Symptoms,&#x201d; Journal of Nursing Education and Practice 6, no. 4 (2015): 72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ICF C statistical agency (CSA) [Ethiopia] and. Ethiopian Demographic and Health survey 2016 key indicators report. Addiss ababa E: [Ethiopia] and. Ethiopian Demographic and Health survey 2016 key indicators report. Addiss ababa, Ethiopia; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taherpour M., Sefidi F., Afsharinia S., and Hamissi J. H., &#x201c;Menopause Knowledge and Attitude Among Iranian Women,&#x201d; Journal of Medicine and Life 8, no. Spec Iss 2 (2015): 72&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5327721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28255401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon P., Chedraui P., Hidalgo L., and Ortiz F., &#x201c;Perceptions and Attitudes Toward the Menopause Among Middle Aged Women From Guayaquil, Ecuador,&#x201d; Maturitas 57, no. 3 (2007): 233&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17293066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khokhar S., &#x201c;Knowledge, Attitude and Experience of Menopause,&#x201d; Pakistan Journal of Medical Research 52, no. 2 (2013): 42A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eshetu N., Ly S., and Yisma E., &#x201c;Knowledge and Attitude of Women Aged 30&#x2013;49 Years Towards Menopause in Gulele Sub&#x2010;City of Addis Ababa, Ethiopia,&#x201d; Annals of Global Health 83, no. 1 (2017): 107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5721600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29216870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsehay D., Mulatie M., and Sellakumar G., &#x201c;Determinants of Menopausal Symptoms and Attitude Among Middle Aged Women: The Case of Dangila Town, North West Ethiopia,&#x201d; Innovare Journal of Social Sciences 2, no. 1 (2014): 15&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kibret B. and Mariam B., &#x201c;Menopausal Experiences Among Women in Addis Ababa,&#x201d; International Journal of Psychiatry 4 (2019): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misiker B., Kashala K., and Misker D., &#x201c;The Severity of Menopause and Associated Factors Among Middle&#x2010;Aged Women Residing in Arba Minch, DHSS, Ethiopia, 2022,&#x201d; BMC Women's Health 23, no. 1 (2023): 287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10211301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37231489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera S. T. and Goonewardena S. E., &#x201c;Prevalence, Knowledge and Attitudes of Menopausal Symptoms Among Women Aged 40&#x2010;60 Years and Their Associated Factors in a Semi Urban Area, Matara District, Sri Lanka,&#x201d; International Journal of Reproduction, Contraception, Obstetrics and Gynecology 9, no. 7 (2020): 2771&#x2013;2778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>mujib A., &#x201c;Assessment of Knowledge, Attitude and Associated Factors of Menopausal Women(Aged 40 Years and Above) Towards Menopause in Bole and Lugo Sub City of Adama Town, Central Ethiopia,&#x201d; Biomass Chemical Engineering 2 (2018): 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simachew Y., Zerfu T., and Alemu W., &#x201c;Treatment Outcomes and Predictors of Recovery From Severe Acute Malnutrition Among Children Aged 6&#x2013;59 Months Attending an Outpatient Therapeutic Program in Wenago District, Southern Ethiopia,&#x201d; Nutrition and Dietary Supplements 12 (2020): 189&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yohannis Kabalo MYK M. and Negash Seifu CNS C.: Treatment Outcomes of Severe Acute Malnutrition in Children Treated Within Outpatient Therapeutic Program (OTP) at Wolaita Zone, Southern Ethiopia: Retrospective Cross&#x2010;sectional Study. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5345228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28279227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayenew A., Yechale M., Nigussie A., and Ayalew N.: Women's Knowledge of Concept of Menopause, Severity, and Climacteric Stage Among Women in Middle Age in Northwest Ethiopia: Community&#x2010;Based Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak V., Ahirwar N., and Ghate S., &#x201c;Study to Assess Knowledge, Attitude and Practice Regarding Menopause Among Menopausal Women Attending Outdoor in Tertiary Care Centre,&#x201d; International Journal of Reproduction, Contraception, Obstetrics and Gynecology 6, no. 5 (2017): 1848&#x2013;1853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid S., Al&#x2010;Ghufli F. R., Raeesi H. A., et al., &#x201c;Women's Knowledge, Attitude and Practice Towards Menopause and Hormone Replacement Therapy: A Facility Based Study in Al&#x2010;Ain, United Arab Emirates,&#x201d; Journal of Ayub Medical College, Abbottabad: JAMC 26, no. 4 (2014): 448&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25672162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibraheem O., Oyewole O. E., and Olaseha I. O., &#x201c;Experiences and Perceptions of Menopause Among Women in Ibadan South East Local Government Area, Nigeria,&#x201d; African Journal of Biomedical Research 18, no. 2 (2015): 81&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devi B., Karki P., Chhetry R., et al., &#x201c;Quality of Life of Post&#x2010;Menopausal Women Residing in Rural and Urban Areas of Sikkim, India,&#x201d; International Journal of Reproduction, Contraception, Obstetrics and Gynecology 7 (2018): 5125&#x2013;5133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loutfy I., Abdel Aziz F., Dabbous N., and Hassan M., &#x201c;Women's Perception and Experience of Menopause: A Community&#x2010;Based Study in Alexandria, Egypt,&#x201d; supplement, Eastern Mediterranean Health Journal 12 (2006): S93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17361681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngome E. and Ama N. O.: Menopausal Perceptions and Experiences of Older Women From Selected Sites in Botswana. 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>