<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41552029</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0974-7052</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical pediatric dentistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Pediatr Dent</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative <i>In Vitro</i> Evaluation of the Antimicrobial Efficacy of Tulsi, Triphala, and Aloe Vera against <i>Streptococcus mutans</i> Relative to Chlorhexidine.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1437</StartPage><EndPage>1442</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1437-1442</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5005/jp-journals-10005-3349</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM AND BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Long-term use of chlorhexidine as an antibacterial mouthwash has been associated with several adverse effects. 80% of the population in developing countries relies on traditional medicines and natural products to meet their primary healthcare needs. This study aimed to evaluate the antibacterial efficacy of herbal extracts and to compare their effectiveness with that of 0.2% chlorhexidine mouth rinse.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The herbal extracts used were <i>Ocimum sanctum</i> (tulsi), a mixture of <i>Emblica Officinalis</i>, <i>Terminalia chebula</i>, and <i>Terminalia belericia</i> (triphala), and <i>Aloe Barbadensis</i> Miller (aloe vera). Blood agar plates were inoculated with <i>Streptococcus mutans</i>, and inhibition zones were measured after 24 hours of incubation at 37&#xb0;C.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Chlorhexidine exhibited the highest antibacterial activity, followed by tulsi, triphala, and aloe vera. The mean inhibition zone diameters (in mm) were 22.33 &#xb1; 0.8, 11 &#xb1; 0.603, 8.6 &#xb1; 0.77, and 8 &#xb1; 0.6, respectively.Intergroup comparison revealed statistically significant differences (<i>p</i> = 0.00), favoring chlorhexidine over the herbal extracts. Intragroup analysis also showed significant differences (<i>p</i> = 0.00), with tulsi demonstrating the highest antibacterial activity among the herbal extracts, followed by triphala and aloe vera.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Within the limitations of this <i>in vitro</i> study, all tested herbal extracts exhibited antibacterial properties against <i>S. mutans.</i> However, chlorhexidine showed the highest efficacy. Among the herbal extracts, tulsi demonstrated the most potent antibacterial activity, followed by triphala, while aloe vera exhibited the least effectiveness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">As the plant extracts demonstrated a notable efficacy in inhibiting the proliferation of oral bacteria, this suggests that these extracts could be formulated into an herbal antibacterial mouth rinse option suitable for individuals seeking herbal alternatives.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HOW TO CITE THIS ARTICLE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Singh D, Rao A, Saralaya V, <i>et al.</i> Comparative <i>In Vitro</i> Evaluation of the Antimicrobial Efficacy of Tulsi, Triphala, and Aloe Vera against <i>Streptococcus mutans</i> Relative to Chlorhexidine. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent 2025;18(12):1437-1442.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025; The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Divya</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-6276-3061</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric &amp; Preventive Dentistry, Manipal College of Dental Sciences, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Arathi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6440-1274</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric &amp; Preventive Dentistry, Manipal College of Dental Sciences, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saralaya</LastName><ForeName>Vishwas</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4940-8045</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Kasturba Medical College, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ullal</LastName><ForeName>Sheetal</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Kasturba Medical College, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gautam</LastName><ForeName>Priyanka</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dravyaguna, Banaras Hindu University, Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shenoy</LastName><ForeName>Ramya</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3126-4415</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Dentistry, Manipal College of Dental Sciences, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srikrishna</LastName><ForeName>Suprabha Baranya</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7003-3121</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric &amp; Preventive Dentistry, Manipal College of Dental Sciences, Mangalore, Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Pediatr Dent</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101585405</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0974-7052</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aloe vera</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibacterial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Herbal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus mutans</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Triphala</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tulsi</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Source of support: This study was supported by the seed money grant of Rs. 10,000 from Manipal Academy of Higher Education, Manipal. Conflict of interest: NoneConflict of interest: None</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41552029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12810167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5005/jp-journals-10005-3349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shah N, Mathur VP, Kant S, et al. Prevalence of dental caries and periodontal disease in a rural area of Faridabad District, Haryana, India. Indian J Dent Res. 2017;28(3):242&#x2013;247. doi: 10.4103/ijdr.IJDR_370_16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijdr.IJDR_370_16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28721985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav K, Prakash S. Dental caries: a microbiological approach. J Clin Infect Dis Pract. 2017;2(1):118. doi: 10.4172/2476-213X.1000118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2476-213X.1000118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkar SM, Thakkar P, Shah K. Antimicrobial activity of four commercially available mouthwashes against Streptococcus mutans: an in vitro study. Univ Res J Dent. 2013;3(3):108&#x2013;112. doi: 10.4103/2249-9725.123971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2249-9725.123971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty RM, Goyal A, Goyal B, et al. An antimicrobial efficacy of guava and tulsi against Streptococcus mutans and E. Faecalis: in vitro study. Int Res J Nat Appl Sci. 2015;2(1):89&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dua K, Sheshala R, Al-Waeli HA, et al. Antimicrobial efficacy of extemporaneously prepared herbal mouthwashes. Recent Pat Drug Deliv Formul. 2015;9(3):257&#x2013;261. doi: 10.2174/1872211309666150608095106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1872211309666150608095106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26051152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonong Y, Satari M, Indriyanti R, et al. Antibacterial test between aloe vera and chlorhexidine based on the number of colony of Streptococcus mutans ATCC 25 175 in vitro. Int J Sci Res. 2016;5(1):1379&#x2013;1385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saima SS, Ahmad R. Efficacy of chlorhexidine vs herbal mouthwash in college students: a comparative study. Int J Appl Dent Sci. 2019;5(2):403&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir TA, Jan M, Khare RK, et al. In: Medicinal and Aromatic Plants. Aftab T, Hakeem KR, editors. Switzerland: Springer Nature; 2021. Medicinal Plant Resources: Threat to Its Biodiversity and Conservation Strategies. (Eds)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sultan MS. Antibacterial effect of aloe vera and glass ionomer modified by aloe vera on Streptococcus mutans. Egypt Dent J. 2019;65:2607&#x2013;2616. doi: 10.21608/edj.2019.72664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/edj.2019.72664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal P, Nagesh L, Murlikrishnan Evaluation of the antimicrobial activity of various concentrations of tulsi (Ocimum sanctum) extract against Streptococcus mutans: an in vitro study. Indian J Dent Res. 2010;21(3):357&#x2013;359. doi: 10.4103/0970-9290.70800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0970-9290.70800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20930344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eswar P, Devaraj CG, Agarwal P. Anti-microbial activity of tulsi {Ocimum Sanctum (Linn.)} extract on a periodontal pathogen in human dental plaque: an invitro study. J Clin Diagn Res. 2016;10(3):ZC53&#x2013;ZC56. doi: 10.7860/JCDR/2016/16214.7468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7860/JCDR/2016/16214.7468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4843387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27135002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padiyar B, Marwah N, Gupta S, et al. Comparative evaluation of effects of triphala, garlic extracts, and chlorhexidine mouthwashes on salivary Streptococcus mutans counts and oral hygiene status. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2018;11(4):299&#x2013;306. doi: 10.5005/jp-journals-10005-1530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5005/jp-journals-10005-1530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6212670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30397374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamath NP, Tandon S, Nayak R, et al. The effect of aloe vera and tea tree oil mouthwashes on the oral health of school children. Eur Arch Paediatr Dent. 2020;21(1):61&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1007/s40368-019-00445-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40368-019-00445-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31111439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devarasanahalli SV, Kurian B, Aswathanarayana RM, et al. Comparison of the antibacterial efficiency of herbal extracts of aloe vera leaves and mushroom against Streptococcus mutans and Lactobacillus: an in vitro study. Int J Exp Dent Sci. 2020;9(1):8&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autio-Gold J. The role of chlorhexidine in caries prevention. Oper Dent. 2008;33(6):710&#x2013;716. doi: 10.2341/08-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2341/08-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19051866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valgas C, De Souza SM, Sm&#xe2;nia EFA. Screening methods to determine antibacterial activity of natural products. Braz J Microbiol. 2007;38:369&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakade LS, Shah P, Shirol D. Comparison of antimicrobial efficacy of chlorhexidine and combination mouth rinse in reducing the Mutans streptococcus count in plaque. J Indian Soc Pedod Prev Dent. 2014;32(2):91&#x2013;96. doi: 10.4103/0970-4388.130780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0970-4388.130780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24739906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bast F, Rani P, Meena D. Chloroplast DNA phylogeography of holy basil (Ocimum tenuiflorum) in Indian subcontinent. Sci World J. 2014;1:847482. doi: 10.1155/2014/847482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/847482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3910118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24523650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh N, Hoette Y, Miller R. Tulsi: The Mother Medicine of Nature. 2nd edition. Lucknow: Organic India Publisher; 2002. pp. 28&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MM. Tulsi&#x2014;Ocimum sanctum: a herb for all reasons. J Ayurveda Integr Med. 2014;5(4):251&#x2013;259. doi: 10.4103/0975-9476.146554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0975-9476.146554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4296439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25624701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan N, Rawal S, Verma M, et al. A phytopharmacological overview on Ocimum species with special emphasis on Ocimum sanctum. Biomed Prev Nutr. 2013;3(2):185&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattanayak P, Behera P, Das D, et al. Ocimum sanctum Linn. A reservoir plant for therapeutic applications: an overview. Pharmacogn Rev. 2010;4(7):95&#x2013;105. doi: 10.4103/0973-7847.65323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0973-7847.65323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3249909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22228948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondal S, Mirdha BR, Mahapatra SC. The science behind sacredness of tulsi (Ocimum sanctum Linn.) Indian J Physiol Pharmacol. 2009;53(4):291&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20509321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena S, Lakshminarayan N, Gudli S, et al. Anti bacterial efficacy of Terminalia Chebula, Terminalia Bellirica, Embilica Officinalis and triphala on salivary Streptococcus Mutans count&#x2014;a linear randomized cross over trial. J Clin Diagn Res. 2017;11(2):ZC47&#x2013;ZC51. doi: 10.7860/JCDR/2017/23558.9355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7860/JCDR/2017/23558.9355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5376913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadiyar A, Ankola AV, Rajpurohit L. Evaluation of the antimicrobial activity of Ocimum sanctum L. (tulsi) extract against Streptococcus mutans and Lactobacillus acidophilus&#x2014;an in vitro study. Int J Health Sci Res. 2017;7(4):224&#x2013;228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kochikar Pai R, Bhat SS, Salman A, et al. Use of an extract of Indian sacred plant Ocimum sanctum as an anticariogenic agent: an in vitro study. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2015;8(2):99&#x2013;101. doi: 10.5005/jp-journals-10005-1292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5005/jp-journals-10005-1292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26379375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal G, Bhavesh R, Kasariya K, et al. Biosynthesis of silver nanoparticles using Ocimum sanctum (tulsi) leaf extract and screening its antimicrobial activity. J Nanopart Res. 2011;13:2981&#x2013;2988. doi: 10.1007/s11051-010-0193-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11051-010-0193-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagdish L, Anand Kumar VK, Kaviyarasan V. Effect of triphala on dental biofilm. Indian J Sci Technol. 2009;2(1):30&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajaj N, Tandon S. The effect of triphala and chlorhexidine mouthwash on dental plaque, gingival inflammation, and microbial growth. Int J Ayurveda Res. 2011;2(1):29&#x2013;36. doi: 10.4103/0974-7788.83188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0974-7788.83188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3157106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21897640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giri P, DivyaLalitha N, Prabu D, et al. A systematic review on the efficacy of aloe vera mouthwash on periodontal health. J Pharm Sci Res. 2019;11(9):3217&#x2013;3222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramaniam P, Dwivedi S, Uma E, et al. Effect of pomegranate and aloe vera extract on Streptococcus mutans: an in vitro study. Dent Hypotheses. 2012;3:99&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner CE, Williamson DA, Stroud PA, et al. Evaluation and comparison of commercially available aloe vera L. products using size exclusion chromatography with refractive index and multi-angle laser light scattering detection. Int Immunopharmacol. 2004;4(14):1727&#x2013;1737. doi: 10.1016/j.intimp.2004.07.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2004.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15531289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurian B, Swapna DV, Ranjini MA, et al. Comparison of antibacterial efficacy of herbal extracts of aloe vera leaves and mushroom against Streptococcus mutans and Lactobacillus&#x2014;an in vitro study. RGUHS J Dent Sci. 2017;9(1):23&#x2013;29. doi: 10.26715/rjds.9_1_4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26715/rjds.9_1_4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yavagal PC, Sivasamy S, Nagesh L. Evaluation of antibacterial potential of aloe vera extracts against Streptococcus mutans and Lactobacillus acidophilus&#x2014;an in vitro study. J Indian Assoc Public Health Dent. 2012;10(19):77&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreekumar S, Hegde VK. Comparative evaluation of antibacterial effect of three commercially available herbal products against Streptococcus mutans: an in vitro study. J Indian Assoc Public Health Dent. 2018;16(1):75&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>