<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41710680</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0973-2284</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Indian journal of occupational and environmental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Occup Environ Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of Relative Health Risks of Vibration-Exposed Equipment Operators in Coal Mines.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>254</StartPage><EndPage>259</EndPage><MedlinePgn>254-259</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijoem.ijoem_74_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The present study aims at evaluating the influence of whole-body vibration (WBV) exposure and its contributing factors on musculoskeletal disorders (MSDs) of equipment operators in coal mines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this paper, WBV measurement was conducted for 100 equipment operators exposed to vibration, followed by a questionnaire survey. This questionnaire survey was also extended to 104 workers with limited exposure to vibration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The daily average frequency-weighted acceleration A(8), when compared with health guidance caution zone (HGCZ) of ISO 2631-1, reveals that 15% operators are exposed to likely health risk and 82% to potential health risk. The relative risk of MSDs of vibration-exposed operators was 2.63 times more than the control group. Moreover, when mines were compared, Mine B showed a 3.27 times higher likelihood of vibration hazards compared to Mine A.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Equipment operators in mines are exposed to vibration as a part of their occupation. The company management may take preventive measures through design of workplace and work environment for minimizing vibration exposure on operators to reduce MSDs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Indian Journal of Occupational and Environmental Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Khane Jithendar</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (BHU), Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palei</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (BHU), Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karmakar</LastName><ForeName>Netai Chandra</ForeName><Initials>NC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (BHU), Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Suprakash</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (BHU), Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Amrendra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mining Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology (BHU), Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Indian J Occup Environ Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9815775</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0973-2284</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coal mines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">equipment operators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">relative risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whole-body vibration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41710680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12912289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijoem.ijoem_74_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJOEM-29-254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay R, Senapati A, Bhattacherjee A, Patra AK, Chatterjee S. A comparison of multiple machine learning algorithms to predict whole-body vibration exposure of dumper operators in iron ore mines in India. Int J Stat Med Res. 2021;10:169&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh KJ, Palei SK, Karmakar NC. Role of contributing factors on health risks of whole-body vibration exposure of heavy equipment and vehicle operators: A critical review. J Vib Control. 2024;30:2338&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smets MP, Eger TR, Grenier SG. Whole-body vibration experienced by haulage truck operators in surface mining operations: A comparison of various analysis methods utilized in the prediction of health risks. Appl Ergon. 2010;41:763&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20185120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Marin LS, Dennerlein JT. Evaluation of commercially available seat suspensions to reduce whole body vibration exposures in mining heavy equipment vehicle operators. Appl Ergon. 2018;71:78&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin LS, Rodriguez AC, Rey-Becerra E, Piedrahita H, Barrero LH, Dennerlein JT, et al. Assessment of whole-body vibration exposure in mining earth-moving equipment and Other vehicles used in surface mining. Ann Work Expo Heal. 2017;61:669&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28637189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayton AG, Kittusamy NK, Ambrose DH, Jobes CC, Legault ML. Jarring/jolting exposure and musculoskeletal symptoms among farm equipment operators. Int J Ind Ergon. 2008;38:758&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajadi N, Bagheri R, Amiri A, Maroufi N, Shadmehr A, Pourahmadi M. Effects of different frequencies of whole body vibration on repositioning error in patients with chronic low back pain in different angles of lumbar flexion. J Manipulative Physiol Ther. 2019;42:227&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31255307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanatta M, Amaral FG, Vidor G. The role of whole-body vibration in back pain: A cross-sectional study with agricultural pilots. Int J Ind Ergon. 2019;74:102872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yassierli Implementation of ergonomic programs to reduce sick leave due to low back pain among nickel mining operators. Int J Ind Ergon. 2017;61:81&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo A, Preti C, Cutini M, Deboli R. Vibration on the backs of mistblower operators: Is it only a (dis) comfort question? Biosyst Eng. 2019;185:4&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennerlein JT, Cavallari JM, Kim JH, Green NH. The effects of a new seat suspension system on whole body vibration exposure and driver low back pain and disability: Results from a randomized controlled trial in truck drivers. Appl Ergon. 2022;98:103588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10861360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34562781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burstr&#xf6;m L, Hyv&#xe4;rinen V, Johnsen M, Pettersson H. Exposure to whole-body vibration in open-cast mines in the Barents region. Int J Circumpolar Health. 2016;75:29373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4749864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26864832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Palei SK, Karmakar NC. Discomfort survey of dumper operators exposed to whole-body vibration in opencast coal mines. Vib Control. 2025;31:583&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mar&#xed;n PJ, Santos-Lozano A, Santin-Medeiros F, Vicente-Rodriguez G, Casaj&#xfa;s JA, Hazell TJ, et al. Whole-body vibration increases upper and lower body muscle activity in older adults: Potential use of vibration accessories. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2012;22:4s56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazell TJ, Jakobi JM, Kenno KA. The effects of whole-body vibration on upper- and lower-body EMG during static and dynamic contractions. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2007;32:1156&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18059590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock RD, Provan S, Martin FC, Newham DJ. The effects of whole body vibration on balance, joint position sense and cutaneous sensation. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:3069&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21455611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azenan AF, Azlis-Sani J. Effects of vibration on intrastate bus drivers. J Phys Conf Ser. 2018;1049:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atal MK, Palei SK, Chaudhary DK, Kumar V, Karmakar NC. Occupational exposure of dumper operators to whole-body vibration in opencast coal mines: An approach for risk assessment using a Bayesian network. Int J Occup Saf Ergon. 2022;28:758&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basri B, Griffin MJ. Predicting discomfort from whole-body vertical vibration when sitting with an inclined backrest. Appl Ergon. 2013;44:423&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23190680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milosavljevic S, Bergman F, Rehn B, Carman AB. All-terrain vehicle use in agriculture: Exposure to whole body vibration and mechanical shock. Appl Ergon. 2010;41:530&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19944407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nawayseh N, Hamdan S. Apparent mass of the standing human body when using a whole-body vibration training machine: Effect of knee angle and input frequency. J Biomech. 2019;82:291&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30466950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer KT, Griffin MJ, Syddall HE, Pannett B, Cooper C, Coggon D. The relative importance of whole body vibration and occupational lifting as risk factors for low-back pain. Occup Environ Med. 2003;60:715&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1740390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14504358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>This is a report published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, US. Nonfatal occupational injuries and illnesses requiring days away from work, 2015. US Bur Labor Stat. 2016.  Available from: https://www.bls.gov/news.release/pdf/osh2.pdf . [Last accessed on 2025 Jan 27]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-P&#xe9;rez JF, Comendador-Jimenez B, Castro-Rodriguez E, C&#xe1;novas M, Conesa M. Characterization of workers or population percentage affected by low-back pain (LPB), sciatica and herniated disc due to whole-body vibrations (WBV) Heliyon. 2024;10:e31768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11140807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38828327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson F, Miralami R, Tansey KE, Prabhu RK, Priddy LB. Deleterious effects of whole-body vibration on the spine: A review of in vivo, ex vivo, and in vitro models. Anim Model Exp Med. 2021;4:77&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8212824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34179716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhushanka JGN, De Silva GHMJS, De Silve GSY. Investigation on whole body vibration exposures of operators of construction vehicles. 6th International Conference on Structural Engineering and Construction Management Kandy, Sri Lanka. 2015:117&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa N, Arezes PM. The influence of operator driving characteristics in whole-body vibration exposure from electrical fork-lift trucks. Int J Ind Ergon. 2009;39:34&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Palei SK, Karmakar NC, Chaudhary DK. Whole-body vibration exposure vis-&#xe0;-vis musculoskeletal health risk of dumper operators compared to a control group in coal mines. Saf Health Work. 2022;13:73&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9348998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35936203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Organisation for Standardisation (ISO): ISO 2631-1. 2nd. Geneva, Switzerland: 1997. Mechanical vibration and shock &#x2013; Evaluation of human exposure to whole-body vibration &#x2013; Part 1: General requirements.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbuckle JL. IBM SPSS amos 23 user&#x2019;s guide. 2011:1&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat D, Patil VK. Human age group classification using facial features. Int J Mod Trends Eng Res. 2016;3:123&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitch AK, Bays HE. Obesity definition, diagnosis, bias, standard operating procedures (SOPs), and telehealth: An Obesity Medicine Association (OMA) Clinical Practice Statement (CPS) 2022. Obes Pillars. 2022;1:100004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10661988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37990702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary DK, Bhattacherjee A, Patra AK, Chau N. Whole-body vibration exposure of drill operators in iron ore mines and role of machine-related, individual, and rock-related factors. Saf Health Work. 2015;6:268&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4682033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26929838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayton AG, Porter WL, Xu XS, Weston EB, Rubenstein EN. Investigation of human body vibration exposures on haul trucks operating at U.S. surface mines/quarries relative to haul truck activity. Int J Ind Ergon. 2018;64:188&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5928797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29725145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayton AG, Jobes CC, Gallagher S. Assessment of whole-body vibration exposures and influencing factors for quarry haul truck drivers and loader operators. Int J Heavy Veh Syst. 2014;21:241&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay R, Bhattacherjee A, Patra AK, Chau N. Association between whole-body vibration exposure and musculoskeletal disorders among dumper operators: A case-control study in Indian iron ore mines. Work. 2022;71:235&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34924417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seidel H, Heide R. Long-term effects of whole-body vibration: A critical survey of the literature. Int Arch Occup Environ Health. 1986;58:1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3522434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassiri P, Koohpaei A, Zeraati H, Shalkouhi PJ. Evaluation of exposure to whole-body vibration and its health effects on train operators in tehran-andimeshk line, Iran. J Low Freq Noise, Vib Act Control. 2009;28:285&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>