<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41619485</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-3171</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Poultry science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Poult Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of in ovo taurine administration on cyclic heat stress in broiler chickens.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106450</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106450</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106450</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.psj.2026.106450</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0032-5791(26)00077-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>High temperature is a known abiotic stressor in broiler chickens, causing oxidative damage and altering gene expression. The present study was conducted to study the role of in ovo feeding of taurine against heat-induced damage in the broiler chickens. It was hypothesized that pre-hatch supplementation with taurine induces epigenetic changes such as DNA methylation and demethylation, which could help develop resistance to heat stress (HS) at later stages of life. For this, at 17.5 days of incubation, 360 fertile eggs from 37-week-old Arbor Acre breeder hens were divided into four groups: injected with distilled water (0TAU) &#xd7; 2, and others injected with taurine at 1 %, 3 %, or 5 % concentrations (1TAU, 3TAU, 5TAU). For the in ovo feeding, a 23-gauge needle was used to deposit 0.6mL of solution into the amniotic sac. During rearing days 29 to 34, broiler chickens were exposed to a cyclic heat stress (HS, 31 &#xb1; 1 &#xb0;C, 8 hours) or kept at a thermoneutral temperature (TN) zone (21 &#xb1; 1 &#xb0;C). Hence, the treatment groups were: (i) 0TAU-TN, (ii) 0TAU-HS, (iii) 1TAU-HS, (iv) 3TAU-HS, and (v) 5TAU-HS. While the organ indices, average daily feed intake (ADFI) and feed conversion ratio (FCR) did not differ significantly, in ovo taurine linearly increased average daily gain (ADG) during the heat stress (HS) period (p = 0.032). The 2,2-diphenyl-1-picrylhydrazyl radical scavenging activity% (DPPH-RSA%) in plasma showed a linear increase (p = 0.001) with taurine doses. Among the studied plasma metabolites, only alanine transaminase (ALT) was significantly affected, being lower in 1TAU-HS and 3TAU-HS compared to 5TAU-HS (p = 0.022). Individual gene expressions showed no significant variation across treatments. However, a planned contrast revealed upregulation of DNA methylation genes in the 5TAU-HS group compared to the 0TAU-TN group (p = 0.030). Strong positive correlations were observed among DNA methylation, demethylation, and NADPH oxidase (NOX) -related genes, suggesting coordinated regulation. Negative correlations between MDA and antioxidant enzymes indicated oxidative stress-related damage under HS. Hence, taurine linearly improved ADG under HS. While it did not significantly influence individual gene expression, 5TAU upregulated the overall DNA-methylation-related genes, suggesting a possible long-term adaptive response under HS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Vaishali</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea; Division of Applied Life Sciences (BK21 FOUR Program), Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hwang</LastName><ForeName>Yun-Ji</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea; Division of Applied Life Sciences (BK21 FOUR Program), Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delmonte</LastName><ForeName>Meg Aui</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ncho</LastName><ForeName>Chris Major</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea; Division of Applied Life Sciences (BK21 FOUR Program), Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Yang-Ho</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea; Division of Applied Life Sciences (BK21 FOUR Program), Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea; Institute of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Gyeongsang National University, Jinju 52828, South Korea. Electronic address: yhchoi@gnu.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Poult Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401150</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0032-5791</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antioxidants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DNA-methylation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heat stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">In ovo feeding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Taurine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosures The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41619485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12887376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psj.2026.106450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0032-5791(26)00077-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abd Al-Qaisy, N.E., and Z. M. Saied. 2023. Effect of adding taurine and vitamin c on physiological performance and antioxidant state of broiler chickens during summer season. Proc. IOP Conference Series: Earth and Environmental Science.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alabsy E.H., Alabdaly Y.Z. Therapeutic effect of taurine on sodium fluoride toxicity in chicks. Iraqi J. Vet. Sci. 2022;36:223&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara&#xfa;jo I.C., Caf&#xe9; M.B., Noleto R.A., Martins J.M., Ulhoa C.J., Guareshi G.C., Reis M.M., Leandro N.S. Effect of vitamin E in ovo feeding to broiler embryos on hatchability, chick quality, oxidative state, and performance. Poult. Sci. 2019;98:3652&#x2013;3661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryal B., Kwakye J., Ariyo O.W., Ghareeb A.F., Milfort M.C., Fuller A.L., Khatiwada S., Rekaya R., Aggrey S.E. Major oxidative and antioxidant mechanisms during heat stress-induced oxidative stress in chickens. Antioxidants. 2025;14:471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12023971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40298812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baliou S., Adamaki M., Ioannou P., Pappa A., Panayiotidis M.I., Spandidos D.A., Christodoulou I., Kyriakopoulos A.M., Zoumpourlis V. Protective role of taurine against oxidative stress. Mol. med. rep. 2021;24:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34184084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardella M.T., Vecchi M., Conte D., Del Ninno E., Fraquelli M., Pacchetti S., Minola E., Landoni M., Cesana B.M., De Franchis R. Chronic unexplained hypertransaminasemia may be caused by occult celiac disease. Hepatology. 1999;29:654&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10051464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baykalir Y., Simsek U.G., Seker &#x130;., Koseman A., Gul B., Eroglu M., Mutlu S.I., Kocyigit S., Karaca M., Demir P. Investigation of the effects of in ovo taurine injection on hatching characteristics and stress reduction potential. Vet. Med. Sci. 2024;10:e1387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10879721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38379352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belal S., Kang D., Cho E., Park G., Shim K. Taurine reduces heat stress by regulating the expression of heat shock proteins in broilers exposed to chronic heat. Braz. J. Poult. Sci. 2018;20:479&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlin KN, Cameron LM, Gatt M, Miller Jr RR. Reduced de novo synthesis of 5-methyltetrahydrofolate and reduced taurine levels in ethanol-treated chick brains. Comp. Biochem. Physiol. C: Toxicol. Pharmacol. 2010 Sep 1;152(3):353-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair R., Jacob J., Gardiner E. Lack of an effect of taurine supplementation on the incidence of sudden death syndrome in male broiler chicks. Poult. Sci. 1991;70:554&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2047349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaschke K., Ebata K.T., Karimi M.M., Zepeda-Mart&#xed;nez J.A., Goyal P., Mahapatra S., Tam A., Laird D.J., Hirst M., Rao A. Vitamin C induces Tet-dependent DNA demethylation and a blastocyst-like state in ES cells. Nature. 2013;500:222&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3893718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23812591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey B.W., Finley L.W., Cross J.R., Allis C.D., Thompson C.B. Intracellular &#x3b1;-ketoglutarate maintains the pluripotency of embryonic stem cells. Nature. 2015;518:413&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4336218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25487152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Y.-Y., Chou C.-H., Chiu C.-H., Yang K.-T., Lin Y.-L., Weng W.-L., Chen Y.-C. Preventive effects of taurine on development of hepatic steatosis induced by a high-fat/cholesterol dietary habit. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2011;59:450&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21126079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das R., Mishra P., Jha R. In ovo feeding as a tool for improving performance and gut health of poultry: a review. Front. Vet. Sci. 2021;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8632539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34859087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatemi S., Elliott K., Bello A., Durojaye O., Zhang H., Peebles E. Effects of source and level of in ovo-injected vitamin D3 on the hatchability and serum 25-hydroxycholecalciferol concentrations of Ross 708 broilers. Poult. sci. 2020;99:3877&#x2013;3884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32731974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda K., Hirai Y., Yoshida H., Nakajima T., Usui T. Free amino acid content of lymphocytes nd granulocytes compared. Clin. chem. 1982;28:1758&#x2013;1761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7094296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentile C.L., Nivala A.M., Gonzales J.C., Pfaffenbach K.T., Wang D., Wei Y., Jiang H., Orlicky D.J., Petersen D.R., Pagliassotti M.J. Experimental evidence for therapeutic potential of taurine in the treatment of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Am. J. Physiol.-Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2011;301:R1710&#x2013;R1722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3233850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21957160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerasopoulos K., Stagos D., Kokkas S., Petrotos K., Kantas D., Goulas P., Kouretas D. Feed supplemented with byproducts from olive oil mill wastewater processing increases antioxidant capacity in broiler chickens. Food Chem. Toxicol. 2015;82:42&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25916917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel A., Ncho C.M., Jeong C.-M., Choi Y.-H. Embryonic thermal manipulation and in ovo gamma-aminobutyric acid supplementation regulating the chick weight and stress-related genes at hatch. Front. Vet. Sci. 2021;1570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8777219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35071394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel A., Ncho C.M., Kim B.-J., Jeong C.-M., Gupta V., Jung J.-Y., Ha S.-Y., Yang J.-K., Choi Y.-H. Dietary shredded steam-exploded pine particle supplementation as a strategy to mitigate chronic cyclic heat stress by modulating gut microbiota in broilers. Sci. Rep. 2022;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9669035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel A., Ncho C.M., Jeong C.-M., Gupta V., Jung J.-Y., Ha S.-Y., Yang J.-K., Choi Y.-H. Dietary supplementation of solubles from shredded, steam-exploded pine particles modifies gut length and cecum microbiota in cyclic heat-stressed broilers. Poult. Sci. 2023;102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9932117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36739799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goo D., Kim J.H., Park G.H., Delos Reyes J.B., Kil D.Y. Effect of heat stress and stocking density on growth performance, breast meat quality, and intestinal barrier function in broiler chickens. Animals. 2019;9:107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6466317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30901977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta V., Ncho C.M., Goel A., Jeong C.-M., Choi Y.-H. Effects of in ovo injection of &#x3b1;-ketoglutaric acid on hatchability, growth, plasma metabolites, and antioxidant status of broilers. Antioxidants. 2022;11:2102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9686527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36358474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta V., Ncho C.M., Goel A., Jeong C.-M., Choi Y.-H. In ovo feeding of &#x3b1;-ketoglutaric acid improves hepatic antioxidant-gene expression, plasma antioxidant activities and decreases body temperature without affecting broiler body weight under cyclic heat stress. Poult. Sci. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11066556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38670054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamaguchi T, Azuma J, Harada H, Takahashi K, Kishimoto S, Schaffer SW. Protective effect of taurine against doxorubicin-induced cardiotoxicity in perfused chick hearts. Pharmacol. Res. 1989 Nov 1;21(6):729-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2626399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H., Zhang J., Chen Y., Shen M., Yan E., Wei C., Yu C., Zhang L., Wang T. Dietary taurine supplementation attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammatory responses and oxidative stress of broiler chickens at an early age. J. Anim. Sci. 2020;98:skaa311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7584273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32954422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han H., Zhang J., Yan E., Shen M., Wu J., Gan Z., Wei C., Zhang L., Wang T. Effects of taurine on growth performance, antioxidant capacity, and lipid metabolism in broiler chickens. Poult. Sci. 2020;99:5707&#x2013;5717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7647726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33142488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C., Jiao H., Song Z., Zhao J., Wang X., Lin H. Heat stress impairs mitochondria functions and induces oxidative injury in broiler chickens. J. Anim. Sci. 2015;93:2144&#x2013;2153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26020310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huxtable R. Physiological actions of taurine. Physiol. Rev. 1992;72:101&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1731369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji X., Tang Z., Zhang F., Zhou F., Wu Y., Wu D. Dietary taurine supplementation counteracts deoxynivalenol-induced liver injury via alleviating oxidative stress, mitochondrial dysfunction, apoptosis, and inflammation in piglets. Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf. 2023;253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36863159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jyothi P., Riyaz N., Nandakumar G., Binitha M. A study of oxidative stress in paucibacillary and multibacillary leprosy. Indian J. Dermatol. Venereol. Leprol. 2008;74:80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18188882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H.W., Yoon S.H., Park T., Kim B.K., Park K.K., Lee D.H. Taurine. Vol. 6. Springer US; Boston, MA: 2006. Gene expressions of taurine transporter and taurine biosynthetic enzyme during mouse and chicken embryonic development; pp. 69&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17153590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara L.J., Rostagno M.H. Impact of heat stress on poultry production. Animals. 2013;3:356&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4494392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26487407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D.-N., Cheng Y.-H., Chuang Y.-S., Shive J.-L., Lian Y.-M., Wei H.-W., Weng C.-F. Effects of dietary taurine supplementation on growth performance, serum constituents and antibody production of broilers. Asian-Australas. J. Anim. Sci. 2004;17:109&#x2013;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H., Decuypere E., Buyse J. Acute heat stress induces oxidative stress in broiler chickens. Comp. Biochem. Physiol. A: Mol. Integr. Physiol. 2006;144:11&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16517194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livak KJ, Schmittgen TD. Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2&#x2212; &#x394;&#x394;CT method. methods. 2001 Dec 1;25(4):402-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotfi A., Shahryar H.A., Kaiya H. Effect of in ovo ghrelin administration on hatching results and post-hatching performance of broiler chickens. Livest. Sci. 2013;154:158&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z., He X., Ma B., Zhang L., Li J., Jiang Y., Zhou G., Gao F. The alleviative effects and related mechanisms of taurine supplementation on growth performance and carcass characteristics in broilers exposed to chronic heat stress. Poult. sci. 2019;98:878&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30239846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z., He X., Ma B., Zhang L., Li J., Jiang Y., Zhou G., Gao F. Dietary taurine supplementation improves breast meat quality in chronic heat-stressed broilers via activating the Nrf2 pathway and protecting mitochondria from oxidative attack. J. Sci. Food Agric. 2019;99:1066&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30014460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x141;ukasiewicz Mierzejewska M., Kotuszewska M., Puppel K., Majewska B.Madras. Effects of in ovo taurine injection on embryo development, antioxidant status, and bioactive peptide content in chicken embryos (Gallus gallus domesticus) Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2024;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11546265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39519333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma B., Zhang L., Li J., Xing T., Jiang Y., Gao F. Dietary taurine supplementation ameliorates muscle loss in chronic heat stressed broilers via suppressing the perk signaling and reversing endoplasmic reticulum-stress-induced apoptosis. J. Sci. Food Agric. 2021;101:2125&#x2013;2134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32978773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q. Role of nrf2 in oxidative stress and toxicity. Annu. Rev. Pharmacol. Toxicol. 2013;53:401&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4680839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23294312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta S.K., Gowder S.J.T. Members of antioxidant machinery and their functions. Basic Princ. Clin. Significance Oxidative Stress. 2015;11:59&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijer M.M., van den Brand H., Niknafs S., Roura E. In ovo delivery of carvacrol triggers expression of chemotactic factors, antimicrobial peptides and pro-inflammatory pathways in the yolk sac of broiler chicken embryos. J. Anim. Sci. Biotechnol. 2025;16:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11742807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39828746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng L., Lu C., Wu B., Lan C., Mo L., Chen C., Wang X., Zhang N., Lan L., Wang Q. Taurine antagonizes macrophages M1 polarization by mitophagy-glycolysis switch blockage via dragging SAM-PP2Ac transmethylation. Front. Immunol. 2021;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33912173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messina, S. A., and R. Dawson Jr. 2002. Attenuation of oxidative damage to DNA by tairome and taurine analogs. Pages 355-367 in Taurine 4: taurine and excitable tissuesSpringer.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11787620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mir N.A., Rafiq A., Kumar F., Singh V., Shukla V. Determinants of broiler chicken meat quality and factors affecting them: a review. J. food Sci. Technol. 2017;54:2997&#x2013;3009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5603000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28974784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miraglia R., Martin W., Spaeth D., Patrick H. On the synthesis of taurine from sulfate by the chick: i. influential dietary factors. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. Med. 1966;123:725&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5959011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriles, K., M. Zubair, and S. Azer. 2024. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) test. StatPearls.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabi F., Arain M.A., Hassan M.F., Shah Q.A., Almutairi M.H., Buzdar J.A. Effects of in ovo supplementation of selenium (Se) and zinc (zn) on hatchability and production performance of broiler chickens. J. Comp. Physiol. B. 2024;194:887&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39158728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardelli T.R., Ribeiro R.A., Balbo S.L., Vanzela E.C., Carneiro E.M., Boschero A.C., Bonfleur M.L. Taurine prevents fat deposition and ameliorates plasma lipid profile in monosodium glutamate-obese rats. Amino acids. 2011;41:901&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21042817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ncho C.-M., Goel A., Jeong C.-M., Gupta V., Choi Y.-H. Effects of in ovo feeding of &#x3b3;-aminobutyric acid on growth performances, plasma metabolites, and antioxidant status in broilers exposed to cyclic heat stress. Sustainability. 2021;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ncho C.-M., Goel A., Jeong C.-M., Youssouf M., Choi Y.-H. In ovo injection of gaba can help body weight gain at hatch, increase chick weight to egg weight ratio, and improve broiler heat resistance. Animals. 2021;11:1364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34064864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ncho C.M., Goel A., Gupta V., Jeong C.-M., Choi Y.-H. Effect of in ovo feeding of &#x3b3;-aminobutyric acid combined with embryonic thermal manipulation on hatchability, growth, and hepatic gene expression in broilers. Anim. Biosci. 2023;36:284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9834729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35798039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohta H., Azuma J., Onishi S., Awata N., Takihara K., Kishimoto S. Protective effect of taurine against isoprenaline-induced myocardial damage. Basic Res. Cardiol. 1986 Sep;81(5):473&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3800845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oke O., Akosile O., Oni A., Opowoye I., Ishola C., Adebiyi J., Odeyemi A., Adjei-Mensah B., Uyanga V., Abioja M. Oxidative stress in poultry production. Poult. Sci. 2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11341942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39084145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrzak E., Dunislawska A., Siwek M., Zampiga M., Sirri F., Meluzzi A., Tavaniello S., Maiorano G., Slawinska A. Splenic gene expression signatures in slow-growing chickens stimulated in ovo with galactooligosaccharides and challenged with heat. Animals. 2020;10:474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7143207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32178295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team . A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing; Vienna, Austria: 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riber A.B., Wurtz K.E. Impact of growth rate on the welfare of broilers. Animals. 2024;14:3330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11591019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39595382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripps H., Shen W. taurine: a &#x201c;very essential&#x201d; amino acid. Mol. Vis. 2012;18:2673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3501277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23170060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senior J. Alanine aminotransferase: a clinical and regulatory tool for detecting liver injury&#x2013;past, present, and future. Clin. Pharmacol. Ther. 2012;92:332&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22871997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffield S., Fiorotto M.L., Davis T.A. Nutritional importance of animal-sourced foods in a healthy diet. Front. Nutr. 2024;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11306033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39119462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim K., Hwang K., Son M., Park G.H. Lipid metabolism and peroxidation in broiler chicks under chronic heat stress. Asian-Australas. J. Anim. Sci. 2006;19:1206&#x2013;1211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohail M., Hume M., Byrd J., Nisbet D., Ijaz A., Sohail A., Shabbir M., Rehman H. Effect of supplementation of prebiotic mannan-oligosaccharides and probiotic mixture on growth performance of broilers subjected to chronic heat stress. Poult. Sci. 2012;91:2235&#x2013;2240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22912458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surai P.F., Earle-Payne K., Kidd M.T. Taurine as a natural antioxidant: From direct antioxidant effects to protective action in various toxicological models. Antioxidants. 2021;10:1876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8698923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34942978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufft L., Jensen L.S. Influence of dietary taurine on performance and fat retention in broilers and turkey poults fed varying levels of fat. Poult. Sci. 1992;71:880&#x2013;885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1608883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uni Z., Ferket P., Tako E., Kedar O. In ovo feeding improves energy status of late-term chicken embryos. Poult. Sci. 2005;84:764&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15913189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uyanga V.A., Oke E.O., Amevor F.K., Zhao J., Wang X., Jiao H., Onagbesan O.M., Lin H. Functional roles of taurine, L-theanine, L-citrulline, and betaine during heat stress in poultry. J. Anim. Sci. Biotechnol. 2022;13:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8908636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira S., Moran E., Jr Effects of delayed placement and used litter on broiler yields. J. Appl. Poult. Res. 1999;8:75&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Xia L., Guo T., Heng C., Jiang L., Wang D., Wang J., Li K., Zhan X. Research Note: Metabolic changes and physiological responses of broilers in the final stage of growth exposed to different environmental temperatures. Poult. Sci. 2020;99:2017&#x2013;2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7587865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32241486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WM Q.-F. Heat stress impairs performance parameters, induces intestinal injury, and decreases macrophage activity in broiler chickens. Poult. Sci. 2010;89:1905&#x2013;1914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20709975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S., Lu Z., Ma B., Xing T., Li J., Zhang L., Jiang Y., Gao F. Dietary taurine supplementation enhances antioxidative capacity and improves breast meat quality of broiler chickens. Br. poult. sci. 2020;61:140&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31698931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahav S. Alleviating heat stress in domestic fowl: different strategies. World's Poult. Sci. J. 2009;65:719&#x2013;732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Bai K., Su W., Wang A., Zhang L., Huang K., Wang T. Curcumin attenuates heat-stress-induced oxidant damage by simultaneous activation of GSH-related antioxidant enzymes and Nrf2-mediated phase II detoxifying enzyme systems in broiler chickens. Poult. Sci. 2018;97:1209&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29438543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N. Role of methionine on epigenetic modification of DNA methylation and gene expression in animals. Anim. Nutr. 2018;4:11&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6112339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30167479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y., Li S., Sun Q., Yang X. Effect of in ovo feeding of vitamin C on antioxidation and immune function of broiler chickens. Animal. 2019;13:1927&#x2013;1933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30621801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y., Li S., Duan Y., Ren Z., Yang X., Yang X. Effects of in ovo feeding of vitamin C on post-hatch performance, immune status and DNA methylation-related gene expression in broiler chickens. Br. J. Nutr. 2020;124:903&#x2013;911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zieli&#x144;ska M., Sawosz E., Chwalibog A., Ostaszewska T., Kamaszewski M., Grodzik M., Skomia&#x142; J. Nano-nutrition of chicken embryos. Eff. Gold Taur. Nanoparticles Muscle Dev. 2010</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>