<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41545550</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of ceramic reinforcements in TIG-welded Al/SiCp and Al/TiB<sub>2</sub> composites for enhanced mechanical properties.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5570</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5570</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5570</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35715-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This research determines the effect of various ceramic particles (SiCp and TiB&#x2082;) on the Tungsten Inert Gas (TIG) welding of Al/TiB&#x2082; and Al/SiCp composites. The reinforcement concentrations of 2%, 4% and 6% were chosen for the investigation for both SiCp and TiB&#x2082; particles, and their effect on tensile strength (TS), hardness, and microstructure was studied using appropriate instruments. The SEM microstructure confirmed the ceramic particles distribution of different composite materials. The microstructure of the welds varies depending on the composition of the Al/TiB&#x2082; and Al/SiCp composites. XRD analysis displayed that the phase compound formed in weld metal is similar to the metal matrix composites (MMCs), indicating strong bonding between the reinforcements and the matrix. XRD analysis confirmed the retention of reinforcement phases without the formation of undesirable reaction products, indicating good metallurgical compatibility and stable interfacial bonding between the matrix and reinforcements. Addition of TiB&#x2082; and SiCp ceramic reinforcements into the aluminum matrix significantly improved the hardness of the welded joints. The highest hardness value of 172.8 HV was obtained for the Al/SiCp composite containing 4 wt% SiCp, representing an improvement of 25.94% and 8.88% compared to the composites containing 2 wt% and 6 wt% SiCp, respectively. Which is greater than 25.94% and 8.88% compare to 2% and 6% respectively. Similarly, the Al/TiB&#x2082; MMC containing 4% TiB&#x2082; showed the maximum hardness value of 98.3 Hv, followed by the composites containing 2% (85.9 HV) and 6% (74.6 HV) TiB&#x2082;, respectively. Which is greater than 14.44% and 24.11% compare to 2% and 6% respectively. This result shown that the inclusion of reinforcement particles increases the hardness of the weld zone, with the optimum reinforcement being 4% of SiCp and 6% of TiB&#x2082;. The welded specimens were tested using tensile tester to determine their TS and ductility. The results revealed that the inclusion of ceramic particles increases the TS of the welds but ductility found to be deceased. The Al/SiCp MMCs with 4% displayed the highest TS of 226.7&#xa0;MPa followed by those with 2% and 6% respectively. Which is increase 8.16% and 3.37% compare to 2% and 6% respectively. Similarly, the aluminium based MMCs containing 4% TiB&#x2082; recorded the highest TS of 228.5&#xa0;MPa followed by the Al/TiB&#x2082; MMCs containing 2% and 6% TiB&#x2082; respectively. Which is increase 11.35% and 4.77% compare to 2% and 6% respectively. However, the Al/SiCp MMCs with 4% SiCp showed relatively lower ductility of 2.9% when compared to the Al/TiB&#x2082; MMCs with 4% TiB&#x2082;. Overall, the inclusion of ceramic reinforcements into the aluminium based MMCs improves the mechanical performance of the weldments, although the optimal composition depends on specific application requirements.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srinivasan</LastName><ForeName>R Ganapathy</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Vel Tech Multi Tech Dr Rangarajan Dr Sakunthala Engineering College, Chennai, 600062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bakkiyaraj</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Rajalakshmi Institute of Technology, Chennai, 600124, India. bakya1984@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rajaravi</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Hindhusthan College of Engineering and Technology, Coimbatore, 641032, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Selvam</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Vel Tech Multi Tech Dr Rangarajan Dr Sakunthala Engineering College, Chennai, 600062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cep</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Machining, Assembly and Engineering Metrology, Faculty of Mechanical Engineering, VSB-Technical University of Ostrava, 70800, Ostrava, Czech Republic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swarna</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosciences, Saveetha School of Engineering, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Chennai, 602105, India. bswarna261@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CZ.10.03.01/00/22_003/0000048</GrantID><Agency>EU</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Al/SiCp</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Al/TiB&#x2082;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microstructure analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TIG welding</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethics, consent to Participate, and consent to publish declarations: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41545550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12891499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35715-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35715-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kamboj, N. &amp; Thakur, L. A study of the processing and characterization of RSM optimized YSZ-Inconel625 wear-resistant TIG weld cladding. <i>Surf. Topogr. Metrol. Prop.</i><b>10</b> (4), 045021 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2051-672X/aca345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvamani, S. T., Bakkiyaraj, M., Palani, S. &amp; Yoganandan, G. Corrosion behavior and analysis on friction stir welded aluminium matrix composites. <i>Surface Topogr. Metrol. Prop.</i><b>10</b>, 025036. 10.1088/2051-672X/ac7a50 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, Y. et al. Studies on microstructure and properties of TiB&#x2082;&#x2013;Al3Ti ceramic particles reinforced spray-formed 7055 aluminium alloy fusion welded joints. <i>J. Mater. Sci. Technol.</i><b>19</b> 1298 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, T. et al. Appropriate amount of TiB&#x2082; particles causes the ductile fracture of the un-weldable spray-formed 7055 aluminium alloy TIG-welded joint. <i>Mater. Res. Express</i><b>8</b> 096512 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/ac2194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo, W. A. N. G., Xue, S. B., Han, Y. L. &amp; Lin Z. Q. Effect of combinative addition of Ti and Sr on modification of AA4043 welding wire and mechanical properties of AA6082 welded by TIG welding. <i>Trans. Nonferrous Met. Soc. China</i><b>27</b> 272 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1003-6326(17)60031-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, T. et al. Study on ductile fracture of unweldable spray formed 7055 aluminium alloy TIG welded joints with ceramic particles. <i>Mater. Today Commun.</i><b>29</b> 102835 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2021.102835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajaravi, C., Ganesh, B., Lakshmanan, S. &amp; Gobalakrishnan, B. Influence of TIG welding processing parameters on mechanical properties of austenitic stainless steel using Taguchi analysis. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>72</b> 2402 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2022.09.422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, Q. D., Huang, B. W., Wu, Y. J. &amp; Su, X. D. Microstructure and mechanical properties of friction stir welds on unmodified and P-modified Al-Mg2Si-Si alloys. <i>J. Mater. Sci. Technol.</i><b>250</b> 320 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2017.07.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattahi, M., Ghaheri, A., Arabian, N., Amirkhanlu, F. &amp; Moayedi, H. Applying the ultrasonic vibration during TIG welding as a promising approach for the development of nanoparticle dispersion strengthened aluminiumweldments. <i>J. Mater. Sci. Technol.</i><b>282</b> 116672 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2020.116672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinaharan, I., Kalaiselvan, K., Akinlabi, E. T. &amp; Davim, J. P. Microstructure and wear characterization of rice husk Ash reinforced copper matrix composites prepared using friction stir processing. <i>J. Alloys Compd.</i><b>718</b> 150 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2017.05.117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi, E. et al. Microstructure and mechanical properties of Al/ZrC/TiC hybrid nanocomposite filler metals of tungsten inert gas welding fabricated by accumulative roll bonding. <i>J. Manuf. Process.</i><b>26</b> 173 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmapro.2017.02.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirizad, M. et al. Evaluation of microstructure and mechanical properties in friction stir welded A356&#x2009;+&#x2009;15% SiCp cast composite. <i>Mater. Lett.</i><b>60</b> 565 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2005.09.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramkumar, K. R. &amp; Natarajan, S. Investigations on microstructure and mechanical properties of TiO2 nanoparticles addition in al 3003 alloy joints by gas tungsten Arc welding. <i>Mater. Sci. Eng. A</i><b>727</b> 51 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2018.04.111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. H., Song, S. L., Qu, S. Y. &amp; Zou, Z. D. Characterization of in situ synthesized tic particle reinforced Fe-based composite coatings produced by multi-pass overlapping GTAW melting process. <i>Surf. Coat. Technol.</i>, <b>201</b> 5899 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfcoat.2006.10.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fattahi, M., Nabhani, N., Rashidkhani, E., Fattahi, Y., Akhavan, S. &amp; Arabian, N. A new technique for the strengthening of aluminium tungsten inert gas weld metals: using carbon nanotube/aluminium composite as a filler metal. <i>Micron</i><b>54</b> 28 (2013)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23948441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varshney, D. &amp; Kumar, K. Application and use of different aluminium alloys with respect to workability, strength and welding parameter optimization. <i>Ain Shams Eng. J.</i><b>12</b> 1143 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asej.2020.05.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy, M. I., Madhavarao, S., BhadriRaju C, R., Kumar, M. A. &amp; Varma, P. R. The effect of carbon fiber powder reinforced composite coating on mechanical properties of TIG welded black steel pipes. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>62</b> 3516 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2022.04.347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. B., Miao Y. G., Li L. Q. &amp; Lin, W. U. Joint performance of laser-TIG double-side welded 5A06 aluminium alloy. <i>Trans. Nonferrous Met. Soc. China</i><b>19</b> 26 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1003-6326(08)60223-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo, W., Xue, S. B., Han, Y. L. &amp; Lin, Z. Q. Effect of combinative addition of Ti and Sr on modification of AA4043 welding wire and mechanical properties of AA6082 welded by TIG welding. <i>Trans. Nonferrous Met. Soc. China</i><b>27</b> 272 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1003-6326(17)60031-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. et al. Effect of filler wire on mechanical properties, microstructure and natural aging behavior of 2A55 Al-Li alloy TIG welded joint. <i>Metals</i><b>13</b> 347 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met13020347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhilip, A. &amp; Nampoothiri, J. Investigating the effects of ultrasonic assistance on TIG welding of AA7075 alloys: a machine learning-based optimization study using RSM-PSO. <i>Phys. Scr.</i><b>100</b> (1), 016002 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, N. K., Pyla, K. R., Debta, M., K &amp; Masanta, M. Performance evaluation of TIG cladded in-situ TiC-TiB&#x2082; composite coating fabricated on AISI304 stainless steel. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>62</b> 5956 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2022.04.687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buytoz, S. &amp; Ulutan, M. In Situ synthesis of SiC reinforced MMC surface on AISI 304 stainless steel by TIG surface alloying. <i>Surf. Coat. Technol.</i><b>200</b> 36984. (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfcoat.2005.02.178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurijala, C., Rajendran, R. &amp; Giridharan, K. Investigation on effects of nano-reinforcement on the mechanical properties, fatigue, and microstructural analysis of dissimilar AA6061-Mg AZ31B weld joints. <i>Phys. Scr.</i><b>99</b> (11), 115928 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1402-4896/ad804e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanjundan, A., Natarajan, U. &amp; Simson, D. Investigation of microstructure and mechanical properties of Al-Si alloy thin-walled cylindrical part fabricated by CMT based WAAM process. <i>Phys. Scr.</i><b>99</b> (10), 105606 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1402-4896/ad7177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, Z. et al. Experimental study on the low-power laser-TIG hybrid welding of SiCp/6061-T6 al matrix composites. <i>Opt. Lasers Eng.</i><b>186</b>, 108861 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlaseng.2025.108861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, Y., Wang, S. &amp; Jian, Y. Inhibition mechanism of the interface reaction in the molten pool of SiCp/Al composites by pulsed laser welding with powder-filling. <i>Chin. J. Mech. Eng.</i><b>37</b> (1), 154 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10033-024-01141-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senthilkumar, J., Bakkiyaraj, M., Balasubramanian, M. &amp; Loganathan, T. G. Effect of FW conditions on mechanical and microstructural characteristic of AA6061/SiC/Graphite hybrid composites joint by empirical relationship. <i>Surf. Topogr. Metrol. Prop.</i><b>9</b> (4), 045042 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2051-672X/ac4148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Effects of laser welding parameters on the porosity and acicular phase in SiCp/6092 aluminum matrix composite welded joints. <i>J. Mater. Res. Technol.</i><b>23</b>, 5127&#x2013;5141 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2023.02.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas, K. &amp; Sahoo, C. K. A review on TIG cladding of engineering material for improving their surface property. <i>Surf. Topogr. Metrol. Prop.</i><b>11</b> (2), 023001 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2051-672X/acd6aa</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chittoriya, B. S., Jayant, A. &amp; Kumar, R. Effect of multipass FSP and (SiC&#x2009;+&#x2009;TiB&#x2082;) nanoparticles on the mechanical and metallurgical characteristic of the hybrid metal matrix composite. <i>Silicon</i><b>15</b> (18), 7927&#x2013;7941 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12633-023-02635-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, F. et al. Microstructure, mechanical and thermal-properties of ultrafine-grained Al2024&#x2013;TiC-GNPs nanocomposite. <i>Mater. Sci. Eng. A</i><b>841</b>, 142855 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2022.142855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>