<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41809289</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Multidisciplinary Approach in the Management of Aggressive Retinopathy of Prematurity With Bleb-Like Posterior Combined Retinal Detachment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103144</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103144</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103144</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103144</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We report two cases of bleb-like combined retinal detachment (BLRD) in infants with aggressive retinopathy of prematurity (A-ROP). Both cases involved premature infants born at 28 weeks of gestation with complex postnatal courses, who were referred to our clinic for ROP management. On presentation, both babies were diagnosed with stage 4B ROP in zone 1 with bilateral BLRD. Indirect ophthalmoscope-guided laser photocoagulation under topical anesthesia was performed on the same day. Pediatric clearance for surgery was obtained. Both infants underwent blood transfusions for anemia. Subsequently, 25-gauge lens-sparing vitrectomy with endolaser and fluid-air exchange was performed in both cases. Postoperative courses were uneventful. Follow-up examinations under anesthesia allowed for laser augmentation in the first case; no additional avascular retina was noted in the second case, and no further laser treatment was applied. At the most recent follow-up, both babies exhibited well-attached retinas with regressing ROP. Refraction was performed, glasses were prescribed, and close monitoring was advised. BLRD in zone 1 ROP presents significant therapeutic challenges. Successful management relies on prompt and coordinated teamwork among ophthalmologists, neonatologists, anesthetists, and opticians. Optimal outcomes depend on maintaining adequate hemoglobin levels, timely surgical management, examinations under anesthesia (EUA), laser augmentation, visual rehabilitation, consistent follow-up, strong parental involvement, and ongoing multidisciplinary collaboration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Jain et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>K Shreeya</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vitreoretina, Srimati Kanuri Santhamma Center for Vitreo Retinal Diseases, Anant Bajaj Retina Institute, Standard Chartered-LVPEI Academy for Eye Care Education, L V Prasad Eye Institute, Hyderabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belenje</LastName><ForeName>Akash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vitreoretina, Srimati Kanuri Santhamma Center for Vitreo Retinal Diseases, Anant Bajaj Retina Institute, Standard Chartered-LVPEI Academy for Eye Care Education, L V Prasad Eye Institute, Hyderabad, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aggressive retinopathy of prematurity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anaemia correction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bleb-like posterior combined retinal detachment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lens sparing vitrectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">role of multidisciplinary approach</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: Akash Belenje declare(s) a grant from Hyderabad Eye Research Foundation (HERF). Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41809289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12969225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lens-sparing vitrectomy for stage 4 retinopathy of prematurity. Hubbard GB 3rd, Cherwick DH, Burian G. Ophthalmology. 2004;111:2274&#x2013;2277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15582086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgical outcomes in aggressive retinopathy of prematurity (AROP)-related retinal detachments. Sen P, Bhende P, Maitra P. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2023;71:3454&#x2013;3459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10752330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37870006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes and prognostic factors for aggressive posterior retinopathy of prematurity following initial treatment with intravitreal ranibizumab. Tong Q, Yin H, Zhao M, Li X, Yu W. BMC Ophthalmol. 2018;18:150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6019321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29940900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Classification of Retinopathy of Prematurity, Third Edition. Chiang MF, Quinn GE, Fielder AR, et al. Ophthalmology. 2021;128:0&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10979521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34247850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bleb-like posterior combined retinal detachment in severe retinopathy of prematurity: clinical characteristics, management challenges and outcome. Patel A, Padhy SK, Saoji K, et al. Eye (Lond) 2021;35:3152&#x2013;3155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8526577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33070158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Factors associated with reactivation after intravitreal bevacizumab or ranibizumab therapy in infants with retinopathy of prematurity. Iwahashi C, Utamura S, Kuniyoshi K, Sugioka K, Konishi Y, Wada N, Kusaka S. Retina. 2021;41:2261&#x2013;2268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33958533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exudative retinal detachment, a primary presentation in retinopathy of prematurity. Sen P, Yusufali H, Khetan V, Rao C, Banerjee A. Can J Ophthalmol. 2018;53:0&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29631849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giant retinal tear with retinal detachment in regressed aggressive posterior retinopathy of prematurity treated by laser. Chandra P, Tewari R, Salunkhe N, Kumawat D, Kumar V. J Pediatr Ophthalmol Strabismus. 2017;54:0&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28665441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical form of retinopathy of prematurity with severe fibrovascular proliferation in the optic disk region. Yokoi T, Katagiri S, Hiraoka M, et al. Retina. 2018;38:1605&#x2013;1612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28800017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A hybrid form of retinopathy of prematurity. Sanghi G, Dogra MR, Dogra M, Katoch D, Gupta A. Br J Ophthalmol. 2012;96:519&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22096143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of anaemia on multifactorial disease retinopathy of prematurity: a prospective observational study. Tandon M, Ranjan R, Muralidharan U, Kannan A. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9462659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36110483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of reactivation between ranibizumab and bevacizumab in aggressive retinopathy of prematurity: a retrospective case series. Gangwe AB, Ekumankama CB, Singh A, Parchand SM, Agrawal D, Azad RV. Indian J Ophthalmol. 2025;73:0&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11834909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39257101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lower hemoglobin levels as a risk factor for the development of retinopathy of prematurity. Gudu RK, Sahoo S, Jena P, Behura SS, Priyadarshini S, Panda SK. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11315375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39130831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>