<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41448090</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3336</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>501</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hazardous materials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hazard Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spatiotemporal characteristics and hydrogeochemical evolution of toluene and trichloroethylene composite contamination zones in groundwater.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>140898</StartPage><MedlinePgn>140898</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.140898</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0304-3894(25)03819-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The synergistic and antagonistic interactions between groundwater composite contamination plumes result in complex and dynamically evolving pollution effects, complicating the formulation of investigation and remediation strategies. This study employed a mesoscale tank system with high environmental fidelity to simulate the migration and transformation processes of dissolved-state toluene and trichloroethylene composite plumes, analyzing their biogeochemical succession. Findings indicate convergence at plume margins, forming persistent composite contamination zones. Toluene degradation rapidly depletes oxygen, creating anaerobic conditions while serving as an efficient carbon source that stimulates proliferation of characteristic microorganisms. Concurrently, molecular hydrogen generated during degradation provided a sustained electron acceptor source, promoting TCE reduction and dechlorination at rates 2.35-4.34 times higher than in single-pollutant zones. Combining intermediate product identification, differentiated degradation pathways for toluene and trichloroethylene were established, regulated by biogeochemical mechanisms. This study elucidates the succession of pollution dynamics within the composite zone, driven by thermodynamic succession of electron acceptors, transitioning from aerobic antagonism to anaerobic synergy. These findings underscore the imperative to integrate redox evolution models with pollutant migration processes to accurately predict the fate of mixed plumes and formulate remediation strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Shuxuan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Environmental Engineering, Anhui University, Hefei 230601, China; State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Simulation and Control of Groundwater Pollution, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China; State Key Laboratory of Environmental Criteria and Risk Assessment, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Simulation and Control of Groundwater Pollution, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China; State Key Laboratory of Environmental Criteria and Risk Assessment, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Zhifei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Poyang Lake Environment and Resource Utilization, Ministry of Education, School of Resources &amp; Environment, Nanchang University, Nanchang 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Environmental Engineering, Anhui University, Hefei 230601, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xuesheng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Environmental Engineering, Anhui University, Hefei 230601, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xi</LastName><ForeName>Beidou</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Simulation and Control of Groundwater Pollution, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China; State Key Laboratory of Environmental Criteria and Risk Assessment, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Yonghai</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Simulation and Control of Groundwater Pollution, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China; State Key Laboratory of Environmental Criteria and Risk Assessment, Chinese Research Academy of Environmental Sciences, Beijing 100012, China. Electronic address: jiangyonghai@craes.org.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Hazard Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9422688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-3894</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biogeochemistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Composite contamination zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Groundwater</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Toluene</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Trichloroethylene</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41448090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.140898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0304-3894(25)03819-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>