<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41230732</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5725</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Blood pressure monitoring</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Blood Press Monit</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improving cardiovascular autonomic function in postmenopausal women with hypertension: a pilot study of supervised versus home-based aerobic exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>53</StartPage><EndPage>60</EndPage><MedlinePgn>53-60</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MBP.0000000000000782</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Arterial hypertension is a major global cause of cardiovascular disease, a risk heightened by postmenopausal physiological changes. Although aerobic exercise is protective, its optimal intensity, duration, and supervision for hypertensive postmenopausal women remain unclear. This study, therefore, compares a supervised intensive aerobic program with a home-based regimen, assessing their effects on key cardiac health indicators in this population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this single-center pilot randomized controlled trial, we enrolled 31 postmenopausal women. Participants were divided into two groups: one underwent a 6-week supervised intensive aerobic exercise program, and the other followed a home-based exercise regimen. Key outcome measures included cardiorespiratory endurance, heart rate variability, and blood pressure variability. Outcome measures were evaluated at weeks 6 and 12. Intra-group and inter-group comparisons were evaluated using appropriate statistical methods.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After 12 weeks, the supervised exercise group showed significant improvements in VO 2 max ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.003), metabolic equivalents (METs) ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.002), and standard deviation of normal-to-normal intervals (SDNN) values ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.034) at both the 6th and 12th weeks. However, the sole significant inter-group difference was a greater reduction in 24-hour SBP variability (SBP-SD) in the supervised arm (&#x394; -0.95&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;1.15 vs. + 1.54&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;0.94&#x2005;mmHg; P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.041), driven mainly by the week 6-12 interval ( P &#x2005;=&#x2005;0.004).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Supervised intensive aerobic exercise produced clear within-group gains in VO&#x2082; max, METs, and SDNN, and it reduced 24-hour SBP variability relative to home-based walking. Although between-group differences for the primary fitness and autonomic outcomes were not statistically significant in this pilot, the pattern suggests that a supervised, tailored program may confer additional clinical benefit and merits evaluation in a larger trial.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gungor</LastName><ForeName>Cengizhan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Antalya Kepez State Hospital, Antalya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akyildiz Tezcan</LastName><ForeName>Ezgi</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Selcuk University Medical Faculty, Konya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zerbil</LastName><ForeName>&#xd6;nder Murat</ForeName><Initials>&#xd6;M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Medicana Atasehir Hospital, Istanbul.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tuncez</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Selcuk University Medical Faculty, Konya, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Blood Press Monit</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9606438</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1359-5237</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017698" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postmenopause</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001341" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autonomic Nervous System</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aerobic exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood pressure variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart rate variability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postmenopause</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41230732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MBP.0000000000000782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00126097-990000000-00176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kallikazaros IE. Arterial hypertension. Hellenic J Cardiol 2013; 54:413&#x2013;415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva BV, Sousa C, Caldeira D, Abreu A, Pinto FJ. Management of arterial hypertension: challenges and opportunities. Clin Cardiol 2022; 45:1094&#x2013;1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavi S, Nevo O, Thaler I, Rosenfeld R, Dayan L, Hirshoren N, et al. Effect of aging on the cardiovascular regulatory systems in healthy women. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 2007; 292:R788&#x2013;R793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stachenfeld NS. Sex hormone effects on body fluid regulation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 2008; 36:152&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancia G, Grassi G. The autonomic nervous system and hypertension. Circ Res 2014; 114:1804&#x2013;1814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart ECJ, Charkoudian N. Sympathetic neural regulation of blood pressure: influences of sex and aging. Physiology (Bethesda) 2014; 29:8&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vongpatanasin W. Autonomic regulation of blood pressure in menopause. Semin Reprod Med 2009; 27:338&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller VM, Duckles SP. Vascular actions of estrogens: functional implications. Pharmacol Rev 2008; 60:210&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cygankiewicz I, Zareba W. Heart rate variability. Handb Clin Neurol 2013; 117:379&#x2013;393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens SL, Wood S, Koshiaris C, Law K, Glasziou P, Stevens RJ, McManus RJ. Blood pressure variability and cardiovascular disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ 2016; 354:i4098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Lavie CJ, Blair SN, Church TS. Heart rate variability characteristics in sedentary postmenopausal women following six months of exercise training: the DREW study. PLoS One 2008; 3:e2288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davy KP, Willis WL, Seals DR. Influence of exercise training on heart rate variability in post-menopausal women with elevated arterial blood pressure. Clin Physiol 1997; 17:31&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Quilis C, Kingsley JD, Malkani K, Cervellin G, Lippi G, Sanchis-Gomar F. Modulation of heart rate by acute or chronic aerobic exercise. Potential effects on blood pressure control. Curr Pharm Des 2017; 23:4650&#x2013;4657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnest CP, Blair SN, Church TS. Heart rate variability and exercise in aging women. J Womens Health (Larchmt) 2012; 21:334&#x2013;339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masroor S, Bhati P, Verma S, Khan M, Hussain ME. Heart rate variability following combined aerobic and resistance training in sedentary hypertensive women: a randomised control trial. Indian Heart J 2018; 70(Suppl 3):S28&#x2013;S35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasertsri P, Phoemsapthawee J, Kuamsub S, Poolpol K, Boonla O. Effects of long-term regular continuous and intermittent walking on oxidative stress, metabolic profile, heart rate variability, and blood pressure in older adults with hypertension. J Environ Public Health 2022; 2022:5942947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MartinezAguirre-Betolaza A, Mujika I, Fryer SM, Corres P, Gorostegi-Anduaga I, Arratibel-Imaz I, et al. Effects of different aerobic exercise programs on cardiac autonomic modulation and hemodynamics in hypertension: data from EXERDIET-HTA randomized trial. J Hum Hypertens 2020; 34:709&#x2013;718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuya M, Ohkubo T, Metoki H, Asayama K, Hara A, Obara T, et al. Day-by-day variability of blood pressure and heart rate at home as a novel predictor of prognosis: the Ohasama study. Hypertension 2008; 52:1045&#x2013;1050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariano IM, Dechichi JGC, Matias LAS, Rodrigues Mateus de Lima, Batista JP, de Souza TCF, et al. Ambulatory blood pressure variability and combined exercise training: comparison between hypertensive and normotensive postmenopausal women. Blood Press Monit 2020; 25:338&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes S, Mesquita-Bastos J, Garcia C, Leit&#xe3;o C, Ribau V, Teixeira M, et al. Aerobic exercise improves central blood pressure and blood pressure variability among patients with resistant hypertension: results of the EnRicH trial. Hypertens Res 2023; 46:1547&#x2013;1557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbarzadeh Ganjeh B, Zeraattalab-Motlagh S, Jayedi A, Daneshvar M, Gohari Z, Norouziasl R, et al. Effects of aerobic exercise on blood pressure in patients with hypertension: a systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis of randomized trials. Hypertens Res 2024; 47:385&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SH, Chae YR. Characteristics of aerobic exercise as determinants of blood pressure control in hypertensive patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Korean Acad Nurs 2020; 50:740&#x2013;756.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>