<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41296032</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1912</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's archives of pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Regulating effect of genistein on&#xa0;the&#xa0;association of endothelial activation and stress index with atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease risk: a cross-sectional study of the NHANES database.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00210-025-04779-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this study is to assess the associations of urinary genistein and endothelial activation and stress index (EASIX) with 10-year atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease (ASCVD) risk. This cross-sectional analysis employed data obtained from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES). Weighted univariable and multivariable logistic regression models examined EASIX-ASCVD risk correlations, with odds ratio and 95% confidence interval [OR (95%CI)] as effect measures. The potential interactions were explored between EASIX and genistein on 10-year ASCVD risk using additive and multiplicative interaction analyses. The relationships of EASIX and 10-year ASCVD risk were further assessed at different genistein levels. Subgroup analyses examined age, BMI, diabetes, hypertension, and dyslipidemia categories. Totally, 4478 eligible participants were stratified into low-risk (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2157) and high-risk (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2321) ASCVD groups. Elevated levels of EASIX (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.35, 95% CI 1.18-1.54), EASIX<sub>median</sub>&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.427 (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.40, 95% CI 1.14-1.73), EASIX<sub>RCS</sub>&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.434 (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.45, 95% CI 1.18-1.77), EASIX<sub>quartile</sub> (0.325-0.427, OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.48, 95% CI 1.05-2.07; 0.427-0.567, OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.51, 95% CI 1.08-2.10;&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;0.567, OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.08, 95% CI 1.57-2.77), and log2(EASIX) (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.32, 95% CI 1.19-1.46) were associated with higher odds of 10-year ASCVD. Low genistein levels presented no significant correlation with 10-year ASCVD risk. The multiplicative interaction between EASIX and genistein levels was significant. When genistein levels&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;54.105&#xa0;&#xb5;g/g, the connections between elevated EASIX levels and higher 10-year ASCVD risk were established in subgroups of age&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;60&#xa0;years, BMI&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;25&#xa0;kg/m<sup>2</sup>, non-diabetes, hypertension, and dyslipidemia. Elevated EASIX levels correlated with a higher 10-year ASCVD risk. Whether genistein modulates this association requires further validation, which may have potential implications for ASCVD prevention strategies in the general population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yongliang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Zhangzhou Yuanshan Hospital, No. 999, Yuanshan Avenue, Zhangzhou High-Tech Zone, Zhangzhou, 363118, Fujian Province, China. Yongliang_Huangg@outlook.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lan</LastName><ForeName>Huijuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Department, Zhangzhou People's Hospital, Zhangzhou, 363000, Fujian Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Hongchuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Zhangzhou Zhengxing Hospital, Zhangzhou, 363000, Fujian Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0326264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-1298</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">10-year ASCVD risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EASIX</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genistein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NHANES</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Regulating effect</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: It is not applicable because the NHANES Database belongs to public databases, the patients involved in the database have obtained ethical approval, users can download relevant data for free for research and publish relevant articles, and our study is based on open-source data, and the Zhangzhou People&#x2019;s Hospital does not require research using publicly available data to be submitted for review to their ethics committee, so there are no ethical issues and other conflicts of interest. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41296032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00210-025-04779-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00210-025-04779-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ajdzanovi&#x107; V, Sosi&#x107;-Jurjevi&#x107; B, Filipovi&#x107; B, Trifunovi&#x107; S, Manojlovi&#x107;-Stojanoski M, Sekuli&#x107; M, Milosevi&#x107; V (2009) Genistein-induced histomorphometric and hormone secreting changes in the adrenal cortex in middle-aged rats. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 234(2):148&#x2013;156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19064942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3181/0807-RM-231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu PV, Si H, Fu Z, Zhen W, Liu D (2012) Genistein prevents hyperglycemia-induced monocyte adhesion to human aortic endothelial cells through preservation of the cAMP signaling pathway and ameliorates vascular inflammation in obese diabetic mice. J Nutr 142(4):724&#x2013;730</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22399524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3301991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.111.152322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai X, Song S, Hu J, Zhu Q, Shen D, Yang W, Ma H, Luo Q, Hong J, Zhang D et al (2024) Association of the trajectory of plasma aldosterone concentration with the risk of cardiovascular disease in patients with hypertension: a cohort study. Sci Rep 14(1):4906</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38418472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10902285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-54971-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang G, Hu Y, Ge Q, Chu S, Avolio A, Zuo J (2023) Arterial stiffness as a predictor of the index of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in hypertensive patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph20042832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20042832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37681789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10487101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SS, Wu JH, Cui J, Hua C, Xia SJ, He L, Li X, Ning M, Hu R, Du X et al (2023) Analysis of dyslipidemia management status in atrial fibrillation patients with very high and high risk of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. Zhonghua Xin Xue Guan Bing Za Zhi 51(6):642&#x2013;647</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37312483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daiber A, Steven S, Weber A, Shuvaev VV, Muzykantov VR, Laher I, Li H, Lamas S, Munzel T (2017) Targeting vascular (endothelial) dysfunction. Br J Pharmacol 174(12):1591&#x2013;1619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.13517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan H, Zhang Q, Liu J, Li R, Wang D, Peng W, Wu C (2021) Suppression of apoptosis in vascular endothelial cell, the promising way for natural medicines to treat atherosclerosis. Pharmacol Res 168:105599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33838291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2021.105599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estler B, Fr&#xf6;hlich H, T&#xe4;ger T, Hund H, Frey N, Luft T, Frankenstein L (2025) Endothelial dysfunction assessed by the endothelial activation and stress index (EASIX) predicts risk of mortality in chronic heart failure patients. Int J Cardiol 438:133566</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40617481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2025.133566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finke D, Hund H, Frey N, Luft T, Lehmann LH (2024) EASIX (endothelial activation and stress index) predicts mortality in patients with coronary artery disease. Clin Res Cardiol. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00392-024-02534-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00392-024-02534-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39535591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12283470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan M, Shen L, Wang S, Guo Z, Zheng T, Tan Y, Fan Y, Liu L, Chen L, Jiang A et al (2020) Genistein inhibits high fat diet-induced obesity through miR-222 by targeting BTG2 and adipor1. Food Funct 11(3):2418&#x2013;2426</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32129363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9FO00861F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Garcia FJ, Gutierrez Avila G, Alfaro-Acha A, Amor Andres MS, De Los Angeles De La Torre Lanza M, Escribano Aparicio MV, Humanes Aparicio S, Larrion Zugasti JL, Gomez-Serranillo Reus M, Rodriguez-Artalejo F et al (2011) The prevalence of frailty syndrome in an older population from Spain. The Toledo Study for Healthy Aging. J Nutr Health Aging 15(10):852&#x2013;856</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22159772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12603-011-0075-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimbrone MA Jr, Garcia-Cardena G (2016) Endothelial cell dysfunction and the pathobiology of atherosclerosis. Circ Res 118(4):620&#x2013;636</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4762052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.115.306301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goff DC Jr, Lloyd-Jones DM, Bennett G, Coady S, D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Gibbons R, Greenland P, Lackland DT, Levy D, O&#x2019;Donnell CJ et al (2014) 2013 ACC/AHA guideline on the assessment of cardiovascular risk: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. Circulation 129(25 Suppl 2):S49-73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24222018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh YX, Jalil J, Lam KW, Husain K, Premakumar CM (2022) Genistein: a review on its anti-inflammatory properties. Front Pharmacol 13:820969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35140617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8818956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.820969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grundy SM, Stone NJ, Bailey AL, Beam C, Birtcher KK, Blumenthal RS, Braun LT, de Ferranti S, Faiella-Tommasino J, Forman DE et al (2019) 2018 AHA/ACC/AACVPR/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/ADA/AGS/APhA/ASPC/NLA/PCNA guideline on the management of blood cholesterol: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation 139(25):e1082&#x2013;e1143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang G, Liu Y, Chang H, Zhang X, Ren D, Wilson JX, Cao X (2008) Effects of genistein on oxidative injury in endothelial cells. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol Tokyo 54(5):402&#x2013;408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3177/jnsv.54.402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo X, Jia S, Sun L, Yao Y, Liao H, Chen X (2024) Association of dietary live microbe intake with frailty in US adults: evidence from NHANES. J Nutr Health Aging 28(3):100171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38423889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnha.2024.100171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jellinger PS, Smith DA, Mehta AE, Ganda O, Handelsman Y, Rodbard HW, Shepherd MD, Seibel JA (2012) Dyslipidemia ATFfMo, Prevention of A: American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists&#x2019; guidelines for management of dyslipidemia and prevention of atherosclerosis. Endocr Pract 18(Suppl 1):1&#x2013;78</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22522068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4158/EP.18.S1.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordelas L, Terzer T, Gooley T, Davis C, Sandmaier BM, Sorror M, Penack O, Schaeper NDE, Blau IW, Beelen D et al (2023) EASIX-1year and late mortality after allogeneic stem cell transplantation. Blood Adv 7(18):5374&#x2013;5381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37477588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10509665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2022008617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krolikoski M, Monslow J, Pure E (2019) The CD44-HA axis and inflammation in atherosclerosis: a temporal perspective. Matrix Biol 78&#x2013;79:201&#x2013;218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matbio.2018.05.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite AR, Borges-Canha M, Cardoso R, Neves JS, Castro-Ferreira R, Leite-Moreira A (2020) Novel biomarkers for evaluation of endothelial dysfunction. Angiology 71(5):397&#x2013;410</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0003319720903586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chen L, Zheng Q, Liu G, Wang M, Wei S, Chen T (2024) Lactate dehydrogenase A promotes nasopharyngeal carcinoma progression through the TAK1/NF-kappaB axis. Mol Biol Rep 51(1):152</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11033-023-09130-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XG, Hou Y, Hou M (2023) How we treat primary immune thrombocytopenia in adults. J Hematol Oncol 16(1):4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36658588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9850343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13045-023-01401-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luft T, Benner A, Jodele S, Dandoy CE, Storb R, Gooley T, Sandmaier BM, Becker N, Radujkovic A, Dreger P et al (2017) EASIX in patients with acute graft-versus-host disease: a retrospective cohort analysis. Lancet Haematol 4(9):e414&#x2013;e423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28733186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3026(17)30108-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luft T, Wendtner CM, Kosely F, Radujkovic A, Benner A, Korell F, Kihm L, Bauer MF, Dreger P, Merle U (2021) EASIX for prediction of outcome in hospitalized SARS-CoV-2 infected patients. Front Immunol 12:634416</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34248931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8261154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.634416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcelo C, Warwick M, Marcelo C, Qayyum R (2019) The association between urinary genistein levels and mortality among adults in the United States. PLoS ONE 14(1):e0211368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30682197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6347457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0211368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marco ML, Hutkins R, Hill C, Fulgoni VL, Cifelli CJ, Gahche J, Slavin JL, Merenstein D, Tancredi DJ, Sanders ME (2022) A classification system for defining and estimating dietary intake of live microbes in US adults and children. J Nutr 152(7):1729&#x2013;1736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9258558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxac074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marx N, Husain M, Lehrke M, Verma S, Sattar N (2022) GLP-1 receptor agonists for the reduction of atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk in patients with type 2 diabetes. Circulation 146(24):1882&#x2013;1894</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36508493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.059595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mas-Bargues C, Borras C, Vina J (2022) Genistein, a tool for geroscience. Mech Ageing Dev 204:111665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35307412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mad.2022.111665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mucka S, Miodonska M, Jakubiak GK, Starzak M, Cieslar G, Stanek A (2022) Endothelial function assessment by flow-mediated dilation method: a valuable tool in the evaluation of the cardiovascular system. Int J Environ Res Public Health 19(18):11242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36141513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9517126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191811242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukund V, Mukund D, Sharma V, Mannarapu M, Alam A (2017) Genistein: its role in metabolic diseases and cancer. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol 119:13&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29065980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.critrevonc.2017.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nedkoff L, Briffa T, Zemedikun D, Herrington S, Wright FL (2023) Global trends in atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. Clin Ther 45(11):1087&#x2013;1091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37914585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2023.09.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicastro HL, Mondul AM, Rohrmann S, Platz EA (2013) Associations between urinary soy isoflavonoids and two inflammatory markers in adults in the United States in 2005&#x2013;2008. Cancer Causes Control 24(6):1185&#x2013;1196</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23558443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3798025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niezen S, Trivedi HD, Mukamal KJ, Jiang ZG (2021) Associations between alcohol consumption and hepatic steatosis in the USA. Liver Int 41(9):2020&#x2013;2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34297882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9330542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/liv.15020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palomo I, Wehinger S, Andres V, Garcia-Garcia FJ, Fuentes E (2024) Rhoa/rho kinase pathway activation in age-associated endothelial cell dysfunction and thrombosis. J Cell Mol Med 28(8):e18153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38568071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10989549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcmm.18153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Read MA, Whitley MZ, Williams AJ, Collins T (1994) NF-kappa B and I kappa B alpha: an inducible regulatory system in endothelial activation. J Exp Med 179(2):503&#x2013;512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7507507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.179.2.503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang M, Ma X, Zhu F, Zhu C, Ying Z (2024) Association between endothelial activation and stress index and 30-day mortality risk in acute myocardial infarction patients: a study based on the medical information mart for intensive care-IV database. BMC Cardiovasc Disord 24(1):699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39633266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11619625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12872-024-04353-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schafer N, Lohmann C, Winnik S, van Tits LJ, Miranda MX, Vergopoulos A, Ruschitzka F, Nussberger J, Berger S, Luscher TF et al (2013) Endothelial mineralocorticoid receptor activation mediates endothelial dysfunction in diet-induced obesity. Eur Heart J 34(45):3515&#x2013;3524</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23594590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3844149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/eht095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schult D, Rasch S, Schmid RM, Lahmer T, Mayr U (2023) EASIX is an accurate and easily available prognostic score in critically ill patients with advanced liver disease. J Clin Med. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm12072553</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12072553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37048641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10094870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si H, Liu D (2007) Phytochemical genistein in the regulation of vascular function: new insights. Curr Med Chem 14(24):2581&#x2013;2589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17979711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/092986707782023325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone NJ, Robinson JG, Lichtenstein AH, Bairey Merz CN, Blum CB, Eckel RH, Goldberg AC, Gordon D, Levy D, Lloyd-Jones DM (2013) ACC/AHA guideline on the treatment of blood cholesterol to reduce atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol 2014 63(25 Pt B):2889&#x2013;2934</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Jian Z, Yuan C, Jin X, Li H, Wang K (2021) Coffee consumption and prostate cancer risk: results from National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey 1999&#x2013;2010 and Mendelian randomization analyses. Nutrients. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu13072317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13072317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35011075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8747721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei TT, Chandy M, Nishiga M, Zhang A, Kumar KK, Thomas D, Manhas A, Rhee S, Justesen JM, Chen IY et al (2022) Cannabinoid receptor 1 antagonist genistein attenuates marijuana-induced vascular inflammation. Cell 185(10):1676-1693.e1623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35489334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9400797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2022.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S, Ilyas I, Little PJ, Li H, Kamato D, Zheng X, Luo S, Li Z, Liu P, Han J et al (2021) Endothelial dysfunction in atherosclerotic cardiovascular diseases and beyond: from mechanism to pharmacotherapies. Pharmacol Rev 73(3):924&#x2013;967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34088867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/pharmrev.120.000096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu HB, Ye Y, Xue F, Wu J, Suo Z, Zhang H (2023) Association between endothelial activation and stress index and 28-day mortality in septic ICU patients: a retrospective cohort study. Int J Med Sci 20(9):1165&#x2013;1173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37575274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10416722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.85870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamagata K (2019) Soy isoflavones inhibit endothelial cell dysfunction and prevent cardiovascular disease. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol 74(3):201&#x2013;209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31356541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/FJC.0000000000000708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamazaki Y, Imura A, Urakawa I, Shimada T, Murakami J, Aono Y, Hasegawa H, Yamashita T, Nakatani K, Saito Y et al (2010) Establishment of sandwich ELISA for soluble alpha-Klotho measurement: age-dependent change of soluble alpha-Klotho levels in healthy subjects. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 398(3):513&#x2013;518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20599764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4130489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2010.06.110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J (2022) Biomarkers of endothelial activation and dysfunction in cardiovascular diseases. Rev Cardiovasc Med 23(2):73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35229564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31083/j.rcm2302073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HP, Zhao JH, Yu HX, Guo DX (2016) Genistein ameliorated endothelial nitric oxidase synthase uncoupling by stimulating sirtuin-1 pathway in ox-LDL-injured HUVECs. Environ Toxicol Pharmacol 42:118&#x2013;124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26829290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.etap.2016.01.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>