<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41602358</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-6302</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>20</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental health insights</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Health Insights</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the Association Between Household Toilet Facility Type and Chronic Malnutrition in Children Under 5 years in Ghana's Northern Zone.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11786302251414761</StartPage><MedlinePgn>11786302251414761</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">11786302251414761</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/11786302251414761</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Childhood stunting is a global public health concern that affects millions of children worldwide. This study assessed the association between household latrine access type and childhood stunting in the Bolgatanga Municipality of Northern Ghana. A cross-sectional study was carried out in health facilities in the study area. Data collection consisted of mother-child pairs with children aged 0 to 59&#x2009;months. The outcome variable was stunting, while the main exposure variable was household sanitation facility type and other covariates. Bivariable and Multivariable analyses were used to determine factors associated with stunting. Key findings of the study included, 40.5% having access to improved toilet facilities, 16.4% using unimproved facilities, and 43.1% practicing open defecation. Prevalence of stunting was 28.5% (95% CI: 23.9-33.1). Children from households practicing open defecation had more than twice the odds of being stunted compared to those with access to improved sanitation (adjusted odds ratio [AOR]&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.26; 95% CI: 1.21-4.02). Male sex, low birth weight, and lower maternal education also emerged as significant risk factors. Our findings highlight the need for integrated public health strategies that address poor sanitation, promote maternal education, and support the nutritional needs of vulnerable children to reduce stunting in similar settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorzie</LastName><ForeName>John Baptist K</ForeName><Initials>JBK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5503-7896</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental and Occupational Health, School of Public Health, University for Development Studies, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chirawurah</LastName><ForeName>Dennis</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental and Occupational Health, School of Public Health, University for Development Studies, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boah</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology, Biostatistics, and Disease Control, School of Public Health, University for Development Studies, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Population Health, University of Global Health Equity, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apanga</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7108-3454</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental and Occupational Health, School of Public Health, University for Development Studies, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health and Preventive Medicine, School of Medicine, University for Development Studies, Tamale, Ghana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Health Insights</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101488505</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-6302</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic malnutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">northern Ghana</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stunting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upper east region</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41602358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12833180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11786302251414761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_11786302251414761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. Malnutrition. 2024. Accessed February 20, 2025. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/malnutrition</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. Child growth standards. 2009. Accessed February 20, 2025. https://www.who.int/tools/child-growth-standards/standards</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization. Levels and trends in child malnutrition: UNICEF/WHO/The World Bank Group joint child malnutrition estimates: key findings of the 2021 edition. 2021. Accessed March 2, 2025. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240025257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO, AUC, ECA and WFP. Africa &#x2013; Regional Overview of Food Security and Nutrition 2023: Statistics and trends. FAO. 2023. Accessed January 25, 2025. 10.4060/cc8743en</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4060/cc8743en</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baguune B, Aminu DM, Bekyieriya E, Adokiya MN. Utilization of growth monitoring and promotion services and undernutrition of children less than two years of age in Northern Ghana. BMC Nutr. 2023;9(1):70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10286350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37349769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coomson JB, Aryeetey R. Scoping review of diet-related health outcomes and associated risk factors in Ghana. Afr J Food Agric Nutr Dev. 2022;22(2):19496-19524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boah M, Azupogo F, Amporfro DA, Abada LA. The epidemiology of undernutrition and its determinants in children under five years in Ghana. PLoS One. 2019;14(7):e0219665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6668784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31365528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghana Statistical Service (GSS) and ICF. 2024. Ghana Demographic and Health Survey 2022. GSS and ICF.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ersado TL. Causes of malnutrition. In combating malnutrition through sustainable approaches. IntechOpen Journals. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patl&#xe1;n-Hern&#xe1;ndez AR, Stobaugh HC, Cumming O, et al. Water, sanitation and hygiene interventions and the prevention and treatment of childhood acute malnutrition: a systematic review. Matern Child Nutr. 2021;18(1):e13257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8710129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34612592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndagijimana S, Kabano I, Ntaganda JM. Analysis of risk factors that influence stunting among Rwandan children under the age of five. Afr J Food Agric Nutr Dev. 2022;22(5):20480-20497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niragire F, Ahishakiye J, Ngaruye I, et al. Spatio-temporal variation of child stunting and associated risk factors in Rwanda. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):1195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11954212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40158157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, United Nations Children's Fund. Progress on Household Drinking Water, Sanitation and Hygiene 2000-2020: Five Years Into the SDGs. World Health Organization; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppong FB, Boateng D, Senkyire EK, Logo DD. Demographic disparities in unimproved drinking water and sanitation in Ghana: a nationally representative cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2022;12(7):e060595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9310154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35863842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>

<i>Municipal Health Administration of the Ghana Health Services, Bolgatanga</i>
. Upper East Region of Ghana;
2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaivada T, Akseer N, Akseer S, Somaskandan A, Stefopulos M, Bhutta ZA. Stunting in childhood: an overview of global burden, trends, determinants, and drivers of decline. Am J Clin Nutr. 2020;112:777S-791S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7487433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addae HY, Sulemana M, Yakubu T, Atosona A, Tahiru R, Azupogo F. Low birth weight, household socio-economic status, water and sanitation are associated with stunting and wasting among children aged 6-23 months: results from a national survey in Ghana. PLoS One. 2024;19(3):e0297698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10977686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38547113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engidaye G, Aynalem M, Adane T, Gelaw Y, Yalew A, Enawgaw B. Undernutrition and its associated factors among children aged 6 to 59 months in Menz Gera Midir district, Northeast Ethiopia: a community-based cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2022;17(12):e0278756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9725165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36473009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mshida HA, Kassim N, Mpolya E, Kimanya M. Water, sanitation, and hygiene practices associated with nutritional status of under-five children in semi-pastoral communities Tanzania. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2018;98(5):1242-1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5953357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victora CG, Adair L, Fall C, et al. Maternal and child undernutrition: consequences for adult health and human capital. Lancet. 2008;371(9609):340-357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18206223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Onis M, Branca F. Childhood stunting: a global perspective. Matern Child Nutr. 2016;12 Suppl 1(1):12-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5084763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Sanctis V, Soliman A, Alaaraj N, Ahmed S, Alyafei F, Hamed N. Early and long-term consequences of nutritional stunting: from childhood to adulthood. Acta Biomed. 2021;92(1):e2021168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33682846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaffan N, Kpozehouen A, Degbey C, Ahanhanzo YG, Para&#xef;so MN. Effects of the level of household access to water, sanitation and hygiene on the nutritional status of children under five, Benin. BMC Nutr. 2023;9(1):95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10391820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37528455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahiledengle B, Petrucka P, Kumie A, et al. Association between water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH) and child undernutrition in Ethiopia: a hierarchical approach. BMC Public Health. 2022;22(1):1943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9583486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36261797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekele T, Rahman B, Rawstorne P. The effect of access to water, sanitation and handwashing facilities on child growth indicators: evidence from the Ethiopia Demographic and Health Survey 2016. PLoS One. 2020;15(9):e0239313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32960921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torlesse H, Cronin AA, Sebayang SK, Nandy R. Determinants of stunting in Indonesian children: evidence from a cross-sectional survey indicate a prominent role for the water, sanitation and hygiene sector in stunting reduction. BMC Public Health. 2016;16:669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4966764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27472935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aboagye RG, Ahinkorah BO, Seidu AA, et al. Birth weight and nutritional status of children under five in sub-Saharan Africa. PLoS One. 2022;17(6):e0269279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9182265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35679306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akombi BJ, Agho KE, Hall JJ, Merom D, Astell-Burt T, Renzaho AM. Stunting and severe stunting among children under-5 years in Nigeria: a multilevel analysis. BMC Pediatr. 2017;17(1):15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5237247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28086835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryastami NK, Shankar A, Kusumawardani N, Besral B, Jahari AB, Achadi E. Low birth weight was the most dominant predictor associated with stunting among children aged 12&#x2013;23 months in Indonesia. BMC Nutr. 2017;3(1):16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AL. Greater male vulnerability to stunting? Evaluating sex differences in growth, pathways and biocultural mechanisms. Ann Hum Biol. 2021;48(6):466-473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9205267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrato CA, Gomes MB. Low birth weight: causes and consequences. Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2013;5(1):49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3765917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24128325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okedo-Alex IN, Akamike IC, Ezeanosike OB, Uneke CJ. Determinants of antenatal care utilisation in sub-Saharan Africa: a systematic review. BMJ Open. 2019;9(10):e031890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6797296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31594900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle IM, Borrmann B, Grosser A, Razum O, Spallek J. Determinants of dietary patterns and diet quality during pregnancy: a systematic review with narrative synthesis. Public Health Nutr. 2017;20(6):1009-1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10261556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27852338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astatkie A. Dynamics of stunting from childhood to youthhood in Ethiopia: Evidence from the Young Lives panel data. PLoS One. 2020;15(2):e0229011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7006942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32032372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>