<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41793544</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1750-0680</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Carbon balance and management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Carbon Balance Manag</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spatiotemporal patterns and driving mechanisms of terrestrial carbon sinks in Jiangxi Province, subtropical China.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">60</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13021-026-00421-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Understanding the spatiotemporal dynamics of terrestrial ecosystem carbon sinks, as well as the underlying driving mechanisms, is crucial for guiding regional carbon neutrality policies. Using Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MODIS) remote sensing data, field measurements data, and multi-source environmental data, we estimated net primary productivity in subtropical zone from 2000 to 2020 with the Carnegie-Ames-Stanford approach (CASA) model, and assessed net ecosystem production (NEP) by subtracting heterotrophic respiration. Regression analysis, coefficient of variation, Hurst exponent, and geodetector were applied to examine the spatiotemporal patterns and driving forces of NEP.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results identified distinct spatial heterogeneity in NEP across the study area, characterized by a west-south high and east-low gradient, with moderate levels in the north. The NEP exhibited positive persistence (H&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.5) in 73.2% of the study area. Notably, natural forest areas showed strong persistent improvement (H&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.65), whereas the Chang-Jiu urban agglomeration was characterized by strong persistent degradation (H&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.35). The elevation range of 550-750&#xa0;m exhibited the peak carbon sink capacity (345.6&#xa0;g C m&#x207b;&#xb2; year&#x207b;&#xb9;); Normalized difference vegetation index and elevation, with the q value of 0.37 and 0.34 respectively, were identified as the key individual factors influencing NEP variation. The strongest interactive effect on NEP variation was detected between soil type and land use type (q&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.586). This evidence, combined with the impact of the climate-land use interaction on NEP, implies that synergistic management of these factors could enhance carbon sink potential.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our research reveals that the carbon sink dynamics in subtropical zone are governed by the interaction of topographic, climate, and human activity. Future efforts must implement zonal management strategies (e.g., conserving mountainous areas and promoting forest-grain intercropping on plains) to bolster forest carbon sinks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Jiangxi Science and Technology Normal University, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Environmental, Nanchang University, No. 999 Xuefu Avenue, Honggutan District, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Environmental, Nanchang University, No. 999 Xuefu Avenue, Honggutan District, Nanchang, 330031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Bofu</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Watershed Carbon Neutralization, Key Laboratory of Poyang Lake Environment and Resources Utilization, Jiangxi Institute of Ecological Civilization, Ministry of Education, Nanchang University, No. 999 Xuefu Avenue, Honggutan District, Nanchang, 330031, Jiangxi Province, China. bfzhen@ncu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wan</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Environmental, Nanchang University, No. 999 Xuefu Avenue, Honggutan District, Nanchang, 330031, China. wanwei@ncu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Land Science and Technology, China Agricultural University, Beijing, 100193, China. wanwei@ncu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024BSQD99</GrantID><Agency>Doctoral Start-up Foundation of Jiangxi Science &amp; Technology Normal University, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>0204072501</GrantID><Agency>Think Tank Project of Jiangxi Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>20252BAC200623</GrantID><Agency>Jiangxi Provincial Natural Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>42301091</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PYH20250011</GrantID><Agency>Open Project of Key Laboratory of Poyang Lake Environment and Resource Utilization, Ministry of Education, Nanchang University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Carbon Balance Manag</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271519</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1750-0680</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CASA model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Driving mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Jiangxi Province</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NEP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatiotemporal dynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Terrestrial ecosystem</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41793544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13001212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-026-00421-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13021-026-00421-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ma Z, Wu J, Yang H, Hong Z, Yang J, Gao L. Assessment of vegetation net primary productivity variation and influencing factors in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. J Environ Manage. 2024;365:121490. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38917537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Liu JG, Klaar M, Chen AF, Gudmundsson L, Holden J. Anthropogenic climate change has influenced global river flow seasonality. Science. 2024;383:1009&#x2013;14. 10.1126/science.adi9501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.adi9501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38422144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Zhang SQ. Assessing and explaining rising global carbon sink capacity in karst ecosystems. J Clean Prod. 2024;477:143862. 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.143862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Liu J, Liu X, Wang T. Multi-scenario simulation and prediction of carbon surplus and deficit under the background of carbon neutrality: a case study of Chang-Zhu-Tan metropolitan area in China. Carb Balance Manag. 2025;20:23. 10.1186/s13021-025-00314-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-025-00314-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12275343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40681806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Z, Sha Z. Modeling the impact of urbanization and climate changes on terrestrial vegetation productivity in China by a neighborhood substitution analysis. Ecol Model. 2023;482:110405. 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2023.110405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2023.110405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao F, Du H, Zhou G, Zheng J, Li X, Xu Y, Huang Z, Yin S. Simulated net ecosystem productivity of subtropical forests and its response to climate change in Zhejiang Province China. Sci Total Environ. 2022;838:155993. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.155993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.155993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Wei YZ, Huang JJ. Urbanization diminishes net ecosystem productivity by changing the landscape pattern. Agric For Meteorol. 2025;362:110369. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2024.110369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2024.110369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y, Huang Y, Zhuang Q, Sun W, Chen S, Lu J. China&#x2019;s terrestrial ecosystem carbon balance during the 20th century: an analysis with a process-based biogeochemistry model. Carb Balance Manag. 2022;17:16. 10.1186/s13021-022-00215-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-022-00215-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9548143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36209183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou Q, Yang H, Wu J, Yu X. Carbon budget response to climate change varies with grassland type in Qilian Mountains China. Glob Ecol Conserv. 2023;47:e02670. 10.1016/j.gecco.2023.e02670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gecco.2023.e02670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Ren X, Wang J, He H, Wang S, Wang M, et al. Interannual variability of terrestrial net ecosystem productivity over China: regional contributions and climate attribution. Environ Res Lett. 2019;14:014003. 10.1088/1748-9326/aaec95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/aaec95</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Fan J, Gu B, Chen Y. Carbon sink response of terrestrial vegetation ecosystems in the Yangtze River Delta and its driving mechanism. J Geogr Sci. 2024;34:112&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11442-024-2197-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Zhao W, Zhang Y. The change in net ecosystem productivity and its driving mechanism in a mountain ecosystem of arid regions Northwest China. Remote Sens. 2022;14:4046. 10.3390/rs14164046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14164046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin J, Xiang W, Zeng Y, Ouyang S, Zhou X, Hu Y, et al. Stand carbon storage and net primary production in China&#x2019;s subtropical secondary forests are predicted to increase by 2060. Carbon Balance Manag. 2022;17:6. 10.1186/s13021-022-00204-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13021-022-00204-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9134694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35616781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JG, Lai DYF. Subtropical mangrove wetland is a stronger carbon dioxide sink in the dry than wet seasons. Agric For Meteorol. 2019;278:107644. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2019.107644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2019.107644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao XL, Yang XY, He QL, Yao YX, Xiao JL, Shi WY. Afforestation resists the drought disturbance on soil carbon sink in subtropical agricultural ecosystems. Agric Ecosyst Environ. 2023;357:108670. 10.1016/j.agee.2023.108670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agee.2023.108670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Shi Y, Fang H, Zhou G, Xu X, Zhou Y, et al. Vegetation carbon stocks driven by canopy density and forest age in subtropical forest ecosystems. Sci Total Environ. 2018;631:619&#x2013;26. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.03.080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.03.080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29533798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y, Shao Z, Dang C, Huang X, Zhuang Q. The impact of policies on land cover and ecosystem services dynamics in the Poyang Lake Ecological Economic Zone China. Ecol Indic. 2023;156:111169. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.111169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.111169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng JY, Li S, Huang C, Tang FR, Li Y, He GW, Zhang XL, Chen FS. Effects of climate change, land use/cover change, and interactions on ecosystem services in Jiulianshan National Nature Reserve of Jiangxi Province, China. J Forestry Res. 2025;36:66. 10.1007/s11676-025-01860-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11676-025-01860-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang QG, Ye H, Ding Y, Cao Q, Zhang YJ, Huang K. Carbon storage dynamics of subtropical forests estimated with multi-period forest inventories at a regional scale: the case of Jiangxi forests. J Forestry Res. 2020;31:1247&#x2013;54. 10.1007/s11676-019-00891-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11676-019-00891-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Jia J, Chen D, Liu S. Evolution of spatial network structure for land-use carbon emissions and carbon balance zoning in Jiangxi Province: a social network analysis perspective. Ecol Indic. 2024;158:111508. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.111508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.111508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X, Zhou Z, Shen R, Xu L, Hu F, Xie Z, et al. Evaluating the suitability of NPP simulation for subtropical forest ecosystems by calibrating the Biome-BGC model: an empirical study at interannual and inter-monthly scales. Ecol Model. 2025;509:111275. 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2025.111275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2025.111275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X, Zheng B, Hu F, Xu L, Wu H, Liu Z, et al. Divergent responses of NPP to climate factors among forest types at interannual and inter-monthly scales: an empirical study on four typical forest types in subtropical China. Forests. 2023;14(7):1474. 10.3390/f14071474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14071474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Z, Zhou Z, Wei X, Xiao D, Xu L, Wan W. Spatio-temporal simulation of the productivity of four typical subtropical forests: a case study of the Ganjiang River Basin in China. Forests. 2025;16(4):603. 10.3390/f16040603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f16040603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piao SL, He Y, Wang XH, Chen FH. Estimation of China&#x2019;s terrestrial ecosystem carbon sink: methods progress and prospects. Sci China Earth Sci. 2022;65:641&#x2013;51. 10.1007/s11430-021-9892-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11430-021-9892-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Li X, Mao F, Huang L, Zhao Y, Song M, et al. Integrating LUCC and forest aging to project and attribute subtropical forest NEP in Zhejiang Province under four SSP-RCP scenarios. Agric For Meteorol. 2025;365:110462. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2025.110462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2025.110462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Th&#x1ecb; H&#x1eb1;ng N, Ran M, Kong J. Spatiotemporal dynamics and drivers of vegetation carbon sinks in Zhejiang Province: a case study in rapidly urbanizing subtropical ecosystems. Plants. 2025;14(7):1151. 10.3390/plants14071151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants14071151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11991596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40219218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Feng H, Zou B, Yang Z, Wang S. Vegetation greening enhanced the regional terrestrial carbon uptake in the Dongting Lake Basin of China. Forests. 2023;14(4):768. 10.3390/f14040768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14040768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen XF, Wang HM, Wang JL, Yu GR, Sun XM. Ecosystem carbon exchanges of a subtropical evergreen coniferous plantation subjected to seasonal drought, 2003&#x2013;2007. Biogeosciences. 2010;7:357&#x2013;69. 10.5194/bg-7-357-2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-7-357-2010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou R, Buchmann N, Chi J, Luo Y, Mo L, Shekhar A, et al. Temporal variations of carbon and water fluxes in a subtropical mangrove forest: insights from a decade-long eddy covariance measurement. Agric For Meteorol. 2023;343:109764. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2023.109764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2023.109764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J, Mao F, Du H, Li X, Zhou G, Dong L, et al. Spatiotemporal simulation of net ecosystem productivity and its response to climate change in subtropical forests. Forests. 2019;10(8):708. 10.3390/f10080708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f10080708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawirdin S, Tian A, Shi L, Fu W, Cheng S, Halik &#xdc;, Liang J. A bibliometric analysis of the research progress and trends during 2002&#x2013;2022 on the carbon stocks in terrestrial ecosystems. Forests. 2023;14(10):2051. 10.3390/f14102051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14102051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Gao W, Liu T, Dai L, Wu L, Miao H, et al. A bibliometric analysis of the impact of ecological restoration on carbon sequestration in ecosystems. Forests. 2023;14(7):1442. 10.3390/f14071442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f14071442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Peng J, Lu Z, Zhu P. Research progress on carbon sources and sinks of farmland ecosystems. Resour Environ Sustain. 2023;11:100099. 10.1016/j.resenv.2022.100099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resenv.2022.100099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu F, Hu H, Sun W, Zhu J, Liu G, Zhou W, et al. Effects of national ecological restoration projects on carbon sequestration in China from 2001 to 2010. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2018;115:4039&#x2013;44. 10.1073/pnas.1700294115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1700294115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5910802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29666317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Meng W, Yun H, Xu W, Hu B, He M, et al. Is urban green space a carbon sink or source? - A case study of China based on LCA method. Environ Impact Assess Rev. 2022;94:106766. 10.1016/j.eiar.2022.106766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eiar.2022.106766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan W, Liu Z, Li J, Xu J, Wu H, Xu Z. Spatiotemporal patterns of maize drought stress and their effects on biomass in the Northeast and North China Plain from 2000 to 2019. Agric For Meteorol. 2022;315:108821. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2022.108821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2022.108821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu WQ, Pan YZ, Zhang JS. Simulation of the maximum light utilization rate of typical vegetation in China. Chin J Plant Ecol. 2007;31(3):413&#x2013;24. 10.17521/cjpe.2007.0050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17521/cjpe.2007.0050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter CS, Randerson JT, Field CB, Matson PA, Klooster SA. Terrestrial ecosystem production: a process model based on global satellite and surface data. Glob Biogeochem Cycles. 1993;7(4):811&#x2013;41. 10.1007/s11676-025-01860-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11676-025-01860-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu WQ, Pan YZ, He H, Yu YD, Hu HD. Simulation of the maximum light utilization rate of typical vegetation in China. Chin Sci Bull. 2006;51:700&#x2013;6. 10.1360/972005-555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1360/972005-555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin L, Dai EF, Zheng D, Wang YH, Ma L, Tong M. What drives the vegetation dynamics in the Hengduan Mountain region, southwest China: climate change or human activity? Ecol Indic. 2020;112:106013. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2019.106013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2019.106013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Dong QL, Pan YJ, Yang F, He ML, Huang X, et al. Spatiotemporal variations and driving forces of regional-scale NPP based on a multi-method integration: a case study in the Beibu Gulf Economic Zone. Ecol Indic. 2025;174:113453. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2025.113453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2025.113453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He YL, Lin C, Wu CY, Pu N, Zhang XH. The urban hierarchy and agglomeration effects influence the response of NPP to climate change and human activities. Glob Ecol Conserv. 2024;51:e02904. 10.1016/j.gecco.2024.e02904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gecco.2024.e02904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang HF, Zhong XN, Deng SQ, Xu H. Assessment of the impact of LUCC on NPP and its influencing factors in the Yangtze River basin, China. Catena. 2021;206:105542. 10.1016/j.catena.2021.105542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2021.105542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Xu L, Zheng B, Song X, Hu F, Zhu J, et al. Responses of productivity and carbon use efficiency of typical subtropical forests to climate change. Sci Silvae Sin. 2025;61:121&#x2013;34. 10.11707/j.1001-7488.LYKX20230622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11707/j.1001-7488.LYKX20230622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DM, Zhang CL, Wu JP, Zhou LX, Lin YB, Fu SL. Subtropical plantations are large carbon sinks: evidence from two monoculture plantations in South China. Agr For Meteorol. 2011;151:1214&#x2013;25. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2011.04.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2011.04.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XJ, Du HQ, Mao FJ, Zhou GM, Xing LQ, Liu TY, Han N, Liu EB, Ge HL, Liu YL, Li YG, Zhu DE, Zheng JL, Dong LF, Zhang M. Mapping spatiotemporal decisions for sustainable productivity of bamboo forest land. Land Degrad Dev. 2020;31:939&#x2013;58. 10.1002/ldr.3509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.3509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng B, Wu S, Liu Z, Wu H, Li Z, Ye R, et al. Downscaling estimation of NEP in the ecologically-oriented county based on multi-source remote sensing data. Ecol Indic. 2024;160:111818. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2024.111818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2024.111818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardle DA, Jonsson M, Kalela-Brundin M, Lagerstr&#xf6;m A, Bardgett RD, Yeates GW, Nilsson MC. Drivers of inter-year variability of plant production and decomposers across contrasting island ecosystems. Ecology. 2012;93:521&#x2013;31. 10.1890/11-0930.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/11-0930.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22624207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markonis Y, Koutsoyiannis D. Scale-dependence of persistence in precipitation records. Nat Clim Change. 2016;6:399&#x2013;401. 10.1038/nclimate2894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nclimate2894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Shao Z, Huang X, Zhuang Q, Dang C, Cai B, et al. Assessing the impact of drought-land cover change on global vegetation greenness and productivity. Sci Total Environ. 2022;852:158499. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.158499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.158499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36058327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin X, Wu Y, Zhao W, Liu S, Zhao F, Chen J, et al. Spatiotemporal responses of net primary productivity of alpine ecosystems to flash drought: the Qilian Mountains. J Hydrol. 2023;624:129865. 10.1016/j.jhydrol.2023.129865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhydrol.2023.129865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Xu C. Geodetector: principle and prospective. Acta Geogr Sin. 2017;72:116&#x2013;34. 10.11821/dlxb201701010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11821/dlxb201701010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Yan W, Cai Y, Deng F, Qu X, Cui X. How does the net primary productivity respond to the extreme climate under elevation constraints in mountainous areas of Yunnan China? Ecol Indic. 2022;138:108817. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2022.108817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2022.108817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HS, Lv XZ, Ni YX, Zhang QF, Wang JW, Ma L. Time-lag effects of NEP and NPP to meteorological factors in the source regions of the Yangtze and Yellow Rivers. Front Plant Sci. 2025a;15:02384. 10.3389/fpls.2024.1502384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2024.1502384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11757257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39866316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Hu BQ, Tang JL, Wang Y. Comprehensive consolidation and ecological restoration projects drive the variation of ecosystem services and their terrain gradient effect in Jiangxi Province, China. Ecol Eng. 2025;220:107728. 10.1016/j.ecoleng.2025.107728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoleng.2025.107728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L, Shao Q, Liu J. Forest restoration to achieve both ecological and economic progress, Poyang Lake basin, China. Ecol Eng. 2012;44:53&#x2013;60. 10.1016/j.ecoleng.2012.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoleng.2012.03.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Yan Q, Zhang M. Ecosystem carbon storage considering combined environmental and land-use changes in the future and pathways to carbon neutrality in developed regions. Sci Total Environ. 2023;903:166204. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.166204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.166204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37567287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enescu R, Dinc&#x103; L, Vasile D, Vlad R. Does the slope aspect influence the soil organic matter concentration in forest soils? Forests. 2022;13(9):1472. 10.3390/f13091472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/f13091472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunn M, Kr&#xfc;ger J, Lang F. Experimental drought increased the belowground sink strength towards higher topsoil organic carbon stocks in a temperate mature forest. Geoderma. 2023;431:116356. 10.1016/j.geoderma.2023.116356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoderma.2023.116356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma S, Wang LJ, Zhao YG, Jiang J. Coupling effects of soil and vegetation from an ecosystem service perspective. Catena. 2023;231:107354. 10.1016/j.catena.2023.107354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2023.107354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma D, Sun Y, Liu M, Fang HJ, Xu XL. Higher endogenous labile organic carbon decreases the temperature sensitivity of soil organic matter decomposition in two subtropical forests. Appl Soil Ecol. 2025;206:105816. 10.1016/j.apsoil.2024.105816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsoil.2024.105816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi H, Binford M, Kleindl W, Starr G, Murphy BA, Desai AR, et al. Drivers of forest productivity in two regions of the United States: relative impacts of management and environmental variables. J Environ Manage. 2025;374:124040. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39793498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Jia C, Wang L, Wen X, Wang H. Solar energy dominates and soil water modulates net ecosystem productivity and evapotranspiration across multiple timescales in a subtropical coniferous plantation. Agric For Meteorol. 2021;300:108310. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2020.108310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2020.108310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu XY, Xu H, Pang JZ, Zhang ZQ. Declining resilience of forest carbon sinks linked to increased atmospheric water deficit during droughts in the Northern Hemisphere. Environ Res Lett. 2025;20:014055. 10.1088/1748-9326/ada170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-9326/ada170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Xing L, Pan J, Jiang L, Yu H. Study of high temperature targets identification and temperature retrieval experimental model in SWIR remote sensing based Landsat8. Int J Appl Earth Obs. 2016;46:56&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.jag.2015.11.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jag.2015.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moinet GYK, Mor&#xe1;n-Rivera K, Moinet A, Wadoux AMJC. Large underestimations of warming-induced soil carbon emissions from oversimplistic Q10 indicator. Soil Biol Biochem. 2025;207:109839. 10.1016/j.soilbio.2025.109839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soilbio.2025.109839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Cui J, Wu N, Zhang Y, Wang J, Xiang H, et al. Ice storm damage to oak forests in subtropical China. Forest Ecosystems. 2023;10:100119. 10.1016/j.fecs.2023.100119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fecs.2023.100119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang MY, Chen Y, Liu HY, Xue P, Liang CZ, Wang X, et al. Effect of Rocky Desertification Control on the nonlinear trends of Gross Primary Productivity in Southwest Karst Areas China. Land Degrad Dev. 2025b;36:872&#x2013;84. 10.1002/ldr.5399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ldr.5399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Dai L, Chen Q, Guo X. Nitrogen addition favors terrestrial ecosystem carbon sink: a global meta-analysis. Sci Total Environ. 2024;948:174826. 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.174826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.174826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39025151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y, Sarkar A, Yu C, Lu Q, Zhao MJ, Das JC. Ecological compensation of grain trade within urban rural areas and provinces in China: a prospect of a carbon transfer mechanism. Environ Dev Sustain. 2021;23:16688&#x2013;712. 10.1007/s10668-021-01376-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10668-021-01376-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>