<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41057888</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-6511</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC pharmacology &amp; toxicology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Pharmacol Toxicol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fenofibrate alleviates sepsis-associated acute kidney injury by enhancing renal fatty acid oxidation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>160</StartPage><MedlinePgn>160</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">160</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40360-025-00997-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Sepsis-associated acute kidney injury (SA-AKI) is a common and severe complication in patients with severe health conditions, yet effective targeted therapies are still not available. Recent studies implicate impaired fatty acid oxidation (FAO) and metabolic dysregulation in its pathogenesis. A clinically approved peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-alpha (PPAR&#x3b1;) agonist, fenofibrate, may improve energy metabolism and enhance renal FAO. This study investigated whether fenofibrate mitigates SA-AKI by restoring renal FAO and mitochondrial function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The three groups (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;6 per group) were as follows: control, lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced SA-AKI, and LPS with fenofibrate pretreatment (0.2% dietary supplementation for 7&#x2009;days), with male C57BL/6 mice used for the study. Kidney injury was induced by intraperitoneal LPS injection (10&#x2009;mg/kg). After 24&#x2009;hours, renal function (serum creatinine [Scr] and blood urea nitrogen [BUN]), inflammation (interleukin-1 beta [IL-1&#x3b2;], interleukin-6 [IL-6], tumor necrosis factor-alpha [TNF-&#x3b1;]), and histopathology were evaluated. Biomarkers of kidney injury, including kidney injury molecule-1 (KIM-1) and neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin (NGAL), as well as indicators of energy metabolism (adenosine triphosphate [ATP]) and lipid accumulation (triglycerides, glycerol, non-esterified fatty acids [NEFA]), were assessed. Mitochondrial function (citrate synthase), FAO capacity, and expression of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK), peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma coactivator 1-alpha (PGC1&#x3b1;), PPAR&#x3b1;, carnitine palmitoyltransferase 1A (CPT1A), CPT2, and acyl-CoA oxidase 1 (ACOX1) were assessed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Fenofibrate markedly enhanced renal function, lowered levels of Scr and BUN, decreased proinflammatory cytokines, and inhibited the expression of KIM-1 and NGAL. Histological damage was alleviated, and Oil Red O staining revealed reduced lipid accumulation. ATP levels and citrate synthase activity were restored, while renal levels of triglycerides, glycerol, and NEFA were decreased. Fenofibrate increased the expression of genes and proteins associated with FAO and restored the AMPK&#x2013;PGC1&#x3b1;&#x2013;PPAR&#x3b1; signaling pathway.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Fenofibrate attenuates SA-AKI by enhancing renal FAO and mitochondrial energy metabolism via the AMPK&#x2013;PGC1&#x3b1;&#x2013;PPAR&#x3b1; pathway, supporting its potential as a metabolic therapy for SA-AKI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s40360-025-00997-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Siyao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harbin Medical University Graduate School, Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jingkai</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harbin Medical University Graduate School, Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Guan</LastName><ForeName>Chumming</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Zhipeng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Frigid Zone Cardiovascular Diseases, Department of Pharmacology, College of Pharmacy, Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China. liyuevickey@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Junbo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China. icuzhengjunbo@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hongliang</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Second Affiliated Hospital of Harbin Medical University, Harbin, China. icuwanghongliang@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Pharmacol Toxicol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590449</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-6511</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FAO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fatty acid oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fenofibrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PPAR&#x3b1;</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-alpha</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SA-AKI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sepsis-associated acute kidney injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: This study involves animal models, all animal experimental protocols were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of Harbin Medical University (SYDW2025&#x2013;052). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41057888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12505558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40360-025-00997-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40360-025-00997-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tahir S, Ganie BA, Beigh TY, Hazar AJ, Reshi AR. Clinico-etiological spectrum and outcome in patients with septic acute kidney injury and its comparison with non-septic acute kidney injury: a hospital-based prospective study conducted in a tertiary care hospital in North India. Cureus. 2023;15(4):e37857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10202667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37223179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeuchi T, Flannery AH, Liu LJ, Ghazi L, Cama-Olivares A, Fushimi K, et al. Epidemiology of sepsis-associated acute kidney injury in the ICU with contemporary consensus definitions. Crit Care. 2025;29(1):128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13054-025-05351-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11924826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40114218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhel F, Peters-Sengers H, Falahi F, Scicluna BP, van Vught LA, Bonten MJ, et al. Mortality and host response aberrations associated with transient and persistent acute kidney injury in critically ill patients with sepsis: a prospective cohort study. Intensive Care Med. 2020;46(8):1576&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-020-06119-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32514599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbock A, Koyner JL, Gomez H, Pickkers P, Forni L, Nadim MK, et al. Sepsis-associated acute kidney injury-treatment standard. Nephrol Dialysis transplant. 2024;39(1):26&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndt/gfad142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37401137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbock A, Nadim MK, Pickkers P, Gomez H, Bell S, Joannidis M, et al. Sepsis-associated acute kidney injury: consensus report of the 28th acute disease quality initiative workgroup. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2023;19(6):401&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41581-023-00683-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36823168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pais T, Jorge S, Lopes JA. Acute kidney injury in sepsis. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11172431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38892111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z, Chen X. Fatty acid beta-oxidation in kidney diseases: perspectives on pathophysiological mechanisms and therapeutic opportunities. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:805281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.805281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9065343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35517820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gewin LS. Sugar or fat? Renal tubular metabolism reviewed in health and disease. Nutrients. 2021;13(5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8151053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34065078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwaki T, Bennion BG, Stenson EK, Lynn JC, Otinga C, Djukovic D, et al. Pparalpha contributes to protection against metabolic and inflammatory derangements associated with acute kidney injury in experimental sepsis. Physiol Rep. 2019;7(10):e14078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.14078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6525329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31102342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Huang Y, Zhang X, Zhang Y, Zhang X. Advances in metabolic reprogramming of renal tubular epithelial cells in sepsis-associated acute kidney injury. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1329644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1329644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10834781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38312312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei Z, Deng S, Xie D, Lv M, Guo W, Liu D, et al. Protective role of fenofibrate in sepsis-induced acute kidney injury in BALB/c mice. RSC Adv. 2018;8(50):28510&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C8RA00488A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9083917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35542461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur J, Kaur T, Sharma AK, Kaur J, Yadav HN, Pathak D, et al. Fenofibrate attenuates ischemia reperfusion-induced acute kidney injury and associated liver dysfunction in rats. Drug Dev Res. 2021;82(3):412&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ddr.21764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33226649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer D, Hoff J, Sommerfeld O, Zipprich A, Gassler N, Press AT. The liver in sepsis: molecular mechanism of liver failure and their potential for clinical translation. Mol Med. 2022;28(1):84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10020-022-00510-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9338540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35907792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez H, Kellum JA, Ronco C. Metabolic reprogramming and tolerance during sepsis-induced AKI. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2017;13(3):143&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneph.2016.186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5508527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28090081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira JP, Vasques-Novoa F, Ferrao D, Saraiva F, Falcao-Pires I, Neves JS, et al. Fenofibrate and heart failure outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes: analysis from ACCORD. Diabetes Care. 2022;45(7):1584&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc21-1977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9274224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35320363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin L, Hua H, Ji Y, Jia Z, Peng M, Huang S. Anti-inflammatory role of fenofibrate in treating diseases. Biomol Biomed. 2023;23(3):376&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17305/bb.2022.8534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10171448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36724021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Zhang X, Hou Y, Zhang Y, Chen J, Gao S, et al. SIRT6 activates PPARalpha to improve doxorubicin-induced myocardial cell aging and damage. Chem Biol Interact. 2024;392:110920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbi.2024.110920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei D, Wu S, Liu J, Zhang X, Guan X, Gao L, et al. Theobromine ameliorates nonalcoholic fatty liver disease by regulating hepatic lipid metabolism via mTOR signaling pathway in vivo and in vitro. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2021;99(8):775&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cjpp-2020-0259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33290156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong YA, Lim JH, Kim MY, Kim TW, Kim Y, Yang KS, et al. Fenofibrate improves renal lipotoxicity through activation of AMPK-PGC-1alpha in db/db mice. PLoS One. 2014;9(5):e96147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0096147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4011795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24801481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimzadeh O, Subramanian V, Sievert W, Merl-Pham J, Oleksenko K, Rosemann M, et al. Activation of PPARalpha by fenofibrate attenuates the effect of local heart high dose irradiation on the mouse cardiac proteome. Biomedicines. 2021;9(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8698387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34944662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv M, Xie D, Long X. The effect of fenofibrate, a peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor alpha agonist, on cardiac damage from sepsis in BALB/c mice. Cell Mol Biol (Noisy-le-Grand). 2022;67(6):260&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14715/cmb/2021.67.6.34</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35818188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Wang J, Ying C, Xing Y, Su X, Men K. Fenofibrate alleviates NAFLD by enhancing the PPARalpha/PGC-1alpha signaling pathway coupling mitochondrial function. BMC Pharmacol toxicol. 2024;25(1):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40360-023-00730-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38173037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali AA, Saad EB, El-Rhman RHA, El-Raouf OMA, Gad AM. Impact of peroxisome proliferator activated receptor agonist drugs in a model of nephrotoxicity in rats. J Biochem Mol toxicol. 2023;37(6):e23350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbt.23350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36988379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallucci GM, Alsuwayt B, Auclair AM, Boyer JL, Assis DN, Ghonem NS. Fenofibrate downregulates NF-kappaB signaling to inhibit pro-inflammatory cytokine secretion in human THP-1 Macrophages and during primary biliary cholangitis. Inflammation. 2022;45(6):2570&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10753-022-01713-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10853883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35838934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu Y, Hamada K, Guo T, Hasegawa C, Kuga Y, Takeda K, et al. Role of PPARalpha in inflammatory response of C2C12 myotubes. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2024;694:149413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2023.149413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38141556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masenga SK, Desta S, Hatcher M, Kirabo A, Lee DL. How PPAR-alpha mediated inflammation may affect the pathophysiology of chronic kidney disease. Curr Res Physiol. 2025;8:100133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crphys.2024.100133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11629568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39665027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portilla D, Dai G, Peters JM, Gonzalez FJ, Crew MD, Proia AD. Etomoxir-induced PPARalpha-modulated enzymes protect during acute renal failure. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol. 2000;278(4):F667&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajprenal.2000.278.4.F667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada M, Kamijo Y, Nakajima T, Hashimoto K, Yamada Y, Shimojo H, et al. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor alpha-dependent renoprotection of murine kidney by irbesartan. Clin Sci (lond). 2016;130(21):1969&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/CS20160343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6331013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27496805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Cheng Y, Fan J, Luo R, Xu G, Ge S. Deletion of lymphotoxin-&#x3b2; receptor (LT&#x3b2;R) protects against acute kidney injury by PPAR&#x3b1; pathway. Mol Med. 2024;30(1):254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10020-024-01026-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11661049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39707217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Zhang Q, Luo S, Han Y, Zhao H, Jiang N, et al. DsbA-L alleviates tubular injury in diabetic nephropathy by activating mitophagy through maintenance of MAM integrity. Clin Sci (lond). 2023;137(12):931&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/CS20220787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37226722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M, Qin S, Xiong J, Xin W, Guan X, Gong S, et al. Oroxylin a ameliorates AKI-to-CKD transition through maintaining PPARalpha-BNIP3 signaling-mediated mitochondrial homeostasis. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:935937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.935937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9445212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36081929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>