<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41201575</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2730-9827</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research in health services &amp; regions</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Health Serv Reg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Availability, affordability, and associated factors of essential medicines in primary health care facilities of the wolaita region, southern Ethiopia: implication for access, a cross-sectional study, 2022.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>18</StartPage><MedlinePgn>18</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">18</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s43999-025-00078-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Access to essential medicines is fundamental to achieving universal health coverage. According to WHO, these medicines should be consistently available and affordable. However, in many low- and middle-income countries, health facilities experience frequent stockouts and high prices, limiting access and affordability. Such barriers reduce adherence, increase out-of-pocket spending, and compromise health outcomes. Assessing availability and affordability in primary health care facilities is therefore crucial to inform policy and promote equitable access.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the availability and affordability of essential medicines and associated factors in Wolaita region, Ethiopia, 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A facility-based cross-sectional study was conducted from February 1-30, 2022. Thirty public health facilities were selected, six from each of five districts. Sample size was determined using a single population proportion formula. Data were collected through patient exit interviews, entered into EpiData 3.1, and analyzed in SPSS version 25. Multivariable logistic regression was employed to identify factors associated with affordability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 601 patients, 98% participated. The average availability of 26 selected core essential medicines was 56.53%. Among patients, 58.1% reported prescribed medicines as unaffordable. Factors significantly associated with affordability included level of health facility [AOR (95% CI)&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.450 (2.275-5.231)], health status [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.807 (1.027-3.179)], educational status [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.413 (1.363-8.548)], and place of residence [AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.596 (1.019-2.551)].</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Essential medicine availability was low across facilities. Many patients were unable to obtain prescribed drugs due to unavailability and unaffordability. District and zonal health offices should ensure timely replenishment to strengthen access.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adale</LastName><ForeName>AtsedeTenna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3513-0326</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, Ethiopia. atsedet12@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Res Health Serv Reg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918803680706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2730-9827</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Res Health Serv Reg. 2026 Feb 3;5(1):3. doi: 10.1007/s43999-026-00087-3.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41632407</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Affordability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Availability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Essential medicines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The research was approved by the Research Ethics Committee (REC) of Wolaita Sodo University College of Medicine and Health Sciences School of Public Health (with ID No. CHSM/ERC/10/2022) before data collection. Permission was obtained from the Wolaita Zone Health Department to get access to participants and health institutions. For the exit interview with patients, informed verbal consent was sought from each eligible client at the selected health institutions. Authors reporting experiments on humans and/or the use of human tissue samples/human data must confirm that all experiments were performed in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations of the Declaration of Helsinki. For the current study, informed verbal consent was sought as per the study protocol, which was approved by the Research Ethics Committee (REC) of Wolaita Sodo University College of Medicine and Health Sciences, as it&#x2019;s supposed to be more convenient for less sensitive issues like that of this study. This study did not utilize experiments on humans or use human tissue samples. The objectives of the study and its benefits were explained to the participants in a language they could understand. Study participants were informed that the study would not have any risks. Furthermore, items seeking personal information (like names, phone numbers, and identification numbers) were kept confidential. Consent for Publication: Not applicable. The study does not include any individual person&#x2019;s identifiable data or images. Competing interests: The Author declares that there are No competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41201575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12595146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43999-025-00078-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s43999-025-00078-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sambala EZ, Sapsed S, Mkandawire ML (2010) Role of primary health care in ensuring access to medicines. Croat Med J 51(3):181&#x2013;190</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Council of Churches (2009) Essential medicines in primary health care</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health ms for managing access to medicines and health technologies (2012). Management Science for Health, Arlington, Va</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food M and HA and C authority of E (2014) Natl Essent Med List Fifth Ed Addis</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) (2007) Everybody&#x2019;s business: strengthening health systems to improve health outcomes: WHO&#x2019;s framework for action. [Internet]. 1&#x2013;56 p. Available from: http://www.who.int/healthsystems/strategy/everybodys_business.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron A, Ewen M, Ball D, Laing R (2008) Medicine prices, availability, and affordability in 36 developing and middle-income countries: a secondary analysis 6736(8):1&#x2013;10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiedenmayer K (2004) Access to medicines: lessons learnt in Tanzania and Mozambique. Swiss Trop Inst</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>QuantilesIMS (2016) Ensuring essential medicines satisfy priority healthcare needs of populations: evolution. Curr State, And Future Needs</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2004) Equitable access to essential medicines: a framework for collective action</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedman L (2016) Medicines shortages: global approaches to addressing shortages of essential medicines in health systems. WHO Drug Inf 30(2):180&#x2013;185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E.ogbe@ids.ac.uk ST s. thompson@ids.ac.u. and DEO (2012) Helpdesk report: availability of essential medicines</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pheage T (2018 December) Dying from lack of medicines: encouraging local production, right policies are the way out. U Nations Africa Renew</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia Ministry of Health (2007 September) Drug financing in Ethiopia</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) (2007) Access to affordable essential medicines</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell S, Abdella K (2002) Too poor to be sick coping with the costs of illness in east hararghe Ethiopia</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saksena P, Xu K, Durairaj V (2010) The drivers of catastrophic expenditure: outpatient services, hospitalization, or medicines? World Heal Rep 21:29</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) (2007) Technical cooperation for essential drugs and traditional medicines. who operational package for assessing, monitoring, and evaluating country pharmaceutical situations Guide for coordinators and data collectors</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyassu M, Waju B, Feyera G (2021. 2021) Affordability of essential medicines and associated factors in Public health facilities of Jimma zone, Southwest Ethiopia. Hindawi, Adv Pharmacological And Pharm Sci</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization and Health Action International (2008) Measuring medicine prices, availability, affordability, and price components</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussien M, Tafese F (2015) Access to essential medicines in primary health Care units of South Wollo Zone, Ethiopia. Open Access Maced J Med Sci Libr [Internet]. 2:1&#x2013;10. Available from: 10.4236/oalib.1100983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abiye Z, Tesfaye A, Hawaze S (2013) Barriers to access: availability and affordability of essential drugs in a retail outlet of a public health center in southwestern Ethiopia. J Appl Pharm Sci 3(10):101&#x2013;105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosmer and Lemeshow (2000) Applied logistic regression, 2ndedn</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno O, Nyanchoka OA, Ondieki MN (2015) Availability of essential medicines and supplies during the dual pull-push system of drugs acquisition in Kaliro District, Uganda. J Pharm Care Heal Syst 1&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carasso BS, Lagarde M, Tesfaye A, Palmer N (2009) Availability of essential medicines in Ethiopia: an efficiency-equity trade-off? Trop Med Int Heal 14(11):1394&#x2013;1400. 10.1111/j.1365-3156.2009.02383.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali EE, Fenta T, Gilani AH, Gedif T (2014) Pharmaceutical pricing in Ethiopia. Pharm Pricing 21st Century 28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozawa S, Shankar R, Leopold C, Orubu S (2019) Access to medicines through health systems in low- and middle-income countries. Health Policy (new Y) Plan 34:34&#x2013;36</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>