<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41618203</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-244X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Retinal and choroidal vascular density alterations in patients with schizophrenia: assessment via optical coherence tomography angiography.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">216</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12888-026-07845-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Previous studies have revealed the retinal and choroidal structural impairment in schizophrenia (SCZ). This study aimed to investigate alterations in retinal and choroidal vascular density in patients with SCZ using optical coherence tomography angiography (OCTA).&#x200b;.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 63 SCZ patients (63 eyes) and 61 healthy controls (61 eyes) were enrolled. Psychopathological symptoms in SCZ patients were assessed using the Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale (PANSS). OCTA images were acquired using an Optovue RTVue-XR system with a 3&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;3&#xa0;mm scan size (304&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;304 pixels) to quantify the following parameters: retinal superficial vascular density (SVD), retinal deep vascular density (DVD), foveal avascular zone (FAZ), superficial FAZ (sFAZ), deep FAZ (dFAZ), choroidal vessel volume index (CVI), and choroidal vessel volume (CVV). Comparisons of retinal and choroidal vascular density were performed between the SCZ group and the control group. The diagnostic efficacy of these vascular density parameters in distinguishing SCZ patients from healthy controls was evaluated. Additionally, correlations between PANSS scores and retinal/choroidal vascular density parameters were analyzed in the SCZ group.&#x200b;.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with the control group, the SCZ group exhibited significantly lower DVD (<i>Z</i> = -4.070, <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and CVI (<i>t</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.204, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.029), along with a significantly larger dFAZ (<i>t</i> = -3.953, <i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). After adjusting for age, sex, and body mass index (BMI), DVD remained significantly associated with SCZ (<i>&#x3b2;</i> = -3.050, <i>P</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.011). Furthermore, the exploratory ROC analysis yielded an area under the curve (AUC) of 0.712 for DVD, indicating a modest level of discrimination between groups. Additionally, no significant correlations were observed between PANSS scores with DVD, dFAZ, or CVI in the SCZ group (all <i>P</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">These results suggest that alterations in retinal and choroidal vascular parameters, particularly DVD, may be associated with SCZ and have potential value as a potential exploratory marker for distinguishing SCZ patients from healthy controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, Anhui, 230601, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, The Third People's Hospital of Hefei, The Third Clinical College of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 230041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Guangyuan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Practice, Chaohu Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 238000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 230022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Suqi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Chaohu Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 238000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Chaohu Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 238000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Ruimei</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Chaohu Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 238000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Le</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Second People's Hospital of Hefei, Hefei, 230011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Yayun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Hefei Fourth People's Hospital, Hefei, 230032, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Dachuan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, The Third People's Hospital of Hefei, The Third Clinical College of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 230041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, 230022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Zhengxuan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei, Anhui, 230601, China. jiangzhengxuan@ahmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023zhyx-C96</GrantID><Agency>Research Fund of Anhui Institute of Translational Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Hwk2025jqz007</GrantID><Agency>Hefei Health Science and Technology Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968559</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-244X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Choroidal vascular density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optical coherence tomography angiography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retinal vascular density</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Schizophrenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Chaohu Hospital of Anhui Medical University (registration number: KYXM-202403-001) and conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent was obtained from all participants prior to enrollment. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41618203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12947328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-026-07845-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12888-026-07845-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Marco S, Georgios S, Dimitris M, Christoph UC, Elena D, Synthia G, Lauri T, Aroldo D, Andre FC, Michele F et al. Incidence, prevalence, and global burden of schizophrenia - data, with critical appraisal, from the global burden of disease (GBD) 2019. Mol Psychiatr. 2023; 28(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37500825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yueqin H, Yu W, Hong W, Zhaorui L, Xin Y, Jie Y, Yaqin Y, Changgui K, Xiufeng X, Jin L, et al. Prevalence of mental disorders in china: a cross-sectional epidemiological study. Lancet Psychiatr, 6(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30792114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavel K, Panos R, Mikhail P, Vahram H. Microvascular anomaly conditions in psychiatric disease:schizophrenia - angiogenesis connection. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2017;77(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5497758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28396239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H W M DW. H B: Functional genomics indicate that schizophrenia May be an adult vascular-ischemic disorder. Transl Psychiatr. 2015;5(8).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4564558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26261884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niron S, Priyadharshini S, Udunna A, Lena P. Neurovascular uncoupling in schizophrenia: a bimodal meta-analysis of brain perfusion and glucose metabolism. Front Psychiatr. 2020;11(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mica&#xeb;l C, J&#xe9;r&#xe9;mie G, Jean-Philippe L, Marie-&#xc8;ve T, Mich&#xe8;le D. Structural and functional features of developing brain capillaries, and their alteration in schizophrenia. Front Cell Neurosci. 2021;14(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7843388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33519380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anat L, Inbal B, Michal S. The retina as a window to the brain-from eye research to CNS disorders. Nat Rev Neurol. 2012;9(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23165340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oana MD, Bart MD, Cristina VS, Diana A-D, Cumara BOC, Maria IA, Patrick DL, Gyanendra K. Retinal microvascular abnormalities as surrogate markers of cerebrovascular ischemic disease: a meta-analysis. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2018; 27(7).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29571764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jee-Young L, Antonio M-B, Ane M-G, I&#xf1;igo G, Nicol&#xe1;s C, Paola P, Beomseok J. Multimodal brain and retinal imaging of dopaminergic degeneration in Parkinson disease. Nat Rev Neurol. 2022;18(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35177849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cemal D, Ferdane A, Berna Y, Merve SG, Ezgi C, Muhammed D, Simge Uzman O, Ekin S, Burak B, Berna BA et al. Choroidal structural analysis in ultra-high risk and first-episode psychosis. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2023;70(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36931136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steven MS, Samantha IF, Docia LD. Schizophrenia and the retina: towards a 2020 perspective. Schizophr Res. 2019;219(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31708400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preeti Patil C, Vikas A, Akshay GN, Sailaja B, Jay C. Retinal findings on OCT in systemic conditions. Semin Ophthalmol. 2017;33(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28640657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhilaksh K, Sandeep G, Vishali G, Swapnajeet S, Ritu N. A comparative study of retinal layer changes among patients with schizophrenia and healthy controls. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2022;35(3).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jairo MG-D, Joaquim R, Bernardo S-D, Anna C-C, Diana CZ, Miquel B. Mapping retinal abnormalities in psychosis: meta-analytical evidence for focal peripapillary and macular reductions. Schizophr Bull. 2022; 48(6).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9673251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35810337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhishek A, Bhargavi N, Dona Maria C, Ananth P, Arpitha J, Chaitra VH, Shivarama V, Muralidharan K, Ganesan V, Shyam Vasudeva R et al. Relation between retinal vascular abnormalities and working memory impairment in patients with schizophrenia and bipolar disorder. Asian J Psychiatr. 2020;49(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debora LN, Josh W. The multifunctional choroid. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2010;29(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2913695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anton R, Malinda ECF, Nobel DM, Chunyan L. Neural control of choroidal blood flow. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2017;64(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5971129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29229444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christian C, Christian G. From oxygen to erythropoietin: relevance of hypoxia for retinal development, health and disease. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2011;31(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22108059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaide R, Fujimoto J, Waheed N, Sadda S, Staurenghi G. Optical coherence tomography angiography. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2018;64:1&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.preteyeres.2017.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6404988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29229445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah A, Apte R. Optical coherence tomography angiography: a window into central nervous system neurodegeneration. Trends Mol Med. 2020;26(10):892&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmed.2020.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang M, Tan A, Cheung C, Keane P, Dolz-Marco R, Sng C, Schmetterer L. Optical coherence tomography angiography: a review of current and future clinical applications. Graefe&#x2019;s Arch Clin Exper Ophthalmol = Albrecht Von Graefes Archiv Fur Klinische Und Experimentelle Ophthalmologie. 2018;256(2):237&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00417-017-3896-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29318383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Miere A, Nghiem-Buffet S, Fajnkuchen F, Souied E, Mrejen S. Clinical applications of optical coherence tomography angiography: what we have learnt in the first 3 years. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2018;28(5):491&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1120672117753704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29554812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koustenis A, Harris A, Gross J, Januleviciene I, Shah A, Siesky B. Optical coherence tomography angiography: an overview of the technology and an assessment of applications for clinical research. Br J Ophthalmol. 2017;101(1):16&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjophthalmol-2016-309389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicola V, Elham S, Elli D, Mohammed Nasar I, Nasiq H, Sandeep Chandra B, Sumit Randhir S, Luigi F, Jose Alain S, Kiran Kumar V et al. Three-dimensional choroidal vessels assessment in fellow eyes of patients with central serous chorioretinopathy. Transl Vis Sci Technol. 2025;14(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12422394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40919871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiqin H, Xiongze Z, Xuenan Z, Yunkao Z, Xuelin C, Yuhong G, Yongyue S, Yining Z, Feng W. Diurnal variation in choroidal parameters among healthy subjects using wide-field swept-source optical coherence tomography angiography. Transl Vis Sci Technol. 2024;13(5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11114611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38767903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan W, Lei L, Cong L, Yuan Y, Xue H, Meijun J, Dongming Q, Yun R, Hanpeng Z, Jianrong J et al. Choroidal vessel density in major depressive disorder using swept-source optical coherence tomography angiography. J Affect Disord. 2023;344(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37820961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A F SRK, L A O. The positive and negative syndrome scale (PANSS) for schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 1987;13(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3616518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuma T, Bogovic J, Gunton K, Jimenez H, Negreiros B, Pulido J. The big warp: registration of disparate retinal imaging modalities and an example overlay of ultrawide-field photos and en-face OCTA images. PLoS ONE. 2023;18(4):e0284905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0284905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10129009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37098039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromeo A, Grulla-Quilendrino P, Antolin R, Salcedo E, Arcinue C, De Jesus R, Veloso A. Optical coherence tomography angiography analysis of changes in the foveal avascular zone in eyes with diabetic macular edema treated with intravitreal anti-vascular endothelial growth factor. Int J Retina Vitreous. 2022;8(1):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40942-022-00406-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9419407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36028899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omid M, Mohammad YP, Reza K, Elahe E, Saeed V, Aram Z, Vahid S. Optical coherence tomography angiography biomarkers in multiple sclerosis and neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: a systematic review. Int J Retina Vitr. 2025;11(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12183867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40551221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed M, Yousra F, Amina N, Khaled EM, Imen K, Saloua M, Ahmed C, Alya G, Riadh G, Leila EM. Optical coherence tomography and angiography in Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other cognitive disorders. Eur J Ophthalmol. 2023;33(4).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36617984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadia KW, Richard BR, Yali J, Marion RM, David H, Amani F, Victor C, Quan Dong N, Yasir S, Elizabeth P. Optical coherence tomography angiography in diabetic retinopathy. Prog Retin Eye Res. 2023;97(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11268430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37499857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam W. Principles of OCTA and applications in clinical neurology. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2018;18(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6209039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30338429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melanie TA, Pamela C, Timothy EY, Maria Francesca C. Retinal correlates of psychiatric disorders. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2020;11(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7065291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Wei L, Iqbal T, Kanagasundram S, Mohammadreza P, Visvaraja S. Retinal nerve fiber layer structure abnormalities in schizophrenia and its relationship to disease state: evidence from optical coherence tomography. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2013;54(12).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24135757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiroshi K, Goh O, Stefan J, Nobuhisa K, Yoshihisa K, Takashi O, Shunichi F, Takeshi Y, Toru N, Hiroaki T. Retinal layers and associated clinical factors in schizophrenia spectrum disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mol Psychiatr. 2022; 27(9).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35501407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayd&#x131;n K, K&#xfc;r&#x15f;ad RZ, Erkut K, Gamze Y, Etem EE. An optical coherence tomography study that supports the neurovascular basis of schizophrenia disease. Alpha Psychiatr. 2022;23(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9674096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36425243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdan D, Adam W, Magdalena K, Aleksandra P-L, Gabriela G, Edward W. Bogus&#x142;awa O-W: vascular changes in optical coherence tomography angiography unveiling the depths of dry age-related macular degeneration: a review. Expert Rev Med Dev. 2024;21(11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39450824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altinkaynak H, Duru N, Uysal B, Erten &#x15e;, K&#xfc;rkc&#xfc;o&#x11f;lu P, Y&#xfc;ksel N, Duru Z, &#xc7;a&#x11f;&#x131;l N. Choroidal thickness in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus analyzed by Spectral-domain optical coherence tomography. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2016;24(3):254&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26154112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panigrahi D. Foveal avascular zone area measurement using OCT angiography. Photodiagn Photodyn Ther. 2023;43:103717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pdpdt.2023.103717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37481148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsunaga D, Yi J, De Koo L, Ameri H, Puliafito C, Kashani A. Optical coherence tomography angiography of diabetic retinopathy in human subjects. Opthalmic Surg Lasers Imaging Retin. 2015;46(8):796&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/23258160-20150909-03</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26431294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaratnasingam C, Inoue M, Ahn S, McCann J, Dhrami-Gavazi E, Yannuzzi L, Freund K. Visual acuity is correlated with the area of the foveal avascular zone in diabetic retinopathy and retinal vein occlusion. Ophthalmology. 2016;123(11):2352&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ophtha.2016.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27523615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun L, Hui Z, Hua Y, Ye X, Qiang L, Chao G, Lihong D, Yong W. Changes in retinal and choroidal thickness and vascular density in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: assessed by optical coherence tomography angiography. Lupus. 2024;33(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38158805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiroshi K, Goh O, Steven MS, Stefan J, Atsushi S, Nobuhisa K, Yoshihisa K, Takashi O, Takeshi Y, Toru N et al. Retina as a potential biomarker in schizophrenia spectrum disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis of optical coherence tomography and electroretinography. Mol Psychiatr 2023;29(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11116118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38081943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parver L. Temperature modulating action of choroidal blood flow. Eye. 1991:181&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2070878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yueling C, Tao W, Linqiong W, Hengyan H, Zhaoxi S, Xinyu Z, Wei T. Investigation of the impact of choroidal capillary flow area on macular ischemia in diabetic patients. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12222812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40604088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rupesh A, Preeti G, Kara-Anne T, Chui Ming Gemmy C, Tien-Yin W, Ching-Yu C. Choroidal vascularity index as a measure of vascular status of the choroid: measurements in healthy eyes from a population-based study. Sci Rep. 2016;6(0).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4751574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26868048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>