<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41790884</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Large terahertz photovoltaic effect enhanced by phonon excitations in ferroelectric semiconductor SbSI.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadw9796</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadw9796</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadw9796</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adw9796</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Quantum geometry of Bloch electron in crystalline solids produces various exotic quantum phenomena. The shift current photovoltaic effect driven by the photo creation of quasiparticle is one such emerging example that enables the conversion from terahertz photon into dc charge current with absence of dissipative photocarrier. Despite wide-ranging potential applications, however, the fundamental nature of terahertz photovoltaic response has remained elusive. Here, we show the large photocurrent generation driven by terahertz phonons (&lt;10 milli-electron volts) in ferroelectric semiconductor SbSI with the electronic bandgap of 2.3 electron volts. Zero-bias terahertz photocurrent is found to be resonantly enhanced by optical phonons. Its generation efficiency is larger than that for the direct interband transition and is comparable to the electronic shift current in Weyl semimetal TaAs. The theoretical scaling law of terahertz shift current and first-principles calculation reasonably explain these observations. The present work establishes the universality and high efficiency of phonon-driven shift current, opening the pathway to terahertz technology based on quantum geometry.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamura</LastName><ForeName>Yoshihiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4987-7095</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Physics and Quantum Phase Electronics Center, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Guang-Yu</ForeName><Initials>GY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3097-0916</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics and Center for Emerging Material and Advanced Devices, National Taiwan University, Taipei 10617, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physics Division, National Center for Theoretical Sciences, Taipei 10617, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaneko</LastName><ForeName>Yoshio</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3510-1739</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Center for Emergent Matter Science (CEMS), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Masao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6812-6334</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Center for Emergent Matter Science (CEMS), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics, Graduate School of Science, Tohoku University, Sendai 980-8578, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Baton Zone Program (BZP), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sotome</LastName><ForeName>Masato</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1929-8161</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Engineering, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Advanced Science and Technology, The University of Tokyo, Komaba, Tokyo 153-8904, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ogawa</LastName><ForeName>Naoki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Center for Emergent Matter Science (CEMS), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Baton Zone Program (BZP), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawasaki</LastName><ForeName>Masashi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6397-4812</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Physics and Quantum Phase Electronics Center, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Center for Emergent Matter Science (CEMS), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tokura</LastName><ForeName>Yoshinori</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2732-4983</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Physics and Quantum Phase Electronics Center, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Center for Emergent Matter Science (CEMS), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tokyo College, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Youtarou</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3630-9782</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Physics and Quantum Phase Electronics Center, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RIKEN Center for Emergent Matter Science (CEMS), Wako 351-0198, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41790884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12965303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adw9796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tonouchi M., Cutting-edge terahertz technology. Nat. Photonics 1, 97&#x2013;105 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sizov F., Rogalski A., THz detectors. Prog. Quantum Electron. 34, 278&#x2013;347 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogalski A., Progress in focal plane array technologies. Prog. Quantum Electron. 36, 342&#x2013;473 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicarelli L., Vitiello M. S., Coquillat D., Lombardo A., Ferrari A. C., Knap W., Polini M., Tredicucci A., Graphene field-effect transistors as room-temperature terahertz detectors. Nat. Mater. 11, 865&#x2013;871 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22961203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppens F. H. L., Mueller T., Avouris P., Ferrari A. C., Vitiello M. S., Polini M., Photodetectors based on graphene, other two-dimensional materials and hybrid systems. Nat. Nanotechnol. 9, 780&#x2013;793 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25286273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q., Grushin A. G., Burch K. S., Topology and geometry under the nonlinear electromagnetic spotlight. Nat. Mater. 20, 1601&#x2013;1614 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34127824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokura Y., Nagaosa N., Nonreciprocal responses from non-centrosymmetric quantum materials. Nat. Commun. 9, 3740 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6138722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30218054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaosa N., Yanase Y., Nonreciprocal transport and optical phenomena in quantum materials. Annu. Rev. Condens. Matter Phys. 15, 63&#x2013;83 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto T., Nagaosa N., Topological nature of nonlinear optical effects in solids. Sci. Adv. 2, e1501524 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4928882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27386523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. I. Sturman, V. M. Fridkin, The photovoltaic and photorefractive effects in noncentrosymmetric materials (Gordon and Beach Science Publishers, 1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sipe J. E., Shkrebtii A. I., Second-order optical response in semiconductors. Phys. Rev. B 61, 5337&#x2013;5352 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young S. M., Rappe A. M., First principles calculation of the shift current photovoltaic effect in ferroelectrics. Phys. Rev. Lett. 109, 116601 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23005660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan L. Z., Zheng F., Young S. M., Wang F., Liu S., Rappe A. M., Shift current bulk photovoltaic effect in polar materials-hybrid and oxide perovskites and beyond. npj Comput. Mater. 2, 16026 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M., Horiuchi S., Kagawa F., Ogawa N., Kurumaji T., Tokura Y., Kawasaki M., Shift current photovoltaic effect in a ferroelectric charge-transfer complex. Nat. Commun. 8, 281 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5561111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28819286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osterhoudt G. B., Diebel L. K., Gray M. J., Yang X., Stanco J., Huang X., Shen B., Ni N., Moll P. J. W., Ran Y., Burach K. S., Colossal mid-infrared bulk photovoltaic effect in a type-I Weyl semimetal. Nat. Mater. 18, 471&#x2013;475 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30833781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa N., Sotome M., Kaneko Y., Ogino M., Tokura Y., Shift current in the ferroelectric semiconductor SbSI. Phys. Rev. B 96, 241203 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotome M., Nakamura M., Fujioka J., Ogino M., Kaneko Y., Morimoto T., Zhang Y., Kawasaki M., Naogasa N., Tokura Y., Ogawa N., Spectral dynamics of shift current in ferroelectric semiconductor SbSI. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 116, 1929&#x2013;1933 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatada H., Nakamura M., Sotome M., Kaneko Y., Ogawa N., Morimoto T., Tokura Y., Kawasaki M., Defect tolerant zero-bias topological photocurrent in a ferroelectric semiconductor. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 117, 20411&#x2013;20415 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32778597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto T., Nagaosa N., Topological aspects of nonlinear excitonic processes in noncentrosymmetric crystals. Phys. Rev. B 94, 035117 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto T., Nagaosa N., Shift current from electromagnon excitations in multiferroics. Phys. Rev. B 100, 235138 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotome M., Nakamura M., Morimoto T., Zhang Y., Guo G.-Y., Kawasaki M., Nagaosa N., Tokura Y., Ogawa N., Terahertz emission spectroscopy of ultrafast exciton shift current in the noncentrosymmetric semiconductor CdS. Phys. Rev. B 103, L241111 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamura Y., Morimoto T., Ogawa N., Kaneko Y., Guo G.-Y., Nakamura M., Kawasaki M., Nagaosa N., Tokura Y., Takahashi Y., Photovoltaic effect by soft phonon excitation. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 119, e2122313119 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9169116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35344426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogino M., Okamura Y., Fujiwara K., Morimoto T., Nagaosa N., Kaneko Y., Tokura Y., Takahashi Y., Terahertz photon to dc current conversion via magnetic excitations of multiferroics. Nat. Commun. 15, 4699 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11156647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38844471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatuzzo E., Harbeke G., Merz W. J., Nitsche R., Roetschi H., Ruppel W., Ferroelectricity in SbSI. Phys. Rev. 127, 2036 (1962).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuchi A., Oka Y., Sawaguchi E., Crystal structure determination of SbSI. J. Physical Soc. Japan 23, 337&#x2013;354 (1967).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal D. K., Perry C. H., Long-wavelength optical phonons and phase transitions in SbSI. Phys. Rev. B 4, 1893&#x2013;1902 (1971).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitsche R., Merz W. J., Photoconduction in ternary V-VI-VII compounds. J. Phys. Chem. Solid 13, 154&#x2013;155 (1960).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. M. Fridkin, Photoferroelectrics (Springer, 1979), 10.1007/978-3-642-81351-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-81351-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M., Hatada H., Kaneko Y., Ogawa N., Tokura Y., Kawasaki M., Impact of electrodes on the extraction of shift current from a ferroelectric semiconductor SbSI. Appl. Phys. Lett. 113, 232901 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M., Hatada H., Kaneko Y., Ogawa N., Sotome M., Tokura Y., Kawasaki M., Non-local photocurrent in a ferroelectric semiconductor SbSI under local photoexcitation. Appl. Phys. Lett. 116, 122902 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebling J., Almasi G., Kozma I. Z., Kuhl J., Velocity matching by pulse front tilting for large area THz-pulse generation. Opt. Express 10, 1161&#x2013;1166 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass A. M., von der Linde D., Negran T. J., 
High-voltage bulk photovoltaic effect and the photorefractive process in LiNbO<sub>3</sub>. Appl. Phys. Lett.
25, 
233 (1974).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenkevich A., Matveyev Y., Maksimova K., Gaynutdinov R., Tolstikhina A., Fridkin V., 
Giant bulk photovoltaic effect in thin ferroelectric BaTiO<sub>3</sub> films. Phys. Rev. B
90, 
161409 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young S. M., Zheng F., Rappe A. M., First-principles calculation of the bulk photovoltaic effect in bismuth ferrite. Phys. Rev. Lett. 109, 236601 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23368233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng F., Takenaka H., Wang F., Koocher N. Z., Rappe A. M., 
First-principles calculation of the bulk photovoltaic effect in CH<sub>3</sub>NH<sub>3</sub>PbI<sub>3</sub> and CH<sub>3</sub>NH<sub>3</sub>PbI<sub>3&#x2212;x</sub>Cl<i>x</i>. J. Phys. Chem. Lett.
6, 
31 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26263087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perdew J. P., Burke K., Ernzerhof M., Generalized gradient approximation made simple. Phys. Rev. Lett. 77, 3865&#x2013;3868 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10062328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baroni S., de Gironcoli S., Dal Corso S., Giannozzi P., Phonons and related crystal properties from density-functional perturbation theory. Rev. Mod. Phys. 73, 515 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannozzi P., Andreussi O., Brumme T., Bunau O., Buongiorno Nardelli M., Calandra M., Car R., Cavazzoni C., Ceresoli D., Cococcioni M., Colonna N., Carnimeo I., Dal Corso A., de Gironcoli S., Delugas P., DiStasio R. A. Jr., Ferretti A., Floris A., Fratesi G., Fugallo G., Gebauer R., Gerstmann U., Giustino F., Gorni T., Jia J., Kawamura M., Ko H.-Y., Kokalj A., K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;kbenli E., Lazzeri M., Marsili M., Marzari N., Mauri F., Nguyen N. L., Nguyen H.-V., Otero-de-la-Roza A., Paulatto L., Ponc&#xe9; S., Rocca D., Sabatini R., Santra B., Schlipf M., Seitsonen A. P., Smogunov A., Timrov I., Thonhauser T., Umari P., Vast N., Wu X., Baroni S., Advanced capabilities for materials modelling with Quantum ESPRESSO. J. Phys. Condens. Matter 29, 465901 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29064822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamann D. R., Optimized norm-conserving Vanderbilt pseudo potentials. Phys. Rev. B 88, 085117 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustino F., Cohen M. L., Louie S. G., Electron-phonon interaction using Wannier functions. Phys. Rev. B 76, 165108 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17358802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponc&#xe9; S., Margine E. R., Verdi C., Giustino F., EPW: Electron-phonon coupling, transport and superconducting properties using maximally localized Wannier functions. Comp. Phys. Commun. 209, 116 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto T., Nagaosa N., Direct current generation by dielectric loss in ferroelectrics. Phys. Rev. B 110, 045129 (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>