<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41476239</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2047-2994</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Antimicrobial resistance and infection control</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Practices and perspectives on antimicrobial drug misuse in Southern Ethiopia: a mixed-method study, 2024.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>18</StartPage><MedlinePgn>18</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">18</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13756-025-01688-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Antimicrobial resistance refers to the ability of microorganisms to become resistant to antibiotics, fungicides, and other antimicrobial agents, which are essential for treating illnesses in humans, land and water-based animals, and plants. This issue is quickly emerging as a major danger to health, economic stability, and livelihoods. One notable driver of these resistant microorganisms is the misuse of antimicrobial medications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the practices and perspectives on antimicrobial drug misuse in Wolaita Zone, 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study employed a community-based cross-sectional mixed-methods design. The study data were collected from 423 community residents for the quantitative phase and 15 participants for the qualitative phase, data collection for the quantitative component was collected using structured interview-administered questionnaires, and the qualitative component involved in-depth interviews with purposively selected participants, guided by a structured interview. Quantitative data management involved the use of EpiData V4.6 and the Statistical Package for the Social Sciences for data entry and analysis, respectively. The qualitative data underwent thematic analysis utilizing OpenCode software, a qualitative data analysis tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In this study, the quantitative data found that 67.1% of participants misused antimicrobial drugs. The factors significantly associated with the misuse of antimicrobial drugs included educational status [AOR: 1.91 (95% CI: 0.93-2.11)], drug cost [AOR: 3.22 (95% CI: 1.18-5.3)], knowledge regarding the use of antimicrobial drugs [AOR: 2.23 (95% CI: 1.66-4.01)], and adherence to stewardship guidelines [AOR: 3.37 (95% CI: 2.44-9.24)]. Additionally, the qualitative study identified four key themes from the data analysis namely, factors related to drug providers, patient-driven factors, sociocultural influences, and limitations in regulatory and policy frameworks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study reveals a troubling rate of antimicrobial drug misuse among the population. The finding underscores the urgent need to address the gaps and barriers that impede proper use of antimicrobial drugs. It is recommended that government and non-government health sectors, along with relevant stakeholders, implement educational initiatives and health campaigns to combat this problem.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bolado</LastName><ForeName>Getachew Nigussie</ForeName><Initials>GN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adult Health Nursing, School of Nursing, College of Health Science and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Sodo, Ethiopia. getachewnigussie4@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Endrias</LastName><ForeName>Eshetu Elfios</ForeName><Initials>EE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adult Health Nursing, School of Nursing, College of Health Science and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ataro</LastName><ForeName>Bizuayehu Atinafu</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adult Health Nursing, School of Nursing, College of Health Science and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayana</LastName><ForeName>Agumas Shibabaw</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, School of Nursing, College of Health Science and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurisa</LastName><ForeName>Habtamu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgical Nursing, School of Nursing, College of Health Science and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bekele</LastName><ForeName>Habtamu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgical Nursing, School of Nursing, College of Health Science and Medicine, Wolaita Sodo University, Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minuta</LastName><ForeName>Worku Mimani</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Jinka University, Jinka, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Antimicrob Resist Infect Control</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101585411</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2047-2994</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000890">Anti-Infective Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000890" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anti-Infective Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076064" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Misuse</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibiotic stewardship</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial drug resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community drug use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wolaita zone</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval for this study was granted by the Wolaita Sodo University Institutional Review Board (WSU-IRB), under protocol number WSU-IRB/598861/2024, on October 25, 2024. Before data collection, informed consent was obtained from all participants. It was clearly communicated to the participants that they had the right to decline involvement in both the quantitative and qualitative aspects of the study at any time, and strict confidentiality measures were put in place to safeguard their privacy. Throughout the study, the core ethical principles of beneficence, non-maleficence, autonomy, and justice were consistently upheld to ensure the safety and well-being of the participants. Furthermore, informed consent was obtained from all participants for the publication of anonymized responses. Additionally, the study adhered strictly to the ethical guidelines outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki for research involving human subjects, as well as the publication ethics standards established by the Committee on Publication Ethics (COPE). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41476239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12865961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-025-01688-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13756-025-01688-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Edessa D, Kumsa FA, Dinsa G, Oljira L. Drug providers&#x2019; perspectives on antibiotic misuse practices in Eastern ethiopia: a qualitative study. BMJ Open. 2024;14(8):e085352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2024-085352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11404147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39209504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food N. Aootu. Fao action plan on antimicrobial resistance 2021&#x2013;2025: supporting innovation and resilience In&#x2026; food and agriculture sectors. Food &amp; Agriculture Org; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejene H, Birhanu R, Tarekegn ZS. Knowledge, attitude and practices of residents toward antimicrobial usage and resistance in Gondar, Northwest Ethiopia. One Health Outlook. 2022;4(1):10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42522-022-00066-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35581659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siam MH, Imran A, Limon MB, Zahid MH, Hossain MA, Siddique MA, Sultana M, Hossain MA. Antibiotic abuse: a cross-sectional study on knowledge, attitude, and behavior among the university students in Dhaka, Bangladesh. Electron J Gen Med. 2021;18(3).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianco A, Licata F, Zucco R, Papadopoli R, Pavia M, Evolution. Med Public Health. 2020;2020(1):129&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7502262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akande-Sholabi W, Oyesiji EJJoPP. Practice. antimicrobial stewardship: knowledge, perceptions, and factors associated with antibiotics misuse among consumer&#x2019;s visiting the community pharmacies in a Nigeria Southwestern State. Journal of Pharmaceutical Policy and Practice. 2023;16(1):120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10566051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37821920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naghavi M, Vollset SE, Ikuta KS, Swetschinski LR, Gray AP, Wool EE, Aguilar GR, Mestrovic T, Smith G, Han C, Hsu RL. Global burden of bacterial antimicrobial resistance 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis with forecasts to 2050. Lancet. 2024;404(10459):1199&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)01867-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11718157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39299261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajd&#xe1;cs M, Jamshed S. Knowledge, attitude and practices of the public and healthcare-professionals towards sustainable use of antimicrobials: the intersection of pharmacology and social medicine. Front Antibiot. 2024;3:1374463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frabi.2024.1374463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11732095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39816269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye Z. Patient knowledge and practice on antimicrobial use and resistance in Felege Hiwot hospital, Bahir Dar, Ethiopia. J Basic Clin Pharm. 2017;8:S010&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzan M, Islam DZ, Lugova H, Krishnapillai A, Haque M, Islam S. Knowledge, attitudes, and practices of antimicrobial uses and resistance among public university students in Bangladesh. Infection and drug resistance. 2021 Feb 11:519&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33603416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muteeb G, Rehman MT, Shahwan M, Aatif M. Origin of antibiotics and antibiotic resistance, and their impacts on drug development: a narrative review. Pharmaceuticals. 2023;16(11):1615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ph16111615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10675245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38004480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jifar A, Ayele Y. Assessment of knowledge, attitude, and practice toward antibiotic use among Harar City and its surrounding community, Eastern Ethiopia. Interdisciplinary Perspect Infect Dis. 2018;20181:8492740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6106796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30174690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabaweesi I, Olum R, Sekite AB, Suubi WT, Nakiwunga P, Machali A, Kiyumba R, Kalyango P, Natamba A, Igumba Y, Kyeyune M. Antibiotic practices, perceptions and self-medication among patients at a National referral hospital in Uganda. Infection and drug resistance. 2021 Jun 10:2155&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8203198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyawali R, Gamboa S, Rolfe K, Westbrook JI, Raban MZ. Consumer perspectives on antibiotic use in residential aged care: a mixed-methods systematic review. Am J Infect Control. 2024;52(12):1452&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajic.2024.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39067702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Understanding and Addressing the Determinants of Antimicrobial Medicine Abuse in Lebanon. WCCPRD6572603, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukwu EE, Abuh D, Idigbe IE, Osuolale KA, Chuka-Ebene V, Awoderu O, Audu RA, Ogunsola FT. Implementation of antimicrobial stewardship programs: a study of prescribers&#x2019; perspective of facilitators and barriers. PLoS ONE. 2024;19(1):e0297472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0297472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10798493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38241406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudenda S, Chabalenge B, Daka V, Mfune RL, Salachi KI, Mohamed S, Mufwambi W, Kasanga M, Matafwali SK. Global strategies to combat antimicrobial resistance: a one health perspective. Pharmacol Pharm. 2023;14(8):271&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/pp.2023.148020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majumder MA, Rahman S, Cohall D, Bharatha A, Singh K, Haque M, Gittens-St Hilaire M. Antimicrobial stewardship: fighting antimicrobial resistance and protecting global public health. Infection and drug resistance. 2020 Dec 29:4713&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33402841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayenew W, Tessema TA, Anagaw YK, Siraj EA, Zewdie S, Simegn W, Limenh LW, Tafere C, Yayehrad AT. Prevalence and predictors of self-medication with antibiotics in ethiopia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2024;13(1):61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-024-01417-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11163721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38853267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edessa D, Asefa Kumsa F, Dinsa G, Oljira L. Inappropriate antibiotic access practices at the community level in Eastern Ethiopia. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):17751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-67688-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11291666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39085272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urugo MM, Yohannis E, Teka TA, Gemede HF, Tola YB, Forsido SF, Tessema A, Suraj M, Abdu J. Journal of agriculture and food research. J Agric Food Res. 2024;18(101316).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhie OA. Antibiotic use and resistance pattern in ethiopia: systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Microbiol. 2019;2019(1):2489063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6701335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31467550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endale H, Mathewos M, Abdeta D. Potential causes of spread of antimicrobial resistance and preventive measures in one health perspective-a review. Infect Drug Resist 2023 Dec 31:7515&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10715026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38089962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woldu MA. Antimicrobial resistance in ethiopia: current landscape, challenges, and strategic interventions. Discover Med. 2024;1(1):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44337-024-00090-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebregziabher NK, Netsereab TB, Franchesko BT, Ghebreamlak HH, Yihdego NM. Prevalence of self-medication practices with antibiotics and associated factors among students in five colleges in eritrea: a cross-sectional study. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2024;13(1):106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-024-01466-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11414089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39300551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erku DA, Mekuria AB, Belachew SA. Inappropriate use of antibiotics among communities of Gondar town, ethiopia: a threat to the development of antimicrobial resistance. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2017;6(1):112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-017-0272-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5678763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29152233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendrix N, Warkaye S, Tesfaye L, Woldekidan MA, Arja A, Sato R, Memirie ST, Mirkuzie AH, Getnet F, Verguet S. Estimated travel time and staffing constraints to accessing the Ethiopian health care system: a two-step floating catchment area analysis. J Global Health. 2023;13:04008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7189/jogh.13.04008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9880518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36701563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahl NA, King JR. Expanding approaches for research: Understanding and using trustworthiness in qualitative research. J Dev Educ. 2020;44(1):26&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>