<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41487450</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1687-9740</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2026</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Incidence and Determinants of Newborn Hypoglycemia Among Neonates Hospitalized in Public Hospitals of Wolaita Zone, Southern Ethiopia: A Multicentered Prospective Follow-Up Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8259158</StartPage><MedlinePgn>8259158</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8259158</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/ijpe/8259158</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Currently, neonatal hypoglycemia is one of the most frequent metabolic disorders and is associated with an increased rate of neonatal morbidity and mortality. Although neonatal hypoglycemia is a common problem among hospitalized neonates, there is limited evidence about its incidence and predictors in Ethiopia, and no studies have been done in our study area. It is critical to consider the incidence and predictors of neonatal hypoglycemia to save neonates' lives from acute problems, long-term neurological impairments, and death. This study is aimed at assessing the incidence and predictors of neonatal hypoglycemia among neonates admitted to Wolaita Zone health institutions' neonatal intensive care units.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A hospital-based prospective follow-up study was conducted on a sample of 785 admitted eligible neonates between November 1, 2023, and June 1, 2024. The eligible neonates were included in the study consecutively. Data were collected using a pretested interview guide and checklist on sociodemographic, obstetric, and neonatal-related risk factors of hypoglycemia. The collected data were coded, edited, and imported to STATA Version 14 from Kobo toolbox for further analysis. The Kaplan-Meier survival curve was used to determine survival time, and the log-rank test was used to compare survival times across categorical factors. To identify predictors, both bivariable and multivariable Cox proportional hazard regression models were employed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Among the 785 neonates included in the final analysis, the overall incidence rate of neonatal hypoglycemia during the follow-up time was found to be 15.47 per 1000 neonate-days (95% CI: 12.55, 19.06). Maternal history of bad obstetrics (AHR: 2.26, 95% CI: 1.29, 3.96), gestational diabetes mellitus (AHR: 2.27, 95% CI: 1.27, 4.05), gestational age (AHR: 2.88, 95% CI: 1.35, 6.18), hypothermia (AHR: 2.55, 95% CI: 1.37, 4.77), and newborn type (AHR: 4.31, 95% CI: 1.03, 8.10) were predictors of neonatal hypoglycemia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this study, we found a high rate of neonatal hypoglycemia. Therefore, monitoring, identifying, and managing the aforementioned predictors is important to prevent as well as to control neonatal hypoglycemia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Belete Gelaw Walle et al. International Journal of Pediatrics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walle</LastName><ForeName>Belete Gelaw</ForeName><Initials>BG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6965-8466</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Child Health Nursing, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, South Ethiopia, Ethiopia, wsu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asmare</LastName><ForeName>Hailu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency and Critical Care Nursing, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, South Ethiopia, Ethiopia, wsu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tadiwos</LastName><ForeName>Kidst</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Child Health Nursing, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, South Ethiopia, Ethiopia, wsu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nega</LastName><ForeName>Banchalem</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, Wolaita Sodo University, Wolaita Sodo, South Ethiopia, Ethiopia, wsu.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Temere</LastName><ForeName>Bogale Chekole</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric and Child Health Nursing, Wolkite University, Wolkite, Central Ethiopia, Ethiopia, wku.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101517077</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1687-9740</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethiopia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wolaita Zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neonatal hypoglycemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">predictors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41487450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12757846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/ijpe/8259158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJPE8259158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bromiker R., Perry A., Kasirer Y., Einav S., Klinger G., and Levy-Khademi F., Early Neonatal Hypoglycemia: Incidence of and Risk Factors. A Cohort Study Using Universal Point of Care Screening, Journal of Maternal-Fetal &amp; Neonatal Medicine. (2019) 32, no. 5, 786&#x2013;792, 10.1080/14767058.2017.1391781, 2-s2.0-85032373044, 29020813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14767058.2017.1391781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29020813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FMOH. Participants Training Manual. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casertano A., Rossi A., Fecarotta S., Rosanio F. M., Moracas C., Di Candia F., Parenti G., Franzese A., and Mozzillo E., An Overview of Hypoglycemia in Children Including a Comprehensive Practical Diagnostic Flowchart for Clinical Use, Frontiers in Endocrinology. (2021) 12, 684011, 10.3389/fendo.2021.684011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2021.684011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8366517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34408725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsaleem M., Saadeh L., and Kamat D., Neonatal Hypoglycemia: A Review, Clinical Pediatrics. (2019) 58, no. 13, 1381&#x2013;1386, 10.1177/0009922819875540, 2-s2.0-85073081560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0009922819875540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31556318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stomnaroska O., Petkovska E., Jancevska S., and Danilovski D., Neonatal Hypoglycemia: Risk Factors and Outcomes, Prilozi. (2017) 38, no. 1, 97&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28593892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah R., Dai D. W., Alsweiler J. M., Brown G. T., Chase J. G., Gamble G. D., Harris D. L., Keegan P., Nivins S., Wouldes T. A., Thompson B., Turuwhenua J., Harding J. E., McKinlay C. J. D., and Children With Hypoglycaemia and Their Later Development (CHYLD) Study Team, Association of Neonatal Hypoglycemia With Academic Performance in Mid-Childhood, Journal of the American Medical Association. (2022) 327, no. 12, 1158&#x2013;1170, 10.1001/jama.2022.0992, 35315886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.0992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8941348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35315886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding J. E., Harris D. L., Hegarty J. E., Alsweiler J. M., and McKinlay C. J., An Emerging Evidence Base for the Management of Neonatal Hypoglycaemia, Early Human Development. (2017) 104, 51&#x2013;56, 10.1016/j.earlhumdev.2016.12.009, 2-s2.0-85008482378, 27989586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earlhumdev.2016.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5280577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27989586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePuy A. M., Coassolo K. M., Som D. A., and Smulian J. C., Neonatal Hypoglycemia in Term, Nondiabetic Pregnancies, American journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology. (2009) 200, no. 5, e45&#x2013;e51, 10.1016/j.ajog.2008.10.015, 2-s2.0-64249099621, 19168170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2008.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19168170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dani C. and Corsini I., Guidelines for Management of Neonatal Hypoglycemia, JAMA Pediatrics. (2020) 174, no. 7, 638&#x2013;639, 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.0632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2020.0632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32391888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards T. and Harding J. E., Clinical Aspects of Neonatal Hypoglycemia: A Mini Review, Frontiers in Pediatrics. (2021) 8, 562251, 10.3389/fped.2020.562251, 33489995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2020.562251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33489995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser J. R., Bai S., Gibson N., Holland G., Lin T. M., Swearingen C. J., Mehl J. K., and ElHassan N. O., Association Between Transient Newborn Hypoglycemia and Fourth-Grade Achievement Test Proficiency: A Population-Based Study, JAMA Pediatrics. (2015) 169, no. 10, 913&#x2013;921, 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2015.1631, 2-s2.0-84943400429, 26301959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2015.1631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26301959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A., Davis A., and Shekhawat P. S., Hypoglycemia in the Preterm Neonate: Etiopathogenesis, Diagnosis, Management and Long-Term Outcomes, Translational Pediatrics. (2017) 6, no. 4, 335&#x2013;348, 10.21037/tp.2017.10.06, 2-s2.0-85032708922, 29184814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/tp.2017.10.06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5682372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29184814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed D. and Mekasha A., Hypoglycemia Among Newborns in a Teaching Hospital, Ethiopia ICP. (2004) .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sertsu A., Nigussie K., Eyeberu A., Tibebu A., Negash A., Getachew T., Debella A., and Dheresa M., Determinants of Neonatal Hypoglycemia Among Neonates Admitted at Hiwot Fana Comprehensive Specialized University Hospital, Eastern Ethiopia: A Retrospective Cross-Sectional Study, SAGE Open Medicine. (2022) 10, 20503121221141801, 10.1177/20503121221141801, 36505973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121221141801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9730006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36505973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurussen I. and Fantahun B., Prevalence and Risk Factors of Neonatal Hypoglycaemia at St. Paul&#x2019;s Hospital Millennium Medical College, Ethiopia, Ethiopian Journal of Pediatrics and Child Health. (2021) 16, no. 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melana N., Ahmed N., Soni R., and Goyal M., Neurodevelopmental Outcome in Neonates With Hypoglycaemia and Associated Risk Factors: A Follow Up Study, Journal of Pregnancy and Child Health. (2017) 4, no. 3, 1000323, 10.4172/2376-127X.1000323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2376-127X.1000323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris D. L., Alsweiler J. M., Ansell J. M., Gamble G. D., Thompson B., Wouldes T. A., Yu T. Y., Harding J. E., Ansell J., Bevan C., Brosnanhan J., Campbell E., Crawford T., Fredell K., Frost K., Gamble G., Gsell A., Hahnhaussen C., Hossin S., Jiang Y., Jones K., Martin S., McKinlay C., McKnight G., McQuoid C., Paynter J., Rogers J., Sommers K., Stewart H., Timmings A., Wilson J., Young R., Anstice N., Arthur J., Bruder S., Chakraborty A., Jacobs R., Matheson G., Paudel N., Yu T. Y., Signal M., le Compte A., Berry M., Nair A., Tuck A., Wallace A., Weston P., Alsweiler J., Harding J., Thompson B., Wouldes T., Chase J. G., Harris D., Feldman H., Wilson D., Hay W., and Hess R., Outcome at 2 Years After Dextrose Gel Treatment for Neonatal Hypoglycemia: Follow-Up of a Randomized Trial, Journal of Pediatrics. (2016) 170, no. 54-9, 54&#x2013;59.e2, 10.1016/j.jpeds.2015.10.066, 2-s2.0-84960079364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2015.10.066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4769950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26613985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah R., Harding J., Brown J., and McKinlay C., Neonatal Glycaemia and Neurodevelopmental Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis, Neonatology. (2019) 115, no. 2, 116&#x2013;126, 10.1159/000492859, 2-s2.0-85056460547, 30408811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000492859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30408811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkalay A. L., Flores-Sarnat L., Sarnat H. B., Moser F. G., and Simmons C. F., Brain Imaging Findings in Neonatal Hypoglycemia: Case Report and Review of 23 Cases, Clinical Pediatrics. (2005) 44, no. 9, 783&#x2013;790, 10.1177/000992280504400906, 2-s2.0-28844442205, 16327965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/000992280504400906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16327965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhand S. A., Sheikh F., Siyal A. R., Nizamani M. A., and Saeed M., Neonatal Hypoglycemia, Professional Medical Journal. (2018) 21, no. 4, 745&#x2013;749, 10.29309/TPMJ/2014.21.04.2312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29309/TPMJ/2014.21.04.2312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasidharan C., Gokul E., and Sabitha S., Incidence and Risk Factors for Neonatal Hypoglycaemia in Kerala, India, Ceylon Medical Journal. (2010) 49, no. 4, 110&#x2013;113, 10.4038/cmj.v49i4.1919, 15693448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4038/cmj.v49i4.1919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15693448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S., Kumar N., and Vivekadhish S., Millennium Development Goals (MDGS) to Sustainable Development Goals (SDGS): Addressing Unfinished Agenda and Strengthening Sustainable Development and Partnership, Indian Journal of Community Medicine. (2016) 41, no. 1, 1&#x2013;4, 10.4103/0970-0218.170955, 2-s2.0-84950311565, 26917865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0970-0218.170955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4746946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26917865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, Health in 2015: From MDGs, Millennium Development Goals to SDGs, Sustainable Development Goals, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ephi M., Ethiopian Demographic and Health Survey 2019, 2021, The DHS Program ICF.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonnen Y., Tensou B., Telake D. S., Degefie T., and Bekele A., Neonatal Mortality in Ethiopia: Trends and Determinants, BMC Public Health. (2013) 13, no. 1, 1&#x2013;14, 10.1186/1471-2458-13-483, 2-s2.0-84877805235, 23683315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-13-483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3659057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23683315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekbib T., Kassaye E., Getachew A., Tadesse T., and Debebe A., The FIGO Save the Mothers Initiative: the Ethiopia&#x2013;Sweden Collaboration, International Journal of Gynecology &amp; Obstetrics. (2003) 81, no. 1, 93&#x2013;102, 10.1016/S0020-7292(03)00071-7, 2-s2.0-0037379811, 12676407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0020-7292(03)00071-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12676407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kayongo M., Rubardt M., Butera J., Abdullah M., Mboninyibuka D., and Madili M., Making EmOC a Reality&#x2014;CARE&#x2032;s Experiences in Areas of High Maternal Mortality in Africa, International Journal of Gynecology &amp; Obstetrics. (2006) 92, no. 3, 308&#x2013;319, 10.1016/j.ijgo.2005.12.003, 2-s2.0-33344476924, 16442536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijgo.2005.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16442536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu T., Huang Y.-Y., Song W., Redding S. R., Huang W.-P., and Ouyang Y.-Q., Development of a Prediction Model for Neonatal Hypoglycemia Risk Factors: A Retrospective Study, Frontiers in Endocrinology. (2023) 14, 1199628, 10.3389/fendo.2023.1199628, 37529595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2023.1199628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10389046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37529595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishikant T., Milind K., Ravindra C., and Shilpa N., Neonatal Hypoglycemia in a Tertiary Care Hospital, Diabetes. (2015) 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar U. and Singh B., To Determine the Clinical Profile of Hypoglycemia in Newborn and to Determine the Prevalence of Hypoglycemia Among Neonates Admitted in NICU, European Journal of Molecular &amp; Clinical Medicine. (2020) 7, no. 10, 3738&#x2013;3743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P., Narayan Singh S., Tripathi S., and Kumar M., Incidence, Predictors, and Outcomes of Hypoglycemia Among At-Risk Neonates, Perinatology. (2021) 22, no. 3, 171&#x2013;177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rop H., Awuor S., Mwasi D., Nyawira N., Warutere P., Njiiri P., Ongecha F., Andaya V. M., and Kahiga T., Prevalence of Neonatal Hypoglycemia and Risk Factors in the Newborn Unit at a Tertiary Care Hospital in Kenya, East African Medical Journal. (2023) 100, no. 4, 5832&#x2013;5838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munye T., Agmas K., Necho W., and Moges N., Incidence of Persistent Neonatal Hypoglycemia and Associated Factors Among Neonatal Intensive Care Unit Admissions in South Gondar Public Hospitals, Northcentral Ethiopia: A Prospective Cross Sectional Study, 2024, 10.21203/rs.3.rs-3823404/v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.3.rs-3823404/v1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11540703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39513160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanie E. S., Shiferaw S. M., Feleke D. G., Bantie B., Moges N., Tasew S. F., Alemayehu T. Y., Teshome A. A., Yirga G. K., Berhan A., Amare A. T., Libanos M., Emrie W. A., and Chanie S. S., Maximizing the Detection Rate of Hypoglycemia Among Preterm Neonates Admitted in Neonatal Intensive Care Unit in Ethiopia, 2021, Scientific Reports. (2023) 13, no. 1, 10.1038/s41598-023-29112-y, 36759521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-29112-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9911727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekanem E. E., Fajola A. O., Ande A. B., Ikeagwu G. O., Anidima T. E., Umejiego C. N., and Usman R., Care of the Sick Newborn in a Cottage Hospital Level in a Developing Country, Nigerian Medical Journal. (2020) 61, no. 4, 206&#x2013;209, 10.4103/nmj.NMJ_162_19, 33284882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/nmj.NMJ_162_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7688024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedeke I., Okeniyi J., Owa J., and Oyedeji G., Point-of-Admission Neonatal Hypoglycaemia in a Nigerian Tertiary Hospital: Incidence, Risk Factors and Outcome, Nigerian Journal of Paediatrics. (2011) 38, no. 2, 90&#x2013;94, 10.4314/njp.v38i2.72252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/njp.v38i2.72252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koolen M. R., van Kempen A. A., Maaskant J. M., Reiss I., and Vermeulen M. J., Incidence and Risk Factors for Early Hypoglycemia in Very Preterm Infants: The Hyporisk Study, Clinical Nutrition ESPEN. (2023) 56, 67&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37344085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Mekkawy M. S. and Ellahony D. M., Prevalence and Prognostic Value of Plasma Glucose Abnormalities Among Full-Term and Late-Preterm Neonates With Sepsis, Egyptian Pediatric Association Gazette. (2019) 67, no. 1, 10.1186/s43054-019-0002-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43054-019-0002-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amponsah G., Hagan O., and Okai E., Neonatal Hypoglycaemia at Cape Coast Teaching Hospital, Journal of the West African College of Surgeons. (2015) 5, no. 2, 100&#x2013;116, 27830125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5036286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27830125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukunya D., Odongkara B., Piloya T., Nankabirwa V., Achora V., Batte C., Ditai J., Tylleskar T., Ndeezi G., Kiguli S., and Tumwine J. K., Prevalence and Factors Associated With Neonatal Hypoglycemia in Northern Uganda: A Community-Based Cross-Sectional Study, Tropical Medicine and Health. (2020) 48, no. 1, 10.1186/s41182-020-00275-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41182-020-00275-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7640646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33292804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosagasi N. H., Aydin M., Zenciroglu A., Ustun N., and Beken S., Incidence of Hypoglycemia in Newborns at Risk and an Audit of the 2011 American Academy of Pediatrics Guideline for Hypoglycemia, Pediatrics &amp; Neonatology. (2018) 59, no. 4, 368&#x2013;374, 10.1016/j.pedneo.2017.11.009, 2-s2.0-85035772985, 29198616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pedneo.2017.11.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29198616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochoga M. O., Aondoaseer M., Abah R. O., Ogbu O., Ejeliogu E. U., and Tolough G. I., Prevalence of Hypoglycaemia in Newborn at Benue State University Teaching Hospital, Makurdi, Benue State, Nigeria, Open Journal of Pediatrics. (2018) 8, no. 2, 189&#x2013;198, 10.4236/ojped.2018.82021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojped.2018.82021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sambany E., Pussard E., Rajaonarivo C., Raobijaona H., and Barennes H., Childhood Dysglycemia: Prevalence and Outcome in a Referral Hospital, PLoS One. (2013) 8, no. 5, e65193, 10.1371/journal.pone.0065193, 2-s2.0-84878541356, 23741481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0065193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3669285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23741481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari A., Savaskar S., and Moin Tamboli P. S., Study of Incidence, Risk Factors and Immediate Outcome of Hypoglycemia in Neonates Admitted in NICU, International Journal of Contemporary Pediatricss. (2023) 10, no. 8, 1303&#x2013;1309, 10.18203/2349-3291.ijcp20232253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18203/2349-3291.ijcp20232253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke D., Godbole P., and Cash A., Hospital Transformation: From Failure to Success and Beyond, 2019, Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
FMOH, Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU) Management Protocol, 2021, Addis Ababa, https://www.scribd.com/document/799316411/Final-NICU-Management-Protocol-Sep-26-2021?utm_source=chatgpt.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcdante K. and Kliegman R. M., Nelson Essentials of Pediatrics E-Book, 2014, Elsevier Health Sciences.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berry D. C., Johnson Q. B., and Stuebe A. M., Monitoring and Managing Mothers With Gestational Diabetes Mellitus: A Nursing Perspective, Nursing: Research and Reviews. (2015) 5, 91&#x2013;97, 10.2147/NRR.S64534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NRR.S64534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voormolen D. N., de Wit L., van Rijn B. B., DeVries J. H., Heringa M. P., Franx A., Groenendaal F., and Lamain-de Ruiter M., Neonatal Hypoglycemia Following Diet-Controlled and Insulin-Treated Gestational Diabetes Mellitus, Diabetes Care. (2018) 41, no. 7, 1385&#x2013;1390, 10.2337/dc18-0048, 2-s2.0-85049726862, 29654142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc18-0048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29654142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negrato C. A., Mattar R., and Gomes M. B., Adverse Pregnancy Outcomes in Women With Diabetes, Diabetology &amp; Metabolic Syndrome. (2012) 4, no. 1, 10.1186/1758-5996-4-41, 2-s2.0-84865974715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-5996-4-41</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22964143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>al MHe, Incidence and Risk Factors of Neonatal Hypoglycemia During the First 48 Hours of Life in a Tertiary Level Hospital, Faridpur Med Coll J. (2020) 15, no. 1, 12&#x2013;15, 10.3329/fmcj.v15i1.49001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3329/fmcj.v15i1.49001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putri A. R., Arumndari R., Liman C. N., Suarca K., and Suryawan I. W. B., Neonatal Hypoglycemia and Associated Factors at Wangaya General Hospital, Indonesian Journal of Multidisciplinary Science. (2023) 3, no. 1, 49&#x2013;52, 10.55324/ijoms.v3i1.709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.55324/ijoms.v3i1.709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniji E., Kuti B., and Elusiyan J. B., Prevalence, Risk Factors, and Outcome of Hospitalization of Neonatal Hyperglycemia at a Nigerian Health Facility, Nigerian Journal of Clinical Practice. (2020) 23, no. 1, 71&#x2013;78, 10.4103/njcp.njcp_229_19, 31929210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/njcp.njcp_229_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31929210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhananjaya C. and Kiran B., Clinical Profile of Hypoglycemia in Newborn Babies in a Rural Hospital Setting, International Journal of Biological and Medical Research. (2011) 2, no. 4, 1110&#x2013;1114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamkin D. H., Neonatal Hypoglycemia, Seminars in Fetal and Neonatal Medicine. (2017) 22, no. 1, 36&#x2013;41, 10.1016/j.siny.2016.08.007, 2-s2.0-84992388183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.siny.2016.08.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27605513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozance P. J., Garcia-Prats J., Wolfsdorf J., and Tehrani N., Pathogenesis, Screening, and Diagnosis of Neonatal Hypoglycemia, UpToDate. (2016) 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanardo V., Cagdas S., and Marzari F., Factors Associated With Neonatal Hypoglycemia in Premature Twins and Singletons, Acta geneticae medicae et gemellologiae: twin research. (1997) 46, no. 1, 69&#x2013;77, 10.1017/S0001566000000763, 2-s2.0-0030847533, 9298160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0001566000000763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9298160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>