<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41381540</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A novel deep learning based spatial ensemble approach and segment anything model for landslide risk assessment in Chamoli district of Garhwal Himalayas.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43592</StartPage><MedlinePgn>43592</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">43592</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-01958-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aims at introducing novel "Spatial Ensemble" approach for landslide risk assessment (LRA). For this purpose, the present work focuses on three different algorithms that includes a state-of-the-art deep learning DenseNet Neural Network, and 2 popular benchmark algorithms of MLPNN and XGBoost. The spatial ensemble approach in LRA focuses on generating two distinct types of&#xa0;"Landslide Impedance Composite Maps", where the first one predicts the broadest possible danger zones covering the maximum extent with potential landslide occurrences across the study area. The second map targets the places in all probability to encounter landslides, by demarcating specific locations with the greatest risk of landslide occurrences to prioritize accuracy and precision, making sure that areas with highest levels of risk receive detailed attention. The outcome of the second map has helped during field verification, leading to identification of a new landslide in close proximity of human settlements and buildings. It is a crucial finding as this study applies state-of-the-art auto-detection algorithm of Segment Anything Model (SAM) to detect buildings automatically in close proximity which is accurate and time-saving alternative to landslides, for risk assessment. And finally, a landslide risk zone is developed to delineate the building vulnerability around the landslide,&#xa0;which is validated against cracked buildings and presence of fault lines in the area. Thus, this research combines cutting-edge technologies with robust field observations,&#xa0;to introduce a novel and stepped approach of landslide risk assessment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mandal</LastName><ForeName>Sayantan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, Delhi School of Economics, University of Delhi, New Delhi, 110007, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saha</LastName><ForeName>Ashis Kumar</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geography, Delhi School of Economics, University of Delhi, New Delhi, 110007, India. aksaha@geography.du.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Joshimath</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Landslide impendence mapping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Segment anything model (SAM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial ensemble</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Informed consent: Informed consent has been obtained from all study participants and/or their legal guardians for the inclusion of identifying information and/or images in this manuscript. The consent includes permission for the publication of this information/images in an online open-access publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41381540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12698865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-01958-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-01958-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stanley, T. &amp; Kirschbaum, D. B. A heuristic approach to global landslide susceptibility mapping. <i>Nat. Hazards</i><b>87</b>, 145&#x2013;164 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-017-2757-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8051514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33867675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, S., Sarkar, S. &amp; Kanungo, D. P. A critical review on landslide susceptibility zonation: Recent trends, techniques, and practices in Indian Himalaya. <i>Nat. Hazards</i><b>115</b>, 23&#x2013;72 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11069-022-05554-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardeshi, S. D., Autade, S. E. &amp; Pardeshi, S. S. Landslide hazard assessment: Recent trends and techniques. <i>Springerplus</i><b>2</b>, 523 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2193-1801-2-523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25674398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thirugnanam, H. Deep Learning in Landslide Studies: A Review. in <i>Progress in Landslide Research and Technology, Volume 1 Issue 2, 2022</i> (eds. Alc&#xe1;ntara-Ayala, I. et al.) 247&#x2013;255 (Springer International Publishing, Cham, 2023). 10.1007/978-3-031-18471-0_20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, W. et al. Landslide susceptibility mapping and dynamic response along the Sichuan-Tibet transportation corridor using deep learning algorithms. <i>CATENA</i><b>222</b>, 106866 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2022.106866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S., Wang, L., Zhang, W., He, Y. &amp; Pijush, S. A comprehensive review of machine learning-based methods in landslide susceptibility mapping. <i>Geol. J.</i><b>58</b>, 2283&#x2013;2301 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gj.4666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agboola, G., Beni, L. H., Elbayoumi, T. &amp; Thompson, G. Optimizing landslide susceptibility mapping using machine learning and geospatial techniques. <i>Ecol. Inform.</i><b>81</b>, 102583 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoinf.2024.102583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha, S. et al. Application of RBF and MLP Neural Networks Integrating with Rotation Forest in Modeling Landslide Susceptibility of Sampheling, Bhutan. (Springer Singapore, 2022). 10.1007/978-981-16-7314-6_10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, M. A., Chen, Z., Zheng, Y., Zhou, Y. &amp; Daud, H. Deep learning and machine learning models for landslide susceptibility mapping with remote sensing data. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>15</b> (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan, N., Bao, Y., Shawon, A. &amp; Huang, Y. DenseNet convolutional neural networks application for predicting COVID-19 using CT Image. <i>SN Comput. Sci.</i><b>2</b>, 389 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42979-021-00782-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8300985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34337432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha, S. <i>et al.</i> Application of RBF and MLP neural networks integrating with rotation forest in modeling landslide susceptibility of sampheling, Bhutan. in <i>Impact of Climate Change, Land Use and Land Cover, and Socio-economic Dynamics on Landslides</i> (eds. Sarkar, R., Shaw, R. &amp; Pradhan, B.) 221&#x2013;245 (Springer Nature Singapore, Singapore, 2022). 10.1007/978-981-16-7314-6_10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Insights into geospatial heterogeneity of landslide susceptibility based on the SHAP-XGBoost model. <i>J. Environ. Manag.</i><b>332</b>, 117357 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2023.117357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong, H., Wang, D., Zhu, A. X. &amp; Wang, Y. Landslide susceptibility mapping based on the reliability of landslide and non-landslide sample. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>243</b>, 122933 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.122933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh, H.-J. &amp; Lee, S. Cross-application used to validate landslide susceptibility maps using a probabilistic model from Korea. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>64</b>, 395&#x2013;409 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-010-0864-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Q. Leafmap: A Python package for interactive mapping and geospatial analysis with minimal coding in a Jupyter environment. <i>J. Open Source Softw.</i><b>6</b>, 3414 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21105/joss.03414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirillov, A. <i>et al.</i> Segment anything. <i>Proc. IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision</i> 3992&#x2013;4003 (2023) 10.1109/ICCV51070.2023.00371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, X. <i>et al.</i> Research Progress on Few-Shot Learning for Remote Sensing Image Interpretation. <i>IEEE J. Sel. Top. Appl. Earth Obs. Remote Sens.</i><b>14</b>, 2387&#x2013;2402 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alayrac, J. B. <i>et al.</i> Flamingo: A visual language model for few-shot learning. <i>Adv. Neural Inf. Process. Syst.</i><b>35</b> (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D. <i>et al.</i> SAMRS: Scaling-up remote sensing segmentation dataset with segment anything model. in <i>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</i> (eds. Oh, A. et al.) vol. 36 8815&#x2013;8827 (Curran Associates, Inc., 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangeeta &amp; Maheshwari, B. K. Earthquake-induced landslide hazard assessment of Chamoli District, Uttarakhand using relative frequency ratio method. <i>Indian Geotech. J.</i><b>49</b>, 108&#x2013;123 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, A. Cenozoic tectonic evolution of the Himalayan orogen as constrained by along-strike variation of structural geometry, exhumation history, and foreland sedimentation. <i>Earth-Sci. Rev.</i><b>76</b>, 1&#x2013;131 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.earscirev.2005.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarafza, M., Azarafza, M., Akg&#xfc;n, H., Atkinson, P. M. &amp; Derakhshani, R. Deep learning-based landslide susceptibility mapping. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>11</b>, 24112 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-03585-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34916586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Fang, Z., Wang, M., Peng, L. &amp; Hong, H. Comparative study of landslide susceptibility mapping with different recurrent neural networks. <i>Comput. Geosci.</i><b>138</b>, 104445 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cageo.2020.104445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bookhagen, B. &amp; Burbank, D. W. Toward a complete Himalayan hydrological budget: Spatiotemporal distribution of snowmelt and rainfall and their impact on river discharge. <i>J. Geophys. Res. Earth Surf.</i><b>115</b> (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Google Earth. https://earth.google.com/web/@0,-2.814,0a,22251752.77375655d,35y,0h,0t,0r/data=OgMKATA (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhukosh. https://bhukosh.gsi.gov.in/Bhukosh/Public (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youssef, A. M. &amp; Pourghasemi, H. R. Landslide susceptibility mapping using machine learning algorithms and comparison of their performance at Abha Basin, Asir Region, Saudi Arabia. <i>Geosci. Front.</i><b>12</b>, 639&#x2013;655 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gsf.2020.05.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y. &amp; Newsam, S. DenseNet for dense flow. in <i>2017 IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP)</i> 790&#x2013;794 (2017). 10.1109/ICIP.2017.8296389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, G., Liu, Z. &amp; Weinberger, K. Densely Connected Convolutional Networks. (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin, E. K. Implementation of free and open-source semi-automatic feature engineering tool in landslide susceptibility mapping using the machine-learning algorithms RF, SVM, and XGBoost. <i>Stoch. Environ. Res. Risk Assess.</i><b>37</b>, 1067&#x2013;1092 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00477-022-02330-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahin, E. K. Assessing the predictive capability of ensemble tree methods for landslide susceptibility mapping using XGBoost, gradient boosting machine, and random forest. <i>SN Appl. Sci.</i><b>2</b>, 1&#x2013;17 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42452-020-3060-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham, B. T., Tien Bui, D., Prakash, I. &amp; Dholakia, M. B. Hybrid integration of Multilayer Perceptron Neural Networks and machine learning ensembles for landslide susceptibility assessment at Himalayan area (India) using GIS. <i>Catena</i><b>149</b>, 52&#x2013;63 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, T. et al. Assessing the imperative of conditioning factor grading in machine learning-based landslide susceptibility modeling: A critical inquiry. <i>CATENA</i><b>236</b>, 107732 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2023.107732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W., He, Y., Wang, L., Liu, S. &amp; Meng, X. Landslide Susceptibility mapping using random forest and extreme gradient boosting: A case study of Fengjie, Chongqing. <i>Geol. J.</i><b>58</b>, 2372&#x2013;2387 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gj.4683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennifer, J. J. Feature elimination and comparison of machine learning algorithms in landslide susceptibility mapping. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>81</b>, 1&#x2013;23 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-022-10620-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, B. et al. PAM-DenseNet: A Deep convolutional neural network for computer-aided COVID-19 diagnosis. <i>IEEE Trans. Cybern.</i><b>52</b>, 12163&#x2013;12174 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TCYB.2020.3042837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34428169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, K., Guo, Y., Wang, X., Yuan, J. &amp; Ding, Q. Multiple feature reweight DenseNet for image classification. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>7</b>, 9872&#x2013;9880 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2018.2890127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Z., Zhu, X., Ding, M. &amp; Zhang, X. Medical image classification using a light-weighted hybrid neural network based on PCANet and DenseNet. <i>IEEE Access</i><b>8</b>, 24697&#x2013;24712 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2971225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osco, L. P. et al. The segment anything model (SAM) for remote sensing applications: From zero to one shot. <i>Int. J. Appl. Earth Obs. Geoinf.</i><b>124</b>, 103540 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J. &amp; Kim, Y. Integrated framework for unsupervised building segmentation with segment anything model-based pseudo-labeling and weakly supervised learning. <i>Remote Sens.</i><b>16</b> (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arabameri, A., Pourghasemi, H. R. &amp; Yamani, M. Applying different scenarios for landslide spatial modeling using computational intelligence methods. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>76</b>, 832 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-017-7177-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dick, F. &amp; Tevaearai, H. Significance and Limitations of the p Value. <i>Eur.J. Vasc. Endovasc. Surg.&#x202f;</i><b>50</b>, 815. 10.1016/j.ejvs.2015.07.026 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26342862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torabi Haghighi, A. et al. Land degradation risk mapping using topographic, human-induced, and geo-environmental variables and machine learning algorithms, for the Pole-Doab watershed, Iran. <i>Environ. Earth Sci.</i><b>80</b>, 1 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-020-09327-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Google. Google Collab. https://colab.google/ (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awasthi, S. et al. Analyzing Joshimath&#x2019;s sinking: Causes, consequences, and future prospects with remote sensing techniques. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 10876 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-60276-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11091150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38740810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>