<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41916437</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-1632</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The spine journal : official journal of the North American Spine Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Spine J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A nomogram prediction model for lumbar disc herniation recurrence after percutaneous endoscopic lumbar discectomy: a multicenter retrospective study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1529-9430(26)00097-5</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.spinee.2026.03.007</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recurrent lumbar disc herniation (rLDH) is a common postoperative complication after percutaneous endoscopic lumbar discectomy (PELD), with recurrence rates reported between 5% and 21%. Identifying patients at risk remains a critical clinical need, yet few predictive models exist to guide prevention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To develop and externally validate a predictive nomogram model for rLDH following PELD, based on preoperative clinical and imaging parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN/SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">A multicenter retrospective cohort study using data from four hospitals in China.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENT SAMPLE" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 3,610 patients who underwent PELD for L4-L5 or L5-S1 disc herniation were included. The training cohort comprised 2,436 patients from two centers between January 2012 and December 2021. The external validation cohort included 1,174 patients from two additional centers between January 2012 and December 2021.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">The primary outcome was the occurrence of rLDH, defined as symptom recurrence at the operated level after a pain-free interval of at least two weeks. Predictive accuracy was assessed using area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC), calibration curves, and decision curve analysis (DCA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Independent risk factors for rLDH were identified using multivariate logistic regression after variable selection with the LASSO algorithm. A nomogram was constructed based on the final model. Internal validation was performed using bootstrap resampling. External validation was conducted in a separate patient cohort. This study received no external funding. The authors declare that no financial support was obtained for the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Younger age (OR per year increase 0.972, 95% CI 0.956-0.988), Modic type I (OR 1.650, 95% CI 1.075-2.607) and type II (OR 5.755, 95% CI 3.702-9.202) changes, smaller multifidus cross-sectional area (CSA) (OR 0.900, 95% CI 0.864-0.937), excessive lumbar lordosis (OR 1.033, 95% CI 1.019-1.049), and larger facet joint orientation (OR 1.047, 95% CI 1.031-1.064) were independent predictors of rLDH. The nomogram demonstrated good discriminative ability in both the training cohort (AUC&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.755) and validation cohort (AUC&#x202f;=&#x202f;0.831), with satisfactory calibration and clinical utility supported by DCA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We developed and externally validated a nomogram model to predict rLDH after PELD using readily available preoperative variables. This tool may assist spine surgeons in early risk stratification and tailored postoperative management; however, as this was a retrospective study, prospective validation and inclusion of intraoperative variables are still needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Kaiyuan</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, 76 Nanguo Road, Beilin District, Xi'an 710054, Shaanxi, China.. Electronic address: kaiyuanlin1208@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Junsong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, 76 Nanguo Road, Beilin District, Xi'an 710054, Shaanxi, China.. Electronic address: vheymqk61@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Tuanjiang</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, 76 Nanguo Road, Beilin District, Xi'an 710054, Shaanxi, China.. Electronic address: dhxzrii74@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Jianmin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Minimally Invasive Spinal Surgery, Xi'an International Medical Center Hospital, 777 Xitai Road, High-tech Zone, Xi'an 710000, Shaanxi, China.. Electronic address: uykfnthn7@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, Hanzhong 3201 Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, 783 Tianhan Avenue, Hantai District, Hanzhong 723000, Shaanxi, China.. Electronic address: hnjkvi979@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Spine Surgery Center, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, 76 Linjiang Road, Yuzhong District, Chongqing 400010, China.. Electronic address: waacihii0@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Yutong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Spine Surgery Center, Zhongshan Hospital of Fudan University, No.180 Fenglin Road, Shanghai, 200032, China.. Electronic address: ohygc6077@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abudouaini</LastName><ForeName>Haimiti</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Spine Surgery, Honghui Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University, 76 Nanguo Road, Beilin District, Xi'an 710054, Shaanxi, China.. Electronic address: ktlir1983@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Spine J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101130732</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1529-9430</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percutaneous endoscopic lumbar discectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction nomogram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recurrent lumbar disc herniation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factor</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interests None of the authors have conflicts of interest to disclose. None of the authors have financial relationships relevant to this article to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41916437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spinee.2026.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1529-9430(26)00097-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>