<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41714765</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on stability analysis and control technology of roadways in the underlying isolated island working face.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9903</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-40307-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The mining of isolated working faces beneath close coal seams is influenced by the overlying goaf, the lateral abutment pressure from adjacent goafs, and the dynamic pressures arising from the preparatory mining operation. The deformation and failure characteristics of the surrounding rock in the roadway show significant variability, especially in sections beneath goaf areas and residual coal pillars, making it difficult to apply a conventional support strategy. This work adopts theoretical analysis, numerical simulations, and field observations to investigate roadway deformation and stability in the underlying isolated island working face according to the geological conditions of the Yanghuopan coal mine in Shaanxi province, China. The results indicate that the stress transfer from the residual pillar beneath the 2<sup>-2</sup> coal seam influences the 3<sup>-1</sup> coal seam up to a distance of 62.1&#xa0;m, with a stress transfer coefficient of 1.6 directly beneath the coal pillar. The vertical stress in the 3<sup>-1</sup> coal seam is distributed across five distinct regions. The 30,119 working face traverses all five regions, with the vertical stress on the coal pillar and surrounding rock deformation reaching their maximum in the regions affected by the concentrated stress of the 1# and 2# residual coal pillars. Stress concentration is significantly reduced beneath the goaf of the 20,201 and 20,202 panels. Based on these findings, a corresponding stability control scheme was developed. The conventional support zone beneath the goafs and the original rock stress region of the 20,201 and 20,202 working faces, and the reinforced support zone within the influence of the residual coal pillars. Field observations, including surface displacement, anchor forces, and internal coal pillar deformation, validated the effectiveness of the combined support system and ensured safe production during isolated island working face mining.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Mining Engineering, Xi'an University of Science and Technology, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yaowei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Mining Engineering, Xi'an University of Science and Technology, Xi'an, 710054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Ming</ForeName><Initials>YM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Mining Engineering, Xi'an University of Science and Technology, Xi'an, 710054, China. yiming.li@xust.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Deep Earth Sciences and Geothermal Energy Exploitation and Utilization, Shenzhen University, Shenzhen, 518060, China. yiming.li@xust.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52404141</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China Youth Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024MD753978</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DESGEEU-2024-01</GrantID><Agency>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Deep Earth Sciences and Geothermal Energy Exploitation and Utilization</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Close coal seams</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combined support system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Field monitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Isolated island working face</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Numerical simulations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Roadway stability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41714765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13018221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40307-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-40307-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S., Wang, X., Fan, G., Zhang, D. &amp; Cui, J. Pillar size optimization design of isolated island panel gob-side entry driving in deep inclined coal seam-case study of Pingmei No. 6 coal seam. <i>J. Geophys. Eng.</i><b>15</b>, 816&#x2013;828 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-2140/aaa148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, Y. et al. Strata movement and mining-induced stress identification for an isolated working face surrounded by two goafs. <i>Energies</i>10.3390/en16062839 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en16062839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T. et al. Impact hazard analysis of islanding face mining based on micro-seismic monitoring and shock wave CT inversion. <i>J. Geophys. Eng.</i><b>22</b>, 520&#x2013;531 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jge/gxae130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, G., Mu, Z., Chen, J., Yang, J. &amp; Cao, J. Rock burst risk in an island longwall coal face by stress field. <i>Geosci. J.</i><b>22</b>, 609&#x2013;622 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12303-017-0074-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W., Wu, Y., Shi, Y. &amp; Zhu, J. Outburst mechanism and hazard prevention technique of limestone aquifer under isolated island panels. <i>Front. Earth Sci.</i>10.3389/feart.2024.1532515 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2024.1532515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. et al. Failure mechanism and control technology of soft-rock roadways subjected to high structural stress. <i>Front. Earth Sci.</i><b>12</b>, 1473108 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2024.1473108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Study on the law of mine pressure manifestation in three-soft coal seam isolated working face. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>15</b>, 1943 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app15041943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, Y. et al. Analysis of stress and deformation on surrounding rock mass of a trapezoidal roadway in a large inclination coal seam and novel high yielding prop support: A case study. <i>Mathematics</i><b>11</b>, 319 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math11020319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, C. et al. Mining pressure distribution law and disaster prevention of isolated island working face under the condition of hard &#x2018;Umbrella Arch&#x2019;. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>57</b>, 8323&#x2013;8341 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-024-03961-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y.-M. et al. A benchmark study of different numerical methods for predicting rock failure. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>166</b>, 105381 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2023.105381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Chen, P. &amp; Wang, S. Study of overlying rock structure and intensive pressure control technology of island longwall panel in extra-thick coal seams. <i>Processes</i>10.3390/pr11113083 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11113083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, Y. et al. Study on failure characteristics and control technology of roadway surrounding rock under repeated mining in close-distance coal seam. <i>Mathematics</i><b>10</b>, 2166 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/math10132166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, J., Xu, J. &amp; Wang, F. Mining-induced stress distribution of the working face in a kilometer-deep coal mine&#x2014;a case study in Tangshan coal mine. <i>J. Geophys. Eng.</i><b>15</b>, 2060&#x2013;2070 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-2140/aabc6c</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, N., Bai, J. &amp; Yoo, C. Failure mechanism and control technology of deep soft-rock roadways: Numerical simulation and field study. <i>Underground Space</i><b>12</b>, 1&#x2013;17 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.undsp.2023.02.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, W. et al. Research on reasonable width of coal pillars of non-equal width isolated working face heading goaf in deep mine. <i>Geotech. Geol. Eng.</i><b>40</b>, 1295&#x2013;1306 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10706-021-01963-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, B. et al. Optimisation research on a thin coal seam isolated island coal face mining back channel layout and its support parameters. <i>Int. J. Oil Gas Coal Technol.</i><b>31</b>, 297&#x2013;315 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1504/IJOGCT.2022.126371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y.-M., Li, J.-L., Wu, Y. &amp; Zhao, G.-F. Extracting rock parameters through digital drilling test. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>57</b>, 8215&#x2013;8241 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-024-03951-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, A., Li, Y., Shoaib, M., Sajjad, U. &amp; Rui, F. Utilizing machine learning and digital twin technology for rock parameter estimation from drilling data. <i>J. Intell. Constr.</i><b>3</b>, 9180088 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y.-M. &amp; Zhao, G.-F. A numerical integrated approach for the estimation of the uniaxial compression strength of rock from point load tests. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>148</b>, 104939 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2021.104939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q., Zuo, Y. &amp; Zheng, L. Deformation failure mechanism and stability-control technology of deep layered clastic-rock roadway under dynamic disturbance. <i>Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol.</i>10.1016/j.tust.2024.106255 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.106255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, D. et al. Influence of strength inhomogeneity on transboundary expansion characteristics of hydraulically fractured fractures in coal seams. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, 29094 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-80588-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11586439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39582082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni, H. et al. Effect of mining-induced abutment pressure on gateroad and grouting-based bolting technology: A case study. <i>Eng. Fail. Anal.</i>10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107421 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2023.107421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, J. et al. Evolution laws of stress-energy and progressive damage mechanisms of surrounding rock induced by mining disturbance. <i>Appl. Sci.</i>10.3390/app13137759 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13137759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, A. et al. Analysis of rockburst hazard and optimization of prevention and control measures in multi-seam mining based on refined numerical simulations. <i>Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ.</i>10.1007/s10064-025-04591-7 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-025-04591-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, C., Yang, H., Zhang, N., Deng, R. &amp; Guo, Y. Zoning control technology of gob-side roadway driving with small coal pillar facing mining in a special isolated island working face: A case study. <i>Appl. Sci.</i>10.3390/app112210744 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app112210744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, W., Jing, G., Ma, L., Zhao, L. &amp; Wang, S. Research on blasting technology for thick and hard roof fracturing in isolated island coal mine working face. <i>Sci. Rep.</i>10.1038/s41598-025-98911-2 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-98911-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12032078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40281198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, H. et al. Study on the energy evolution mechanism and fractal characteristics of coal failure under dynamic loading. <i>ACS Omega</i><b>10</b>, 54710&#x2013;54719 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c08162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12631684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41280835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, B., Liu, S., Zeng, S., Wang, S. &amp; Wang, S. Dynamic characteristics and fractal representations of crack propagation of rock with different fissures under multiple impact loadings. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>11</b>, 13071 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-92277-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8219689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34158549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, P., Fan, H., Liu, H., Jin, K. &amp; Zhong, H. Experimental study on energy evolution and damage characteristics of unloading coal under cyclic loading. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 16630 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-01118-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12075643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40360642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C., Ji, H., Fu, Z. &amp; Zhang, Y. Analysis of fracture characteristics and energy evolution of tectonic coal after loading based on acoustic emission. <i>Measurement</i><b>252</b>, 117388 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2025.117388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>