<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41694858</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inter-observer and Intra-observer Reproducibility for the Determination of Female Urethral Narrowing on Voiding Cystourethrogram: A Retrospective Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e101464</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e101464</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e101464</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.101464</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background The voiding cystourethrogram (VCUG) is used in women to evaluate the anatomy of the lower urinary tract. Once common for detecting reflux, urethral mobility, and diverticula, its use in adults has declined. However, VCUG remains valuable in urogynecology and reconstructive pelvic surgery (URPS) by identifying structural causes of recurrent urinary tract infections (RUTI), such as urethral pathology. Objective The main objective of this study is to evaluate the inter and intra-observer variability among radiologist interpretations of urethral caliber and narrowing on VCUG. Methods Following IRB approval, 83 VCUG cases performed on non-neurogenic women between 18 and 85 years old, and without prolapse &gt;stage 2, were identified retrospectively from a tertiary care urology clinic between January and July 2023. All studies were performed in the upright sagittal oblique projection. Each image was independently reviewed by four abdominal fellowship-trained radiologists, who judged whether each urethra was narrow or not. If narrow, the rater noted severity (mild, moderate, severe) and location (proximal, mid, distal). The Shrout-Fleiss reliability statistic for a fixed set of raters (intra-class correlation (ICC): 3, k) was then calculated for the presence or absence of narrowing. Results In 50/83 (60%) of cases, all raters agreed on whether the urethra was narrow. Majority agreement (at least three of four raters) was present in 75/83 (90%) of cases. The ICC (3, k) was 0.79 for the reliability of the four scores. For the 61 cases rated as narrow by at least three of the four radiologists, the majority agreed on the degree of severity in 43/61 (70%; ICC = 0.89) of cases, and on location in 51/61 (84%; ICC = 0.43) of cases. Conclusion To our knowledge, this is the first study to assess the inter-reader reproducibility of urethral narrowing on standing VCUG in women with lower urinary tract symptomatology. A majority agreement was reached on urethral narrowing, including its location and severity. Correlating VCUG findings with clinical data will help establish a standardized radiologic definition of urethral narrowing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Zone et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zone</LastName><ForeName>Alea I</ForeName><Initials>AI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carlton</LastName><ForeName>Caitlin E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Kinani</LastName><ForeName>Mortadha</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khatri</LastName><ForeName>Gaurav</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>Kristen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Theresa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christie</LastName><ForeName>Alana L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zimmern</LastName><ForeName>Philippe E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urethral narrowing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urethral stricture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urogynecology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vcug</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">voiding cystourethrogram</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41694858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12900545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.101464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Radiation exposure during standing voiding cystourethrography in women. Arbique GM, Gilleran JP, Guild JB, Harris JE, Poon CI, Zimmern PE. Urology. 2006;67:269&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standing cystourethrogram: an outcome measure after anti-incontinence procedures and cystocele repair in women. Showalter PR, Zimmern PE, Roehrborn CG, Lemack GE. Urology. 2001;58:33&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SEAPI QMM incontinence classification system. Raz S, Erickson DR. Neurourol Urodyn. 1992;11:187&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15098217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bladder prolapse configuration on baseline standing cystogram can predict anterior vaginal wall suspension procedure outcomes. Wu YR, Christie AL, Lavelle RS, Alhalabi F, Khatri G, Zimmern PE. Urology. 2017;103:73&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28188759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blander DS, Zimmern PE. Female Pelvic Reconstructive Surgery. London: Springer; 2003. Diagnosis and management of female urethral diverticula and urethrovaginal fistula; pp. 299&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Distal intramural urethral pathology in women. Romman AN, Alhalabi F, Zimmern PE. J Urol. 2012;188:1218&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22902013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term functional outcomes following non-radiated urethrovaginal fistula repair. Lee D, Zimmern PE. World J Urol. 2016;34:291&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26049863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaginal approach to vesicovaginal fistula. Lee D, Zimmern P. Urol Clin North Am. 2019;46:123&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30466697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urethral distortion after placement of synthetic mid urethral sling. Murray S, Haverkorn RM, Koch YK, Lemack GE, Zimmern PE. J Urol. 2011;185:1321&#x2013;1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Structural support of the urethra as it relates to stress urinary incontinence: the hammock hypothesis. DeLancey JO. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1994;170:1713&#x2013;1720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8203431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines, criteria, and rules of thumb for evaluating normed and standardized assessment instruments in psychology. Cicchetti DV. Psychol Assess. 1994;6:284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urethral stricture disease guideline amendment. Wessells H, Morey A, Souter L, Rahimi L, Vanni A. J Urol. 2023;210:64&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37096574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACR Appropriateness Criteria&#xae; pelvic floor dysfunction in females. Khatri G, Bhosale PR, Robbins JB, et al. J Am Coll Radiol. 2022;19:0&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35550798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A machine learning-based approach for quantitative grading of vesicoureteral reflux from voiding cystourethrograms: methods and proof of concept. Khondker A, Kwong JC, Rickard M, Skreta M, Keefe DT, Lorenzo AJ, Erdman L. J Pediatr Urol. 2022;18:78&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34736872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>