<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41850207</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-8630</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>404</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of environmental management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Environ Manage</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Eco-hydrological thresholds of vegetation transition from groundwater-dependent to non-dependent in a hyper-arid endorheic basin.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>129398</StartPage><MedlinePgn>129398</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jenvman.2026.129398</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0301-4797(26)00858-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Defining precise ecological boundaries and setting clear hydrological benchmarks are critical for achieving sustainable management of groundwater-dependent vegetation (GDV), which plays a vital role in both ecologically significant and highly fragile ecosystems. However, accurately identifying these thresholds remains a complex task. This study applied a space-for-time substitution approach to investigate the eco-hydrological thresholds governing vegetation transitions from GDV to non-GDV states in the hyper-arid Shule River Basin of northwestern China. Extensive vegetation surveys were conducted across approximately 30,000&#xa0;km<sup>2</sup>, encompassing diverse environmental gradients within the study region. The survey included 256 systematically sampled plots to ensure robust data representation. Using a combination of diversity indices (species, functional, and phylogenetic), cluster analysis delineated five distinct vegetation communities, with altitude and water table depth (WTD) emerging as the strongest drivers of community composition. Threshold Indicator Taxon Analysis (TITAN) identified twelve plant species-five responding negatively and seven positively to WTD gradients-as effective indicators for distinguishing between GDVs, non-GDVs, and their transitional states along hydrological gradients. The study revealed critical transition zones at WTD ranges of 9.16 to 11.04&#xa0;m, with a 90% confidence interval extending from 3.79 to 15.41&#xa0;m. These thresholds are intricately linked with the varying adaptive capabilities of the indicator plant species to WTD gradients, marking the hydrological boundaries between GDVs and non-GDVs. The shallower and deeper zones indicate the niche optima WTD for the GDVs and non-GDVs, respectively. Thus, for practical groundwater regulation, managers should interpret the thresholds by incorporating both the biotic indicators and their associated WTD intervals into adaptive management strategies. This study presents a reproducible TITAN-based methodology for determining dryland vegetation thresholds, with the identified eco-hydrological thresholds offering valuable scientific insights for regime-shift warning systems and conservation planning, and informing sustainable groundwater management strategies in arid regions globally.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ecological Safety and Sustainable Development in Arid Lands, Northwest Institute of Eco-Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Lanzhou, 730000, China; Linze Inland River Basin Research Station, Chinese Ecosystem Research Network, Lanzhou, 730000, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ecological Safety and Sustainable Development in Arid Lands, Northwest Institute of Eco-Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Lanzhou, 730000, China; Linze Inland River Basin Research Station, Chinese Ecosystem Research Network, Lanzhou, 730000, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100029, China. Electronic address: lhayz@lzb.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Wenzhi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ecological Safety and Sustainable Development in Arid Lands, Northwest Institute of Eco-Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Lanzhou, 730000, China; Linze Inland River Basin Research Station, Chinese Ecosystem Research Network, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Shuhong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hydrogeology and Environmental Geology, Chinese Academy of Geological Sciences, Shijiazhuang, 050057, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jintao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Hydrology-Water Resources and Hydraulic Engineering, Hohai University, Nanjing, 210098, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Hydraulics and Mountain River Engineering, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Lihe</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Engineering Research Center on Water Resources &amp; Environment, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China; Xi'an Center of Geological Survey, China Geological Survey, Xi'an, 710054, Shaanxi, China. Electronic address: ylihe@cgs.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yetemen</LastName><ForeName>Omer</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eurasia Institute of Earth Sciences, Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Environ Manage</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401664</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0301-4797</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drylands</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eco-hydrological thresholds</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Groundwater-dependent vegetation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrological threshold zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Threshold indicator species</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vegetation surveys</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41850207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2026.129398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0301-4797(26)00858-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>