<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41703538</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6963</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC health services research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Health Serv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health promotion strategies among pharmacists in Nigeria: perceptions, attitudes, and challenges.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">396</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12913-026-14217-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Nigeria faces a dual burden of communicable and non-communicable diseases, placing considerable strain on the healthcare system. Pharmacists, as accessible healthcare providers, are well-positioned to promote health and prevent diseases; however, their potential remains underutilized. This study assessed pharmacists&#x2019; health promotion strategies, perceptions, and attitudes, identified predictors of perception and attitude, and examined challenges affecting implementation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A descriptive cross-sectional survey was conducted among 383 community and hospital pharmacists across Nigeria between December 2024 and April 2025 using convenience and snowball sampling. A structured questionnaire assessed socio-demographics, health promotion strategies, perceptions, attitudes, and barriers. Perception and attitude scores were categorized based on median values. Data were analysed using SPSS v27. Descriptive statistics summarized responses, while the Fisher&#x2013;Freeman&#x2013;Halton exact test and multiple linear regression identified associations and predictors of pharmacists&#x2019; perceptions and attitudes toward health promotion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Overall, 351 (91.6%) pharmacists reported participation in health promotion activities, particularly interprofessional collaboration (345, 98.3%) and adherence counselling (343, 97.7%). Most pharmacists had positive perception (375, 97.9%) and attitude (371, 96.9%) toward health promotion. Key barriers included lack of training (234, 61.1%), inadequate consultation space (251, 65.5%), and limited patient time (271, 70.8%). Significant predictors of perception and attitude included age, gender, years of experience, additional qualifications, location of practice, and geopolitical zone. Specifically, younger pharmacists (21&#x2013;30 years) had higher perception (B&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.18, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.046) but lower attitude (B = &#x2212;&#x2009;2.27, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) scores than those aged 31&#x2013;40 years. Male pharmacists had lower perception scores than females (B = &#x2212;&#x2009;1.31, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.010). Rural practitioners had lower perception (B = &#x2212;&#x2009;2.68, <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) but higher attitude (B&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.79, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.014) scores than urban counterparts. Pharmacists in North Central (B&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.36, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.030) and South West zones (B&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.99, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.042) demonstrated higher perception scores compared with North West practitioners while area of practice was not significantly associated with perception (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.458) or attitude (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.763).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Pharmacists in Nigeria demonstrated positive perception and attitude toward health promotion but faced systemic and resource challenges. Professional experience, qualifications, and geopolitical location significantly influenced the pharmacists&#x2019; perception and attitude. Targeted training, policy support, and infrastructural investment are essential to enhance pharmacists&#x2019; contribution to preventive healthcare and public health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL NUMBER">Not applicable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12913-026-14217-7.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orok</LastName><ForeName>Edidiong</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5273-1927</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy and Public Health, College of Pharmacy, Afe Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti State, Nigeria. pharmorok@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ariyo</LastName><ForeName>Eniola</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy and Public Health, College of Pharmacy, Afe Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ogundipe</LastName><ForeName>Mary</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy and Public Health, College of Pharmacy, Afe Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Showande</LastName><ForeName>Segun Johnson</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy and Public Health, College of Pharmacy, Afe Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy and Pharmacy Practice, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ekada</LastName><ForeName>Inimuvie</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pharmacy and Public Health, College of Pharmacy, Afe Babalola University, Ado-Ekiti, Ekiti State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Health Serv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6963</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health promotion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nigeria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacy practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical clearance was obtained from Afe Babalola Multisystem Hospital Health Research Ethics Committee (AMSHREC) with approval number AMSH/REC/25/081 before the research was conducted. Participant eligibility was assessed based on study inclusion criteria after which a written informed consent was obtained before enrolment into the study. The confidentiality of the information they gave was maintained. This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41703538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13019989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-026-14217-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12913-026-14217-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adebayo A, Naima N, Kenneth Y, Shalkur D, Comfort S. Assessment of community pharmacists&#x2019; perceived barriers and disadvantages in providing health promotion services in Jos, Nigeria. World J Pharm Sci. 2015;3(6):1050&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David UA, Oparah AC. Evaluating pharmacist level of involvement in disease prevention activities in Nigeria. Pharm Biosci J. 2017;5(4):55&#x2013;61. 10.20510/ukjpb/5/i4/166546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20510/ukjpb/5/i4/166546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Health promotion. World Health Organization. 2022. https://www.who.int/health-topics/health-promotion. Accessed 8 Feb 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Offu O, Anetoh M, Okonta M, Ekwunife O. Engaging Nigerian community pharmacists in public health programs: assessment of their knowledge, attitude and practice in Enugu metropolis. J Pharm Policy Pract. 2015;8(1):27. 10.1186/s40545-015-0048-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40545-015-0048-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4638028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26557368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirdel F, Shamsi M, Najimi A, Zamanian H. Role of community pharmacists in health promotion and disease prevention: A review. J Educ Health Promot. 2021;10:123. 10.4103/jehp.jehp_977_20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jehp.jehp_977_20</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenor JE, Bowles SK. Evidence for pharmacist vaccination. Can Pharm J (Ott). 2018;151(5):301&#x2013;4. 10.1177/1715163518783000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1715163518783000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6344972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31080529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gheewala PA, Peterson GM, Zaidi STR, Jose MD, Castelino RL. Australian community pharmacists&#x2019; experience of implementing a chronic kidney disease risk assessment service. Prev Chronic Dis. 2018;15:E88. 10.5888/pcd15.170485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5888/pcd15.170485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6016429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29908050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniyi MA, Nasir N, Yakubu K, Sariem C. Assessment of community pharmacists&#x2019; perceived barriers and disadvantages in providing health promotion. World J Pharm Sci. 2015;3(6):1050&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oseni TO, Afolabi MA. Development and evaluation of a health promotion training program for community pharmacists in Oyo State, Nigeria. Int J Pharm Pract. 2020;28(3):241&#x2013;8. 10.1111/ijpp.12557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijpp.12557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saka SA, Ali MM. Pharmacists&#x2019; knowledge and practice regarding immunization in Ogun State, Southwest Nigeria. West Afr J Pharm. 2021;32(2):100&#x2013;12. 10.60787/wapcp-32-2-233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.60787/wapcp-32-2-233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nsengimana A, Biracyaza E, Hategekimana JC, Tuyishimire J, Nyiligira J, Rutembesa E. Attitudes, perceptions, and barriers of community pharmacists in Rwanda towards health promotion: A cross-sectional study. Arch Public Health. 2022;80:149. 10.1186/s13690-022-00912-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-022-00912-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9217721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35733223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oparah AC, Okojie OO. Health promotion perceptions among community pharmacists in Nigeria. Int J Pharm Pract. 2005;13(3):213&#x2013;21. 10.1211/ijpp.13.3.0007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1211/ijpp.13.3.0007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odukoya OO, Akande TM, Adefolalu AF. Attitudes, practices, and barriers to pharmacist-led smoking cessation services in Lagos State, Nigeria. BMC Public Health. 2016;16:1092. 10.1186/s12889-016-3692-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3692-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osemene KP, Erhun WO. Evaluation of community pharmacists&#x2019; involvement in public health activities in Nigeria. Braz J Pharm Sci. 2018;54(3):e17447. 10.1590/s2175-97902018000317447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/s2175-97902018000317447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunyinka I, Yusuff K, Erah PO, Oshikoya K, Faponle F, Ungo-Kore H, et al. Community pharmacists&#x2019; knowledge and attitudes toward pediatric pain management in Nigeria. Risk Manag Healthc Policy. 2021;14:4595&#x2013;607. 10.2147/rmhp.s329387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/rmhp.s329387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8593593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34795543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaeze O, Akinola A, Aiyeolemi A, Lawal F, Ijomone O, Mbata U. Community pharmacists&#x2019; services during the COVID-19 pandemic: A case study of Lagos State, Nigeria. J Res Pharm Pract. 2022;11(1):25&#x2013;30. 10.4103/jrpp.jrpp_5_22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jrpp.jrpp_5_22</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9585806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36277966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akande-Sholabi W, Akinbitan AA, Adebisi YA. Public health activities: evaluation of community pharmacists&#x2019; attitude, practice and barriers in a Nigerian Southwestern state. Malays J Pharm Sci. 2023;21(1):135&#x2013;47. 10.21315/mjps2023.21.1.9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21315/mjps2023.21.1.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adejoro L, Punch Newspapers. One pharmacist serves 13,385 Nigerians, PCN laments. 2023 Sep 2. https://punchng.com/one-pharmacist-serves-13385-nigerians-pcn-laments/. Accessed 8 Feb 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekpenyong A, Udoh A, Kpokiri E, Bates I. An analysis of pharmacy workforce capacity in Nigeria. J Pharm Policy Pract. 2018;11:20. 10.1186/s40545-018-0147-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40545-018-0147-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6120071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30186611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ipingbemi AE, Erhun WO, Adisa R. Pharmacist-led intervention in treatment non-adherence and associated direct costs of management among ambulatory patients with type 2 diabetes in Southwestern Nigeria. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21:1000. 10.1186/s12913-021-06979-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-021-06979-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayogu O, Oladapo OA, Okpala L. Effectiveness of a pharmacist-led educational intervention on hypertension management in Nigerian community pharmacies: A two-arm, parallel, single-blind randomized controlled trial. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2022;47(5):826&#x2013;34. 10.1111/jcpt.13567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpt.13567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubakar U, Tangiisuran B. Nationwide survey of pharmacists&#x2019; involvement in antimicrobial stewardship programs in Nigerian tertiary hospitals. J Glob Antimicrob Resist. 2019;19:118&#x2013;23. 10.1016/j.jgar.2019.10.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgar.2019.10.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31628999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedima EW, Okoro RN. Primary health care roles of community pharmacists in low- and middle-income countries: A mixed methods systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2025;25(1):1269. 10.1186/s12913-025-13387-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-025-13387-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12487115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41034858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayenew W, Seid AM, Kasahun AE, Ergena AE, Geremaw DT, Limenh LW, Demelash TB, Simegn W, Anagaw YK. Assessment of community pharmacy professionals&#x2019; willingness, involvement, beliefs, and barriers to offer health promotion services: A cross-sectional study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2022;22(1):1539. 10.1186/s12913-022-08944-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-022-08944-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9758862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36527057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmacy Council of Nigeria. About &#x2013; PCN &#x2013; Pharmacy Council of Nigeria. Pharmacy Council of Nigeria. 2024. https://pcn.gov.ng/about-pharmacy-council-nigeria/. Accessed 8 Feb 2026.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>