<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41933153</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Revisiting the application of variable infiltration capacity (VIC) model in the Colorado River Basin using SMAP and GRACE.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-47430-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Colorado River Basin (CRB) is a crucial water supply source experiencing prolonged drought conditions. Hydrologic models of the CRB have historically relied on streamflow calibration alone, limiting confidence in their representation of spatially distributed hydrologic processes. Here, we implemented a calibration and multi-source evaluation framework for the Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) model using observations from ground snow stations, streamflow records, and NASA's Soil Moisture Active Passive (SMAP) and Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE) missions. After model calibration with snow and streamflow records, VIC achieved an excellent streamflow performance at key sub-basin outlets in the CRB (e.g., Nash-Sutcliffe Efficiency of 0.96 in the Upper Basin). Independent evaluations with SMAP further revealed a strong model performance in reproducing surface (R<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.71) and root-zone (R<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.81) soil moisture, with systematic elevation-dependent patterns in the comparison. A multi-year evaluation with GRACE demonstrated a robust reproduction of basin-scale terrestrial water storage dynamics and their interannual variability (R<sup>2</sup>= 0.66-0.86). This multi-source evaluation framework establishes the VIC model capacity to represent subsurface water storage dynamics in different land cover types, providing enhanced confidence for supporting water management in the CRB.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhaocheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sustainable Engineering and the Built Environment, Arizona State University, WCPH, Room 418, 777 E. University Drive, Tempe, AZ, 85287-8704, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Hydrologic Innovations, Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghimire</LastName><ForeName>Swastik</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sustainable Engineering and the Built Environment, Arizona State University, WCPH, Room 418, 777 E. University Drive, Tempe, AZ, 85287-8704, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Hydrologic Innovations, Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whitney</LastName><ForeName>Kristen M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center, Greenbelt, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Earth System Science Interdisciplinary Center, University of Maryland, College Park, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mascaro</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sustainable Engineering and the Built Environment, Arizona State University, WCPH, Room 418, 777 E. University Drive, Tempe, AZ, 85287-8704, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Hydrologic Innovations, Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Mu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scripps Institution of Oceanography, University of California, La Jolla, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yue</LastName><ForeName>Haowen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sustainable Engineering and the Built Environment, Arizona State University, WCPH, Room 418, 777 E. University Drive, Tempe, AZ, 85287-8704, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Hydrologic Innovations, Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vivoni</LastName><ForeName>Enrique R</ForeName><Initials>ER</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sustainable Engineering and the Built Environment, Arizona State University, WCPH, Room 418, 777 E. University Drive, Tempe, AZ, 85287-8704, USA. vivoni@asu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Hydrologic Innovations, Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ, USA. vivoni@asu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>80NSSC22K0925</GrantID><Acronym>NASA</Acronym><Agency>NASA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>80NSSC22K0925</GrantID><Acronym>NASA</Acronym><Agency>NASA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>80NSSC22K0925</GrantID><Acronym>NASA</Acronym><Agency>NASA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>80NSSC22K0925</GrantID><Acronym>NASA</Acronym><Agency>NASA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>80NSSC22K0925</GrantID><Acronym>NASA</Acronym><Agency>NASA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>80NSSC22K0925</GrantID><Acronym>NASA</Acronym><Agency>NASA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>80NSSC22K0925</GrantID><Acronym>NASA</Acronym><Agency>NASA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Land surface modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Satellite remote sensing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Snow</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soil moisture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial patterns</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Terrestrial water storage anomalies</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41933153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-47430-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-47430-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>U.S. Bureau of Reclamation. Colorado River Basin Water Supply and Demand Study. U.S. Department of the Interior Study Report, 99 pp. (2012). Available at: https://www.usbr.gov/lc/region/programs/crbstudy/finalreport/Study%20Report/StudyReport_FINAL_Dec2012.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udall, B. &amp; Overpeck, J. The twenty-first century Colorado River hot drought and implications for the future. Water Resour. Res. 53, 2404&#x2013;2418 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mote, P. W., Li, S., Lettenmaier, D. P., Xiao, M. &amp; Engel, R. Dramatic declines in snowpack in the western US. Npj Clim. Atmospheric Sci. 1, 2 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milly, P. C. D. &amp; Dunne, K. A. Colorado River flow dwindles as warming-driven loss of reflective snow energizes evaporation. Science 367, 1252&#x2013;1255 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass, B., Goldenson, N., Rahimi, S. &amp; Hall, A. Aridification of Colorado River Basin&#x2019;s snowpack regions has driven water losses despite ameliorating effects of vegetation. Water Resour. Res. 59, eWR033454 (2023). (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castle, S. L. et al. Groundwater depletion during drought threatens future water security of the Colorado River Basin. Geophys. Res. Lett. 41, 5904&#x2013;5911 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, C. &amp; Piechota, T. C. Spatial and temporal soil moisture and drought variability in the Upper Colorado River Basin. J. Hydrol. 379, 122&#x2013;135 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, P. D. et al. Groundwater dominates snowmelt runoff and controls streamflow efficiency in the western United States. Commun. Earth Environ. 6, 341 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajagopalan, B. et al. Water supply risk on the Colorado River: Can management mitigate? Water Resour. Res. 45, 1&#x2013;7 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reclamation, B. Reclamation announces 2022 operating conditions for Lake Powell and Lake Mead. Newsroom https://www.usbr.gov/newsroom/news-release/3950</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler, K. G. et al. What will it take to stabilize the Colorado River? Science 377, 373&#x2013;375 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Bass, B., Hall, A., Rahimi, S. &amp; Huang, L. Disentangling climate and policy uncertainties for the Colorado River post-2026 operations. Nat. Commun. 16, 8625 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlon, B. R. et al. Multidecadal drought impacts on the Lower Colorado Basin with implications for future management. Commun. Earth Environ. 6, 214 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding, B. L., Wood, A. W. &amp; Prairie, J. R. The implications of climate change scenario selection for future streamflow projection in the Upper Colorado River Basin. Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci. 16, 3989&#x2013;4007 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukas, J. &amp; Payton, E. Colorado River Basin Climate and Hydrology: State of the Science. Western Water Assessment, University of Colorado Boulder, 531 pp. (2020). Available at: https://wwa.colorado.edu/resources/colorado-river-resources/CRBreport</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett, K. E. et al. Global sensitivity of simulated water balance indicators under future climate change in the Colorado Basin. Water Resour. Res. 54, 132&#x2013;149 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vano, J. A., Das, T. &amp; Lettenmaier, D. P. Hydrologic sensitivities of Colorado River runoff to changes in precipitation and temperature. J. Hydrometeorol. 13, 932&#x2013;949 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vano, J. A. &amp; Lettenmaier, D. P. A sensitivity-based approach to evaluating future changes in Colorado River discharge. Clim. Change. 122, 621&#x2013;634 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, H., Mascaro, G., Wang, Z. &amp; Vivoni, E. R. Hydrometeorological forecast skill of the North American Multi-Model Ensemble in the Upper Colorado River Basin. J. Hydrometeorol. 26, 933&#x2013;949 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, M., Udall, B. &amp; Lettenmaier, D. P. On the causes of declining Colorado River streamflows. Water Resour. Res. 54, 6739&#x2013;6756 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen, N. S., Wood, A. W., Voisin, N., Lettenmaier, D. P. &amp; Palmer, R. N. The effects of climate change on the hydrology and water resources of the Colorado River basin. Clim. Change. 62, 337&#x2013;363 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn, T. J., Whitney, K. M., Mascaro, G. &amp; Vivoni, E. R. A deterministic approach for approximating the diurnal cycle of precipitation for use in large-scale hydrological modeling. J. Hydrometeorol. 20, 297&#x2013;317 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn, T. J. &amp; Vivoni, E. R. Process-based characterization of evapotranspiration sources over the North American monsoon region. Water Resour. Res. 52, 358&#x2013;384 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn, T. J., Vivoni, E. R. &amp; MOD-LSP MODIS-based parameters for hydrologic modeling of North American land cover change. Sci. Data. 6, 144 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreadis, K. M., Storck, P. &amp; Lettenmaier, D. P. Modeling snow accumulation and ablation processes in forested environments. Water Resour. Res. 45, 1&#x2013;13 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livneh, B. et al. A spatially comprehensive, hydrometeorological data set for Mexico, the U.S., and Southern Canada 1950&#x2013;2013. Sci. Data. 2, 150042 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitney, K. M. et al. Spatial attribution of declining Colorado River streamflow under future warming. J Hydrol 617, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Vivoni, E. R., Bohn, T. J. &amp; Wang, Z. H. A multiyear assessment of irrigation cooling capacity in agricultural and urban settings of central Arizona. J. Am. Water Resour. Assoc. 57, 771&#x2013;788 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang, T., Vivoni, E. R. &amp; Gochis, D. J. Seasonal evolution of ecohydrological controls on land surface temperature over complex terrain. Water Resour. Res. 50, 3852&#x2013;3874 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, A., Mascaro, G. &amp; Vivoni, E. R. Strategies to improve and evaluate physics-based hyperresolution hydrologic simulations at regional basin scales. Water Resour. Res. 55, 1129&#x2013;1152 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demb&#xe9;l&#xe9;, M., Hrachowitz, M., Savenije, H. H. G., Mari&#xe9;thoz, G. &amp; Schaefli, B. Improving the predictive skill of a distributed hydrological model by calibration on spatial patterns with multiple satellite data sets. Water Resour. Res. 56, eWR026085 (2020). (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch, J., Jensen, K. H. &amp; Stisen, S. Toward a true spatial model evaluation in distributed hydrological modeling: Kappa statistics, Fuzzy theory, and EOF-analysis benchmarked by the human perception and evaluated against a modeling case study. Water Resour. Res. 51, 1225&#x2013;1246 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, M., Mascaro, G., Wang, Z., Whitney, K. M. &amp; Vivoni, E. R. On the value of satellite remote sensing to reduce uncertainties of regional simulations of the Colorado River. Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci. 26, 5627&#x2013;5646 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Entekhabi, D. Propagation in the drought cascade: Observational analysis over the continental US. Water Resour. Res. 59, e2022WR032608 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoylman, Z. H. et al. Optimizing drought assessment for soil moisture deficits. Water Resour. Res. 60, e2023WR036087 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichle, R. H. et al. Assessment of the SMAP Level-4 surface and root-zone soil moisture product using in situ measurements. J. Hydrometeorol. 18, 2621&#x2013;2645 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Entekhabi, D. et al. The soil moisture active passive (SMAP) mission. Proc. IEEE. 98, 704&#x2013;716 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmohsen, K., Famiglietti, J. S., Ao, Y. Z., Mohajer, B. &amp; Chandanpurkar, H. A. Declining freshwater availability in the Colorado River Basin threatens sustainability of its critical groundwater supplies. Geophys. Res. Lett. 52, eGL115593 (2025). (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlon, B. R. et al. Hydrologic implications of GRACE satellite data in the Colorado River Basin. Water Resour. Res. 51, 9891&#x2013;9903 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, P., Liu, X. &amp; Liu, C. Improving hydrological simulations by incorporating GRACE data for model calibration. J. Hydrol. 557, 291&#x2013;304 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. Validation of terrestrial water storage variations as simulated by different global numerical models with GRACE satellite observations. Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci. 21, 821&#x2013;837 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hale, K. E., Musselman, K. N., Newman, A. J., Livneh, B. &amp; Molotch, N. P. Effects of snow water storage on hydrologic partitioning across the mountainous, western United States. Water Resour. Res. 59, eWR034690 (2023). (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J. et al. Streamflow seasonality in a snow-dwindling world. Nature 629, 1075&#x2013;1081 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll, R. W. H., Gochis, D. &amp; Williams, K. H. Efficiency of the summer monsoon in generating streamflow within a snow-dominated headwater basin of the Colorado River. Geophys. Res. Lett. 47, eGL090856 (2020). (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Jaya Baskar, J. V., Naga Sai, S., Svoma, M. S. &amp; Vivoni, E. R. B. Spatiotemporal patterns of intermittent snow cover from PlanetScope imagery using deep learning. Geophys. Res. Lett. 52, eGL116582 (2025). (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trujillo, E. &amp; Molotch, N. P. Snowpack regimes of the western United States. Water Resour. Res. 50, 5611&#x2013;5623 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascaro, G., Ko, A. &amp; Vivoni, E. R. Closing the loop of satellite soil moisture estimation via scale invariance of hydrologic simulations. Sci. Rep. 9, 16123 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivoni, E. R. et al. Observed relation between evapotranspiration and soil moisture in the North American monsoon region. Geophys. Res. Lett. 35, L22403 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateni, S. M. &amp; Entekhabi, D. Relative efficiency of land surface energy balance components. Water Resour. Res. 48, W04510 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koster, R. D. et al. A catchment-based approach to modeling land surface processes in a general circulation model: 1. Model structure. J. Geophys. Res. Atmos. 105, 809&#x2013;824 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getirana, A., Kumar, S. &amp; Rodell, M. Inconsistencies in GRACE-based groundwater storage estimation&#x2014;A call for a proper use of land surface models. Geophys. Res. Lett. 52, e2025GL119197 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S. et al. An agenda for land data assimilation priorities: Realizing the promise of terrestrial water, energy, and vegetation observations from space. J. Adv. Model. Earth Syst. 14, e2022MS003259 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie, W. et al. Assimilating GRACE into a land surface model in the presence of an irrigation-induced groundwater trend. Water Resour. Res. 55, 11274&#x2013;11294 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boardman, E. N. Constraining kilometer-scale mountain snow transport and snowshed areas. Geophys. Res. Lett. 52, e2024GL113599 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boardman, E. N. et al. Wind and topography underlie correlation between seasonal snowpack, mountain glaciers, and late-summer streamflow. Cryosphere 19, 3193&#x2013;3225 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitney, K. M. et al. A stakeholder-engaged approach to anticipating forest disturbance impacts in the Colorado River Basin under climate change. J. Water Resour. Plan. Manag. 149, 04023020 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Vivoni, E. R., Whitney, K. M., Xiao, M. &amp; Mascaro, G. On the sensitivity of future hydrology in the Colorado River to the selection of the precipitation partitioning method. Water Resour. Res. 60, eWR035801 (2024). (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamman, J. J., Nijssen, B., Bohn, T. J., Gergel, D. R. &amp; Mao, Y. The variable infiltration capacity model version 5 (VIC-5): Infrastructure improvements for new applications and reproducibility. Geosci. Model. Dev. 11, 3481&#x2013;3496 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, X., Wood, E. F. &amp; Lettenmaier, D. P. Surface soil moisture parameterization of the VIC-2L model: Evaluation and modification. Glob Planet. Change. 13, 195&#x2013;206 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, X., Lettenmaier, D. P., Wood, E. F. &amp; Burges, S. J. A simple hydrologically based model of land surface water and energy fluxes for general circulation models. J. Geophys. Res. 99, 14415 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Bureau of Reclamation. Colorado River Basin Water Supply and Demand Study, Technical Report B &#x2013; Water Supply Assessment, Appendix B4: Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) Hydrologic Modeling Methods and Simulations, 18 pp. (2012). Available at: https://www.usbr.gov/lc/region/programs/crbstudy/finalreport/Technical%20Report%20B%20-%20Water%20Supply%20Assessment/TR-B_Appendix4_FINAL.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly, C., Neilson, R. P. &amp; Phillips, D. L. A statistical-topographic model for mapping climatological precipitation over mountainous terrain. J. Appl. Meteorol. Climatol. 33, 140&#x2013;158 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, L. et al. Drought variability over the conterminous United States for the past century. J. Hydrometeorol. 22, 1153&#x2013;1168 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton, D. &amp; Hall, A. An assessment of high-resolution gridded temperature datasets over California. J. Clim. 31, 3789&#x2013;3810 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitney, K. M. et al. Quantifying the impacts of dynamic lapse regimes on snow simulations over complex terrains. J. Hydrometeorol. 26, 1525&#x2013;1560 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly, C. et al. Physiographically sensitive mapping of climatological temperature and precipitation across the conterminous United States. Int. J. Climatol. 28, 2031&#x2013;2064 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohn, T. J. et al. Global evaluation of MTCLIM and related algorithms for forcing of ecological and hydrological models. Agric. Meteorol. 176, 38&#x2013;49 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett, A., Hamman, J., Nijssen, B. &amp; MetSim A Python package for estimation and disaggregation of meteorological data. J. Open. Source Softw. 5, 2042 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosgrove, B. A. et al. Real-time and retrospective forcing in the North American Land Data Assimilation System (NLDAS) project. J. Geophys. Res. 108 (D22), 8842 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichle, R. et al. SMAP L4 Global 9 km EASE-Grid Surface and Root Zone Soil Moisture Geophysical Data. (SPL4SMGP, Version 7). NASA National Snow and Ice Data Center Distributed Active Archive Center. (2022). Available at: https://doi.org/10.5067/T5RUATAQREF8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koster, R. D. et al. On the nature of soil moisture in land surface models. J. Clim. 22, 4322&#x2013;4335 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodell, M. &amp; Famiglietti, J. S. An analysis of terrestrial water storage variations in Illinois with implications for the Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE). Water Resour. Res. 37, 1327&#x2013;1339 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldardiry, H. et al. Characterizing how meteorological forcing selection and parameter uncertainty influence Community Land Model Version 5 hydrological applications in the United States. J. Adv. Model. Earth Syst. 17, eMS004222 (2025). (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreadis, K. M., Storck, P. &amp; Lettenmaier, D. P. Modeling snow accumulation and ablation processes in forested environments. Water Resour. Res. 45, W05429 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jawad, M. et al. Improved evapotranspiration estimation using the Penman-Monteith equation with a deep learning (DNN) model over the dry southwestern US: Comparison with ECOSTRESS, MODIS, and OpenET. J. Hydrol. 660, 133460 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>