<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41692020</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-547X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>407</Volume><Issue>10532</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lancet (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lisocabtagene maraleucel in patients with relapsed or refractory marginal zone lymphoma (TRANSCEND FL): primary analysis results from the global, multicohort, single-arm, phase 2 study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>963</StartPage><EndPage>975</EndPage><MedlinePgn>963-975</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0140-6736(25)02435-3</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0140-6736(25)02435-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Effective treatments with deep and durable responses for relapsed or refractory marginal zone lymphoma (MZL) are lacking. The objective of the primary analysis from the MZL cohort of TRANSCEND FL was to evaluate the efficacy and safety of the CD19-directed chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T-cell therapy lisocabtagene maraleucel.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this phase 2, single-arm, multicohort study, patients from 30 sites in the USA, Canada, Europe, and Japan with relapsed or refractory MZL who had at least two previous lines of systemic therapy were eligible to receive lisocabtagene maraleucel (100&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;10<sup>6</sup> CAR<sup>+</sup> T cells). Bridging therapy was allowed. The primary endpoint was overall response rate per independent review committee by CT by use of Lugano 2014 criteria (null hypothesis &#x2264;50%). This study is registered with ClinicalTrials.gov, NCT04245839, and is ongoing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 77 leukapheresed patients recruited between November 11, 2020, and August 24, 2023, 67 received lisocabtagene maraleucel and 66 were efficacy evaluable. MZL subtypes included nodal (n=32 [48%]), splenic (n=18 [27%]), and extranodal-mucosa-associated lymphoid tissue (n=17 [25%]). Median (IQR) previous lines of systemic therapy was 3 (2-4). Median on-study follow-up was 24&#xb7;1 months. The primary endpoint was met, with an overall response rate of 95% (n=63; 95% CI, 87&#xb7;3-99&#xb7;1; one-sided p&lt;0&#xb7;0001). All patients experienced a treatment-related adverse event. Grade 3 cytokine release syndrome or neurological events occurred in three (4%) patients each (no grade 4-5 events). 11 (16%) patients had grade &#x2265;3 infections: six (9%) patients during the 90-day treatment-emergent period and seven (10%) during the post-treatment-emergent period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In patients with relapsed or refractory MZL, lisocabtagene maraleucel showed high rates of durable responses. The safety profile was manageable, with no new safety signals. These results support lisocabtagene maraleucel as a new treatment option for patients with relapsed or refractory MZL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Celgene, a Bristol-Myers Squibb Company.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palomba</LastName><ForeName>M Lia</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, New York, NY, USA. Electronic address: palombam@mskcc.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuster</LastName><ForeName>Stephen J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lymphoma Program, Abramson Cancer Center, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Karmali</LastName><ForeName>Reem</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Robert H Lurie Comprehensive Cancer Center, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skarbnik</LastName><ForeName>Alan P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novant Health Cancer Institute, Charlotte, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abramson</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lymphoma Program, Massachusetts General Hospital Cancer Center, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardeshna</LastName><ForeName>Kirit</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College London Hospitals Biomedical Research Centre, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borchmann</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe4;t zu K&#xf6;ln, Albertus-Magnus-Platz, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Brian T</ForeName><Initials>BT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Sancho</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro Martin</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Universitario de Salamanca, IBSAL, CIBERONC, Universidad de Salamanca, Salamanca, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marcacci</LastName><ForeName>Gianpaolo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Cancer Institute, Fondazione 'G Pascale', IRCCS, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rapoport</LastName><ForeName>Aaron P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Maryland Marlene and Stewart Greenebaum Comprehensive Cancer Center, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cartron</LastName><ForeName>Guillaume</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montpellier University Hospital Center, UMR CNRS, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleury</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>H&#xf4;pital Maisonneuve-Rosemont, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Izutsu</LastName><ForeName>Koji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Cancer Center Hospital, Chuo City, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamdar</LastName><ForeName>Manali</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Colorado Cancer Center, Aurora, CO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mielke</LastName><ForeName>Stephan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Laboratory Medicine and Medicine at Huddinge, Center of Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplantation and Cellular Therapy, Karolinska Institutet and University Hospital, Karolinska Comprehensive Cancer Center, Karolinska ATMP Center, H5 Laboratories Medicine, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbui</LastName><ForeName>Anna Maria</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Azienda Socio Sanitaria Territoriale Papa Giovanni XXIII, Bergamo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortega</LastName><ForeName>Juan Luis Reguera</ForeName><Initials>JLR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Universitario Virgen del Roc&#xed;o, Instituto de Biomedicina de Sevilla, Universidad de Sevilla, Seville, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nastoupil</LastName><ForeName>Loretta J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Southwest Oncology, CommonSpirit Mercy, Durango, CO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Sairah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bar</LastName><ForeName>Merav</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Boudry, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diaz</LastName><ForeName>Lizbeth</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Boudry, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Furustrand</LastName><ForeName>Ulrika</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Boudry, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diab</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Princeton, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vedal</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Boudry, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avilion</LastName><ForeName>Ariel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Jinender</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Princeton, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishii</LastName><ForeName>Rina</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Princeton, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colicino</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bristol Myers Squibb, Boudry, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morschhauser</LastName><ForeName>Franck</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>D&#xe9;partement d'H&#xe9;matologie, Universit&#xe9; de Lille, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Lille, Groupe de Recherche sur les formes Injectables et les Technologies Associ&#xe9;es, Lille, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04245839</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017427">Clinical Trial, Phase II</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985213R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0140-6736</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018941">Antigens, CD19</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000076962">Receptors, Chimeric Antigen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018941" MajorTopicYN="N">Antigens, CD19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016219" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immunotherapy, Adoptive</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018442" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lymphoma, B-Cell, Marginal Zone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009364" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasm Recurrence, Local</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptors, Chimeric Antigen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015316" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests MLP discloses consulting fees from Bristol Myers Squibb, Kite, Novartis, and Synthekine; and data safety monitoring or advisory board participation for Bristol Myers Squibb and BeiGene. SJS discloses honoraria from Janssen and Novartis; consulting or advisory roles for AbbVie, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, BioNTech, Bristol Myers Squibb, Caribou Biosciences, Fate Therapeutics, Genentech, Genmab, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Incyte, Janssen, Legend Biotech, Loxo Oncology, MorphoSys, Mustang Biotech, Novartis, Regeneron, Roche, and viTToria Biotherapeutics; research funding from AbbVie, Adaptive Biotechnologies, Bristol Myers Squibb, DTRM Biopharma, Genentech, Incyte, Merck, Novartis, Pharmacyclics, and Roche; steering committee membership for Caribou Biotech and Novartis; and patents for Methods for Treating CLL (autologous co-stimulated T cells). RK discloses consulting fees from AbbVie, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, Genentech&#x2013;Roche, Genmab, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Lilly Oncology, and Miltenyi Biotec; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events for AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, and Incyte&#x2013;MorphoSys; data safety monitoring or advisory board participation for AvenCell Therapeutics and Calithera Biosciences; and committee or advocacy group participation, paid or unpaid, for American Society of Hematology committee on quality and ASCO National Comprehensive Cancer Network guideline committee for histiocytic disorders. APS discloses support for the current manuscript from Bristol Myers Squibb; consulting fees from AbbVie, Alexion, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Epizyme, Genentech, Genmab, Jazz Pharmaceuticals, Janssen, Kite, Lilly, MorphoSys, Novartis, and SeaGen; honoraria from AbbVie, ADC Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Genentech, Genmab, Janssen, Jazz Pharmaceuticals, Kite, Lilly, and SeaGen; and data safety monitoring or advisory board participation for Alexion Pharmaceuticals and Bristol Myers Squibb. JSA discloses consulting fees from AbbVie, ADC Therapeutics, Alimera Sciences, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, bluebird bio, Bristol Myers Squibb, C4 Therapeutics, Caribou Biosciences, Cellectar Biosciences, Century Therapeutics, EMD Serono, Epizyme, Foresight Diagnostics, Genmab, Incyte, Interius Biotherapeutics, Janssen, Karyopharm Therapeutics, Kite, Kymera Therapeutics, Lilly, MorphoSys, Mustang Bio, Novartis, Ono Pharmaceutical, Roche, SeaGen, EMD Serono, and Takeda; honoraria from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Janssen, Kite, and Regeneron; and research funding via institution from Bristol Myers Squibb, Cellectis, Merck, Mustang Bio, Regeneron, and SeaGen. KA discloses support for travel and attending meetings from Bristol Myers Squibb, Gilead, and Novartis. PB discloses institutional grants from Incyte, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Miltenyi Biotec, and Takeda Oncology; consulting fees from Bristol Myers Squibb, Gilead, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Miltenyi Biotec, Roche, and Takeda Oncology; honoraria from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, Gilead, Incyte, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Miltenyi Biotec, Roche, and Takeda Oncology; and support for travel and attending meetings from Bristol Myers Squibb, Gilead, Incyte, Miltenyi Biotec, Roche, and Takeda Oncology. BTH discloses consulting fees and research funding from Bristol Myers Squibb. AMG-S discloses consulting fees from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Genmab, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, GlaxoSmithKline, Ideogen, Incyte, Janssen, Lilly, Miltenyi Biotec, Regeneron, Roche, and Sobi; honoraria from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Ideogen, Incyte, Janssen, Kyowa Kirin, Lilly, Roche, Sobi, and Takeda; support for travel and attending meetings from AbbVie, Bristol Myers Squibb, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Lilly, and Roche; data safety monitoring or advisory board participation for AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, and Regeneron; and leadership or fiduciary role in other board, society, committee or advocacy group, paid or unpaid, with the GELTAMO Foundation. GM discloses no conflict of interest. APR discloses data safety monitoring board participation for National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute, Rapa Therapeutics, and University of Pennsylvania Abramson Cancer Center. GC discloses consulting fees for Bristol Myers Squibb, Mabqi, Onward Therapeutics, and Roche; honoraria from AbbVie, Janssen, Novartis, and Takeda; and support for travel and attending meetings from Janssen and Roche. IF discloses consulting fees from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, Incyte, Janssen, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Merck, Novartis, Roche, SeaGen, and Takeda; speakers bureaus from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, Incyte, Janssen, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Novartis, Roche, and SeaGen; and support for travel and attending meetings from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Roche, and SeaGen. KI discloses consulting fees from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, Carna Biosciences, Chugai, Eisai, Genmab, Kyowa Kirin, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Otsuka, Nippon Shinyaku, Novartis, Ono Pharma, Symbio, Takeda, Yakult, and Zenyaku; honoraria from AbbVie, Astellas, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Genmab, Gilead, Janssen, Kyowa Kirin, Lilly, Meiji Seika Pharma, Novartis, Nihon Kayakueutical, Ono Pharma, Pfizer, SymBio, Takeda; and institutional research funding from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, Bayer, BeiGene, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Genmab, Gilead, Incyte, Janssen, Kyowa Kirin, LOXO Oncology, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Otsuka, Pfizer, Regeneron, and Yakult. MK discloses consulting fees from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, BeiGene, and Genentech; and data safety monitoring board participation from Bristol Myers Squibb and Genentech. SM discloses support for the present manuscript from Bristol Myers Squibb; institutional grants or contracts from Gilead&#x2013;Kite; honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb, Janssen, and Novartis; data safety monitoring board participation from Immunicum&#x2013;Mendus and Miltenyi Biotec; leadership or fiduciary role, paid or unpaid, for SWECARNET; and other financial or non-financial interests from Scientify Research. AMB discloses grants or contracts from Incyte, Pierre Fabre, and Roche. JLRO discloses consulting fees from Johnson &amp; Johnson and Kite; honoraria from Amgen, Bristol Myers Squibb, Johnson &amp; Johnson, and Kite; and support for travel and attending meetings from Johnson &amp; Johnson. LJN discloses support for the present manuscript from Bristol Myers Squibb; honoraria from AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Genentech, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Incyte, Janssen, Merck, Novartis, Regeneron, and Takeda; and research support from Daiichi Sankyo, Genentech, Gilead&#x2013;Kite, Incyte, Janssen, Novartis, and Takeda. SA discloses consulting fees from Gilead&#x2013;Kite and Myeloid Therapeutics; honoraria from ADC Therapeutics, Genmab, and Gilead&#x2013;Kite; and research funding from Chimagen Biosciences, Caribou Sciences, Genmab&#x2013;Seattle Genetics, Janssen Oncology, Merck, and Nektar Therapeutics. MB, LD, UF, VD, MV, AA, JK, RN, and SC disclose employment and stock ownership in Bristol Myers Squibb. FM discloses consulting fees from AbbVie, Bristol Myers Squibb, Gilead, Janssen, and Roche; honoraria from AstraZeneca, Chugai, and Takeda; and data safety monitoring or advisory board participation for AstraZeneca, Miltenyi Biotec, ModeX Therapeutics, and Roche.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41692020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(25)02435-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0140-6736(25)02435-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>