<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41502825</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0885-6087</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hydrological processes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hydrol Process</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Insights into heterogeneous streamflow generation processes and water contribution in forested headwaters.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e70241</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/hyp.70241</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Understanding how diverse headwater streams contribute water downstream is critical for accurate modeling of seasonal flow dynamics in larger systems. This study investigated how headwater catchments, with diverse subsurface storage, influence downstream flows within Lookout Creek-a 62 km<sup>2</sup>, 5<sup>th</sup>-order catchment in the rain-snow transition zone in western Oregon, USA. We analyzed one year of hydrometric and water stable isotope data collected at ten stream locations, complemented by a decade of precipitation isotopic data. As expected, isotopic data revealed that most of the streamflow was sourced from large fall and winter storms. Generally, stream isotope ratios decrease with elevation. However, some streams had higher isotopic values than expected, reflecting the influence of isotopically heavy storms and relatively low storage. Other streams that tended to have low flow variability in response to precipitation inputs had lower isotopic values indicating higher elevation water sources than their topographic watershed boundaries. Both hydrometric data and water isotope-based end-member mixing models suggest storage differences among headwater catchments influenced the seasonal water contributions from tributaries. Most notably, the contributions of Cold and Longer Creeks, which occupy less than 10% of the Lookout Creek drainage area, sustain up to 50% of the streamflow in the summer. These catchments have high storage and high groundwater contributions, as evidenced by flat flow duration curves. Finally, our data suggest that geologic variability and geomorphic complexity (presence of earthflows and landslides), can be indicators of storage that dramatically influences water movement through the critical zone, the variation in streamflow, and the response of streams to precipitation events. Heterogeneity in headwater catchment storage is key to understanding flow dynamics in mountainous regions and the response of streams to changes in climate and other disturbances.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortega</LastName><ForeName>Jaime</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-7178-043X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Forest Engineering, Resources, and Management, OSU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Segura</LastName><ForeName>Catalina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0924-1172</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Forest Engineering, Resources, and Management, OSU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brooks</LastName><ForeName>J Ren&#xe9;e</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5008-9774</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Forest Ecosystems and Society, OSU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pacific Ecological Systems Division, Office of Research and Development, US Environmental Protection Agency, Corvallis, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sullivan</LastName><ForeName>Pamela L</ForeName><Initials>PL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8780-8501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Earth, Ocean, and Atmospheric Sciences, OSU.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>EPA999999</GrantID><Acronym>ImEPA</Acronym><Agency>Intramural EPA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hydrol Process</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101534565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0885-6087</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical zone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">damping ratios</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">end-member mixing analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isotopic lapse rates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">storage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">streamflow sources</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water stable isotopes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41502825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2105381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12774411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hyp.70241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">e70241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexander RB, Boyer EW, Smith RA, Schwarz GE and Moore RB (2007) The Role of Headwater Streams in Downstream Water Quality1. JAWRA Journal of the American Water Resources Association 43(1), 41&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22457565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araguas-Araguas L, Froehlich K and Rozanski K (2000) Deuterium and oxygen-18 isotope composition of precipitation and atmospheric moisture. Hydrological Processes 14(8), 1341&#x2013;1355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asano Y, Kawasaki M, Saito T, Haraguchi R, Takatoku K, Saiki M and Kimura K (2020) An Increase in Specific Discharge With Catchment Area Implies That Bedrock Infiltration Feeds Large Rather Than Small Mountain Headwater Streams. Water Resources Research 56(9), e2019WR025658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansah S and Ali G (2019) Streamwater ages in nested, seasonally cold Canadian watersheds. Hydrological Processes 33(4), 495&#x2013;511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhart TB, Tague CL and Molotch NP (2020) The Counteracting Effects of Snowmelt Rate and Timing on Runoff. Water Resources Research 56(8).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Befus KM, Sheehan AF, Leopold M, Anderson SP and Anderson RS (2011) Seismic Constraints on Critical Zone Architecture, Boulder Creek Watershed, Front Range, Colorado. Vadose Zone Journal 10(3), 915&#x2013;927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benettin P, Rodriguez NB, Sprenger M, Kim M, Klaus J, Harman CJ, van der Velde Y, Hrachowitz M, Botter G, McGuire KJ, Kirchner JW, Rinaldo A and McDonnell JJ (2022) Transit Time Estimation in Catchments: Recent Developments and Future Directions. Water Resources Research 58(11), e2022WR033096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin L, Knobel LL, Hall LF, Cecil LD and Green JR (2005) Development of a local meteoric water line for southeastern Idaho, western Wyoming, and south-central Montana.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berghuijs WR, Woods RA and Hrachowitz M (2014) A precipitation shift from snow towards rain leads to a decrease in streamflow. Nature Climate Change 4(7), 583&#x2013;586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beria H, Larsen JR, Ceperley NC, Michelon A, Vennemann T and Schaefli B (2018) Understanding snow hydrological processes through the lens of stable water isotopes. WIREs Water 5(6), e1311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bershaw J, Penny SM and Garzione CN (2012) Stable isotopes of modern water across the Himalaya and eastern Tibetan Plateau: Implications for estimates of paleoelevation and paleoclimate. Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres 117(D2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bershaw J, Saylor JE, Garzione CN, Leier A and Sundell KE (2016) Stable isotope variations (delta O-18 and delta D) in modern waters across the Andean Plateau. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta 194, 310&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bierlmaier FA and McKee A (1989) Climatic Summaries and Documentation for the Primary Meteorological Station, H.J. Andrews Experimental Forest, 1972 to 1984. Gen. Tech. Rep. PNW-242., U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Pacific Northwest Research Station, Portland, OR. 56 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birkel C, Correa-Barahona A, Martinez-Martinez M, Granados-Bola&#xf1;os S, Venegas-Cordero N, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Garc&#xed;a K, Blanco-Ram&#xed;rez S, Quesada-Mora R, Solano-Rivera V, Mussio-Mora J, Chavarr&#xed;a-Palma A, Vargas-Arias K, Moore GW, Dur&#xe1;n-Quesada AM, Vasquez-Morera J, Soulsby C, Tetzlaff D, Espinoza-Cisneros E and S&#xe1;nchez-Murillo R (2020) Headwaters drive streamflow and lowland tracer export in a large-scale humid tropical catchment. Hydrological Processes 34(18), 3824&#x2013;3841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birkel C, Soulsby C and Tetzlaff D (2011) Modelling catchment-scale water storage dynamics: reconciling dynamic storage with tracer-inferred passive storage. Hydrological Processes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen GJ, Cai Z, Fiorella RP and Putman AL (2019) Isotopes in the Water Cycle: Regional- to Global-Scale Patterns and Applications. Annual Review of Earth and Planetary Sciences 47(Volume 47, 2019), 453&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen GJ and Revenaugh J (2003) Interpolating the isotopic composition of modern meteoric precipitation. Water Resources Research 39(10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen GJ and Wilkinson B (2002) Spatial distribution of &#x3b4;18O in meteoric precipitation. Geology 30(4), 315&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brantley SL, McDowell WH, Dietrich WE, White TS, Kumar P, Anderson SP, Chorover J, Lohse KA, Bales RC, Richter DD, Grant G and Gaillardet J (2017) Designing a network of critical zone observatories to explore the living skin of the terrestrial Earth. Earth Surf. Dynam. 5(4), 841&#x2013;860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks JR, Rugh WD and Werner RA (2022) Stable Isotopes in Tree Rings: Inferring Physiological, Climatic and Environmental Responses. Siegwolf RTW, Brooks JR, Roden J and Saurer M (eds), pp. 191&#x2013;213, Springer International Publishing, Cham.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks JR, Wigington PJ, Phillips DL, Comeleo R and Coulombe R (2012) Willamette River Basin surface water isoscape (delta O-18 and delta H-2): temporal changes of source water within the river. Ecosphere 3(5), 21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bush SA, Johnson SL, Bladon KD and Sullivan PL (2024) Stream chemical response is mediated by hydrologic connectivity and fire severity in a Pacific Northwest forest. Hydrological Processes 38(7), e15231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buttle JM (2018) Mediating stream baseflow response to climate change: The role of basin storage. Hydrological Processes 32(3), 363&#x2013;378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvi C, Carol E, Fennell L and Naipauer M (2024) Assessment of hydrological systems associated with groundwater discharges in arid high mountain environments of the Argentine Andes. Groundwater for Sustainable Development 26, 101218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciais P and Jouzel J (1994) Deuterium and Oxygen-18 in Precipitation - Isotopic Model, Including Mixed Cloud Processes. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres 99(D8), 16793&#x2013;16803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark ID and Fritz P (1997) Environmental Isotopes in Hydrogeology, Taylor &amp; Francis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig H (1961) Isotopic Variations in Meteoric Waters. Science 133(3465), 1702&#x2013;1703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17814749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crampe EA, Segura C and Jones JA (2021) Fifty years of runoff response to conversion of old-growth forest to planted forest in the H. J. Andrews Forest, Oregon, USA. Hydrological Processes 35(5), e14168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daly C, Schulze M and McKee W (2019) Met eorological data from benchmark stations at the HJ Andrews Experimental Forest, 1957 to present. Long-Term Ecological Research. Forest Science Data Bank, Corvallis, OR. [Database]. Available: http://andlter.forestry.oregonstate.edu/data/abstract.aspx?dbcode=MS001. 10.6073/pasta/c021a2ebf1f91adf0ba3b5e53189c84f. Accessed 2024-10-08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6073/pasta/c021a2ebf1f91adf0ba3b5e53189c84f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dierauer JR, Whitfield PH and Allen DM (2018) Climate Controls on Runoff and Low Flows in Mountain Catchments of Western North America. Water Resources Research 54(10), 7495&#x2013;7510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingman SL (2002) Physical hydrology, Prentice Hall, Upper Saddle River, N.J.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dogramaci S, Skrzypek G, Dodson W and Grierson PF (2012) Stable isotope and hydrochemical evolution of groundwater in the semi-arid Hamersley Basin of subtropical northwest Australia. Journal of Hydrology 475, 281&#x2013;293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dye AW, Reilly MJ, McEvoy A, Lemons R, Riley KL, Kim JB and Kerns BK (2024) Simulated Future Shifts in Wildfire Regimes in Moist Forests of Pacific Northwest, USA. Journal of Geophysical Research: Biogeosciences 129(2), e2023JG007722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>England JF Jr, Cohn TA, Faber BA, Stedinger JR, Thomas WO Jr, Veilleux AG, Kiang JE and Mason JRR (2018) Guidelines for determining flood flow frequency &#x2014; Bulletin 17C, p. 168, Reston, VA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y, Toran L and Schlische RW (2007) Groundwater flow and groundwater-stream interaction in fractured and dipping sedimentary rocks: Insights from numerical models. Water Resources Research 43(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fennell J, Geris J, Wilkinson ME, Daalmans R and Soulsby C (2020) Lessons from the 2018 drought for management of local water supplies in upland areas: A tracer-based assessment. Hydrological Processes 34(22), 4190&#x2013;4210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floriancic MG, Fischer BMC, Molnar P, Kirchner JW and van Meerveld IHJ (2019) Spatial variability in specific discharge and streamwater chemistry during low flows: Results from snapshot sampling campaigns in eleven Swiss catchments. Hydrological Processes 33(22), 2847&#x2013;2866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman MC, Pringle CM and Jackson CR (2007) Hydrologic Connectivity and the Contribution of Stream Headwaters to Ecological Integrity at Regional Scales1. JAWRA Journal of the American Water Resources Association 43(1), 5&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gat JR (2010) Isotope Hydrology: A Study of the Water Cycle, Imperial College Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gat JR and Matsui E (1991) Atmospheric Water-Balance in The Amazon Basin - An Isotopic Evapotranspiration Model. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres 96(D7), 13179&#x2013;13188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genereux D (1998) Quantifying uncertainty in tracer-based hydrograph separations. Water Resources Research 34, 915&#x2013;919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomi T, Sidle RC and Richardson JS (2002) Understanding processes and downstream linkages of headwater systems. Bioscience 52, 905&#x2013;916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonfiantini R, Roche M-A, Olivry J-C, Fontes J-C and Zuppi GM (2001) The altitude effect on the isotopic composition of tropical rains. Chemical Geology 181(1), 147&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman AC, Segura C, Jones JA and Swanson FJ (2023) Seventy years of watershed response to floods and changing forestry practices in western Oregon, USA. Earth Surface Processes and Landforms, esp.5537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groning M, Lutz HO, Roller-Lutz Z, Kralik M, Gourcy L and Poltenstein L (2012) A simple rain collector preventing water re-evaporation dedicated for delta O-18 and delta H-2 analysis of cumulative precipitation samples. Journal of Hydrology 448, 195&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hale KE, Musselman KN, Newman AJ, Livneh B and Molotch NP (2023) Effects of Snow Water Storage on Hydrologic Partitioning Across the Mountainous, Western United States. Water Resources Research 59(8).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halofsky JE, Peterson DL and Harvey BJ (2020) Changing wildfire, changing forests: the effects of climate change on fire regimes and vegetation in the Pacific Northwest, USA. Fire Ecology 16(1), 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herschy RW (2009) Streamflow Measurement (3rd ed.), CRC Press; &#x2025;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden ZA, Swanson A, Luce CH, Jolly WM, Maneta M, Oyler JW, Warren DA, Parsons R and Affleck D (2018) Decreasing fire season precipitation increased recent western US forest wildfire activity. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 115(36), E8349&#x2013;E8357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang C-C and Yeh H-F (2022) Evaluation of seasonal catchment dynamic storage components using an analytical streamflow duration curve model. Sustainable Environment Research 32(1), 49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes CE and Crawford J (2012) A new precipitation weighted method for determining the meteoric water line for hydrological applications demonstrated using Australian and global GNIP data. Journal of Hydrology 464-465, 344&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasechko S (2019) Global Isotope Hydrogeology&#x2015;Review. Reviews of Geophysics 57(3), 835&#x2013;965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeelani G, Saravana Kumar U and Kumar B (2013) Variation of &#x3b4;18O and &#x3b4;D in precipitation and stream waters across the Kashmir Himalaya (India) to distinguish and estimate the seasonal sources of stream flow. Journal of Hydrology 481, 157&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jefferson A, Grant G and Rose T (2006) Influence of volcanic history on groundwater patterns on the west slope of the Oregon High Cascades. Water Resources Research 42(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings K and Jones JA (2015) Precipitation-snowmelt timing and snowmelt augmentation of large peak flow events, western Cascades, Oregon. Water Resources Research 51(9), 7649&#x2013;7661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf3;dar J, Cabrera JA, Martos-Rosillo S, Ruiz-Const&#xe1;n A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ram&#xf3;n A, Lamb&#xe1;n LJ, Herrera C and Custodio E (2017) Groundwater discharge in high-mountain watersheds: A valuable resource for downstream semi-arid zones. The case of the B&#xe9;rchules River in Sierra Nevada (Southern Spain). Science of the Total Environment 593&#x2013;594, 760&#x2013;772.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K, Christensen JN, Gardner WP, Sprenger M, Li L, Williams KH, Carroll RWH, Thiros N, Brown W, Beutler C, Newman A and Sullivan PL (2024a) Shifting groundwater fluxes in bedrock fractures: Evidence from stream water radon and water isotopes. Journal of Hydrology 635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K, Harpold A, Carroll RWH, Barnard H, Raleigh MS, Segura C, Li L, Williams KH, Dong W and Sullivan PL (2023) Leveraging Groundwater Dynamics to Improve Predictions of Summer Low-Flow Discharges. Water Resources Research 59(8), e2023WR035126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K, Williams KH, Christensen JN, Carroll RWH, Li L, Beutler C, Bird KS, Dong W and Sullivan PL (2025) Hidden Features: How Subsurface and Landscape Heterogeneity Govern Hydrologic Connectivity and Stream Chemistry in a Montane Watershed. Hydrological Processes 39(3), e70085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson SL, Wondzell SM, Rothacher JS and Jones JA (2024b) Stream discharge in gaged watersheds at the HJ Andrews Experimental Forest, 1949 to present. Long-Term Ecological Research
Forest Science Data Bank, Corvallis, OR. [Database]. Available: http://andlter.forestry.oregonstate.edu/data/abstract.aspx?dbcode=HF004. 10.6073/pasta/0066d6b04e736af5f234d95d97ee84f3. Accessed 2024-10-08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6073/pasta/0066d6b04e736af5f234d95d97ee84f3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones JA and Perkins RM (2010) Extreme flood sensitivity to snow and forest harvest, western Cascades, Oregon, United States. Water Resources Research 46(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung YY, Koh DC, Shin WJ, Kwon HI, Oh YH and Lee KS (2021) Assessing seasonal variations in water sources of streamflow in a temperate mesoscale catchment with granitic bedrocks using hydrochemistry and stable isotopes. Journal of Hydrology-Regional Studies 38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlstrom L, Klema N, Grant GE, Finn C, Sullivan PL, Cooley S, Simpson A, Fasth B, Cashman K, Ferrier K, Ball L and McKay D (2025) State shifts in the deep Critical Zone drive landscape evolution in volcanic terrains. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 122(3), e2415155122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall C and Coplen TB (2001) Distribution of oxygen-18 and deuterium in river waters across the United States. Hydrological Processes 15(7), 1363&#x2013;1393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchner JW, Tetzlaff D and Soulsby C (2010) Comparing chloride and water isotopes as hydrological tracers in two Scottish catchments. Hydrological Processes 24(12), 1631&#x2013;1645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles N, Dettinger MD and Cayan DR (2006) Trends in snowfall versus rainfall in the Western United States. Journal of Climate 19(18), 4545&#x2013;4559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruskal WH and Wallis WA (1952) Use of Ranks in One-Criterion Variance Analysis. Journal of the American Statistical Association 47(260), 583&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane CR, Creed IF, Golden HE, Leibowitz SG, Mushet DM, Rains MC, Wu Q, D&#x2019;Amico E, Alexander LC, Ali GA, Basu NB, Bennett MG, Christensen JR, Cohen MJ, Covino TP, DeVries B, Hill RA, Jencso K, Lang MW, McLaughlin DL, Rosenberry DO, Rover J and Vanderhoof MK (2023) Vulnerable Waters are Essential to Watershed Resilience. Ecosystems 26(1), 1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leibowitz SG, Mushet DM and Newton WE (2016) Intermittent surface water connectivity: Fill and spill vs. fill and merge dynamics. Wetlands 36(s2), 323&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuthold SJ, Ewing SA, Payn RA, Miller FR and Custer SG (2021) Seasonal connections between meteoric water and streamflow generation along a mountain headwater stream. Hydrological Processes 35(2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li DY, Wrzesien ML, Durand M, Adam J and Lettenmaier DP (2017) How much runoff originates as snow in the western United States, and how will that change in the future? Geophysical Research Letters 44(12), 6163&#x2013;6172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liotta M, Grassa F, D&#x2019;Alessandro W, Favara R, Gagliano Candela E, Pisciotta A and Scaletta C (2013) Isotopic composition of precipitation and groundwater in Sicily, Italy. Applied Geochemistry 34, 199&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litwin DG, Tucker GE, Barnhart KR and Harman CJ (2022) Groundwater Affects the Geomorphic and Hydrologic Properties of Coevolved Landscapes. Journal of Geophysical Research-Earth Surface 127(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyon SW, Nathanson M, Spans A, Grabs T, Laudon H, Temnerud J, Bishop KH and Seibert J (2012) Specific discharge variability in a boreal landscape. Water Resources Research 48(8).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloszewski P, Rauert W, Stichler W and Herrmann A (1983) Application of Flow Models in an Alpine Catchment-Area Using Tritium and Deuterium Data. Journal of Hydrology 66(1&#x2013;4), 319&#x2013;330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinelli LA, Victoria RL, Silveira Lobo Sternberg L, Ribeiro A and Zacharias Moreira M (1996) Using stable isotopes to determine sources of evaporated water to the atmosphere in the Amazon basin. Journal of Hydrology 183(3), 191&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGill LM, Brooks JR and Steel EA (2021) Spatiotemporal dynamics of water sources in a mountain river basin inferred through &#x3b4;2H and &#x3b4;18O of water. Hydrological Processes 35(3), e14063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlynn BL, McDonnel JJ and Brammer DD (2002) A review of the evolving perceptual model of hillslope flowpaths at the Maimai catchments, New Zealand. Journal of Hydrology 257(1&#x2013;4), 1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire KJ and McDonnell JJ (2006) A review and evaluation of catchment transit time modeling. Journal of Hydrology 330, 543&#x2013;563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire KJ, McDonnell JJ, Weiler M, Kendall C, McGlynn BL, Welker JM and Seibert J (2005) The role of topography on catchment-scale water residence time. Water Resources Research 41(5), W05002-W05002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan H, Westerberg I and Branger F (2017) Five Guidelines for Selecting Hydrological Signatures. Hydrological Processes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer JL, Strayer DL, Wallace JB, Eggert SL, Helfman GS and Leonard NE (2007) The Contribution of Headwater Streams to Biodiversity in River Networks1. JAWRA Journal of the American Water Resources Association 43(1), 86&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR and Wondzell S (2005) Physical hydrology and the effects of forest harvesting in the Pacific Northwest: a review. Journal of the American Water Resources Association 41(4), 763&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mote PW, Li S, Lettenmaier DP, Xiao M and Engel R (2018) Dramatic declines in snowpack in the western US. npj Climate and Atmospheric Science 1(1), 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller S, Stumpp C, Sorensen JH and Jessen S (2017) Spatiotemporal variation of stable isotopic composition in precipitation: Post-condensational effects in a humid area. Hydrological Processes 31(18), 3146&#x2013;3159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickolas LB, Segura C and Brooks JR (2017) The influence of lithology on surface water sources. Hydrological Processes 31(10), 1913&#x2013;1925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6171129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30294067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega J (2024) Driver of Relative Streamflow Contribution in Mountainous Headwater Streams. Masters Thesis, Oregon State University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng T-R, Chen K-Y, Zhan W-J, Lu W-C and Tong L-TJ (2015) Use of stable water isotopes to identify hydrological processes of meteoric water in montane catchments. Hydrological Processes 29(23), 4957&#x2013;4967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry TD and Jones JA (2017) Summer streamflow deficits from regenerating Douglas-fir forest in the Pacific Northwest, USA. Ecohydrology 10(2), e1790-n/a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips DL and Gregg JW (2003) Source partitioning using stable isotopes: coping with too many sources. Oecologia 136(2), 261&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12759813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips DL, Newsome SD and Gregg JW (2005) Combining sources in stable isotope mixing models: alternative methods. Oecologia 144(4), 520&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15711995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poage MA and Chamberlain CP (2001) Empirical relationships between elevation and the stable isotope composition of precipitation and surface waters: Considerations for studies of paleoelevation change. American Journal of Science 301(1), 1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putman AL, Fiorella RP, Bowen GJ and Cai Z (2019) A Global Perspective on Local Meteoric Water Lines: Meta-analytic Insight Into Fundamental Controls and Practical Constraints. Water Resources Research 55(8), 6896&#x2013;6910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu D, Tian L, Zhao H, Yao P, Xu B and Cui J (2020) Demonstration of a memory calibration method in water isotope measurement by laser spectroscopy. Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry 34(8), e8689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31802558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safeeq M and Hunsaker CT (2016) Characterizing Runoff and Water Yield for Headwater Catchments in the Southern Sierra Nevada. JAWRA Journal of the American Water Resources Association 52(6), 1327&#x2013;1346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Murillo R, Brooks ES, Elliot WJ and Boll J (2015) Isotope hydrology and baseflow geochemistry in natural and human-altered watersheds in the Inland Pacific Northwest, USA. Isotopes in Environmental and Health Studies 51(2), 231&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25692981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawicz K, Wagener T, Sivapalan M, Troch PA and Carrillo G (2011) Catchment classification: empirical analysis of hydrologic similarity based on catchment function in the eastern USA. Hydrology and Earth System Sciences 15(9), 2895&#x2013;2911.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seabold S and Perktold J (2010) Statsmodels: Econometric and Statistical Modeling with Python.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segura C (2021) Snow drought reduces water transit times in headwater streams. Hydrological Processes 35(12), e14437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segura C, Noone D, Warren D, Jones JA, Tenny J and Ganio L (2019) Climate, landforms, and geology affect baseflow sources in a mountain catchment. Water Resources Research 55, 5238&#x2013;5254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segura C, Perry Z and Ortega J (2024) Water stable isotopes for streams and precipitation samples in the HJ Andrews Experimental Forest and Mary&#x2019;s River Watershed, 2014&#x2013;2023. http://andlter.forestry.oregonstate.edu/data/abstract.aspx?dbcode=HF028., Long-Term Ecological Research. Forest Science Data Bank, Corvallis, OR. [Database]. 10.6073/pasta/f7bfbab3132ac23002d5df6e837a9d0e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6073/pasta/f7bfbab3132ac23002d5df6e837a9d0e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siirila-Woodburn ER, Rhoades AM, Hatchett BJ, Huning LS, Szinai J, Tague C, Nico PS, Feldman DR, Jones AD, Collins WD and Kaatz L (2021) A low-to-no snow future and its impacts on water resources in the western United States. Nature Reviews Earth &amp; Environment 2(11), 800&#x2013;819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sklash MG and Farvolden RN (1979) Role of groundwater in storm runoff. Journal of Hydrology 43, 45&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somers LD and McKenzie JM (2020) A review of groundwater in high mountain environments. WIREs Water 7(6), e1475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soulsby C, Birkel C, Geris J and Tetzlaff D (2015) Spatial aggregation of time-variant stream water ages in urbanizing catchments. Hydrological Processes 29(13), 3038&#x2013;3050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soulsby C, Malcolm R, Helliwell R, Ferrier RC and Jenkins A (2000) Isotope hydrology of the Allt a&#x2019; Mharcaidh catchment, Cairngorms, Scotland: implications for hydrological pathways and residence times. Hydrological Processes 14(4), 747&#x2013;762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soulsby C, Piegat K, Seibert J and Tetzlaff D (2011) Catchment-scale estimates of flow path partitioning and water storage based on transit time and runoff modelling. Hydrological Processes 25, 3960&#x2013;3976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soulsby C, Tetzlaff D, Rodgers P, Dunn S and Waldron S (2006) Runoff processes, stream water residence times and controlling landscape characteristics in a mesoscale catchment: An initial evaluation. Journal of Hydrology 325, 197&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence C (2007) On the relation between dynamic storage and runoff: A discussion on thresholds, efficiency, and function. Water Resources Research 43(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spies T (2013) LiDAR data (August 2008) for the Andrews Experimental Forest and Willamette National Forest study areas. [Database]. Long-Term Ecological Research. Forest Science Data Bank, C., OR. Available: http://andrewsforest.oregonstate.edu/data/abstract.cfm?dbcode=GI010 (26 January 2015). (ed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprenger M, Carroll RWH, Marchetti D, Bern C, Beria H, Brown W, Newman A, Beutler C and Williams KH (2024) Stream water sourcing from high-elevation snowpack inferred from stable isotopes of water: a novel application of d-excess values. Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci. 28(7), 1711&#x2013;1723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Clair J, Moon S, Holbrook WS, Perron JT, Riebe CS, Martel SJ, Carr B, Harman C, Singha K and Richter D (2015) Geophysical imaging reveals topographic stress control of bedrock weathering. Science 350(6260), 534&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26516279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stock BC, Jackson AL, Ward EJ, Parnell AC, Phillips DL and Semmens BX (2018) Analyzing mixing systems using a new generation of Bayesian tracer mixing models. PeerJ 6, e5096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6015753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29942712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson F and James M (1975) Geology and geomorphology of the H.J. Andrews Experimental Forest, western Cascades, Oregon. Res. Pap. PNW-188, p. 14, U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service, Pacific Northwest Forest and Range Experiment Station, Portland, OR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson FJ (2005) Upper Blue River geology clipped to the Andrews Experimental Forest, 1991. Long-Term Ecological Research. Forest Science Data Bank, Corvallis, OR. [Database]. Available: http://andlter.forestry.oregonstate.edu/data/abstract.aspx?dbcode=GE009 (12 November 2018) DOI: 10.6073/pasta/1c428e8798a2f3975f202636d3ad6139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6073/pasta/1c428e8798a2f3975f202636d3ad6139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson FJ (2013) Mass movement assessment: cascade hazards ratings, Andrews Experimental Forest, 1992. Long-Term Ecological Research
Forest Science Data Bank, Corvallis, OR. [Database]. Available: http://andlter.forestry.oregonstate.edu/data/abstract.aspx?dbcode=GE010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurber D, Lane B, Xu TF and Neilson BT (2024) Dissolving the mystery of subsurface controls on snowmelt-discharge dynamics in karst mountain watersheds using hydrologic timeseries. Hydrological Processes 38(5).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uhlenbrook S, Frey M, Leibundgut C and Maloszewski P (2002) Hydrograph separations in a mesoscale mountainous basin at event and seasonal timescales. Water Resources Research 38(6), 31&#x2013;31-31-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vano JA, Nijssen B and Lettenmaier DP (2015) Seasonal hydrologic responses to climate change in the Pacific Northwest. Water Resources Research 51(4), 1959&#x2013;1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verfaillie D, Lafaysse M, D&#xe9;qu&#xe9; M, Eckert N, Lejeune Y and Morin S (2018) Multi-component ensembles of future meteorological and natural snow conditions for 1500&#x202f;m altitude in the Chartreuse mountain range, Northern French Alps. The Cryosphere 12(4), 1249&#x2013;1271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss KA, Bookhagen B, Sachse D and Chadwick OA (2020) Variation of deuterium excess in surface waters across a 5000-m elevation gradient in eastern Nepal. Journal of Hydrology 586, 124802.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wampler KA, Bladon KD and Faramarzi M (2023) Modeling wildfire effects on streamflow in the Cascade Mountains, Oregon, USA. Journal of Hydrology 621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wassenaar LI, Athanasopoulos P and Hendry MJ (2011) Isotope hydrology of precipitation, surface and ground waters in the Okanagan Valley, British Columbia, Canada. Journal of Hydrology 411(1&#x2013;2), 37&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiler M, McDonnell JJ, Tromp-van Meerveld I and Uchida T (2005) Encyclopedia of Hydrological Sciences.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windler G, Brooks JR, Johnson HM, Comeleo RL, Coulombe R and Bowen GJ (2021) Climate Impacts on Source Contributions and Evaporation to Flow in the Snake River Basin Using Surface Water Isoscapes (&#x3b4;2H and &#x3b4;18O). Water Resources Research 57(7), e2020WR029157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao LL, Sankarasubramanian A and Wang DB (2021) Climatic and Landscape Controls on Long-Term Baseflow. Water Resources Research 57(6).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>