<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41251796</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0070-217X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current topics in microbiology and immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Top Microbiol Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Phytoplankton Cell Death Under the Global Change Scenario.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/82_2025_331</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Phytoplankton are aquatic unicellular eukaryotic (i.e. protists) or prokaryotic photosynthetic organisms thriving in the world oceans. They are at the base of aquatic food webs and play a key role in determining the effects of the environmental change on the ocean surface. Phytoplankton are responsible for around 50% of the net amount of carbon assimilated annually by photoautotrophs. The removal of atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub> does not only depend on CO<sub>2</sub> fixation, but long-term carbon sequestration also requires the export of the organic matter fixed by phytoplankton in the surface layer (euphotic zone) into the deep ocean via a suite of processes collectively referred to as the biological carbon pump (BCP). The BCP likely transports 5-12 Pg&#x2009;C year<sup>-1</sup> into the deep ocean where it is buried and where it remains between thousands and millions of years. Approximately 50% of the CO<sub>2</sub> emitted by human activity accumulates in the atmosphere, causing an increase in the average temperature of the Earth's surface and oceans. Around 40% of the CO<sub>2</sub> emitted into the atmosphere is absorbed by the surface layers of the oceans, causing ocean acidification (OA) due to the increase in CO<sub>2</sub> concentration in the water. We are therefore currently facing one of the greatest challenges of the twenty-first century. The scenario based on the SSP5-8.5 climate simulation (IPCC, AR6 2021) closely matches the total historical accumulated CO<sub>2</sub> emissions (within 1%); moreover, this SSP5-8.5 scenario best represents mid-century greenhouse gas concentrations with current and declared emission policies, while forecasting very plausible atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub> levels of 1,200 &#x3bc;atm by 2,100. Considering that even small changes in the BCP can have substantial effects on atmospheric CO<sub>2</sub> levels, thus, the response of the BCP to future climate change is uncertain. Phytoplankton dynamics are driven by imbalances between growth and loss processes that are controlled by a combination of physical, chemical, and biological factors (drivers). Usually, grazing by zooplankton and viral infections stand at the base of phytoplankton population collapses. However, cell death (CD) also accounts for phytoplankton losses. Accumulating evidence suggests that CD, accidental (ACD) or regulated (RCD), occurs in phytoplankton under diverse environmental stresses, both in natural phytoplankton communities and in laboratory controlled experiments. GC affects phytoplankton species composition and size structure and favours species traits best acclimated and/or adapted to changing conditions associated with global change. Shifts in phytoplankton can have far-reaching consequences for the entire food web. The way phytoplankton dies critically determines marine ecosystem structure, functioning, and services. We aim in this chapter at capturing, re-grouping, and thoroughly analysing all the GC drivers studied up to date that cause cell death and/or severe stress in phytoplankton, trying to gain further insight on what could be the subsequent cell death outcome regarding the BCP.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Segovia</LastName><ForeName>Mar&#xed;a</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9765-5817</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Department of Ecology, University of M&#xe1;laga, M&#xe1;laga, Spain. segovia@uma.es.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ram&#xed;rez</LastName><ForeName>Librada</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8854-2821</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Department of Ecology, University of M&#xe1;laga, M&#xe1;laga, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Top Microbiol Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0110513</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0070-217X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biological carbon pump (BCP)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon dioxide (CO2)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell death</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Climate change (CC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Global change (GC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Global change drivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Marine ecosystems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ocean acidification (OA)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ocean warming</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phytoplankton</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultraviolet radiation (UVR)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41251796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/82_2025_331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; S (2004) Viability and niche segregation of Prochlorococcus and Synechococcus cells across the Central Atlantic Ocean. Aquat Microb Ecol 36(1):53&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.3354/ame036053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/ame036053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; S, Duarte CM (2000) Strong seasonality in phytoplankton cell lysis in the NW Mediterranean littoral. Limnol Oceanogr 45(4):940&#x2013;947. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.2000.45.4.0940</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.2000.45.4.0940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; S, S&#xe1;nchez MC (2002) Cell viability in natural phytoplankton communities quantified by a membrane permeability probe. Limnol Oceanogr 47(3):818&#x2013;828. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.2002.47.3.0818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.2002.47.3.0818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; S, Satta MP, Mura MP, Benavent E (1998) Dissolved esterase activity as a tracer of phytoplankton lysis: evidence of high phytoplankton lysis rates in the northwestern Mediterranean. Limnol Oceanogr 43(8):1836. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.1998.43.8.1836</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.1998.43.8.1836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agust&#xed; S, Duarte CM, Vaqu&#xe9; D, Hein M, Gasol JM, Vidal M (2001) Food-web structure and elemental (C, N and P) fluxes in the eastern tropical North Atlantic. Deep-Sea Res II Top Stud Oceanogr 48(10):2295&#x2013;2321. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0967-0645(00)00179-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0967-0645(00)00179-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ainsworth TD, Wasmund K, Ukani L, Seneca F, Yellowlees D, Miller D, Leggat W (2011) Defining the tipping point: a complex cellular life/death balance in corals in response to stress. Sci Rep 1:160. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep00160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep00160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews OD, Bindoff NL, Halloran PR, Iudicone D, Le Qu&#xe9;r&#xe9; C (2013) Detecting an external influence on recent changes in oceanic oxygen using an optimal fingerprinting method. Biogeosciences 10(3):1799&#x2013;1813. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-10-1799-2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-10-1799-2013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker KG, Geider RJ (2021) Phytoplankton mortality in a changing thermal seascape. Glob Chang Biol 27:5253&#x2013;5261. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.15772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.15772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakun A, Field DB, Redondo-Rodriguez A, Weeks SJ (2010) Greenhouse gas, upwelling-favorable winds, and the future of coastal ocean upwelling ecosystems. Glob Chang Biol 16(4):1213&#x2013;1228. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2486.2009.02094.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2486.2009.02094.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banaszak AT, Trench RK (1995) Effects of ultraviolet (UV) radiation on marine microalgal-invertebrate symbioses. I. Response of the algal symbionts in culture and in hospite. J Exp Mar Biol Ecol 194(2):213&#x2013;232. https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-0981(95)00072-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-0981(95)00072-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Zeev E, Avishay I, Bidle KD, Berman-Frank I (2013) Programmed cell death in the marine cyanobacterium Trichodesmium mediates carbon and nitrogen export. ISME J 7(12):2340&#x2013;2348. https://doi.org/10.1038/ismej.2013.121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ismej.2013.121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berges JA, Falkowski PG (1998) Physiological stress and cell death in marine phytoplankton: induction of proteases in response to nitrogen or light limitation. Limnol Oceanogr 43(1):129&#x2013;135. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.1998.43.1.0129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.1998.43.1.0129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berman-Frank I, Bidle KD, Haramaty L, Falkowski PG (2004) The demise of the marine cyanobacterium, Trichodesmium spp., via an autocatalyzed cell death pathway. Limnol Oceanogr 49(4):997&#x2013;1005. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.2004.49.4.0997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.2004.49.4.0997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berman-Frank I, Quigg A, Finkel ZV, Irwin AJ, Haramaty L (2007) Nitrogen-fixation strategies and Fe requirements in cyanobacteria. Limnol Oceanogr 52(5):2260&#x2013;2269. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.2007.52.5.2260</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.2007.52.5.2260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boelen P, van de Poll WH, van der Strate HJ, Neven IA, Beardall J, Buma AGJ (2011) Neither elevated nor reduced CO2 affects the photophysiological performance of the marine Antarctic diatom Chaetoceros brevis. J Exp Mar Biol Ecol 406(1&#x2013;2):38&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jembe.2011.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jembe.2011.06.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard JN, Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez C, Lorenzo MR et al (2013) Differential effect of ultraviolet exposure (UVR) in the stress response of the Dinophycea Gymnodinium sp. and the Chlorophyta Dunaliella tertiolecta: mortality versus survival. Mar Biol 160(10):2547&#x2013;2560. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00227-013-2247-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00227-013-2247-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd PW, Doney SC (2002) Modelling regional responses by marine pelagic ecosystems to global climate change. Geophys Res Lett 29(16):531&#x2013;534. https://doi.org/10.1029/2001GL014130</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2001GL014130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyd PW, Hutchins DA (2012) Understanding the responses of ocean biota to a complex matrix of cumulative anthropogenic change. Mar Ecol Prog Ser 470:125&#x2013;135. https://doi.org/10.3354/meps10121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps10121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brussaard CPD, Noordeloos AAM, Riegman R (1997) Autolysis kinetics of the marine diatom Ditylum brightwellii (Bacillariophyceae) under nitrogen and phosphorus limitation and starvation. J Phycol 33:980&#x2013;987. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0022-3646.1997.00980.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0022-3646.1997.00980.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Gutierrez D, Bauer MA, Zimmermann A, Aguilera A et al (2018) Guidelines and recommendations on yeast cell death nomenclature. Microbial Cell 5(1):4&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.15698/mic2018.01.607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15698/mic2018.01.607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi CJ, Brosnahan ML, Sehein TR, Anderson DM, Erdner DL (2017) Insights into the loss factors of phytoplankton blooms: the role of cell mortality in the decline of two inshore Alexandrium blooms. Limnol Oceanogr 62:1742&#x2013;1753. https://doi.org/10.1002/lno.10530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lno.10530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung C, Hwang SL, Chang J (2008) Nitric oxide as a signaling factor to upregulate the death-specific protein in a marine diatom, Skeletonema costatum, during blockage of electron flow in photosynthesis. Appl Environ Microbiol 74:2315&#x2013;2321. https://doi.org/10.1128/AEM.01481-08</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.01481-08</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciais P et al (2013) Carbon and other biogeochemical cycles. In: Stocker TF, Qin D, Plattner G-K, Tignor M, Allen SK, Boschung J, Nauels A, Xia Y, Bex V, Midgley PM (eds) Climate change 2013: the physical science basis. Contribution of working group I to the fifth assessment report of the intergovernmental panel on climate change. Cambridge University Press, pp 465&#x2013;570. https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9781107415324.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/CBO9781107415324.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crutzen PJ, Stoermer EF (2001) The anthropocene. In: Global change and the earth system: a planet under pressure. Springer, New York, pp 12&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Bodt C, Van Oostende N, Harlay J, Sabbe K, Chou L (2010) Individual and interacting effects of pCO2 and temperature on Emiliania huxleyi calcification: study of the calcite production, coccolith morphology, and coccosphere size. Biogeosciences 7(5):1401&#x2013;1412. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-7-1401-2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-7-1401-2010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingman JE, Lawrence JE (2012) Heat-stress induced programmed cell death in Heterosigma akashiwo (Raphidophyceae). Harmful Algae 16:108&#x2013;116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doney SC, Fabry VJ, Feely RA, Kleypas JA (2009) Ocean acidification: the other CO2 problem. Annu Rev Mar Sci 1(1):169&#x2013;192. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.marine.010908.163834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.marine.010908.163834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doney SC, Busch DS, Cooley SR, Kroeker KJ (2020) The impacts of ocean acidification on marine ecosystems and reliant human communities. Annu Rev Environ Resour 45:83&#x2013;112. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-environ-012320-083019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-environ-012320-083019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas AE (2003) Coral bleaching &#x2013; how and why? Mar Pollut Bull 46(4):385&#x2013;392. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0025-326X(03)0003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0025-326X(03)0003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn SR, Bythell JC, Le Tissier MDA, Burnett WJ, Thomason JC (2002) Programmed cell death and cell necrosis activity during hyperthermic stress-induced bleaching of the symbiotic sea anemone Aiptasia sp. J Exp Mar Biol Ecol 272(1):29&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-0981(02)00036-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-0981(02)00036-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durand PM, Ramsey G (2019) The nature of programmed cell death. Biol Theory 14:30&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13752-018-0311-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13752-018-0311-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durand PM, Choudhury R, Rashidi A, Michod RE (2014) Programmed death in a unicellular organism has species-specific fitness effects. Biol Lett 10(2):20131088. https://doi.org/10.1098/rsbl.2013.1088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsbl.2013.1088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykens JA, Shick JM, Benoit C, Buettner GR, Winston GW (1992) Oxygen radical production in the sea anemone Anthopleura elegantissima and its endosymbiotic algae. J Exp Biol 168:219&#x2013;241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisaman M, Geilert S, Renforth P, Bastianini L, Campbell J, Dale A et al (2023) Assessing technical aspects of ocean alkalinity enhancement approaches. State Planet Discussions 2023:1&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.5194/sp-2023-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/sp-2023-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans C, Malin G, Mills GP, Wilson WH (2006) Viral infection of Emiliania huxleyi (Prymnesiophyceae) leads to elevated production of reactive oxygen species. J Phycol 42(5):1040&#x2013;1047. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1529-8817.2006.00256.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1529-8817.2006.00256.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farman J, Gardiner B, Shanklin J (1985) Large losses of total ozone in Antarctica reveal seasonal ClOx/NOx interaction. Nature 315:207&#x2013;210. https://doi.org/10.1038/315207a0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/315207a0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Warner ME, Zhang Y, Sun J, Fu FX, Rose JM, Hutchins DA (2008) Interactive effects of increased pCO2, temperature and irradiance on the marine coccolithophore Emiliania huxleyi (Prymnesiophyceae). Eur J Phycol 43(1):87&#x2013;98. https://doi.org/10.1080/09670260701664674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09670260701664674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng EY, Koeve W, Keller DP, Oschlies A (2017) Model-based assessment of the CO2 sequestration potential of coastal ocean alkalinization. Earth&#x2019;s Future 5(12):1252&#x2013;1266. https://doi.org/10.1002/2017EF000659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2017EF000659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferderer A, Chase Z, Kennedy F, Schulz KG, Bach LT (2022) Assessing the influence of ocean alkalinity enhancement on a coastal phytoplankton community. Biogeosciences 19(23):5375&#x2013;5399. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-19-5375-2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-19-5375-2022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field CB (1998) Primary production of the biosphere: integrating terrestrial and oceanic components. Science 281(5374):237&#x2013;240. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.281.5374.237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.281.5374.237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foresi N, Correa-Aragunde N, Parisi G, Cal&#xf3; G, Salerno G, Lamattina L (2010) Characterization of a nitric oxide synthase from the plant kingdom: NO generation from the green alga Ostreococcus tauri is light irradiance and growth phase dependent. Plant Cell 22(11):3816&#x2013;3830. https://doi.org/10.1105/tpc.109.073510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1105/tpc.109.073510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin DJ, Hoegh-Guldberg O, Jones RJ, Berges JA (2004) Cell death and degeneration in the symbiotic dinoflagellates of the coral Stylophora pistillata during bleaching. Mar Ecol Prog Ser:117&#x2013;130. https://doi.org/10.3354/meps272117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuess LE, Pinz&#xf3;n JHC, Weil E, Grinshpon RD, Mydlarz LD (2017) Life or death: disease-tolerant coral species activate autophagy following immune challenge. Proc R Soc B Biol Sci 284(1856):20170771. https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2017.0771</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rspb.2017.0771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallina AA, Brunet C, Palumbo A, Casotti R (2014) The effect of polyunsaturated aldehydes on Skeletonema marinoi (Bacillariophyceae): the involvement of reactive oxygen species and nitric oxide. Mar Drugs 12(7):4165&#x2013;4187. https://doi.org/10.3390/md12074165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/md12074165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Erdner DL (2022) Cell death responses to acute high light mediated by non-photochemical quenching in the dinoflagellate Karenia brevis. Sci Rep 12:14081. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-18056-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao K, Xu J, Gao G, Li Y, Hutchins DA, Huang B, Wang L, Zheng Y, Jin P, Cai X, H&#xe4;der D-P (2012) Rising CO2 and increased light exposure synergistically reduce marine primary productivity. Nat Clim Chang 2:519&#x2013;523. https://doi.org/10.1038/nclimate1507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nclimate1507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao K, Beardall J, H&#xe4;der D-P, Hall-Spencer JM, Gao G, Hutchins DA (2019) Effects of ocean acidification on marine photosynthetic organisms under the concurrent influences of warming, UV radiation, and deoxygenation. Front Mar Sci 6. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2019.00322</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez C, Parages ML, Jim&#xe9;nez C, Palma A, Mata MT, Segovia M (2012) Cell survival after UV radiation stress in the unicellular chlorophyte Dunaliella tertiolecta is mediated by DNA repair and MAPK phosphorylation. J Exp Bot 63(14):5259&#x2013;5274. https://doi.org/10.1093/jxb/ers185</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/ers185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez C, Gordillo FJL, Palma A et al (2014) Elevated CO2 alleviates high PAR and UV stress in the unicellular chlorophyte Dunaliella tertiolecta. Photochem Photobiol Sci 13:1347&#x2013;1358. https://doi.org/10.1039/c4pp00044g</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c4pp00044g</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez C, Mata MT, Van Breusegem F, Segovia M (2016) Low-steady-state metabolism induced by elevated CO2 increases resilience to UV radiation in the unicellular green-algae Dunaliella tertiolecta. Environ Exp Bot 132:163&#x2013;174. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envexpbot.2016.09.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envexpbot.2016.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Santana D, Segovia M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-D&#xe1;vila M, Ram&#xed;rez L, Gonz&#xe1;lez AG, Pozzo-Pirotta LJ, Arnone V, V&#xe1;zquez V, Riebesell U, Santana-Casiano JM (2024) Ocean alkalinity enhancement using sodium carbonate salts does not lead to measurable changes in Fe dynamics in a mesocosm experiment. Biogeosciences 21:2705&#x2013;2715. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-2705-2024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-21-2705-2024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff van Creveld S, Rosenwasser S, Schatz D, Koren I, Vardi A (2015) Early perturbation in mitochondria redox homeostasis in response to environmental stress predicts cell fate in diatoms. ISME J 9(2):385&#x2013;395. https://doi.org/10.1038/ismej.2014.136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ismej.2014.136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;der D-P, Kumar HD, Smith RC, Worrest RC (2007) Effects of solar UV radiation on aquatic ecosystems and interactions with climate change. Photochem Photobiol Sci 6(3):267&#x2013;285. https://doi.org/10.1039/B700020K</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/B700020K</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao T-B, Balamurugan S, Yang W-D, Wang X, Li H-Y (2021) Regulatory role of death specific protein in response to nutrient limitation in a marine diatom. Algal Res 58:102392. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.algal.2021.102392</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.algal.2021.102392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann J, West AJ, Renforth P, K&#xf6;hler P, De La Rocha CL, Wolf-Gladrow DA, D&#xfc;rr HH, Scheffran J (2013) Enhanced chemical weathering as a geoengineering strategy to reduce atmospheric carbon dioxide, supply nutrients, and mitigate ocean acidification. Rev Geophys 51(2):113&#x2013;149. https://doi.org/10.1002/rog.20004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rog.20004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helgoe J, Davy SK, Weis VM, Rodriguez-Lanetty M (2024) Triggers, cascades, and endpoints: connecting the dots of coral bleaching mechanisms. Biol Rev 99:715&#x2013;752. https://doi.org/10.1111/brv.13042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/brv.13042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helm KP, Bindoff NL, Church JA (2011) Observed decreases in oxygen content of the global ocean. Geophys Res Lett 38:L23602. https://doi.org/10.1029/2011GL049513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2011GL049513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchins DA, Fu F-X, Yang S-C, John SG, Romaniello SJ, Andrews MG, Walworth NG (2023) Responses of globally important phytoplankton species to olivine dissolution products and implications for carbon dioxide removal via ocean alkalinity enhancement. Biogeosciences 20:4669&#x2013;4682. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-20-4669-2023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-20-4669-2023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IPCC (2021) Climate change 2021: the physical science basis. In: Masson-Delmotte V, Zhai P, Pirani A et al (eds) Contribution of working group I to the sixth assessment report of the intergovernmental panel on climate change. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, p 2391. https://doi.org/10.1017/9781009157896</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/9781009157896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janknegt PJ, De Graaff CM, Van De Poll WH, Visser RJW, Rijstenbil JW, Buma AGJ (2009) Short-term antioxidative responses of 15 microalgae exposed to excessive irradiance including ultraviolet radiation. Eur J Phycol 44(4):525&#x2013;539. https://doi.org/10.1080/09670260902943273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09670260902943273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jauzein C, Erdner DL (2013) Stress-related responses in Alexandrium tamarense cells exposed to environmental changes. J Eukaryot Microbiol 60(4):437&#x2013;449. https://doi.org/10.1111/jeu.12065</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jeu.12065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RJ, Hoegh-Guldberg O, Larkum AWD, Schreiber U (1998) Temperature-induced bleaching of corals begins with impairment of the CO2 fixation mechanism in zooxanthellae. Plant Cell Environ 21(12):1219&#x2013;1230. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365-3040.1998.00345.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-3040.1998.00345.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeling CD, Mook WG, Tans PP (1979) Recent trends in the 13C/12C ratio of atmospheric carbon dioxide. Nature 277(5692):121&#x2013;123. https://doi.org/10.1038/277121a0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/277121a0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kheshgi HS (1995) Sequestering atmospheric carbon dioxide by increasing ocean alkalinity. Energy 20(9):915&#x2013;922. https://doi.org/10.1016/0360-5442(95)00035-F</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0360-5442(95)00035-F</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvitt H, Rosenfeld H, Tchernov D (2016) The regulation of thermal stress induced apoptosis in corals reveals high similarities in gene expression and function to higher animals. Sci Rep 6:30359. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep30359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep30359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasternas S, Piedeleu M, Sangr&#xe0; P, Duarte CM, Agust&#xed; S (2012) Carbon fluxes forced by anticyclonic mesoscale eddies generated by islands at the subtropical NE Atlantic Ocean. Biogeosci Discuss 9(8):10241&#x2013;10274. https://doi.org/10.5194/bgd-9-10241-2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bgd-9-10241-2012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesser MP (2006) Oxidative stress in marine environments: biochemistry and physiological ecology. Annu Rev Physiol 68:253&#x2013;278. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.physiol.68.040104.110001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.physiol.68.040104.110001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesser MP, Farrell JH (2004) Exposure to solar radiation increases damage to both host tissues and algal symbionts of corals during thermal stress. Coral Reefs 23:367&#x2013;377. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-004-039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00338-004-039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesser MP, Barry TM, Banaszak AT (2002) Effects of UV radiation on a chlorophyte alga (Scenedesmus sp.) isolated from the fumarole fields of Mt. Erebus, Antarctica. J Phycol 38(3):473&#x2013;481. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1529-8817.2002.01171.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1529-8817.2002.01171.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levitan O, Rosenberg G, Setlik I, Setlikova E, Grigel J, Klepetar J, Prasil O, Berman-Frank I (2007) Elevated CO2 enhances nitrogen fixation and growth in the marine cyanobacterium Trichodesmium. Glob Chang Biol 13(3):531&#x2013;538. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2486.2006.01314.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2486.2006.01314.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Gao K (2023) Deoxygenation enhances photosynthetic performance and increases N2 fixation in the marine cyanobacterium Trichodesmium under elevated pCO2. Front Microbiol 14:1102909. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2023.1102909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2023.1102909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Beardall J, Gao K (2018) Diatom performance in a future ocean: interactions between nitrogen limitation, temperature, and CO2-induced seawater acidification. ICES J Mar Sci 75(4):1451&#x2013;1464. https://doi.org/10.1093/icesjms/fsx239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/icesjms/fsx239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Listmann L, LeRoch M, Schl&#xfc;ter L, Thomas MK, Reusch TBH (2016) Swift thermal reaction norm evolution in a key marine phytoplankton species. Evol Appl 9(9):1156&#x2013;1164. https://doi.org/10.1111/eva.12362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eva.12362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llabr&#xe9;s M, Agust&#xed; S (2006) Picophytoplankton cell death induced by UV radiation: evidence for oceanic Atlantic communities. Limnol Oceanogr 51:21&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.2006.51.1.0021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.2006.51.1.0021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longhi ML, Ferreyra G, Schloss I, Roy S (2006) Variable phytoplankton response to enhanced UV-B and nitrate addition in mesocosm experiments at three latitudes (Canada, Brazil, and Argentina). Mar Ecol Prog Ser 313:57&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.3354/meps313057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps313057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenzo MR, Segovia M, Cullen JT, Maldonado MT (2020) Particulate trace metal dynamics in response to increased CO2 and iron availability in a coastal mesocosm experiment. Biogeosciences 17(3):757&#x2013;770. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-17-757-2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-17-757-2020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannfolk A (2016) Will nitrogen limitation and high CO&#x2082; concentrations impact upon the sinking velocity of phytoplankton? Doctoral dissertation, Monash University</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mata MT, Palma A, Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez C, L&#xf3;pez-Parages M, V&#xe1;zquez V, Cheng-S&#xe1;nchez I, Sarabia F, L&#xf3;pez-Figueroa F, Jim&#xe9;nez C, Segovia M (2019) Type II-Metacaspases are involved in cell stress but not in cell death in the unicellular green alga Dunaliella tertiolecta. Microbial Cell 6(11):494&#x2013;508. https://doi.org/10.15698/mic2019.11.696</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15698/mic2019.11.696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mausz MA, Segovia M, Larsen A, Berger SA, Egge JK, Pohnert G (2020) High CO2 concentration and iron availability determine the metabolic inventory in an Emiliania huxleyi-dominated phytoplankton community. Environ Microbiol 22:3863&#x2013;3882. https://doi.org/10.1111/1462-2920.15160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1462-2920.15160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millero FJ, Graham TB, Huang F, Bustos-Serrano H, Pierrot D (2009) The pH of seawater: a critical review of the fundamentals. Mar Chem 113(1&#x2013;2):4&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marchem.2009.04.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marchem.2009.04.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris LA, Voolstra CR, Quigley KM, Bourne DG, Bay LK (2019) Nutrient availability and metabolism affect the stability of coral&#x2013;Symbiodiniaceae symbioses. Trends Microbiol 27(8):678&#x2013;689. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tim.2019.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tim.2019.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neale PJ, Sobrino C, Segovia M, Mercado JM et al (2014) Effect of CO2, nutrients and light on coastal plankton. I. Abiotic conditions and biological responses. Aquat Biol 22(1):25&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.3354/ab00587</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/ab00587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen DA, Petrou K, Gates RD (2018) Coral bleaching from a single cell perspective. ISME J 12(6):1558&#x2013;1567. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41396-018-0080-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41396-018-0080-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orellana MV, Pang WL, Durand PM, Whitehead K, Baliga NS (2013) A role for programmed cell death in the microbial loop. PLoS One 8. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0062595</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez SF, Cook CB, Brooks WR (2001) The role of symbiotic dinoflagellates in the temperature-induced bleaching response of the subtropical sea anemone Aiptasia pallida. J Exp Mar Biol Ecol 256(1):1&#x2013;14. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-0981(00)00282-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-0981(00)00282-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter KH, Sommer U (2013) Phytoplankton cell size reduction in response to warming mediated by nutrient limitation. PLoS One 8. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0071528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piscoya E, von Dassow P, Aldunate M, Vargas CA (2022) Physical-chemical factors influencing the vertical distribution of phototrophic pico-nanoplankton in the oxygen minimum zone (OMZ) off northern Chile: the relative influence of low pH/low O2 conditions. Mar Environ Res 180:105710. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.marenvres.2022.105710</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marenvres.2022.105710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polovina JJ, Howell EA, Abecassis M (2008) Ocean&#x2019;s least productive waters are expanding. Geophys Res Lett 35(3):L03618. https://doi.org/10.1029/2007GL031745</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2007GL031745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu P, Fu F, Hutchins DA (2018) Responses of the large centric diatom Coscinodiscus sp. to interactions between warming, elevated CO2, and nitrate availability. Limnol Oceanogr 63(3):1407&#x2013;1424. https://doi.org/10.1002/lno.10781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lno.10781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabalais NN, Diaz RJ, Levin LA, Turner RE, Gilbert D, Zhang J (2009) Dynamics and distribution of natural and human-caused hypoxia. Biogeosciences 6(12):2063&#x2013;2094. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-6-2063-2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-6-2063-2009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xed;rez L, Pozzo-Pirotta LJ, Trebec A, Manzanares-V&#xe1;zquez V, D&#xed;ez JL, Ar&#xed;stegui J, Riebesell U, Archer SD, Segovia M (2024) Ocean alkalinity enhancement (OAE) does not cause cellular stress in a phytoplankton community of the sub-tropical Atlantic Ocean. EGUsphere. https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-847</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raven JA, Giordano M, Beardall J et al (2011) Algal and aquatic plant carbon concentrating mechanisms in relation to environmental change. Photosynth Res 109(3):281&#x2013;296. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-011-9632-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11120-011-9632-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renforth P, Henderson G (2017) Assessing Ocean alkalinity for carbon sequestration. Rev Geophys 55(3):636&#x2013;674. https://doi.org/10.1002/2016RG000533</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/2016RG000533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riahi K, van Vuuren DP, Kriegler E, Edmonds J, O&#x2019;Neill BC, Fujimori S, Bauer N, Calvin K, Dellink R, Fricko O, Lutz W, Popp A, Cuaresma JC, Samir KC, Leimbach M, Jiang L, Kram T, Rao S, Emmerling J, Hasegawa T (2017) The shared socioeconomic pathways and their energy, land use, and greenhouse gas emissions implications: an overview. Glob Environ Chang 42:153&#x2013;168. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2016.05.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2016.05.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riebesell U, Tortell PD (2011) Effects of ocean acidification on pelagic organisms and ecosystems. In: Ocean acidification. Oxford University Press, pp 99&#x2013;121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riebesell U, Bellerby RGJ, Grossart HP, Thingstad F (2008) Mesocosm CO2 perturbation studies: from organism to community level. Biogeosciences 5(4):1157&#x2013;1164. https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-5-1157-2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/bg-5-1157-2008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riebesell U, Basso D, Geilert S, Dale AW, Kreuzburg M, Meysman F (2023) Mesocosm experiments in ocean alkalinity enhancement research. State Planet Discussions 2023:1&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.5194/sp-2023-11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5194/sp-2023-11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins SJ, Singleton CM, Chan CX, Messer LF, Geers AU, Ying H, Baker A, Bell SC, Morrow KM, Ragan MA, Miller DJ, For&#xea;t S, ReFuGe2020 Consortium, Voolstra CR, Tyson GW, Bourne DG (2019) A genomic view of the reef-building coral Porites lutea and its microbial symbionts. Nat Microbiol 4(12):2090&#x2013;2100. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41564-019-0532-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rokitta SD, Rost B (2012) Effects of CO2 and their modulation by light in the life-cycle stages of the coccolithophore Emiliania huxleyi. Limnol Oceanogr 57(2):607&#x2013;618. https://doi.org/10.4319/lo.2012.57.2.0607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4319/lo.2012.57.2.0607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenwasser S, Graff van Creveld S, Schatz D, Malitsky S, Tzfadia O, Aharoni A, Levin Y, Gabashvili A, Feldmesser E, Vardi A (2014) Mapping the diatom redox-sensitive proteome provides insight into response to nitrogen stress in the marine environment. Proc Natl Acad Sci 111(7):2740&#x2013;2745. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1319773111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1319773111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rost B, Riebesell U (2004) Coccolithophores and the biological pump: responses to environmental changes. In: Thierstein HR, Young JR (eds) Coccolithophores. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, pp 99&#x2013;125. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-662-06278-4_5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-662-06278-4_5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabine CL, Feely RA, Gruber N, Key RM, Lee K, Bullister JL et al (2004) The oceanic sink for anthropogenic CO2. Science 305(5682):367&#x2013;371. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1097403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1097403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schl&#xfc;ter L, Lohbeck K, Gutowska M et al (2014) Adaptation of a globally important coccolithophore to ocean warming and acidification. Nat Clim Chang 4:1024&#x2013;1030. https://doi.org/10.1038/nclimate2379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nclimate2379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segovia M (2008) Programmed cell death in dinoflagellates. In: Programmed cell death in protozoa. Molecular biology intelligence unit. Springer, New York. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-0-387-76717-8_11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-0-387-76717-8_11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segovia M, Berges JA (2009) Inhibition of caspase-like activities prevents the appearance of reactive oxygen species and dark-induced apoptosis in the unicellular chlorophyte Dunaliella tertiolecta. J Phyco 45(5):1116&#x2013;1126. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1529-8817.2009.00750.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segovia M, Lorenzo MR, Maldonado MT, Aud L, Berger SA, Tsagaraki TM et al (2017) Iron availability modulates the effects of future CO2 levels within the marine planktonic food web. Mar Ecol Prog Ser 565:17&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.3354/meps12025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps12025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segovia M, Lorenzo MR, I&#xf1;iguez C, Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez C (2018) Physiological stress response associated with elevated CO2 and dissolved iron in a phytoplankton community dominated by the coccolithophore Emiliania huxleyi. Mar Ecol Prog Ser 586:73&#x2013;89. https://doi.org/10.3354/meps12389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/meps12389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sett S, Bach LT, Schulz KG, Koch-Klavsen S, Lebrato M et al (2014) Temperature modulates coccolithophorid sensitivity of growth, photosynthesis, and calcification to increasing seawater pCO2. PLoS One 9(2):e88308. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0088308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0088308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobrino C, Neale PJ, Lubi&#xe1;n LM (2005) Interaction of UV radiation and inorganic carbon supply in the inhibition of photosynthesis: spectral and temporal responses of two marine Picoplankters. Photochem Photobiol 81:384&#x2013;393. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1751-1097.2005.tb00198.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1751-1097.2005.tb00198.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobrino C, Segovia M, Neale PJ, Mercado JM et al (2014) Effect of CO2, nutrients and light on coastal plankton. IV. Physiological responses. Aquat Biol 22(1):77&#x2013;93. https://doi.org/10.3354/ab00590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3354/ab00590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strychar KB, Sammarco PW, Piva TJ (2004) Apoptotic and necrotic stages of Symbiodinium(Dinophyceae) cell death activity: bleaching of soft and scleractinian corals. Phycologia 43:768&#x2013;777</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suggett DJ, Smith DJ (2020) Coral bleaching patterns are the outcome of complex biological and environmental networking. Glob Chang Biol 26(1):68&#x2013;79. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.14871</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.14871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatters AO, Schnetzer A, Xu K, Walworth NG, Fu F, Spackeen JL, Sipler RE, Bertrand EM, McQuaid JB, Allen AE, Bronk DA, Gao K, Sun J, Caron DA, Hutchins DA (2018) Interactive effects of temperature, CO2 and nitrogen source on a coastal California diatom assemblage. J Plankton Res 40(2):151&#x2013;164. https://doi.org/10.1093/plankt/fbx074</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/plankt/fbx074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas MK, Aranguren-Gassis M, Kremer CT, Gould MR, Anderson K, Klausmeier CA, Litchman E (2017) Temperature&#x2013;nutrient interactions exacerbate sensitivity to warming in phytoplankton. Glob Chang Biol 23:3269&#x2013;3280. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.13641</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.13641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor-Knowles N, Granger BR, Lubinski TJ et al (2011) Production of a reference transcriptome and transcriptomic database (PocilloporaBase) for the cauliflower coral, Pocillopora damicornis. BMC Genomics 12:585. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2164-12-585</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-12-585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trench RK (1988) Specificity in dinomastigote-marine invertebrate symbioses: an evaluation of hypotheses of mechanisms involved in producing specificity. In: Scannerini S, Smith D, Bonfante-Fasolo P, Gianinazzi-Pearson V (eds) Cell to cell signals in plant, animal and microbial Symbiosis. NATO ASI series, vol 17. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-73154-9_23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-73154-9_23</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Woesik R, Shlesinger T, Grottoli AG et al (2022) Coral-bleaching responses to climate change across biological scales. Glob Chang Biol 28:4229&#x2013;4250. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.16192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.16192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez V, Le&#xf3;n P, Gordillo FJL, Jim&#xe9;nez C, I&#xf1;iguez C, Mackenzie K, Bresnan E, Segovia M (2022) High CO<sub>2</sub> levels rather than acidification restrict Emiliania huxleyi growth and performance. Microb Ecol. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00248-022-02035-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Mi T, Zhen Y, Jing X, Liu Q, Yu Z (2017) Metacaspases and programmed cell death in Skeletonema marinoi in response to silicate limitation. J Plankton Res 39(4):729&#x2013;743. https://doi.org/10.1093/plankt/fbw090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Wang R, Meng L, Chang W, Chen J, Liu C, Song Y, Ding N, Gao P (2024) A laboratory study of the increasing competitiveness of Karenia mikimotoi under rising CO2 scenario. Sci Total Environ 926:171688. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.171688</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.171688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warner ME, Fitt WK, Schmidt GW (1999) Damage to photosystem II in symbiotic dinoflagellates: a determinant of coral bleaching. Proc Natl Acad Sci 96(14):8007&#x2013;8012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weeks SJ, Currie B, Bakun A, Peard KR (2002) Hydrogen sulphide eruptions in the Atlantic Ocean off southern Africa: implications of a new view based on SeaWiFS satellite imagery. Deep-Sea Res I Oceanogr Res Pap 49(1):67&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0967-0637(01)00047-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0967-0637(01)00047-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weis VM (2008) Cellular mechanisms of cnidarian bleaching: stress causes the collapse of symbiosis. J Exp Biol 211(19):3059&#x2013;3066. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.009597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.009597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JCY, Raven JA, Aldunate M, Silva S, Gait&#xe1;n-Espitia JD, Vargas CA, Ulloa O, von Dassow P (2023) Do phytoplankton require oxygen to survive? A hypothesis and model synthesis from oxygen minimum zones. Limnol Oceanogr 68(6):1417&#x2013;1437. https://doi.org/10.1002/lno.12367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lno.12367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wooldridge SA (2014) Differential thermal bleaching susceptibilities amongst coral taxa: re-posing the role of the host. Coral Reefs 33:15&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-013-1111-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00338-013-1111-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuasa K, Shikata T, Kuwahara Y, Nishiyama Y (2018) Adverse effects of strong light and nitrogen deficiency on cell viability, photosynthesis, and motility of the red-tide dinoflagellate Karenia mikimotoi. Phycologia 57(5):525&#x2013;533</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeballos N, Grulois D, Leung C, Chevin L-M (2023) Acceptable loss: fitness consequences of salinity-induced cell death in a halotolerant microalga. Am Nat 201(6):825&#x2013;840</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Liu J, He Y, Xie Z, Zhang S, Zhang Y, Lin L, Liu S, Wang D (2019) Quantitative proteomics reveals the key molecular events occurring at different cell cycle phases of the in situ blooming dinoflagellate cells. Sci Total Environ 676:62&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.04.216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.04.216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Cao H, Zheng J, Teng F, Wang X, Lou K, Zhang X, Tao Y (2020) Suppression of water-bloom cyanobacterium Microcystis aeruginosa by algaecide hydrogen peroxide maximized through programmed cell death. J Hazard Mater 393, Article 122394. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.122394</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorz J, Paquette AJ, Gillis T, Kouris A, Khot V, Demirkaya C, De La Hoz SH, Strous M, Vadlamani A (2023) Coordinated proteome change precedes cell lysis and death in a mat-forming cyanobacterium. ISME J 17:2403&#x2013;2414. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41396-023-01545-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41396-023-01545-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>