<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41902656</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1748-3115</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Disability and rehabilitation. Assistive technology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proposed modification of the playing area in table tennis for wheelchair players (C3).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>7</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/17483107.2026.2649981</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Short balls near the net in wheelchair table tennis reduce rally continuity and may increase injury risk due to biomechanical constraints and the limited forward reach of wheelchair players. Modifying the effective playing area may improve rally dynamics and enhance playing safety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty wheelchair table tennis players (class C3; mean age = 26.5&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;3&#xa0;years) participated in a repeated-measures quasi-experimental study. Players first competed on the official table and then on a modified table after completing an 8-week familiarisation training program. The modification introduced a safety line 20&#x2009;cm from the net on both sides, reducing the effective playing depth from 113.5&#x2009;cm to 93.5&#x2009;cm per side. Ten matches were conducted under each condition. Performance was analysed using video analysis. The recorded variables included total and effective playing time, number of ace serves, average rally duration, strokes per rally and the work-to-rest ratio. Differences between conditions were examined using a paired samples <i>t</i>-test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Significant differences (<i>p</i>&#xa0;&#x2264;&#xa0;0.05) were found between the official and modified tables. The modified table increased total and effective playing time, rally duration, strokes per rally and the work-to-rest ratio, while the number of ace serves decreased, indicating improved rally continuity and longer exchanges.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The modified table improved rally continuity and gameplay dynamics among wheelchair players and may reduce the likelihood of upper-limb injuries, supporting its potential value for training and competitive performance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>BaniSaaed</LastName><ForeName>Nedal M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7276-2723</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and sport sciences, Yarmouk University, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qasim</LastName><ForeName>Samir H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5379-1008</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and sport sciences, Yarmouk University, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alzoubi</LastName><ForeName>Rashad T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-5481-7617</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and sport sciences, Yarmouk University, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alzoubi</LastName><ForeName>Amal S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and sport sciences, Yarmouk University, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101255937</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1748-3107</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>The findings of the present study indicate that modifying the playing area dimensions extends beyond performance and competitive aspects to encompass important implications for sports rehabilitation among wheelchair table tennis players (C3). Reducing the unreachable zone near the net decreases the need for excessive compensatory movements of the upper limbs, particularly at the shoulder and elbow joints, which are known to be the most vulnerable to chronic overload and injury in wheelchair users. Consequently, this modification contributes to lowering unnecessary mechanical stress associated with forced forward reaching, thereby supporting the prevention of overuse injuries and enhancing musculoskeletal safety.Furthermore, the observed increases in rally continuity, effective playing time and work-to-rest ratio reflect a more balanced physical and functional stimulus, which is a key element in sport-based rehabilitation programs. This pattern of progressive and sustained effort provides a training environment that aligns with contemporary principles of functional rehabilitation, emphasising improvements in aerobic capacity, motor control and muscular endurance without exposing athletes to excessive acute stress or movements beyond their functional range.In addition, the reduction in reliance on ace serves and the resulting extension of point duration promote greater active participation throughout the match. This increased engagement has positive implications for psychological motivation and perceived motor competence, both of which are critical factors in the success of long-term rehabilitation programs. Accordingly, the proposed modification of the playing area may be considered an effective environmental intervention that integrates athletic performance requirements with functional safety considerations, thereby contributing to improved training quality and competitive experiences for wheelchair table tennis players.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Para-sport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Table tennis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">playing area modification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wheelchair players (C3)</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41902656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17483107.2026.2649981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>